[Music]
it annoys me so much when
prohibitionists try to tell me there is
something wrong with cannabis
i have to practice calmness in the face
of this idiocy
so you can imagine my frustration when
reports began being published
that some cannabis users were becoming
weak and nauseous with abdominal pain
and in need of hot showers because of
their heavy cannabis use
but then as someone who attracts
cannabis patients like i do i learned
that there really seemed to be something
going on
because of an increasing number of cases
being called
cannabis hyperemesis syndrome in the
community
yet i remain skeptical and curious
cannabis social media was apoplectic
about chs
and arguments about if it existed and if
it was caused by neem or eagle 20 or any
other additive were really common
this week lead author dr ethan russo has
released the first original research on
cannabis
hyperemesis syndrome and they have
discovered the genetic markers behind
chs an understanding of what triggers
the expression of those genetics is
vital and cannabis is clearly one of
them
if you want to learn about cannabis
health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer
i encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too
don't rely on social media to let you
know when a new episode is published
sign up for the updates to make sure you
don't miss an episode also we're giving
away very cool prizes to folks who are
signed up to receive the newsletter
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive that newsletter so
go to shapingfire.com to sign up for the
newsletter this week
and be entered into this month's and all
future newsletter prize drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and
i'm your host shango los
today my guest is dr ethan russo
ethan russo is a board certified
neurologist and former senior medical
advisor to gw pharmaceuticals
he served as study physician to gw
pharmaceuticals for three phase three
clinical trials of sativex
he has held faculty appointments in
pharmaceutical sciences
at the university of montana in medicine
at the university of washington
and as visiting professor at the chinese
academy of sciences
he has been president of the
international cannabinoid research
society
and is former chairman of the
international association for
cannabinoid medicines
in 1995 he pursued a three-month
sabbatical doing ethnobotanical research
with indigenous people in peru
dr ethan russo is author of several
books of cannabis medicine
and has published over 30 articles in
neurology pain management cannabis and
ethnobotany
dr russo has joined us before on shaping
fire
episode 22 on treating traumatic brain
injury with cannabis and mushrooms
and episodes 11 and 27 about his famous
research papers on cannabinoids and
terpenoids
and episode number 67 about treating
migraines with mushrooms and cannabis
and of course the shaping fire sessions
on the shaping fire youtube channel
today we offer dr russo's first public
interview on the results of his
groundbreaking paper
on cannabis hyperemesis syndrome
welcome back to shaping fire ethan
thanks for having me
well you know let's start out by getting
a little bit of context while there's
been a lot of social media discussion
for what would become known as
cannabinoid hypermesis syndrome
in the last three years the original
index case that you know way before it
was named goes all the way back to
1996. how has interest in this syndrome
increased over these 25 years or so well
it has a great deal
there's been increasing recognition of
it so that diagnosis has become a little
bit better
although it still remains the case that
people that have it often have to go
through many hospitalizations
or er visits before it's identified
it is increasingly common in relation to
more potent material meaning that
cannabis being higher in
but overall it still would have to be
considered an
uncommon condition but one that is
important to recognize
that original case back in 1996
what about it made it stand out i mean
that's that's some time ago
uh what you know at the time did they
just say oh this person got really high
and and therefore
you know we're going to tie this to thc
or or was it not even originally tied to
thc
it was not um but basically this is in
australia and it was published along
with about eight other cases
only in 2004 so it was only
after a series of patients who were high
cannabis users and
were with close questioning that
the pattern was identified and
recognized
so over these 25 years or so what do you
think was the main
feature that caused the interest to
increase was it just simply
the increased use of cannabis and
therefore there were
um just statistically more cases of it
and so there was
more ability to look at it or was there
some
change in you know a scientific
policy or or a particular grant that
broke the right way like
like what has increased the interest in
it
where people are actually looking at it
now well it
it goes along with liberalization
of cannabis laws in many jurisdictions
but
most particularly with the increasing
availability
of high potency material such as in vape
pens and concentrates
so that's a factor but again there's the
recognition factor
at all enters into the equation i see
multiple things happening at the same
time making for this opportunity to look
at it
sure right on so hyperamisa syndrome is
described
you know mostly by or at least up until
now
as a basket of symptoms a basket of
these common symptoms would you describe
them for us
yeah absolutely it's a very stereotyped
syndrome so what it includes are
cycles of severe nausea vomiting
and abdominal pain but they're
accompanied by a very
characteristic finding that is of the
patients who are afflicted with it
engaging in hot showers and bathing
uh almost in a compulsive fashion
sometimes hours a day
and so that is really what we call the
patho-mnemonic sign
the sign that clinches it when it's
combined with the other symptoms
so is it because what's interesting that
you would say hot showers so we're not
talking cold showers because they might
have a fever or something
they want hot showers does the does the
afflicted patient
know why they want to take hot showers i
mean what's what's their motivation why
do they think they want to go take a hot
shower
uh usually people are not aware
of the condition and that this is an
accoutrement
of it and they may just notice on a day
when they're having abdominal pain and
nausea
that the time they're in the shower they
feel better temporarily
and so you know humans notice patterns
and eventually they come to realize that
this is making them feel better and they
pursue it
sometimes hours a day and it's a
frequent occurrence that
the hot water runs out and then
eventually they
end up in the emergency room with an
extensive
evaluation when you say that um
that the syndrome has got stereotyped
syndrome
that sounds like the medical use of the
term stereotype because i didn't hear
you describing any kind of like stoner
stereotypes what does stereotype
symptoms mean
it means in this instance that you see
the same thing
throughout so if someone has this
syndrome they're going to have
all these features nausea vomiting
abdominal pain
and the hot shower behavior or bathing
behavior
i see in contrast say for example if we
were talking about lupus
where there yeah it's another basket of
symptoms but of the 30 symptoms somebody
might have their particular four or five
so instead of a mix and match pretty
much everybody has
most of these symptoms or if not all of
them that's exactly right the vast
majority of people are going to manifest
all of these four features um has
anybody died yet
yeah unfortunately there have been two
clear cases
on you know this was not related to
an overdose per se rather
they died of complications of the
vomiting uh if someone vomits repeatedly
eventually it's going to cause chemical
imbalances
uh problems with the electrolytes the
minerals in the blood and um there have
been two
documented uh cases of deaths and
question and a third and there may have
been others but uh there have been two
reported so so
let's look at the uh the symptoms uh in
a slight from a slightly different
perspective
so as we've talked about them so far
we've been talking about these
established stereotyped symptoms
um and we're looking we're able to look
at them in hindsight
can you give us a first person
perspective of the patient
and what they would experience like what
are the first ones to come
on and and how can a patient uh
delineate between these
and you know maybe like smoking while
they have the flu or something you know
like how how do they know when they
should be
like thinking about this right well
let's set up a sort of
archetypal patient um this presents in
phases
so uh cannabis hyperemesis or
hyperemesis syndrome is going to appear
in someone who uses cannabis and
usually it's going to be a high volume
user
most often of high potency material
meaning high in thc
and on a regular basis most often daily
or more than daily but the phases are
these
there's what's called a prodrome this
means an initial stage
where while people are using cannabis
they may develop nausea and vomiting
along with anxiety and some sweating
behavior
you know things that go along with
stress
the second phase is clearer this is
going to have the
hyperemesis along with the abdominal
pain and
the hot water water bathing and then the
third
is recovery which happens only following
abstinence basically as long as someone
continues to use cannabis
even in lower amounts they're usually
going to be at risk
for having episodic attacks of a similar
nature so when we're talking about the
volume of
thc um that is required and we'll talk
about some of the
the other you know requirements or what
we are seeing
along with the thc but specifically on
the thc
you're saying like high amounts and
you're saying that okay so we're seeing
more of this
as flowers getting uh stronger and we're
doing um concentration and
and high high thc
edibles does it matter
let's see how do i want to say this does
it matter if somebody smokes
a little low thc
flower every day versus somebody who
dabs on the weekends right like maybe
over the course of the week they're
going to get the same amount of thc
but in one time you're going to get it
all at once and then the and the other
person they're going to get a little bit
every day
i'm trying to understand the nature of
the threshold
yeah well that's going to vary with the
individual and unfortunately
when once the syndrome has become
established
the threshold is not very high um so
for example if someone's been in
remission after abstinence from cannabis
for a while
we find that they often will resume
pretty soon afterwards
not long and it usually goes along with
establishing again some degree of
tolerance
so when somebody begins to escalate
their dose
to achieve their desired level of high
um often they'll have a recurrence
so you know to mention your example this
could
occur in either context the low volume
user
during the week or the dabber during the
weekend
but i'm afraid there'd be no guarantees
and it's people can try to skirt the
edges of this but they're usually quite
unsuccessful
sure sure so and i can imagine that and
we'll talk a lot more about the the
genetic makeup of of these patients
during the second set but
i would think that at the top of that
list would be somebody who dabs every
day because
these are the people in our community
who are getting the highest amounts of
thc every day
quite true quite true so so how about um
with edibles as well
um you know we know that the the mode
of of using thc matters a lot for you
know a whole range
of you know body responses um
are people who are taking high levels of
thc from edibles having these
experiences as well
well they certainly may um in our survey
people had mixed methods of
administration
but most prevalent were either
smoking a flower or high potency
inhalation by whatever method
that was the most frequent but there's
nothing to say
that using an edible would prevent this
and in fact um it's going to be tough
for someone who's in the midst of
an episode of susceptibility to keep
material down and inedible
so you know the fact that this um this
research
it was done as a survey plus a
uh genetic um uh portion of it
um it's it's interesting because it kind
of shows two sides of of the coin on one
side you're asking people about their
use
and then on the second side you're
actually
you know running um you know taking a
look a short read of their genetics to
find out
what you can what you can find in common
um you know i would have i can't help
but have some amount of of awareness
that
people don't usually want to talk about
their cannabis use um because if it's
historically being
you know prohibited and taboo um would
you explain
how the survey functions um
because you know you and i have talked
off mic about this before and you know
you've got you've got a lot of good
feels and a lot of confidence and the
information that you're getting from
these surveys
um and and i think we'd all like to
understand
how that works when when the basis of
the survey is asking questions
yes sure well first of all this is all
anonymized um you know if you ask me who
was in it i couldn't tell you
except for a couple of people who have
told me themselves after the fact
so great pains were taken to
protect people's identities
especially in the instance of taking
their genetic material
uh it's a highly formalized procedure of
ensuring that
that infra information can't escape
so and this went the the other
layer of protection was that this went
through what's called an
institutional review board an ethics
committee
to ensure that there'd be no danger to
patients and that includes
being identified when they do not wish
to be
is it hard to communicate this safety
idea to people who are doing a study on
something that may even be illegal where
they live
um it sure has been in the past a little
bit less now with the liberalization of
laws but it remains an issue
absolutely i like actually your use of
the word liberalization of laws i hadn't
heard anybody use that before you know
people a lot of people use legalization
or normalization but
liberalization is is yet a different way
to put it which is which is not the
other two which i don't i don't think
the other two really fit are what we're
experiencing yet so
i like that i think i think i'll use
that myself so um
and and did you reach out to these
people because they were showing
symptoms and you reached out to them
through healthcare providers or did you
just put a you know a big
call out to everybody and people who
identified with the
with the nausea and the hot showers just
kind of like self-identified
yeah more the latter it was uh
systematized
um i sent this to various list serves
related to cannabis to physicians
who have an interest in cannabis we also
reached out
to emergency departments
and gastroenterologists and we contacted
people who had previously been authors
of studies of chs
and you know it's put on social media as
well
so there were a variety of methods of
outreach
but people could only come to it if they
self-identified
as being a venture being interested in
the study
random okay well i wanted i want to go
into the thc
survey aspect and the uh genetics
aspect in the same set so that we can
talk about all of that at once so let's
go ahead and
take our first short break and be right
back you are listening to shaping fire
and my guest today is neurologist and
cannabis researcher
dr ethan russo
[Music]
over the years shaping fire has been
invited to sponsor several cannabis cups
and i've said no to them all
it wasn't until the autoflower cup that
i really wanted to help promote
something
and the producers sebastian and carla
didn't even invite me i approached them
i told them that autoflower cup was
important to me for three reasons
first it was obvious that they were
going for a friends and family vibe
instead of some sort of commodified
cannabis vibe
this event was going to gather really
cool folks
second the event had a ton of cool stuff
to do and to learn and to participate in
the event isn't just about cannabis it's
about living life fully
enjoying community eating together
laughing and listening to music
and mushrooms third and most important
to me personally the event was
authentically
for the autoflower community and the
autoflower community needs a place
too autoflower is about getting high
sure but i find that much of the
autoflower community is still focused on
cannabis patients
sharing best practices sharing seeds and
humility
these are the ideals that i share with
the event and i wanted to make sure i
did my part to help it succeed
announcing the 2021 autoflower cup
august 6th 7th and 8th
in lillawup washington just outside of
seattle
this over 21 event is presented by camp
ruderalis
the autoflower competition is open to
everyone commercial and home growers
so get your skills recognized and enter
today a cup win now will make you a
leader in the community
here comes the ear candy stunned in
glass hookah lounge
pop-up magical butter chocolate shop
waterfront marketplace with an array of
vendors
there will be an old school autoflower
seed swap joint rolling competition
cannabis cooking demos solventless
squishing demos
and late night documentary screenings of
fantastic fungi
chef sebastian carosi's award-winning
classics like
elk chili kobe beef kimchi dogs
oyster po boys and razor clam chowder
wild oyster harvesting mushroom foraging
s'mores around the campfires each night
dan jimmy of mandalorian presentations
psilocybin mushrooms presentations
camping glamping rvs and airbnb
so check out camprooteralis.com for
those details
and follow the instagram at the
autoflower cup 2021
[Music]
sometimes the topics i want to share
with you are far too brief for an entire
shaping fire episode
in those instances i post them to
instagram i
invite you to follow my two instagram
profiles and participate
online the shaping fire instagram has
follow-up posts to shaping fire episodes
growing and processing best practices
product trials and
of course gorgeous flower photos the
shango los
instagram follows my travels on cannabis
garden tours my successes and failures
in my own garden
insights and best practices from
personal grows everywhere
and always gorgeous flower photos on
both profiles the emphasis is on sharing
what i've learned in a way that you can
replicate it in your own garden
your own hash lab or for your own
cannabinopathic health
so i encourage you to follow at shaping
fire and
at shango lows and join our online
community on instagram
[Music]
with the national hemp program in flux
due to stringent thc testing
requirements
brother seth and eric crawford continue
to release seeds to hemp farmers that
will be legal
no matter how you grow them or when you
test them these new varieties from
oregon cbd seeds have substantial
amounts of cbdv
cbgv cbcv and thcv
while always staying below the 0.3
percent thc limit
and guaranteeing complying crops for
farmers every time
also these new varieties cannot be
pollinated by your neighbor's
uncontrolled pollen
or a rogue male in your own crop either
oregon cbd seeds are non-gmo certified
too
oregon cbd seeds was founded and funded
in 2015 by
seth and eric maxing out their personal
credit cards without
outside investment they continue to
refuse outside investment that would
change their company culture
oregon cbd grows tons of fresh food on
their research farms for local food
banks
literally tons of food they also give
away tens of thousands of pounds of r d
flour to patients as their company began
to succeed
seth and eric started donating money to
the cannabis medicine and hemp fiber
cause too
by giving millions of dollars to oregon
state university in order to establish
the world's leading cannabis genomics
research program
and they treat their employees right
oregon cbd pays for full health and
dental coverage for their employees
a 401k program and their minimum
starting wage is 20 bucks an hour
plus everyone shares food from the farms
seth has been on shaping fire a few
times to talk about novel cannabinoids
you can check out episodes 25 and 37 on
cbd cultivars in the hemp market
episode 66 on triploid cannabis genetics
and the very first shaping fire live
episode 47
with seth and soil expert jeff lowenfels
talking about autoflowers if you are a
hemp farmer and you want to grow
reliable seeds that are sure to thrive
in past testing
check out oregoncbdseeds.com to learn
more about buying seeds for the 2021
season
that's oregoncbdseeds.com
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shanglos and
our guest this week is neurologist and
cannabis researcher dr
ethan russo so let's dive into the first
half of this paper which is about
the survey about talking to cannabis
users
about their usage of cannabis generally
but
more specifically you're trying to tease
out thc
how did you go about asking the
questions ethan what were you trying to
pull
out of them and and after they answered
what did you see in the results sure
well it was a large series of questions
as
you've seen and will be evident in the
paper because we include
links to the entire survey both the
uh chs patients and the controls
uh so we went through simply saying have
you used cannabis
in the last year how often how much a
day
what type by what method
etc etc until we got the answers we
wanted
but we started out with 585
respondents of that
there were 205 patients who had the
constellation of symptoms of cannabinoid
hyperemesis syndrome
and carried a diagnosis so we were being
very careful about who we selected for
the study
we needed medical confirmation plus
ongoing symptoms so that's how you get
from
five eighty five to two hundred and five
of that group most were very high
frequency
users of cannabis ninety one percent
used daily or multiple times a day
and as we mentioned it was a high amount
cannabis flower concentrates the median
response was 4 grams a day of thc
predominant material
other features of the chs patients
15.6 percent carried a diagnosis of
either cannabis dependency or addiction
so that's much higher than you'd expect
in other populations and to corroborate
that
almost 57 percent had experienced
withdrawal symptoms from cannabis which
is all
also uncharacteristic um
now on the good side when people stopped
uh
like they might have gone to the
emergency room and told they had to stop
using cannabis 87.7
improved after they stopped but almost
all suffered a recurrence when they
resumed
now big problem in this study was
finding out
who do we compare these people to we
couldn't
just use normal people
who didn't use cannabis because who
wouldn't know if they had a
susceptibility
to developing cannabis hyperemesis
syndrome if they hadn't used it
in similar amounts so we found
control so-called
who were high-volume users of cannabis
but did not have chs
so we ended up with 54 of those
and in the survey information all of
them had used within
a year 70 were daily or more than daily
and again mostly by smoking thc
predominant material
now in contrast to the chs
patients only 3.7 had been
labeled as cannabis addicted or
dependent
and the vast majority 76 percent had
never had withdrawal symptoms
uh only 11 percent have been told that
they needed to stop cannabis for health
reasons
um so we felt that this was a good
comparison group
and uh so these two pools the 205
patients with chs that was confirmed
they had all the symptoms they had
ongoing symptoms
they had a diagnosis from a physician
and 54 controls
all of these people were offered the
option
of having their genomes tested
this is done by a swab in the mouth and
through the technology
that samples amplified so that we can
look at all the base pairs
um of the genetic sequence and see if
there are any unusual patterns
so that's how it was done now that
really whittled things down
although 99 patients
from the chs group agreed to get a test
kit only
28 returned it that seems especially low
yeah yeah well especially after they
were said they were willing to do it but
we actually had a little bit of
pushback uh from the chs community
uh there were people that questioned our
motives uh there were some people that
said
you shouldn't do this study um
and so it was very difficult it took us
a year
of recruitment to get our sample which
ended up being 28
chs patients and 12 controls
were people pushing back because it was
being sponsored by a private company
instead of an academic institution
uh well it could have been a factor
but let's make something clear and i i
don't know how to say this except
telling the truth
it's going to sound accusatory um
but people with chs tend to be very
uh suspicious um
and many uh people who have it don't
believe
that it's related to their cannabis
usage i mean
after all everyone knows that cannabis
is supposed to be good for nausea and
vomiting
so how could it be creating this problem
well
in fact thc is an antimatter
something that helps prevent vomiting
but it's also
subject to what's called a biphasic dose
response
what that means is at low doses thc
will prevent nausea and vomiting to some
degree
hopefully a lot but at high doses it
flips its activity and can be
pro-emetic meaning making vomiting more
likely
plus there are other considerations when
someone uses cannabis to this extent
they have tolerance part of tolerance is
that the cb1 receptors in the brain
where thc
works uh down regulate they sort of fold
in
it's the brain's way of saying saying
too much activity here we've got to turn
down the volume
so there are all these things that may
be coming into play
as well as the metabolism the breakdown
of of thc that
we had to consider on as we discuss
the results this will become more clear
so as um so you sent out these these 99
kits and and about you know ended up
buying about 25 percent of people
responded um did you um
did you see uh enough in the data
where you were able to get what you
wanted even though you got less
participation
uh we believe so i mean the the
proof of something medical is in the
statistics
so what we want to see to make something
statistically significant
is what's called a p-value probability
value of five percent or less what that
means is
that the results that are seen could
only happen by chance
one in 20 times or less and so we
achieved that
with several uh examples
obviously it would have been better to
have more patients but that
again proved very difficult uh wasn't
just the pushback from the community
there are a lot of people who don't want
their
chromosomes tested they've heard of
situations of
people getting arrested not because they
had their
genetic profile done but their cousin
did and somehow
law enforcement found their way to the
person in question
there have been some high profile cases
solved recently
related to this technology
all right well i can see that so so um
as far as a patient having hyperemesis
syndrome it seems like we're after
reading paper we're talking about uh
two things that have to both happen
number one
the the cannabis user uh
needs to have a high overall use of thc
which appears to be predominant daily
and that they're using more than um four
grams of high thc
material a day and of course while
that's a big swing between
four grams of flour versus four grams
of um oil one way or another
you're you're at a high level as far as
the the overall
um you know users in the united states
you know four grams of flour a day
wow well not necessarily incredibly high
for a lot of people i know
if we take the pool of all cannabis
viewers it's actually exceptionally high
it is and i i would emphasize that lower
levels of use could
also lead to problems in someone who's
susceptible
right but this will vary all right then
let's get to that susceptibility part so
the first part is
you take you you know more or less you
take in a lot of thc
but that has to be uh coordinated with
um someone's genetic predispos
disposition
and so this part of the paper um uh
you know to unraveling the genetic
makeup
um you know i can i can admit to the
fact that it's a bit over my head but
but luckily you break it down to
you know there's there's pretty much
five places
that popped up for you that showed
that some some correlation um would you
go through
as you know as you see fit the the five
sites and what you what you learned from
those sites
sure be happy to but let's start off
with one that
we suspected that didn't turn out to
have a pattern at least in the patients
that
that we examined so that would be a gene
called
cnr1 that's the gene that encodes the
cb1 receptor
so cb1 is where thc works and the
endogenous cannabinoids work
so this has been examined before in
relation to other disorders
um and what we're looking for is often
what are called
single nucleotide polymorphisms
this this is a way of saying that there
is a change in
one pair of
these base pairs in dna
so there's been some correlation of
mutations
on cnr1 the cb1 receptor gene
related to cannabis usage but we didn't
see that pattern
in the uh cannabinoid hyperemesis
syndrome patients
but um there's a
disorder that's sometimes confused with
chs called cvs
that's cyclic vomiting syndrome now this
is actually
different um this is often something
that appears in childhood
but may persist into adulthood and
people have episodes of
vomiting that come out of the blue it
seems to be related to a propensity
for migraine so sometimes it starts off
with a child who has episodic vomiting
without a headache
and it's only when they're older that
they get the headaches
now cvs cyclic vomiting syndromes
become more confused with chs because
in cvs people use cannabis to advantage
to treat than nausea and vomiting
but in cyclic vomiting syndrome there
have been mutations
in the cnr1 gene that have been observed
so
this is another point of distinction so
i wanted to start there
where we expected a finding but it
wasn't there but it still is
useful because we can differentiate this
from cyclic vomiting syndrome got it it
creates a nice point of contrast
sure now what did we find
well we'll start off with a gene called
comt
that is short for a mouthful catechol
o methyl transferase comt
is the gene that
codes for an enzyme that breaks down
catecholamines especially
dopamine so these are neurotransmitters
in the brain and elsewhere
so what we saw was a mutation
in the comt and this occurred in 57.1
of the chs patients but only 10 percent
of controls
so that had what what's called a p-value
of 0.012
so that's well below the 0.05
threshold that makes something
statistically significant
from a medical standpoint and it had
what's called an
odds ratio of 12 which is is quite
wide as compared to the controls
so what do we know about this mutation
well when comt has a loss of function
you have too much dopamine and an excess
of that
is associated with a number of different
problems
like compulsive behavior and that can be
anything from
substance abuse gambling even sex
addiction
uh have been related to this
this specific mutation that we saw is
called
rs464
46316 i'm sorry let me do that again
rs 464
um in prior studies this has been
related to
depression uh what's called rumination
behavior where people
can't get something out of their head
they ruminate about it
and also having heavy alcohol intake at
a younger age
and that is a feature in our survey that
we saw in chs patients that
a lot of them had problems with alcohol
at one point in their life or not
other mutations on this gene have been
associated with
impulsive behavior disinhibited behavior
also some associations with attention
deficit
obsessive compulsive disorder and
i'm afraid a tendency towards anxiety
and even psychosis
so it doesn't mean that somebody who has
has all these things but we have seen
similar problems
in this population it means that they're
more
likely to have these kinds of problems
but certainly this finding
provides some insight into some of the
things the epi phenomena
the um features that we see in chs
patients
all right so uh is that is that complete
on the c-o-m-t
um is that as everything that we want to
move on to the next one
sure all right sure let's do that well
the next one is one that
that i predicted um one of the features
of chs
is one of the things that seems to help
of course is the heat
also uh use of capsaicin ointment on the
skin
capsaicin is the caustic part of chili
peppers
some time ago it was noticed that when
people had
application of an ointment with a lot of
capsaicin
in it that it would reduce the nausea
and vomiting at least temporarily
so what the hot showers and the
capsaicin have
in common is that they're working
through another receptor called the trip
v1 receptor um
and we saw a mutation there and that was
something we predicted
so 71.5 percent of the chs patients had
this
and only 30 percent in controls
uh so that's a p-value of 0.015
below the .05 threshold
and an odds ratio of 5.8
so this gene has been linked to
anxiety and pain responses in the brain
and it's also um
has activity on areas of the brain that
relate to
how fast or slow your gut is moving on
how much
fluid is secreted so it has
a definite tie-in to nauseum mechanisms
um now as far as we know
um so far the trip v1 mutations
haven't been observed previously when
it's
we've looked at patients with cannabis
dependency
now our finding on this specific
mutation
may be a new one because it wasn't in
the usual databases
of genetic changes so this one is called
rs879207
but certainly the findings that we got
suggest a linkage
of cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome to
mood and gut disturbances as well as
obviously the hot water
uh bathing behavior um and it
again goes along with the
success of using capsaicin on the skin
that trip v1 receptor is really
important in this disorder
is capsaicin a common input
into topical lotions i i haven't
personally come across it before though
it could be very common
when i heard that people were using that
and they're like oh this works for me
i'm like i would never have even tried
that sure
well you know it's funny because it
burns when you put it on
it's like chili peppers um i should
point out though
that um absorption of capsaicin
orally is not very good um you know
people have used uh have uh eaten
thai food that was too hot sometimes
it'll burn on the way in
and on the way out it's not getting into
the bloodstream
but it does get in the bloodstream
through the skin as can
as opposed to cannabinoids um so we
we know that you can get blood levels um
this way
interesting yeah that is interesting um
is there anything else that you want to
mention on this particular site uh
no i think that's good for now we
actually saw
mutations in another area of the same
gene but it didn't quite reach
statistical significance
um is it the kind of thing where you
know you you highlighted it and you're
and
but and it's worthwhile to look later on
or is it like
oh yeah you do you want to tell us a
little bit about it even though
for this study it's not statistically
significant uh sure
you know it's something we're going to
keep in the back of our minds
as we get more people tested
maybe it will achieve statistical
significance at some point
and certainly if if a person ends up
having a mutation on two areas of the
same gene
it increases the likelihood that
it isn't going to work properly and that
they'll be attendant
problems in other words disease
manifestations
right on um so what what is this other
site
oh it's just a different area of the
same gene oh i see
so so you just saw you just saw the
correlation number was high
but you didn't take it that next next
level to figure out
um what it might be doing there yet
because the numbers were too low
ah right i understand it's something to
keep an eye on in the future
all right well then what's our next site
next one also makes some good
sense this is the cyp2c9 gene
so this is a gene uh that
it's in the cytochrome p450 series these
are um enzymes that
break down drugs and toxins in the liver
okay as it turns out cyp2c9
is the uh breakdown enzyme
uh for thc
and its first metabolite 11-hydroxy thc
so if there's a problem with this gene
it may mean
that thc doesn't get broken down as
readily
so we we saw a mutation in the chs
patients in 46.4 percent
and only 10 percent of controls so the p
value wasn't quite as dramatic but it
was still
0.043 which is below 0.05
um so you know if we think about this
conceptually
if this enzyme is not as functional as
it should be it could lead to
accumulation of thc
and get into that biphasic dose response
where
thc instead of becoming antiemetic
becomes problematic
uh or it's even possible because the
enzyme isn't quite right
that it's making a different metabolite
than usual
instead of 11-hydroxy thc it's possible
probably unlikely but it's possible that
it's making a different product that
could
uh have toxic effects
now to help us out here
just a couple of months ago there was a
new study where a single patient
got tested and they had two sites on
cyp2c19 that were off
that was a chs patient who
was cannabis dependent and they they
said had a personality disorder
uh as well they didn't provide a lot of
detail on that
so this is something that's been seen at
least one other time
but our study was the first to look at
it systematically
the idea that um this uh cyp2c19 is
where
thc gets broken down um am i thinking
about this correctly
if i think we're to think of it as okay
normally
when we um use thc it
is cleared from our body in you know
three to four hours or at least from
from the usable flow in three to four
hours
and so um with this site not working
effectively
um it would just simply either a
break down the thc in longer
than three or four hours so there's like
a like almost like a half-life because
you'd already be smoking your next smoke
before it's it all your prior thc
is processed or maybe it's and or
um the thc is being broken down
incorrectly not towards like body best
practices if you will
and and so it's actually kicking out um
chemicals that are are not what you
expect when you smoke thc
yeah that's right um you had said cyp2c9
this is actually cyp2c9 okay but i'm
glad you mentioned that
because um cyp2c19
also breaks down thc it's just not the
predominant enzyme that does
and we did see changes there in a few
patients but again
not with statistical significance
okay so by my account um
we have hit either three or four sites
so we've either got one or two left what
is what's our next one
yeah we've done three well we've talked
about four but three that were
statistically significant
now the next one relates to the first
one and that is
this is drd2 this is the gene that codes
for the
d2 dopamine receptor
again dopamine is a chemical messenger
neurotransmitter in the brain
and drd2 is the target of most
antipsychotic drugs drugs used to treat
schizophrenia
and when there's a drug that stimulates
this receptor
it actually causes vomiting and affects
the gut motility how fast the gut is
moving
so we saw mutation in drd2
in 60.7 of the chs
patients and only 20 percent of controls
so the p-value on that was .031
well below 0.05
this same mutation which is on a thing
called rs464
8318 in prior studies
is strongly associated with depression
and anxiety
those are features we see a lot in
chs patients unfortunately
also there have been associations of
other mutations on this gene
with nicotine addiction uh tourette
syndrome and chronic pain
and uh those are all well addiction and
chronic pain were
features that we saw in a number of the
respondents
um now i should point out that
we have a mutation on drd2
also on comt the the gene that breaks
down dopamine
so we've got sort of a double whammy
here so to speak
affecting dopamine metabolism and this
may really help
explain how cannabinoid hyperemesis
syndrome is associated with nausea and
vomiting and some of these psychiatric
problems that seem to appear in the same
patients right
so um it's interesting to see that this
is the second
site that we've talked about that's
directly related
to uh the dopamine system
and so uh no doubt that's playing a
significant role in
in the the um
syndrome yeah yeah and it also points
out something else we know
phenomenologically and that is that the
drug haloperidol which is
normally used to treat schizophrenia
is more effective in treating the nausea
and vomiting in chs patients
than the more commonly used drugs more
commonly used or uh things like on
dansetron
um and grenisatron that work through a
different receptor they work very poorly
in chs patients
now the problem is that haloperidol
is a drug you don't want to be taking
all the time
um uh it has a lot of side effects it's
extremely sedating
uh can be associated with massive weight
gain
um and some really terrible long-term
side effects
possibility of developing diabetes
or a movement disorder from the drug
called
tardive dyskinesia which is extremely
difficult to treat
so taking hilo peridol on a regular
basis
isn't uh something that people are going
to want to do
we have to look at better approaches
all right i've got two uh two quick
comments on vocabulary first of all
um uh you know i don't know much about
the drug dance-a-tron but
i love the name dance tron it sounds
like a video
on dance-a-tron oh all right well it's
still it's still pretty good
it's got a playful ring to it still but
more importantly so
you know from a moment ago i was
searching for the word syndrome right
and i kept on wanting to come up with
disease when used you know as a medical
term
what does this word syndrome
a syndrome is a pattern of
problems that leads to a diagnosis a
disease
is due to one cause whereas a syndrome
may have
multiple different causes okay so
actually we'll use a misnomer we talk
about parkinson disease
it's not really a disease because
there's more than one cause
it should be called parkinson's syndrome
because
when you lose a certain number of
neurons related to the dopamine system
again
um in the brain that can come from any
cause
aging strokes toxins
when you have killed off 90
of those cells you have a parkinson's
syndrome
so a disease would be more like strep
throat
a disorder caused by streptococcus
but unfortunately these terms are used
somewhat interchangeably and
um you know but a syndrome is a
pattern of symptoms or signs that leads
to a diagnosis
okay thanks thanks for doing that so so
what's the the the fifth and final
um site we're going to talk about here
yeah well this one
is a little harder to explain um and
this is on
something called abc a1 that's the atp
binding cassette transporter this
gene affects cholesterol and other
lipid metabolism
it's most important in that it's related
to alzheimer's disease
and in that disorder there's an
accumulation
of abnormal uh proteins
in the brain and we'll get to how that
relates here if we can
so we saw a mutation uh in abc a1
that was present in 67.9 of the
cannabinoid hyperemesis patients
and only 20 percent of control so that
was a p-value of 0.012
well below the 0.05 threshold
now additionally this is a homozygous
mutation meaning that
you know we have two sets of of each
chromosome
and it appeared in both um it wasn't
just on one it was on
both so unfortunately because
this gene mutation appeared in both
um chromosomes in affected patients
it could imply an increased risk of the
development of dementia
memory loss later in life
and additionally it could
lead to risk factors for coronary artery
disease
heart attacks and the development of
type 2 diabetes
and uh not this specific mutation
but another mutation on a closely
related gene abcb1
uh were associated with cannabis
dependency in another study
so you know but we certainly see
a higher degree of cannabis dependency
in the chs patients
than we could explain by chance so
when you got the results and you saw
these five sites um
there was a lot of correlation and then
there were the there was
uh the other one that didn't have quite
enough uh significant correlation
was your initial response like hot damn
there's five
sites we have something here or we're
like oh we're really hoping for ten this
isn't a lot or like anything
more than one you know as somebody who
is you know i don't do your job so
i don't know whether or not getting five
hits like this
is like like wildly successful
or or regular or low
um i was excited i think we really have
something here
we have um several genes that help
explain the phenomenology
of chs um now i should emphasize
um i don't know that any of the patients
had all
five mutations but
often they'd have combinations of of one
or several
and what we're looking at again is a
susceptibility factor
we hope that we can use this as a
screening device
as it is now someone who has this
constellation of
symptoms ends up with a lot of
hospitalizations
and emergency department visits on
and that is very invasive and expensive
there have been two quotes in the
literature of how much people have spent
before they've gotten a diagnosis and
it's ranged between
twenty six thousand dollars and ninety
six thousand dollars
wow um and that was then the ninety six
thousand dollars was
some years ago i guarantee those costs
would be higher
now if this is not recognized
so it's our hope that in the future
if a patient comes to the er and the
doctor there is wondering about this
they may want to do this
test and see if there's a
susceptibility there especially if
they've previously
had tests cat scans mris
upper gi lower gi um these tests are
almost always
negative um they're expensive they can
be invasive
um we're hoping that this is going to
lead to
better identification and saving people
time and money as well as pain
yeah definitely that um before i move us
off the sites do you have anything that
you want to say on
on any of these sites before i move to
the next the next set oh i think we're
good
all right so so let's talk about so far
during this set we have talked about
you know the the two primary you know
folks who are in this dance the first
being high thc
and then and then second being um
showing mutations on these sites
and you know as somebody who's been in
the scene for a long time
and and have had friends who have
experienced these these
um symptoms um and i've seen them
firsthand there's
there's a lot of us who have
participated in really
ugly threads on social media about what
was
causing um these symptoms
and then you know eventually being
called
chs two of those
um are neem which is a crushed up seed
used as a fertilizer and
to some a pest discouragement
and then and then other people were
making suggestions that it's clearly
eagle 20 a classically banned
cannabis pesticide and the defense of
you know it being one or two or both of
these were just like off the charts to
see
people get so angry with each other
about bro science is really
disheartening
um so you know we've got to address
these ethan so
so what can you tell us about neem and
what can
you tell us about it pesticides as their
you know ability to
be causes for chs
well they are not um i have been a great
critic
of pesticide use in cannabis i've
published about this before
and it would have been nice if that were
the answer but it's not
um as someone who had the misfortune
of treating patients with pesticide
exposure i can tell you
that it's a totally different situation
to chs
and as someone who uses organic neem on
my
fruit and berries it doesn't fit either
the symptoms do not match up at all and
they
certainly are not producing genetic
mutations
at this level it is the case that some
pesticides could
mess with a person's dna but um i
i'm afraid that that is
just uh delusional to think that that's
the cause of this syndrome
um a couple of other examples uh
again this syndrome chs was first
described in 2004
at that time it was not the degree of
pesticide usage in cannabis culture that
there
is today so that doesn't make sense
additionally chs has been encountered
unfortunately with some synthetic
cannabinoids as well
where although they certainly can be
toxic
there's no reason to think that there
would be pesticides or neem
in those uh so that's just one of those
theories that doesn't hold water so
ethan the the
the assertion that you made that uh
there were
less pesticides being used in 2004 than
there are now
like that jumps up to me like a red flag
so i'm curious
if you would break that thought out to
me because you know as far as
most of us chat we most of us say you
know back in the day
people would put you know any kind of
evil pesticide on their stuff so that
they could get it out through you know
the black market and they
and people didn't know their customer as
often
and because they were you know they're
shipping it places or they were you know
putting it downstream whereas nowadays
people are more aware
of the pesticides being unhealthy and
more people are looking for pesticide
free stuff
that's my assumption right um
what what what's in your head that gives
you the idea that they were used more in
um well it's based on what i've heard
from testing labs
um now again the sophistication in
identifying these compounds is greater
uh than it was
i i think that this is a phenomenon
that's gone through peaks and valleys
yeah um so you know i
i couldn't give you the the statistics
in any given year
um but suffice it to say that
pesticides and neem are not the cause of
cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome
right that part i get well all right
great so
um all right so let's wrap up this set
when we come back and um
to set three we're gonna talk about um
you know a handful of questions that
don't have
um you know easy categories but for now
let's go ahead and and
take our break you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is
neurologist and cannabis researcher dr
ethan russo
[Music]
while i love growing under the sun
there's a lot of good reasons to grow
indoors
and if you're like most folks you want a
lighting source that grows high yielding
healthy plants without using excessive
amounts of electricity
bios lighting creates biological
lighting solutions
that brings the natural brilliance of
the outdoors into your grow room
bios lighting has the attributes that i
look for in a horticultural lighting
solution
i've bought those cheap lights online
and they're difficult to work with and
fail in no time
in contrast my bios led light is
industrial grade to last a long time
it is ip66 wet rated so little foliar
overspray won't harm it
it is easy to clean without taking it
down and of course the most important
aspect
is built for the exact light spectrum i
want for great yielding healthy cannabis
plants
and it doesn't hurt that their lighting
rigs look badass too
many horticultural led lighting systems
are based on irrelevant performance
metrics
and people love to argue online about
these numbers i prefer to judge on
par photon efficiency and how happy my
plants are
and the bios lights exceed my
expectations in these categories
bios lights have an optimized broad
spectrum that maximizes photosynthesis
and plant growth
while also providing the ideal
conditions for superior par
efficacy and a comfortable visual
experience i also love their attentive
and over-educated customer service folks
bios starts with a team of biologists
before getting the electrical engineers
involved they have studied how light
impacts cannabis plants
and devised an overall strategy that
works i encourage you to check out their
website at
bioslighting.com to learn more about how
this strategy can work for you
and shaping fire listeners can get a
special deal use the discount code
shaping fire all one word no caps for 10
off your entire purchase that's
biosliding.com
after you've caught up on the latest
shaping fire episodes do you sometimes
wish there was more cannabis education
available to learn
well we got you shaping fire has a
fabulous youtube channel with content
not found on the podcast
when i attend conventions to speak or
moderate panels i always record them and
bring the content home for you to watch
the shango los youtube channel has
world-class speakers including
zoe sigmund's lecture understanding your
endocannabinoid system
kevin jodrey of wonderland nursery
talking about breeding cannabis for the
best terpene profile
frenchy cannolis lost art of the
hashishin presentation
nicholas mahmoud on regenerative and
polyculture cannabis growing
dr sunil agarwal on the history of
cannabis medicine around the world
eric vlosky and josh rutherford on
solvent-less extraction
and jeff lonefels on the soil food web
there are several presentations from dr
ethan russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system too
while there be sure to check out the
three 10-part shaping fire sessions
series
one with kevin jodrey one with dr ethan
russo and one with jeff lowenfels
and even my own presentations on how to
approach finding your dream job in
cannabis
and why we choose cannabis business even
though the risks are so high
as of today there's over 200 videos that
you can check out for free
so go to youtube.com forward slash
shangolos or click on the link in the
newsletter
[Music]
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated
it is increasingly important to avoid
the use of chemical pesticides when
cultivating cannabis
beneficial insects have been used for
decades by the greenhouse vegetable and
ornamental plant industry
and today many cannabis cultivators are
moving from sprays and chemicals
to beneficial insects covert biological
systems has the beneficial insects
mites and nematodes microbials sticky
cards and air distribution units
you need to partner with nature to
defend your garden
whether you manage acres of canopy or
have a simple grow tent in your home
cobra is ready to help answer your
questions and help you transition away
from chemical sprays towards clean and
natural solutions
since 1967 culprit has assisted growers
in identifying pests
and devising reliable solutions while
providing healthy insects and mites that
will protect your yield
since the 1990s cobra has been a leader
in cannabis pest and disease control
worldwide and have highly trained
consultants
to assist you in canada and the us from
coast to coast
no matter where you live covert
biological systems can help
visit cobert.com choose your country and
get detailed information
that's cobert k-o-p-p-e-r-t
dot com for the most up-to-date cannabis
related biological control information
you can also check out their instagram
at covert canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and culprit is ready to help visit
cobert.com today
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host shango los
and our guest this week is neurologist
and cannabis researcher
dr ethan russo so ethan you know one of
the things that the paper
points out that you know i i really
identified with was
the paper said that uh in general people
waited a long time to get help
and while i'm certainly the kind of man
who's willing to
ask for directions when i'm driving my
car and i'm not afraid to go to the
doctors
it all just sounds like you know a pain
in the ass
um to have to go but at the same time
these symptoms are severe and the sooner
you go
the better you know your likelihood for
treatment
is so um can you kind of talk to
both both the psychological aspect of
you know people resisting going to a
doctor about something
but also more specifically
what you saw as the line in the sand
for these patients of when they had had
enough
well i i think it often is uh required
the intervention of a family member or
friend
um quite frankly um
for some of these patients they'll spend
all day in the shower as long as the hot
water lasts
um it really can come down to that
unfortunately
plus there's the factor that some of
them have already been told that
uh this is likely related to cannabis
usage and it's not a message that's well
received
and then there's the whole factor of
legality or illegality
you know we on the west coast are more
accustomed to
cannabis being legal but that's not true
everywhere at all
and there's still a stigma attached
no matter how you look at it yeah i buy
that and
and for for most of us who use cannabis
um you know even though i consider it
all medical
most people think about it either
medical or recreational
but but the medical care system is not
necessarily our friend
either of us and um and no one wants to
go to the hospital to be
you know treated like an addict or
something you know exactly
yeah so so let's talk about the
treatment
so um you know if
the paper makes it sound very cut and
dry
that the only treatment apparently is
stopping using cannabis for a while is
it that cut and dry
well it is if we're talking about uh
eliminating the problem yes um
now that doesn't preclude the idea that
we may develop approaches that are going
to reduce
or mitigate symptoms but we don't have
anything like that
now you can't cover your body in
capsaicin cream
as a regular treatment
so you know at this point we have
signals from our results
uh places to point for possibilities
you know we know that haloperidol works
better than
other antimatters um
there is another drug a prepatin that's
been used in one patient
it works on a different area in the
brain
you know one of the things to wonder
about is could the
problem be attacked by something from
cannabis other than thc and that's
really possible
say for example when whenever you take
your thc make sure you take some
cbn with it or something like that um
no i'm afraid that isn't gonna work um
seemingly
any exposure to thc is a risk factor
for someone who has chs um
again there may be a certain threshold
and we we find people are trying to
skirt that threshold all the time
but when an attack hits it's too late
um you know again there's an
extremely high relapse rate uh
with this syndrome once it's established
um and uh i i we
have to recommend or someone in my
position as a physician has to recommend
abstinence from thc exposure
is it more like a tolerance break or i
mean like is it is it
you know you should stop using thc
forever ever
or is it i at all so it's not like oh
you're a daily dabber
you need to go down to joints only
something like that again i wouldn't
rule out the possibility that there is a
low-level threshold but
people are not going to be able to
resume their prior uh
intake levels i see that's clear yeah
and this is very individualized medicine
so none
none these are generalities really
depending on the susceptibility of each
person you use the term attack
you said when they have an attack i had
not really considered it as an attack so
is do they come on like an episode where
you're not feeling it okay will you
describe an episode
well i again i could start with this pro
drum of nausea and vomiting
um or low level nausea and then progress
to a full-blown um episode with nausea
vomiting abdominal pain
and over the course of a day or is this
like over the course of a week
it again it can vary but um
often there may be weeks or even months
of the pro drone before
uh full-blown attacks so we've we've got
you know the possibility that changes in
usage
could be helpful we've got a possibility
that um
you know some of this pharmaceuticals
might be useful but but really the long
and the short of it is
is once you're diagnosed with chs
what is actually called for is cessation
of thc
sure yeah now again there may be other
adjunctive approaches that are helpful
um we're trying to look at whether
lifestyle factors enter in
you know whether they're dietary changes
that could be helpful
anti-inflammatory diets more
healthy healthy diets fruits and
vegetables
that's unclear at this point but that
would be possible
could uh aerobic activity or meditation
or any of these other things be helpful
you know we're at a stage where these
are avenues that need to be explored
but i wouldn't have any hard and fast
suggestions aside from thc
avoidance the study mentions a couple
times
the particular patients that exhibited
withdrawal symptoms
and most folks don't consider
cannabis addictive therefore it's not
really going to have withdrawal symptoms
and
and i understand that like for a patient
who is using
thc for you know
reduction of suffering um you know the
lack of
that you know causes pain but that's not
really withdrawal
what are these withdrawal symptoms that
that some of the patients exhibited
well it isn't pink elephants you know
associated
with uh alcohol addiction
rather when people have withdrawal
symptoms from cannabis usage it's
usually
some combination of mild symptoms
anxiety
insomnia nervousness
it's usually relatively short-lived
but the fact that people had been
labeled as cannabis
addicted or admitted to withdrawal
symptoms
to a higher degree in our population
is significant and i guess one might
expect
it from the high levels of use but again
the controls had similar usage rates
without uh the same levels of
addiction or withdrawal so there's
clearly a difference here
the um both this study and an earlier
study that is quoted within
your um survey um
list differences between the genders
both in participation
and in people who are experiencing
um chs are we seeing any
i don't know you'd call it but gender
predilection for
for you know you know men or women to
be more likely to get this yeah that's
always an interesting issue
it's clear from prior studies that there
seem to be a male
predominance in chs but
that's not what we saw um now
first let's look at what happened before
it is clearly the case that more men
are going to be high volume users of thc
but maybe less and less the case again
given current demographic trends
in our survey we had a female
predominance and both the chs patients
and the controls
now that could be due to the willingness
of women to participate in the study
so hard to say but
i think that it's clear that
a person of either gender could be
susceptible
to development of chs if they have
a genetic predilection towards it
and high uh rates of use of thc
all right that makes sense um so
it's interesting too that th that the
the older study
showed more males and this this newer
study shows more females
um because the sample size
is you know pretty small in both studies
do you think that's
you know more likely just the randomness
of who who signed up
it always could be um
yeah it's certainly possible all right
fair enough
um you know before this
survey came out a lot of people who
believed they had chs
were trying to
help themselves by using cbd
increasing their cannabidiol is there
any suggestion
that cannabidiol because of its general
ability to modulate thc is going to be
any use for us
maybe the problem is
it's not clear cut from the information
that we have at this time
part of the problem of course is that
it's hard to get material that
that is solely cbd with no thc
on labeling isn't always going to give
you the answer
either you know we see a fair amount of
thc
contamination if you will of supposed
cbd material but
it is possible that a pure cbd
preparation might offer some protection
but that's conjectural at this point
and it also may not be what people
really want
um meaning it won't get them won't get
them the results that they're looking
for
exactly right you know why
are people using this much cannabis it
may be
because there are two reasons number one
they enjoy it
and or it's treating something
they're using it to treat something
some symptom that they have um so
could cbd replace that one hopes but
i wouldn't say there's any guarantee at
all
uh but there could be other cannabis
components that are going to be proved
it proved to be useful
or adjunctive treatments but again
that's conjectural at this point
and something we'd like to explore in
the future
the five uh the five sites that we
looked at earlier
um are we aware of um
other other actions that happen
on those sites that could suggest that
there is a different cause
to this than than thc or is the
correlation
so high that that um
you know other other suspects are
less likely yeah it's the latter
um you know thc is the scenic unknown
if there isn't thc a board you don't see
chs right that part's clear
so that there might be other things
involved but thc is the
without that it's not going to happen
yeah there's this expression
uh there's no never and no always in in
medicine
but this is one of those situations
where it appears that
thc is always associated with chs
right on um great well uh i think that
wraps us up for today um ethan thank you
so much for sharing this information you
know this is
you know chs or or this host of symptoms
has been a boogeyman
in our in our community for so long and
um you know i remember being
down at emerald cup uh i don't know
probably three or four years ago and
we all shared a house and i remember one
of
the friends who was staying with us lost
her whole weekend
because she you know had an attack an
episode
and she spent the entire weekend um in
the hot bath and a hot shower and
you know that was my first time that i
had really come across it and it seemed
absolutely you know terrible to go
through it but also
she was there you know as an employee
before she was where they're working and
she wasn't able to do that either either
and um
it's nice that there's finally you know
i believe this is
if not the first study to pull it all
together at least the biggest study
it's nice to see this finally coming
together to put some light on it do you
do you see um research on this
now continuing like are there already
second and third wave
studies that have seen what you're doing
and are ready to jump on and
take the baton well we're not quite
published yet
so no um this uh study has been accepted
for publication
in the journal called cannabis and
cannabinoid research
we hope that it will spur other efforts
we certainly plan to remain involved
in studying this unusual
condition um so yeah it's our hope this
is going to
uh lead to better identification of chs
and hopefully better treatment in the
future all right that's great and and so
if you're listening
um uh we're not gonna publish this
episode until the paper comes out and so
there will be a link to the paper on the
website
and uh you know in case the idea that
ethan just said the paper's not out and
yet you want to read it you know
this this this episode will not come out
until it actually
comes out into the world so ethan thank
you so much uh appreciate to have you
here as always thank you for reaching
out and
and offering us your first interview on
the topic
and we we wish you much success in in
fleshing this out more
thank you i welcome the opportunity
if you want to find out more information
about this study or the
the folks that were involved with it you
can go a couple places
first and foremost you can go to ethan
russo's company
credo science which is
c-r-e-d-o-science.com
you can also go to their partner for
this survey which is
endocannahealth.com that's
e-n-d-o-c-a-n-n-a
health dot com and if you listened to a
couple episodes ago
with dr chris springer the naturopath
who taught about individualized medicine
he's over at endocan endocanna health as
well and
he is one of the co-authors with uh
ethan on
this on on this survey and then of
course uh ethan always shares
his email address in case you want to
reach out to him directly
and that's ethan russo at comcast.net
and if you do
email ethan you know give him uh some
time to get back with you because
he does try to get back with everybody
but you know he's a
busy person doing a lot of traveling for
research so you know be kind
and be patient you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at
shapingfire.com and wherever you get
your podcasts
if you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you would leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download
your review will help others find the
show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for insights
into the latest cannabis news
exclusive videos and giveaways on the
shaping fire website you will also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast
that's at shaping fire and at changolos
on instagram
be sure to check out shaping fire
youtube channel for exclusive interviews
farm tours and cannabis lectures
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts
email hotspot shippingfire.com to find
out how
thanks for listening to shaping fire
i've been your host shango los
you