[Music]
my favorite kind of people
are open-hearted active learners these
are people who generally are kind to
others
try to not be a jerk and are really
engaged with the world and learning new
things
this is one of the reasons i fell in
love with the autoflower breeding
community a few years back
this often maligned and ridiculed
subgenre of cannabis cultivation
are some of my favorite underdogs in the
early days
they were laughed and trolled right off
the popular message boards until they
eventually formed their own
and throughout the years of being
hassled they just kept sharing genetics
and best practices with each other
slowly dueling the difficult grunt work
on autoflower genetics
that will make all the future autoflower
breeders look good
modern autoflowers are pretty much just
starting now
there have been some winners in the past
but now that rudoralis has been tamed
now is the time when talented growers
will really start building up the
library of autoflower terping profiles
if you've been listening to my show for
a while you probably noticed that i got
turned on to the power of autoflowers
about two years ago
i was attracted to autoflowers because
they were a perfect solution for me to
recommend to cannabis patients
who have weather not as perfect for
growing cannabis as california
from the pacific northwest where i live
through the northern climates of the
midwest
and the short summer cold northeast we
all want to grow
under the sunshine but our summers don't
stay hot enough
and our real summer weather rarely lasts
to the middle of
october when we normally harvest with an
autoflower
you can start it outdoors the last week
in may and harvest it
mid-september fully ripe and packed with
terps and cannabinoids
regular plants won't finish most places
until at least mid-october if at all
early october cold and rain makes for a
lot of disappointing growing seasons
with autoflowers you are harvested hung
to dry
and often in jars well before the rain
starts
so when i discovered autoflowers for
myself i dug in deeply to learn as much
as i could
and then programmed a whole year of
autoflower content in 2019
i had a few podcast episodes put
together a half dozen live panels and a
pair of live events
i was even invited to write a jacket
endorsement for the new jeff lowenfell's
book on autoflowers that came out that
year
it was a lot of fun commercialization
hasn't really come to autoflowers yet
they still have a very mixed reputation
and home growing is still in its infancy
in the u.s
but patients have adopted them and they
are remaking patient home growing which
is really cool to watch
so today shows an attempt to get the
early days of autoflower history up to
the present
on record from the perspective of a
person who is present from the beginning
this isn't a complete history because no
one could do that and we don't cover
modern commercial hemp varieties like
the work of oregon cbd and others
but at the end of the show today you
will have a really well fleshed out
understanding of the last 12 years of
thc autoflowers
being grown by home cultivators and the
basics of what breeding autoflowers is
all about
have you used cbg dominant cannabis
flower tincture or other preparations in
the last six months
dr ethan russo asked me to let you know
that he and others are conducting a
study to determine the benefits and
drawbacks to cannabiroll
and they would love your opinion the
questionnaire takes about 10 minutes and
can be anonymous if you wish
the study is available at bitly forward
slash
cbg study that's b i t dot l y
forward slash capital cbg small case
study
and the link is in the notes for this
episode on shaping fire.com too
thanks for considering participating if
you want to learn about cannabis health
business and technique efficiently and
with good share
i encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary and a couple of the most
important news items from the week
and videos too don't rely on social
media to let you know when a new episode
is published
sign up for the updates to make sure you
don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter this month we are giving
away farmer fly
selections seed packs of cheddar wizzy
and vashon lime tonic
to four different listeners who are
subscribed to the updates we did this
contest last month on instagram and
farmerfly had such a good experience
that he suggested we run it again just
for the shaping fire newsletter
subscribers
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive the newsletter so go
to shapingfire.com to sign up for the
newsletter this week and be entered into
this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings and be sure to
check out farmerfly selections on
instagram too
you are listening to shaping fire and
i'm your host shango los
my guest today is dan jimmy more
commonly known in the underground as
full duplex
dan is founder and breeder at
mandalorian genetics
an award-winning and exceptionally
well-respected line of autoflower seeds
he is also co-founder of autoflower.net
the center of the auto flower breeding
and cultivation universe
since 2010 today we're going to take you
back to 2008 in the autoflower world
and walk us back to the present hey
welcome to the show dan
hey good morning shango thanks for
having me i'm really glad that you made
the time here during the holiday season
i've been wanting to have this chat with
you for a while and
and i'm glad we finally found the time
so let's get going by starting talking
about the
legacy um the legacy autoflower
cultivars
that existed prior to um
2010 because you know as we'll talk
later 2010 seemed to be a real changing
time but prior to 2010 it was kind of
crazy
tell us about those early cultivars so
yeah
um around 2009 and 2010 we
started to see the emergence of
autoflowering strains hit the market i
can remember
looking at seed banks like attitude seed
bank back in the day and
noticing these things were called
autoflowers and that they were
light cycle independent the only bad
thing about that was is they
weren't very potent and they didn't have
a lot of terpene content
and they just weren't robust plants
some smaller cultivars quick and fast to
grow
i think they were they were definitely
very early in their infancy at that
stage
so when you say not a lot of chirping
profile do you mean that there just
wasn't a lot there
at all or just that it was unpleasant
i would say a combination of both
honestly um you know it smell
the smell that was emitted from the
flower wasn't like
the gas that we look for today or the
other terpene profiles
that you know produce bakery smells or
sweets and things of that nature
but it was just though the smoke was a
little harsh because it was still
you know early root or alice it hadn't
had a lot of selection done to it
but what it did do was flower an
unseenly or obscenely quick time
so where did these reuteralis genetics
come from
from my memory and being around back
then watching them emerge a majority of
the stuff
was coming from the european market
spain and other eu territories where
uh they had been working with them you
know prior to 2010
low rider i think everybody remembers
low rider 2
there was you know snow rider and
mossy's purple gem there was also
a few other companies out there i think
dynafem had the roadrunner auto
and very early on
exploration of this plant it makes sense
that the
rotorolus genetics would you know show
up
in europe first considering the plants
originally came from siberia and russia
i mean those are those are you know so
close as far as
traffic routes go i can see how those
seeds would
you know easily be discovered in russia
then make their way
into you know europe for people to start
playing with then
you know isn't it isn't it odd to think
about how um
these same cultivars these pre-2010
cultivars
you know to one group of people um who
are like you know
visionary breeders they're like oh my
god this can change
everything you know over the next you
know x amount of years
and then they're also the same cultivars
that gave autoflowers such a terrible
reputation right because
even though alder flowers have gotten so
much better there's still people who
have
that knee-jerk response that oh autumn
flowers suck you know bad yield bad
smells and stuff and
you know that was definitely true
pre-2010
but uh but yeah these same cultivars
inspired a bunch of people and then
turned off a bunch of other people
that they did it was it was truly a
catch-22 and i think what you said there
was right on point
you know people saw a huge potential for
these
and maybe they may not have known at
that time what that potential was
but they decided to give the plant a
chance and then there are the folks that
you know got that impression stuck in
their head and then they didn't want to
either mess with it anymore or give the
the cultivar an opportunity
to change by assisting it you know we've
been assisting the cannabis plant in
whole for
centuries and i think that there was a
group that snatched a hold of that
new potential and really became like you
said a visionary on it and some people
stuck in their ways it's kind of like
the led versus uh
hid lighting debate you know there's new
tech and old tech and you see people
using a hybrid of the two
yeah and you know it's what a pain in
the ass too i mean as far as breeding
goes for
we'll talk more about the you know the
breeding in the third set but just
quickly
you know breeding autoflowers is not as
simple as
breeding regular photo periods where
you're just like you know male meat
female
boom you you've chucked some pollen and
now you've got new seeds
you know with with the autoflowers the
the root oralist genetics were so
janky with their low yields and smells
to to you know to dress that up people
were crossing it
into flowers that had a better
reputation and more attributes that
people liked but
but man it you're taking something that
is
janky and poor smell and hitting it
against something
that um that you potentially like well
gosh that takes a lot more work to breed
out those attributes that we don't want
exactly it does take some time
especially if you're you know
what i like to say building a new
cultivar from the ground up with reuter
alice
it's hard to get your hands on true
reuter alice these days
most people that want to start a project
to where they
take their their favorite photoperiod
strain and they want to make it an
autoflower
it does involve a few years worth of
work to do so
so those early days was there just
essentially one
rooteralis cultivar that people were
handing around
to to hit their their favorite plants
with or
were were there several to choose from
earlier on there were several to choose
from a lot of the painstaking work had
been taken out of it with the arrival of
low rider and lowrider 2 the purple
rider or purple gem
sour 60 was another big one back in that
early time frame
and i think a lot of that sub work had
been done to where the autoflowering or
day neutral trait
was dominant in the plant and we sure
owe
a lot of credit to those cultivators
breeders early on who did all that like
really annoying work to stabilize the uh
you know the autoflower recessive trait
right because like
it would not be nearly as much fun if
you had to do all that work
just to make your own fl autoflower
nowadays
that's correct you know it's they were
definitely pioneers in the field
and again i'll touch back on like dutch
passion and dynafem you know they saw
the potential very early they put in a
lot of work behind the scenes and
you know i come from and we've talked
about this we may talk about it a little
more as
i came from the forum days you know
there wasn't a um
a instagram out there or can a buzz or
any of these other platforms that we see
today to where we could just openly
share
about what was going on so how were
autoflower breeders finding each other
back pre pre-2010 so
i can i started delving into autos in
and that's when you know you just kind
of perused these forums um
that were out there mainly at the time
for me was i see mag
and you would find other people
growing these autoflowers and you would
have to you know key item search or key
term search to be able to locate them
but that's kind of how we were finding
each other um
or through the forums and once we found
each other you know
um you start developing the
relationships and sharing knowledge
yeah you were dead we're going to be
talking more about autoflower network
here in a little bit
but um and talk a little bit about how
rough it was to be an autoflower person
on these on these breeders sites
so you know we were the the joke the
butt of all the jokes
the never taken seriously any time that
you would go into say just a
generalistic forum about
understanding a set of nutrients or
understanding a soil type or a grow
medium type
the minute that you mentioned that you
were growing an auto cultivar
do with you know radio silence or you
got
you know or you get you know you got
laughed at you got told you're growing
ditch weed
um you know it was kind of you know
it was getting bullied for the for lack
of a better term back in those early
days so you know we kind of had to uh
you know rely on each other and rely on
a community
right on so so that was a drag and we're
really grateful
um that we have so many more resources
now and and let's so let's let's
let's talk about how that turning that
corner happened so
you know for anybody who's been
following this there's something like
like magic happened there around 2
2010 2011. and a lot of things in the
autoflower scene happened at once and
they were all going
in the direction of stronger autoflowers
and a stronger autoflower community
um so what do you think happened there
in 2010
um that really started to you know push
the threshold and turn the corner to
to this what you know present blossoming
of the autoflower scene
you know i'll take it back to community
um everybody that was joining up on
these forums they initially started out
in one place and then one thing leads to
another you either get banned or you
move on
and around 2010
we started finding each other in a new
forum roll it up and i noticed an influx
and what we decided to do
was basically have one sole dedicated
thread
to autoflowering cannabis because we
were searching and hunting for a sub
forum
or a place that we could go in as the
community at large who all had the same
love for the specific cultivar cannabis
and we could share the stuff that to all
make us understand it and grow it better
because in the main forums it was
getting lost in the wind
you know it was you know a few posts
here a few posts there a section here
and there wasn't one simple central
resource for all of us just to get
together and
trade ideas with and have a virtual
smoke sesh if you will and
share about this so i think around 20 i
know around 2010
there was a thread formed and roll it up
and that's where i noticed a lot of
people starting to migrate too
and see a need for um
better information more in depth and
places to talk about experience with
them other than just
oh my god this plant flowers without a
light cycle yeah it doesn't taste very
good but we can grow a lot of weed quick
so is this so so right after this period
when you started seeing these people
come together um
on the roll it up is this when you and
your co-founders
decided now is the time to create your
own home with autoflower.net the
autoflower network
in a nutshell yes you know i had brought
over the forum call or not the forum but
excuse me the thread called the art of
the auto and
roll it up and it was a place where it
was centralized like i was speaking
about before
and after working in there for a few
months i got
um approached by um a breeder by the
name of mossy
and a gentleman from canada
to basically create our own home we had
bagged admin and roll it up
multiple multiple times just to give us
a sub form we weren't looking for a
dedicated forum
our main page splash page on their site
we just wanted a place where we can make
it easier for people to find each other
instead of having to come and comb
through
you know google search results or even a
really poor search engine on a forum
and so we got approached and we started
spitting ideas and what we wanted it to
be
and one thing led to another and the
gentleman from canada
got the server space and knew a little
bit of coding i knew some back end work
as far as server maintenance and
building
and mossy had the information and
experience she was one of the earlier
what i like to call independent breeders
that weren't big name like dutch passion
and dynafem
you know she had really put the work
into
early root or alice and really working
it
geared towards meds and improving
terpene profiles
to where you know it was actually a good
medication for
better circulation for nighttime and so
she played a huge key role and she's
kind of a silent
person and i like to talk about you know
talk about her as much as i possibly can
because she was a mentor a to me
and i think she left a huge impact as
she had one of the first colored autofl
autoflowering cannabis varieties out
there
so is where was she living or still i
don't know
she's still in spain spain it's
interesting how much spain comes up
right around this time with the change
in genetics would you say that
um you know spain was at the
forefront of the of the new the new wave
of autoflower genetics at this time
i would agree with that there was a huge
gravitational pull towards that region
spain's has some different laws
than what we do and especially at that
time and i think it was a as a hub
for a lot of this autoflower and from
what my experience has been and you know
kind of growing up in this culture for
lack of a better term
has seen like a lot of the stuff is
european-based but
a lot of it's spain based it's it's
interesting too because um you know
people there's one set of people who
talk about the fantastic
heritage genetics that come from europe
and then and then you've got other
people who talk about these trashy
european genetics and i think that like
you know they both are probably true
right
just just just like most truths have got
a little bit of
this and a little bit of that um you
know there's all of this
this uh this new amazing work that's
coming out of spain at this time
but then there's also other people
putting out stuff that had not really
hit
the mark of of some of those folks that
were bringing their
seeds over and so yeah there was good
and good and bad stuff coming out of
europe just like there's probably good
and bad stuff coming out of everywhere
right now
what you know do you remember some of
those names coming out of spain who
who were the first reliable people doing
stuff in spain
around around this 2010 time around the
2010 time
again dutch passion dynafem
i hadn't seen some of our newer big
brands that come out of spain quite yet
at 2010 because
i think with we'll give an example one
of the cultivars was think different by
dutch passion
it was the largest autoflower i had ever
seen
within a year and i think they were
working on it well before
obviously the 2010 marker coming into
the 2011 mark
but it was called think different and it
was huge
um guys went from getting a few ounces
per plant and it
to getting a pound per plant grown in
the you know proper conditions and it
really
i think set off like this emergency
flare of like
there's some huge potential here and so
i think it helps shift
some people who are on the fence to
really take a look at this plant and
start working it as a whole and i think
some people made some huge
you know changing decisions to grab a
hold of that
um with with the resurgence
of of spain spanish autoflower
genetics or maybe not resurgence but the
explosion of spanish
autoflower genetics and with people
around the world
you know being able to see that
happening
between the various forums uh you know a
couple of the threads but then also the
beginning of autoflower
um network um did there did there
did spain start to attract attention for
being a leader and start to
you know attract brain power towards it
i definitely think it did i can remember
early on
so you know we'll kind of fade into the
beginning of autoflower.net we get a
forum up we have an informational board
we've got people coming from all over
the world to join
we you know harvested a lot of people
from the older threads the older message
boards
and i think it gave a gateway for people
to come in and start to share
and then i noticed after we get
everything up and running i have to take
a little bit of a hiatus and
i come back and when i come back i see
this this new brand that a at first
the hillbilly and me didn't know how to
pronounce to pronounce the name
but after seeing it enough i had to do
my research and that was mephisto
and and so i've um
was was mitch in spain or was
was mitch going to spain because i've
never been clear about that because i
always thought i always thought
mephisto was an american brand but then
then but then people keep on telling me
like
oh when mitch went to spain like did he
come back what's what's the story
um from what i know mitch left to go to
spain from where i am not 100 certain on
that part of the backstory
but i do know that he went to spain
to really put in the work to you know
build up the mephisto brand
for so many people that really seems to
have been
like mitch is part of a lot of people's
um
background story right like when i when
i talk to people
early heads who are into autoflowers a
lot of them
you know get to a point in their story
where and then i got a bunch of seeds
from
mitch you know and it seems that
um uh you know mitch going to spain
with the connections that he already had
solidified and him deciding that he was
going to be
you know he wanted to he wanted to learn
in that scene he wanted to be a part of
the best practices
uh and and you know i don't want to put
words in his mouth because i
i haven't had the opportunity to
interview him but but um
you know someone goes to a hot spot
because they want to participate and i
can
imagine that um he got so excited that
that's where a lot of these people
got turned on to was like through him
yeah and you know i agree you know and
once his genetics started popping up on
the forums
and started popping up on the autoflower
network
you know it really gained him a lot of
credibility for what he was doing
and so to answer your other question
about it being a stateside company
i don't think it really was a stateside
company ever it was just a way to
get that flowing to the state side and
and maybe maybe i just thought it was
a u.s company because there are there's
so
many of his seeds here and um there is
such a
huge um
following for him you know i mean there
are there are a handful of good
autoflower uh breeders putting out seeds
now no doubt
but i would say for for you know most
folks mephisto is you know has been the
top of the mountain for a long time
people wanted those seeds and and they
were often sold out which you know makes
everybody want them more
and you know in the last few years
certainly there there's a lot of other
really
excellent you know other people breeding
including yourself
um but i think that uh mephisto deserves
a lot of
um respect for for being some of the
first folks to
you know really stabilize mass produce
and get out these new autoflower
cultivars but at the same time doing it
in a savvy cool way with creative
packaging
and and you know engaging names
and they you know the whole the whole
package where it made it really easy
to become like a fanboy you know exactly
no i agree you know it was a different
it was definitely a different approach
that none of us had seen before because
i don't know if you purchased seeds back
around that time frame i mean they had
us
they may have came in a snazzy like
matchbox style
um booklet with a glass
vial in the center you know they may
have some cultivar information on the
back expected cycle times
and expressions but there was never
really a
marketing angle that what you saw with
mephisto it was definitely different
than
we had seen before and that this kind of
like kind of brings it all together
right like
we've got we've got all these new
genetics being developed in spain
um now that the you know the actual
autoflower you know the recessive rudy
has been stabilized so that people could
just use it you know they don't have to
do
six or seven years of of you know
breeding work to isolate that before
even trying to make their flavors
they could just take somebody else's
work and then build their flavors on top
of it so all these great
uh all this all these great seeds coming
out of spain
and then and then you know mitch and
folks like mitch going to spain
and spreading that information around
the world and then
autoflower network creating this
community where
autoflower breeders could feel at home
and share
best practices internationally i mean
boom right i mean i think that is
that is the turning point where the
entire modern autoflower scene come from
comes from yeah you know i definitely
think that
it was a you know a tri-spoked thing
where it was like these three
massive things came to a head and it
just kind of supernovaed from there
um you know they started to get in
better recognition cultivars were
becoming better there was actually
variety
you know it wasn't just short plant one
and short plant three you actually had
some you know real varieties starting to
show up
you know you were talking about laying
the foundation of the original root or
alice and
you know like we've talked about earlier
in this it's a very gangly
and you know runty style plant and then
now for somebody to be able to just
give you pics and choices and
expressions that you want
you could really see how the foundation
and how the mentality has changed
yeah right on cool right on well let's
go ahead and take our first short break
and be right back you're listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is dan
jimmy of mandalorian genetics and the
autoflower network
oxygen is an essential plant nutrient
and keeping sufficient dissolved oxygen
in the root zone is a challenge
gaia's brand of ultra fine nanobubble
systems will help your garden thrive in
ways you may not have considered
no matter if you grow in soil
hydroponics or aquaponics
gaia's ultrafine nanobubble systems will
increase your dissolved oxygen
and increase your yield often the first
sign of inadequate oxygen supply to the
roots is wilting of the plant under warm
conditions and high light levels
insufficient oxygen results in an
accumulation of toxins
and an insufficient amount of water and
mineral absorption
if oxygen starvation continues mineral
deficiencies will begin to show
roots die back and plants will become
stunted
healthy roots supplied with sufficient
oxygen are able to absorb nutrient ions
selectively
from the surrounding solution as
required in studies
this has shown a 30 increase in plant
growth
not only do ultra fine oxygen bubbles
allow your plants to thrive
but they will keep your drip lines and
irrigation pipes and plumbing clean too
because algae pythium and other invasive
species only survive in low oxygen
environments
and the gaia system only costs about two
dollars per day to run
gaia ultrafine oxygen nano bubblers
are also great for making compost teas
and wild crafted nutrient teas
the smaller bubbles of truly dissolved
oxygen
allow more microbes to reproduce faster
go to gaia's website at h205.com
to learn more about using dissolved
oxygen and how to purchase this simple
yet amazing technology
that's h205.com
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated
it is increasingly important to avoid
the use of chemical pesticides when
cultivating cannabis
beneficial insects have been used for
decades by the greenhouse vegetable
and ornamental plant industry and today
many cannabis cultivators
are moving from sprays and chemicals to
beneficial insects
covert biological systems has the
mites and nematodes microbials sticky
cards and air distribution units
you need to partner with nature to
defend your garden
whether you manage acres of canopy or
have a simple grow tent in your home
cobra is ready to help answer your
questions and help you transition away
from chemical sprays towards clean and
natural solutions
since 1967 culprit has assisted growers
in identifying pests
and devising reliable solutions while
providing healthy insects and mites that
will protect your yield
since the 1990s cobra has been a leader
in cannabis
pest and disease control worldwide and
have highly trained consultants to
assist you in canada and the u.s
from coast to coast no matter where you
live
covert biological systems can help visit
choose your country and get detailed
information
that's covert k-o-p-p-e-r-t
dot com for the most up-to-date cannabis
related biological control information
you can also check out their instagram
at covert canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and cobert is ready to help visit
cobert.com today
with the national hemp program in flux
due to stringent thc testing
requirements
brother seth and eric crawford continue
to release seeds to hemp farmers that
will be legal
no matter how you grow them or when you
test them
these new varieties from oregon cbd
seeds have substantial amounts of cbdv
cbgv cbcv and thcv
while always staying below the point
three percent thc limit
and guaranteeing complying crops for
farmers every time
also these new varieties cannot be
pollinated by your neighbor's
uncontrolled pollen
or a rogue male in your own crop either
oregon cbd seeds are non-gmo certified
too
oregon cbd seeds was founded and funded
in 2015 by seth and eric
maxing out their personal credit cards
without outside investment
they continue to refuse outside
investment that would change their
company culture
oregon cbd grows tons of fresh food on
their research farms for local food
banks
literally tons of food they also give
away tens of thousands of pounds of r d
flour to patients as their company began
to succeed
seth and eric started donating money to
the cannabis medicine and hemp fiber
cause 2
by giving millions of dollars to oregon
state university in order to establish
the world's leading cannabis genomics
research program
and they treat their employees right
oregon cbd pays for
full health and dental coverage for
their employees a 401k
program and their minimum starting wage
is 20 bucks an hour
plus everyone shares food from the farms
seth has been on shaping fire a few
times to talk about novel cannabinoids
you can check out episodes 25 and 37 on
cbd cultivars in the hemp market
episode 66 on triploid cannabis genetics
and the very first shaping fire live
episode 47
with seth and soil expert jeff lowenfels
talking about autoflowers
if you are a hemp farmer and you want to
grow reliable seeds that are sure to
thrive in past testing
check out oregoncbdseeds.com to learn
more about buying seeds for the 2021
season
that's oregoncbdseeds.com
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host shango los
and our guest this week is dan jimmy
of mandalorian genetics and the
autoflower network
so before the break we were talking
about this threshold moment
in like 2010-2011 time where we had this
combination
of um you know auto flowers
becoming really stabilized in spain
people going to spain because they
wanted to participate
people then sending their seeds all
around the world
and then people getting to know each
other and best practices through the
autoflower network
and it all kind of came together at once
so
you know over these last you know
nine years or so since then we have seen
uh yields increase terpene profiles uh
better um just just the plants are
getting more sophisticated
i'm really curious uh dan what you are
seeing now i mean like
you're you're a breeders breeder right
like you you you not only breed really
excellent autoflower plants that people
enjoy to grow and are great for parent
patients and they look pretty like not
only that but you're also like
um you know you you help run autoflower
network and you're a nerd right so
you are you're you're you're you're you
know you
you are into the details of a lot of
this and so i'm hoping that um
you can give me a good kind of overview
of of what we're seeing the different
veins of because you know as we know
breeders work on different parts of the
plant the parts that interest them
and um i am not involved enough in the
autoflower
breeding scene to know what these other
buckets
are so so let me just hand you the mic
and why don't you just tell us
what you are seeing um evolve here
in the in the last you know let's say
six years and
and where you see people working and
feel free to name drop
if you want but mostly i want us all to
have a better idea
of of what's being worked on and what's
novel in autoflowers right now
sure i mean honestly you know quickly
the things i can see is a potency
increase
true terpene profile inc changes
and i think the biggest thing is the
overall structure and
flower to leaf ratio are the biggest
three
shifts i've seen most recently
i've seen you know in the earlier days
you see a lot of stuff that was probably
based off the low rider or low right or
two genetics some of it could have been
done from
the sour 60 stuff we saw earlier even
the road runners from donovan
and oh you can see even though it was
from these different brands and
different breeders you could see some
similarities between those plants and
what i mean by that is you see a lot of
the
root or alice you know still coming
through yeah the yields increased yeah
the plant size has increased
but we're still seeing a lot of the
morphology from the root or alice
may that be high leaf ratio long
extended leaves
um from the main stem on your main fans
um up until now where you actually can
tell the difference between a cultivar
through some breeders um you know
they've become more stabilized
uh i think the people that have put in
the most work are seeing
more of a homozygous you know um
cultivar expression per ten pack um
another thing that i i've seen that has
shifted
is it used to be
commonplace to get regular seeds all the
time like when you got autoflowers back
in the early days it was regular seed
there were very very few feminized and i
think that was a big milestone for mitch
as well was getting out mass numbers of
feminized seeds
for people and now
in the market it's really really hard to
find regulars and all you seem to find
is feminized autoflowers which is fine
and dandy and it's great because there's
multiple benefits and we can talk about
that later um
but i think those are the biggest things
that i've seen shift um
as well as potency um you know i
personally took my whistle just a little
bit
i've got several 18 to 25 percent thc
cultivars that are coming out where back
in the day you were lucky to see 13
percent
you know so that's been a big change and
i think that comes with the selective
reading that's been going on
people moving more away from the
traditional root or alice and just
seeking more of the day neutral trait
rather than getting to the autoflower
tray quicker
it's interesting i like i like that
little insight you tossed in there about
the different the different strategies
breeders will have whereas
some folks are are taking hyped strains
and just hitting it with the rudy
and putting something out which you know
may be
a faster you know girl scout cookies
but but it may not be i don't know
finished right like like yes you
successfully made the autoflower
uh she goes fast but um but there's
something
extra to it to i don't know sculpt the
terpene profile
so that it's more than the hype name and
whereas
other folks are not looking to reproduce
the hype name
and they're coming at it from a
different direction
you know independently not trying to
recreate something else
but instead to create something
different and i'm not saying that
that neither i'm not saying that just
hitting you know a hype strain
with you know root or alice is bad i'm
not saying that because i've
i have grown a lot of fun stuff that way
too all i'm pointing out is that it's a
different approach it is a
you know it's a very specific breeding
strategy
correct yeah it's just a different
approach it's just like you know you can
have several cooks in one kitchen they
all have one dish they got to make but
everybody gets to that point differently
yeah two totally and you know even we
get this even in regs right we've got
people who are
they're taking their uber mail and
they're hitting the top the ten
hot strains that they like and they're
doing you know all ten of those versus
this one uber mail
versus people who every project they've
got has got different males
correct yeah so um so
um as you are as you were seeing these
um
these different attributes come out of
the plant
um when did you start to see that period
where people were starting to
start to be picked up more at retail
right
like like um no doubt when they started
making so many feminized autoflower
seeds
they got picked up um really quickly by
the uh by the patient market right
because
there there really isn't a better
patient homegrown plant than a feminized
autoflower it is the easiest of easiest
and uh and you know um you know i
you know i teach that to the patients
that i work with like hey you need any
safe place to start this is your safest
place to start
but that doesn't necessarily mean that
that's where when peop when
when autoflower breeders used to like
more successfully actually get
money for their seeds right because it's
one thing trading with your friends
because the market isn't there for it
but then there's the day that comes that
people start buying the seeds when did
you when do you think that started
i mean i bought my my first autoflower
seeds all the way back in 2009
when i first got what i got involved
with and that came from the attitude
seed bank
um that you had you still had some
options available but it wasn't as
widespread as today
um there were a couple brands out there
um
and i know i keep repeating dutch
passion and dynafin but those two
are so stuck in my memory from just the
wow factor
seeing these things and there are
several other great brands that i know
i'm forgetting to mention right now and
i apologize but
you know i want to say nirvana was
another location you could find them too
and yeah you could buy them as early as
back then but i think the larger influx
came probably 12
13. once the form started getting more
momentum and
you know mephisto was getting momentum
and then the market was kind of driving
itself
that way and i could be off a little bit
with those dates as far as like the mass
boom of when everything took off for
that group
but um from my memory and if my mom
serves me right you know i know it was
somewhere
in between 2011 and 2012 2020 that it
really
really took off but you could buy them
back as early as 2009 on attitude
so um you know as far as the ruderalis
taste
um to what degree do you think the
ruderalis taste is still
prevalent in all of the autoflowers
because
it does seem to be different from
breeder to breeder what do you think is
influencing how much you're tasting the
the grassy rudy in there i think it's
breeder selection
i think it is you know dependent upon
what they're looking for as a result
part of the plant what the parent inputs
were
i think i spoke about this earlier about
the higher leaf ratio
rugeralis is known to have high leafy
content in between its buds therefore
giving you more chlorophyll which in
turn if it's not dried and cured
properly gives you a lot more of that
grass hay
taste to the flower and i think with the
improvement of
you know the calyx to leaf ratios on
these plants we're seeing a lot of that
dissipate
and i think that's what's happening when
people are doing selective breeding
with an outside source maybe another
photo period or something of that nature
where it's not continuance
of the rudy gene
so i'm going to put you on the spot here
which is probably not fair but i'm going
to be i'm going to ask you to
name drop some of the breeders that that
you think are doing good work
and i want to i want to preempt this by
saying that you know i recommend that
everybody
go to autoflower.net and you know if
you're interested in growing auto
flowers or if you're interested in
breeding them that is the place to go
because
that is where i went to find um
the seeds that were being made by
talented people
that may not necessarily have the
commercial push behind them yet right
because
the autoflower for sale scene is still
very
young and and so you're still
you know buying from a lot of uh
individuals
either you know via mail or um you know
at a at a convention
or or a big smoke sesh or something like
that
and um so so you know that is really
great place to buy
is to go and and look at the plants and
read the threads and find out the person
who you dig their style
and then and then buy direct so so
that's cool but there's no question also
that there are a couple
um really good seed banks now that are
bringing people together to represent
them to take some of the sales
off of the sales stress off of
um the the breeders themselves because
just because you're a breeder does not
mean that you are a great marketer of
your own stuff either and you know you
got to have respect for that
so with all that being said and my
encouraging people to hunt
out breeders that are maybe less
commercial
um why don't you plug a couple folks who
you appreciate their work for people who
are are looking to start with um
they want a good first autoflower
experience
um definitely there's a few that come to
the top of my head if they want a good
first experience there's a company out
there called night owl seeds
which is run by daz he has done some
phenomenal work
has been trained by one of the best to
produce auto femmes and his stuff sells
out everywhere
it's one of the hardest one of the
hardest you know cultivar lineups to get
your hands on
when they come up for sale they
immediately sell out
um definitely think that that's a good
place that people should start
i've got a friend uh brother mendel's
selections
they're based out of the middle of the
country uh they're not
so much on in the seed banks but if you
search them out on facebook
and instagram you'll find some beautiful
beautiful
worked cultivars from these guys um
they're auto femmes um i've worked with
some i'm working with some of them
myself now
he really has a passion behind it like
daz and myself and you know to kind of
have that same
in visionary style i got a friend out
here in eastern washington he's an up
and coming
breeder it's fire buds genetics good
friend of mine
actually have been mentoring him for the
last couple years we trade some
information i've seen some really good
work coming out from him
so those are i'd say up in my top three
of
you know what you can find locally that
are doing
you know approaching it in a different
style to make a better plant for the
community at home
you know go ahead i was gonna say i've
just seen a lot of their stuff
expanding with the green wave coming
and it's nice to see that happen with
guys that are passionate about it
and you know really put the time into
work and and i know you're a humble dude
but but i will also
say that you know plug your mandalorian
genetics because i love
i love growing purple plants and you do
a lot of purple
lots of uh you know uh candy smells
and um reliable plants right and um
you know we have grown a lot of them
here on vashon island when i say we
i mean uh folks who are patients on the
island who are growing with their
with their medical certification and
you've been so kind as to
donate seeds to our our local vimeo
meetings
and so patients have been able to get
some of your seeds for free and it was
really nice
to see if so many people have a good
first time experience with autoflowers
especially here in the pacific northwest
where like you often have summers like
we did this summer where nothing photo
period finished
because the weather was so bad and
nights got cold so fast so
by all means oh you know and and your
stuff wins awards too right
so i'll trash on awards a different day
but you know that is something to be
said when
when uh you know your stuff's winning
awards so mandalorian
is uh well to be considered um as well
so i like what you said though about um
the you know the the autoflower
scene being lifted up by this kind of by
the green
rush right and i think that autoflowers
are really the right place at the right
time
because there's so much more home
growing and
autoflowers are so convenient for newbie
home growers
and feminized seeds are um you know
convenient for everybody and you know a
lot of people still prefer
the reg seeds and that's fine but you
know um
so many people when ease is their number
one thing a
a feminized autoflower is is the top of
the pile
it is cool to see some other people
like helping push the auto flower
tide forward if you will and so
like let's talk a little bit about the
autoflower cup so
um i i unfortunately missed
the autoflower cup the last time i had
the opportunity two years ago because
i was actually running a panel at
cultivation classic
on autoflowers so i didn't get to go um
so
you'll have to tell me all about it so
so so who's behind the autoflower
cup and what have we seen so far
so the 2019 cup was down in the grants
pass
oregon area it was put together by a
gentleman of the name of james hastings
james i wasn't too familiar with him
before
the word started buzzing around that
this cup was going to be put together
um they put the cup together for five
days down
in oregon on a campground that was
cannabis friendly which was really
really amazing and honestly the things
that i take from that experience were
one it was nice it was the first time
that i've been around
that kind of event um as far as like
everybody's there for the same minded
goal
everybody's there to share their
cannabis cultivation and
you know exchange information and talk
it was like bringing the forum
alive because i got to meet a lot of
people that i've only known screen names
for years
yeah you know and their personalities
outside of that screen name was just an
amazing
way to see that they were the same way
on the forum because they all cared
about the plant and it was an experience
like
it'll be one of those ones for me to go
down like i'll never forget it i met so
many great people there was so much good
food
it could have been a little bit better
planned for events over five days and
i'm just being honest
um you know we're pretty much willing
free to roam anywhere down there because
it's absolutely gorgeous there were
lakes there are hiking trails
all kinds of stuff to do but when it
came down time for like you know
competition and things like people were
doing their testing and
um you know it was basically people's
choice you know there was
we entered into it without all the hype
i think that you sometimes see behind
um larger competitions it was nice like
a communal thing
to where people that had been putting in
all this work for all this time and
talking to each other we were able to
come out
show our best and just have a good time
over a long weekend
yeah five days that's a really long time
man i mean like even
even a three day event feels long by the
by day three
but you know a five-day when you add
um you know the campground and the
forest
and you know i can i mean we're in
oregon so there are probably mushies
everywhere
um i can see how you know a good
summertime camp out is
is going to be even more than the cup
it's more like a
it actually sounds more like an
autoflower rainbow gathering
yeah i mean yeah to be completely honest
with you
know everybody you know enjoyed the the
hikes and the fishing and
um it was just kind of like this pow-wow
with a award
ceremony at the end and i think the
reason it was done for five days is
a lot of the stuff wasn't you know i've
seen different
uh framework as far as these
competitions go where the flowers sent
out way ahead of time
and people have weeks to maul over the
different stuff that they're looking at
and i think this is what the one spot
where it was lacking was because
everything had to be tested over those
five days so i think that's what gave it
its length
but i think that it could have been done
a little sooner as far as testing
because
you know you depending on your amount of
entries that's a lot of cannabis to get
through without having some kind of like
entre entres effect or you know overlap
of what's going on
yeah i hear that let's uh let's give
some love to jeff lowenfels
about his autoflower book too because um
you know one of the one of the
challenges the autoflower community has
is just reaching
outside of the autoflower community it's
so
insular and we you know we we trade
genetics we trade stories we cherry
best practices but most of it is kind of
like uh
inward focusing um which which kind of
explodes the expansion of the scene
which may be
for the better right because it makes
that um
you know primarily authentic very
interested people get involved but at
the same time
if we want the scene to grow and if we
want people to buy
autoflower seeds from the people putting
in the work the word's got to get out
there and then
you know so anybody who doesn't know
jeff lowenfels is
um known as lord of the roots and he put
out a
seminal series of books
all about living soil you've probably
heard of teaming with microbes
teeming with nutrition and teaming with
fungi you know they are they are a
baseline
of understanding well growing anything
in in
soil but certainly growing cannabis in
soil if you haven't read them you should
check them out but
jeff got all turned on to autoflowers
living up in alaska
and just generally being a you know 40
plus year
gardening nerd and so he put out um
this book on autoflowers and um
and it was an interesting book um why
don't you tell us dan
about the interesting direction um uh
that that jeff took it and and who who
his book ended up actually being
for um you know in a show ended up being
the introduction for people to give an
autoflower a try for the first time
and you know i have to laugh because you
know i was excited about the book coming
out and
you know somebody with jeff's caliber
stepping into the limelight with
something that we
that you were talking about we have been
quote unquote in the shadows with for so
long
was amazing to see and you know you
talked about how like it's so much
you know inclusive with the autoflower
community i think that's
you know done wanted to you know done a
couple things one like you said
we haven't really got out there until
somebody like jeff but two it's also
created this
weird um bond
amongst the breeders and the people who
take it passionately to kind of watch
out for one another
so it was kind of cool to see but jeff's
exposure
to the autoflower approached i think was
great you know he joked with me i told
him i was buying the book and i was
honored enough to have a few pictures in
there you know and that was awesome to
me so of course i had to purchase it he
kept telling me he's like no dan
he's like this book isn't for you he's
like it's not for people who
already understand the cultivation of
the autoflower it's for your aunt or
your uncle
or your crazy cousin who wants to get in
there and start growing some
homegrown and take an you know easier
approach to it
and you know i think jeff hit the nail
on the head with that one
he got it out there i've read through it
a couple times and
you know he's bait he's made a nice
introductory way of people to
know what an autoflower is see the basic
mechanics of the plant and what to do
with it when it's done
and not just with jeff sir i got to say
you know you stepping out into the
limelight
um with the several different seminars
that you have done
to discuss auto flowering plants you
know you
between jeff and yourself you have given
the autoflower community
that outward shining light that hey
these guys are over here doing
miraculous things we see it we love it
we think you guys should love it too and
this is why
and i think your approach with the live
seminars and
the shaping fire recordings that you
have done about the autoflowers is
really given a broader
spectrum of what we're trying to do and
what they can do for
either a commercial setting or the home
grower and patient right on dude well
first thanks for saying that but but i
think that jeff and i come from the same
place where
we are both like giddy
and excited about autoflowers and what
it can do for home growers and patients
and um we you know neither of us are
breeders but we're so excited about it
we wanted to talk to people about it so
you know he he wrote a book about it
that was how he
you know voiced himself and for me i i
programmed all of 2019 with like
autoflower events
that were free for folks and stuff and
that was what i was able to do but
i think in the end we all want the same
thing we want we want the breeders to
get the recognition that they deserve
for the hard work that they're putting
in and these beautiful plants they're
designing
and we want to make sure that people
who have any kind of interest in growing
cannabis
have can grow cannabis so they know how
to get into it because
you know hell we all want cannabis to be
in gardens as commonly
as tomatoes and the only way we can do
that is if we've got you know breeders
breeding
and people you know like like jeff and i
and you
telling people that it's happening so so
that's cool and also you know
there's nothing like um uh throwing
events
um uh to be able to meet new cultivators
right because like i met
so many great people um you know like
like
like for example at uh uh indo expo i
was giving a talk on on autoflowers and
why she people should try them and
and daz was there you know and like you
know i had heard about dazmofisto and
followed him and stuff and
and he came up after the after the talk
and he's all like hey man nice to meet
you and
you know it wasn't my best performance
but it was you know it was cool to turn
people on to stuff but it was nice to
meet people who
um i look up to in the scene like dads
right you know good folks who are doing
good work
and i think that's that's part of what
makes um autoflowers so good is because
everybody has been so ignored
for so long that really there aren't a
lot of [__] in the scene people are
really nice to each other
because um we've all been on the edges
for so long
yeah and i agree and that's that second
part i was talking about earlier is just
kind of it's formed a bond between all
of us to where
yeah i i haven't i've met a few that
were a little persnickety but i've never
met
like um that elitist mentality it's like
okay you've experienced this and you've
worked with him in this long
and you've seen that but we can both
avoid that by doing this at the other
it's it's it's
almost like the forums have shifted into
real life
um because one of the main mindsets that
we wanted to create
on the autoflower network was
a lack of better term a safe place where
you come in and share that knowledge and
you're not going to get
you know barked at by 15 20 other people
telling you you're stupid and that
autoflowers are [__]
yeah you know it was a place and it was
amazing to watch the morphology of that
too because
after that tone was set and the site
started to gain its momentum
like the admin didn't have to step in
the the
the general population by going there's
no room for that here we're not here for
that and
it's cool to hear you see that come out
in real life too
yeah i absolutely do um you know the
autoflower network
while i don't um spend a lot of time
there because i don't um
breed i love just going and reading
threads to learn
best growing practices and honestly for
the jokes
oh absolutely because it's like the
folks there are really funny
so um all right so so let's go ahead and
take our second break when we come back
we're gonna talk about
um uh breeding with autoflowers and
we're not gonna go
into it heavy duty uh science approach
but but i do want to talk about um
why breeding autoflowers is are
different
some of the unexpected challenges and
uh and mostly why why we need to make
sure we have respect for these
autoflower breeders because
because this is not super easy uh we're
gonna take a short break and be right
back
you are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is dan jimmy of mandalorian
genetics and the autoflower network
as a business owner you are incredibly
busy in reality you are responsible for
everything your company does you've got
so many responsibilities every single
day
that often you just don't have the time
to really dig into your marketing as
deeply as you'd like
you know there's more that you could do
to reach out to new customers and
encourage
loyalty and the customers you already
have but you certainly don't have the
time for it and you're not ready to hire
somebody full time for that role either
for you i recommend blunt branding at
blunt branding kirsten nelson and her
team are focused on
improving your bottom line you know most
marketing firms are excited to make your
logo
packaging and website very pretty but
they leave responsibility for improving
your bottom line up to you
they don't want that kind of
responsibility but that's pretty much
the most
important part of marketing right
kirsten and her team will help you
engage new customers
funnel them to your point of sale
whether it be online or a storefront
and keep them coming back to you and
telling their friends
now if you happen to be a new cannabis
company or an established company moving
from medical to adult use in your state
kirsten especially can help you not only
is she well reversed in marketing and
finance but she totally gets cannabis
whole plant medicine terpenes heritage
farmers and the particular needs of
startups
check out what she did recently for moon
time medicinals and humboldt at
moon time medicinals.com kirsten and her
team put together
a whole brand package for them built
their website and wrote their sales
materials
no doubt this is a paid commercial spot
but that does not mean they bought my
opinion
i've worked with blunt branding on five
projects now for various of their
clients and
every single time they have done more
than they have promised and over
delivered on results
i love how they generate new revenue and
focus on that as the goal instead of
just making a pretty logo
similarly every single friend i have
referred them to has come back to thank
me
and that just does not happen every day
grab a pen and paper because the website
address is coming up
if you want someone to implement
marketing programs that feed your bottom
line
give blunt branding a call they will
share proven techniques to increase your
audience and generate sales while using
cutting edge technology solutions in the
background
that make all of this easy automatic and
trackable
go to shapingfire.com forward slash
blunt branding to find out more
you can also click the link in our
newsletter blunt branding
marketing that makes you money
[Music]
after you've caught up on the latest
shaping fire episodes do you sometimes
wish there was more cannabis education
available to learn
well we got you shaping fire has a
fabulous youtube channel with content
not found on the podcast
when i attend conventions to speak or
moderate panels i always record them and
bring the content home for you to watch
the shango los youtube channel has
world-class speakers including
zoe sigmund's lecture understanding your
endocannabinoid system
kevin jodrey of wonderland nursery
talking about breeding cannabis for the
best terpene profile
frenchy cannolis lost art of the
hashishin presentation
nicholas mahmoud on regenerative and
polyculture cannabis growing
dr sunil agarwal on the history of
cannabis medicine around the world
eric vlosky and josh rutherford on
solvent-less extraction
and jeff lonefels on the soil food web
there are several presentations from dr
ethan russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system too
while there be sure to check out the
three 10-part shaping fire sessions
series
one with kevin jodrey one with dr ethan
russo and one with jeff lowenfels
and even my own presentations on how to
approach finding your dream job in
cannabis
and why we choose cannabis business even
though the risks are so high
as of today there's over 200 videos that
you can check out for free
so go to youtube.com forward slash
shangolos or click on the link in the
newsletter
sometimes the topics i want to share
with you are far too brief for an entire
shaping fire episode
in those instances i post them to
instagram i
invite you to follow my two instagram
profiles and participate online
the shaping fire instagram has follow-up
posts to shaping fire episodes
growing and processing best practices
product trials and
of course gorgeous flower photos the
shango lost instagram follows my travels
on cannabis garden tours
my successes and failures in my own
garden insights and best practices from
personal grows everywhere
and always gorgeous flower photos on
both profiles the emphasis is on sharing
what i've learned in a way that you can
replicate it in your own garden
your own hash lab or for your own
cannabinopathic health
so i encourage you to follow at shaping
fire and
at shango lowe's and join our online
community on instagram
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and our guest this week is dan jimmy of
mandalorian genetics and the autoflower
network
so to bring this show on home what we're
going to talk about next is uh the
actual breeding of the autoflowers
because
it is not the same you know i've i've
made seeds right i'm not really a
breeder i'm a pollen chucker you know i
get a male plant i like and a
female plant i like and i put them near
each other or i
or i apply some pollen with a paintbrush
and oh i've made seeds for next year and
that's just
fun right it makes me feel closer to the
plant
but when i started listening to breeders
talk about breeding autoflowers i'm
like oh hell no that sounds like a lot
of work
and um and the thing is is that for the
for the passionate people i know in the
in the breeding community for
autoflowers they ain't no thing to them
they're like oh no
well this is just expected to get
something good and i like and i love
them for it because i get to pop their
seeds
but i think it's a good thing for for
growers to know what's behind the secret
sauce so they can you know properly
value these seeds
so so dan why don't you like walk us
through um
what the breeding of an autoflower looks
like
yeah i'll approach it um in two
different ways and we'll keep it you
know like you
look at a high level here that way we
can get a generalistic understanding um
you know you did mention and i'll start
with the simplicity first
um you did mention about you know you
take your favorite cultivar and
male and then female put them beside
each other and then you get seeds from
that run
and autoflower to autoflower is pretty
much going to do that for you
if you're somebody who is wanting to
experience pollen chucking to see
how this takes place if you have a
percent auto flower female and 100 auto
flower male
and you let them pollinate each other
you will get 100 auto flowering seeds
now with that said um you're gonna get a
lot of genetic
variety you're gonna see a lot of
different things so expect
all kinds of different phenotypical
expressions showing up in that seed
but at a high level if you just want to
experience that process and
you know be self-sufficient and make
your own seeds that's one way you can
approach
it now the more in-depth side of it and
it's a side that you were talking about
with the complexity levels is i think
the breeder or the more current breeders
approach to it is
taking a photo period male or female and
introducing it to an autoflower
now when you do so you have a lot of
work to do and what i mean by that is
you have generation
generational selections that have to
take place
in order for you to make that plant a
true autoflower
i think a lot of the earlier autoflowers
that were done this way were done with
the expectation of
bringing out the autoflowering trait
first and i can understand that you know
like we were talking earlier
the hype strains you want to get that
fast flowering cookies out there or the
flash flowering gmo
and the quickest way to do that is
inbreed or you know make your initial
parental selections and then inbreed
looking for the autoflower trait
only if you're looking more to change
the morphology and get rid of a lot of
the ruderalis i think there's a lot more
of a selection process that has to go on
and with that selection process i'll
cover that a little bit your initial
cross is going to give you your f1 seeds
those f1 seeds
are going to be primarily dominant in
the photo period lines genetic makeup
it's going to be very rare for you to
see a fully auto flowering
expression out of that first round of
seeds so then you ask yourself well
what do i do to make that show up the
best option there is to inbreed that
line and what i mean by that
is you take a male and a female from
that first generation
and and breed them together giving you
your
f2 generation at the f2 generation
you're going to start seeing
similarities from mom similarities from
dad you may even see some autoflowering
expression
now with that i will caution you back to
what we were talking about
you know breeding quickly for just the
autoflowering trait if you're that's
your end goal
let's start looking at the f2 and if you
find
you know one that is going to go full
autoflower and one that kind of stalls
out
from the autoflower it'll grow up it'll
start to pre-flower it'll go into what i
call bud set
and then it needs 1212 to finish its
light cycle
at that point i think that would be a
good selection for you if you're just
hunting something that's going to come
out
in an autoflower fashion that would be
my next round
to select from if you're looking to kind
of incorporate you know what you really
liked about the photoperiod mom
but you want just the autoflowering
genetic from the father
or vice versa i think you need to start
really digging into
your seed count at that point at the f2
look for something that's
doing the stall on both sexes both male
female and then push that to the third
you know generation and at the third
generation you could
probably start seeing a little bit more
of a balance between
auto flowering and some that still may
be photo period
and then you can start picking at that
point based upon your terpene profiles
your flower densities your expressions
of
leaf color whatever your you know
tickles your fancy
and then making your f4 by f4 if you
select in that manner you should see
really close to 100 autoflowering
genetics
um it's a little bit more time intensive
it's a lot more sifting through seeds
and there's a good possibility if you
pick up that nature or if you pick up
that direction
that you're going to have to go through
quite a few seeds to find what you want
if you want a true if you want to
represent both parents truthfully
i believe so if it takes to f4
just to get all of the seeds to
be autoflower
do we have to go further than that to
also
lock down some of the individual tray or
like the
like like taste traits shall we say like
do you need to do
can you be selecting for both at the
same time can you be selecting
for both the autoflower traits and the
um you know yield and
potency traits at the same time or do
do you need to choose which ones first
i think you could do it all at the same
time if you know you're taking good
notes and you know what you're hunting
you know
i'm guessing you need a big sift too as
i'm asking the question i'm all like oh
you can you can choose for both if
you've got a lot to work with and so
if you're if you're if you're gonna
you're trying to do this with 20 seeds
you're going to be a lot more limited
than if you're trying to do this with
200 seeds
that's correct and that's what i was
talking about earlier you know having
that sift and
also you know if you're wanting to do a
true photo to autocross you know have
your end goal and have your mindset
you know where you want to be at the end
and you can definitely do that sifting
and hunt out the multiple traits you
know you see one that goes
to pre-flower and stalls but it has a
leaf structure you want it's got a
balance on each side
that you want it the plant itself looks
balanced you see some nice symmetry in
the plant
and then you might have color from the
other one you're like okay i want the
color too
and you could do that as part of your
sift and i think that's what's creating
the more modern day autoflower i think
that's what a lot more
the approach is rather than seeing a lot
of you know
new stuff come out that's yeah it's
autoflower but it still kind of looks
like root or alice but it's
had a different photo parent that wasn't
worked as in depth
you know needing to work something to f4
or further
you know is definitely further if you're
not going to have a lot of sift
um that that means that you're going to
be doing
a lot of cycles and selecting um
is it a fair assumption to say that a
lot more of the autoflower folks
are incorporating indoor uh breeding
over the winters because like you know
with a lot of the
a lot of the um photoperiod stuff um
people can just grow
outdoors during the summer and get work
done enough that over a couple seasons
though they can develop something really
good for the outdoor
but if you need to get to f4 before
all of your seeds are even showing the
autoflower trait
that tells me that um you know to get
to get anything done in your lifetime
you're going to need to be growing
in you know multiple tents indoors at
the same time
as you're you're watching for
expressions under the sun during the
summer and testing
that's absolutely correct i think that's
the one key thing that we need
as breeders is the indoor space
separated space especially
because i mean yes pollen is highly
volatile but there are easy steps to
contain and control that
um but it does take
around the clock year-round work
especially if you're working on
something new and i
you did ask um in the earlier question
and i didn't touch on it but i i'd like
to is you asked about like
continuing the f generations for
stabilization and to answer that
question is yes
um a lot of the work that i have done
um is in the neighborhoods of s6
f7 f8 and f9
and then really around f5 or f6 i'm
starting to see that
balance across so not only do you have
the years of work or the time frame of
work just to get what you want
then you have to stabilize it to a point
where it's become
that same or close to same cultivar
expression across the ten pack that way
it's not like pokemon and you open it up
and there's 15 different types
and i like to steal that one from you
i i said that yeah i i'm pretty sure you
had a meme on that at one point in time
oh yeah i did that's funny all those
different animals together ah dude
that's funny
um all right so so now that people are
getting an idea of what it would take
um i'm sure that people are falling into
at least two categories there's one
category
of folks who you know they just want to
understand
autoflowers because they're going to
grow some and they want to sound cool
talking with their friends about
autoflowers and then there's another
basket which are people who are like
okay i want to try breeding some
autoflowers i've got this idea i want to
do i've got these tastes i want to bring
out
um what would you tell what what are the
steps that you would tell somebody to do
if they wanted to
um get involved i'm assuming that
there's probably a thread
on autoflower net that's dedicated this
and then
and then what are people using as the
ruderalis input nowadays i'm sure that
there's
you know some kind of stabilized option
that most people are working with that's
hard to screw up
um i think a majority and i'll answer
that part first so like
the majority of the people i think are
using
predefined autoflowering genetics that
have been worked for years i don't think
a lot of people are going back to
pure root oralists for their foundation
because that takes a lot of work
it takes a whole lot of work because
you're not only just hunting the
autoflower
trait from the original reuteralis what
you're also dealing with is all of the
other genetic recessive traits of
low potency bad yield funky growth
um so if they are wanting to learn about
it i definitely think you know get out
there and find some regular seeds and
put them side by side to understand it
if they want to get into the depth i
would get out there and i would
look for you know reputable breeders
especially
independent breeders because the
independent breeders tend to have more
regulars
which i was talking about before which
are really really hard to find
you don't have a lot of people out there
offering regular autoflowers these days
and to have a foundation
without the complexity of understanding
how to feminize a seed
you need to have a male counterpart
let me i want to i'm going to plug heart
rock mountain right now because that's
where i've been uh
his seeds and your seeds are the are the
stuff that i've been getting that's
regular
and it's actually kind of an interesting
upside i'm a big fan of the dragonfly
earth medicine uh regenerative
agriculture
techniques certification and
at the moment most of their people are
are shying away
from from making feminized seeds and so
they're putting out lots of autoflowers
but they're all
rags and so if you can find um
a seed breeder who's playing with
autoflowers that's also dragonfly
certified
it's like hitting a gold rush oh i agree
yeah totally i um his um hard rock
mountain
uh farms uh their uh their lions claws
one of the first ones that i personally
came across
that truly hits like funk and gas i i
don't know why and maybe it's just the
stuff that i've grown i've probably only
grown 45 or 50
autoflower cultivars but do you find gas
is kind of
still missing in autoflowers i don't i
don't i haven't come across
you know i come across like you know you
know the sweets and the candies and the
bubble gums and the and even the cheeses
and the northern
um cheese hazes and stuff but but i
don't i haven't found a ton of gas
i personally haven't either i've got a
few different cultivars and i got one
that smells like acetone
and it was the first chemically chemical
smelling autoflower that
i had ever personally experienced and
i've you know obviously been to a few
different events i've got friends that
have been growing auto cultivars for
years and you're right
the floral the berries the fruits the
candies are really coming out from them
but i think the more modern day auto is
leaning that way
because they're getting the the breeders
that are working with them
are the ones that are taking their time
are in search of those terpenes so i
definitely think we're going to start
seeing more of a gassy because that's
one
thing that i've been approached and
asked the most honestly by
people that are interested in growing
these in large scale is so where are the
terpenes at
where's the gas at like we want that
fuel smell because that's
what the public wants and i even think
even the home grower wants that for a
nostalgic reason
you know because that's a very common um
nose profile that we we often associate
to cannabis and
it's getting there but i don't think
it's full-fledged hammered there yet
i think we still have some work to do
yeah i think that you're right on that
and so
let's use that to transition here to
kind of a wrap up where do you see
the autoflower scene uh going right now
what are the major trends that you think
are going to play themselves out over
the next couple years
number one is just the uprise in the
homegrow
i'm part of a bunch of different groups
about two different forums
and you know i can see as each new state
is going legal
either medicinally or adding
recreational to their medicinal
certified you know
legalities a lot of home growers really
starting to pick it up because they can
literally put a 2x4 tent in their closet
with an led
and get at it you know i remember back
in the day we would grow them in pc
cases
um because you mean like computer cases
yeah
so i would just you know take a large
computer case got the internals
rig up some you know fluorescent lights
inside of it and let it go to town wow
um you know so seeing the plant evolve
from that into the home grow i
definitely think that's we're going to
see a huge influx there and i'm already
seeing it
um based upon instagram and
like i said a few other platforms you
really see the home growers
grabbing a hold of the autoflower
especially now the states are legal and
the second wave and what i'm really
seeing is supplemental for
farming um especially and i'll talk
specifically to our climate
um our climate in this northern section
is similar to the one that's over in
maine
and you know kind of central us michigan
and stuff like that
and i'm seeing farmers use them to
supplement
either their veg space during the winter
because they're an all outdoor facility
and they veg their moms over the winter
they do their cuttings and stuff like
that
and they're producing a yield during the
same time they're flowering out or not
flowering out excuse me
vegging out their next year's crop
indoor facilities are
filling their mother rooms with
autoflowers while they're waiting for
their clones to take
and get ready for the bloom room it's
adding another layer of
revenue for the company with extremely
low overhead costs
because as you as and i know and jeff
speaks about it in the book
they don't need a lot of food now there
i'll caveat that there are a few out
there
you know as the selective breeding is
taking place that
they do need some food they need a
little bit more attention but i think
that's with any kind of plant
but i'm seeing that wave hit the
the farm the large scale farm market too
from coast to coast
it's really interesting to see how
they're being used as a tool and some of
them are selling it as flour and some of
them are
a lot of them are doing it for extracts
maybe rosin
maybe for cartridges for edibles
see a lot of different options happening
with it so i'm seeing those two direct
avenues really starting to
move through with the auto
wave so to speak it's really interesting
to see
folks who ordinarily would not be into
autoflowers
suddenly warm up to them and start
growing in them when they realize
that you know if you start your auto
flowers
um early in may that they'll finish
uh in the same time of year that a light
depth would
and so you actually have flour to bring
to the market that's uh fresh and usable
maybe even just um you know if you're
doing outdoors on
a on a less quality part of your
property because
because they actually you know being
from siberia a lot of these plants like
really like to be
abused and have stones in the soil and
like just be kind of ganky soil
but then you know other folks who are
doing indoor they realize that oh wow we
can grow
ottos in our mother room or in our veg
tent
you know because they are they are light
independent
correct and you know i mean you're
vegging out and you're holding your
mothers at
either 18 6 or 24 any kind of higher
variation and these guys are just
going through their mechanics and they
just need a little bit of water along
the way
yeah absolutely i think that is i think
that as they are
increasingly picked up um by
i don't know let's let's let's call them
commercial taste makers right
as as the bigger players are are
bringing out autoflowers
you know early season offerings you know
i think that
um you know the last vested vestiges of
autoflower
taboo will go away and it's just going
to be part of the scene it's going to be
like you know
you know regs light depth and
autoflowers and it's it's they're all
going to be on the same playing field
i would love to see that um and like you
said a minute ago it's
you know slowly changing one mind at a
time some people that were so hell-bent
about
you know oh it's ditch weed oh it's just
that you know it's low rider
to actually watching them grow and then
they see it and they're like holy [__]
okay so yeah it's not the same thing
anymore
and that's usually all it takes if you
can get the a person who is a
disbeliever and say here
here's 50 seats grow them
let me know what you think you know and
that
usually helps turn the mind around and
you know providing pictures and coas you
know that that really helps too
because you know your commercial taste
makers
uh love to see numbers and when they see
numbers and
and everything lines up to their model i
think they're more apt to do so and i
hate that sometimes it takes that depth
of transition
but sometimes it just does some people
are open to it yeah we'll give it a shot
other people need a little bit more
proof
but they're slowly coming around it's
nice to see yeah you give to use your
example you give somebody 50 seeds and
they look at it
they will look at autoflowers all with
new eyes
because they'll see a couple different
phenos some of which they'll like
they'll see the increased consistency
versus what it was like before
2010 and then they'll smoke it and go
like damn though this is really good
especially since you know it's it's a
misnomer that potency is the end-all
anyway
like thc potency and a lot you know you
can get stuff in the mid-teens with good
terpene profiles
that just give you a fantastic buzz you
know people who are demanding you know
you know 28 29 30 i think they're
missing the bigger picture
and and since autoflowers don't do those
kinds of numbers
um if you're if you're gonna cozy up to
autoflowers it also teaches you
that you don't need those kinds of thc
potency numbers either
you know and i agree with you and thank
you so much for saying that uh you know
i've had stuff that's been in the lower
percentage you know from
a photo period plant that you know it
might have
it had you know just enough terpenes it
had the right amount of thc there was
enough synergy there to melt my face off
to where like you smoke at 31 and it's
just like oh
you know it's it there's something else
going on there other than just potency
or even trichrome coverage you know
that's the other thing too and a lot of
that was one of the that's one of the
biggest reps that otters get is
oh they lack trichromes i could see that
at a beneficial point for hash making
but like i also don't believe that
that's fully translated into potency
yeah i agree with that and you know
since you mentioned hash one of the
things that um
i personally like about autoflowers is
um in my experience they don't
nug up the same way that many photo
periods do
they're they're they're a little looser
and um
i think they hash great they because the
the internal trichomes are so much
easier to get cold
and to have you know drop off and
leave the actual material without having
to beat it all up i think that
autoflowers are great for hash
yeah i i've got some experience had some
really
good experiences with returns on you
know either ice water hash
or even dry ice hash you know a lot
better
breakage because i think exactly what is
happening is what you said
is you they don't get super tight there
are some out there that do but a
majority don't
and there's more surface area of good
trichrome heads that you can actually
get into
rather than having to pulverize it and
release a lot of the chlorophyll too
yeah right on well dan thank you so much
for
joining me especially on this like quiet
and sleepy sunday morning after
christmas
um i really appreciate uh you sharing
your time and your experience and you
know honestly
you know i knew i wanted to do this show
about uh the the history of autoflowers
so that we could
you know get this into the history books
before it's uh either lost or because
before some
big autoflower company you know
commoditizes the story and claims that
they
invented autoflowers you know um and
there's no there's not a lot of people
who were there
at the early days and so um luckily you
were
and uh you know your involvement with
autoflower.net gave you a um
you know gives you a really big
perspective so
um thanks for taking your time to share
that with us
and you know thanks for just generally
being a dude with good chair who
represents the otter flower community
positively
well thank you shane go and thank you
tremendously for having me on this
morning i really appreciate it and i
you know love what you do and the
involvement with the community and the
you know how we first met with your
vimeo events over on the island and
seeing your compassion to the people as
well as the plant and spreading good
knowledge it's an honor to be on the
show
you know i i hired you in high regard
and especially the guests that you have
so thank you for your time this morning
and bringing me on
right on brother thank you so if you
want to follow up on this stuff that
we've been talking about today uh here's
a whole bunch of avenues for you to go
down uh first and foremost
i recommend that you follow dan jimmy's
instagram which is um
unendingly interesting and has beautiful
flower photos
and that's on instagram at mandalorian
underscore
genetics also
you want to probably want to check out
autoflower.net
which is the forum where you're going to
learn all about your best practices and
up-and-coming breeders and see great
photos and
and as you get into autoflower growing
and breeding if you've got questions
that is a
fabulous community to be a member of
very warm uh very very low amount of
trolls
just a really great heartfelt community
if you want to
get more of dan jimmy you can
you can enjoy the youtube video that is
on um
my shango los youtube channel of dan
before he was using his
uh his his his government name i guess
uh of of dan jimmy uh he he did a
special video with another friend of
ours sebring
all about giving seeds away to patients
and and you know for those of you who
listen to the show
the patient focused breeding and patient
photicist
growing is very important to me and
these two guys
both both make
seeds to give away and also facilitate
other people giving away
their seeds as well and um you can you
can find that uh
giveaway grow i think the video is
called giveaway seeds
on on my youtube channel um you can also
listen to earlier shaping fire episodes
that had to do with autoflowers
there was episode 47 which was uh the
very first
shaping fire live that was at a
cultivation classic
in portland and my guests for that are
jeff lowenfels who wrote the book we
were talking about earlier
and seth crawford who is a an autoflower
breeder from
oregon cbd seeds they focus on making
autoflowers for the hemp market
but the two of them together on on stage
not only was
insightful for both commercial growers
and home growers but they're also both
funny as hell dudes so that was a good
presentation
um you can find the video version of
that on youtube or you can just listen
to
shaping fire episode 47 and audio only
because it works either way
and then you can also check out episode
uh shaping fire 53
um all about uh recruiting new cannabis
gardeners with autoflowers and that's my
interview with jeff lowenfels about his
book
and um and about how we uh you know
through things like his book we're gonna
expand the autoflower scene
which i gotta admit i'm very proud he
asked me to uh
to write a testimonial on so it's my
first first book i'm on the jacket cover
on so that's pretty cool
you also on the shaping fire youtube
channel you can see my own presentation
on why autoflowers are useful to
patients
i recorded one version of it in portland
at
indo expo and another version at indo
expo denver and those are both on the
youtube channel
and then if you if you want to get
direct links to any of this or links to
heart rock mountain farm that i
mentioned
or mephisto genetics which we mentioned
all of those links will be on
the page for this episode at
shapingfire.com you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at
shapingfire.com and wherever you get
your podcasts
if you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download
your review will help others find the
show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
exclusive videos and giveaways
on the shaping fire website you'll also
find transcripts of today's podcast as
well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast that's at shaping fire and at
changolos on instagram
be sure to check out shaping fire
youtube channel for exclusive interviews
farm tours and cannabis lectures does
your company want to reach our national
audience of cannabis enthusiasts
email hotspot shippingfire.com to find
out how
thanks for listening to shaping fire
i've been your host shango los
you