[Music]
vaguely remember when I started hearing
about fake marijuana on local news
stations it sold under the brand names
like spice and k2 I didn't pay much
attention because you know come on fake
marijuana fig marijuana is oregano that
some rookie accidentally buys but one
time I came across it and they didn't
refer to it as fake marijuana instead
they called it synthetic cannabinoids
and it was then that they had my total
attention fake marijuana is a stupid
name synthetic cannabinoids is specific
enough and shows enough understanding of
the plant that I decided it was worth
searching online and I'll be darned
people were actually making synthetic
cannabinoids in a laboratory and selling
it on the street and folks were getting
[ __ ] up folks were having outlandish
side effects like blurred vision
vomiting seizures hallucinations heart
attacks and some folks even died the
crazy thing is that calling it fake
marijuana is just totally untrue and
really lazy journalism somebody made
cannabinoids in a lab that do not even
occur in the marijuana plant these are
totally not of nature they may
technically be in the same chemical
class as what is in a real plant
cannabis sativa but they really have 0
in common in nature that said synthetic
cannabinoids why they exist and how they
made it out of the laboratory and for
sale at your local gas station is a
really interesting story if you enjoy
hearing frank discussions that dive deep
in the cannabis health business and
techniques i encourage you to subscribe
to our newsletter every week you'll
receive a new podcast episode delivered
right into your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week
social media sites are becoming very
unreliable and showing folks every post
they want to see so sign up for the
shaping fire newsletter and make sure
you don't miss an episode you are
listening to shaping fire and i am your
host Shango Lohse my guest today is dr.
Greger demon and today we're going to
talk about synthetic cannabinoids greg
is a neurophysiologist with expertise in
the endocannabinoid system he has
received research support
from the National Institute on Drug
Abuse and the National Science
Foundation and his articles have
appeared in journals such as nature
neuroscience trends and neuroscience and
neuropsychopharmacology his ongoing
research while an assistant professor of
biology at Eckerd College includes the
molecular physiology of cannabinoid
receptors in their evolution within
neural systems welcome to the show Greg
hey Chango thanks for having me I'm glad
that you can be on so you know before we
get into synthetic cannabinoids let's
review what actually are naturally
occurring cannabinoids so that people
can see the contrast sure what it's
going to be easy for your audience to
realize that the naturally occurring
cannabinoids as their name implies are
those that are naturally synthesized
from the cannabis plant that's when I
think about cannabinoids I'm thinking
about that family of molecules that are
made by cannabis now I know that there's
more and more interest in other natural
products that have some interaction with
the cannabinoid system like say beta
carry a saline is a you know natural
product in black peppers and in cannabis
but when I think it cannabinoids i'm
thinking of THC CBD varieties thereof
look at those are the are the real the
most popular ones things that come from
the cannabis plant and so you know some
people talk about endocannabinoids you
know the the endogenous cannabinoids
that are produced inside the human body
then other folks are talking about fight
okinawa dodes that uh you know phyto
meaning coming from the plant our
synthetic cannabinoids neither of those
therefore they are they are a third
thing you know yeah I think I'm as a
third thing and I like those
distinctions of course the
endocannabinoids are as natural as can
be that's really waxed and my time
mostly thinking about and our are found
all throughout animals and if the plants
have molecules that we now see as
endocannabinoids like an and amide phyto
cannabinoids come from the plants and
mostly I'm thinking about cannabis you
one could use synthetic chemistry to
make
a a cannabinoid like THC can be made
synthetically you know and it is and so
if that would be a synthetic or semi
synthetic cannabinoid in my view but if
it's just mimicking a natural
cannabinoid it may be gray area most of
what we call synthetic cannabinoids are
chemical structural analogs that are
based on either the phyto cannabinoids
or the endocannabinoids but tweaked a
little bit at a different atom here
there give it a proprietary new look to
see if it can act in the body a little
differently a little stronger a little
longer less psychoactive that kind of
thing right on that makes a lot of sense
so you know when when k2 and spice came
out and people started talking about
them as being you know fake pot or or
synthetic cannabinoids I remembered you
know anybody who's a cannabis enthusiast
was just you know it makes you pull your
hair yea verily why on earth would you
do something so evil with something so
natural and beautiful but you know as I
got into this doing my research you know
for the show today I actually realized
that the synthetic cannabinoids were
made you know for the good of humans
would you go ahead and tell us that
story well yeah I mean what we call
synthetics I mean they came out of the
research endeavor the research
environment because the people who
understand sort of the narrative of
discovery may not get that but honestly
I mean when we celebrate the zendo
endocannabinoid system the receptors and
the and the ligands that the
endocannabinoids themselves in some way
we really owe that to synthetic drug
tools case in point I mean some of the
hot potent THC analogues were discovered
in the were synthesized and created like
in the 70s and 80s and they were just
chemical structural analogs of TAC and
pharmacologists we didn't know what CB
recept cv1 cb2 receptors were
but they knew that this drug looked like
TC it was made to look like THC and it
was much more strong much stronger than
TAC in like how it affected rodent
behavior especially and then some
chemists stuck a little radioactive
probe on it made it hot leg into what we
call a radio isotope that's a weekly
radio active and those synthetic
cannabinoids became probes that were
used to probe around brain tissue in
experimental animals and and discover
that in fact there was a specific
receptor it's how the receptor was
initially discovered was a binding site
for these synthetic THC analogs then as
the receptor was discovered the
endocannabinoids were discovered amongst
the and I was just getting into the
field at that point and at a young age
and the there was so much excitement
amongst the small field of
endocannabinoids researchers but those
can have cannabis cannabinoid
researchers who were chemists were
continuing to tweak the molecules and
try to come up with with analogs of an
anime ador ta see that could be more
specific or maybe a more useful
therapeutic or just used as a research
tool to figure out hey is cb1 doing this
or a CB to doing this it is it
responsible for something that's seen in
the lab and you don't know unless you
can specifically activate or block them
with synthetic drugs and so as far as
you know a lot of people don't I mean I
didn't even know when I first got into
this you know the idea that has a lab
tool so can you kind of explain a little
bit how building a lab tool to be used
in an experiments as helpful because
sometimes you need to run a test that
that the molecule you need doesn't
actually exist in nature yeah I mean in
a general sense you said it quite what
it's it mean the brain is so complicated
the pharmacology of our bodies are so
complicated that trying to get
specificity of a of a drug that hits
certain targets and not others it is not
something that you necessarily have I
mean it's not something you have in the
cannabis plant those molecules are
actually the phyto cannabinoids are
actually delightfully wide acting I mean
it gets a bad rap historically to say
it's a dirty drug because th Co hit
multiple things it come to find out I
think that's a big part of why it's a
surprisingly gentle kind of medicine
that you have this entourage of
molecules that hit so many things I
digress a little bit with that I mean as
a tool to try and figure out the fine
nuts and bolts of how these this unseen
world of molecules in our mind work you
have to develop specific compounds that
really target them or in the world of
genetics tinker with an animal so that
it has slightly different receptors I'm
not saying all of this is necessary to
come up with the best medicine as part
of where the disconnect is but it is
necessary for this quest to understand
how things work right on so to kind of
like summarize that you know dr. Hoffman
and others in those early days they were
developing these synthetic cannabinoids
not because they ever intended them to
become a product but because they for
example wanted to take a receptor and
say okay well natural cannabinoids can
can you know highlight this receptor up
to you know forty percent but but what
would it take to open up all the way to
a hundred percent or whatever and those
those didn't exist in nature but they
wanted to see what it would take to to
open it up all the way and so they may
made fake ones synthetic ones to see
what it would take and then maybe you
know after the fact they would try to
find something that in
nature that acted the same way so
essentially they're kind of like they're
kind of like crutches to move the
research on which aren't really ever
supposed to get out of the lab perhaps
yeah I mean in a way I see it that way I
mean it developing a tool like I made
that example without full much
forethought but how the tools were used
as probes to find the receptor to work
to work experimentally it's got to be
it's going to be a better molecule as a
probe if it binds more tightly than THC
does and though binding tightly isn't
synonymous with being a POW more
powerful potent drug it tends to check
that way so these super powerful
activators that are like a thousand
times more potent than THC they were
developed as a tool to be strong binding
ligands drugs now you know when you say
that the drugs were never meant to be
out of the lab I mean it's not like
these medicinal chemists are open to it
becoming a product I mean when they
synthesize a series of things John
Houseman at Clemson developed at jwh
series of drugs that is his initials and
and there are other like real eminent
chemists who have done stuff including
rough you missoula my mean the series of
drugs called hu hu 210 is 1 i've used
experimentally it's a very strong THC
analog and it has appeared in some of
these illicit spice products not as many
as the jwh series because they're easier
to synthesize by the clandestine
chemists who whip them up and so you
know here's a thing science scientists
aren't so they may have been open to the
idea that this could be a therapeutic
and then course they would patent it and
spin it off and that's you know not
outside their thinking but you know when
they go to scientific conferences and
say here's this drug in it works to
target this population of receptors and
not this one and in our animal model it
shows hey it might be useful for
diabetes or so
saying in a way that won't make you high
I mean these are these are trying to
scientists chemists trying to contribute
to their view of the greater good and
developing therapeutics and in the
process of giving scientific talks and
publishing papers you know they show
what the molecule is and someone with a
decent organic chemistry background can
look at molecules like the jwh series
that look a lot like a arachidonic acid
and Ananda mind things that are very
easy to obtain and they can make it in
the lab so you open these things up
there's all there's all kinds of
parallels with the other you know
serotonin reuptake psychedelics I mean a
lot of drugs that were developed as
research tools got out into a club scene
and some of them have led to fatal
overdoses right on so we're going to
talk more about their uses bye bye you
know recreational drug users after the
first break but before we go to
commercial I wanted to ask you you know
when I first got into researching
synthetics I kind of thought that people
were developing the synthetic
cannabinoids because using real cannabis
was so restricted in research by the
federal government that they had to
create other synthetics and I've heard
this from other people but now hearing
you talk about it it sounds like
synthetic cannabinoids would be useful
as tools in the laboratory regardless if
the if the research scientist had access
to real whole plant cannabinoids is that
true I think it is true but what you
said I mean I wouldn't be surprised if
that has entered into the equation
either I mean there you know when a lot
of these drugs were were developed they
were already hundreds of labs interested
or at least dozens and cannabinoids
there are now thousands and yeah I mean
developing something that could get
around the DEA scheduling because it's
so proprietary
would have been an advantage but a lot
of the synthetics I mean I remember very
well when the hu compounds is suddenly
got moved to schedule one and and it put
our huge burden on people who are using
it for their research right on that
makes sense we're going to go ahead and
take our first short break and be right
back you are listening to shaping fire
and my guest today is cannabinoid
researcher dr. Greger dhiman now that
the health benefits of terpenes have
become well known in the cannabis
industry people everywhere are looking
for the purest terpenes without
adulterants the problem with most
chirping providers is that they're not
sourced naturally and instead are made
as a byproduct of refining petroleum and
that's so sketchy the terpenes sold by
true terpenes are entirely different
they are certified organic non-gmo and
food grade that means that they are
extracted from real plant sources there
are no solvents of any kind they are
distilled only with steam that's right
only steam in fact terpenes from true
turbines are so pure that you can eat
them not only that but you can stack
them with better results too what I mean
is other companies turbines have got a
few percent of impurities and when you
stack those terpenes to make your blend
you're adding a variety of impurities
that degrade your final product true
terpenes also have strain-specific
turbines for a wide range of cannabis
strains like durban poison sunset
sherbet and granddaddy purple true
terpenes has robust in support of
customer service so your questions will
get answered fast and efficiently if you
shop for terps before you know how rare
that is so whether you want to cup your
hands just smell some beta carry a
saline to calm down after getting too
high or if you want to dab some pining
so your lungs feel fabulous and your
mind feels liberated true terpenes will
provide you with a truly natural
experience if you are a cannabis product
developer these are the terps you want
to add to your oil or edible or capsule
or whatever true terpenes are simply the
best your money can buy don't try and
make a premium product with substandard
terms choose true terpenes for a
top-shelf experience go to shaping fire
calm board flash true terpenes to find
out more or
on the link in this week's newsletter
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host Shango Lohse
and our guest this week is cannabinoid
researcher dr. Greger diamond so before
the break we were talking about the
development of synthetic cannabinoids
and their beneficial original uses that
they were being used for in the lab well
you know right towards the end we were
talking about how they got out into the
open and they started being produced by
folks who want we're more interested in
using them as an enlisted or at the very
least recreational drug for for just
drug users can you kind of explain Greg
how that works how does this information
that's being used in the lab get into
the possession of somebody who sees you
know an opportunity to make money as a
street drug with it well I can speak in
general ways to it I mean I'm not privy
to the route with which really any of
these escape from the lab in specific
but you know people publish their
science and discuss it at conferences at
in open ways and someone who is a savvy
organic chemist can look at structures
especially if there's a publication they
found that talks about the synthesis I
mean I think that some of these some of
these drugs whether they're in the first
papers that use them or in patent
filings described the synthesis so what
you need is some glassware and burners
and knowledge about how to do synthetic
chemistry and you can do it if you've
got that chemistry background yeah and
it's interesting too because you know
they're there are to a certain degree
you know how to guides in in the
appendix right because a lot of these
papers you know they give you the the
data and the research and explanation in
the main body but man there's a treasure
trove of good stuff in the appendix a
lot of these papers that really give you
give you secrets so how do you make it
in your own lab at home if you've got
the right apparatus if you some of the
require certain precursor molecules that
are not just something you go get at the
store but you know I mean those
compounds that are easy to synthesize
and are so potent that's the thing I
mean with some of these synthetics again
are a thousand or ten thousand times
more active at cb1 receptors than THC is
so it you know you think about testing
cannabis or something with key force to
elevate the THC content these people use
various whatever cheap dried herbs and
just spritz a little bit of these super
potent cannabinoids on now and then and
it's enough that at least sometimes it's
going to cause a powerful psychoactive
effect so you know I'm sure that there's
some people are alike Wow thousand times
stronger than THC get me some of that
but it was when when you know start to
research you know phyto cannabinoids you
find that they're all kind of they've
all got a braking system inside of them
so that you can't is so it doesn't act
open-ended ly on your endocannabinoid
system would you explain a little bit
why you know using synthetics is so much
more dangerous than using a naturally
occurring phyto cannabinoid well I think
the way to talk about it is breaking
down how drugs work under two different
terms that are very different to a
pharmacologist one is potency and the
other is efficacy and this is jargon
people wouldn't know the difference when
you're talking about it drugs about
drugs if they haven't studied it but
potency means you know the concentration
of a drug how much do you need in order
to elicit its maximal effect or like
half maximal effect and we use that term
potency very generally like oh there's
more THC and pot so it's more potent now
but to a pharmacologist potency the
potency of THC is the potency of THC if
you have more than you just have a
higher concentration so you're pushing
the effect
but THC in different cells and tissues
of your body or any molecule but just
take th see it has because that's the
problem child of cannabis right THC will
still only activate and turn on that
receptor to a certain extent it maxes
out and that is the property of the THC
receptor relationship that's referred to
as efficacy and that's what protects all
of us cannabis users from from having a
bad day that's why there's been zero
deaths that's why what advice is safe
herb to use is because of this just cap
if you will that nature intended well
the final cannabinoid certainly have a
certain limited bit considered partial
efficacy agonist or just partial agonist
so yeah THC has its own sort of limiting
step so to speak and we didn't know that
honestly until all these synthetics were
made for the various reasons we talked
about before the break and and you
suddenly you have a drug wow wait a
minute we thought TC was turning the
system on but you wash on this CP
compound and it's like a thousand times
it's active at a thousand times smaller
dose that's potency and it drives the
system stronger it doesn't it's not
going to have a thousand times the
efficacy it has a thousand times the
potency but what we do know and this is
still growing we're learning more about
these different synthetics they not only
push the receptor system to a higher
level than anything the plant will do
especially if it's within an entourage
with molecules like CBD that will help
temper THC but even if you've got a
straight THC and a lot of it you know
like some sort of straight THC dab or
something taking a synthetic that has a
higher efficacy or a higher intrinsic
activity we also say we'll do more than
that high level of THC because it pushes
the receptor further it's a molecular
property and I'll plug a little bit I
wrote something about this that was over
on project CBDs website recently if
people want to look that up
oh right on yeah and you should everyone
should know about project CBD org not
only is it a great repository for for
research like Greg is referring to but
also they've got a great section on the
website where you can go and click on
the word conditions and it goes down i
don't know maybe fifty different
conditions that you may have as a human
and it gives you easy links to the
Western science that's been done about
cannabinoids in that in that condition
so we're both big fans of project CVD
org yeah and i felt i hope the kind of
curate those lists over time and i
advise if emma lon right well thanks for
that work because i use them with
patients all the time so so what is the
experience that a user an end user would
have experiencing some of these
synthetics that have got you know so
much increased potency well you know one
thing is that it'll knock you on your
ass i mean it can well for one thing
inning it's there's absolutely if people
think it's tough to know what's in your
cannabis i mean these products that are
sold as you know spice products there
may be nothing in there but but you may
get some super potent agonist and you
know for example is several of us in the
field know someone who was an early used
synthesizer of this or tester of one of
these drugs and and tried some on
himself and was like literally unable to
move for like 48 hours and i won't drop
this person's name but it was terrifying
i mean you talk about someone compare
that to the worst you know brownie over
ingestion that you possibly can have and
it's not it's not the same it alright
curiously it is somewhat similar to what
happens in rodents i mean you can give
TAC at such high levels to a rat that
he's unable to move and though it's been
known for a long time it's called a
cataleptic response you can like lift up
the animals legs and stuff and he just
can't move that's what these and THC
doesn't do that too
people I mean you can be totally out
there from a super high dose but it
doesn't make you an able to move and
some of these super potent agonist I
believe can the other though I think the
more alarming a thing is that
cannabinoids do have cardiovascular
effects they affect your heart rate they
affect the dilation of your blood
vessels the endocannabinoids are used to
help maintain an optimal balance with
blood flow and cardiovascular tone like
that the phyto cannabinoids do influence
these things hence you know you can have
sort of a postural drop in blood
pressure if you smoke smoke a bowl and
and get a high THC that lowers your
blood pressure it can make you need to
sit down the and it letici elicits a
transient increase in heart rate the
synthetics do so much more and those
increases in heart rate those quick
dynamic changes in blood flow very
possibly or increasing the risk for
suffering a cardiovascular incident like
a stroke and there's literature to
suggest that there are I've talked to
multiple neurologists who they haven't
you know done a controlled study but
they're convinced it's real because
they've seen people who have taken these
synthetics and of our suffering
significant strokes at ages where it's
not common and and that has been used to
malign cannabis as well because that
literature will pop up and people from
like whatever project Sam or something
will say oh yeah we know that cannabis
increases the risk of stroke but they're
citing papers that are looking at its
synthetic cannabinoid that is not just
fake THC is a super potent full agonist
instead of a partial agonist it does
things to your receptor system drives it
more powerfully causes it to activate
cells and ways to teach he doesn't even
at heroic doses so we don't I couldn't
tell you all the reasons why it these
synthetics are likely to be more
dangerous
just named a couple of them but there
may be others in it it won't be known
unless it's really studied carefully and
in the meantime people should pursue a
more natural alternative it's been safe
for thousands of years yeah I think
that's really the end point as far as
the the end consumer of these it's like
okay well we recognize that your you
know you're using spice or k2 or any one
of these marketed products because you
know it's written it's available you can
buy it at you know the local bodega or
you're partying or whatever and you know
maybe where you live cannabis is hard to
get but just because it's synthetic
cannabinoids it doesn't mean that it is
going to your head and have an
experience that's in any way like like
safe natural marijuana that's been you
know you used interaction with with
humans for thousands of years this is
more like some crazy frankenstein
version of it with none of the natural
safeguards that come with using whole
plant cannabis ray yeah I mean there's
natural safeguards and there's the
safeguards with people who are are
trying to create a medicine as opposed
to just you know trying to make a buck
yeah right on that makes sense well
let's go ahead and take our second short
break when we come back we're going to
talk about a potential for synthetic
cannabinoids be useful in the future you
are listening to shaving fire and my
guest today is cannabinoid researcher
dr. Greg tournament for anyone who is
paying attention to cannabis medicine it
has become incredibly apparent that full
extract cannabis oil known to some as
rick simpson oil is the cornerstone of
healing humans with medical marijuana if
you own a medical dispensary or retail
store you know that your customers are
asking for it every single day and if
you have been working with patients and
seeking out quality full extract oil in
the Pacific Northwest you know the
provider deep green cat Jeter and her
team at deep green had been making full
extract cannabis oil and setting the
standards for quality and exact dosing
for years in Washington state the deep
green brand is known by patients and
cannabis media as a premium quality
provider for sick children
cancer patients and others in need at a
time when there are no national
standards for cannabis oil ensuring a
product as whole plant quality assured
and lab tested is often a matter of
knowing your sources reputable trust and
a quality brand is essential in choosing
a cannabis medicine that is going to be
used concentrated and in volume by any
patient and especially those with
weakened immune systems deep green is
looking for national brand partners to
expand the availability of their legacy
top-shelf cannabis oil to emerging
medical and licensed states partners
benefit from the deep green brand
recognition and credibility as well as
ongoing customer and marketing support
not only that but deep green knows how
to employ the 280e tax rule so you can
deduct it all from your taxes working
with deep green can provide the trust
and authenticity too often pushed aside
in favor of lifestyle products your
customers can assure themselves that
regardless of the state in which it is
made grand licensees adhere to the same
strict standards that patients
everywhere have come to expect from deep
green deep green licensing includes
startup and capital planning as well as
operational and manufacturing
instruction as you'd expect for more
information on how your company co-op or
medical dispensary can benefit from
partnering with deep green to provide
full extract canna soil to patients go
to shaping fire calm ford / deep green
to connect with cat Jeter and her team
that's shaping fire calm forward slash
deep green welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire i am your host
Shango low so i guess this week is
cannabinoid researcher dr. Greger dhiman
so Greg you know we kind of trashed
synthetic cannabinoids pretty hardcore
in the last set but you know we know
that they came out of a lab where they
were you know trying to do good research
you know do you see a future in
pharmaceuticals for synthetic
cannabinoids to be used for something
that's you know positive I see that it
certainly could happen I mean you know
for for 20 years now
in researching in this field you know I
can't tell you how many grant proposals
or sort of paper discussion taglines
have sort of played the language that we
could develop more specific drugs or
that our have a better profile
specifically that don't have the kind of
psycho activity that cannabis does and I
mean as we learn more about the
endocannabinoid system being everywhere
in the body you know I read a read of
paper the other day by you know some big
research team not a usual suspect
cannabinoid team I mean so many people
on the cannabinoids and they said very
straight forward in their paper the
endocannabinoid system is now seen as a
mast as V they use the word V master
regulator of physiological homeostasis
that kind of thing if I to set it in
1999 I'd have been you know laughed out
of the room and now we so we know the
importance of the endocannabinoid system
its robust its diverse and there are
many different targets and some
synthetics may be developed that have
better delivery better a longer lasting
effect something of those nature that
nature that makes it very usable by
physicians and could target specific
things like maybe there's a subset of
mitochondrial disease that as we learn
more that certain synthetics like target
really well and on the other hand maybe
some of the minority cannabinoids that
have been terribly understudied might
treat those populations as well too so I
think there's promise in both i and also
you know synthetic cannabinoids can be
used in researching you know full plan
natural cannabinoids too because you
know they're just they're being used in
the experiments as well so maybe maybe
there may be synthetic cannabinoids can
still be used maybe maybe not as
pharmaceutical products but they
certainly seem to have
uses in the lab in conducting your
experiments oh for sure for sure they do
and drugs that block receptors are very
useful tools drugs that have different
little labels on them that you can see
them on brain scans have tools but you
know what funds and drives brain
research is the promise of discovering
treatments and cures for brain disease
primarily I mean I'm a total science
geek I'm all about our drive to
understand how it works but primarily
research is funded to find new tools and
I mean new treatments and and Jersey
even some some synthetic tools could be
useful for that even if the end result
is I mean I should back up some
synthetic tools will be useful for that
are useful for that even if we should be
able to step back from the end result
and say maybe the best answer
therapeutically is something that's been
here all along oh I love that segue to
because the next point I wanted to make
is you know as much as as you are
positing the possibility of synthetic
cannabinoids being useful in for future
patients from the pharmaceutical
industry I know you to be a whole plant
guy like I am and and you know if
there's if there's you know X amount of
money available for cannabinoid research
I'm guessing that you're going to say
put all that money into naturally
occurring whole plant medicine and set
aside to synthetic cannabinoids until
we've done a hell of a lot more research
on the plan you know with with apologies
to all of the classical pharmacologists
who have trained me and worked with me
yeah I do think I also I don't think
it's a total zero sum game you know
within certain Institute's there will be
certain budgets for research mostly if
the constraints for research weren't
there funding would come in to support
whole plant cannabis therapeutics and
there are enough really good minds that
are fascinated by this because it's the
most fascinating subject you know I'm
just amazed by how many bright thinkers
want to study cannabis if they can and
if the constraints to studying it
there you know I think that that's where
a lot of the the money would go and that
is of concern to the sort of traditional
pharmaceutical industry I think where
they're trying to adapt to it I took
your question a little bit of a twist
but yeah I mean there is the and it's
the kind of thing that mr. Ullom has
been saying like a profit for decades
and others but of course he's such a
real mentor to so many of us that this
plant is a treasure trove and it's just
one of the hugest discoveries and we
shouldn't be attached to the fact that
it was discovered a long time ago and
rediscovered and rediscovered and we now
have the state of Technology to dig
deeper and and do the kind of studies to
understand how these different molecules
work and how different preparations work
and what they work to help you know I
was I was talking to a group two weeks
ago and somebody asked a question during
Q&amp;A about synthetic cannabinoid and and
you know I was just getting ready for my
my talk with you and I wasn't too deep
on it but I said you know what I
understand about something that can have
annoyed so far is it's as if you were
going to judge yourself on your worst
cousin you know your cousin that comes
with a party and it's disruptive and
gets drunk and you know hits on your
sister-in-law or whatever right you
can't judge you know you and your whole
family based on that one that one cousin
and synthetic cannabinoids kind of seems
a bit to be like that you can't judge
the cannabis plant and all of the
healing possibility that it holds just
because synthetic cannabinoids found
their way out of the lab and are being
sold to people who are using it wrong
all right level well it mean it's funny
because it's like it's like THC has been
the bad uncle for a lot at least
according to the the propagandists you
know and and to an extent the the black
market illegality created the you know a
selection for high THC plants many of
which are feeble
things that don't really grow very well
but they create a lot of THC and you
know the THC has gotten a bad rap
because of simply getting you high at
all and we know that molecules like CBD
and THC V just to name a couple of
tremendous therapeutic value and they've
been short shifted because of
relationship with THC and now exposing
it this is what drives me nuts when when
I see a local news story about fake pot
it's because the media just don't know
enough at all or don't care to know that
it's not fake pot at all it's a chemical
that has never been found in cannabis
ever so it's you know kind of like
saying crystal masses fake dopamine you
know they have biological interactions
but they're not the same they're not
they're not a mimic of one another it's
a it's a bad Act right on that's that's
well said so in the end we come full
circle around to holding up the whole
plant and the and the Safety's that
nature has imbued it with as being are
our primary medicine and not something
that's necessarily coming out of the lab
today I believe it yeah well Greg thanks
for being on the show you know I had
been curious about this for actually
actually that's not actually true i was
going to say i was curious about this
for a long time but most of the time
spice and k2 is just been something i
ignored because had nothing to do with
working with patients it was just some
crazy stuff i'd see on local news
sometimes but then when's the first time
i heard them say you know synthetic
cannabinoids I'm like well my whole life
is cannabinoids I guess I should get too
worried about this right so even though
I understand now better that it's it's
you know doesn't really have anything to
do with marijuana except for how the
news reports about it I feel far more
confident in discussing it with people
and and that I know what the hell I'm
talking about so thank you very much for
sharing your experience well you're
welcome and of course you know it does
act on a similar path ways it's just
different and it is important because
you know wait like in Florida right now
we're dealing with
where the industry is getting started in
what I will delicately say is a very
clumsy way and it you know the medicines
are starting to roll out under the state
legal system and they're they're
absurdly expensive they're not
transparently tested and you know it's
easy to imagine scenarios where the
dialogue around cannabis being medicine
is much more common and somebody in a
different in some community somewhere
gets ripped off by saying hey man this
is the same stuff it's medicine you
don't want to pay that through the you
know through the system this stuff is
like cannabis only it's a lot better you
don't have to use you know so if this
dialogue can help to inform better that
people don't make those mistakes and
could lead to a serious problem then
it's it's important to have right on dr.
Greger diamond is a cannabinoid
researcher and assistant professor of
biology at Eckerd College in st.
Petersburg Florida you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shaping fire
calm and on Apple iTunes stitcher and
Google Play if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you'd leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too on the shaping fire website you
can also subscribe to the weekly
newsletter for insights into the latest
cannabis news and product reviews on the
shaping fire website you will also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
for information on me and where i'll be
speaking you can check out Shango
lowes.com does your company want to
reach our national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hot spot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shake on fire I've been
your host Shango lowes
[Music]