[Music]
in the early days of medical cannabis
growers learned that a particular strain
they grew had more of medicinal value
than usual because of the feedback from
the people who smoked it a grower would
hear that it helps stop someone's
seizures or a decreased pain or maybe a
Parkinson's patients tremors subsided
for a while after enough comments like
that a grower knew that this particular
chemo var was one to keep around 2009
though the first publicly accessible
cannabis analytics labs began to open
and cannabis producers could for the
very first time ever get reliable
scientific potency testing and they
realize that many of these especially
medicinal strains contained
cannabidiol more commonly known as CBD
because there is no federally allowed
cannabis market in the US we now find
ourselves at a moment where CBD is sold
separately and differently in the for
existing markets of state regulated
medical state regulated recreational
adult use the unregulated market or
black market and the international
market for CBD isolate production and
distribution of CBD right now is wild
and volatile and the markets continue to
crash against each other as price
availability and quality between the
different markets continues to shift
anyone involved with cannabis business
or caring for patients will benefit from
an understanding of how these market
fluctuations will affect them if you
enjoy hearing frank discussions that
dive deep into cannabis health business
and technique I encourage you to
subscribe to our newsletter every week
you'll receive a new podcast episode
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode you
are listening to shaping fire and I am
your host
Shango lows my guest today is Seth
Crawford Seth is a deinstitutionalized
academic with a master's in public
policy and a PhD in sociology his focus
has been on the political economy
cannabis for years now he's been
consulted by lawmakers and policy
specialists for a better understanding
of how the underground cannabis economy
works
he's now co-founder of oregon CBD
company researching developing and
wholesaling high CBD cannabis seeds
today we're going to talk with Seth
about the past present and future of the
CBD market welcome to the show Seth
thanks so much for having me so Seth you
know until the research on CBD began to
be more readily available in media
everywhere you know there really wasn't
a CBD market at all but but now through
the efforts of hardcore CBD evangelists
like like Martin Lee and dr. Ethan Russo
and Kevin Jodrey and Lawrence Ringo and
you know lots of others including the
Sanjay Gupta TV special a profound
search for whole plant CBD is in the
hearts of patients everywhere when do
you think that we first began seeing
something that we could call the CBD
market it's a good question you can
almost look at it as something that has
organically emerged with the
availability of CBD rich plants I
listened in to the oral history with
Kevin Jodrey and it was absolutely
absolutely fantastic my personal
experience with the CBD market started
really with the availability of ac/dc
clones and so hearing that oral history
was really informative and it was need
to need to hear how it all ended up
forming a CDC in Oregon where I'm at
really became available after about 2013
that's when it kind of hit the scene and
that was the same year that industrial
hemp production took off in the state of
Colorado
now this occurred before the passage of
the 2014 federal farm bill which allowed
industrial hemp production in the United
States to happen the following year 2015
is when I would say the CBD market
really exploded
really took off just in the sense of
product actually being available for for
consumers that that just that plant
availability
seems to be the the big driver and as
you know obviously as we've seen as more
people get into the production side of
CBD it's become more available the price
has gone down and more and more people
are becoming exposed to it today yeah
that makes a lot of sense too because
you know it really is not the academic
papers or even you know it's to a
certain degree to the media attention
but the thing that's really driving the
CBD market from what I've seen is the
fact that people are actually getting
relief from it because someone will get
relief and then they'll tell their
sister and their sister-in-law and their
uncle and their kids and then suddenly
now you've got five more people who are
looking for CBD and then they tell
someone so you know we know that
referral is that is the best marketing
and when people get relief man they just
they want to talk about cannabinoids
they do they really do and the fact that
it's non psychoactive is you know it's
really a godsend I think for a lot of
people who are suffering and find some
relief from CBD and I know there's quite
a few people even in the still in the
medical marijuana community who don't
view CBD as something other than you
know a passing fad they view it as snake
oil because maybe they've tried it it
didn't work for them but when you see
the look on on a child's face or on a
grandparents face when they have some
sort of suffering relieved from it
whether it's drivet syndrome and
epileptic seizures and children or
osteoarthritis from age and just you
know long-term degeneration for for the
elder members of our communities it's
it's real and it strikes a pretty
powerful chord for those of us that are
participating in this this side and this
side of the cannabis market right on
so generally today we're going to be
focusing mostly on cannabidiol or CBD
but you know CBD is only one of over a
hundred cannabinoids that are in whole
plant cannabis and and and before we
move on I just want you to touch on you
know other emerging markets for
cannabinoids because you know I've seen
you know people marketing cbn CBG THC V
for appetite suppression are you seeing
the the the market for other
cannabinoids other than can have a dial
coming coming along as well they will be
yeah you know the thing about plant
breeding at least the way that we've
experienced it it takes about six months
to develop a new variety and that's when
you're really really making progress
we're lucky enough now to have a lot of
analytical labs on board we have PCR
screens that we can use with some folks
that are putting that stuff together for
us the the emergence of new cannabinoids
I think is going to accelerate now most
of them are not on the market at this
point but they will be in the next three
to five years
CBD was really the forerunner I think on
the the non-psychoactive cannabinoid
side it's really created a groundswell
and it had a in terms of just having as
we were talking about before having
people from a range of backgrounds and
ages and life experiences being more
open and accepting of a compound that's
coming from a cannabis plant simply
because it's non psychoactive it's I
think CBD has definitely paved the way
for for future inroads in that in that
department yeah yeah I buy that so you
know after that Sanjay Gupta special on
television that focused on the
wide-ranging uses of CBD you know lots
of folks like the Stanley Brothers in
Colorado you renamed hi-c be strange
that had they had come across and began
to market them aggressively and they
found a really warm welcome by both the
media and patients the the challenge
being of course that that the patient's
believed that it was only the Stanley
Brothers Charlotte's Web that was the
only strain that had health benefits and
that was certainly not the case and a
lot of people fault the Stanley Brothers
for their approach but it was was really
the media attention that they garnered
that helped explain the benefits of
whole plant CBD to everybody and got it
to reach middle America you know that's
when my family back in the Midwest
started talking to me about it was after
the Sanjay Gupta TV special so so to
what degree do you think
the heavy media coverage has led to that
fast rise and the popularity of CBD oh
it could not be could not be overstated
you know that's the thing with just
about any type of idea or product though
is as soon as it's picked up and moved
into popular consciousness either by
media or today active social networks on
social media people moving ideas around
once it gains traction it definitely
takes off I mean there's some
fascinating research that looks at the
popularity of specific songs and whether
or not you know a popular popular tune
will catch on you know there's formulas
for crafting music that will sell
millions and millions of you know
records or whatever the same thing is
probably true when it comes to either
cannabis varieties or you know any other
idea it just comes down to being able to
get it out into the marketplace and have
people pick it up and that I understand
where you're going with the Stanley
Brothers and Sanjay Gupta it definitely
had a positive impact in terms of being
able to get the word out the dangers
with something like that when you have
one particular plant that gets
identified as as the be-all and end-all
is that you lose out on the amazing
diversity that is actually present in
the cannabis family yeah and it confused
a lot of people right because even
though it was wonderful to have people
talking about cannabis as a medicine
there was also you know a handful of
misinformation mixed into the reporting
and so now folks like you and I and our
in our and our contemporaries have to go
and kind of help people unlearn the
first wave of information that came out
and helped them fine-tune it so that
people can get the the proper medicine
that's going to work for them yeah no no
kidding I mean the same thing is is true
I would say on the THC side as well
people go to a dispensary and they're
asking for something that's going to
make them uplifted it's going to have a
positive euphoric feeling for them or
give them pain release and you know the
thing that they've been taught is indica
and sativa so you know
a little bit more sophisticated version
is narrow leaf and broadleaf plants but
you know the reality is and you had even
Rousseau on a few weeks ago we know that
it's not just those things it's terpenes
and in our breeding program we've
noticed that in open pollinated f2
generations we can find every
combination of terpene in plant shape
imaginable if it's a if it's a properly
bred line you can find anything in those
so it's two different different small
things like that where were the folks
who are who are learning and doing it by
experience end up having to correct some
of that information as we go but you
know that's I think that's science right
good yes I also appreciate that you're
you're plugging some of my former shows
you've already plugged to in our
interview so I appreciated both that the
oral history of CBD with Kevin Jodrey
and and the two shows that I've done
with dr. Rietz and Rousseau so I'm glad
that I'm glad that you've had a chance
to listen to the show too definitely and
these are these are good people doing
great work it's a very small community I
think of people who are really out on
the forefront of this and it's it's neat
to be a part of you know the the
misinformation about CVD that we were
talking about just a moment ago you know
I think that's what has led us to a lot
of these CVD only medical marijuana laws
at states because anybody you know these
legislators who are a little pushing for
CVD only laws because they don't want to
involve evil THC they just start missing
the point they don't understand the
importance of the entourage effect and
that you really need all of the
different cannabinoids in the plant to
you know creates the best medicine and
secondarily a lot of people especially
cancer patients and others it's the THC
part of the plant that is healing for
them I mean CBD is super healing and can
be used by every human because we all
have endocannabinoid systems but really
depending on what your issue is it may
be the THC that part of it that's the
medicine for you and I think a lot of
those legislators miss that it's a
hundred percent and you know one of the
issues that you I think is probably
contributing to that is
the piecemeal approach from state to
state with different type of
legalization frameworks what what I've
seen is a lot of the more conservative
states particularly in the south end up
passing the CBD only laws and their I I
don't want to say they're they're
totally misguided but I think they're
pushed in a particular way by people who
have vested interests in the production
side and who are trying to develop drugs
that would fit whatever you know laws
they come up with in those places
there's certain certain laws
they call them CBD CBD only laws but you
can have up to five percent THC in in
your extracts and compounds to me that's
not a CBD only law that would be more
like a one to one law which is great and
like you mentioned that's probably one
of the more efficacious medical
applications is the synergy that's
involved between THC and CBD in the body
but it's led to a very very interesting
patchwork of legislation across the
country that in some cases makes good
sense and provides access and in other
cases just is bewildering yeah and and
since we're talking about the CBD market
today I think it's important to point
out that that that patchwork of laws has
made a really weird market where we're
at least two things are happening the
first thing is is that the patients are
are leaving their state and going to
another state either either temporarily
to just make a purchase or permanently
so they can have a long-term supply of
whatever part of the cannabis plant that
they need that's not available or in
their state so that's number one and
number two the simple arbitrage where
people are going to another state you
know buying thousands of dollars of
whatever specific medicine is needed in
their locale and then bringing it back
and then distributing it amongst their
friends and family you know if if we had
saying national cannabis medicine law
then this kind of arbitrage and and you
know cherry-picking where you were going
to purchase from state to state which is
not that happening I mean this is this
is not people trying to be criminals
this is people trying to work around a
nun
workable law 100% yeah and it's a what
you're saying to is highlighting just
the overall legal landscape in the
United States it's to me it's
fascinating we can basically divide it
into you look at it as a tripartite
division between in terms of
legalization going forward in the United
States right now on on one component you
have medical and recreational laws or
CBD only laws that are either passed
through citizens initiatives and states
or by state legislatures you have large
pharmaceutical companies who are
pursuing fda-approved
cannabinoid drugs for very specific
conditions and then you have industrial
hemp which is a federally legal and the
products that come out of industrial
hemp programs can be shipped to any
state legally in the United States and
there's a lot of in addition to the
cannabinoid research that's going on is
that there's a lot of agronomic research
as well and having those three three
totally separate divisions that are all
operating simultaneously with different
restrictions and different barriers to
entry for both people who are in that
marketplace or trying to consume
products from those marketplaces it's
just created a it's created all kinds of
issues well at the same time providing
you know just enough gray area I think
for a lot of people to move forward with
some pretty interesting work and you
know it gets even more messy because of
the lexicon is so messy I mean a
people's usage right I mean you know a
lot of people argue back and forth
between using the word marijuana which
has got a sordid history versus using
the word cannabis which is more accurate
and scientific but but even beyond that
you've got people who are in industrial
hemp who like to call their product
cannabis because technically it's
cannabis sativa and then you've got
people who are in medical marijuana
which is also cannabis sativa who want
to also use the word hemp because maybe
they were you know grow hemp for victory
people back in the day and so the
industry itself doesn't even have a
stable lexicon where people who are in
what what you and I would probably see
as different product categories using
each other's vocabulary which which not
only makes it more confusing for
investors but just totally loses
patience
yeah and the legal definitions do
exactly the same thing 100% agree with
you you look at the federal guidelines
and marijuana quote-unquote is you need
type of cannabis that contains THC over
0.3% by way that's the definition that's
used anything else is considered
industrial hemp when will you step back
it's all of it is cannabis it's all part
of the same larger family and all of
these divisions that we've put in front
of us whether it's from a marketing
perspective or from a legal perspective
or all social constructs I mean the
blood the plants are the same same way
that we've created you know I think
about it from a from a social science
perspective race is probably the best
example of it we have no no real genetic
difference not a meaningful difference
between the racial categories that have
been constructed over the years if you
take one person and analyze their genome
from one particular race that they've
been assigned to and you compare it to
another person from a different race you
will end up with more similarities than
you would get if you had taken two
people from the same race and analyzed
their genomes same thing is true with
cannabis
these are socially constructed
boundaries that are that are basically
vestiges of 20th century prohibition
mentality so now that we've established
pretty thoroughly that there is a CVD
market and that it's growing really
quickly and and including both the
licensed cannabis market or medical
marijuana market and and and if you if
you know this the gray market what would
would you calculate the total size of
the CBD market to be in the United
States you know honestly and this is
weird I mean this is my area of
expertise but I have no idea and I think
that that would be the honest answer
that anyone anyone who's looking at this
seriously would would tell you I know
that it has dramatically expanded in the
last two years in particular and a lot
of the high CBD the hemp or
CBD flowers that are being produced in
the United States at least under the
industrial hemp program get exported to
other countries Israel is a very large
buyer there are a lot of people in a lot
of companies in Europe that are creating
basically using high CBD flowers as an
alternative to tobacco for a smoking
cessation there at least to nicotine
cessation it's it's large and like we
talked about earlier I think the more
that's available the more if you can end
up seeing produced because the demand is
actually there you know I did this back
of the envelope calculation last year as
some legislation was going through the
going through the Oregon Legislature
that was going to be changing some
aspects of the industrial hemp program
here and the number that I came up with
was specifically for horses for aged
horses old horses with arthritis because
one of the cool things that has been
demonstrated with CBD is that it not
only helps people but it also helps
animals as well specifically with
age-related degeneration arthritic
horses are large animals that would
require a lot of CBD but you know it's
basically sixteen thousand acres worth
to be able to treat all of the horses in
the United States that's horses I mean
there's other animals too and and people
could probably benefit from it as well
and at this point we're getting close to
having that many acres lashes we're this
year we will be over it nationally I
think the state of Kentucky has 14,000
acres licensed I know the state of
Oregon has 3,000 acres licensed this
year it's it is getting very large now
compared to the THC market overall in
the United States it's still smaller in
terms of total total amount demanded
total amount produced but I think I
think we're going to see a change in
that definitely within the next ten
years yeah isn't that an interesting
aspect of this right I mean CBD
availability is low and the demand for
it is is on a wicked rise and yet nearly
all of the licensed
Cannabis producers in the united states
emphasize high THC strains as their
flagship products but the th the price
of THC is crashing and CBD you know CBD
is going down a little bit just because
it's not prohibited as much anymore but
really the demand is so high that you
can't even keep CBD on the shelves and
and yet because they think they want to
decrease their risk most licensed
producers are still focusing on THC
where if I had a license I'd be going
all-in on CBD because that market is
going to outpace any kind of price
decrease for years and years and years
to come to a certain extent I I agree
with you on that over the long term I
think in the short term at least the way
that we've seen it unfold in Washington
and Colorado in Oregon and I'm assuming
we'll see the same thing happen in
California with adult use legalization
comes a lot of restrictions a lot of
security requirements and a very very
high overhead in terms of barriers to
entry you have to have a you have to
have a lot of money to get into those
markets and the prices that we've seen
per pound on CBD rich flowers are still
there they're way below what ithc
Flowers command at this point so I think
in the short term it makes good business
sense to get into the THD market if
you're in a state legal recreational
program or adult use program on the
other hand and we've seen this bolt in
Colorado Washington and Oregon now the
the production for THC has typically
outpaced
the demand and so it makes it very
difficult for these farmers to actually
sell their product whereas with the CBD
side it tends to go pretty quickly you
know I think that's a really really good
insight and and I think I'll amend my
position a little bit based on what you
just said and I think that one of the
reasons why the price for CBD is not on
par as much with THC is because the
right CBD products have not necessarily
in the market yet you know a lot of
folks are taking CBD and you know
spiking them with flavorings or you
using CBD isolate in an edible or you
know so much of the recreational mindset
of the products is not bringing products
to the market that are actually is
actually CBD for patients and I think
that as product designers get more
sophisticated and understand patients
more the demand will increase I see that
happening for sure yeah well let's go
ahead and take our first short break and
be right back you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is
cannabis policy analyst Seth Crawford
we humans are attracted to plants
because they offer us relief and are a
whole lot of fun sometimes though the
best parts are buried inside the plant
and we need to use specialty extraction
technology when it comes to cannabis it
is extraordinarily important to extract
its precious oils without changing them
in the process we want to preserve the
properties of the cannabinoids terpenes
and other constituents that all work
together since 1994 Eden labs has been
developing extraction technology and
processes to do just that Eden labs was
founded by a cannabis loving engineer
during the early days of medical
marijuana in California and the expanded
Eden team has been designing and
building industry-leading solutions for
cannabis extraction ever since
Eden labs flagship product is the newly
improved high flow co2 extractor as
other extraction companies enter the
market it is the high flow from Eden
labs that everyone chases and tries to
compare themselves with not only that
but the improved automation software
allows data to be collected stored and
studied Eden labs can outfit your whole
lab Eden's coldfinger
ethanol extractor creates astonishing
whole plant extracts working alone or in
tandem with an initial stream distilling
step to isolate monoterpenes before
extracting the rest of the botanical
constituents Eden offers you many
options including vacuum distillation
column distilling stirred reactor units
and accelerated solvent recovery when
you partner with Eden labs your lab team
is enrolled into the ena labs training
program to boost their understanding of
Eden's best practices to ensure that
your outputs are exactly what you
require for your application
whether it be dab oil oil for pen
cartridges or edibles when you work with
Eden you're not just buying the tech you
are buying dedicated customer support to
help you attain your business goals -
you can hear Eden's CEO AC Braddock talk
about the company's values during
shaping fire episode 19 that was all
about co2 extraction so many of the new
companies in the market just smell
opportunity slap an ex tractor together
and hire a marketing company Eden labs
has been listening to feedback from
extractors and consumers for about 25
years now they care about both you and
your consumer partner with Eden labs to
extract astonishing cannabis oils and
terpenes that you will be proud of go to
shaping feiyr.com /e Dhin to find out
more
now that the health benefits of terpenes
have become well known in the cannabis
industry people everywhere are looking
for the purest terpenes without
adulterants the problem with most
chirping providers is that they're not
sourced naturally and instead are made
as a byproduct of refining petroleum and
that's so sketchy the terpenes sold by
true terpenes are entirely different
they are certified organic non-gmo and
food grade that means that they are
extracted from real plant sources there
are no solvents of any kind they are
distilled only with steam that's right
only steam in fact terpenes from true
drippings are so pure that you can eat
them not only that but you can stack
them with better results - what I mean
is other company's turbines have got a
few percent of impurities and when you
stack those terpenes to make your blend
you're adding a variety of impurities
that degrade your final product true
terpenes also have strain-specific
turbines for a wide range of cannabis
strains like turbine poison sunset
sherbet and granddaddy purple true
terpenes has robust and supportive
customer service so your questions will
get answered fast and efficiently if you
shop for tips before you know how rare
that is so whether you want to cup your
hands to smell some beta Kari awfully to
calm down after getting too high or if
you want to dab some pining so your
lungs feel fabulous and your mind feels
liberated true terpenes will provide you
with a truly natural
experience if you are a cannabis product
developer these are the Terps you want
to add to your oil or edible or capsule
or whatever true terpenes are simply the
best your money can buy don't try and
make a premium product with substandard
terms choose true terpenes for a
top-shelf experience go to shaping fire
calm board flash true terpenes to find
out more or click on the link in this
week's newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I'm your host
Shango Lowe and I guess this week is
cannabis policy analyst Seth Crawford so
during the first break
excuse me during the first set we talked
pretty much exclusively about the size
of the market and how it's just going to
get bigger and bigger from for all the
cannabinoids and cannabis but at the
moment specifically CBD and
interestingly because of federal
prohibition there are some states where
you're not able to get legal whole plant
CBD and and so what we're seeing in the
market is a lot of folks have started
extracting the single molecule of CBD
out of industrial hemp plants which are
not only increasingly legal in the
United States but also you can buy the
single molecule CBD you know overseas
and then people can put them into
whatever the product they're making and
you know there's there's become a lot of
infighting between the CBD from hemp
people and the CBD from whole plant
cannabis folks so let's start with you
know Sepp how big has the CBD from hemp
market become a big big and I think part
of that is driven you know as you just
described folks importing either isolate
krystal krystal and isolate from
European countries or from China we're
importing actual industrial hemp flowers
and then doing the extraction here in
the United States which is again
federally legal under the farm bill and
that one actually goes back to 2004 that
was the ninth
a Court of Appeals decision with the
hemp industry Association versus the DEA
that allowed for the importation of
industrial hemp but Lia seed products
flowers fiber etc from from other
countries so long as it met that 0.3
percent THC threshold for folks who
aren't very familiar with what we're
talking about about the CBD whole plant
CBD from medical plants versus extracted
from industrial hemp would you go ahead
and just give a nice little summary of
that for folks yeah industrial hemp
traditionally was you know we know the
history of it in the United States it
was basically made illegal along with
all other cannabis the European Union
today and individual European countries
previously had allowed industrial hemp
production and different different
requirements on THC ranging from 0.2
percent up to 0.3 percent were allowed
in those countries and over the last 20
years they developed a number of
different varieties that that meet those
requirements but to meet those
requirements from a plant breeding
perspective the easiest way to do it is
to just shut off the THC production so
if you'd like to grow cannabis on an
industrial scale you have to have plants
that have the THC synthesis essentially
turned off it active alleles what
normally happens in a in a in a any
cannabis plant if the THC side is turned
off the opposite side is essentially the
CBD production side so these European
breeders were by accident not
necessarily understanding what they were
doing they were creating CBD cultivars
that were then being used in production
now the problem with that is that to
obtain the 0.2 percent or the 0.3
percent THC also requires that your
total cannabinoid content be very very
low and there's a lot of overlap between
total oil production with terpenes and
cannabinoids so those two things are
definitely linked together so what you
end up with is cannabis plants that come
in at say 2% CBD or
I know there are some cultivars now up
to five percent CBD in Europe but what
they lack are terpenes and we know about
the synergistic relationship between
terpenes and cannabinoids it's a very
important distinction so on the one hand
we have very cheap massive-scale
flowers that have been seeded and you
know grown in hundreds and hundreds of
acres and then mechanically harvested
compressed and shipped over to the
United States for extraction that's
going into the CBD isolytic market and
then you have other folks who've
realized that you know we can we can
actually make high CBD plants that are
also turkey enriched and that sort of
been a renaissance in inbreeding in the
United States and that very happy to be
here in the u.s. at this point because I
feel like we are definitely definitely
leading the world in regards to that
approach right on and for and for folks
who this information is new to you I
recommend that you go back and listen to
the episode about oh I don't know about
eight weeks ago with dr. Ethan Rousseau
where we go through his historically
significant paper taming THC where he
talks about the different components in
medical cannabis and how each one of
them is important from CBD and THC like
we're talking about today but also the
terpenes the flavonoids even the lipids
and the chlorophyll for some patients
and it's how all of these different
constituents work together versus the
other option which we're also talking
about the CBD from hemp where they're
using extraction processes to to just
pull out the CBD molecule and make it
into an isolate and then put that into a
into a product so it's interesting when
you say Seth that to see the folks who
are buying CBD from hemp without
understanding the entourage effect be
surprised when they don't necessarily
get the medical benefits that they were
hoping for it's true yeah and you can
actually see it
selected in the marketplace at this
point as well it's very funny timing I
got some would call it internet spam but
I got an email this morning from someone
who was trying to push CBD isolate guy
just because I am working in that market
and the prices right now for CBD isolate
are half half of what the raw oil raw
co2 oil prices are in the United States
and I'm convinced that it's because
people are realizing that the isolate
just doesn't work as well for for most
conditions not going to say all but for
most conditions as you actually need to
have what people refer to as the
botanical drug substance the BDS the
full whole plant extract that contains
both the terpenes major cannabinoids but
then also the minor cannabinoids as well
those seem to be playing an interesting
role that people are working to figure
out at this point but it's sort of at
the nascent stages yeah yeah yeah I
think that it's interesting because you
know the folks who are selling CBD
isolate as a cure-all they refer to all
of the great things that CBD can do and
they refer to the studies but the
studies are not using CBD isolate the
studies are always using CBD in the
presence of THC and other cannabinoids
and so they're they're referring to
these studies which are not actually
talking about isolate to support their
isolate which is which is a challenge
but you know they're marketing people
and they're trying to sell their CBD
isolate and and yet when it comes right
down to it it's it's it's not a product
that's going to get you where you want
to go so that's interesting I had not
realized that that the the wholesale
prices for isolate had had crashed so
much do you think that that there are
any good uses for CBD isolate I'm sure
there are I personally haven't found any
it's not something that has been very
effective but I will also say that from
my own personal experience at certain
certain cultivars of CBD rich cannabis
plants don't work very well either it's
it's really
about finding something that works
really really well for your particular
condition and unfortunately a lot of
this is still clouded in mystery and
just in part because you know the plants
change environmental conditions change
the overall composition even if you're
working with a clone and realistically I
don't think the analytical capabilities
of many of the labs are on par with what
we need to be able to identify all of
the substances that are actually
medically useful for particular
conditions amen you know where we have
problems all the way down the line right
we've got labs that need to get more
complex we need more research in it and
also each plant has got its variables
and each human has their own variables
so we're talking about highly
personalized medicine here which needs a
lot more research you know I talked
about not being a fan of CBD isolate
from hemp when when I'm doing public
speaking and I always get somebody who
wants to argue with me and and and I
have to be open to two possible
applications of CBD isolate which can be
helpful to patients one is that it seems
that CBD isolate it tends to work with
for some people with eczema and
psoriasis topically I've got patients
that I've talked to who they aren't
taking any other form of whole plant
cannabinoid or THC or anything they're
just using that topically and they've
gotten some good anecdotal results so
I'm open to that being a possibility and
also patients who can't afford as much
cannabidiol as they need they may be
taking a like a whole plant tincture and
also may be smoking some and so they're
getting all this whole plants so they're
getting a wide variety of cannabinoids
but then they're also taking some CBD
isolate to kind of spike how much CBD
they're getting each day each day and
that you know spiking in in the
environment of all this other whole
plant I kind of got to be open to that
potentially being you know offering some
benefit to I think yeah yeah definitely
but again it's for most of these things
that's you're dealing with the entre
effect and in a case with psoriasis
psoriasis and eczema you're dealing with
a whole new set of cannabinoid receptors
that have not been investigated properly
that happened to exist in her dermal
layer so again it's just all kinds of
every time we uncover something new
it raises 50 new questions and that's
the beauty of being sort of out on the
out on the outskirts of something new
and fun and if it's hard that patients
need to be so flexible at this point and
also be doing so much research right
because when you're a patient you may
not have a lot of money you may not have
the wherewithal to be doing all this
research and yet the cure that you need
if somewhere in all of this all these
data points and all this education that
it has to happen and so I come across
folks who have spent hundreds of dollars
on the wrong products and then they get
frustrated and then they go back to
their pharmaceuticals or you know it's
just it it's so frustrating to see the
people who are at most risk in our
society not being able to get clean
information because in some instances
the plants aren't developed and in other
instances the research hasn't been done
and so there's so much anecdotal
information that people are making
serious buying decisions based on
totally totally it's it's a problem and
you know it's it's both a problem and a
blessing and a curse
it's difficult for people to get good
information and to have I'd say a
consistent treatment regimen for
whatever it is that they also definitely
an issue and the normal answer in the
United States and in other countries to
deal with that is to go to the
pharmaceutical route and in the United
States you know the FDA drug approval
process is one that is incredibly
reductionist it's sort of the worst
aspects of the 20th century ideas about
science and in methods that you can
possibly dream up and cannabis is by its
very nature in its internal synergy in
the way that it works with with people
it ends up challenging that that very
reductionist approach which means that
it's incredibly difficult for a large
pharmaceutical company to step in and
come up with a particular formulation
that
can be replicated over and over and over
and actually work that involves all of
the compounds that you would find in in
a whole whole plan to extract so both
good in the sense that you know it's
very complicated but also bad in the
sense that it's it's really hard to nail
down
yeah well said so we're going to we're
going to hit the pharmaceutical industry
as a whole after the break but before
the break I know you are a a scotch how
would I like say you're at a medicinal
hemp breeder because what you breed is
kind of different right you're taking
you're taking medicinal strains and
crossing them with traditionally
industrial hemp to create this kind of
you know hybrid that grows fast and
close to each other but also has got
great Terps and a high CBD percentage so
what what do you what do you call what
you grow oh man I'm just a farmer
alright it's I would say that what we
are doing and I it's not just us or
there are others who are participating
in this kind of craft Renaissance we're
trying to create cannabinoid rich
terpene rich plants that can be grown
grown in it on an industrial scale and a
lot of that is just being made possible
under the farm bill with less
restrictive canopy requirements and you
know basically just a federal legal
framework to operate under it allows us
to you know at this point we have we're
running a test field right now we have
30,000 plants out there on four foot
centers we can go through and identify
the standout candidates that are really
doing interesting things not only with
the terpene profiles the cannabinoid
profiles but also on the agronomic side
we we're a breeding company that's
trying to not only make oil-rich plants
but also make those plants flower at the
right time you know once you step
outside of you know growing in a small
space or in your backyard and you you
apply industrial agricultural techniques
and you know try to do it organically
and responsibly as possible
you run into a whole host of new issues
so like I was mentioning before this is
just one of those avenues within the
legalization framework that that's
coming out and what's what's really
driving our work on the on the terpene
and cannabinoids side is the demand as
you were mentioning before the market is
actually demanding terpene rich plants
rather than these these these isolate
compounds so I've got a really nerdy
question for you so a lot of people take
a shot at CBD from hemp by saying that
CBD from hemp is bad because there's so
little CBD in any particular industrial
hemp plant that you have to extract from
just acres and acres of plant material
in order to get a viable amount of CBD
for sale and that is dangerous because
hemp is an exceptionally good heavy
metal and toxin aggregator from the soil
it just pulls it out of the soil which
is why they use hemp to clean up the
areas around toxic spills and such now
on the other side people are crowing
about CBD from medical plants but at the
end of the day they're both cannabis
sativa and are in pull from the earth so
is there a difference in the botany
between industrial hemp pulling up
toxins out of the soil versus medical
cannabis plants pulling toxins out of
the soil if the toxins are there they
will be bio accumulated what we have
seen there's a really interesting paper
that was put out as a white paper from
the Canada Safety Institute organization
that was put together
Mowgli homes with Philo's was one of the
one of the originators of the group and
they did some some work on heavy metal
accumulation in cannabis plants and
they're there of actual final analysis
was that it's not
something that we need to worry about
I'm I'm it's something I'm very worried
about I'm moving forward but I think
it's less of a problem than just
traditional agricultural pesticides one
of the things that we've seen in Oregon
and I do want to give Oregon just a
little bit of a little bit of a mention
here because I think in some ways we are
doing things very right on the from a
safety perspective with cannabis testing
testing of products we have some of the
most rigorous pesticide screens in the
world at this point for cannabis
products and what we're finding is that
even the people who are doing everything
exactly right who did not spray anything
on their plants who are operating
biodynamically and organically and then
just farming farming in a sustainable
way they still end up getting
contaminated and it's not because of
anything they've done it's because of
just how pervasive pesticides and
herbicides are in the environment and
widely used in in agricultural areas
that I think is something to be very
very concerned about and to be honest
that's why you see so much of the
industrial hemp from other countries
getting turned into isolate it's because
of contamination from from pesticides
right on I'll buy that so let's go ahead
and take our second break when we come
back we're going to be talking about the
opportunities in the pharmaceutical
industry with CBD you are listening the
shaping fire and my guest today is
cannabis policy analyst Seth Crawford if
you grow cannabis with sunshine you can
often feel limited by the seasonal cycle
you want to grow sustainably and save
money so you use as little electricity
as possible but if you haven't studied
or implemented light deprivation
techniques into your greenhouse you're
leaving a lot of money on the table by
incorporating light deprivation
solutions into your greenhouse you can
often add two or three additional
growing cycles to your year when you
pencil out the financial benefit of
those additional cycles you'll realize
why commercial scale light deprivation
technology is remaking the cannabis
industry what used to be done by pulling
tarps over hoop houses has been scaled
up over the last few years in such a way
that it's become mechanized easy and
affordable to even small-scale
commercial cannabis operations
forever flowering greenhouses is the
industry leader in light deprivation
greenhouse design in operation for the
commercial cannabis industry their team
of greenhouse experts have been in the
fields of Northern California for
decades and they're now building
greenhouses for commercial cannabis
companies across the country if you are
new to light DEP and growing in
greenhouses I encourage you to go back
to shaping fire episode 13 with guest
eric Branstad of Forever flowering I
talked with Eric about the importance of
intelligent greenhouse management as
well as the huge financial benefit of
incorporating light depth techniques
there are so many aspects of utilizing a
greenhouse that can go wrong from
temperature and airflow to light depth
and workflow forever flower and will
help you produce crop after crop of
well-cared-for flowers they can help you
retrofit your existing greenhouse with
light depth and other modern systems at
a level that fits your budget if you're
just starting out forever flowering can
help you plan and build your new
greenhouse so that you get started on
the right foot the candidates business
has enough risks without trying to go it
alone with your greenhouse contact
forever flowering greenhouses to partner
with folks who have an indisputable
reputation as knowledgeable and easy to
work with go to shaping fire calm board
/ FFG to find out more as cannabis
normalization sweeps the country
knowledge of how to grow cannabis
naturally and without synthetic inputs
has become more and more available in
fact probiotic growers are experiencing
large yields and exceptional terpene
profiles without using chemicals banned
in their state move away from the risks
inherent to chemical nutrients and
instead invest in your soil use your
soil again and again reducing costs and
improving the vitality of your soil with
each cycle keep it simple organics has
been a leader in aerated compost teas
for years and now provide premium soils
and nutrients to the cannabis industry
they offer a full line of all-natural
inputs for building your soil feeding
microbe communities and brewing nutrient
and compost teas they can even help you
test your soil to spot deficiencies that
may be holding you back check out their
website at Kay eye s organics calm
enter the word Shango into the format
check out to receive 10% off your first
order stop pouring bottled nutrients on
your soil only to throw it out each
cycle start building living soil that
will serve you for years to come visit K
is organics calm and grow healthy
thriving cannabis welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I'm your host
Shanga 'lose and our guest this week is
cannabis policy analyst Seth Crawford so
so far we've talked about how huge the
CBD market is and why it's important to
know your source and that of course is
going to lead us into the opportunities
for the pharmaceutical industry because
the pharmaceutical industry has
certainly seen the promise in CBD and
has begun bringing products to the
market like Sativex from GW
Pharmaceuticals
but medical cannabis activists are very
concerned that if cannabis is made
scheduled too it will leave it solely in
the hands of big pharma which won't
benefit anyone except for big pharma
pocketbooks so Seth what are your
thoughts on the attempts by
pharmaceutical companies to develop and
profit from CBD medicine uh it's
complicated
just like the plant which is what I
really appreciate it
GW Pharmaceuticals is a great example so
they were granted essentially an
monopoly in the UK to do cannabis
research and the research that they have
done is phenomenal it's actually
changing the way that people look at not
only THC but more importantly the
non-psychoactive cannabinoid they have a
world-class breeding program they're in
possession of some absolutely incredible
plants that nobody else has the rest of
us are just basically trying to play
catch-up now the problem with that is
that we're playing catch-up with as I
just mentioned a government-granted
monopoly in the UK and American farmers
American researchers have not had the
ability to to be able to make the
inroads that GW has in the last 15 years
the other issue with this is that
they're trying to basically protect
their long-term profit with the creation
of epidemics it's a 20 to 1
CBD to THC
a compound that is going through
clinical trials in the United States for
Jobeth syndrome for childhood epilepsy
now those are all really good things the
main issue is that now GW
Pharmaceuticals is engaging with
lobbyists in states all across the
country particularly states that do not
have adult use medical or even CBD only
laws in place yet and what they're
trying to do is Lobby those legislators
to pass bills that essentially banned
non-fda-approved CBD anybody who wants
to get a CBD product then in those
states would be required under the state
law to purchase GW Pharmaceuticals
version of that there's a whole host of
other issues that they come along with
that in terms of creating problems for
patients and other types of consumers
but the main issue to me is just from a
supply standpoint GW Pharmaceuticals
just spent 40 million dollars to build
out a brand-new production facility in
California specifically for their CBD
products forty million dollars was how
much it costs them to in the letter that
they sent out to their investors to be
able to produce 1,000 pounds of CBD rich
cannabis per year if they're successful
in being able to lobby CBD products out
of states and they put their own product
on the market and they're only able to
produce a thousand pounds a year I think
we're all going to be in a world of hurt
and we're going to be paying in their
estimates their own financial estimates
anywhere between eighty three dollars
two hundred and sixty six dollars per
gram a thousand pounds that that's not
nearly enough no I mean if they have an
exclusive market that's ridiculously low
for all the people who need it there are
in the state of Oregon we have the
deputy epidemiological estimates are six
hundred and fifteen children with dravet
syndrome just based on on based on
represent representation in the
population that each one of those
children require twelve pounds of
cannabis high-cbd cannabis and we're
talking you know 15% CBD or higher
extracted and turned into oil just to be
able to to meet their needs for a single
year 12 pounds is you know significant
but that's something that that any any
decent industrial hemp farmer who's
growing a high cannabinoid content seed
can do with on one anchor and one acre
of farmland say here in the valley in
Oregon rents for say three hundred three
hundred and fifty dollars the equipment
that it would take to actually go out
and plant and harvest an acre of
cannabis most farmers have it just
sitting around the the scale and the
cost the economics of trying to pursue
some of these different compounds from a
pharmaceutical perspective with all the
regulatory burdens and investors and
that sort of thing is just completely
out of line with what this what this
plant can actually do and what farmers
can do with this plant geez and I mean
just my mind is racing ahead thinking
about if if the pharmaceutical companies
are are successful with their lobbyists
to not allow independent licensed
cannabis producers to to create and
distribute CBD and if they you know two
things will happen number one the the
pharmaceutical companies will have it
locked up and and and so ordinary
law-abiding people will be forced to get
some kind of not whole plant
stripped-down version from the
pharmaceutical company but then what's
really going to happen is that the the
gray market for CBD is just going to
explode because most people know that
they want whole plant CBD and they and
they don't don't want it from a
pharmaceutical company what a what a
enforcement and legal mess that would be
completely it gets even more complicated
you know as it always does who in it
states have the ability to regulate
their own medicines as well and that's
why the that's why GW has gone after
individual states trying to pass these
laws rather than trying to do it at the
national level
they're definitely lobbying Congress and
the FDA and the DEA on a regular basis
to be able to make their product the
only one available but at the end of the
day you know there there's always been a
lot of people growing cannabis and that
was the reason that it made you know
enforcement of any type of prohibition
impossible and right now the genie is
completely completely out of the bottle
on with hemp production and all other
forms of cannabis production at the
state level I think it's going to be
very difficult for for any
pharmaceutical company if they don't
have a very unique product that works
incredibly well and they can get get
doctors to be able to prescribe it I
think they're going to have a very
difficult time in recouping all those
millions and millions of dollars they've
put into to research um you know GW
Pharma is one of the companies who are
working on CBD products do you have an
idea of how many other pharmaceutical
companies I have got CBD products in the
works not CBD products specifically but
there are the last time I checked the
Federal Register
there were over 60 different companies
that had registered with the DEA to be
able to produce cannabinoid products
under the new there was a call for
proposals that the DEA put out for
basically new product development and
production to increase the total supply
of cannabis that was available for
researchers through the National
Institute on Drug Abuse apparently the
University of Mississippi's 12 acres is
not enough and stuff that they have
there is not is not good enough to to
meet all the researchers demands but
what it what it's led to is a pretty big
explosion of mostly small but also some
medium-sized firms entering into the
cannabinoid pharmaceutical marketplace
so to go back to your one example with
GW Pharma they spent 40 million on the
series of greenhouses to to grow I think
you said a thousand pound
of over 15% CBD a year will they simply
just scale up and and produce more of
those to reach demand or or does scaling
up at those numbers not work to bring
the price down yeah it's what we're
dealing with is the demand and the need
is is so much higher than what could be
what could be achieved with a closed
system in and the reason that GW had to
spend so much money on that is all the
security requirements that go along with
producing a Schedule one compound
you know the greenhouses have to be
completely secure that the product
facility has to be spotless and you know
cameras everywhere everyone has to be
monitored at all times you know if you
come out to our farm it's a field full
of plants and we don't have any of that
stuff except for a time-lapse camera
because we just like watching what
happens to the plants either this isn't
a totally different environment and and
you know a lot of the other farmers that
are doing this have scaled in a similar
way you just like I was mentioning
before you can't provide CBD to all the
arthritic horses in greenhouses it's
just not going to work I think that's a
really good point you made because the
idea you know you know the way that GW
is doing it with all of the you know the
fences and security and the cameras and
all the stuff it is it's an assumption
that it's still a prohibitive or-or-or
criminal drug that people are going to
be you know wild drug-crazed people are
gonna be trying to break in to steal all
the stuff that won't get them high at
all you know yeah it's just you know
yeah it still might be cannabis and yeah
the tab you might still be out there but
but you know people do not routinely
steal CBD because their patients and
they're generally too sick sick to steal
anything yeah yeah it's again I mean
this goes back to that that tripartite
division when you've got folks that are
developing pharmaceutical products you
have people that are developing
recreational products and you have
people who are just doing things a
little bit differently on the agronomic
side
but I think there is always going to be
a market for the types of products that
these these cannabinoid pharmaceutical
research companies are putting together
and I think that it's really important
for us to may not necessarily support a
company that you know got to their spot
in their market position via a natural
monopoly in another country before
Americans could actually do the research
on it but I think it's also important to
to see the benefits that have come out
of that research because I mean as a
plant breeder
I read the work that GW pharmaceutical
breeders wrote they published these
these articles in peer-reviewed journals
about how to attain different types of
cannabinoids and plants and after that
it just became an analytical and a
sifting process for us to to find those
things so it's they're doing good things
but when you turn it into a monopoly and
you try to control access to something
that is already proliferating throughout
the country I
that's when I start to have issues and
question the question the motives oh
that's an awesome transition to our last
topic which is I to read the GW Pharma
papers because I wanted to find out what
was in Sativex
and when when it comes right down to it
it's it's essentially roughly two point
five milligrams of THC and two point
five milligrams of CBD in an oral spray
that you're supposed to take as needed
up to like five times a day and you know
that's so easy to reverse engineer into
an alcohol tincture and then move you've
got whole plant sativex that you made at
home one thing for sure the gray market
will be providing CBD to neighbors and
family and loved ones probably forever
now that CBD genetics are all over the
country do you think there's any model
that would quell people from growing and
sharing their own CBD with sick friends
now that the genetics are everywhere the
only thing that would make sense is that
you can walk into a store and buy the
product
and you don't have to grow it prepare it
and you know basically compound the the
substance to give to your friends and
family and if you walk into most stores
at this point those products are already
on the Shelf when it comes to CBD and I
guess and the the challenge of course is
the model that we you and I were just
discussing where where CBD you know go
scheduled to and isn't solely in the
hands of pharmaceutical companies that
would theoretically put pressure on the
states to to remove CBD from their
licensing structure which I don't know
how that would work but the idea is that
you just can't limit availability of CBD
because if you put any restriction on it
the people will will work around it
because their health is way more
important to people than following the
law 100% accurate I'm looking at this
this move by GW Pharmaceuticals and
reaching out to the farmers that we work
with here in Oregon and saying you know
they're going to go forward with this
and and keep this is something to keep
in mind as well with just the way that
the laws are written as I'd mentioned
the state's actually do have a little
bit of control over over drugs it's not
just the FDA so if you're manufacturing
a product in your state and it that
product does not leave your state it's
sold within the boundaries and under the
legal framework of your state the FDA
can't do anything to step in and say hey
you can't do that unless you're making
medical claims so in the case of CBD and
say children with dravet syndrome we
could just give it away which I mean
from a perspective of seeing cannabis
culture change now that it's been
permeated by by legal in a legalization
and the forces that come along with with
modern late-stage capitalism to me
that's that's a bit of beautiful
beautiful contribution to kind of keep
in line with what the people who kept
cannabis alive during the Prohibition
would want to have happen
so I honestly I think companies like GW
need to be very careful with their
approach because people have people have
have the ability to to undermine what
they're trying to do you know
mechanisation doesn't work I don't think
people have been saying free the plant
for all these decades free the plant for
pharmaceutical companies you know they
they wanted it back in the hands of the
citizens amen
yeah it's I agree with that and at the
same time I also it's I'm going to
hammer at home one more time the
research that they're doing is stuff
that you know I have a PhD and know how
science works I can't do what these
these big companies are doing they're
doing some really incredible work and
they should be able to to get that
product in the hands of people who could
benefit from it and they they deserve to
make some money off of it but total
control of the marketplace is not
something that should ever be ceded to
any any individual or corporation right
on well set thank you so much for taking
the time to be on the show it's really
nice to talk to somebody who's got a
command of the economics of the CBD
market like you do because so much of
the talk around CBD is just myth and
rumor and people playing the telephone
game with facts so to be able to come
and talk to somebody like you who has
done doctoral research in this and is
essentially an uber nerd is very
refreshing so thank you so much for your
time thank you so much for having me you
can find out more about Seth Crawford at
oregon CBD seeds calm you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shaping fire
calm and on Apple iTunes stitcher and
Google Play if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where i will be
speaking you can check out shank
lowes.com does your company want to
reach our national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host Shango Lowe's
[Music]