[Music]
providing your own cannabis is exploding
across the united states
some folks are self-contained growing
and smoking their own flower
some neighbors are working in small
groups with some neighbors growing while
others are turning the flower into
edibles
tincture bubble hash and hash rosin
there are so many options for making
high quality cannabis products without
expensive equipment or hydrocarbons
communities of cannabis patients and
enthusiasts are coming together to be
self-sufficient
if you want to learn about cannabis
health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer
i encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week
and videos too don't rely on social
media to let you know when a new episode
is published
sign up for the updates to make sure you
don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive the newsletter
this month regenerative farming nutrient
company everflux
is giving away their full line of
products to one lucky subscriber
you'll receive a full-size bottle of
their bio flux fermented plant booster
their bamboo wood vinegar bio stimulant
and a big old bucket of terraflux their
infused biochar blend you'll get all
three
make sure to listen to their commercial
during the first break to learn more
go to shapingfire.com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month's and all future newsletter prize
drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and i
am your host shango los
today my guest is ganja gill the ice
wook
i connected with gil after watching a
video of him giving best practices for
making regeneratively minded hash
at the dragonfly earth medicine hive
gathering earlier this year
gill is a lifelong cannabis cultivator
and hashmaker he's your hashmaker's
hashmaker
his hard to find hash and hash rosin are
sought after by heads throughout
california
gill is incredibly difficult to connect
with he lives way out in the forest and
doesn't often return to town
we eventually were able to connect via
satellite phone to record this episode
for you
today we're going to talk about
fine-tuning your ice water hash
production
some tricks of the trade and why making
quality hash is a love language
welcome to the show gill
thank you very much jango i really
really appreciate it thank you so much
awesome so let's get right into it you
know a lot of people the first thing
that they learn about when they when
they start trying to figure out how
they're gonna make ice hashes
at home is um about hash bags right
and you know hash bags have now been
around a long time
and of course there are the original
bubble bags um
and and now there's a whole bunch of
knockoffs and actually some of the
knockoffs are pretty damn good
too um i'm curious uh you know for
yourself
what do you look for when you are buying
a uh a hash bag you know i i know you
know
my first set was a you know bottom mesh
and i liked that but now i'm seeing
these new ones
that have got mesh on all sides and i
kind of covet those as well
so what are your thoughts
i'm just a frugal person by nature if
you know me
that's just how i am i try to garden um
as inexpensively as possible and
when it comes to extraction i kind of
think the same thing
um i don't try to cut corners per se
but i am often making this in a home
setting i'm not really in a lab like
situation so again
um not necessarily cutting corners but
i'm also not trying to spend tens of
thousands of dollars to accomplish
what i'm trying to do so having said
that
affordability is important to me
personally
simply because if you wash fresh frozen
material
you're gonna destroy bags um just the
way it goes
unfortunately um you can stay on top of
cleaning your bags
which i do um but eventually
the bags get ruined they don't last
forever you know if you're washing dried
material
they seem to last longer in my
experience but uh
you know uh typically they just don't
last forever so i see some bags out
there these days that
are getting more and more expensive and
personally they kind of
turn me off just to the extent that i
see them as disposable
having said that at the same time if
you're washing as much material as i am
it's very small expense the bags in the
grand scheme of things so
i'm kind of being vague i'm not giving a
real straight answer right now
but i personally do use bubble bags um
they've always worked for me i've been
using them almost 20 years now
they give me good results
they last long enough i can get them for
a very affordable price
i like them for that reason i've seen
now
marcus just dropped all side mesh walls
i
am interested in trying those i would
like to try those but uh
what were you gonna say buddy i was
gonna say when you're looking at
bags um are you looking primarily at the
like the quality of the stitching and
the material itself and whether or not
it's a bottom or a sidewall
or is there something else um you know
another variable that you look at in
addition to that
no that's very important you know the
stitching is probably mainly what it is
like to me
you can kind of get a good gauge on how
quality something's made by looking at
the actual stitching
um stitching is good materials that
they're made is good
if you want to get really really
technical you know you magnify
you look under a microscope at the
actual mesh
um i will say that that not all mesh is
created equal
people are using less professional mesh
than others and then some people are
using really professional mesh um
like companies that are using more
accurate micron
sizing sizing that is inaccurate so if
it's a 90
u bag then the spacing is is for 90 u
i have found sometimes looking at other
brands real close under the scope
it might not be what they're claiming it
to be
and that could be just from simple error
or just using more generic screen but
to me that is important you want to be
actually
capturing what you are intending to
capture for sure
so bags are important but like
i've made great cash with all bags
that's kind of where
i'm at is like i don't really want to
hop on the hype train there's a
particular brand of bags out there that
i'm not going to mention
that everyone promotes and personally me
i had a terrible customer service
experience with them
it really turned me off i will not use
that product anymore because
that's just what type of stubborn
[ __ ] i am you know so again
me personally i don't put much weight in
the bags
you know obviously there's a certain
level of quality that should be brought
but at the end of the day i've had
people send me these random bags from
random people
it's a bag you know what i mean like to
me
that's not gonna make it or break it for
you personally
again i stand by bubble man's product
there's definitely other ones out there
that are decent
i'd be scared of anything with a really
high ticket item
um but i'd also be scared to maybe use
something that was extremely um
inexpensive i think what's really
important first and foremost
is just clean the [ __ ] out of your bags
when you get them when you get your bags
clean them clean them clean them clean
them clean them
12 times if you have to because i've had
to before i've cleaned bags before
you go to do a wash and then you see
fibers and in your product and there's
nothing more disheartening
than to go months of growing as in
extracting the resin and then looking
down and realizing the bags that you
purchased have actually contaminated the
resin that you just harvested you know
to me that is just
the biggest kick in the nuts i've
experienced so again personally
you know not all bags are created equal
but uh don't trip out on what bags you
have available to you
you know just make sure they're nice and
clean seem solid
and that's really what's all that's
important to me personally i do like
this
the mesh side walls the all mesh as
someone who works by themselves
that's something i kind of just started
playing with this past year
i'm excited to see that bubble man came
out with some
they save your back you know if you're
pulling large
washes by yourself all day every day
those all mesh ones are definitely
really nice in my opinion there's
something to be said for them for sure
so you know there are there are
different sizes of sets
and everybody kind of has their own
thoughts on what their favorite bags
you know favorite you know micron bags
are to use
and uh you know i i uh you know my first
set was a nine set
and there were several of the bags that
i just never freaking used and now you
get people who are selling
you know you know three four five bag
sets
um and you know they cost a little bit
less so you're not paying money for bags
that you're not using
um what are your thoughts as far as how
many bags
are are you know the best to buy do you
use all nine of yours or you're like you
know in the end we're probably only
gonna use
four so a four set will be the way to go
it's a really good question um to me it
just depends what your goals are what
you're trying to do
um me personally i make a lot of hash
rosin
but i also make a lot of just hash melt
to me they are two different things so i
wash for them differently um
if you're watching for more of a full
spectrum hash rosin type situation
less bags is the way um if you're
looking
for more of a melt situation to me
is use all the bags you possibly can
and sometimes you don't know what you're
trying to make you know that the the
strain or the cultivar you're using
dictates what you're gonna make you know
so
if you're gonna wash something for the
first time sometimes i tell people do a
test wash and use all your bags
use all your bags that will give you a
lot of information
it'll show you where it dumped and where
it didn't dump and then it might let you
know you know what
there wasn't really all that much 73
anyways in there so we could negate that
bag and throw it into the 90 if we
wanted to and again that's just
hypothetical situation that i'm
describing
i would probably very rarely put the 73
in the 90 but
again uh there's just situations that
you wouldn't really know until you wash
and then you know
what the size of the heads are and where
it's spinning and whatnot
but uh more bags for melt less bags for
rosin
i never use a 25 u-bag
to me that just slows down the uh the
draining and i've never grabbed anything
from a 25 micron bag that i felt like
was worth
you know keeping personally so uh
you know if i'm gonna do a full spectrum
hash wash i'll typically you know
washington 220 i keep the 190
the 160 the 90
and the 45. it's pretty much
those four bags that i'm filtering
through for the full spectrum raw
uh ash rosin and when it comes to the
melt like i said i'm gonna use all eight
of those bags
right on so um do you really think that
they're
like as far as like making connoisseur
grade
versus regular toker grade um
outside of you know the little uh the
little pieces of material that might get
in your finished
product which of course sucks and as
you've already referred to
you know in cp i would think that um
mediocre bags plus good technique
could make killer hash the same way that
great bags
and crappy technique could equal poor
hash
and so i generally encourage people to
buy the bags that fit their budget
but go heavy on care preparation and
technique
does that do you you know does that make
sense to you
that totally makes sense to me and that
is where i
am at with mechanical extraction um
growing cannabis and extracting it
inflates egos it's just
something that i've come across in my
life it's how it goes
i don't know what it is about the nature
of growing cannabis but it does that
and i'm just here to say i really really
try to portray
that i have no ego when it comes to this
it is always the ganja doing the
performance
it is always the ganja that is
turning heads impressing people
mechanical extraction
is simply not that hard
anyone can do it it's like cooking is
what i like to
describe it to people some people are
better at cooking than others that's
just the way it is
to me the people that are better at
cooking are just better at following
directions
and then they might even have a little
bit of passion about it as well to add
to it
um anyone can mechanically extract
if you have passion about it you're
going to pursue it with more passion and
more focus and more drive and yeah
you'll probably be better at someone
who's being forced to do it for an
hourly wage job which
doesn't make sense to me but it's
probably going on somewhere in the world
but uh
the end of the day it's not that hard to
mechanically extract
anyone can do it what it comes down to
is the material the material the
material
if you're extracting great material it's
going to be easy
if you've got some mediocre stuff it's
just always going to be mediocre so
yes you can extract make amazing hash
with decent bags and great cannabis with
decent cannabis and great bags good luck
so um actually the first time that i
came across you
i was actually watching a video and you
were talking about the choosing a
material and that's when i first got
turned on i'm like oh this guy really
approaches making ice hash in the way
that
in a way that i value you were talking
about how
um you know you were talking about some
of the attributes that you
you look for when choosing hash but then
you also said
as you've kind of referred to earlier
already that that
the ganja will tell you you know what
application will be best for it and what
bags to use so
so i'm going to kind of give you this
like you know broad question
and so that you can kind of take us
through your thought process
how do you choose material and when
you're when you're examining material
to potentially wash what are you looking
for
so that's a good question um i'm in a
different situation with people
then to be honest currently i am only
focused and for years now i've only been
focused on
processing my own material that i grow
myself so
it's kind of easier answer than could be
where it's like i freeze everything i
grow
and i wash everything i grow so it's not
really
um a debate of hey am i going to wash
this or not if
i'm growing it i'm washing it um and
again
i am only washing my own material uh so
i'm not really going to other farms and
looking and seeing like oh is this
potentially something i should wash
that's not really necessarily going on
because that's not what i'm doing with
my time
but i do just in theory walk a lot of
farms and wonder hey would this wash
with that wash
and to me it comes down to
two things it's the texture of the resin
and the structure of the flower
that's what i'm looking for first and
foremost you know if i can touch that
resin
and i can see heads on my hand you know
it's that dry
eye um resin that you can literally just
touch a flower
move your hand and you will see heads on
your fingertips you know uh
it's not that super sticky resin that
like just so sticky that it just leaves
like i said just
a smear on your hand in there you won't
see the heads
um and then also a
a structure of flour that exposes a lot
of surface area is how i describe it
not necessarily really large dense
spheres but stuff that actually
exposes the surface area um
you know allowing the material to to
come off
basically you know making it where it
gives it up
when i prep the material that's another
big part of the process as well is
you really want to break the stuff down
as much as you possibly can
you know certain structure of flower
allows you to break it down
naturally to very small and then other
structure of flower it's really big
and it just doesn't lend itself to being
broken all the way down
um but those are the two things that i
look for first and foremost is
basically the the texture of the resin
and the structure of the flower
and then obviously i'm i'm forgetting
just the smell
the overall aroma and smell you know of
something isn't
appealing to me uh the smell i don't
really care about washing it you know
what i mean even if it's the greatest
resin in the world
many years ago we all used to wash a
bunch of ogre and it was like oh it
dumped ogre
it was just so much resin it was white
it was great
just didn't really have much of a smell
or anything to now we've all forgotten
about it at this point you know it's
kind of got to be
terpe first and foremost especially in
you got to come with something really
loud and
something to get your attention these
days
right on so those are those are good i
um
suggestions for you know if we're
shopping around for
a flower that we're gonna run or for
confirming the flower that we already
have that we want to run it
i do like this idea though which um you
know
i had not come across before i talked to
you about somebody who
who exclusively grows their own stuff
and then washes their own stuff
for for people who are listening who
like that idea
um you know when you are choosing
the uh the the flower that you're gonna
grow for a season you know if you're
gonna run a bunch of it that's
that's a lot of commitment to grow a lot
of that one plant so
do you for example run a couple
trial plants you know summer one
and then if you like it you you know you
start earlier in the season and may and
and start those plants again and clone
them and put them
into your grow so that you have it in
volume
the next year um i guess that's kind of
a way for me to back into how do you
choose
what cultivars you're going to run
um since i know that you're an uh
primarily an
outdoor guy i kind of think that
generally you need to
test it one summer and then go big with
it the following summer unless you've
got a different technique
no that's uh that's smart that's uh that
would be a very
well calculated way to do it um
i am blessed enough to live in you know
the cannabis hub of the world in my
opinion which is humboldt county
and i'm surrounded by ganja people who
you know all we do is talk speak eat
sleep ganja and fortunately through that
there is just certain cultivars out
there
that we know perform and hash
mechanical extraction um over the years
there's
just kind of been tried and true ones
that we all know work
fortunately people have then begun
breeding with those same tried and true
strains so
you know there's certain genetics that
you begin to be familiar with
and then you know that they perform um
a lot of clone only strains are floating
around humboldt county that
we've all determined you know these ones
washed these ones don't wash
um so fortunately i'm in that position
where i have access to solid genetics
that
you know myself and others have tried
over the years and we
know they perform um now
having said that over the years
i have been growing a lot of these what
i call them now classics you know
classic
mechanical extraction strains uh classic
uh
you know solventless strains like you
know garlic cookies gmo we all know a
dumps
strawberry banana we all know a dumps
key lime pie it works great you know
there's
cookies and cream you know there's all
these different things out there gorilla
glue
sour diesel you know we can just keep
naming them wedding cake
all the cakes you know so there's
different things that we
know for a fact wash um
so it's really easy to plant those and
just know um
i will say learn from my mistakes and
don't put all your eggs in one basket
you know
don't grow one varietal grow multiple
you know grow you know as many as you
can within reason you know that can
become a problem too just having too
many things that becomes a burden so
you know i think diversity is definitely
a good approach um definitely running
some tried and true
things is always wise as far as a
business goes
but i'm not going to pretend that
i don't chase um terps
and there is something extremely
exciting
about growing strains that you don't
know
that they're gonna wash maybe you got it
from a breeder you know there's a lot of
breeders these days
we're breeding for hash you know
awning noodles hairy palms exotic
genetic mics
you know they're all these different
guys uh that are out there that are
breeding strictly for hash so
to me there's these sure bets where you
can get the clones that you know wash
you can try to get the seeds from the
guy who's breeding for hash
but like i'm not going to lie like right
now my second round is
all seeds they're all seeds all
different phenos
um yeah i'm doing it with the intention
that hopefully it all washes
but i don't know you know they're
definitely hashy crosses
so some of them are gonna come but some
of them are not
and that's kind of just the life of a
hashmaker
you know as a hashmaker i have eaten it
many times thrown thousands of dollars
in barrels
to get nothing you know that's just kind
of uh
the nature of being a hashmaker there is
definitely
some faith involved and to me you have
to be
in it for reasons that you know
you have some questions that you want
answered or you have some things that
you want to discover yourself
potentially
and that's why you're doing it you're
doing the research through washing it
and it's not all home runs it's not all
grand slams
it's very much ups and downs and that's
just
the way it goes i was talking to a guy
at the um at an after party after
emerald cup and i actually don't know
his name but um
he said to me he says the worst hash he
makes
is hash that he's making for money and
the best hash that he
makes is stuff that he's making because
he's passionate about the cultivar
or he's making it for he and his friends
to smoke
yeah no that makes total sense to me
personally you know it's all about
intention in life
it really is tell a lot of people you
know cannabis
yeah can make money you know totally
this industry
is profitable i'm not gonna try to act
like it's not
but the people that flock here strictly
for profits
strictly for money i tell them all
all the time like there's so much easier
ways in this life to make money
if you really your sole focus is to make
money
don't get involved in cannabis there's
easier ways to get money
money comes and money goes um cannabis
yeah you can get rich growing it but the
people who come here
solely for the money they fail they
leave
you know they they spend lots of money
and uh
have these like you know crazy ideas
but it doesn't seem to pan out to those
people in my opinion you know it's like
to me you know passion and cannabis
are intertwined you know it's this thing
where
i pursue it because that's what i choose
to do you know the money is like a
a secondary thing that just comes along
with it to be honest you know but
what keeps me interested in cannabis is
cannabis you know it's
it's the biggest rabbit hole that ever
existed in my opinion
and you know uh we can go down any road
talk about anything you know you want to
talk about soil nutrients you know
environment
strains you know like extraction is just
another one and that's just a small
piece of it there's so many
other facets of extraction that we can
talk about you know so
uh you know extraction is just one way
to uh
to look into cannabis you know to look
at it more closely
to learn more about it it's just a way
to focus your intent is how i see it you
know like
as a cannabis grower what are you trying
to do what are you trying to say you
know there's so many different avenues
that you could be
taking you know are you trying to
produce for flower are you trying to
grow the most
are you trying to grow just a little bit
like what are your intentions you know
me personally once i started focusing
towards hash it just all made sense to
me
everything clicked it was like oh this
is it this is why i'm growing is for
this
they're different things in my opinion
growing for extraction and growing for
flower production you know they kind of
lead different lives
yeah that's a i can see how that is also
like the perspective of a true
you know passionate artisan right when
you're doing it for your heart
as as as well as surviving and i
personally think it's really great you
know
as as really premium hash
rosins and uh and even melt
become increasingly popular in the scene
it's nice to see high quality product
fetching good prices from a lot of
people
now um you know that there's always been
a hash market but this
you know the the the market for elite
hash
and really good hash rosin is certainly
exploding right now and
is becoming this you know increasingly
large part
of our scene the last question i want to
ask you about the choosing of material
is uh
do you have any uh insight on uh washing
indoor material versus washing outdoor
material
i'll talk to you about that we could
talk about that all day if you wanted to
shackle we could just go back and forth
now that is a that is a interesting
subject to me personally because yes for
the past uh
i think it's seven years now i've been
cultivating solely outdoors you know i
hung up the indoor towel i've only been
outdoors for
seven years you know running some
nursery inside here and there
some moms and stuff like that but i
haven't really flowered indoors in years
now
um and there's definitely this
you know thing going around i feel like
in the community
where people are convinced
indoor flower is superior than outdoor
flower and therefore
indoor grown resin is superior than
outdoor grown resin
um me personally i do not
believe that could be further from the
truth um
indoor will always you know
require a higher ticket because
it has a higher overhead and i am not
going to argue with that you know if
something costs more to produce inside
okay cool you know get more for it you
know
can you grow more aesthetically um
pleasing pretty flowers indoors yeah
you're in a sealed room
you know it's literally sealed you're
not in an outdoor environment
with fluctuating light patterns you know
different weather you know
not to mention insects wind and all of
the above
you know what i mean there is some
things going on outdoors that you just
can't
control you know and yes
we are trying to make clean resin that
is the goal
of a hashmaker is to make very clean
resin that is simply just resin
so obviously that is easier to do
indoors
you're in a sealed environment obviously
it's easier to keep contaminant
out of indoor grown resin it's just a
fact
so you know a lot of people i know who i
see extracting indoors
i'm like you should be doing melt all
you should do is make melt because
it's so easy to make clean melt in an
indoor situation it's not grown outside
with the dust flying around and
everything else you know so
indoor it's very easy in my opinion
to create clean resin for sure
however the sun produces terpene levels
and compounds and flavors and things
that no lamb could ever do i just don't
believe it so
i see these terp results and these um
even just uh potency tests from same
cultivars grown outside versus inside
and the terp levels are quadrupled
to me you can't argue with data
i have very rarely seen like terp levels
that have rivaled
outdoor ones in my experience do they
exist i'm sure
you know but to me
it's easier to grow more
complex uh terpene profiles
outdoors in the great outdoors
and i also will just always stand by the
fact that
there's all these things that come into
play when you're growing outdoors
you know like to me things that i like
to think about you know that to me
are kind of like these romantic ideals
about cannabis growing you know like
i like the idea that cannabis grown in
southern california is different than
northern california and
the stuff in washington is different and
i like to see how humidity and elevation
and you know terroir and all that
plays a role in the production of
cannabis you know indoor growing
is really cool i got awesome homies who
have dedicated their life to it
and they're doing amazing things shout
out to my homies in rhode island
liberty llc they're doing amazing things
with
living soil inside steve cantwell
in vegas green life productions blows my
mind every time i see it i had the
luxury of walking here last summer it
was
one of the greatest indoor facilities
i've ever seen so
i'm not trying to take away from what
people are doing indoors many states
don't allow
outdoor cultivation so you can only do
what you can do
but uh at the end of the day for me
personally
i much rather enjoy working with
outdoor resin typically people grow
larger plants outside
it's all just uh proportional
larger plants mean larger trichome heads
larger yields um
i enjoy working with the resin outdoors
a lot of times
it's more able to be captured
i find a lot of times the stuff indoors
is very greasy
very very hard to capture um
and there's there's great qualities
about that you know there's nothing
wrong with greasy
resin besides the fact that it's hard to
capture you know so
uh there there's great things all around
you know you can grow great resin
indoors and you can grow great resin
outdoors
um i obviously am biased because what
i'm focused on
is growing outside and it's because i
live in a great region for
growing cannabis outdoors um if i wasn't
i would obviously be growing it indoors
um
doesn't bother me that indoor commands a
higher
premium but the whole
rhetoric of indoor
rosin is better because it was grown
indoor
i just think that's [ __ ] you know
like i've seen a lot of indoor stuff
that like
wasn't really turned in my head well
that is
probably the most elegant and insightful
uh comparison of indoor and outdoor that
i have ever heard
um that was beautifully put together and
that's probably informed a lot of folks
and
it's nice too to hear uh a kind of a
summation of the pros and cons
which kind of like le satisfies both the
indoor people
and satisfies the outdoor people since
you spoke to
like the clear advantages of both so
that's great um let's go ahead and take
our first short break
we'll be right back you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today
is hashmaker ganja gill the ice book
for many transitioning to organic
gardening can be overwhelming
there's so much to learn about soil
biology and fermentation
bioflux fermented plant boost from
everflux
simplifies organic farming so you can
start growing organically today
invented by a california farmer growing
organic for 40 years
bioflux is a fermented natural farming
preparation
for those who want a natural micro
booster without having to brew their own
this extraordinary chemical free growth
and terpene enhancer
improves root development accelerates
the conversion of organic matter into
humus
increases nutrient use efficiency and
uptake and increases beneficial microbe
activity
in addition to the bioflux fermented
plant booster
everflux also makes an activated biochar
called terraflux
that is infused with the bioflex plant
booster
imagine combining the buffering and
rhizosphere enhancing qualities of
biochar
infused with a range of earthworm
castings insect frass
kelp and crabmeal oyster shell and other
ingredients
i'm using terraflux infused biochar this
summer myself
and it smells alive rich and potent
these products have been scientifically
proven to match yields and increase
flower quality and pest resistance
when compared to traditional npk inputs
if you are looking for reliable organic
fertilizers that will free you up to
focus on other aspects of your garden
consider using the range of all natural
regenerative fertilizers and natural
biostimulants from everflux
find out more at
everfluxtechnologies.com
or by following their instagram at
everflux
for years organic cultivators have been
looking for a replacement for using peat
moss
peat moss has long been the go-to soil
amendment for water retention and
container growing
but organic growers know that peat moss
is an unsustainable resource
and the mining of peat bogs destroys
habitat and releases sequestered carbon
but peat moss works so well that many
have continued to use it
but now there's finally a revolutionary
replacement for peat moss that shares
the same benefits
while also being sustainable pit moss
sounds and axe like peat moss but
instead of being mined from fragile
ecosystems it actually is made from
upcycled organic paper and tree bark
pit moss is excellent at retaining water
in your substrate and creating air
pockets and
tiny living environments for microbes
pit moss
instantly increases aeration nutrient
absorption
and water conservation too carefully and
locally sourced
pit moss is the result of decades-long
research into the use of recycled paper
fibers
pit moss has the fluffy nature of peat
moss and handles exactly the same
and like peat moss pit moss is inert so
it won't change your ph
available in a range of preparations
including a nutrient enhanced blend
a coco coir blend and also as an organic
soil conditioner with
no added nutrients pit moss is also
available as an
animal bedding so go to pittmoss.com now
to learn more
that's p i t t m o
s s dot com growing healthier
more sustainable plants pit moss
for 20 years humboldt seed company has
been family owned and providing reliable
high yielding seeds originating in
northern california
while the current trend is to slap one
super male into a line of hyped strains
humboldt seed company continues to breed
with precision and care
by doing large sifts and back crosses to
emphasize the absolute
best traits that a line has to offer
this kind of breeding takes time
talent and space to work no matter what
kind of aroma you are particularly into
humboldt seed will likely have something
you'll love if you love fruit
you can choose from banana mango apricot
papaya blueberry blood orange melon and
lemons across their various strains
they have all gas glue and classic sour
diesel lines as well
of course there are the heritage
california strains like og kush
jack hair and headband and their
award-winning blueberry muffin
is one that delights just about
everybody's palette especially when
concentrated
humboldt seed company is proud to bring
to market the infamous freak show
cultivar 2
which has a great thc high but looks so
much like a fern that some folks can't
even identify it as cannabis
it's a plant that really needs to be
seen to be believed
if you're looking for well-balanced cbd
seeds humboldt seed company can turn you
on to cbd strains
that actually have flavor like the dill
and pepper terpenes of willie g's
lebanese land race
whether you are looking for regular
feminized or autoflowers
humboldt seed company has the gear to
make this your best growing cycle
ever visit humboldtseedcompany.com today
to check out their line of vigorous
genetics download their catalog
and find out where you can pick them up
you can also check out their
instagram at the humboldt seed company
to check out their gorgeous flowers and
the extraordinary freak show plant
humboldt seed company let them know
shango sent ya
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host shango los
and our guest this week is hashmaker
ganja gill the ice wook so during the
first set we were talking a lot about
you know
the the types of bags and the materials
that you needed just to kind of like get
us started
but during this second set we're going
to talk a lot more about the actual
process of of manufacturing and
mechanically separating the heads
so um so gil let's start with
temperature of the location
and you know a lot of people you know
have got these
very um very expensive locations
with with like you know a gazillion
watts of air conditioning
and i really like visiting those places
and a lot of really high quality hash
comes out of those locations
at the same time i know that i've hung
out with my friends
and we have washed on a
on a deck you know on a on a summer day
where the where our washing machine is
like
in the shade but we're in the sun and
we're
we're having as much social time and
enjoying ourselves as we are making the
hash
and we've also made good hash not in a
freezing
environment and so my question for you
is is how uh how important do you
see the temperature of the location
being
and and where on that range do you think
that we want to be
both for the the the home
hash maker who's making something for
their head and also
somebody who is planning on on sharing
with their friends maybe even at a price
that's a great question um you know
there's lots of variables in my opinion
um the first and foremost is what are
you washing
you know what what kind of material are
you washing um
decent you know to me if you're gonna
wash fresh frozen
you need a cold room um that's not
every single situation certain strains
have a more
drier resin like gmo or strawberry
banana
you might get away with doing that in a
not cold room
but if you're gonna wash freshly frozen
cannabis
to me you're gonna have a lot easier
time
in a cold room and by a cold room
i mean under 50 degrees if you can keep
it under
50 it's going to be better the colder
the better if you could keep it
mid 35s that's ideal um
i understand that's not really possible
for everybody
such as myself i live in trinity county
um it's mid july i just harvested some
light depth
it's 100 degrees during the day my
little cold room
cannot keep up with the ambient
temperature outside
so it's part of the reason i you know
work and live
seasonally where i am just cultivating
all summer long and i wait for the
colder weather to come in november
before i start processing stuff
that's what works for me i just have a
small room that i wash and it's like a
8x10 room
with just a typical window unit in there
you know buy the biggest window
unit you can afford and i just have a
little cool bot on it it's like a 300
controller that basically just tricks
the air conditioner into
not freezing and it just keeps it
running and cycling below 60 so it'll
get your room cold you know they're used
in all different types of applications
cut flower industry hunters use them
blah blah blah they're out there
um you can definitely also get cold
rooms
um that are affordable you know 3 500
bucks or so for a walk-in that you can
just drop on top of a slab
to me that's affordable um obviously
it's not for some home hash maker
um but i would still encourage you to
try to use a cold space
whether it be your basement your porch
or you wash in the middle of the night
i've done that many times where you know
sleep during the day wash in the middle
of the night it's not that crazy to
someone like me
um but to me if you are washing
freshly frozen material you're gonna be
frustrated doing it
in something that isn't cold um you're
gonna coat your bags
you're gonna hurt your yields
you know even really greasy material in
a cold room can be challenging you know
a lot of times the wedding
cakes and the ice cream cakes and the
stuff that i wash the stuff's just so
greasy by nature that even in a 40
degree room
it's hard you know the difference
between a 45 degree room and a 40 degree
room is a difference
and then one that's 35 it's different
you know
like uh it helps so having
everything be cold cold cold your bag's
cold the water cold your tools cold
everything cold it does help with
washing fresh frozen for sure
if you're gonna wash dried material or
flash
dried material it's not as important in
my
opinion um man i've done so many trim
runs as a young kid like
outside you know uh on porches you know
not in controlled rooms at all and it
was never an issue never an issue at all
so trim run or dried run you know i
flash dried some stuff this past year
and i washed that
the flash dried versus you know i flash
dried
the same strain and then i fresh froze
it just to wash the two
and compare myself just to see the
difference from my own
you know knowledge teaches you a lot i
suggest anyone to do that they're just
trying to like figure it out for
themselves and have some fun you know
take the same material give it a three
to five day dry
and then freeze it and then just fresh
freeze it um
the stuff that has a three to five day
dry it was like
so easy to work with it was like washing
gmo it's just like
you know very easy clean up there's no
contaminant in the hash
it's like you barely have to spray it
clean you know it isn't coat in your
bags it's not coating your
spoons it's like real easy to work with
so if you're gonna work with dried stuff
you don't really need a cold room so
much you know and uh
you know maybe that's what makes the
decision for you
if you're like hey i am in a warm
climate i don't have a cold situation
i would tell you personally you should
probably dry your material if you're
trying to extract it
and that's someone who loves washing
fresh frozen first and foremost
but if you don't have a cold room to do
it man i don't know i'd be a little
nervous dude you know that's just me
personally
like i said no i got freezers right now
of some
stuff that i'm so excited to watch but
i'm not even thinking about it till come
november you know it just
doesn't seem possible when
talking about the final product um
you know it sounds like the process that
you use
is going to be dependent on whether or
not it is fresh frozen or dried
what do you see in the difference of the
final product though
at versus uh fresh frozen and dried
um the first thing that comes to mind is
probably terpenes but
you've certainly seen you know a lot of
um you know head-to-head comparisons of
the
same cultivar being run both ways what
do you see the differences in the final
product
of fresh frozen versus dried
you know they're different um i was just
talking with a buddy the other day
yesterday and uh
to me they're very different um i think
there's just this weird thing going on i
feel like in the cannabis community
where people just love to jump on
bandwagons they don't necessarily have
their own opinion but like they got
someone else's opinion in their pocket
who they respect and they're like oh i'm
gonna use that person's opinion because
i don't know then i align with that
person or something i'm not sure what it
is exactly but
i feel like there's this whole oh
indoors better than outdoor and then
oh fresh frozen is better than dried
and like i was even on that train too
where i was like
you know how would dried material make
better
concentrate i don't believe it
so that's why i started to do it myself
you know who do i trust more than most
people
myself so i was like all right i am
going to personally start drying
material and washing it
even though i don't think i like that
even though i think it might be a waste
of my
time i want to prove to myself
that you know that this is why and i
have reasons to stand by
and through doing that i don't
necessarily have
a opinion on one being better than the
other
it all depends there's just too much
um there's too much opinion involved in
it where
it's preference in my opinion you know
they are different dried material
and fresh frozen material are different
and what's wrong with that what's wrong
with them being
different things i like i like variety
i like there being other options and
stuff like that
so i just don't feel like we need to say
fresh frozen is better and
dried is inferior or vice versa to me i
try to tell people now
they make different different products
and
you're asking me what is different about
them i find
um you know sometimes the dried material
it will make a drier
resin um i also find sometimes
that drier material will yield
slightly more not necessarily
exponentially more where you're like oh
why are we even washing fresh frozen i
haven't really found that i haven't
really washed something dry versus fresh
and been like
the yield was twice dry i am only
washing dried material from now on
that hasn't happened to me very small
yield increases
i have noticed for sure um
definitely different smells flavors
aromas
and i'm saying different i can't sit
here and tell you
that the fresh frozen is always louder
because it hasn't been i have washed
some stuff that was dried
and i was like yo that that stuff is
that's louder
like you got them sitting next to each
other and you can't help but decide
and then i'll give them to a friend
who's who's you know very experienced
smokes a lot of hash
and they can't tell me which one's
frozen and which one's dried
so to me that just shows you that
there's a place
for both there is a place for dried
material there is a place for fresh
frozen material and you'll see these
people who are quick to
knock the man doing the other thing oh
you know fresh frozen's the way
screwdriver material or screwdriver
fresh frozen dries the way
and to me yo there's room for for all of
us in this game
there's enough room for everyone so
don't knock the other man's hustle if
someone's
stoked to wash fresh material you don't
know why they're washing fresh material
maybe they don't have a space to dry it
uh
you know maybe there was a problem along
the crop blah blah blah who knows what
but like if someone's stoked on washing
fresh frozen
and they're making a great product
that's all i care about
and if someone's washing dried material
dry runs and then
making great product that's all i care
about you know is the end result
i just want to be quality first and
foremost
you know that's what really matters and
just something that's trippy to me that
like always like uh
interests me when i wash dried material
is it always dumps in the larger micron
bags
if i wash something fresh frozen
it'll yield you know let's say like in
the 73 and 90
and then i'll wash it dried and it will
be dumping in the 120
and 160. i wonder
if the heads just naturally you know
shrink
pucker up a little bit from the drying
process
and then once maybe you hit them into
that water
they actually expand is what i imagine
is happening i don't know what else
could be going on
um i lack a lot of
um terminology
and experience as far as the science
goes i am the master of bro science when
it comes to hashmaking
and terminology i'm not going to sit
here and try to
sound like i'm a lab technician or that
at um i have some kind of expertise that
i don't
so again a lot of knowledge i've gained
is simply through experience
and a lot of the conclusions i've come
to are simply me
just you know thinking about it and
imagining
it and coming to it through um uh
common sense i guess you know so again i
don't necessarily know that's what's
happening with the heads but that's what
i imagine
is happening but something that i've
seen over and over again
is for some reason the the heads are
bigger with the dried material
typically bigger heads mean better hash
in my experience
i'm not necessarily saying that though
in this regard there's just something
weird where like
i'll have the stuff dumped in the 190
bag and i'm not saying it's like amazing
i'm just saying it's like when i washed
it fresh frozen there was absolutely
nothing
capturable in the 190. and then i washed
it dry
and it was tons of stuff in the 190.
like it just
it's interesting to me you know you
would think that a dry a
fresh frozen trichome head would be
bigger than one that you dried and then
rehydrated
but it's something that i've seen with
multiple cultivars so
that's just something that i've seen
that i found interesting when i was
physically washing the stuff
but as far as having like a
a rule of thumb for the end results like
fresh frozen will always give you this
and dry will always give you that hasn't
been my personal experience
you know things have surprised me
and that's what keeps me doing it right
on man that's beautiful like being able
to keep that surprise in your craft
too probably keeps it you know fresh
instead of getting
bored and ever feeling like a job so we
were comparing the indoor versus outdoor
you know regardless of
where we do um are growing or
where we do our mechanical
separation we always need to make the
plant material cold and so
we turn to ice and i'd like to hear your
insights on
on the kinds of ice i think you were the
first person
who i met who actually
cares so much to make his own ice which
i thought was pretty badass
and and it wasn't until i moved out to
the country
that i realized that um the water that
goes into
making the ice matters a lot because um
there's a lot of
minerals in the water out where i am now
and uh it makes crappy hash so i
actually i actually can't use my local
water
so um and you know everybody's got
different preferences about you know
size of ice and edges and all this kind
of stuff
well um you have run a lot of ice
um what have what does your experience
tell you and what are some of your
preferences
i'm going to be clear i do not make ice
anymore by hand
there was a time where i fully to do
that
and uh enough respect to all the
hashmakers who are making uh
handmade ice uh just to me it becomes
like a
job unto itself of making ice like man
i've got hundreds of ice trays and we
used to sit there and put
them and i would have stand and up
freezers to fill with the ice trays and
like
it was just a job unto itself to just
hand make the ice definitely you know
made a nice
larger cube and we were able to use the
ro
water and uh man if you're making hash
on a small
scale um i'm not discouraging you
by all means make your ice you know
there's nothing wrong with that at all
um uh but as far as
practicality if you're doing stuff on
scale
uh making ice is not gonna be possible
in my opinion you know you are going to
require
a ice machine um you know luckily
there's a lot of reverse osmosis ice
machines available out there
manitowoc makes them oshizaki make some
i might be pronouncing both those brands
wrong
i apologize if i am um uh
oshizaki they make a large cube
uh ice machine you know it's like one
that like
you know if you're in vegas and you get
a nice glass of whiskey they give you
like you know a large
squared cube for it they make a machine
that does
that um you know it doesn't last very
long
i guess because of the nature of it or
the auger and the
mechanics can fail is what they've told
me but they're not much more than the
standard unit so in my opinion if you're
gonna splurge on an ice machine i would
definitely
go with that larger square cube than the
crescent cube that they typically make
but uh
again you know you're going to want to
get an ice machine with uh
ro water in my my opinion is important
um uh i luckily live
in um you know not far i'm about an hour
from arcata california which is like
the uh hub of all things hippie
and uh i don't know uh
natural and you know gold
country living and whatnot uh so
fortunately arcata has the water store
shout out miss aya's water store casey
down there
supply in all of humboldt county with
the reverse
osmosis ice she's got a couple ice
machines down there
as well as a very nice water store
that can give you great water but she
started making ice for the local hash
community
not specifically the local hash
community but as you can imagine there's
a lot of people
up here doing it so she's providing
reverse osmosis eyes for the people
doing
a huge community service which is really
awesome of her
so believe it or not man i drive an hour
and i load up my truck
and bring it back to chest freezers at
my place because i have not bought an
ice machine yet again something i should
invest in myself
but as i mentioned earlier in the show
i'm pretty cheap
you know so as far as buying an ice
machine
if you buy an ice machine to me you
gotta keep it running
you gotta keep it running or you're
gonna have to shut it down
take it apart clean it all store it so
it's kind of this game of like
i only work seasonally
to me it makes sense to just get ice
from her
support a local business otherwise i'd
have to be taking my machine apart and
kind of putting it away for the summer
which again
it's not unrealistic just uh wasn't
necessarily practical for me
so yes i buy reverse osmosis ice
from the store bring it out to my place
store it in chest freezers and use it as
i need it
um not very practical maybe for everyone
i have a lot of friends who make
incredible hash
and they get their ice from costco and i
bust their balls about it all the time
i'd like to joke about how the food
poured down the way
it's not too far from the ice machine
those foot long costco hot dogs
and those chicken baked terps are
working their way into
your eyes and you know their flavor and
stuff but but no but seriously like i
don't know like i said i know a lot of
people who are
are making gas station ice hash and it's
fine
uh obviously not all gas station ice is
created equal
you know what i mean i've been to some
places and you're just like oh god this
is terrible and then other places are
like
no this is great i would eat out of this
cooler so
to me cleanliness is first and foremost
you know
um if you don't know what your ice
situation is like
melt a bag of it in a five gallon bucket
see what floats
see what's in there drink some does it
taste like chlorine
you know like little common sense
things like that you know uh i have a
lot of friends who believe if the water
is really cold the ice is really cold
and everything's really cold it's in
there so
short period of time it doesn't really
matter and i have friends who are using
hose water
and gas station ice again me personally
i am using reverse osmosis water
and reverse osmosis ice to me that just
takes out a variable for contamination
you know your water is clean you know
your herbs clean you know your ice is
clean and you know your equipment's
clean
i feel pretty good about that um so
comes down to preference i've seen great
hash i know great hash makers who are
just using whatever for ice
so i don't want to like put it out there
that people think they have to have
reverse osmosis that it's not
necessarily the case at all
um again you live on a mountain you got
great spring water coming out the
mountain and all cold that sounds even
better than ro to me
so uh you know just have clean water
source clean water clean ice
that's what matters that's great do you
have um
any insight on the size of the cubes
you've mentioned preferring large uh
cubes a few times
um it is is that just because is that a
personal preference
or do you think that it actually
functions better than
smaller cubes or crushed ice
my point for this for that mainly is i
do multiple washes you know what i mean
typically the stuff i'm washing requires
three or four
washes a larger cube lasts longer so you
need to use
less ice in between washes it just
allows you to go through less
um to me it really is just about
cold cold water um the agitation
and the rowing or if you're using
machines that's what's breaking off
the trichome head it's not necessarily
the ice
um ice contributing factor to that
yeah i'm sure it's helping as well but
again
to me it's more about the vortex of the
water that's actually
doing the mechanical separation it's not
necessarily your ice so
if you want to use crushed ice use
crushed ice you want to use big cube
dice i don't really
care it's really just about being cold
cold cold the reason i like a larger
cube is to me it helps
just last longer so you know in between
washes while that stuff's sitting
and i'm filtering out it's on ice still
some nice
chunky ice that's how i see it right on
so uh i have one question about water
quality because we've already talked
quite a bit about water quality
you know going into the frozen ice
um but uh speaking to your frugal self
um you know there's a lot of folks who
are working at home
and they live rurally um and they have
got maybe they've got mineralized water
or maybe you know maybe they've got kind
of sulfury water or you know there's a
lot of variability
in water as soon as well heck we could
this is even a good question for
the city grid because a lot of city grid
water has got
you know uh fluoride and chlorine in it
and my question is is that you know we
if we all have got
the the you know the best practice of
getting ro
but ro is not available to us for
whatever reason
um how low do you think the threshold is
for
chlorine fluoride you know or
or these mineralization minerals to
actually
impart taste to the finished product
if we want to get ro that's one thing
but
but how likely do you think it is that
that these these lesser than waters
are actually going to mess with the
final hash product
to me it's like it goes to like a common
sense thing is how i would approach it
you know
um obviously not all water water sources
are created equal
um you know i'm back from new england
you know and uh
you know a lot of my friends in vermont
you know the water that comes out the
tap
is seriously brown and extremely sulfury
to me that's common sense if your tap
water you know is smelling sulfury
is tainted in color you're not drinking
your tap water
you know i wouldn't want to be making
hash with it you know i just don't see
how it's going to lend itself to that um
i would do whatever i could to have
cleaner water you know to me um
it's not a fine line though it's it's
like obvious it's like oh this water
smells like eggs
yeah i'm not gonna use it you know what
i mean or if you taste some water
in the city and you're like oh it tastes
slightly chlorinated you know i'm saying
ever so slightly
i wouldn't necessarily be terrified to
use it you know what i mean like if you
live in a city
your water source probably isn't that
great if you're asking a hippie like me
you know what i mean
so uh it's tough you know do i expect
you to go to the store and buy
gallons of spring water to do your hash
runs
if you're washing in a 5 gallon bucket
doesn't seem crazy to me if you're
washing in 20 gallon barrel
or 32 gallon barrels you know that kind
of doesn't seem practical
but to me then if you're doing that on
scale then you invest in a water filter
um small home bath patches
again i go to like cooking an analogy
like if you're cooking at your house and
you're making a birthday cake for your
kid and it requires water and your tap
water is brown
like are you going to use that or are
you going to pour it out of like a jug
of water you're probably going to use a
jug of water to make that you know what
i mean so
to me just common sense goes a long way
you know if your water's terrible don't
use it
um but just get a filter there's all
different kinds of filters out there you
know you can get
really quality filters for 200 bucks and
you can get one for five thousand
dollars it just kind of depends on what
you're trying to do what kind of volume
of water you're trying to actually
filter off
but uh you know it's one of those things
that you kind of just figure it out for
yourself you know like if you're just
trying to make a little hash for
yourself at home make a little hash for
yourself at home and
sadly yeah you might be like you know
what the water ruined this hash
i've been there i've definitely done
that before um
and to me the only way to determine that
is just a little bit of common sense you
know pour a glass of that water look at
that water drink that water
if it's not something you're trying to
drink like
i don't know if you really want to soak
all your resin in it you know
like uh you know like that's just my
opinion and i think it is an opinion you
know what i'm saying i have other
friends who are like hey if everything's
really cold
it's just an extraction thing nothing's
getting absorbed
you're then putting it in a freeze dryer
and it's you know sublimating out all
the water
so you know i have some people who are
probably going to listen to this and be
like dude it doesn't matter
but again to me not all tap water is
created equal
fair enough so we've already talked
about uh material quite a bit
um but at this point you know we're kind
of going through the process and we're
we're still in the
in the prepping stage you know getting
getting our or
getting prepared to actually make the
hash and
um what do you do as far as
breaking down the flower to be most
prepared
um for the hashing process
to me it's all about exposing the
surface area break it down
break it all the way down you got some
chunky stuff
you're gonna have to break it down like
i don't like necessarily cutting
into the actual flour just chopping up
the flour
i don't think that lends itself to
making clean hash
but again just the way the structure the
natural structure of the plant
allows you to break it down do it as
much as you possibly can
um you know sometimes i'll tell people
you know
keep them nickel sized small you know
the smaller the better
if you've got a big old butt in there
there there is trichomes on the inside
of it and
in order for you to get those you're
going to have to physically break that
big old bud up
in your barrel whether you're using a
paddle or you're using a machine
you're gonna have to wash it and wash it
until that
bud um breaks down and
exposes all the trichomes so to me
the best thing to do is just do that
when you're prepping the material then
you don't have to row it as hard or wash
it as hard
i want that resin just to fall off so me
personally i spend a lot of time
prepping
and i break it all the way down and then
i put my turkey bags
in my freezer with them open i don't
close them
i don't compact them i leave it open
for 24 hours i feel that allows the
moisture
to escape the bags and to get stuck on
the walls of your freezer or whatnot
and doesn't necessarily um create
freezer burn or too much moisture in
your bags
um and i also feel like it allows the
material to
freeze quicker rather than like
enclosing it and encapsulating it with a
bag
kind of almost you know does the
thermophilic compost
reaction where it does throw heat having
all that stuff so i figure
sleep the bags open allow it to escape
the moisture you escape
um you know and then also that way
when you open those bags to dump them
into your barrel
they just fall apart when i dump my bags
into my barrels
it's just a bunch of loose little buds
it's not this compressed
football of like ganja you know i see a
lot of people still
using vac sealers and stuff for their
material like to me
don't compress your material do not
compress it
do not pack it in your freezers all
crazy don't stuff a freezer in a day
you know work multiple freezers you know
have the bags and they're all
loose all open so that when you dump
them out
you want i just see it as you want
everything to be gentle you want to be
able to like gently roll the heads off
those necks you don't want it to be this
like
forced thing so might as well just have
it where all the material is exposed and
everything can just fall off real easily
right on
so let's talk about agitation now so
there have been so many evolutions
in hash technique when talking about
you know how actually to add
motion to the ice and the flower
to get those um you know resin heads to
knock off when i
when i first learned around a decade ago
to make my own hash you know we were
using
uh you know the paint mixer on a drill
and that was
messy but it was efficient and
um and it worked and then you know i
we we started having the advent of these
small camping washing machines and you
know
people are running bigger washing
machines too but essentially a washing
machine
that you know moves it around which is
in a much more gentle way
than the paint mixers and then you know
some hardcore people
have come all the way around and they're
they're using hand paddles again
to you know be super super gentle
with it and i think that each of those
processes
are all being used still today so what
do you see as the pros and the cons
of some of these more common uh
you know methods for agitating
um um i personally hand row um i
personally use paddles and i row by hand
um
to me if you work solo or if you just
have a
lot of material a lot of material you're
trying to process
there is a place for machines um you
know one person
can only do so much so i understand
the place for machines my gripe with
machines is just the cleaning of them i
just feel like
you got to clean them when you're done
clean them before you use them
and i just feel like when
you're using machines or when i've used
machines i'm relying on them to run
through a lot of material
so you end up not using one machine but
you end up using like 15
machines and then your job becomes like
oh every day
cleaning these machines at the end of
every day cleaning these machines
and it's just a lot of maintenance and
personally that's not how i
enjoy spending my time but again uh
if you got a bunch of material to run
machines will help you do that
me personally i like the hand row
um the hand row
has a physicality to it that
can't be matched with a machine you know
i
joke around it's like you know when you
feel
that fish on the end of your rod you
know what i mean there's there's a
sensitivity with that that paddle that
you can achieve
um you know uh material
me personally i don't have an sop you
know a lot of people
everyone nowadays in 2020 they all want
your sop
you know show me how you do this you
know and
to me you know there isn't really one i
i
approach each wash differently and
paddling allows me to do that you know i
can paddle
for 15 minutes and then be like look at
the result and be like you know you went
too hard or you know what you're gonna
need to go harder
and that allows me to determine you know
okay you know what i'm gonna do this in
four washes
ten minutes each and i'm gonna start
more gentle
and then i'm gonna go more aggressive
and to me that's kind of the approach
that i start with
is i try to make that first wash real
delicate
real pure and then i ramp up the
aggression
more and more with each wash um
i like hand rolling to me it allows me
to be like
go harder or go less the machines they
just have a timer setting
and they go one way and then go the
other way they don't really have like a
aggressive washer a light walk you know
what i mean obviously
someone would tell you what will you
just adjust that through time
you know you just do a three minute wash
versus a seven minute and i hear that
but some material is just denser and you
have to beat the hell out of it
and some material is light and you gotta
be gentle
so personally um as weird as
hand doing anything being more
consistent than a machine
doesn't make sense but for me personally
it allows me to get more consistent
results because i just
cater the way i watch based on the
material
if that makes sense yeah i do follow
when
you said that when you are using the
paddle
um you can get real-time feedback on
whether or not you need to
you know go less hard or go more hard
and be more aggressive
what is a sign or a signal that you are
looking for that you have gone
too hard and you need to mellow it out
just green contamination in the in the
product you know if you pull your bags
and there's a bunch of green in there
you've been beating the hell out of it
you know what i mean like honestly like
you know i've made very few
i made very little green hash in my life
very little
um to me you gotta really be beating the
hell out of it to make green hash
like really going crazy soaking it for
crazy long
beating it for crazy long because like
i've washed up a fifth time before
and i've done it knowing like okay this
is the fifth wash like
give it your all like really like let's
try to get every single head off this
and let's even try to make it green like
let's try to be so thorough that we make
and it's hard sometimes it's literally
hard in my opinion
so to me you really gotta abuse the
material like
i've watched with kids and they like
do this special little row that they do
you know they like got this little like
like uh posture that they have and they
just do this repetitive little row
and i can tell they think like this kid
thinks he's [ __ ] rowing in a special
way like this dude thinks like he's got
a special row technique and like to me
it's not that deep man like you you're
just agitating the stuff you know what i
mean
like yeah you can do it wrong but like
not really man to be honest like i wrote
those bigger vessels you know bruteless
dropped those large 65 gallon troughs
i've gone at one with three other
buddies before like let's just beat the
[ __ ] out of this stuff
and see what happens and like we've just
been like oh
just dumped like cool we got we got it
out in two washes instead of three or
four you know what i mean so to me
it's kind of hard to like i don't know
overly
beat up the stuff that's my experience
again some people are listening that's
probably thinking i'm crazy but like
i've never really done that you know
i've never really like
made green stuff and just totally have
to be terrible but
i'm often usually washing fresh frozen
and like i said i am kind of going
gradually you know
multiple washes so
um as far as the washing machines
and hand paddling both um you know with
experience anybody can learn
what the appropriate length of time
is but for the vast majority of people
who are making hash who are making it
for themselves
they're never going to like really make
enough hash
to to know exactly when to stop
are there any signs that you look for
when either paddling or using the
washing machine
that tells you okay i have agitated
enough
whatever i'm gonna get is has already
come off and now i just need to you know
wait for it to settle in the bag
to me it's just yields you know that's
what i look to you know uh
my first wash is gonna dump my second
wash is gonna be about half what my
first is
my third is gonna be about half what my
second is
and then i kind of gauge what's in the
bottom of that third wash you know i'm
like
you know what i pulled 20 grams out of
this
i know i'm gonna get 10 more off a
fourth i'm gonna do it you know what i'm
saying but
sometimes you get from the first to
second then that third comes and you're
like you know what
there's really not much [ __ ] in here
it's kind of getting darker at this
point
you just know like you know like ah
that fourth wash is gonna yield very
little and it's gonna be green
and sometimes though if you're that home
washer and you only got two pounds to
wash you might be like
i don't care i'm just gonna keep washing
this until there is nothing left
that i've done that that's not crazy to
me like i've washed stuff six times
before
and just pulled nothing out and then
like oh that was a waste you know what i
mean that's all it really
but then you know you're like okay now i
know i'm done
exactly and then you know going forward
oh i can wash that cultivar
five times for this much time and
keeping data is good i have a little
book you know what i mean like to me for
the hashmaker
it's nice you know i'm not typically
that type of person but when it comes to
hash
i do i write down how much i'm washing i
write down you know
how long i washed it for how many washes
and then i'm
writing down what i'm capturing so that
i know my percentages i know what's
dumping in what bag
and it's something to reflect on you
know what i mean you can go back and
look you know and you can see how
something washed this year that year and
whatnot but
that's the only real way to know you
know no one knows looking at material
how
oh that's going to take 45 minutes of
agitation and it will be done no one
knows that the only way to do it is to
do it you know
and to me there's nothing wrong with
washing material
until there's nothing there you know
what what's wrong with that
you just wasted some time that's all you
know and at the end of the day
if you're thorough with your sprayer and
cleaning the material
i've made some crazy green looking stuff
blonde
by just spending the time cleaning it
cleaning it cleaning it spraying it
cleaning it spraying it cleaning it you
know over and over again so
don't be scared to make green hash like
a
you might be able to clean it up but b
like
worse comes the worse you made some
green hash and i don't know
there's always something you know what i
mean there's always something you can do
with it make edibles out of it
roll it up whatever you know what i mean
i'd rather uh
know you extracted it all than just know
what's in the compost pile you know what
i mean like uh
i'm i'm guilty of that some days i'll
wash all day long you get to the end of
the day and you're like
do i want to do a fourth wash on this
[ __ ] right now like no i've already
washed 15 barrels today like i don't
want to do a fourth wash i know i'm
throwing 40 grams of hash in my compost
pile right now but like i don't want to
do it you know and that sounds crazy but
it happens right on so um
excuse me the part of hash making that i
like the least is uh draining the bags
because you know it's it's um you know
your the bags are filled with water and
you're
lifting them up to to create the
opportunity for gravity to pull the
water through the bags
and you know it's heavy and it takes a
long time
and you know the first few runs um you
know you're all enthusiastic and you're
feeling
robust and it's good but like you know
if you're doing a lot over the course of
the day
you know by after lunch or feeling
sluggish from eating and
you know like this starts to suck and
people start to cut corners
which is dangerous at that point do you
have any
um you know insights or or tricks
about you know essentially lifting the
bags
up so that the water can drain through
uh most efficiently
yeah now this is this is a serious
problem
i've definitely been there many a times
where i'm just by myself
end of the day just defeated you know
body just exhausted and you got like a
45u bag that just
will not drain and it's got like 20
gallons of water in there and it's just
like a hundred pounds and you can't even
lift it you know what i mean it's
it's it's stressful and uh you know uh
just the nature of resin working with
fresh frozen material time is of the
essence you don't have time and
you know the longer that that bag sits
the longer the resin coats it and makes
it harder to drain you know so
personally the thing that i found the
best is i use
20 gallon bags and i use 20 gallon you
know
trash barrels little smaller 20 gallon
brew
trash barrels to put those in for the
filter
and um i use a conical drill bit and i
drill um holes in the bottom
of the the 20 gallon
brew trash barrels
you can use as many of those as you need
i have gone
as far as i have a barrel for literally
every bag so the 45u bag has its own
barrel the 73u bag has its own barrel
the the you know 90 u bag has its own
barrel
and you just stack them in each other
like you normally would with the bags
but you have them in its own barrel and
that way you can kind of grab that
barrel by the handles
and you can kind of really give it hell
force it up
you know that's what you basically got
to do is you got to break the seal
you know the hashes naturally through
gravity being forced on the bottom of
that screen
and it's sealing it making it hard to
drain so if you can grab that barrel
and pop it up and pop it up and force um
you know that pressure that suction
that's starting to break
um that will get that thing going again
um sometimes it takes multiple pops you
gotta really
give it hell but you grab that barrel
and you
keep just just keep lifting it and
dropping it lifting it and dropping it
and lifting it and dropping it and if
you just do that over and over again
that bag will drain
um sometimes it seems like it just will
not but just keep lifting it and popping
it keep lifting it and
that's when it helps if you have a drain
on your floor
or you know and something large to drain
in and you can really just
take that barrel and just like put it on
the ground if that's what you gotta do
then that's what you gotta do um but uh
yeah to me it helps to have those
bruteless with holes drilled
in the bottom of them for sure and again
you could just use one
and put all the bags in that one and
then put that in another barrel
um i've seen many people's different
setups
to where they like put a small bruteless
on top sorry
same bruteless put a small trash barrel
on top of another trash barrel you'll
see different people's pictures
but there's all this different tech to
just elevate that bag
so that you're not really having to do
much lifting
yourself i will say that just letting it
sit there
is kind of um not the way if you just
fill it up to the brim and keep adding
water and it's just slowly slowly more
draining
the move is to not just sit there and
look at it you need to be proactive
even if you're just hitting the side of
the barrel just over and over again i've
seen people
use weird machines to vibrate the barrel
and to hit the barrel and different
things like that but just
agitation anything that you can keep it
moving so that that water goes through
is what you need to do i'd love to see a
super cut of all of the crazy ideas
people have come up with to agitate the
bag
while it's draining to try to you know
open up the the micron filter i bet you
there's some crazy ass
uh inventions that people have used that
have both worked
not worked and worked but been a pain in
the ass
it'd be really interesting to kind of
see them all lined up
so so this brings us to the part where
okay so we've got our
our our hash bag and the water is
drained out
and our glorious resin is there sitting
in the bottom
in the screen now i've only ever heard
of
or i've i've only ever experienced and
worked one
way to get the hash out of the bag and
and you know i was taught that i i put a
frisbee
um open side of the frisbee pointed up
and i stretch my micron screen
over over the frisbee and um
and then i i gently scrape along that
with a
with a sharp knife and um gently remove
the the hash um i've never i haven't
made hash with a lot of other people
though
um and i'm i'm guessing that a frisbee
and a sharp knife is probably not
industry standard
um what techniques do you like for
removing
hash from that delicate micron screen
so this is when uh the game kind of
changed um due to freeze dryers
this is when um the game kind of changed
due to freeze dryers
um you know it used to be kind of a
harder process when you had to
gather um the resin out the bags
and whatnot um now thankfully due to the
freeze dryers
it's not this technical thing anymore in
my opinion
um you really want it to be wet when you
put it in your freeze dry trays um
wetter the better that allows the water
to actually sublimate out i see a lot of
people trying to dry their patties
and that is not the way you need the
water
in order for the water to be able to
escape um
that's just how sublimation works so
again
we're now pouring this very liquidy
stuff
into trays there it is much easier in my
opinion you're just scooping it out as
quickly as possible pouring it in the
trays and loading it into the machine
um that's why i love freeze dryers
there's a lot of people who are still
hand drying hash air drying hash that's
cool
i'm not one of them i'm when i wash i'm
usually doing
production um and the the freeze dryer
allows that to be possible um air drying
to me is a art unto itself
um just a different thing um
that i personally have moved away from
and i am not looking back
i am not looking back to continue
microplaning
continue air drying now that i have
freeze dryers personally
um it changed everything for me for the
better
wow being so i have yet to use an air
dryer i certainly have shopped them
and and have have enjoyed the quality of
you know sandy blonde hash that comes
out of them but
that description that you gave of that
that hashy
slurry that you're just able to pour
right out of the bag
into the tray god that sounds like um
that sounds really convenient and
efficient right it's just it's just made
me realize like god
i really need to reconsider uh getting
um a dryer like that um so but for the
folks who are not going to be doing that
uh
folks like you know most of us who are
going to be air drying
um once you have the the micron
screen taut over something like
a frisbee and and you are
removing it as much as you can from the
screen
what do you recommend that people
put that hash on to
start the process of air drying you know
the classic is the pizza
box right as a matter of fact there's
it's totally funny that the pizza place
here on the island
um where i live on vacheron island they
are so
used to people coming in and just buying
pizza boxes for hash
because there's so much cannabis
produced historically on my island that
that the pizza place knows
what they're going to be used for and
everybody gets a chuckle out of it
but um but you know people have been
using pizza boxes for a long time
and i suspect there are much better
options to use
so so what do you recommend to folks if
if they're not going to go
the uh the freeze dryer away
uh see again this is just like something
that like uh
i don't wanna necessarily uh dive down
because
it's been literally probably two years
since i
air dried hash um
it's just really not my focus it's not
what i'm into
um and i will say though the last times
i did do it i totally used pizza boxes
like everybody else
i would freeze the patties you know take
them out
freeze the patties and then microplane
them onto
um onto cardboard you know and to me it
was never perfect
wasn't ideal and that's why i've moved
away from it personally
so one of the things that you know i
know that microplaning is
um you know kind of standard for
non-commercial um
you know production um i've always had
the idea though that
you know i don't particularly like
microplaning because
if i am using the microplane and i am
rupturing the trichomes um that is
releasing
the oil to become in contact with air
and sure my my hash is going to get
oxidized anyway
if i'm going to be um air drying it but
it's also creating
an opportunity for the terpenes that are
within the resin
to touch the air and to just simply you
know
you know go away
right you know like they're so they're
so easily volatilized
that i i suspect i'm losing terpenes is
is that a fair concern when microplaning
or or
am i being or am i aware of a concern
that really is doesn't play out
i mean that goes back to me to common
sense i completely agree with you
how could grinding a glandular trichome
head across
a sharp metal surface not potentially
rupture multiple
i imagine it is and that's why to me
personally
i feel that microplaning is inferior to
the freeze dryer
i feel air drying is inferior
to the freeze dryer that's just how i
personally feel
i have friends think um you know air
drying is the way it makes a superior
product
i have never experienced that not once
in my life have i ever seen air dried
stuff
next to a freeze dried and been like oh
that's better i never have
um i understand someone sitting at home
doesn't necessarily have
access to a freeze dryer um so you're
just gonna have to dry it any way you
possibly can
breaking it down exposes the surface
area and allows it to dry quicker that's
why people microplane is simply because
it breaks it all the way down
um i've seen people use credit cards
knives just push it through a sieve
there's many ways you can go about
breaking it down further if you want to
um it's just going to be in my opinion
about trial and error and seeing which
one works for you
um i hate to promote
freeze dryers so hard to the home person
but just to me it really was a game
changer you know
definitely an investment nonetheless but
if you're making enough
cash to fill a freeze dryer then to me
it's a no-brainer
it pays for itself really quickly yeah
yeah it's one of those economies of
scale like if you're going to be
producing enough to fill that
that dryer it'll pay for itself the
first time you use it
and and so that it is for that but you
know to be inclusive of
all the home folks um you know
put pushing through a sieve and then
um and then removing the water just
simply with evaporation is still
incredibly common
and and i know that you you know you
don't practice this anymore but i'm
going to take one more step down
this path because there's a lot of
people who are listening who like me
this is this is what we got right and so
this is the process that we're going to
use so
so once the once the the hash material
is pushed through
a strainer or a sieve which helps break
it up
on the pizza box perhaps a pizza box
covered with
parchment um you know i see
there's a lot of different versions of
people maybe you know
putting the pizza boxes in a tent or
putting them in front
of a box fan some people who have got a
nice enclosed area
they'll put in a box fan for rotation
and potentially an air conditioner to
keep it cool
and then potentially a dehumidifier to
help remove the water
as well um you know if you can reach
back
two years into your experience was there
a particular setup that you
liked when you actually did air dry
i like it doing it in the cold to me
it's all about doing it in the cold
you can pretty much dry hash in a
regular freezer almost all the way you
know
to me cold is the way to do it not
warm but cold as cold as you possibly
can get it
well that's a really that's a really
interesting idea i hadn't not even
considered that
it's the same process that eventually uh
you know freezer burns food but if
you're only using it for a few days
the the nature of the freezer um
is dehydrating and and putting it in a
freezer
you will not only keep it cold and keep
those terps from volatilizing
but you are evaporating out the water
well
you just upgrade upgraded my game i'm
going to be doing that next time
um that's right there's lots of ways
and like i said please reach out to
someone like reach out to like
cush kirk um brandon he loves air drying
he's like real passionate about it so
like i'm not trying to be big and
suddenly
shut down when it came to this for you
know where the conversation switched
i just don't like to like talk on stuff
that i'm not
super familiar with not actively doing
now
i just don't want to sound um um
naive um so like i said i'm sorry to be
vague about
hand drying or air drying um
i just haven't been doing it a lot
recently i don't want to
you know talk on it too much but like i
said
brandon um does it uh
there's a lot of a lot of people out
there that are doing it still um simply
adam he's one too
uh please by all means you're trying to
air dry hand dry
you can do it there's many ways to do it
you can do it with d hums you can do it
with heat you can do it with coal to me
the way is cold
right on so the last thing before we go
to
our second commercial break is is uh
kind of like a like a systemic strategy
right
um you know you you've used the idea of
cooking and recipes several times and
you know there's a there's this
idea in french cooking of of mison place
which is you
you cut all your ingredients and you get
all your your stuff out and on the
counter
before you start so that you're not like
oh where the hell did i put the whatever
when you're in the process of cooking
the meal
and um i suspect that we've not talked
about this that you are probably a
person who is
um you know maybe not now since you are
so experienced but
writing a list of what your process
is and making sure that you have
everything out in advance
you know is is probably a good idea
especially for folks that are
trying to teach themselves how to do
this you know
the less pressure or the more time you
can buy for yourself
as you're actually in the moment making
the hash
is probably the best thing so so what do
you recommend for people as far as like
you know you got all your materials what
do you recommend for people for like
a a smart efficient setup
you don't need much you know what i mean
like you really don't need much
um you know my room is probably about
eight by ten
uh that's all it really is you know uh
i definitely have a sink in there it's
going to help to have a
deep sink so you can rinse your bags as
soon as possible as soon as you pull
them out
that's really important with fresh
frozen material is you know cleaning
them almost instantly
um so having a sink with water is good
um i like to have a wall a large
reservoir there that's there
that um holds all the water that i need
you know
some places labs i work they have you
know enough water that's on demand
that's really nice
i like to have a large reservoir that i
can ice down
personally you know something that i can
physically be dropping ice into
so that my water source is nice and cold
so
i like to have a reservoir that you know
has enough water for the day and that i
can continually drop
ice into uh you know i like to have a
small
freezer in my workspace so that i can
have my
material in there and it's going
straight from the freezer into the bags
you know and
also have enough ice on demand in there
if you don't have the ice machine
present
um so it's nice to have that um you know
personally i have my freeze dryer in my
cold room so that it's right there so
that i am you know
my my freeze dryer is on and running so
it is all cold the trays are cold so
that
when i am putting it into there it is
going from like you know the cold room
into that negative 40 almost instantly
it freezes in minutes you know
so it's nice to have the freeze dryer in
the cold room right next to you
um in a perfect world you would have a
drain in your floor
you know obviously that's not ideal but
working outside
takes care of that situation as well
it's nice to have a assortment of
different size spoons on
you know just small medium large spoons
have them on a nice metal tray so that
they're all nice and clean
um helps to have you know some hand
sprayers little pump sprayers filled
with alcohol you know
just so you can keep cleaning your
utensils clean your bags
um i also like to have a sprayer so that
you can spray
on the hash whether you're using a hand
and pump sprayer from chapman use that
for years that works
you know a lot of people now are using
those like nine gallon flow zone
um you know battery operated pumps to
spray with
other people labs i'm seeing people are
you know basically getting these things
installed so they have water pumps with
little sprayers at the end of it
i like that because then you can kind of
have a reservoir for your
hand sprayer so you can ice down that
real nice and have as much water as you
need and not have to be
pumping all day long possibly
um and then obviously just an assortment
of barrels
barrels to row in barrels for your bags
it's always good to have extra barrels
just to like throw bags in while you
work and whatnot
never hurts but uh i feel like that's
pretty much
everything that's in my room you know
there's not really much in there it's
kind of just an open space so that you
got room to work in
right on so we're going to talk about
storage next but let's do that after
the commercial break you are listening
to shaping fire and my guest today is
hashmaker
ganja guild the ice book
if you listen to shaping fire and you
grow your own cannabis
chances are high that you are very
particular about the inputs you use for
growing
people like us painstakingly
self-educate on cannabis nutrients and
techniques
so we can cultivate the best tasting and
cleanest flowers possible
and when we go to purchase those
nutrients we want to be sure that our
supplier shares our values
and is providing exceptional quality
this is why i recommend
buildasoil.com to my friends who care
about quality
build a soil empowers organic growers to
do their best work
by sourcing and shipping only the finest
cannabis growing supplies
from organic inputs soils soil testing
and pots
to lights growing tents sprayers and
cover crops
build a soil founder jeremy silva
doesn't just stock his store with what's
available
he goes deep to personally vet each
product for quality
and determine that there isn't a better
version of the product that he could be
selling
because of this arduous process you know
that your options on buildasoil.com
have been carefully curated to create
the results you are looking for
not only that but the build a soil way
is a philosophy that will permeate your
interaction with the company
from website design to pricing and
shipping to after purchase support
jeremy and his team always strive to do
their best
and give you the best customer service
in the business
check out buildasoil.com today
for top tier quality cultivation
supplies and a friends and family buying
experience
and check out their educational videos
and extraordinary social
media while you're there too quality
organic growing supplies
at buildasoil.com
while i love growing under the sun
there's a lot of good reasons to grow
indoors
and if you're like most folks you want a
lighting source that grows high yielding
healthy plants without using excessive
amounts of electricity
bios lighting creates biological
lighting solutions
that brings the natural brilliance of
the outdoors into your grow room
bios lighting has the attributes that i
look for in a horticultural lighting
solution
i've bought those cheap lights online
and they're difficult to work with and
fail in no time
in contrast my bios led light is
industrial grade to last a long time
it is ip66 wet rated so little foliar
overspray won't harm it
it is easy to clean without taking it
down and of course the most important
aspect
it is built for the exact light spectrum
i want for great yielding healthy
cannabis plants
and it doesn't hurt that their lighting
rigs look badass too
many horticultural led lighting systems
are based on irrelevant performance
metrics and people love to argue online
about these numbers
i prefer to judge on par photon
efficiency and how happy my plants are
and the bios lights exceed my
expectations in these categories
bios lights have an optimized broad
spectrum that maximizes photosynthesis
and plant growth
while also providing the ideal
conditions for superior par
efficacy and a comfortable visual
experience i also love their attentive
and over-educated customer service folks
bios starts with a team of biologists
before getting the electrical engineers
involved
they have studied how light impacts
cannabis plants and devised an overall
strategy that works
i encourage you to check out their
website at bioslighting.com
to learn more about how this strategy
can work for you and shaping fire
listeners can get a special deal
use the discount code shaping fire all
one word
no caps for 10 off your entire purchase
that's biosliding.com
did you know that shaping fire has a
fabulous youtube channel with content
not found on the podcast when i attend
conventions or speak or moderate panels
i always record them and bring the
content home for you to watch
the shango los youtube channel has
world-class speakers
including kevin jodry of wonderland
nursery talking about breeding cannabis
for the best terpene profile
nicholas mahmoud on regenerative and
polyculture cannabis growing
dr sunil agarwal on the history of
cannabis medicine around the world
ben cassidy of true terpenes on using
terpenes for health in your everyday
life
reggie gaudino of steep hill on the
cannabis genome
and jeff lowenfeld's on the soil food
web there are several presentations from
dr ethan russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system
and even my own presentation on how to
approach finding your dream job in
cannabis
and why we choose cannabis business even
though the risks are so high
as of today there are over 100 videos
that you can check out for absolutely
free
go to youtube.com forward slash
shangolos
or click on the link in this week's
newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire i'm your host
shango los and our guest this week is
hashmaker ganja gil the ice book
so at this point we have got ourselves
some hash
made and it is ready to rock and my
question
for you gill is curing you know a lot of
people believe
that some special magic happens um
from the interplay of the the terpenes
and the other
subtle you know organic compounds that
are in the hash
that make it something more than simply
a a trichome that's been removed from
the plant
what are your thoughts on on curing to
capture
any of that increase in quality from
just time
yeah curing is interesting um you know
curing
you know i feel like you know with flour
it's just essentially letting the flour
marinate in its own aromas
that's what it is um with resin
you know it's tough because you're you
know i'm typically washing fresh
frozen resin and then when it comes out
i want to keep it cold so it's this
process
of continuing to keep it cold
so what i would call you know
fresh resin
i don't know if it's really curing all
that much in my freezer you know me
personally my melt
i have to keep it in my freezer
otherwise it'll grease
so in my freezer is it really curing
i'm not really sure it is you know
that's that's where i stand with it the
melt
i'm not sure if it's really doing much
while in that freezer i don't know if
it's getting better you know i have
freezer
i have melt in my freezer from two years
ago i don't know if it's much
different today than it was two years
prior
for me the curing process really comes
into play
with rosin you know me personally i'm
not
so much into the traditional hashish the
temple balling
and stuff like that the pucks that's not
me
i keep my full melt at freezer
temperature
that's the way to keep it pixie dust
beach sand whatever you want to call it
you know so
me personally it's staying in the
freezer and i don't think my hash is
really curing too much in there in my
opinion
i then take the hash and i turn it into
rosin and there is definitely a very
big difference between freshly pressed
rosin
and cured rosin there is absolutely a
difference into that
so and to me it goes back to they're
just two very
different things i'm not willing to call
one superior
to the other um i really enjoy fresh
press rosin
i also enjoyed cured rosin so
it kind of again to me they're just
different things
um when it comes to
curing the rosin you know uh most people
these days are calling it a cold
cure um it's one of those
funny things about the industry where no
one is curing it
in the cold sadly if you cold cure rosin
it's going to actually give you
a real dry texture kind of the opposite
of what people are trying to achieve
through the curing prop process you know
people want that wet
batter and again the way you get that
wet batter
is by letting your rosin sit in my
opinion at a
you know 70 degrees or higher
you know 70 to 90 is kind of perfect you
know
once you start pushing the temperatures
i start to call it more like a jam
tech or jar tech you know you're gonna
start crashing stuff
out so me personally i am never heating
post press i just you know press it
and then let it sit at room temperature
essentially
um i live in trinity county so it is
very hot in the summertime so i have a
pantry that gets a little warmer than my
house that's air conditioned
so i'm personally putting my jars in
that room that's slightly warmer
just takes several days depending on
strain
it goes through the marbling process and
then ends up being
one um tone and then you essentially
just stir it
you whip it you press it you uh compact
it
and give yourself that wet batter um
texture um which people like to refer to
as cold cured
um some people are then not getting a
wet enough consistency for their liking
so then they're putting it in an oven at
200 degrees
and heating it to give it that more wet
sweaty texture
again personally that goes against my
beliefs and what i'm trying to do um
i'm seriously just trying to do it with
like i said
room temperature essentially yeah the
idea of reheating it
after the fact oh my gosh that sounds
like that'd be terrible for volatilizing
all those all those terps that you've
gone through so much effort at this
point
to be able to preserve it's like it's
like giving them all back
there at the end the other thing that um
is remarkable or or worth remark from
the curing that you just described
unlike when we're making temple balls
or or pressed uh hashish bricks or
something like that
that is often so the the you know that
the
hashish components can intermix and kind
of like evolve their flavor together
it sounds like the curing process you're
describing
is not so much for the evolution
of the taste it sounds like it's more
about
um getting the hash rosin to a
a uniform consistency
and stability so that it stays the way
you want it to be
over time um is that a an agreeable
you know understanding of what you're
what you're suggesting
yeah i don't really disagree with that
that's a that's a good uh that's a good
way of looking at it for sure it's
definitely
about texture um you know
the the art of hashies is a deep complex
thing there's a lot of you know
traditional hashish methods that exist
um you know the aging and the what not
that you're talking about
there that is that is very valid
and there are many people doing that
it's just not necessarily what i am
currently focused on
from watching from watching fresh frozen
material
we're focused on terp preservation
that's what we're trying to do we're
trying to preserve
those terpenes at all costs and that's
why we're freezing material
we're washing it cold that's why we're
freeze drying it
you know to me letting hash sit
at room temperature simply degrades
terpenes that's just a fact to me
just happens um you know some people
will tell you
the ones that stick out and the ones
that last
are what it's about you know that's what
frenchie can only told me is he likes
you know
the stuff to sit out and age and the
terpenes that are
able to like still stay you know the
ones that don't dissipate
you know that's what's interesting to
him you know he he
really enjoys the aging of hash
personally me and what a lot of people
are doing in california right now
that that's not what we care about you
know like we are trying
to preserve those things that just
evaporate we're trying to hold on to
those things that
just eventually aren't there anymore
we're trying to preserve that
that's what it's all about washing fresh
frozen that's what the freeze dryer is
about
you know me personally i don't care
about having 10 year old hash
i'm not trying to like have stuff in 20
years and open it up and be like
oh this is 20 years old that doesn't
appeal to me
personally um have i smoked some really
old hash before that was really
enjoyable
absolutely totally um i just
feel like stuff has shifted in
california
and i'm not saying it's better i'm not
saying what we're doing now
is better than you know this ancient
stuff that's been going on
i just see it as an evolution i just see
it as in it's it's come to this now and
it's gonna continue to change to it
um and me personally
i don't see the freeze dryer leaving i
don't see it like
being a phase to me they're here to stay
and uh to me uh
with the freeze dryer it's really about
preserving those terps
you know it's really about working with
fresh frozen material
otherwise yeah you don't need one just
air dry your hash and then like
leave it out make bricks of it make
temple balls
totally cool that's totally fine just to
me it's a different pursuit than working
with fresh frozen
yeah fair enough and i think you're
right there's definitely been a
bifurcation of the scene
where you know part of it um you know
generally people who
don't have access to the freeze dryers
are still temple balling it up and you
know i'm one of those people and i and i
really like how
temple balls evolve taste wise over time
i certainly don't leave them at room
temperature they're in a cooler
but that's really great but then you
know when i go over to my buddy's place
who's got a
a freeze dryer and we're having his you
know you know beautiful
sandy stuff i'm like damn this is really
freaking good too
in a different way than the temple balls
that i have at my house
and yeah and it's just and it's hey i i
love adding colors to this palette of
our relationship with hash
and uh yeah and so um i think i think
it's good
to have lots of different products for
us all to be able to enjoy what
we want um your your comment about you
know you're not really
you know concerned about you know having
your hash be 10 or 20 years vintage down
the line
but we do all need to to store our hash
right
um especially folks who work like like
uh like you do where you are seasonal
right you need to you need to grow your
your plants during the summer and wash
them during the winter
and then and then store it in a way that
it's going to be good both for your head
stash but then also for providing
for friends and so how do you
store your hash material and i'm going
to give you two different threshold
points
let's say the first threshold point is
stuff that you're gonna
smoke within like the next two weeks
right so it's like your
you know your your carry-around jar or
whatever
and then you've got stuff that's gonna
be in the freezer that you're gonna be
you know keeping at that perfect uh
consistency
you know further than two weeks out so
tell us a little bit about how you
handle your stuff
yeah to me um what i really love about
my process
is i just freeze all the melt
out of my freeze dryer instantly i used
to put it in jars
um but as people know you know glass
condensates when it comes out at room
temperature
so if you've got hash in a glass jar
and it's in your fridge or even freezer
um and you bring it into room
temperature do not open that jar right
away i'm sure most people on your show
listen and know this but for the people
that don't you don't
open your jar right away you let it come
to room temperature and you kind of
wipe the sweat off it the condensation
you know you don't want
the hash to absorb that moisture you
know
to me the whole idea of using a freeze
dryer and drying hash properly is to get
the moisture out so then you don't want
to be reintroducing it
every time you're pulling your jar out
your fridge or freezer
so again me personally i stopped using
jars
to store my melt i just put it in
parchment
um uh there's brand out there it's
called
if you care um they make a parchment
sandwich bags they're these like you
know
sandwich size parchment bags it's what
they are
personally me i fill those up with melt
and then i put them in ziploc
freezer bags and i put them in my
freezer
that allows me to store a lot more hash
in a small space
than having just a bunch of random jars
also then when i want it it's easier for
me
to take i honestly keep all my melt in
my freezer
at all times if i want to smoke it
i pull it out and personally just
drop it on some parchment paper and i
press up a little bit with my fingers to
start smoking it but it stays
in my freezer um you know when you pull
that little bit out
to enjoy you know sometimes i honestly
always just keep it in my freezer i
don't even pull it out into the room so
to let it allow it to get room
temperature
i feel like if you're just really quick
with it you know there's not enough time
for moisture to really get in there
but again i am keeping the melt in there
at all times
and what i love about that is i have
melt in there from two years ago
that looks exactly the same as the day
as when i put it in there
it is white sand and then now i'm able
to make fresh
pressed rosin and at my leisure you know
if suddenly someone wants some rosin
i just pull it out the freezer and i
load it into my little bags
and make my rosin with it and then i
have my fresh pressed rosin
um to me that fresh rosin should be
stored in a wine cooler
um 40 degrees ish that will keep that
fine
um it should keep most rosins
stable uh some or sorry i'm
most rosin that is stable will be fine
in a wine cooler
that is all you need um some stuff
that's a little less stable
you may want to freeze it just to keep
it totally the same for
long long storage but typically
in my opinion rosin is fine um in a
refrigerator
melt in the freezer and then
once you cold cure the rosin at room
temperature
i then like to keep it back in the
fridge um
you know if it's just stuff that i'm
smoking and enjoying over the next
couple weeks
it's totally fine to just keep your cold
cured rosin on your coffee table you
don't have to keep it in the fridge by
any means
that's the beauty of the cold cure
texture
is it will stay as that texture um the
whole time
whereas if you have that fresh pressed
rosin on your coffee table
it's gonna start to go through the
changes which is nice that's what i like
about fresh press and that's why i
serve a lot of fresh press is because i
like to provide that experience where
people can actually watch the texture
change for them
and then they can kind of make any
consistency that they enjoy with it
hell yeah well you know i think this
brings us to our
end there guilt thank you so much for
you know a spending this much time with
me
i know we've been trying to put together
this interview for a few months been you
know it's the
it's the summer busy season for all of
us so thank you for making the time for
us but then also
thank you for sharing your vast
experience on this topic because
you know as as you said at the top of
the show making quality
hash is about addressing
as many of these little variables as we
can
and as we continue to address more of
these variables it just continually
ups the game of our hash and as uh
you know hash becomes a new american
pastime
as uh as more homegrowers come into the
scene um
this you know these these best practices
that you've developed will
will trickle throughout the scene so so
thank you so much for your time
and uh and uh i i've enjoyed our chat
no thank you i really really really
appreciate you uh
being so persistent and making this
conversation happen
i really hope it helps people who are
listening
um i really hope your vision
of an america where everyone's making
small batch
concentrates at their home happens i
hope that's where
cannabis evolves to i really hope
legalization and normalization really
just
leads to everyone growing their own
cannabis in their yard for themselves
you don't need much room you know a few
plants goes a long way
that relationship that you'll have with
the plant will be therapeutic unto
itself
that's my vision for future of cannabis
you know it's not this
crazy wreck world of all these
corporations rolling in it
i really want to see just everyone
growing cannabis in their yard
sharing it with their neighbors sharing
it with their friends
and healing themselves beautiful
beautiful
right on so if you want to follow along
on ganja gil the ice books adventures
you can follow him best on instagram and
he's actually got two different
instagram feeds um you'll find that the
the
the kind of content that he posts at
either one are kind of different but
you'll probably want to follow them both
and so the first instagram is at the
real ice wook the real ice book
on instagram and uh uh you know you're
gonna see a lot of
hash photos and and hash you know
preparation
photos there and then uh his second
instagram is a little bit more personal
i would say
and that's uh at ganja underscore
gill underscore and gill is gil so it's
ganja underscore
gill underscore and both of those are on
instagram
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at
shapingfire.com and wherever you get
your podcasts
if you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download
your review will help others find the
show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
exclusive videos and giveaways
on the shaping fire website you will
also find transcripts of today's podcast
as well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast
that's at shaping fire and at shango
lose on instagram
be sure to check out shaping fire
youtube channel for exclusive interviews
farm tours and cannabis lectures does
your company want to reach our national
audience of cannabis enthusiasts
email hotspot at shippingfire.com to
find out how
thanks for listening to shaping fire
i've been your host shango los
[Music]