[Music]
most cannabis enthusiasts live
somewhere in the murky area between
science and bro
science we all aspire to have accurate
information but because of prohibition
we don't have a lot of good answers to
many important cannabis medicine
questions yet
and so for many it's easier for them to
give you their best
guess rather than say they don't know
and so it goes with so many cannabis
educators as well
it's not hard to get a speaking gig on
cannabis medicine at a cannabis
convention
without any actual scientific or medical
training
i've seen a multitude of speakers and
panelists who were simply
parroting what they heard from someone
else or something they read in an
unsourced internet post
too many medical cannabis speakers
vaguely explain the endocannabinoid
system
and when you ask follow-up questions
reply with additional vagueness and
platitudes but not very much detail or
scientific rigor
these are the charlatans and
carpetbaggers that degrade our community
as a whole
however there's a new breed of cannabis
educator ready to replace these folks
they are well educated well spoken
enough
confident enough and full of heart and
the right intentions
i'm seeing more and more of a new
generation who are able to study
cannabis medicine
or the cannabis plant in school they
combine
the highest ideals of our community with
the knowledge that comes from rigorous
study
i am exceptionally enthused by this new
generation of cannabis leaders
and look forward to working with them
and someday handing off the baton to
them as they take over
i encourage you to do the same if there
is someone that you follow online that
has the depth and accuracy of
information that you respect
take a moment and tell somebody about
them or make a post to your social media
about them
intentionally help their message rise
above the noise of charlatans
so that more of your friends and family
have the opportunity to learn from
someone offering
real science and real actionable
information
shining light on good cannabis people is
an act of cannabis
activism if you want to learn about
cannabis health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer
i encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week
and videos too don't rely on social
media to let you know when a new episode
is published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive that newsletter so
go to shapingfire.com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month's and all future newsletter prize
drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and i
am your host shango los
today my guest is miyabi shields phd
dr shields is co-founder of real
isolates which
ironically focuses on the importance of
secondary plant components and
synergistic cannabis blends
so essentially whole plant medicine
miyabi received their phd in
pharmaceutical sciences
focusing on the biochemistry of the
endocannabinoid system
from northeastern university in 2018.
miyabi has authored or co-authored six
peer-reviewed publications
and presently has a patent under review
for a novel
fungus and plant extraction method
miyabi also has a substantial list of
honors and awards
including a 2016 international
cannabinoid research society
pre-doctoral research award their tick
tock channel
at miyabi phd has 130 000 followers and
is where i first met miyabi
today we're going to focus on the
detailed mechanics of the
endocannabinoid system
and further understand how cannabis
medicine works
welcome to the show miyabi thanks for
having me so
cannabinoids interact with cannabinoid
receptors
in the endocannabinoid system and they
do that by
binding with those receptors that's how
they take action that's how they do what
they do
but what is actually going on at a
chemical level
when a cannabinoid pings a receptor
most cannabis educators just kind of
generally explain agonist
and antagonist and leave it at that but
my audience really wants to understand
what's going on at that granular level
so if you would
please explain what's going on at that
point of the receptor and
maybe include why some cannabinoids act
upon some receptors and not others
all right so we're gonna dive into
structural biochemistry then
but a protein so receptors are proteins
um and not protein like nutritional
protein that we eat in our diet but a
protein
molecularly just means a long string of
amino
acids so basically the receptor is this
giant
ribbon of amino acids which are it's a
really long molecule
and it forms these different shapes and
the receptors like the gpcr is a
which is a type of receptor which is
what the cannabinoid receptors are
happen to be these shapes that have like
seven
like helixes or cylinders and they're
they're arranged in such a way that
they're floating around in our membranes
and what actually happens when a
molecule binds to a receptor is that it
changes
the shape very very slightly and that
change in shape which we call a change
in conformation
is what activates or inactivates the
receptor so
this is like it's it's this amazing
process
where when thc binds to the cb1 receptor
when it changes the shape of the
receptor by binding it
um all of a sudden this new area of the
receptor becomes available because if
you're imagining these
seven cylinders all kind of floating
around all of a sudden when thc binds
it arranges the seven cylinders you know
such that this other patch is available
that starts the signaling process it's
called a signaling cascade
that happens afterwards um and in terms
of why
certain molecules have different actions
or can bind to different receptors
um that that comes down to three
different things
and the first one is shape so you know
everyone's heard
square peg round hole the same thing
with receptors and with molecules there
is a binding pocket
for most molecules which is on the
receptor it's like
a piece of the receptor that's shaped
such that it can
accept these molecules now in the cb1
receptor
thc binds you know somewhere towards the
top
um and it binds every single time in the
same
exact way because it fits into this
shape like a square peg
and another molecule that doesn't fit
into that pocket
will not bind to that receptor so that's
the first thing
and the second thing is charges like
positive and negative charges
so in chemistry there are partial
positive and negative charges and just
like
magnets they attract and repel one
another
so inside in addition to the binding
pocket
having a very specific shape there also
are very specific charges almost like a
magnet
that interact with the charges on thc or
cbd that then help to bind it even
closer
um and then the third thing is what's
called van der waals interactions but
it's really
um a metaphor for that i just think of
it like fatty velcro
because molecules that are very fatty
like the cannabinoids which are you know
extremely fatty molecules
they can have these interactions with
each other where they
they kind of stick to other fatty
molecules
and that's the third thing that kind of
binds these molecules to the receptors
and you have to have a match-up between
the shape the charges
and the fatty velcro for a molecule to
have what's called
affinity to a receptor which just means
that the molecule will bind the receptor
and then the next step further will be
what happens to the receptor when that
molecule binds
so what you were mentioning about like
the different ways in which
a molecule can interact with a receptor
thc is often called a partial agonist
for a cb1 receptor that means that it
turns it on
but only partially and this is because
when thc binds it changes the shape to
turn the receptor on
there are other molecules that can also
bind to the receptor
but they change the shape in a different
way that leave the receptor off
these are called inverse agonists and
then there are molecules that bind
and don't change the shape at all and
these are called neutral antagonists
so there's and that's just you know
those are the three main ones there's
actually
a large array of other interactions that
the molecules have but i'll stop there
i like that idea that you've got these
these uh these spirals
and and the cannabinoid approaches the
receptor
and those excite somehow and then reveal
this this lock that the cannabinoid may
or may not have the appropriate key for
um does the does the receptor
get sick
or excited to reveal that lock to every
cannabinoid that goes by that seems like
that would use a lot of energy
or or does the receptor know when it's
being approached by the cannabinoid
if it's the right one that it should
change shape for so this is actually
what's the most like what's the most
fascinating thing to me
about biochemistry is that nothing
is conscious and nothing no these
receptors and the enzymes the proteins
all the signaling molecules like the
endocannabinoids
phytocannabinoids like thc cbd serotonin
serotonin receptors all of these
um none of them are consciously aware
of things approaching or are not
approaching
everything is just happening based on a
chemical equilibrium
and everything actually in our whole
entire bodies
pretty much occurs due to forces of
enthalpy which is energy and entropy
which is like a measurement of disorder
and chaos
and right everything in the universe
tends towards disorder and chaos and
between those two you know factors it's
it's just like
whether or not something is
statistically likely to so occur
so the receptor is sitting there the
receptor is in the as
is in the membrane and it's empty and
it's you could say that it's waiting for
a molecule but really it's just kind of
floating around um
and then when you have thc molecules
floating around
at a certain concentration there will be
enough thc molecules present
that it will be you know energetically
favorable for it to bind to the receptor
and so that what i mentioned earlier
about the shape the charges
and the fatty velcro you know
hydrophobic interactions
those three things determine how
energetically favorable it is
so the affinity determines how little or
how much
you need of a certain drug to cause the
receptor to what you call
to get excited um because it's all
it's all based on whether or not it's
it's favorable
and these things are just kind of
floating around like waiting to interact
and whether
or not they interact depends entirely
upon how closely
they are shaped to one another and and
attract one another
so so the it's it's a
non-conscious thing that is looking to
continually
bring the energies into balance and so
it sounds like to a certain degree how
the the likelihood
of the receptor and the cannabinoid
interact
is a level of subtlety that that
might just be based on luck i mean not
to be
i mean it sounds like it takes a little
bit of luck they're going to put them
next to each other but we don't even
necessarily know if it that
if it's going to if they're going to
interact until they do
right so but rather than luck it's it's
based on
chemical affinity or properties so it's
not luck because the receptor
has a shape that happens to fit the
molecule very well
so if you think about it as like okay if
you and i if you and i
are like boats float we're in two boats
floating in the ocean and then there's
like
we're bumping into each other whether or
not the boats will stick to one another
depends on how strong
the magnets and velcro we have on the
outside of the the boats are to one
another right
um so it's it is exactly like you're
saying like
in luck in a certain sense people like
the the molecules are just kind of
floating around but whether or not it
chooses to interact and it's not
necessarily a choice
it depends upon how strongly they're
attracted to one another
um by these these chemical forces so
it's it's predetermined in some sense um
where
the more of a molecule you add to the
solution the more of them that are
present the higher the statistical
chance of the likelihood
um and it is exactly as you described
although i
i wouldn't say that it's luck i i would
say it's it's chemically and
energetically favorable
at that point uh i regretted using luck
as soon as i said it i'm like i'm
talking to a hard scientist
i mean i i get i get what you're saying
though it is it's not conscious though
which is
it is something amazing to think about
that you know if i go to snap
my fingers like you know i'm snapping
when i snap my fingers the chemical
reactions that
occur that allow me to snap those
fingers
at a certain point there is a conscious
thought that goes into beginning that
cascade
but all of the molecular interactions
that occur
are actually just energetically
favorable
[Laughter]
so far i'm glad that when we you know we
go to snap
the probabilities are that it happens
you know pretty much without fail
exactly and all of those probabilities
are predetermined
by our signaling systems and receptors
and i mean that's just how amazing it's
miraculous to me i mean
it's it's amazing that we can think
about snapping our fingers and that
you know for most of us and most of the
time if you want to snap your fingers
it'll just happen
so let's uh let's pull out a levels of
magnitude a little bit
so how many of these cannabinoid
receptors do we have in our body
because you know it's it's a lot of
people you know when i when i was
brought into cannabis medicine i was
taught
that um the number of receptors you have
are
not related to body weight um it has
everything to do with
your particular ability and likelihood
to grow more receptors
but more and more within dosing i'm
seeing from people
giving dosing recommendations based on
body weight
which as far as i'm aware doesn't match
the science as i learned it five six
years ago
so what is the state of the art now
about how many of these receptors we
have
and if there's any relationship to body
mass
so i don't i can't say this for absolute
fact but i
do not think that the number of
receptors are related to your your body
mass like
at all um and they they change all the
time that's another thing that we're not
like well aware of that we're still
figuring out is that there are a lot of
um interactions with our environment and
with our diet and
yes using cannabis that change the
density what's called a receptor density
for cb1 receptors and you know and also
something
you point out is how many how many
receptors do we have
normally we talk a lot about cb1
sometimes we'll talk about the cb2
receptor which
is generally uh attributed to the immune
system but
we rarely talk about the other receptors
beyond that
which you know there's there's multiples
and there's also receptors that we
originally classified
in different systems that interact with
the endocannabinoid system and
you know this is going to get a little
bit into the weeds here in terms like
separating out
different receptor types for for
specific purposes but
i personally don't believe that the
systems are separated
at all uh the endocannabinoid system is
integrally linked to the serotonin
system the dopamine system
all pretty the gaba system there's
actually an endocannabinoid
that is dopamine plus arachidonial
acid it's it's there's a there's a
serotonin um
arachneal amine to ethanol amine as well
i mean there's
those are like rare endocannabinoids and
we we don't research them as much as
we've researched or we we haven't
yet researched them as much as we've
researched um the other ones but
it also is fascinating because
the cb1 receptors and the cb2 receptors
have been shown to to dimerize which
means they bind
to receptors in other systems like for
the dopamine it'd be the d2 receptor
um and and it's been shown that if they
dimerize and if there's more than one
type of receptor that it will have a
different effect and so
we're still in the even though receptor
pharmacology has there's been a lot of
work and a lot of amazing progress i
still think we're
in the early you know in the early
stages of understanding these receptors
how they interact with each other um and
then to go further into your question
about
like dosing and and knowing how much is
good for someone i
really don't think that there's any way
to judge that from the outside
um i i can't think of any
way that you would know honestly other
than starting small
and starting with the least amount
possible and titrating up
slowly until you get your desired effect
um because everybody's so different
right yes exactly and especially with
the endocannabinoid system it's a
chicken or an egg
situation where since it's so connected
to the other
systems any change in any of those
systems will cause changes in the
endocannabinoid
system there is this theory it's a
theory
although i i believe there's a lot of
evidence for it um
that many of us have what's called
clinical endocannabinoid deficiency
which means that we have less
circulating endocannabinoids
which actually means we have more
cannabinoid receptors
um and this can cause a slew of problems
from like gi
issues mental health chronic pain
and it's you know it's still it's still
in the early stages to being
we're still early to being able to
understand all of this and how genetics
play
a role in into this um when we when we
had uh dr
russo on a few months back and well heck
probably three years back now we had him
on to talk about his
uh clinical endocannabinoid deficiency
paper and
um he talked about this this evolving
idea of the uh
uh endocannabinoid tone the cannabinoid
tone
and and he said at the time that you
know we weren't really sure
how we were going to measure it but but
people were starting to use this
vocabulary to talk about the
general i don't know veracity of the
endocannabinoids
present in the body you know whether you
had many or whether or not you had few
or
or whether or not your system was
sluggish but we haven't talked to him
about that in a long time and and i know
you're not dr rusdo
so i'm asking for your opinion not not
his of course
but um what are you seeing is the state
of the science because
you know you are you are a re you know a
more recent
phd and you are in the trenches doing
you know basic cannabinoid science every
day does this idea of the cannabinoid
tone is it is it still being
played with or have we moved past that i
mean
i believe that i have low
endocannabinoid tone
and i know other scientists who feel the
same way
i mean it's really there is no way of
clinically testing it yet
you know if i went to my doctor and i
asked hey can you check the level of my
endocannabinoids
um first of all they don't have you get
a blank stare
a test to do that but you know second of
all it's really really difficult to
measure the endocannabinoids because
they
um they degrade they oxidize really
really easily they're
it's it's difficult so there are many
reasons why
the endocannabinoid system has been um a
little bit sluggish in research behind
like other salt systems like serotonin
and dopamine are like salt based
systems you know you're cooking in the
kitchen it's easier to clean a glass
that had salt water in it than it is to
clean a glass that had like butter mixed
with maple syrup
and it's the same when you get to the
molecular scale
so if not if not maybe even a little bit
more difficult when things get sticky
um but in going back to the
endocannabinoid tone and the state of it
um i think that there is a lot more
research coming out like more recently
i've seen some more clinical data on
um you know different instances of
people with chronic health conditions
where they're finding hey
this has they have low endocannabinoids
like the ones that come to mind are
autism spectrum disorder and ptsd
both there have been clinical studies
for both of those populations that show
that you have a decreased amount of
circulating endocannabinoids
and with ptsd they've actually shown
that that either it's a chicken or an
egg
there's an increase in the number of cb1
receptors
and so in theory if you were
you know to have a clinical
endocannabinoid deficiency and like me
you know i'll just talk about myself i
believe i have low endocannabinoids i
don't i don't make enough of them
um and this is how cannabis helps me
because
the molecules in cannabis mimic the
endocannabinoids and so
i have a sub threat i have a low level
of endocannabinoids and it causes me
a myriad of symptoms really and if i
use cannabis products my body is feeling
like a restoration of balance
because even though i'm low in
endocannabinoids i'm giving my body
phytocannabinoids that restore that that
signaling i don't know if that does is
that
that makes sense yeah absolutely as a
matter of fact i would think that just
about everybody
is experiencing uh deficiency if you
look at what the general
causes are which are you know generally
you know stress
questionable stress sleep questionable
nutrition environmental
toxins and immune suppressing
pharmaceuticals i mean that's american
life
it's funny you mentioned nutrition
because the i mean the endocannabinoids
are
omega-6 fatty acids and yeah we often
we often don't think about how you know
pushing for a certain
you know high carb low fat diets
it would affect your endocannabinoid
tone i mean most
yeah i agree it's most people
potentially have a deficiency and the
only thing
to say though is that like you don't
know this right i mean this is the only
thing
left clinically is to to actually go in
there and figure it out and i think it's
it's in progress to and to go all the
way back to answering the question
um it is in progress and i i do believe
i
have spoken to many people who believe
that endocannabinoid deficiency is real
and so far in terms of like a theory and
calling it a theory
there hasn't been anything to refute it
um so that's important so here
around here we pretty much take it as
fact so it's interesting actually to
hear
you know um a frontline scientist like
you referring to it as a theory because
we're all like sold already you know so
yeah i mean yeah gravity
i mean gravity is a theory well good
point
so so let's talk you really attracted my
attention when you said that over the
course of our lives
the amount and sorts of receptors that
we have come and go
that's super interesting to me and then
the part that um you know you mentioned
that
the cannabinoids are are fatty acids and
um
last episode we had dr chris spooner on
and he was
encouraging everybody to take fish oil
supplements
as a way to support your endocannabinoid
system so i'm going to give you kind of
like a
a big big area question and you can take
it where you wish
i'm curious to know if our receptors
increase and decrease during our lives
are they is is this increase and
decrease more
related to well i guess i want to know
what factors are right is it
is it age is it diet is it everything
because most of us
want to i would think want to increase
the
number of receptors in our body so that
we can
process more cannabinoids for our
overall
health and so we would want to build
those up and if there are things that we
can do
or awarenesses we should have at times
of life that the the number of receptors
would go down that would probably be
good information for us to know
absolutely and i and i do want to point
out that for some people it would be
good to have your receptor levels
actually go down
which would be like making more
endocannabinoids it's all about a
balance
so you're trying to find you're trying
to find the right balance
and some of us have too many receptors
and some of us have not not enough
um and it's interesting about the
omega-3 for fish oil
supplements my my very first research
project ever
was looking at omega-3 and omega-6
dietary fatty acids in in mice um
and seeing like what changes that had on
on a cosinoids and which are downstream
of the endocannabinoids and i think
so in terms of what causes the changes
in receptor density i mean there's a
number of factors
age is certainly a factor i lean away
from just saying everything because
that's just a non-answer right
um but unfortunately it's pretty much
true
but i mean age is certainly a fast
factor because the endocannabinoid
system
is really important for a huge number of
very important processes right like the
the basic
the basic ones are metabolism immune
system
and inflammation and then overall brain
activity brain hyperactivity um so those
are really really important tasks and
they have different needs depending on
whether or not we're still growing as
we're children
as we you know as we age and mature um
so age is certainly a factor and and it
does change
the other factor that you mentioned
stress stress is a factor
um cortisol and elevated levels of
stress factors in the brain will change
it and
and this is where we we get into the
chicken and the egg
because it's hard to know whether like
whether the endocannabinoid system and
the dysregulation
of it is the source of the problem or
whether it's a symptom
however an unbalanced a quote-unquote
like unbalanced or dysregulated
endocannabinoid system
has been associated with almost every
single disorder
or pathology like i i don't think i can
think of a single one that hasn't been
associated with the endocannabinoid
system other than like genetic mutations
or genetic disorders
um that have a very clear like molecular
mechanism
and it's funny because that's kind of a
challenge right because it's great to
have this
one herb that can help us in so many
ways but it also has caused so many
people to say
oh what is with this cannabis medicine
they talk about it like it's a panacea
like it's like it solves everything and
and what i try to tell people is like no
it doesn't solve everything it just
solves
one thing but that one thing is the
endocannabinoid system and it touches
all the systems it makes it very hard
for people to believe
that's that's a great way of putting it
the way the way that i usually
explain it is that um you know the the
cannabinoids are really powerful
anti-inflammatories and it's my personal
belief that almost
all of these disorders come from like
dysregulations and in inflammation
and not not inflammation in terms of
like oh i sprained my ankle and now my
ankle has
swollen up and is inflamed but you know
at the cellular and molecular level
inflammation is just inflammatory
signaling
molecules um and like you said about
about
you know endocannabinoid tone being kind
of an american having low
endocannabinoid tone being an american
feature
there's there's a lot of evidence that
shows that having high
in systemic inflammation is is a problem
um and that we we don't really have any
way of of knowing or understanding
where we're at on our threshold until we
remove something right so it's like
like speaking from my personal
experience like i have a lot of
inflammation all the time stress causes
inflammation and then also like
chronic pain inflammation gi
inflammation um there's so many things
with which i think inflammation plays a
mechanistic factor
because it's i mean in terms of our
immune system
like what is inflammation at the
molecular level it really is
the most basic way that our body signals
to
itself hey something is wrong here like
if you think of it as like one cell
trying to talk to another cell in the
body
when it releases inflammatory like
inflammatory factors
it's trying this is one part of your
body one single cell
trying to tell the other part of your
body hey something's wrong here
um and so having super high levels of
inflammation causes just a
large number of problems and we often
get like desensitized to it because
we're just living
with systemically high inflammation
um and so when yes cannabis has um
like you know people are saying oh it's
a cure-all i do not believe it's a
cure-all
but i do believe that it's a powerful
anti-inflammatory and that
inflammation plays a crucial role in
most disorders and is really you know
not like underappreciated but it's just
that it's not really
talked about as inflammation because in
the general public when we think of
inflammation we think of like a swollen
lip or or a bruised ankle not the
signaling version of it
exactly uh and inflammation is probably
the most
basic cellular response to stress that
any type of of life has and that we
developed it's
it's part of what's called the uh the
innate immune system so like our immune
systems have two different
two different sides of it and
inflammation is the most basic side and
so
cannabis helps by being a powerful
anti-inflammatory
and there are so many symptoms
that are mechanistically related to
systemic inflammation
so if we we've so we've been talking
about how the endocannabinoid system is
actually integrated with all the systems
and i like what you said early on that
you know you
you actually see it all as one system
not really as discreet parts because
they're all
there's so much interplay and and in
passing we all just kind of say oh
you know the endocannabinoid system is
the body's homeostasis
uh device it's it you know if
something's running hot it cools it down
if something's sluggish it picks it up
well that's that's great as far as like
copywriting goes right
but what happens at uh at a more
chemical level like
like we did earlier on what what happens
that what is the method of action that
the endocannabinoid
system takes to create homeostasis
so i would say then to and it's
different in
different parts of the body in different
parts of the brain it could even be
different but the number one like most
generic way of describing
it would be that it it can
quiet like different
cells and it tells things to be quiet so
sometimes you hear people saying like oh
cannabis makes you slow or
cannabis reduces your brain activity um
you know technically that's true
but that's not always a bad thing
because sometimes there's too much brain
activity
and it's desirable to quiet
parts of the brain that are not supposed
to be speaking um so if you think about
the way that if we're talking about i'm
talking about signaling now from
one brain cell to another brain cell you
could think about it as a one-way street
or like have you ever played the game
telephone sure where
yeah where one person whispers in
someone's ear and then and so on and
it's
it's one direction um that's how
neurotransmitters
fire so they go from when you have one
they're like an end-to-end daisy chain
yes that's exactly
the their end to end and you have one
neuron and then you have what's called a
synapse which is the place or the space
between the neuron
and then you have the the other end so
you have a speaking neuron and a
listening
no does that make sense there's a
talking a talking side
and then a listening side um so the
pre-synapse
before is the talking side and the post
synapse is the listening side
and for all of the classic
neurotransmitters they fire
from the presynapse across the synapse
to the
postsynapse so they go from speaking
side to listening side
and the endocannabinoids are the only
molecules that go the opposite direction
and so the endocannabinoids are created
in the postsynapse on the listening side
and they transport across the synapse in
what's called a retrograde
fashion like opposite and they go to the
pre-synapse
so essentially if you have a long daisy
chain if let's let's say
in your telephone line of one-way daisy
chains
you have one telephone in there that's
talking way too loud or way too much
the only way for us to quiet it other
than finding a way to go
all the way around the daisy chain again
to quiet it is through the
endocannabinoid system
which talks in the opposite direction
and says hey like
can you just be quiet and and what is
scent
what what is actually sent is that a
particular chemical that's sent
upstream and that endocannabinoid oh
this is the endocannabinoid itself and
so
then it goes and it will interact with a
receptor there and then and then
depending on the nature of how it's
talking it'll either be a
agonist or antagonist or a would you say
reverse agonist
inverse agonist so all the all the
endocannabinoids are
um some not all of them but the main
ones anandamide and 2hg
are agonist partial agonists at the at
the cannabinoid receptors
so if we're going back to the the
pre-synapse and post-synapse the talking
and the listening
end you have the endocannabinoids they
get created on the listening end
and then the receptors are on the
talking end so they
are being transported across the synapse
they bind to the receptors and they
activate them and when you activate the
cannabinoid receptors
it activates this very specific g
protein that is inhibitory
and that g protein follows the signaling
cascade that ultimately
it changes the voltage all of all of our
cells have
a voltage potential it's like an it's an
electrical potential to fire
so if you think about it like whether or
not a brain cell let's say this brain
cell is firing way too often
if you then synthesize the
endocannabinoids
and then they activate the cannabinoid
receptors the cannabinoid receptors will
change the voltage of that entire cell
so that it's less likely
to fire i follow this
so and yeah please ask please ask me a
question i'm just catching up so so
and because it's less likely to fire
that
is its response to the up chain
saying shh like don't talk so much
that's really great
you know me not miyabi i really and
there's actually
liberation in this information i can't
be the only one listening to you going
oh my god i've wondered this for so long
but most people are most people don't
have this education
uh and and to have it be so
contemporary that they can speak to us
in this level of detail so this is this
is really fantastic
um so thank you and we are going to go
ahead and take our first break
um you are listening to shaping fire and
my guest today is cannabis scientist and
educator
miyabi shields
[Music]
there is no doubt that autoflowering
cannabis plants have finally come in to
their own
and night owl seeds works tirelessly
bringing you autoflower genetics that
are reliable
thriving and with extraordinary terpene
profiles
night owl seeds is an industry leader
because of the focused work of their
founder daz
daz is passionate about the cannabis
plant and pushing what autoflowers can
do and cultivators know that these
efforts show through in his seeds
and night owl seeds really are
extraordinary just take a look at the
thousands of photos by fans on instagram
the proof is there and obvious terpenes
are complex and rich plants have vigor
if you are a fan of mephisto genetics
like i am you'll likely also love night
owl seeds
night owl founder daz worked with mitch
mephisto to build the mephisto brand for
years
including breeding mephisto's much-loved
sour stomper and cosmic queen cultivars
i'm growing both night owl and mephisto
this year because i want the best
and night owl seeds knows how to
cultivate community too
daz puts out great stickers exclusive
packaging for limited runs
and desirable freebies he really draws
you in if you love creative branding
night owl even has the secret owl
society text club
just text the word night owl one word to
seven 760-670-3130
for early announcements and exclusive
opportunities
of course you can see lots of photos and
find out about upcoming drops by
following the night owl seeds instagram
too
at daz.nightowl that's
d-a-z-dot-night owl you can get your
packs of night owl seeds at several
distributors
including dc seed exchange insane seeds
and hembra genetics that's night owl
seeds
there's a difference because we're
different
[Music]
for 20 years humboldt seed company has
been family owned in providing reliable
high yielding seeds originating in
northern california
while the current trend is to slap one
super male into a line of hyped strains
humboldt seed company continues to breed
with precision and care
by doing large sifts and back crosses to
emphasize the absolute
best traits that a line has to offer
this kind of breeding takes time
talent and space to work no matter what
kind of aroma you are particularly into
humboldt seed will likely have something
you'll love if you love fruit
you can choose from banana mango apricot
papaya blueberry blood orange melon and
lemons across their various strains
they have all gas glue and classic sour
diesel lines as well
of course there are the heritage
california strains like og kush
jack hair and headband and their
award-winning blueberry muffin
is one that delights just about
everybody's palate especially when
concentrated
humboldt seed company is proud to bring
to market the infamous freak show
cultivar ii
which has a great thc high but looks so
much like a fern that some folks can't
even identify it as cannabis
it's a plant that really needs to be
seen to be believed
if you're looking for well-balanced cbd
seeds humboldt seed company
can turn you on to cbd strains that
actually have
flavor like the dill and pepper terpenes
of willie g's lebanese land race
whether you are looking for regular
feminized or autoflowers
humboldt seed company has the gear to
make this your best growing cycle
ever visit humboldtseedcompany.com today
to check out their line of vigorous
genetics download their catalog
and find out where you can pick them up
you can also check out their instagram
at the humboldt seed company to check
out their gorgeous flowers
and the extraordinary freak show plant
humboldt seed company
let them know shango sent ya
if you're an autoflowering cannabis
enthusiast this event's for you
announcing the 2021 autoflower cup
august 6th 7th and 8th in a little whip
washington
just outside of seattle presented by
camp rudderalis this gathering has
something for everyone
there's the autoflower cup competition
of course but it's so much more than
that
there'll be a stunden glass hookah
lounge a pop-up magical butter chocolate
shop
and waterfront marketplace with an array
of vendors there will be an old school
autoflower seed swap
joint rolling competition cannabis
cooking demos
solventless squishing demos and late
night documentary screenings
of both dost and fantastic fungi the
food will be lit too
including chef sebastian carosi's
award-winning classics like elk chili
kobe beef kimchi dogs oyster po boys and
razor clam chowder
enjoy the campfire chili and oyster
chowder cook off
wild oyster harvesting mushroom foraging
and s'mores around the campfires each
night
each day there dan jimmy of mandalorian
will teach about autoflowers and there
will be presentations on closet
cultivation
and hunting for psilocybin mushrooms the
competition is open to everyone
commercial and home growers there's a
category for photoperiod plants too
so check out the autoflower cup 2021.com
for those details
clearly there will be plenty of cannabis
around but due to state law it won't be
supplied by the event
but there will be easy public toking
which is why this is a strictly over 21
event
you can camp rent a cabin or stay at a
local airbnb
glamping and rv packages are available
too
i'm happy to say that shaping fire is a
sponsor of the event and i'll be there
too
i look forward to connecting with other
autoflower fans like me
so get all the details at the autoflower
cup
2021.com and follow the instagram at
the autoflower cup 2021 and i'll see you
in august at autoflower cup
when we bring the autoflower family
together to celebrate
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host
shango los and our guest this week is
cannabis scientist and educator miyabi
shields
so during the first set we were talking
about the endocannabinoid
system itself the the system of
receptors
and and how they work to keep our body
in homeostasis
um clearly we could have continued on
that topic and it's
so fascinating but we're gonna shift a
little bit during second set
and focus on individual cannabinoids
because
since most of what we try to learn here
on shaping fire are things that we can
use either for our own health or
or in the you know the for the health of
the people that we are we love
um you know we try to keep things very
um
um very usable very actionable
information so let's let's start talking
about individual
uh cannabinoids so miyabi you know most
of us have seen the chart
um showing how cannabinoids degrade
from starting as cbg or cbn and then
degrading
down into other cannabinoids when
exposed to
time or heat i believe it is so
it's not really usually explained why
though um
and you know i've seen on your tic toc
many times you play with the molecular
models
and i know you've got an intimate
understanding of this so
if you'd walk us through it what is
happening and why is it happening at the
chemical level
all right so we're gonna basically go
all the way back and just talk about how
that
everything in the universe i mentioned
earlier that in in the body
everything comes down to a chemical
equilibrium but actually this applies to
everything in the entire
universe pretty much although i'm not
sure about
i'm not sure if you go way out into
space if that applies but um
but pretty much everything comes down to
basically
energy and entropy so the reason
why these molecules degrade is because
if you leave them open to oxygen
so let's let me back up if you were to
have the molecules by themselves
like in a complete vacuum and and or you
can add what we call like an
inert gas which is like argon or helium
it's it's a gas that is non-reactive
um if you were to have the molecule and
it were to be kept
in the dark in some either a vacuum or
a gas that's non-volatile and if it were
to be kept very very cold
like as cold as you possibly could keep
it um it in theory
would be stable that way forever the
only reason
why things degrade with heat light and
exposure to air and oxygen
is because even though we see air around
us and we don't think anything of it
there's a lot of of things floating
around in the air mostly oxygen and
nitrogen
um and some other forms like carbon
dioxide and
and other depending on where you are and
what what's in your air right
um but you know you heard that um the
story where it's like hey you asked the
fish how's the water and the fish goes
like what's water
yeah um we're pretty much the same way
with air so we don't really think too
much about it but there's plenty of
things
in air that when you expose them over
time will will come to
have a chemical reaction with these
molecules um and the cannabinoids are
quite stable
but there are certain areas of of it
that are prone to
oxidation that's the main chemical
reaction that occurs
and then slowly from there things will
continue to break down because
oxygen is pretty reactive um in terms of
like the types of
of molecule or the types of atoms that
you introduce
it introduces charges whenever you have
charges around they're likely to
interact with other charges
um and that's that's the reason so the
reason why it occurs is just that it's
it's chemically favorable um so that's
another reason why if you he
if you heat things you're giving them
energy and it just happens faster
so the reason why heat is a factor is
just because
it adds energy into the system
exactly for this thing to occur that
would have occurred regardless
um and yeah there's i guess if you look
at a molecule
there are certain areas of certain
molecules that are more vulnerable
to degradation or to like an attack of
of an outside
molecule and all of these things depend
on how these atoms are
linked together and how stable that link
is to one another because if you think
about it um if you
have seen my videos and you see the
molecules are held together by these
little plastic
um you know they're just bonded together
by these little plastic strings
in my model all of those pieces of
plastic look the same
but in real life they're all different
um and they're they're different
strengths
like some of the atoms are held together
by a fishing line and others are held
together by steel poles
so so different cannabinoids have got
their weak spot where they're at the
most risk
yep and that that will change when you
once you introduce
a you oxidize it then everything changes
again
um and that's one of the things i found
so fascinating about chemistry
um in the beginning is just this crazy
crazy amount of versatility that small
small changes
in molecular structure cause giant
changes um
you know downstream so
let's talk about the the time of
efficacy for
um you know two of our most favorite
cannabinoids uh thc and cbd
so excuse me so for
for caregivers everywhere we're often
trying to explain to our patient
um you know the time frame that they're
going to get relief
and you know most most cannabis patients
especially at the beginning they don't
have a really good understanding of the
endocannabinoid system
and honestly most caregivers even the
ones with their heart in the right place
might not have that great of an
understanding of the endocannabinoid
system
they just know how to apply the medicine
in ways that tend to get relief and for
that
everyone is grateful however you know
there
are faster acting cannabinoids and there
are there seem to be slower action of
the cannabinoids as well
and i'm going to give you an example
that's pretty common for caregivers to
talk about
which i'm open to the possibility that
this is not true right so
you don't have to defend my position if
this is wrong like call it out but
very often when we talk about cbd people
talk about
benefits that you get now and benefits
you get later for example
if you are having you know an anxious
day
full of rumination you can take some you
know whole plant cbd
and you know something with cbd dominant
and it will
um you know have a tendency to correct
the balance of chemicals
and or um you know hit the receptors
that that
that decrease your experience of
dysphoria
of anxiety so so so that would be your
benefit potentially today
but over the long term for example after
somebody
has been taking cbd for you know four or
six weeks
i'll often hear back from them and
they'll say oh yeah you know i
um i started taking cbd for my migraines
uh but then the diarrhea that i've had
for three years uh cleared up and and i
explained to them
you know in layman's terms that one of
the properties
of a strong endocannabinoid system is
that the
the system goes through and does uh
housekeeping like cleaning the cilia in
the gut
of of the mucus and so there's there's
essentially gifts with purchase when you
when you take cbd things that you never
intended but which are totally great to
have
so um um i'm very open to the
possibility that there's scientific mess
in that example miyabi so so so feel
free to
you know correct me but but essentially
the part i'm trying to get at is
cannabinoid seems to have help now and
help
later how does how
what's up with that from your viewpoint
as a scientist
so i would say that first of all that
it's
not it's absolutely not a pseudoscience
and that it's definitely true
that there are different types of
effects that are separated so
help now would be what you would call an
acute effect
that's something that's happening
immediately so we're gonna use cbd as
the example
um cbd actually has very low affinity
for
the cb1 and cb2 receptors but it has
been shown to be what's called
an allosteric modulator at the cb1
receptor which is
just a fancy way for saying it like
binds to a different location
um but let's use cbd as an example
so the acute effect of cbd is when you
are actually taking the cbd
and like it happens within like let's
say if you take it if you take it orally
like in a tincture
or an edible um you know it takes 45
minutes to an hour
and then like maybe it lasts like two
hours maybe four hours
that those effects that you feel right
then are acute effects
so that's the effect of the molecule
binding to the outside of the cb1
receptor
and it actually decreases the cb1
receptors activity
um that would be an acute effect the
help later
that you described help now being acute
effect help later
is what's called a it's like a a
longer-term effect
um this actually comes from how our body
restructures itself our body does
housekeeping like you mentioned the
endocannabinoid system does housekeeping
um our body goes through all of its
systems and does housekeeping
pretty much you're in a constant state
of managing
what is happening now and what's going
to happen in the future
and what your body does when let's say
you're taking a little bit of cbd i take
a bit of cbd every day
and what my body has done over time it
is it is
it's responded to that happening so i
get the acute effects
from taking cbd every day but then
there's also these secondary long-term
effects that
happen later which is your body
restructuring and changing certain
levels of receptors
and changing certain levels of
endocannabinoids and
other like highly likely other signaling
molecules like serotonin
um and actually this may seem like a
little bit like scary that there's these
two types of effects but
that's pretty much the entire premise of
like
ssris and anti like you know mood mood
stabilizing medications
many of those also function in the same
way where they take a few weeks
to to see actually whether or not
they're going to
you know have have a beneficial effect
because they work on this
what is a secondary mechanism um that's
a longer term thing
so our bodies do these things so
every single receptor when it's when
it's activated
um will eventually go through a process
to to inactivate it
part of this is our body takes it it's
called endocytosis and our body like
recycles
the receptors you could think about it
as like a recycling program
and if you think about it as a recycling
program every time our body recycles
these receptors
it's kind of like counting and taking
into account how many of each type
is being recycled then it will adjust
the amount that it creates like in in
response to that
that's that's incredible it's it's it's
it's um
i mean i know we don't want to put too
much consciousness into these processes
but it's like a thinking machine it's
self
it's self calibrating based on what our
body needs and i love that
oh absolutely i mean yeah it's between
knowing that things are happening
completely
like based on just chance or luck as you
put it earlier but as i was putting it
chemical
like chemical affinity and energy
everything is happening based on that
but it's
it's this magical combination that is
quite conscious i mean there is
the reason why this is happening is to
try and keep us
well and to try to keep us alive and and
functioning
and life is miraculous in that way
before we move on
i want to hit on one more example of
this acute versus
longer term uh impacts and let's talk
about thc
with inflammation since you sound like
you're very deep on inflammation as well
so we talk about thc being useful
both in the moment acutely for
inflammation pain
and then long term for inflammation as
well
and for lack of having heard a better
explanation how i normally
ask how i normally explain it to
patients when they stop me
like after a talk or something i'll say
well you know
if you take uh thc now even at
subperceptual doses
you are decreasing uh
some inflammation now but even more so
you're decreasing your experience of the
pain that comes from inflammation now
which makes you feel like you have less
inflammation but then
if you keep on taking thc every three or
four
hours the natural anti-inflammation
characteristics of thc
keep on for lack of a better term
beating down
on the inflammation and or or shushing i
guess
you know telling telling those receptors
to be quiet
and and then over time the inflammation
goes down
because those cells are not yelling as
much
that there is a problem so i don't know
if that's the correct science but there
does seem to be this dichotomy between
thcs helping an inflammation patient
now in the next three hours versus a
month from now when they've been taking
thc
all that time and they're all like gosh
you know my
my arthritis is significantly improved
oh absolutely one of i guess what i
would say this has to do with is that
inflammation is like a threshold or an
exponential
response where you feel pain
above a certain threshold right um of
inflammation and your body responds to
that
by firing like let's just call it like a
pain signaling it's like a it's like a
chain
depending on where your inflammation is
so actually rheumatoid arthritis runs in
my family
and i wake up with stiff fingers all the
time right now
um and the pain would originate
in the nerves in my hand so the
inflammation originates in your hand
and but you actually feel the pain in
your brain
right so it it's true that they have
anti-inflammatory properties it's
also true that if you reduce
inflammation and you decrease the amount
of pain that you feel
overall that you're decreasing the
strength of the pathway
of pain which is something that's um
you know it's difficult it's a difficult
topic and it's difficult to prove
but there's this saying that that people
neuroscientists say it all the time
you say i don't know if you've heard it
but it's neurons that fire together wire
together
that's this is the this is the saying
because
when you have brain cells that are in a
circuit and they're used to firing
in this circuit they become stronger so
actually if you think about them as like
roads uh if you imagine
like when you're if your brain is
totally naive
it's like a desert or an area and
there's there's no roads there's no
point from a to b
so everything's just a dirt path you
start making the dirt paths
but then over time you start using this
one path
more and more and more let's say that's
the pathway for
inflammatory pain right your body
becomes really sensitized to that path
because
you're using it so much that it's not a
dirt road anymore it turns into
a street that then turns into a major
highway
that then turns it turns into the
fastest route of signaling
and our our brain cells are like that so
when they fire together they wire
together more tightly and it's easier
for them to go down
these pathways um and so it's
interesting
specifically with pain it's so difficult
to piece apart
whether or not it's inflammation
certainly but also whether it's it's a
sensitization
to your body even even feeling pain um
and this is i don't have the answers
for this either this is just you know me
talking out loud thinking about
inflammation and and how people feel
inflammation and pain because
like from from my perspective i have
chronic joint pain i have a lot of
form i have a lot of injuries um that
i've been told that these injuries
are the cause of my pain but i've also
had
a lot of scans and things where i didn't
disclose to anyone that i had prior
injuries and
no one can see anything structurally
wrong
um with any and any part of it um and
there's this there's this piece that i
guess you cannot prove
which is where is the sensitivity like
where is the sensitization to pain
part of it is in the inflammatory
factors which is the acute effect which
you were
saying part of it is that that first
effect
which is that there are inflammatory
factors there and that cannabis can help
by reducing that inflammation
and then the second part of it is
breaking the cycle
of firing your pain cells all the time
or your pain signaling pathway all the
time because like
the less than your body uses that
pathway
the less likely it will be to sort of
follow down that pathway
you know i've been talking a lot about
just like entropy
and chemical like statistical chance of
something happening and
and everything in the body just runs
downhill
so meaning like the easiest path forward
yes
and if it's the easiest path for your
body to feel pain because your body has
been in pain for years and years and
years
it will be difficult to break that cycle
without
removing the pain and then there's
obviously the fact that some
there are some aspects of pain that are
structural that are caused that the
cannabinoids can only help so much with
right like if you have a nerve
impingement
or something that's actually like
causing like a physical cause
yeah something that's mechanically wrong
um but i think uh
for from from my opinion a big piece of
the long-term benefits of cannabis for
chronic pain is breaking this cycle
and also in what i mentioned earlier in
the in the quieting or the shushing
of the cells because some of us are are
hypersensitive to a lot i mean i'm
i'm hypersensitive to a lot of stimuli
not just
not just pain but other types of things
too right like auditory stimuli or
like certain types of like tactile
feelings
and you know we we don't know
between between person to person it you
can't tell
what what someone's threshold for pain
is because pain is completely subjective
you know we we can only feel what we
feel
in in our bodies which is why those pain
charts are always so
unsatisfying you know i feel seven today
or six or sometimes they show
you know uh stick drawing faces it's
like oh gosh this is a fool's errand
from the beginning
right and as speaking from someone who's
pretty much lived like my entire life at
like a five
or above like at a at a certain point it
just starts becoming like a status quo
and your body
actually your body actually can
think of it that way if that if that
makes sense like your body gets into
these patterns
that it will perpetuate um and i think
that
in some ways that's that's a way that
the cannabinoids can help is by
decreasing that that sensitivity
um and then there's there's another
follow-up piece which is that
the cannabinoids and the metabolites so
we talked about thc and you mentioned
that like you know
if there's an onset of action and then
it's metabolized by the body
and it's it is sequestered away
in our fat and it gets stored in our fat
and that's that's one of the reasons why
you can test positive
on a on a drug test for weeks and weeks
afterwards
um is because our body still is
processing and releasing these
metabolites so
if you're using over a longer course of
time then you have a build up
of these metabolites um it's something
called like the depot effect it's
actually
um something that is harnessed for other
medications like birth control is the
first one that comes to mind
um utilizes the depot effect for like a
long-term
release essentially um so that's a whole
nother mechanism
in which like a long-term effect of of
cannabis can can build up and be slowly
released because
even though those metabolites are not
psychoactive
it doesn't mean that they're not still
circulating at low levels causing like
anti-inflammatory effects
um and that's something that i think is
is possible but to my knowledge i don't
know if either of those things
have been like proven right on i follow
that so
let's talk about tolerance breaks for a
moment so
we understand that tolerance breaks are
are good so that we can increase our
sensitivity to cannabinoids
um and we also know that anybody who
works with patients knows that
trying to convince a patient to go on a
tolerance break is very difficult
because
if you know for a lot of people they get
to cannabis last
and then when it works they're all like
well none of the pharma works without
terrible side effects and they hold on
to cannabis so dearly
now we're telling them to you know take
two three seven days off
which seems unreal and i think every
all of us who work with patients would
would be
served by having a better understanding
of what
happens at a chemical level during a
tolerance break so that we can make it
more you know more real more mechanical
for the patient that we're trying to
encourage to
give up their most effective medication
for a few days
so will you go through what happens in
our body during a tolerance break
yep absolutely so when when you are
using
cannabis regularly and so i i use
cannabis regularly and i regularly take
tolerance breaks
um and when you're using it regularly
what your body does have a compensatory
reaction which is what i was describing
earlier is it it decreases the level
of cb1 receptors that are present and
this is
kind of an oversimplification
simplification because there are other
changes that occur too but for the most
part
when you have that decrease in cb1
receptors
you notice it because you have to
increase
the amount of cannabis that you use to
get the same effect
right and this is at the this is kind of
at the crutch of of tolerance
is you your body has
less and less cb1 receptors and actually
you know i
personally believe that a certain level
of tolerance is beneficial for
me i maintain a low level of tolerance
like i never
i never take a tolerance break to
completely re-sensitize
because if i completely re-sensitize my
body goes a hundred percent
the opposite direction and it makes way
too many cb1 receptors
so essentially when you're talking to or
what would be my opinion if i was
talking to cannabis patients about
tolerance breaks and why they're
necessary
it's because you're trying to balance
the endocannabinoid system
and when you use cannabis every day
you're constantly
lowering not constantly it doesn't
happen like super quickly like not to
don't want to make anyone look paranoid
but you're lowering your level of
cb1 receptors right like as you use
cannabis
if you use it every day you use it over
time you're going to be lowering those
cb1 receptors when you go on a tolerance
break it allows your body
to make more cb1 receptors and increase
them again
and you're kind of always shooting to
find a sweet spot and
if you just continuously use cannabis
and
you never take a tolerance break you're
continuously developing tolerance and
you're going to be continuously lowering
your cb1 receptor density and for some
people there's not a huge
downside to that but for others there's
big negative
side effects and it all depends on the
patient and what their goals are
right because one of the biggest
problems with tolerance is that
when you develop a tolerance then the
cannabis is no longer effective
for what you need it to be effective for
um
and i was just talking to another
scientist about this is that
in our opinion the reason why we take
tolerance breaks is because we need the
plant to work
when we need it and maybe that would be
a way
to to describe it to people who are
maybe hesitant to try even taking a
tolerance break is that
you don't want the plant to lose
efficacy
you don't want it to stop working
and it's possible that that happens when
you develop tolerance
and it's also possible that continuing
to develop tolerance will lead to other
negative side effects like having
problems sleeping or having like other
like
there's some people who get um
withdrawal symptoms of anxiety when they
go to take a tolerance break so
essentially the more tolerance you
develop the more difficult it becomes to
take a tolerance break and it's always
easier just to regularly take
you know build breaks into your routine
um
and again though this is this is going
to be different from from person to
person because
i feel like i'm hypocritical even saying
this because i do
maintain a a level of tolerance like i
pretty much take i take very short
tolerance breaks
but i don't take breaks that are longer
than a week
um and i don't i don't completely
re-sensitize my system because
my system as it is on a complete
tolerance break
is not a high quality of life for me so
it
i don't want to be i don't want to like
mislead or you know
spread spread negative um negative
suggestions this is just
like my experience is that i i do
maintain a low
a very very low tolerance um and i find
that to be
beneficial and i think it's it's all
about finding that
balance and maybe explaining it in that
way where you
need the balance of having the risk like
the the relief
like having the plant actually provide
you with
an effective relief balanced with
having the right level of receptors in
your brain right on i follow this
and um and it makes a lot of sense too
because there are a lot of patients who
they do want to take some amount of
tolerance breaks so that the
the cannabis is more effective for them
on a daily basis they want to get
their receptors and and you know
cannabinoids more in balance but at the
same time
going down to zero tolerance could be
very extreme as well because
i know that if i if if i have to stop um
using cannabinoids for a while for some
reason when i come back
sometimes i get so high that like it's
it's dysphoric right
or people who have got um severe pain
and they use cannabinoids at work to
treat their pain
well you know if they were to go a
significant amount of time
for a for a complete tolerance break
well they may just be like super stoned
at work
you know like there there really is you
know advanced patients with a lot of
experience about cannabis
really embrace the whole idea of
individualized ken habitopathic care
because
we are all different but at the
beginning we have to give patients
general ideas and then you know it takes
them almost no time you know once a
patient has got
cannabinoids they become you know
scientists of their own body and it's
and it's great to see
i think that that's an amazing piece of
you know on one side i know that it's
something that people view as a very
negative thing
about cannabis and about plant medicine
just in general is that
everyone says are all it works for some
people and it does nothing for other
people and there's and it's
i think that that's an amazing gift to
be able to be empowered
you know with with the option um and i
do think that having like
guidelines though is like for example if
i was talking to someone
new who was who is just getting into
cannabis i absolutely would tell them to
take tolerance breaks
i i also think that tolerance breaks are
really great
you know clarity or relativity where
then you can approach
your use again every time you take a
tolerance break
it allows you to rehash exactly
what therapeutic benefits you're getting
from the plant how it's helping you
and it gives you more perspective i
think um
on that so i absolutely would in the
beginning like
advise people to take tolerance breaks
and then
like you said um most of the time you
know if this when when cannabis works
for someone and like you said it's a
last resort i mean
i have to admit like cannabis was not
the first
thing that i tried um and it was in many
ways
a last resort like i was not
i was not well um and when people
are when you when you come to that and
you find something that works for you
it drives you to be so interested in it
because especially
in this prohibition era when we've been
educated
or at least i was educated that there
you know there's nothing worse than
being an addict and that it's going to
ruin your life
and that it's this horrible horrible
thing um and then you know you
experience this relief from it that you
don't get from anything else
i think that instills a passion of
understanding of health on a deeper
level and i think that's one of the
greatest things
about cannabis i think personal
empowerment and personal responsibility
in our in our
lives is important and and a huge
positive thing so
i would encourage like other people you
know listening and people
that like spreading the knowledge and
the education that
there's a lot of power in personal
experience and i know scientists are
always talking about
you know clinical research and having to
have you know having
trying to have the most experimental
hard scientific data i agree with that i
think that research is necessary
but i also think that there is a huge
huge amount of value in in the personal
stories and in the personal narrative
and we're all a part of that so right on
the the oral history of medicine
so i've got one one last quick question
for you before we go to commercial
these tolerance breaks that we're
talking about um
that don't get rid of all of your
tolerance but bring you down to
i don't know more usable levels while we
know that they are different for every
single person
we have to recommend something to people
for their like first time until so they
can start
start somewhere um when you take one of
these tolerance breaks
you said you you know rarely do it more
than a week okay
but what's your regular like my regular
is 48 hours i go two full calendar days
with a
without anything and and on day three i
seem to be
you know reset what how does it work for
you and what do you recommend
wow that's that's so funny we are very
very similar um
so yeah it all depends on what your
therapeutic minimum is so
the therapeutic minimum is like the
smallest dose
that you can use to get the benefit that
you're looking for
right and and each of us has a different
minimum
some some people have a therapeutic
minimum far
far above mine mine's actually pretty
low um
so let's say that you have a therapeutic
minimum that is like
well above like 50 milligrams of like an
edible
an edible dose or something something
relatively large
right um it would probably mean that you
would have to take tolerance breaks
more often if you wanted them to be as
short as what you and i
are talking about for me my normal thing
is i go
usually somewhere between 36 to 48 hours
at least every week and a half
or so that seems to that seems to keep
things i don't have a regular schedule
i did for a while when i proposed my phd
thesis i was
i was like oh i'm proposing my phd
thesis let me also propose this other
thesis in my life and that's actually
when i first introduced cbd
into my regimen and i was keeping a
notebook and i was writing everything
down
i was very rigid for about three years
with it
and developed a routine that now i can
sort of just sense
by feel but sometimes if i have
if it lines up where i'm i'm free and i
have like a
a time on the weekend to take like a
macro dose or a
larger dose than i i normally would the
beneficial effects can last for far
longer for me
and so that's sometimes i like kick off
my tolerance break so
to say with like a larger dose than i
normally would and then i experience
benefits that last for
a few days after that um and it can
begin like what would be a tolerance
break
um and then another thing that's
important about tolerance breaks that i
just want to hit on before we go to
commercial is that
it's an it's a good time when you're on
a tolerance break also to think about
your diet and water intake and other
nutritional
um it's just it's just a good time to
think about it because you're already
doing something different
um so since you're already doing
something different and taking a
tolerance break you could think about
really
trying to you know make change like i
you mentioned about
like fish oil supplements or like even
just in general un
unsaturated fatty acids right like olive
oil or coconut oil or fish or
thinking about about your diet and um
sleep hygiene and other times i use
tolerance breaks those times to think
about my overall health
it's like a little mental retreat one
more one more thing before we go to
break
these tolerance breaks this is all
cannabinoids right you can't just stop
thc
but keep using cbd right you have to you
stop all cannabinoids because you're
trying to give the whole system a break
right
oh i never stopped taking cbd but that's
just me that's just
me personally um and i use like pretty
low low doses of it i didn't i don't
experience
um i don't experience any like tolerance
with cbd but i l i use at much lower
concentrations i have
i definitely have spoken to people like
specifically people with seizures or
migraines that use that benefit from
like larger
doses of cbd it will they will develop
tolerance um to it so i do
cycle them um in terms of like cbg
cbd thc but thc is probably the only one
that i take
mandatory tolerance breaks from as far
as how the receptors
respond as far as like making more or
making less which is essentially what
we're trying to do with the tolerance
break
will if we're still taking
cbd and we're not taking thc do the thc
receptors
go down in number as we want them to
so in theory cbd has almost like an
opposite effect on the cb1 receptor
as thc so in theory it would not
although i
i can't say like with 100 knowledge that
it's true because
so here's here's the theory right like
thc activates the cb1 receptor and it's
that activation
that causes the decrease um and cbd
actually
like it doesn't inactivate it it binds
to the outside and it turns it down like
it turns down the volume
so it acts in a totally different
mechanism it's not
clear to me whether cbd has chant has
caused changes in
cb1 receptor density i i would need to
look into that to see if
if anything has been done before but i'm
not in in theory it doesn't interact the
same
the same exact way um but
i'm not i'm not yeah what you're saying
makes sense though i mean there's a lot
of the stuff that we talk about that we
have to go on
you know your educated intuition because
this research hasn't been done but
you're certainly got a perspective and a
vista point a viewpoint of the
the medicine which is you know a lot
better than most of ours so
so i'd rather go with your opinion than
and then not know at all so
yeah well i mean this is also it's my
opinion and maybe the study has been
done and i haven't read it yet i mean
there's plenty you know
there's there's um there's a lot more
coming out and i am excited for us to
you know i i am excited to see where
where we go with research and like where
the information takes us because i would
like to know that is something that's
an interesting like cb cbd the largest
um to me at least benefits i in my
opinion are happening through the
the serotonin receptors for me but i use
it for mental health
um and cbd is really promiscuous it's a
complicated molecule i mean it's
promiscuous like it's not necessarily a
bad thing but it binds to many things in
the body
it's busy right on so let's go ahead and
take that break finally uh you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is cannabis scientist and educator
miyabi shields
[Music]
this message is for folks who grow
cannabis i'm talking to home growers
patients and commercial growers too i'm
probably talking to you
when you plan out your next growing
cycle be sure to check out
humboldt csi seeds at humboldtcsi.com
caleb and specta and his family have
lived in humboldt county for over 100
years
for the last 40 years three generations
of his family have cultivated
extraordinary sense of meat cannabis in
humboldt
mendocino and trinity counties because
of his lineage and the hard-earned
experience that comes from growing up
smoking and sifting large populations of
cannabis plants in northern california
the seeds you'll cop from csi will be
winning genetics
based on long-time heavy hitters and
updated and re-sifted to bring out new
and exotic traits and better yields
go ahead and ask around caleb also known
as inspecta
and pirates of the emerald triangle is a
breeder's breeder
he reaches way back and works with
significant strains
recreating them in new and interesting
ways that you'll love as a toker
and a grower as well as offering you
some surprises that will delight
serious seed traders and cultivators
humboldt's csi goes a further step
and selfs all these chemivars so you
know all the seeds will be female
these are not experimental feminized
seeds
humboldt csi releases some of the best
female seeds available
anywhere and it will show in your garden
folks grew quite a bit of csi humble gen
x last year here on vashon island
and everyone was pleased the patients
had beautiful
female plants and didn't have to cull
half of their garden as males
the folks growing for the fun of getting
high grew colorful flowers with
exceptional bag appeal and great highs
and breeders had seven out of seven
females in a pack
which gave them a lot of phenotypic
choices
take a moment right now and visit
humboldt csi.com
you'll find an up-to-date menu of both
feminized and regular lines
along with photos and descriptions
that's humboldt
csi.com
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated
it is increasingly important to avoid
the use of chemical pesticides when
cultivating cannabis
beneficial insects have been used for
decades by the greenhouse vegetable and
ornamental plant industry
and today many cannabis cultivators are
moving from sprays and chemicals to
beneficial insects
covert biological systems has the
mites and nematodes microbials sticky
cards and air distribution units
you need to partner with nature to
defend your garden
whether you manage acres of canopy or
have a simple grow tent in your home
cobra is ready to help answer your
questions and help you transition away
from chemical sprays towards clean and
natural solutions
since 1967 culprit has assisted growers
in identifying pests
and devising reliable solutions while
providing healthy insects and mites that
will protect your yield
since the 1990s cobot has been a leader
in cannabis
pest and disease control worldwide and
have highly trained consultants to
assist you in canada and the u.s
from coast to coast no matter where you
live
covert biological systems can help visit
cobert.com
choose your country and get detailed
information
that's covert k-o-p-p-e-r-t
dot com for the most up-to-date cannabis
related biological control information
you can also check out their instagram
at covert canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and cobert is ready to help visit
cobert.com today
[Music]
while i love growing under the sun
there's a lot of good reasons to grow
indoors and if you're like most folks
you want a lighting source that grows
high yielding healthy plants without
using excessive amounts of electricity
bios lighting creates biological
lighting solutions
that brings the natural brilliance of
the outdoors into your grow room
bios lighting has the attributes that i
look for in a horticultural lighting
solution
i've bought those cheap lights online
and they're difficult to work with
and fail in no time in contrast my
bios led light is industrial grade to
last a long time
it is ip66 wet rated so little foliar
overspray won't harm it
it is easy to clean without taking it
down and of course the most important
aspect
it is built for the exact light spectrum
i want for great yielding healthy
cannabis plants
and it doesn't hurt that their lighting
rigs look badass too
many horticultural led lighting systems
are based on irrelevant performance
metrics
and people love to argue online about
these numbers i prefer to judge on par
photon efficiency and how happy my
plants are and the bios lights exceed my
expectations in these categories
bios lights have an optimized broad
spectrum that maximizes photosynthesis
and plant growth
while also providing the ideal
conditions for superior par
efficacy and a comfortable visual
experience i also love their attentive
and over-educated customer service folks
bios starts with a team of biologists
before getting the electrical engineers
involved
they have studied how light impacts
cannabis plants and devised an overall
strategy that works
i encourage you to check out their
website at bioslighting.com
to learn more about how this strategy
can work for you and shaping fire
listeners can get a special deal
use the discount code shaping fire all
one word
no caps for 10 off your entire purchase
that's biosliding.com
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host
shango los and our guest this week is
cannabis scientist and
educator miyabi shields so miyabi
we are to the part of the show that i
have been the most uncomfortable about
um and i didn't tell you much about this
in advance so
you know i know your company that you
helped found which you know is not the
point of the show today but it's called
real isolates right
and i know that you are a pharmaceutical
chemist
and you spend a lot of time looking at
cannabinoid isolates
and for people who aren't familiar we're
talking about the pure
molecule thc pure molecule cbd
whereas normally i'm talking on this
show about you know taking the whole
plant
resin from directly from the plant so
instead of
pulling out the isolates of the plant
and then
mixing and matching them like a
pharmaceutical company would to kind of
you know build a medicine i'm more in
the family of let's breed a plant
that um uh affects that has the positive
effect for the
for the patient and then let's just do a
whole resin
extraction of that plant and then we've
got
a we've got a you know we've got we've
got a medicine directly from nature
and so that's what we talk about a lot
on the show um
but you know you are right there on the
front lines
of this science so
so what what is your take on this like
you know
you you clearly understand what i'm
talking about about whole plant medicine
and the resin
but i also know that from what i
understand a lot of your research is
into these individual
molecules and for many of us like you
know when cbd was really hard to find i
mean nowadays the prices crashed but you
know six years ago
cbd was really hard to find and so we
would we would often
um recommend to patients that they take
a whole plant extract from a thc
plant and then add isolate to it to kind
of artificially
spike it so they could get the cbd that
the studies were saying they were needed
and oh my gosh i felt like i was making
or participating in frankenstein
medicine you know
so so with with that whole kind of set
up
what are your thoughts in comparing
whole plant medicine
versus the more common use of cbd
isolate thc isolate and now got help is
d
uh you know um delta eight isolate
well actually it's funny that you
mentioned that um our company name real
isolates is sort of a play on words
because there are there is no such thing
as a
real isolate um and we do research
and doing research involves isolating
these compounds and
and looking at them but in terms of the
the efficacy
of whole plant extracts versus isolates
i think that there are huge benefits to
chemo diversity that are undervalued and
under-researched and
actually our whole company which i know
is now probably a misnomer at the time
we thought it was funny
um real isolates um at the time we were
like this makes perfect sense we'll tell
everyone about how there's no real
islets
oh so it's like a science joke that no
one gets
well hopefully people will get it
eventually um but actually our
our entire our entire research is that
we do
and and everything is based upon you
know this theory that
i've been working on that has to do with
chemo diversity and
the potential essentially what you were
just describing about whole plants
making crude extracts with whole plants
and the extremely extremely complex
pharmacology that comes with crude
extracts
because if you think about have you have
you heard of the the three body problem
in physics
no i'm not familiar with that okay so
basically it's just a problem that says
in in physics in a vacuum of space if
you have two planets or two bodies
it's it's very very easy to derive a
mathematical equation
that describes those two bodies it's
very predictable
and it's it's safe um so pharmaceutical
chemistry
is in many ways a two-body problem
because you have the one
synthetic molecule or in this case if
you were looking at isolates of cbd and
thc
you have the one molecule and then you
have the the human body
right um but in physics there's this
problem where instead of two bodies you
introduce a third body like a third
planet and
they're all rotating on each other and
all of a sudden it becomes
impossible to generate an equation
to describe because it suddenly gets so
complex and that's with three
and the cannabis plant has over 400
unique molecules
in depending on the strain depending on
the grow
so depending on like the genetics and
the chemovar depending on the grow
conditions and how it's grown
depending on the dry and cure process
and how it's dried and cured
then depending on how it's extracted
whether or not it's distilled
what are the distillation parameters
like fraction distillation versus short
bath distillation
it is a hundred plus body problem
like easily for sure but i'm at the
point where like i embrace that problem
because that hundred plus body problem
has very specific solutions that i don't
believe that isolates can
can solve um that's just a personal
opinion
of mine i personally believe that there
are huge advantages
to chemo diversity which is just a
description of like the number of total
molecules
that are in an extract like for example
um i have huge success making topicals
with crude extracts of cannabis and
willow bark
and white willow bark has the precur has
salicylic acid in it
which is the scaffold that we use to
make aspirin
um but in addition to salicylic acid it
has a bunch of other
rare you know rare derivatives of
salicylic acid similarly to how cannabis
has all the rare cannabinoids and
terpenes and flavonoids
and other fatty acids and bioactive
molecules right
and do we do we understand exactly how
all of these things interact like
no we don't understand that at all yet
we're not there yet where we could say
i will give you a synthetic mixture of
all 400 of these things
to cause a very specific effect i mean
that would be
the holy grail or that would be you know
that would be the goal eventually of
research um
but we're nowhere close to there and in
my opinion
does the whole plant have unchartered
territory and uncharted opportunities
for various specific therapeutic effects
and or increased effects
um for like a a lower like risk
potential
like yes i think that isolates not
necessarily cbd isolate but okay well
cbd isolate maybe i'll
i'll i could talk a little bit about
that right so
epidiolex is the pharmaceutical um
cbd formulation and the dose for
epidialex is extremely high i mean it's
in the
it's in like for my weight it would be
like more than a gram
more than once per day um extremely
extremely high dose
for it to be efficacious and obviously
that's you know seizure disorders
require higher doses
but it's my personal opinion that you
could
potentiate cbd meaning you make cbd
more effective by giving it with other
cannabinoids that act
synergistically so a synergistic
interaction means
more than additive um and these are
things that are difficult to prove in a
laboratory setting and i know that
people are working on it and that it's
it's being done um but in in the
meantime in terms
in terms of just like what my opinion is
of it i think that the whole plant
extracts have a lower
risk potential for negative effects and
potentially in many ways
a higher efficacy although there are
advantages no there are no doubt
advantages to distilling and purifying
you can't you can't argue that there
there are some
advantages to that um i guess just in
in the personal context i am a big fan
and use crude extracts and flour
and i got to tell you i'm very relieved
because i thought i was going into
a a debate with a scientist who loved
isolates
and i'm like oh my god how am i going to
hold my own defending
whole plant and then here you are saying
oh actually whole plant
you know is you know is is is probably
preferred which is a huge relief
to me well the whole whole plant is
really just a combination of isolation
right right i mean but it's but it's but
it's not i mean i
it's kind of like contrary right because
i by name
isolate means you're isolating one thing
and um there
there are absolutely advantages to to
isolate
although but in in my opinion
um not for chronic use
um it's like specifically we're talking
about tolerance and taking tolerance
breaks and i know i didn't i didn't
mention it when we were talking about it
but there's
there's a very specific type of
withdrawal and acute withdrawal
um that is coming up more and more uh
called cannabis hyperemesis syndrome
or chs and it's my personal opinion that
that develops due to a very
very specific type of tolerance and
withdrawal to
just thc um and it's i don't it's not
it's nowhere near close to we're nowhere
near close to understanding exactly how
all of these things work or or whether
or not
this is this is like a hundred percent
the mechanism but
when you take a a whole plant extract
that has
you know a large number of different of
different cannabinoids also
you know the perfect example of this
section which is you know touching on my
current research project is smoking
right like i
i prefer cannabis smoke to the edible
experience i know that that's true for a
majority of people actually i recently
pulled
i pulled off my social media and got
over 13 000 responses and it's
pretty much an overwhelming majority of
people prefer smoking and there's
there's
no doubt advantages to edibles and
that's in a comparable way to that
there's no doubt advantages to
pharmaceutical formulations but
many edibles these days are made with
distillate
um they're made with very very
concentrate and distillate even though
it's not isolate
is practically isolated i mean it
depends it depends on
you know the the dispensary the producer
and the lab that's making it
but they're it's often i think it's
common practice for people to distill
above 85
right um which basically means that
you're taking out everything else and
you're hyper selecting for the
cannabinoids
and you know i'm kind of going to circle
here but i prefer smoking and i always
had
and and majority people prefer smoking
and one of the reasons why i believe
that is because
smoking produces the most diverse
formulation
out of anything that you possibly could
intake
in terms of like a crude edible
extraction like butter or rso
versus a distillate extraction versus
smoking
the distillate edibles are on one side
and so like isolates and distillate are
on one side
of like the purest form of just thc
or just cbd um and then crude extracts
or whole plant extracts are in the
middle
and then smoking is on the opposite side
in terms of just the the total number of
like the complexity of the formulation
of cannabinoids that you're taking in
and that you know this has been
my big passion and something that i'm
passionate about researching for
like for a while now is why is that and
looking into it and
you know it would take a super computer
and
a lot of simulation to even be able to
to
begin to predict the like the complex
interactions like at the receptor level
um that occur with with so many
different mixtures
right like especially especially when
you have
the fact that you have like flavonoids
and terpenes and other bioactive
molecules like
there's a lot of factors to take into
consideration
and you blew me away the other day when
you when you taught that um
that even regardless of what your
your analytics say about your flower
when you
burn the flower you are actually
bringing
additional cannabinoids into existence
so that a
burnt a combusted flower like in a joint
or something
is even more pharmacologically complex
than
what you think is in it when you look at
your lab tests
absolutely i mean there's we always talk
about the negatives and the downsides
to smoking and i there's it you can't
argue that there
are some negatives to smoking as a
method
but there are some benefits as well and
there are some
very very unique um you know things that
that occur and
yeah in terms of like what i was
mentioning about like depending
regardless of what the flower looks like
i mean a lot of
thc will get converted because it is a
it's a reactive molecule and you heat it
to a very very high temperature
and then the flower has other reactive
molecules as well
the terpenes are all extremely volatile
um
and then there's just the fact like when
we talk about combustion you know true
combustion means you're going all the
way down to co2 and
water and we do not fully combust
the the flour i mean when you're at the
very very end of your bowl and it's all
white and ashy
like yeah okay that's you know that's
completely combusted
but when we're typically smoking you
know like when you're not running
totally dry
like you're not fully combusting um
you're heating and extracting at the
same time
and you're also transforming and yeah
it's
i think chemo diversity has a huge
impact on the overall effect i mean i
i can tell you right now that like no
one will be able to convince me
that smoking doesn't give me a different
formulation because it feels
so different it sure does like and
there's so many
specific effects um in terms of strain
specificity that i'm
and perhaps i just don't have experience
with enough experience with strain
specific edibles because
you know so many edibles are made with
distillate um
which distills them back down so it
simplifies them and
i just know that the high is not nearly
as good smoking
you know distillate or actually any
version of distillate
let's let's let's finish with this
question because i i don't want to keep
you
uh longer than we agreed to the
um when we talk about whole plant
medicine with many scientists at
conventions
people tell me ah whole plant medicine
is
messy we can't control it we don't know
what's in it whereas
you're talking about the benefits of
chemical uh diversity and and you know i
come from a place of efficacy that just
works so much better
when you're talking scientists to
scientists what do you tell that other
scientist who says that
you know cannabis resin is messy and
uncontrolled and so we should go in a
different direction
i tell them that real life is messy
real life is pretty uncontrolled and
that i absolutely love the scientific
regor
of getting in the lab and minimizing
variables but that's just not
life and i i know that
this is something that many scientists
do
and will in future disagree with me over
and
i was very hesitant about talking about
it for
for a long time for that reason um
because i
i do agree that there is it is messy i
mean i
i agree that it's unknown right um
and it's it's complicated
but then i also can't help but think
about
reality and um you know reality is
messy and uncontrollable and complicated
and
to your point you know just to close
like the most important thing
to me is helping other people improve
their quality of life
and efficacy is where it's at and let me
just like
this is just like a thought like a
little like thing a seed of thought but
you know most drugs that go to clinical
trial
from like pharmaceutical synthetic drugs
going to clinical trial
um first of all it's extremely expensive
to get them to a clinical trial but
by the time they get there the most
common reason why they fail
is not because they're toxic but it's
because they are not
efficacious the most common reason why a
drug
will fail a clinical trial is because it
just simply doesn't
work so i guess
my question to another scientist who
would say that it's messy my question
would be like
so it's messy but it works and like
the reduction of suffering is the goal
is in
is it the goal right exactly is that the
goal and if that is the goal which i
i think everyone agrees that that's the
goal um
then why shouldn't we value something
that's messy and try to work with it
because i
i totally agree and understand it is
messy there
there's tons of questions i mean even
with you know my project is looking at
cannabis smoke i opened
pandora's box and
there's a lot of questions and a lot of
things to be figured out and a lot of
unknown and i think the unknown makes
people scared but
you know there's a thing about science
like where
scientists are like searching around in
the dark underneath
one street lamp so like the universe is
this dark mysterious thing and science
just has this
like the little street lamps of
technology like if you imagine every new
technological advance is a new little
street lamp that you can kind of like
turn
on and look under and all of us are down
on our hands and knees as scientists
with a magnifying glass
looking under the street lamp and then
everyone else is like well what if the
answer is in the dark
you know what i mean and we we don't
have the answer to that
so you know that would be i guess this
is like and i would love to have a
discussions with
and i'm sure i will have many
discussions with other scientists on
this
but um you know i've been speaking with
a lot of people on chemo diversity and
most people that i talk to especially
people who have used and benefited from
plant medicine
most of those people who have that and
hear
what i'm saying about chemo diversity
they're just kind of like right that
just
it just makes sense um that's fantastic
miyabi it has been such a joy to
interview you
um your your depth and detail of
knowledge
is like so liberating and and
and you know it says in the intro to the
show that we we do all of this with good
cheer and
you're you're such a cheerful and
enjoyable person to chat with i really
appreciate it and i gotta tell you like
i had so many
i've got a whole you know half show of
questions that we didn't get to you
would you be so kind to come back again
soon so that we can continue our
conversation
oh absolutely thanks for having me this
was really enjoyable and
i love talking about this stuff it's
actually my
it's like extremely special and narrow
interest of mine
fantastic well thank you so much we'll
talk to you again soon if you are
interested
in following um miyabi shields on social
media there is a lot of fun there so i'm
going to start out by giving you
um their instagram which is miyabi which
is
m i y a b
e p h d um because uh
the tick tock channel keeps on getting
uh deleted and
and and uh there isn't a website yet so
so just go to miyabi phd on instagram
and from there you will be able to start
picking up on the rest of their teaching
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show
at shapingfire.com and wherever you get
your podcasts
if you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download
your review will help others find the
show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for insights
into the latest cannabis news exclusive
videos and giveaways
on the shaping fire website you also
find transcripts of today's podcast as
well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast
that's at shaping fire and at shangolos
on instagram
be sure to check out shaping fire
youtube channel for exclusive interviews
farm tours and cannabis lectures
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts
email hotspot shippingfire.com to find
out how
thanks for listening to shaping fire
i've been your host shango los
you