[Music]
we are experiencing a clash of
civilizations right now in cannabis
generally speaking the heritage of
cannabis is sharing we've always shared
canvas flowers and seeds and insight on
how to grow at the center of cannabis
culture is the whole idea of puff puff
pass and not to Bogart the joint while
certainly there were some folks who may
not have wanted you to circulate their
special cut of some strain or another
the vast majority of time cannabis folks
shared whatever they had because we were
all sharing in the oppression of the
government through prohibition now
though the emerging licensed cannabis
market is based on ownership extravagant
packaging and intellectual property this
is a very significant change and I won't
say that the schism is within the
cannabis community I will say that it's
within the cannabis industry because
again generally those who are seeing the
green rush is a quick way to grab it all
are often Outsiders coming in or
longtime insiders working with newly
accessible outside capital investment
and we all know how corrupting sudden
access to piles of cash can be one of
the ways that companies are trying to
take advantage of the young
infrastructure of the cannabis industry
is by filing exceptionally broad patents
and daring for anyone to try to take
them on because few people have the
depth of pockets to take them on
certainly I'm making some pretty big
generalizations here but if you're
watching the cannabis scene evolve you
know that on the whole I'm right
certainly I know some newcomers to
canvas who have their heart in the right
place and it's also certainly true that
some of the heritage folks were not all
that kind intellectual property is legal
though and you either are or are not
filing for an over broad patent you do
not accidentally lawyer up and file a
patent that pretty much says you
invented an entire product category it
is not like accidentally bogarting the
joint while talking too much before
passing it if you want to learn about
cannabis health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of most important
news items from the week and videos too
don't rely on social media to let you
know
new episodes published sign up for the
updates to make sure you don't miss an
episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter this month we're giving
away prize packs of the endo Michael
inoculant from dynamite there's nothing
else you need to do to win except
receive that newsletter so go to shaping
fire com2 sign up for the newsletter and
be entered into this month's and all
future newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shaping fire and I'm your
host Shango lows today my guest is plant
scientist and patent attorney Dale hunt
Dale has extensive experience with
patent protection with a technical
emphasis in Life Sciences like cellular
biology genetics genomics immunology
microbiology molecular biology
pharmaceuticals protein engineering stem
cells transgenics agriculture plant
genetics plant patents and plant variety
protection amongst a bunch a whole other
bunch of other areas Dale also has
experience with patent portfolio
management and strategy advice internet
international intellectual property
manners intellectual property due
diligence and licensing he pretty much
does it all having started as a botanist
and plant geneticist Dale continued his
study of plant biology at the cellular
and molecular level completing a PhD at
UC San Diego Dale then went on to UC
Berkeley for law school Dale has spoken
at Emerald Cup as a panel expert on
cannabis patents and Dale was also a
pretty great all-around guy his law firm
is called plant and planet if that tells
you anything today we're gonna talk in
detail about two of the most hotly
discussed cannabis patents that
presently exist and what breeders and
cannabis lovers everywhere can do to
help support open access to cannabis
genetics welcome to the show Dale thank
you I'm glad to be here so let's jump
right into it and and even though we've
done quite a few shows about cannabis
patenting at this point I think it's
really important to bring people up to
the now in the difference between plat
patents versus use patents because a lot
of people who are new to this topic of
cannabis patents they kind of just
picture them all in one big bucket but
since we're gonna be talking about both
plant and use patents today I think it's
good to get us right on the same page of
what the differences are
between those so would you start there
please yes I'd be happy to so I think
the easiest way to think about how to
distinguish these things is to think
about the fact that a plant selection a
plant variety a cultivar can be seen as
a unique thing a unique result of
creative effort by a plant breeder or it
can be seen as an invention that has
lots of different applications and
really that they're both true but the
reason I set it up that way is that a
plant patent is meant to cover the plant
as a unique thing and it protects
against copying it and so the the best
analogy that existed intellectual
property is to say that a plant patent
is a lot like a copyright on a plant
variety it only protects against direct
copying it doesn't protect against
similarity it doesn't protect against
independent derivation of something even
with the same parents it only protects
clonal copying of that exact genotype as
well as it's harvested material in
contrast a utility patent is it can
cover the same the same underlying plant
variety but it treats it like an
invention that you can use in a lot of
different ways and that you can
potentially claim in a lot of different
ways so what I mean by that is with a
utility patent one of your claims and I
should just stop and explain a patent
claim is like a fence around your
invention it's it's the definition of
the boundaries between what you invented
and what still is out there outside the
scope of your coverage and so when
you're doing a utility patent you can
claim if you can claim your invention
any way you want as long as you can
demonstrate to the patent examiner that
it is new and it's not obvious and that
it has utility and that it's not outside
of what's called patentable subject
matter so if I treat my plant variety as
an invention one of the claims I could
write would be the cannabis plant or
plant yeah okay a cannabis plant
TIPA fide by I'm not finding the best
words for right now but a cannabis plant
typifies by the seeds that are on
deposit under accession XYZ or cannabis
plants related to the seeds that are on
deposit and if you do it this way you do
need to make a seed deposit but then
that so that could be claimed one is
defining the plant based upon the
deposit the next claim could be
something like progeny of the plants of
claim one another claim could be an
extract made from the plants have
claimed one or claim two so an extract
made from that variety or from its
progeny you could have a claim to a
method of breeding cannabis comprising
having the clay at the plaintiff claim
one as one of the parents now what this
does is it makes it so that you can
protect that variety a lot more broadly
than just straight-up clonal copying you
can protect you could well you can
maintain exclusivity as to the right to
breed with that plant if you care to if
that's how you want to claim it you can
have control over the extracts who can
make extracts and and so on and again
it's you think about the each of these
claims is a fence around the property of
your invention and so there's nothing
inherently right or wrong about either
one of these approaches plant patents
are a little less expensive and faster
to grant utility patents do take a
longer process to persuade the examiner
that each one of these claims is
actually worthy of patent protection but
in both cases they're really going to be
focused upon the variety that the
breeder developed and so in both cases
it's I my opinion it's well within the
right of the breeder to protect that
kind of invention or that kind of
development right on um I actually never
really thought about the idea of a
breeder having a choice whether which
one they wanted to pursue I didn't
realize that there was so much overlap I
thought it was either clearly going to
be a pair
plant a patent or it was clearly going
to be a use patent but really there's a
lot of overlap and and and how you'd
file it contains a lot of strategy about
what you expect your challenges to look
like that's very true and I actually
wrote a blog about this topic because it
came up so much and I wanted people to
be able to understand the kind of the
analytical pathway you go down to decide
what kind of IP protection you need for
your for your plant variety the blog is
titled something like let's talk about
reproduction and how you will get paid
and I have all my blogs on plant law
comm but the point of that blog and the
point of the analysis is that if you are
going to protect your plants if you're
gonna sell clones let's say you want to
be able to control who is who's allowed
to make clones and if that's how you're
gonna make your money you need a plant
patent and you also need more than that
because you still need you need to
control you know you need to be careful
about who makes the clones and who sells
them because it's so easy to go out and
copy it a plant and make more clones
that the patent will give you the right
to stop vermin someone from making those
clones if you're willing to litigate
against them and if you even find out
about them but it's always best if
you're selling clones to only work with
someone that you really trust to make
the clones and to restrict what's done
with the clones afterwards so for
example maybe you've got a variety that
has just that just as a great flower
quality and you want that to be as
accessible to people as possible you
want it to be in a lot of dispensaries
and so you want there to be a lot of
harvested material that's available for
for commercial access but you don't
really want somebody to just grab a
little bit of your propagating material
and start to compete with you that's the
whole reason you got a patent in the
first place and so if you're selling
clones only so that other people can
propagate and and sell harvested
material that's great but you should
restrict even then you should restrict
what they can do with those clones
and that that that gets into some other
complicated areas that are probably
beyond what we should go into today but
I'm happy to explain those in more
detail with if anyone's interested so
okay that's one thing if you're selling
clones you've got to go with the plant
patent because that's well that's one
thing you can do and it's a simpler
option but if you're selling seeds it's
really important to understand that a
plant patent won't even protect that
because the plant patent only protects
direct clonal progeny it does not
protect seed progeny so you're really
your only choice if you're selling seeds
is a utility patent if it's a high THC
variety or if it's industrial hemp seeds
that's also something that you can
protect through the USDA plant variety
Protection Act that's called the plant
variety protection certificate and I'm
just gonna stop here to explain that the
rest of the world is different sometimes
I get I was actually challenged by
someone who said you're giving bad
advice you should tell everybody to seek
youp of type protection
well you pop is an acronym for it's a
for a French the French title of this
convention but it's basically the
English version is the International
Convention on protection of plant
varieties and it establishes plant
breeders rights that you can apply for
in any member of this convention and
those plant breeders rights are very
they cover both seeds and clones but
they have some exemptions that make them
a little bit problematic anyone can
breed with something that is covered by
a Utah you pop certificate as there's
Express breeders exemption so that if
you obtain you you pop rights but
someone has access that has legitimate
access to your plants you can't stop
them from using that plant to breed
other plants now some people may say
that's great that's a great result
that's great public policy it enhances
the diversity of what people have access
to for breeding but anyway so the rest
of Maat the bottom line here is the rest
of the world is different in the way
protects plant varieties the us is
unique in having really three different
approaches the USDA PvP approach which
is like you pub in the rest of the world
the USPTO plant patent which is like a
copyright and the USPTO utility patent
which treats the plant like any other
invention right on Wow thank you for
that explanation I can I can already
hear the breeders strategizing in their
head on the other side of the signal and
for folks who are listening because you
yourself are a breeder and you actually
have to think through this strategy for
yourself stick around for the second set
of the show where we're going to be
talking with Dale in detail about about
what actions that you can take to
actually protect yourself but right now
during the first set I want it I want to
shift with you Dale because now that we
generally have an idea what the area
that we're talking about I would like
you to give us some good detail on the
two probably most talked about patents
that that cannabis folks especially to
heritage growers are calling over abroad
and and certainly these names have been
coming up a ton since the Philo's
debacle but you know people have been
discussing the the biotech LLC patent
for a few years now I give credit to
amanda chicago lewis when she wrote that
story in rolling stone that kind of made
it apparent to everybody what was going
on and kind of brought it up to the
public consciousness but people talk
about that and you know how people talk
on the internet my god all these people
who have either wrong information or
their or an incomplete set of
information but everybody's got an
opinion right and so I figure as both a
plant scientist and a patent attorney
you are going to be able to offer us you
know some rare insight into this so
let's the first of the two I want to
talk about is the biotech LLC patents so
if you would like take us from square
one explain what the the patent is
kind of the two sides of the debate and
and share your thoughts if you would
sure
yeah well this patent is it's definitely
a utility patent and it's it's there's
actually a family of patents that have
similar strategies to cover related
subject matter so I'll just talk about
the the one that gets talked about the
most which is let's see I'll get you the
number of the patent it's vertical its
patent number nine three seven zero one
six four and anyone who wants to follow
along at home can actually google that
and they'll probably be able to get a
copy of the patent right in front of
them so it's nine three seven oh one six
four actually there are a few of them
that are like this but this is a good
one to talk about so you know how I
talked about the fact that when you have
a utility patent you can claim it any
way you can claim your invention any way
you want as long as you can persuade the
examiner that the that what you've
claimed is new and not obvious and
adequately described and falls within
allowable subject matter and I should
explain what that means the allowable
subject matter thing is comes from
section 101 of the patent statute and it
just says that well the court
interpretation of section 101 is that
there are certain things that are just
not patentable including laws of nature
and products of nature and so we can get
into more detail about that when we talk
about the the next patent but in this
case this the the kinds of claims in
this patent are not not restricted by
section 101 and so the patent examiner
would look at the claim and ask is this
new is this obvious and has it been
adequately described and the patent
examiner clearly was reached the answer
to a yes answer to all three of those
questions I'd like to walk through the
claim and then we can talk about whether
that yes answer was was appropriate that
sounds great okay so
which is typical and it's the only claim
we'll spend any time on because this has
a lot of claims and it would get tedious
but it claims a pan of a cannabis plant
or an asexual clone of a plant or a
plant part or a tissue or a cell that
produces a female in fluorescence so
basically it's a female cannabis plant
and it has at least three percent THC
and at least 3 percent CBD and a terpene
profile that is not mercy and dominant
and a terpene oil content greater than
1% now there's some other other language
in the claim that just talks about what
the other terpenes are that's pretty
standard list of terpenes as far as I've
been told and then it also talks about
how those terpenes are measured as
measured by gas chromatography and then
the last phrase is we're in a
representative sample of seed producing
said plants has been deposited under and
then there's a list of accession number
so they made several seed deposits as
representative samples what's important
about this claim is that this is what I
would call and what other people have
called it a chemo type claim it's not
it's not limited to any of those
particular samples that's why they
deposited multiple samples and said it's
just representative so this this claim
would cover by most people's
interpretation and I've got to stop and
just say I'm not from not providing any
legal advice to anyone this is this is
my educational analysis kind of of the
way patent law works as applied to an
exemplary claim if anyone needs legal
advice on this I get a lot lot deeper
and provide legal advice in a way that
is much much more detailed so no one
should rely on this as any kind of legal
advice this is educational only alright
so what I've been told by lots of people
is that this chemo type is one that has
been around for a long time that people
can point to
examples of other cannabis plants that
pre-existed the filing date and let's go
back and look at that filing date so we
can be clear about this the filing date
of this patent is July let's yeah sorry
it's well the yeah the filing date is
July 17th 2015 and the earliest date
that it claims back to which matters the
the the patent eligibility analysis is
always a function of different dates and
then was there anything before those
dates that was out there in the public
domain and was known so the earliest
date that this is entitled to under any
theory is going to be March 15th 2013 so
back to the kind of the public
discussion of this there are people lots
of people who say that this particular
chemo type pre-existed 2013 they can
point to other strains or cultivars of
cannabis that are at least 3 percent THC
at least 3 percent CBD and and then are
not mercy and dominant and that have
greater than 1% terpene oil now I want
to emphasize that I haven't I haven't
independently analyzed any cultivars and
I haven't fact checked anyone's
assertions about this so from here on
out this is a discussion of the way the
patent law would work if those
assertions were true and this does
expose one of the fundamental problems
with with cannabis patents any kind of
cannabis patents with any kind of breath
and that is that when the examiner is
looking at this claim and trying to
decide if it's new or non-obvious they
don't just put their finger in the wind
and and wonder they have a particular
procedure that they go through and they
do this for biotech patents medical
patents airplane engines electronic
devices anything at all that you that
you're claiming to invented what they do
is they look at the claim and then they
do a search involving keywords and
categories to try to find the closest
thing they can find to this claim
and they look in in in other industries
they will have you know at least tens of
thousands or hundreds of thousands of
moderately relevant academic papers to
look at in in the overall database of
what's already known what's in the
public knowledge
so they'll they'll do a search if it's a
biotech case they might they might
really have access to well they would
easily have access to over a hundred
thousand different academic papers and
probably a lot more than that as well as
they they would also search all of the
prior patent literature and they look
for whatever is closest to that claim
and then they use that as a basis for a
rejection of the claim and it's almost
always the case that a claim will be
rejected the first time around because
it's almost it's kind of the examiner's
job to explain why that well to say that
the the claim isn't allowable for these
reasons and then put it on the applicant
to explain why those reasons are
incorrect now the reason I'm going in
all this detail is that suppose now
you're an examiner handling the
first-ever chemo type patent application
for for cannabis you go through your
normal procedure you look in all the
academic literature but how much
academic literature is there on this
topic there's a little but not very much
not remotely not not even orders of
magnitude within the same amount of
literature that is typically available
for a patent search then you look at all
the prior patent literature and somewhat
surprisingly to some people the USPTO
has been handling and granting cannabis
related patents all the way back to the
40s but this was the first time anyone
had tried to claim chemo type so the
examiner can't just say this seems like
it's too broad the examiner has to have
a basis for rejecting the claim the
examiner looks in the so called prior
art that's the whole public database of
prior literature academic literature or
patents and can't really find anything
or maybe find something that's kind of
close but not not all the way closed or
maybe find something that looks like it
but whatever the the problem in utility
patents with cannabis is that there is
just a complete disconnect between a lot
of prior commercial activity we know
that people have been enjoying chemo
VARs and chemo types for a long time
right but no one was documenting it
people were going out of their way not
to document it and so the the robust
literature that usually corresponds to a
robust commercial environment doesn't
exist for cannabis now the result of
that is that the examiner looking at
this didn't have access to all of the
commercial activity at a record of all
the commercial activity that happened
before legalization and so in a way you
think if the examiners tools for giving
a rejection our prior publications the
examiners just don't have the tools to
adequately examine some especially broad
patent applications relating to cannabis
so Dale before you before you go further
let me give voice to what a lot of
people are probably thinking which is
like what the eff like what you just
described is is a mess because there are
two things that we know true number one
there were clearly chemo VARs that had
more than three percent THC and three
percent CBD in the market and while
Mersin dominant sure that limits because
mere seen is clearly the most popular
terpene dominant team of our out there
there are absolutely plenty of chemo
VARs that are not mere sane dominant so
if those are your two most limiting
factors and really only need above three
percent on THC and CBD and above three
percent and excuse me and not mere seem
dominant I can hear people out there
feeling like me like we know those exist
of course those existed we you know
however the second part is is where is
the evidence because we've had to be in
the underground for all this time or we
didn't have analytic labs or or people
have these plants and they have not
filed them
to to get a time stamp on them it's it's
astonishing right I mean I you I like
how you are approaching it neutral and
Suns emotion to give us the data point
but I can since I'm not the attorney but
I can say what the hell right because
right we know damn well that these
plants existed period and and and I now
understand more what I when I talk to
other experts what they often will say
is ah you know the USPTO didn't want to
put in the work for the research so they
granted the patent and they figured that
will all kick it around in court for a
few decades and it'll get sorted out but
they didn't want to be in the middle of
it now what you're saying though kind of
lets them off the hook to me a little
bit until I hear what you say because
I'm like oh if this stuff has to exist
in a in a searchable form in the patent
library or in a searchable form on
Google well hell I might have a hard
time finding that myself and so now I'm
like alright so so before you continue
on what's your thoughts on the I don't
know let's say the attitude of the
patent and trade office did they did
they not do their job or did they do
their job because we are uniquely
talking about a plant that has been
prohibited it's not their fault there's
nothing and this is gonna have to play
out in court because the prior law
doesn't exist I will start by saying I'm
no apologist for the Patent Office I
I've worked with the Patent Office for
23 years and there are good examiner's
and bad examiner's at the Patent Office
just like there are in any organization
but if the examiners ever try to take a
shortcut or do the safe thing it is to
just refuse to allow a claim I've I've
in addition to my practice in cannabis
I've worked a lot in biotech and and
cancer and other things like that and
I've certainly done battle with
examiner's for years trying to get some
some claims to cancer treatment allowed
they were brought claim
but the examiner couldn't find anything
that was right on point but was still
very very hesitant to allow the claims
because he didn't want to get
second-guessed in the Patent Office and
he certainly didn't want to have his his
patent associated with some ugly
litigation over its validity or
associated with you know become kind of
almost a household topic a dinner table
topic about how the examiner didn't do
his job and so my my answer to people
who say that the Patent Office just just
punted on this is that notwithstanding
my frustrations with many patent
examiner's they are much more likely to
just say no than to say yes but they
have to have some remote basis for
saying no and it has to be defensible
and if they just don't have any
literature they can cite they can't just
have a feeling and they can't there's a
limit to how much independent
investigation they can do one thing they
can do and that I want to encourage the
Patent Office to do more is to actually
put the applicants on the spot with what
are called requests for information and
sometimes when a patent examiner
believes that there must be something
out there that they haven't been able to
find but that must still be out there
they can they can ask they can issue a
request for information so for example I
was handling a plant patent on a mango
in Australia and the examiner couldn't
find any evidence that the plant itself
had been commercially available but he
did find something in in a fruit
catalogue that listed this that the
fruit itself is having been commercially
available and he said I'm putting it on
you to tell me on the record whether
those trees were ever sold to anyone
where the trees ever publicly available
that's what you're trying to patent and
I see evidence this evidence gives me
enough to ask you to put it to say on
the record what was actually going on
that how did this fruit get into
commercial availability and so we had to
investigate that and we were able to
supply enough information to make it
clear that
while the fruit had been available the
plants hadn't been and and that mattered
I won't go into all the details of that
but it is up to the examiner if there's
any shred of indication that something
may have gone on that they just didn't
that don't have access to in their
database they can force the applicant to
to state on the record what they know or
to characterize the historical situation
and I think what happened in this case
is there's so little about prior
existence it's a syllable published or
accessible information about prior
existence of this kimo type especially
and we should emphasize this especially
when the examiner was looking at this
there's been a lot of information
published since then about people
reacting to this patent but when the
examiner had this in front of him or her
they didn't even have enough to issue a
request for information so in the future
I'm hoping that patent examiner's
looking at these kinds of things well
what I'd really like to see is have
people be less inclined to do what our
people are calling the equivalent of a
land grab or a gold rush on broad patent
claims they have people seek claims that
are more narrowly directed to what they
actually bred and created but I would
also like the examiners to feel more
equipped to issue these requests for
information and say alright I can't find
anything in the prior art but I know
that there was a whole closet industry
or an underground industry here and so I
want you to show to tell me how you
characterize prior unpublished
commercial activity in this space and
that doesn't make the applicant that
doesn't give the applicant of duty to do
it in that in independent investigation
but it does put them in a position where
they have to say on the record what they
know about that why don't you think the
Patent Office asked that I think they
just didn't know enough about the
industry you know the patent examiner's
probably are not the same ones that that
were really familiar
with a great variety of chemo types from
their own personal use of their own
personal experience in the industry and
so I don't think it it stood out that
that was something that was even likely
to exist in and in this patent in this
patent examiner's experience now this is
a few years ago and there's been as we
all know there's been a hell of a lot of
talk about it since then and people do
have the same reaction that you had
which is of course this isn't new
maybe it's never been published but of
course it's not new and that's what I've
heard a lot of people say but I think
the patent examiner just didn't didn't
have that same kind of instant reaction
and didn't have a real basis for issuing
a request for information plus I will
say requests for information are pretty
rare they usually come when you find
when you find a document that points you
in a direction it just doesn't get you
all the way there to a valid rejection
and so then the examiner says I'm going
to rely on this for a rejection unless
you can convince me that I shouldn't so
I could go into a lot more detail about
this but but basically I I to answer
your original question I don't think
this was a case of the Patent Office
taking the easy way out I think it was
them working with the tools they had and
recognizing that there was a limit to
what they could do and not having any
kind of genuine legal basis for
rejecting this they went ahead and
allowed it but the other part of what
you said really is true if this is going
to play itself out in the public
discourse like this and if they ever
choose to enforce this patent against an
alleged infringer then I think there
will probably be all kinds of people in
the industry that will come forward and
say okay well here's here's a cultivar
that we can show existed prior to 2013
that has this this chemical profile
again I'm not saying I haven't done my
own investigation but you know I've
heard your reaction lots of times and so
if that's factually accurate probably
multiple people will come forward and
defend whoever gets sued for patent
infringement
and say here's our evidence that this
claim doesn't meet the novelty
requirement and therefore is not valid
you know that's really interesting now
what what they've got essentially is an
over broad patent that exists unless
they were to try to defend it at which
case everything would be put into
question again and and I don't know it's
odd the idea that there's an
unenforceable patent it's like they're
their best strategy maybe just to not
try to but then what value does it have
it's a very interesting legal position
it certainly got them a lot of press I
wouldn't say it's all good press
obviously but I actually haven't heard
any of it I haven't either but there
there are some other nuances that to
patent strategy that they did employ
that you know we've we've been talking
about is a very broadest claim and it
sounds like that broadest claim is quite
vulnerable to an attack for lack of
novelty they have a series of narrower
claims and maybe there's some narrower
claim that actually would define the
invention specifically enough that it
would be new and would hold up in court
and then the question is would there be
anybody out there who's infringing that
particular claim because it would be
narrower and a lot harder to infringe
and that's just you know that's a matter
for a matter to be sorted out
it when there are specific facts on the
table one other thing I'll say though is
that this is this kind of risk of your
own patents validity when you sue
someone for patent infringement is
that's that's standard in patent
litigation I've worked with lots of
clients where before they decided
whether to assert their patent they did
kind of a double check to see what are
the what are the greatest the most
viable challenges to validity that
someone could pose for our patent do we
really believe our patent is valid
because if we don't we don't want to
spend millions of dollars litigating it
and we don't want to come out of that
process with an invalidated patent and
so in in the real world in kind of more
mature
established industries people recognize
that getting an overbroad patent is
mostly a waste of money because you
can't enforce it or at least you're
really risking losing it when you
enforce it sometimes though people will
pursue broad patents in the hopes that
they can become part of a licensing
scheme that they can make it more
attractive to take a somewhat
troublesome but not prohibitively
expensive license just as insurance
against ever having to defend yourself
from from a patent infringement suit so
you know that there are a lot of things
that someone can do with a patent
besides winning a case in court and I am
not privy to what the strategy was
behind this but I will say that I've
heard your reaction a lot of times as to
the novelty now I did because I got so
many questions about chemo type patents
generally and about people you know
coming up with something that's really
new and then wanting to claim more than
just their own genetic developments that
I did write a blog about that too so if
you go to plant law calm I have a lot of
detail about what it would take to
actually get a valid chemo type patent
and why it's probably a bad idea to even
try right on so so um so before we go to
our first commercial Dale I know that I
changed your path and took you down this
rabbit hole so you know obviously we're
not going to cover all the all the
vagaries of the biotech LLC patent today
but is there anything that is in your
notes where you're like I need to get
this in before we go to commercial and
come back and talk about United cannabis
no I think that pretty much covers it
it's just kind of sum it up to say that
it's it's a matter of I think everyone
who dislikes this patent should almost
do their civic duty to identify whatever
evidence they're personally aware of
that would that would would fall within
the scope of these claims because if
this ever if this ever does get enforced
and if it is as invalid
as people say it is then there will be
someone who meets help and so if people
in the community are outraged by this
patent the call to action would be
document what you know that was prior to
2013 and be ready to step up and help
your neighbor I think that's that's a
good call to action I think that's great
deal it's not only is it crowdsourcing
from within our community but it's also
citizen science kind of stuff and and
we're big supporters of both so so if
any of you have got evidence of these
kima VARs that existed prior to the 2013
save that evidence before they dusted
I'm so with that we're gonna take our
first short break and be right back
you're listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is plant scientist and
patent attorney Dale hunt growing
cannabis in greenhouses is taking over
the cannabis industry an efficient and
effective blend of sunshine grown
terpene profiles and the controlled
environment of indoor greenhouses can be
the best of both worlds for many
greenhouse operators though building
their greenhouse before gaining insight
into how cannabis greenhouses differ
from ornamental crops can be the start
of a world of hurt
eric Branstad and his team at greenhouse
advisory group have the experience and
technical know-how to help you avoid
these pitfalls Eric Branstad has been
helping cannabis growers find locations
design build and equip their greenhouses
for over a decade first starting in
Northern California but expanding over
the last five years to helping clients
throughout the world he has an
impeccable reputation
for both depth of knowledge and kindness
and communication you can hear Eric
explains some of the challenges facing
cannabis greenhouses and how to overcome
them in episode number 41 of the shaping
fire podcast no matter where I go in the
country good people with smart
backgrounds still are making the mistake
of building without knowing cannabis and
it causes them to burn through capital
and time fast everyone has their own
failure point for some it is improper
ventilation planning for others it is
surface temperatures of the building or
the
plants leaves or both some folks that
build their greenhouse from scratch make
really basic errors like placement of
the greenhouse on the property or not
understanding the natural environment
where the greenhouse sits
some have even built a decent greenhouse
but are inefficient in their deployment
of light deprivation techniques and
never really hit their target yields
it's great when you learn from your
mistakes but it's even better when you
learn from the mistakes of others when
you bring on greenhouse advisory group
you will learn from the mistakes of
their many clients and you'll take
advantage of the best practices
developed by Eric Branstad over his
years of working with clients just like
you from location development to
choosing a builder and tricking out your
new greenhouse or retrofitting or
rescuing your failing greenhouse Eric
will help you through it
visit greenhouse advisory group com to
learn more and connect with Eric and his
team that's green house advisory group
as a listener of shaping fire you
already understand the importance of
living soil when growing cannabis when
you have active microbe communities in
your substrate you go way beyond simply
fertilizing with nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium having active microorganisms
in your substrate supports vigorous
plant growth throughout the plants root
zone making for higher yields and
thriving flowers mammoth pea is the
first organically derived microbial
inoculant that focuses on your plants
nutrient cycling processes to release
soil phosphorus and other micronutrients
from they're bound forms making them
more available to the plant increased
levels of phosphorous will also keep
internode shorter and focus your plants
energy on bud production not only that
but the microbes act as a defense shield
for the plants rhizosphere
by out competing potentially harmful
pathogenic microbes pretty cool right
mammoth pee not only unlocks the
nutrients in your soil but it also helps
protect your plant from disease mammoth
peas beneficial bacteria act like
microbial reactors continually producing
enzymes that release nutrients mammoth
pee was developed at a u.s. university
has been extensively tested by Colorado
growers and independent laboratories
mammoth pee is proven to increase growth
and enhance blooming one of the great
things about
with microorganisms is that they won't
compete with whatever fertilizer program
you're already running simply dose on
top of your fertilizer schedule for
increased benefits to learn more and to
find out where you can buy namma pee
near you check out their website at WWF
microbes calm partner with
microorganisms to create beautiful
thriving cannabis mammoth pee welcome
back you are listening to shaping fire
I'm your host Shango Lowe's and our
guest this week is plant scientist and
patent attorney Dale hunt so I thought
we were gonna get through both of the
troublesome patents in the first set but
there's a lot more to the biotech to
talk about than I thought and so let's
go ahead and we'll start waiting into
the United cannabis patent just like we
did the biotech LLC you so Dale if you
would take us through a general
explanation so people understand the
context of what we're talking about and
then dive into the two sides of the
debate so people can really grok what's
going on that would be really
appreciated you bet
so this time we're talking about u.s.
patent number 9 7 3 0 9 1 1 so if anyone
wants to google that and pull it up
again it's 9 7 3 0 9 1 1 and this is a
patent that was granted to United
cannabis claim 1 is really short and
really easy to understand so I'll read
it verbatim a liquid cannabinoid
formulation we're in at least 95 percent
of the total cannabinoids is
tetrahydrocannabinol ik acid or THC a
that's it so they're claiming to have
invented and I don't actually have the
priority date here I could I could get
that before during the next commercial
break but they're claiming to have
invented I think it was before about
2015 to be the first people to have ever
had a liquid cannabinoid formulation
that is at least 95 percent THC a and
you know in the last one we only looked
at claim one but here it's important to
emphasize that they also have
independent claims 5 if you're following
along at home look at claim 5
claimed 10 claimed 16 claimed 20 and
claimed 25 and here's why they all have
the same phrasing a liquid cannabinoid
formulation where where in at least 95
percent of the total cannabinoid is and
then claimed one is THC a claimed 5 is
THC claimed 10 is CBD claimed 16 is a
combination of THC a and CBD CBD a
claimed 20 is THC and CBD together and
claimed 20 is CBD CBN and THC so what
that means is these this patent
applicant went to the patent office
claiming to have been the first to ever
have in their possession to have to have
made a liquid cannabinoid formulation
that was 95 percent of one thing as
compared to all the other cannabinoids
in the mix now what's important to
understand is that the way you interpret
this claim it doesn't mean that it's 95
percent pure
it could be it's any liquid it's any
liquid that has cannabinoids in it where
95% of the cannabinoids in it are one
thing the thing that's claimed and the
other 5% or less is some other
cannabinoid let's poke at that for a
second yeah so so the two things that
stand out for me are number one would
this include a solution that was 95
percent THC isolate and then five
percent vehicle solution yes because
that would make it a hundred percent THC
and the claim is at least 95 percent I
see so it's it's it's not 95 percent of
the total solution right that's exactly
it that that whatever else is in the
solution that's what makes this claim
really breathtakingly broad yeah is that
it doesn't matter what else is in the
solution it doesn't matter how clean the
solution is Lee
by a conventional interpretation of the
claim the plain language of this claim
it is just that of the total
cannabinoids at least 95 percent is
whatever they call that's that
clarification is huge right it's not
right because like at first when you
were reading it I'm like okay well you
know my specialty is not extraction
right but and and when I'm you know
seeing tests for analytics for DAB oils
and RSOs and things like that you know
they'll they'll float between 55 and 85
pretty easily well yeah 95 percent for
an extracted oil is pretty high in in
any situation but the fact that that
what it describes as oh not the oil how
it comes out of the plant but any fluid
that 95% of the cannabinoids are one of
our target cannabinoids that suddenly
makes it from huh curious - holy crap
laughable yeah and and that's it's it's
so strange credulity that I do urge
people to google it and read the claim
for yourself and I'll read it one more
time in the context of what you just
said it's a liquid cannabinoid
formulation so it's just a formulation
in a liquid state that has some
cannabinoids in it a liquid cannabinoid
formulation wherein at least 95 percent
of the total cannabinoids is whatever
they call out is THC ETH CA CBD that
they have a series of claims that claim
each one of these as a separate
invention that observe of the total
cannabinoids is a major phrase right
there
it sure is it sure is so obviously again
I will point out that I haven't done any
chemical analysis on this I haven't even
done any any literature research all I
have all I'm doing is processing the
reactions of people who have first-hand
experience in the industry and their
reaction is so far I not exaggerating to
say it's uniformly what the hell or
something like that is it's uniformed
incredulity that that
this claim is would be a post-2015
invention and didn't exist before that
so do I know I know that you roll with
these like serious patent people and
plant science people because I know
you're talking with them like on stage
and before you go on stage and and do
you know what their position is on this
how you know what their fallback is how
would they respond to this do you know
that well what I hear I mean for some
reason maybe just because it came first
or maybe because it's it's actually into
chemo types and people care about their
their chemo type their there their chemo
type profiles I still pick up a lot more
upset and outrage and stress and
frustration about the biotech LLC patent
family but but when people do talk about
this one and focus on this one it's just
kind of a it's an almost mutely
astonish'd reaction that this just can't
be
again I'm passing along there their
reaction to it and I think maybe it's
it's that mutely astonished either
because it creates a sense of complete
defeat or it creates a sense of ok well
this there's just no way this can stand
in any in any just situation and what's
interesting about this is this patent
has been asserted this is in active
litigation in Colorado right now do tell
ok so you can sued a group called the
pure hemp collective and sued them on
the basis of some CBD formulations that
they were selling and this case I
believe it was initiated last July give
or take and so you know then there was a
little bit of an outcry about alright
what's going to happen here is the court
even going to hear this because one of
the questions before this case happened
was will a court even will a federal
court even permit patent litigation to
proceed
if the subject matter the patent claims
overlaps with something that's federally
illegal some people thought it would
just get thrown out now there there are
at least two reasons well there's a one
really good counterpoint I've heard
which is alright maybe some of these
claims cover THC just like well like
claim one and claim five and claim ten
and so on not Clinton to claim 16 but
the the product that was being sold
commercially was not federally illegal
it was a CBD product and so you know the
people who want to maintain hope that a
federal court would never entertain
patent enforcement litigation over
something that was all about THC they
can still hold that hope out because in
this case tea a THC product is not the
accused product it's the CBD product and
that might make a difference the other
part of it though is just that I would
think you know the argument I would make
in favor of a court hearing a case like
this is look this is a federal agency
that granted this right it's a federal
right and you're a federal court so do
your job right and in this case if if
we're to believe everyone that says that
these claims just aren't new the job of
the court would be to hear all the
evidence and eventually to find that
there's enough evidence of prior
commercial activity involving basically
prior public availability of liquid
cannabinoid formulations that fall
within the scope of these claims to
invalidate the claims that were asserted
and that's that's another bit of
esoterica that is worth discussing
when you sue someone for patent
infringement you typically say that
they're infringing claims x y&amp;z you call
out the specific claims that they're
that you're accusing them of infringing
and then they have a right to petition
for declaratory judgment by the court
that those claims are invalid but they
they can only invalidate the claims that
are inserted asserted against them the
other claims
aren't in play so the outcome of this
litigation I believe that it was just
claims and I think it was claims 10 and
16 and 20 that were asserted because
those are the claims that recite some
amount of CBD in the formulation and so
those are the claims that would be at
risk and it could be invalidated in this
litigation but that wouldn't touch the
other claims that were not asserted
alright so taking this back away from
the just the generalized incredulity
other in whatever yeah
at this point of the show the lips
aren't working as well so so we're all
astonished that it was granted but
beyond that you know if we go back to
the beginning and talk about the biotech
LLC issues part of it is where is this
stuff and the historical record right
because everybody was underground in the
medical days things were not archived as
often and without evidence the patent
and trade office doesn't have anything
to turn down a patent on I'm thinking
that we're gonna run into that that
we're in the middle of that same
situation now and and the folks who have
are you know are having to defend
themselves against these patent claims
they're probably trying to find any kind
of evidence that's out there showing
pre-existing art and that might be a
really difficult thing that's it is very
difficult and I think I I kind of talked
about this topic a lot at different
meetings and one of the things I say is
that I believe that that the patent
system the utility patent system is
going to have a problem with the with
the so-called presumption of validity of
an issued patent when it comes to to
cannabis utility patents they're gonna
have that problem for a generation
because it's going to take it a full
generation to have an academic
literature and a patent literature that
is comparable even even comparable to
the kind of academic literature and
patent literature that examiner's
usually search when they're looking for
looking to analyze the the novelty and
non-obviousness of a claim
and so see when a patent issues the
courts treat it with the so called
presumption of validity which just means
that they presume that the patent that
the patent examination process was done
correctly and that that the patent was
issued properly and what that
presumption means is that the defendant
who's trying to invalidate the patent
has a higher hurdle of evidence to
submit in order to actually get the
patent invalidated it's not just like a
50-50 okay you win this coin toss you
have to have what is called clear and
convincing evidence of patent and
validity and but I do think that this
presumption of validity it will it's
based on the idea that the Patent Office
did its job and had the right tools to
do its job and I think that when it
comes to broad cannabis utility patents
since there's essentially no prior art
or you know no no significant prior art
it's it's maybe 1% or less of the prior
art in other industries the searchable
usable prior art that is a tool and of
an examiner's job that that because of
that this presumption of validity is
just much much weaker it has to be
weaker because we know that there was in
parallel with all this lack of published
literature there was a very robust
commercial activity still happening it
was just not documented okay so a couple
things so the first thing is is so
outside of any potential American
companies that might have made these
products and had evidence of them being
brought to market
how about non-us companies say like GW
Pharma who I would suggest probably had
such a had a thing that they had created
in the lab but had not brought to market
how does that play out the fact that
they are a British company and not an
American company and the fact that they
had not yet brought it to market you're
asking in terms of what what their role
would be in terms of creating prior art
yeah correct so so would would this
would this serum that was more than 95%
THC
and or CBD the fact that it just existed
in the world is prior art enough to
unravel something this yes well not
quite because the prior art has to be
has to be evidence of either prior
excuse me prior public public knowledge
or prior public availability and so it
has to be either be a printed
publication or on sale or somehow some
kind of commercial availability so if GW
Pharma was publishing studies that
involved that kind of a solution in the
research that would be that would count
as public knowledge right absolutely
anything that's published is considered
public knowledge so Dale if if this is
already being litigated right now in
Colorado and and these folks are trying
to defend their product against the
patent claims of United cannabis what is
the where we at with it right now where
are we at with that litigation and are
we starting to get a smell of how this
is gonna play out because this is a
pretty big deal for the whole industry
yeah it really is interesting one of the
things that happens when someone gets
sued for patent infringement is that
they have a deadline to provide an
answer to the complaint and in the in
the answer by pure hemp collective they
listed all kinds of products that that
were allegedly available here they're
commercially and that that already met
the standard of being 95 plus percent
CBD as part of whatever other things
were present in the liquid you know so
there are things that were 99% CBD in a
liquid formulation or something so they
put all that evidence into well they put
they put assertions that such evidence
existed into their answer but for the
all that evidence to really be
considered the case would have to go all
the way to trial there are some things
that can happen pretrial and one of
those things was pretty interesting they
suit for what is called summary judgment
they mow they they moved for
summary judgment partial summary
judgment as to some of the claims on the
basis that what was really being claimed
was a product of nature and therefore
unpatentable under Section 101 if you
remember from the previous segment and
so there was because that didn't require
any particular amount of evidence it was
really more of a question of objective
scientific fact and applying the law to
that fact the judge was able to handle
that motion without ceding a jury or
without going all the way into trial and
because of some of the the evidentiary
standards and so on there they're only
certain things that you can even put
into a motion like that but what they
they did ask the judge to consider
whether this was an unpatentable product
of nature and after both sides made
their arguments that the patent owner
you can argued that the product of
nature that that comes straight out of
the plant is not a liquid it's it's a
soft solid and you know people who've
done resins and and other kinds of you
know crude extractions you know they can
all have their own opinion about what it
is that comes out when you just what
what is really present in the trichome
is it a liquid or is it a soft solid but
the judge considered the two the two
possibilities if the judge had found it
to be a liquid then it would be a
product of nature wouldn't even be
patentable but the judge was persuaded
by this by this argument instead that
rather than being an actual liquid
according to the dictionary definition
of liquids it was more of a soft solid
and therefore that what is claimed is
not a product to make sure it has been
altered by by human interaction so that
that was that hit the news wires as some
kind of a defeat for pure hemp and kind
of a strengthening of you cans position
but I actually wrote a blog about that
one as well and just said this is no big
deal finding refusing to find invalidity
on this particular point is not a
finding of validity of the patent
it's just a finding that that this
particular theory that could be advanced
at this stage wasn't successful but what
we're likely to see is as they get
further into the the process of
producing evidence and so on if the
parties don't settle if it actually does
go to trial then pure hemp collective
will put all this evidence in front of a
jury or in front of the judge I don't
remember if they've demanded a jury
trial or if this is something that the
judge will handle but either way the
evidence will be considered and if if
what appears to be abundant evidence
that there were plenty of liquid
formulations they're only even even has
to be one but if there are if there is
even one liquid formulation that falls
within the scope of these claims that
predated the patent then these claims
will be ruled invalid all right so the
idea that if if it goes to trial is
really interesting because we have been
seeing all over the cannabis industry
these big well-funded in capitalized
behemoths in the industry coming in and
pushing on trademarks and and on product
product patents with these smaller
players who just simply don't have the
kind of deep pockets that it takes to
defend themselves
with somebody with highly paid lawyers
that can go a long time so what are we
seeing in the moment as far as as the
hemp folks being able to even garner
their resources to present a defense
well that is a good question and I can
tell you I've looked at the court papers
I did that in in preparation for another
talk I was giving and I looked in quite
a bit of detail and they they do seem to
have good representation that is doing a
thorough job of the defense I don't know
how they're funded I hope that there are
people that are coming to their defense
if they need it they may have had
litigation insurance so I don't actually
know how they're affording the defense
they have and I I think if they ever
seem to be running low and need some
help they're proud
people that would volunteer to step up
and help them because everyone benefits
if if it is true that this patent is
over broad and invalid and again I'm
trying to be more objective about that
and because I haven't looked at the
evidence myself but if it is true that
there is that kind of evidence and that
this patent is invalid then having it
invalidated really benefits everyone
because then no one will be will be
getting a letter saying you need to take
a license to our patent or you need to
stop selling your product that would be
a public benefit yeah it sounds like a
good reason for a GoFundMe so so how
long do we expect this to play out is
this something that's going to be
kicking around for a decade or is this
something that's you know gonna be
pretty aggressive and we'll be wrapping
up here in the next you know year or two
well I have no litigation expert usually
what I do is is transactions relating to
IP and helping people get patents I've
I've walked some clients through
litigation and so I know about how
litigation works from that perspective
but I my general sense is that different
judges set different pace different
kinds of pace for the cases they handle
and that the pace of this case will be
somewhat up to the judge and then
somewhat up to the time required to
gather the evidence in discovery and
then the parties if they're negotiating
some kind of a settlement they may
request some kind of a continuance to to
settle the case but I would expect that
this if it goes all the way to trial it
could drive on for another year or two
all right I don't know that before the
authoritative lis though yeah right I
just just something for us to go with
right so that we can all have a better
understanding so all right so before we
go to our second commercial you said
something and I didn't want to interrupt
your flow a while back but I thought I
think it's very important to note that
the fact that there is not a rich
library of cannabis information make is
showing proof of products that have been
in the market how long they were in the
market what the packaging looked like
what their claims on the packaging was
their analytics there's this big void
and you said something interesting you
said you know this Kree
it's a sense of you know a lack of
knowingness that is probably going to go
forward a generation as the old evidence
comes out of the shadows wherever it may
be and if there's not evidence in the
past the new body of work that is
happening now with decreasing
prohibition as it fills in the holes and
like a generation later will have this
stuff you know decided better for worse
but you know yeah I spent most of my
life as a business strategist and that
sends up huge red flags for me because
so many of these businesses that are you
know getting high-level capital
investment and our you know IP owing as
part of their value package they're
claiming IP and this IP is not settled
and what this tells me is that I love
here on your laughing what this tells me
is that these these value claims of
these companies will be in question for
a while and wildly increasing the risk
that these companies need to overcome I
think that's true although it's not I
would say that it's it's more true in
some fields than others if you're
claiming something that that has the
technology to have been around for a
long time and just isn't documented
you've got to really be suspicious about
whether that patent is valid so you know
something as technologically friendly is
can you make a liquid formulation that's
not that's not very new so liquid
formulations have clearly been around
for a long time and it makes you wonder
have these particular liquid
formulations can are they how likely are
they to be new in other situations so
you know there are really new
fundamental technologies that are being
applied to cannabis and it's very
unlikely that some new like let's I'm
not advocating genetic engineering but
let's talk about there's there's
something called CRISPR which is a
technology the less people edit genes in
and live
organisms and change the genetic
expression without actually putting in
any foreign genes and so if you have a
technology that's as new as CRISPR and
you have patent claims that are directed
to some new beneficial use of cannabis
that involves that then you could as you
could safely assume that you wouldn't
need a long old history of prior art
going back a few decades to establish
whether that was patentable or not you'd
have less of a likelihood that that
existed in a in a in a previous industry
that was kept in the shadows so it is a
function of what kind of invention it is
that would it would give you more or
less confidence about the the strength
of someone's patents and there's just
one other thing I want to say about
utility patents because these two
patents are so far out there and incite
such an emotional reaction in a Hana
what the hell kind of reaction from
people it has it has kind of created a
bad name for all utility patents and if
you if you have a cultivar of cannabis
that you bred yourself and that is
special and it can do some great things
and you know you originated it and
you're trying to get utility protection
just so you can protect the seeds
because that's the only way to protect
your seeds if it's a high THC cannabis a
plant patent isn't available plant
variety protection certificate isn't
available so it's a utility patent or
nothing hating on people who get utility
patents of any sort is I think that's a
gross over interpretation of the problem
I would liken these two patents to you
know 18-wheelers with 30-foot trailers
rumbling down a school zone at 90 miles
an hour and if you don't like that that
doesn't mean that you can't like someone
riding their bike through the school
zone or driving a normal car at 25 miles
an hour in the school zone just because
they're all motor vehicles doesn't mean
they're all doing the same thing doesn't
mean they all pose the same threat and
sometimes a utility patent is the only
tool available to
one who just wants to protect what they
actually created within a normal
appropriate scope that isn't
overreaching and because these utility
patents have so offended people in the
industry there is I think a real
backlash against what I would call very
appropriate and necessary utility
patents well yeah that's for sure I mean
I'm a big fan of open source nearly
everything but it wasn't until I
interviewed Reggie Godinho on an earlier
episode that I realized that open source
is a good place to come from in the
heart but we need these Pat we need good
people to get patents and exert their
patents just so that we can defend the
heart of cannabis so it isn't all owned
by folks who don't want to use it in the
same way that that those of us who've
been in the family for a long time want
it to be used I would agree with that
yeah so all right so so let's go ahead
and take our second break and when we
come back we're gonna talk about some
real brass tacks about how folks who are
are breeding and developing plant lines
can play a little defense against these
types of patents and and stick there you
know draw their line in their stands so
you are listening to shaping fire I'm
your host
Shengo Louis and our guest this week is
plant scientist and patent attorney Dale
hunt this message is for folks who grow
cannabis I'm talking to home growers
patients and commercial growers too I'm
probably talking to you when you plan
out your next growing cycle be sure to
check out Humble CSI seeds at Humble CSI
dot-com
Kaleb Inspectah and his family have
lived in Humboldt County for over a
hundred years for the last 40 years
three generations of his family have
cultivated extraordinary sensimilla
cannabis in Humboldt Mendocino and
Trinity counties because of his lineage
and the hard earned experience that
comes from growing up smoking and
sifting large populations of cannabis
plants in Northern California
the seeds you'll cop from CSI will be
winning genetics based on long time
heavy hitters and updated Andrus if
today bring out new and exotic traits
and better yields go ahead and ask
around Caleb also known as inspect
and pirates of the Emerald triangle is a
breeders breeder he reaches way back and
works with significant strains
recreating them in new and interesting
ways that you'll love is a toker
and a grower as well as offering you
some surprises that will delight serious
seed traders and cultivators Humboldt
CSI goes as further step and selfs all
these chemo VARs so you know all the
seeds will be female these are not
experimental feminized seeds Humboldt
CSI releases some of the best female
seeds available anywhere and it will
show in your garden folks grew quite a
bit of CSI humble gen-x last year here
on Vashon Island and everyone was
pleased the patients had beautiful
female plants and didn't have to call
half of their garden as males the folks
growing for the fun of getting high grew
colorful flowers with exceptional bag
appeal and great highs and breeders had
seven out of seven females in a pack
which gave them a lot of phenotypic
choices take a moment right now and
visit Humboldt CSI comm you'll find an
up-to-date menu of both feminized and
regular lines along with photos and
descriptions
that's Humboldt CSI calm now that the
health benefits of terpenes have become
well known in the cannabis industry
people everywhere are looking for the
purest terpenes and custom terpene
blends true terpenes isolated terpenes
and terpenoids
are tested to the most demanding
worldwide safety and stability standards
terpenes from true terpenes our
third-party tested non-gmo and food
grade their triple distilled making them
the purest terpenes available in the
world with over a thousand terpene
isolates strain profiles and Terp
flavors you can be sure that true
terpenes will have the perfect aromatics
for your manufacturing goals true
terpenes also offers custom blending so
that you can match your company's
marquee strains across all your product
categories while you can certainly
simply just order terpenes and go right
to manufacturing true terpenes also
offers a wealth of manufacturing insight
best practices and a willingness to help
you break new ground with your product
formulations true terpenes has robust
and supportive customer service too so
your questions will get answered fast
and efficiently if you shop for Terps
before you know how rare that is
if you are a cannabis product developer
these are the Terps that you want to add
to your oil or edible or capsule or
beverage true terpenes are simply the
best your money can buy don't try and
make a premium product with substandard
Terps choose true terpenes for a
top-shelf experience go to shaping
feiyr.com
ford slash true terpenes to find out
more or click on the link in this week's
newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I'm your host
Shengo Lowe's and our guest this week is
plant scientist and patent attorney Dale
hunt so Dale now that we've scared the
hell out of everybody
during the first two sets let's then
bring this on home right because one of
the things that I appreciate about
chatting with you is that you're
constantly looking for solutions for
these challenges for breeders because
you know the more I read your blogs and
talk to you about the kinds of things
that interest you you know I can't be
the first person to recognize that you
have you have made a bit of a path from
being a straight up you know patent
attorney to actually being a bit of a
cannabis activist it's pretty obvious
what side of this that you are on while
you know remaining clear-headed and
neutral but I enjoy talking to you the
other day about you know what strategies
are that you recommend for people
developing you know clonally chemo VARs
and seed sets to protect what they've
got going on because you know clearly
everybody cares a lot more about this
since the Philo's mess and people don't
really have solutions and you know from
show to show I mean we talk about
patents pretty regularly on this show
and and everybody kind of comes to the
same point of you know we don't know how
this is gonna play out yet there are no
clean right answers because everything
is in play but the you will hold this
unique see where you are a plant
scientists and also patent attorney
where you can kind of see the state of
play and say alright we don't know how
this is gonna play out but the best
defenses that we can do today are ABC
and that's what I want to talk about
because a lot of folks that are listed
they're putting their life's work you
know out into the world and and they and
they don't want to get skunked they
especially don't want to be skunked by
people don't have that don't have the
same heart that they have so so talking
specifically about plant genetics and
breeders wanting to protect their
creations what are the present best
protections available for these folks
well one of the protections is actually
free and I and I wrote a blog about it I
look up on plant law comm and look for
the picture of grapes and I don't really
remember the title of blog something
about protection from furrier IP that is
free and never expires and unfortunately
it only helps with it only works with
one business strategy and that is let's
suppose you have a cultivar that you've
developed in and you love it and it's
fantastic and but you either can't
afford a patent or you just don't want
to go there
if your so if all you're selling is
flower and you're never going to sell a
clone then you can sell you can then
that the challenge you have is to just
control whoever gets access to your
propagating material you can sell
harvested material all day long it's
dried its cured and no one can replicate
your clone from the harvested material
if you control all the cloning and
control where all those clones go and
who grows them and you've got good
agreements to govern all of that then
you might not need a patent the bad news
of that is that even getting those good
agreements in place with people is going
to cost some money and then there's
still some trust involved and some
challenges when you have to trust other
people and that's why people even even
big companies that control when I talk
about big companies I'm talking about
like my grape clients and my my
blueberry clients they don't let any of
their genetics out of their hands
they're vertically integrated but they
still get patents because if it does
slip out and they can't there's it's
impossible to have a big organization a
big operation
and still have perfect security if
anything does slip out they and ends up
in the market they need to be able to
have some recourse against whoever is
using their genetics without their
authorization and if that's not someone
you made it a made a contract with then
you can't sue them for breach of
contract and unless they're the ones
that stole it and you can prove they
stole it you can't go after them for
theft but you can always go after them
for patent infringement if they're
propagating your plants without your
permission and you can prove the patent
infringement with a DNA test that gives
me an opportunity to say one thing about
DNA a lot of people think you have to
have a full DNA sequence or a DNA map or
something to apply for a plant patent
it's not true I wrote so wrote a blog
about that and I think it's titled
something like none that's how much DNA
you need - how much DNA information you
need to apply for a plant patent I've
obtained counting international ones
I've obtained thousands of plant patents
for my clients and we've never submitted
DNA now on the other hand the first time
we had to prove infringement in a really
contested case and with these grapes
that I've worked with we got a DNA test
right away for that because that was the
way to prove infringement and the point
is that you can always go get the DNA
evidence it can be helpful to have it in
advance because then you don't have to
show a chain of custody and everything
you could say this is the same DNA test
that we submitted in our patent
application and our queue this accused
plant matches it completely and so it's
clearly infringing but you don't have to
have that DNA evidence to to to get the
patent in the first place and then you
just you just basically do a comparison
of your patented cultivar and the
accused cultivar and the DNA will make
it open and shut so that's why even
though people can have a viable business
just based on agreements and on high
security
some people that have good agreements
and also have high security still choose
to patent what they have because it
gives them recourse a different
kind of legal recourse against people
who end up coming in and using their
stuff without permission and just you
know you don't have to prove theft you
don't have to prove a breach of contract
you just can prove that that they don't
have a right to that they're using your
plants and without your permission
oh so got it so so if that is the if
that is the business model that is most
easily protected it's also like one of
the least common in in the scene right
now right folks who are growing their
own cultivar and are the exclusive
people bringing out on the market
certainly they exist but certainly
there's a hell of a lot more people who
are bringing seeds to market and that's
probably gonna be the bulk of people's
concerns so let's wait into that all
right I'm glad you asked about that
because that's when your choices are
really different if you are
commercializing seeds or selling seeds
or or anything except except harvested
except flower and you want any kind of
intellectual property protection your
you really do have to either go with a
utility patent to protect the seed to
have claims that protect the seeds or if
it happens to be industrial hemp you can
go through the USDA plant variety
protection system but in any of those
cases you still have to have McGuirk
perfect flawless control over your
plants and what's done with them or you
have to have some kind of some kind of
contracts or you have to have some kind
of intellectual property recourse and
the problem is you can't exercise that
flawless control over your genetics if
you're selling seeds that's that's the
whole point is you're putting them out
there and so in this case if you want to
be selling seeds you're either going to
have people growing those seeds without
permission or you're going to be able to
get a patent on on your seeds and at
least restrict you know they can buy
your seeds they can grow your seeds but
they can't use them for their own
breeding and that's a hot button because
a lot of people really believe in the
importance of open source can
was breeding and I'm I'm someone that
supports that not notwithstanding the
fact that I'm a patent attorney I
recognize that the industry itself in
the community is very passionate about
sharing genetic resources it's been a
kind of an ethic within the industry for
a long time and those people who want to
do that it's not for everyone but people
who want to do that should be able to do
it and I I I caused a little bit of a
stir by writing a blog that is says why
open-source cannabis doesn't work and
how to fix it and so I definitely have a
and an illegal analysis behind that
right now
so so let's let's let's get very
specific so let's say that I am a seed
maker and I'm breeding unique cultivars
or at least ones that I consider unique
we'll have to talk whether or not
they're unique legally or not and I want
to put my seeds out and I I want to be
the only person that can sell seeds that
have got my name on it and and no one
else should be able to breed with my
seed stock unless I give them permission
I'm guessing from the rest of the show
today that that's actually a pretty high
high level of difficult to just secure
that but let's hear what you have to say
well it doesn't have to be difficult if
you are if you're focused on if you're
if you're willing to pursue a utility
patent that isn't one of these over
broad 18 wheelers barreling down the
school zone it's it's a it's a nice
friendly Subaru or something going 25
miles an hour it's an appropriate
vehicle for protecting your invention
that you limit your claims to the
specific cultivar that you placed on
deposit which would be a seed sample and
you say I'm claiming seeds related to
these seeds seeds they're the same
progeny of the same cultivar as the
seeds that are on deposit I'm not
claiming anything else I'm not using
those just as an example of what else as
an example of something typical of my
claim that is what I'm claiming so first
of all that's a modest request it's a
modest scope of protection you're only
protecting the thing that you invented
not other things pea
that not things that other people might
someday invent and if you do that
through utility patent then you can you
can get claims to seeds that are progeny
of the of the plant of the plant
cultivar that's on deposit you can claim
a method of breeding cannabis involving
crossing one of those one of your
cultivar with something else and so if
you do want to be able to maintain that
kind of exclusivity and you don't want
to be in more of an open-source model
then then utility protection isn't
actually it's not inaccessible and it's
not it's not an overreach that's that's
the only available way really to protect
your seeds if they have over 0.3% THC
well if they make plants that do that so
I understand how that works downstream
from me if I was the breeder but how
does that work upstream so you know just
about nothing out there to breed with as
a land race anymore right you know most
breeders are not going you know into
these like original heritage countries
and bringing back seeds so let's say
that let's say I'm a breeder and I'm
going to cross you know one seed that I
bought from one breeder and another seed
from another breeder and I'm gonna cross
those and I'm gonna make a whole bunch
of seeds and then let's say i do a sift
of a hundred of them and i find my
favorite to like how far away from the
original two seeds do I need to get
before I can patent it do I have to do I
have to do something novel to them or
can I just take any two in Kaikohe just
cross the Mac one two anything I'm like
boom I want to patent this well well I
could or not that this the standard for
novelty when it comes to patents and
plant genetics is really low if it's if
you're trying to patent a cultivar you
just have to show that it's new if your
if your patent claim is limited to that
cultivar it's it's impossible for one
cultivar to be obvious over another one
it's legally not possible and so it's
really all about the novelty and if you
think about the novelty re
and this this sounds crazy but it really
is true every single seed ever formed in
a cross is new and different from every
other seed genetically if you think
about all of the genes that get shuffled
in a sexual cross that results in seeds
there are no two that end up being
genetically identical yeah that's true I
mean we've got all these different fee
knows and and so so would it be based on
the short read of the genotype or of the
genome instead of how it expresses
itself as a you know in any particular
environment Russ yeah I'm just thinking
out loud so so what I'm what I'm hearing
here is that I can take any two seeds
and if they are not already patented
that you're not allowed to breed with
them I can take any two seeds and cross
them at this state of the industry and
suddenly I've got a not novel keema var
and I can patent it yes and one of the
blogs on plant law calm is it answered
the title is how can I tell if my strain
I think I use the word strain there how
can I tell if my strain is new and
different enough for patenting and my
answer to that in the blog is if you
made it and it's a new it's a new result
of a sexual cross it's by definition
different and distinct enough for
patenting and you know that it's new the
question is always going to just be is
it worth patenting many things that you
produce are not going to be you know if
you do a cross you'll have thousands of
seeds you'll grow many of those out and
decide which ones have the phenotype
that you want and then you'll save if
you know a small handful of those is
your special results of that cross and
you may do some more crossing in some
more selection but when you finally have
something that you think is going to
have commercial value for years that's
when you think about patenting it and if
you think it's going to have commercial
value for years then you know you're
going to grow that plant you're going to
do some back crossing you're going to
try to stabilize the seed line as much
as you can try to get it as homozygous
as you can without losing all the traits
that you're after and when you have a
stable seed line that's probably when
that's what you would probably want
to try to commercialize and that's
probably the appropriate time to try to
patent it and that is you know you are
going to if you're doing seeds you do
need to be able to say that the seeds of
this particular cultivar are
substantially say it's stable and that
they're substantially true to type and
so you know if you have a segregating
population that wouldn't even count as a
as a cultivar per se but but the real
question of is it new it's it's new
because every sexual cross is new it you
know and and is it distinct even you and
your siblings are different from each
other even though you came from the same
parents and it's the same with every
seat okay
um but going into the future as utility
patents on seeds become more common the
the breeder is going to also have to ask
does does the original breeder of this
seed that I'm crossing already have an
existing utility patent on it which
would restrict me from breeding it right
that's right okay of course if they want
to assert their rights they need to
label their product and so if someone is
selling patented seed there would be a
patent number on the label and that's
when you'd have to respect the utility
patent so if if you don't see a patent
on the label chances are it's not
patented and even if it is that the
patent owner isn't doing what they need
to do to put the public on notice and
you would have a defense to infringement
and now of course if you if you later
got notice and you kept reading that
would be a different different problem
right on I follow that and so let's take
that one more step farther so if we want
to lock down our genetics even further I
would think that the next step would be
doing you know kind of a strategy like
some of these seed companies are where
they are developing chemo VARs and
honestly now they're not they're not
just clones but but but where they're
selling seeds in bulk to for example
hemp folks where they'll buy five
thousand seeds but it comes with a
license that you won't breed or share
sorry that is that is kind of creating
[Music]
a safety zone for those seeds but not
involving the US Patent Office that's
right that's that's really creating a
system where your recourse against
someone who violates that is a breach of
the agreement under which you sold in
the seeds the problem with that is so
you know if I sell seeds that are
restricted I say you're allowed to use
these seeds for growing plants to grow
harvest and material I I can't stop you
from breeding with these seeds unless
unless I only sell that maybe I sell
that under terms where I say you're not
allowed to breed with these seeds and
your purchase of these seeds is an
acknowledgment of an agreement between
us that you won't breed with these seeds
then if someone did go ahead and breed
with those seeds or did try to sell you
know a second generation of those seeds
without your permission and that was all
in the contract you'd be able to go
after them for breach of contract and
again that comes to the problem of what
about the person downstream from that
agreement what if someone else gets
their hands on those seeds and they have
a defense of not being a party to that
agreement not being aware of the
agreement and so yeah you can you you
can have agreements like a shrink-wrap
license in the software industry that
restrict what people do with seeds you
sell but unless you can show that that
the person that that accepted those
terms when they bought the seeds is the
person that is violating those terms
that's you know you're not you can't sue
someone for breach of contract if
they're not the party to the contract
and that's the problem
Wow that that right there is such a
messy thing to have it turn on right
because you know some of my favorite
seed companies are licensing their seeds
because the material is so unique and
and I do I actually believe they should
be able to charge to to pay for the
research and the significant part of the
life that they put into developing them
but they can really only enforce it
against the people they had the licenses
if somebody they had a license with gave
it to a
friends surreptitiously they can only
sue the person they had the license with
not their friend that took it and
crossed it with something else
that's I would call that a big gaping
hole it is and that's that's why people
choose to plug that hole with a patent
and you know one of my sayings I use a
lot is if you're a hammer everything
looks like a nail and if you're a patent
attorney you can fall into the trap of
thinking the solution to every problem
is a patent and I don't want to sound
like that I I try to learn what people
want to accomplish and then help them
accomplish that in a way that's most
consistent with their needs and their
goals and their budgets so I don't
always recommend patent protection but
if you're working with biological
organisms that that self reproduce and
that are so easy to reproduce in large
quantities if you're if you're free to
do so not having some kind of a backstop
of intellectual property rights just
means that you've got to have much
tighter control in other aspects of your
business plan there's just no other way
around it right now I'm advocating a new
system that would change that but but
the current system just doesn't it
doesn't give you recourse against anyone
who's not a party to the agreements that
you made great and I'm glad that you
mentioned your new system because this
is where I want to go next but before we
do you go there we have talked about a
lot of Vig areas back and forth and I
just like would like your bulleted
action points for somebody who is
listening and they are breeding their
own seeds what is the best thing that
they can do right now to protect
themselves as this evolves just give me
the short version so that they can write
it down and have a task list first thing
is to make sure you're you're selling
your seeds with some kind of
restrictions on the label and that you
make that sale as conditional as
possible try to sell only to trustworthy
parties and if you can't do that and you
value those seeds and you think they'll
have commercial value for a long time
the bad news is you really do need a
patent and it needs to be a utility
patent
okay and I think that that probably
describes just about everybody in the
seed game so then what are the next
steps they take to do that and let me
just let me just amend that if if it's
industrial hemp then you have two
options you've got utility patent or
plant for any protection certificate but
there are some reasons not to do PvP
including that there's an express
exemption that permits people to breed
with the seeds that they obtain that are
protected that way so it still goes back
to utility patent the steps are if you
want a utility patent make sure that you
that you get an application filed within
a year of the first the first public
availability of the seeds or any part
any any part of the plant so you've got
to move relatively quickly make sure
that you're working with someone that
knows what they're doing
find out how many plant patents they've
filed before or not even plant patents
but utility patents relating to plants
and you know just just make sure that
you are getting what you pay for when it
comes to getting the legal advice that
you need okay so so let's talk about
this new idea that you've put together
for a new spirited international
convention that would protect nearly all
the people who are breeding cannabis
plants because it certainly got me
excited listening to it and it sounds
like a really great way for to bring
everybody together for the good of the
availability of the plant and honestly
it feels a lot like open source it the
more you and I talked about it so so go
ahead and give us the the elevator
speech if you will yeah I have been an
advocate I've been sympathetic at least
to open source and I advocate its use
for people who want to use it it's not
for everybody but the problem the
biggest problem with open source in
plant genetics is its contrast with or
as demonstrated by contrasting it with
with computer software software open
source works because software has an
automatic copyright the moment it's
create
you don't have to apply for a copyright
the problem with open source in plant
genetics is that there is no automatic
right that exists upon creating a new
genetic selection you have to go apply
for that you have to pay for it and so
the analogy between an open source
software and open source plant genetics
breaks down at this point where a
copyright infringement is a form of
recourse you can use against someone who
never agreed to your your the conditions
of your open source software situation
but if you create an open source seed
sharing or genetic sharing community and
someone is outside that agreement and
you don't have underlying IP rights to
assert against them you don't have
anything to assert against them because
you can't go that after them for
breaching your agreement they weren't a
party to your agreement and so what I'm
advocating is a form of plant breeders
right that is very similar to a
copyright and now copyrights exist upon
creation of an original work because
there there was an international
convention though there still is called
the Berne Convention that was
established in 1896 or 1886 I think in
the the US I don't remember 86 96
whatever but the u.s. joined it a
hundred and two years later and so as of
that date copyrights in the US were
automatically protected I think it was
it was 86 and 88 so in 1988 the u.s.
finally joined the Berne Convention and
copyrights became automatically
protectable as soon as you created an
original work now what I'm advocating is
something very much like the Berne
Convention for plant breeders so that
when you create an original cross and
you make a selection and you you
establish a cultivar that you don't have
to apply for any form of protection it's
already there it's there like a
copyright and someone who violates that
by illicitly obtaining and propagating
your genetic selection would be in
violation just the same as someone who
illicitly obtained some software code
and commercialize that that's what I'm
advocating it's going to take some work
but I think there are enough people who
would benefit from this and enough
people who care about it that I do
10 for this just to be talk so if if
every single seed is unique and you're
talking about giving everybody who's
plant breeding default protection how
does that drill down to the uniqueness
of every individual seed that's a great
question and if you if you read the blog
that I wrote about open source one of
the headings is my dad is such a pain
lol now the reason that's relevant is
that anything we ever write anything we
ever write that is original is protected
by copyright but that doesn't mean we
commercialize we do anything with most
of those copyrights every email you've
written today and my example in the blog
is everything my kids text on their
phones practically is copyright
protected unless it's completely
unoriginal like my dad is such a pain
lol that's not original enough to
qualify for copyright because my kids
were not the first ones to type that in
a text even if they type it a lot so the
point is that there's there's a there's
more copyright protected material out
there in the world that's being created
every second than anyone is ever going
to do anything with in terms of
particular ting their legal rights but
the fact that that protection is
automatic gives you all kinds of
latitude if you write a blog or if you
write software or if you you know
whatever whatever kind of creation you
you you do whatever kind of creative
activity that that is protectable by
copyright you've got that just by having
created it and by analogy you know if
you think about all the text of people
right that might be analogous to all the
diversity that is in a single batch of
seeds every one of those seeds would be
protectable would be would be under the
basically the the the basic breeders
right but what they choose to do with
that is another thing now how many
people how many things do we have that
are copyright protected that we never
care to assert our rights over but if
something in there is really valuable
the difference between the text that you
send and a book that you write then
you're going to have some rights that
you do care to assert but you still
don't have to go
apply for those rights now let's extend
that let's apply that to an open-source
system if every breeder that puts
something into an open-source system
already had a right to assert against
someone who used their their genetics
without permission then an open-source
system would work because within the
system you'd say all right we're gonna
share seeds under conditions we've all
got rights under these CR these seeds
but we're gonna share them under
conditions that you will do you know
this and that and you won't do this
other thing with these seeds or that if
you do this other thing let's say if you
if you commercialize something that was
derived from these genetics that you
have to pay something back into a fund
that protects everyone from patent
infringement litigation or something
like that
so you can put conditions on the use of
those seeds and if everyone had
protection of their genetic varieties
that was automatic then anyone who
illicitly obtained those seeds and did
something that was outside the
open-source system you'd have recourse
against them just like people have
recourse against against a copyright
infringer so if it plugs the hole that
exists we talked about the fact that you
can't sue someone for contract for
breach of contract if they're not a
party to that contract but you can sue
someone for breach of an intellectual
property right without ever having a
contract with them that's a really
interesting and engaging idea the fact
that if if every seed that is bred is
automatically protected it opens us up
to be able to more casually share the
seeds with other seed makers because we
don't really have to worry about what
they're doing with it and so it's it
reminds me of that old phrase fences
make good neighbors well it's like if
everybody who's breeding already has got
protections for their stuff but people
generally don't mind if other people are
breeding with their seeds as well then
everybody kind of is this is on equal
footing which I think most is what most
breeders want I think most breeders just
don't want their work usurped
right people recoil at the notion of
having everything just just dripping
with intellectual property because it's
new to them and it sounds like that's
just overkill but the real overkill the
real problem is the difficulty and
expense of getting the intellectual
property protection because once you
have it you're free to do whatever you
want with it including just leave it
there and not not assert it at all we're
not we're not troubled by the automatic
nature of copyright protection I would
say that plant breeding is at least as
much a creative activity as writing is
you know certainly not not all plant
breeding results are created equal and
not all writing is created equal but
it's all protected by copyright and it
hasn't made you know planes fall out of
the sky and and disaster happen all over
the place it so it's it's it's a little
bit foreign and it in a way it's
counterintuitive just like you said all
of these rights that everyone have has
would actually make it safer and easier
to share what we have because it would
it would give us a way to kind of sift
between the people who are willing to
play by some some basic rules of respect
and trustworthiness and still have some
recourse against people who aren't
willing to do that someone who comes in
and and takes what you've got and then
commercializes it and and does something
you don't approve of or whatever you've
got you're gonna have some recourse
against them also so I see one more big
challenge to this the first one of
course being this this you know keeping
in balance protecting myself while
wanting to share with you and and I and
I like your I like your answer to that
but as we've seen time and time again
well-funded folks are are just pushing
low funded folks to go to settlement and
not really getting their day in court
just simply because they can outspend
them legally how would a small person in
your or an under financed person in your
system defend their automatic patent on
their seeds
well that that kind of depends on if
they're trying to assert their rights
against against someone who is who's
using their seeds without permission
that's a challenge because there you
know the you face you face different
challenges when you're asserting your
rights then when someone is asserting
their rights against you you you
basically you've got to fund the
litigation upfront and if the abuse is
bad enough then you may be able to
recover damages one thing that I've
advocated in addition to this open
source system which is more about
defending against abusive patent suits
against defending people who are who are
sued for infringing and abusive patent
is a system of mutual defense and but
that is about defending against being
sued for an abusive you know an abusive
over-broad patent that we that the
community has already come to the disc
um to the conclusion that is invalid and
should be fought so I do advocate in a
blog that I wrote called standing up to
big AG a mutual defense approach where
it's kind of like NATO you know if you
sue any of our members we're going to
band together and use all of our patents
to see if there's any of our patents
that we own that we could counter sue
against you for infringing our patent
that's better described in the blog than
we have time for in this situation but
basically it's a mutual defense approach
and we are actually I'm I don't like to
just write about things and not put them
into action I am trying to form some
kind of a coalition of United small
cannabis companies and and individual
breeders that can create that kind of
mutual defense in the event that one of
them gets sued for patent infringement
it's harder to put together a mutual
offensive approach just because it's
it's it's harder to insure against it's
harder for it to get in
for that kind of outcome but it could
still happen and I think depending on
how you fund the open source system you
know if if the open source system has
some kind of fund that people who
infringe it have to you know if they
let's say the the the damages that come
from an infringement of an open source
system if those damages went into a fund
that could then be used to further
assert the rights against you know just
the people who violate the system that's
a pretty sensible thing to do with with
proceeds from an open source fund but
those are really two different things
the mutual defense against offense
against being sued for infringement of
an overbroad utility patent is kind of a
separate institution separate animal
from the the open source and open
automatic rights approach all right I
follow that and so so a lot please allow
me to distill this down to see if I've
got this right so so what you're
proposing is kind of like this this this
two-part 1-2 punch thing the first thing
that we need to do is to set up an
international convention so that there
is a default setting that when breeders
and it sounds like you're talking about
all plants but since we're talk about
cannabis where where cannabis breeders
the moment they make the cross and they
have resultant seeds those are by
default defended by a patent and so that
creates the protections that most
everybody is needing and then your
second is let's pull these newly
protected breeders together into some
kind of cannabis breeders union and and
call ourselves an organization and you
know pay some sort of yearly fee that
will go to litigation insurance so that
if any one of us is having to defend
ourselves we are able to turn on the in
turn to the insurance policy so that all
of all of we
sir funded cannabis folks are able to
represent ourselves the same way that
NATO if one country gets attacked
everybody comes another defense is that
it do my close that's pretty close I
would just I would correct not even
correct I just am and one thing that you
said about you know the automatic
protection for plant breeders it
wouldn't be a patent because patents get
applied for and they get examined and
they have certain rights it would be
more like a copyright that is that that
is automatic and it's basically just a
prohibition it's not something you can
write claims for and that you that you
you copyrights are inherently available
but they're they're not as I'd say
they're not as usually complicated or
strong as patent rights per se and so
what I'm advocating for is a really
basic breeders right that but that gives
you some recourse against someone who
would in infringe your your rights all
you'd have to do is just show that yeah
this is your this is your part your your
selection your the result of your
breeding and that someone has in print
has had someone's taken it that the DNA
matches and therefore you have a right
to stop them from from making further
use of it in a way that would be very
similar to a patent but it would just be
I don't think you'd want to use the term
patent because that implies it's gone
through this whole process that's great
route going so it's not really a patent
or a copyright it is not a patent but
it's kind of like a patent but it's not
in its and it's kind of like copyright
but it's not a copyright it's some third
thing yeah I'm advocating the creation
of a natural plant breeders right to the
the selections of you know the crosses
and the selections that that breeder
makes that would be equivalent to a
copyright it wouldn't be the same as a
patent but it would give the breeder the
right to control what people do with
that production just the same as a
writer has the right to control what
people do with his or her written work
you know as as you roll this out and you
and you start to make this real you're
gonna have to find yourself a new
vocabulary right because patent
the word is not only not what you're
doing but it's packed with all of these
expectations and and such from people
and then it's also not copyright and
it's also not open source and so what
you're creating is an animal that we
have not seen in cannabis so far and I
think I think that you need some new
vocabulary man yeah we do and and but
the whole reason to do this is to
facilitate open source it's to make it
so that you'd you can have recourse
against people who are not parties to
your open source agreement if they're if
they're violating your open source terms
without ever having agreed to them it
gives you a recourse just like people
have a recourse against copyright
infringers that's the whole point of it
and there may be some other things that
people could do with it but the the main
the reason I came up with this idea is
that it it would fit would make open
source workable and I want to see open
source be workable so it's it's
explained in more detail in the blog
that I wrote about that and then in
terms of the mutual defence fund it is
it would be really a group that
purchases some kind of group litigation
insurance I've done some preliminary
pricing on this and I I don't have a
strong enough commitment on the pricing
to be able to quote it or anything but
the idea would be that yes you have a
coalition that forms an organization
that buys this group insurance and that
the group insurance covers people who
get sued for patent infringement
so that they have just as big a patent
in a patent litigation war chest as the
people who are suing them so that the
size disparity goes away and then
there's also a mutual commitment by
members of this organization that if
they have a patent that this other said
that this that this opponent is is
infringing that the defendant can use
this other organization members patent
against them just and it is in a way
analogous to NATO that you know you
point your guns at me everybody on my
team's guns point back at you and so we
hopefully don't shoot each other we
decide to find a way to settle our
differences obviously this would need to
be administered by some kind of a
non-profit and but I think that
once once we had an idea of how many
members were interested in that and what
the insurance rates would be then you
basically charge a fee that covers that
plus maybe the cost of one administrator
and then you have a mutual defense
that's workable it it's not something
that I that I would advocate doing on a
for-profit basis just because we have so
many trust issues in this industry
already if someone thought this was just
a scheme to make money I don't think
people would want to be part of it but
if we see that see it as an answer to
the does the balance the the imbalance
of power between big cannabis or big AG
and a bunch of small cannabis people who
still want to be able to stay in
business they don't want to have to
consolidate they don't want to have to
sell to a big company they want to be
able to stand and and and do what
they're doing and and not not be at the
mercy of this huge imbalance of power
that the way to do that would be to form
a coalition that actually has teeth in
it that can provide a mutual defense in
the event that some of these over broad
patents get asserted against one member
of the community so Dale just because I
know you a bit I know that this is
actually kind of a activists kind of
heart taking thing that you're taking on
and yet most of the listeners including
me you know like we're stoners who know
about pipe dreams right and so what can
you tell us that that would encourage
people to pay attention to what you're
doing or think that this is reasonable
that this has come together instead of
just being a really great story to tell
over a bowl well I think the the that
the answer always has to be watch what
people do and not just what they say do
you cut them some slack in terms of
getting things done and if you're not
sure whether they're real or not talk to
them and offer to help and you know if
someone if if someone thinks that I'm
floating these ideas just
for fun or just to give people kind of a
like a temporary pipe dream or something
talk to me reach out to me ask how you
can help because I do want to I do want
to turn these things into action I have
become a bit of an activist even though
I still run a law firm and have to pay
bills and things like that a lot of what
I do and care about the most is not
really tied to anything that I can bill
anybody for in my law firm I just want
to see things work well enough that
everybody in this industry prospers and
and achieves their their goals well Dale
this has been great and I really
appreciate meeting an attorney who I
find both personable or divine
personable skilled and on my side and
usually I don't get all three in the
same so so thank you very much for for
spending your valuable time with us
helping us get to the bottom of these
two biotech and United cannabis patents
that people are talking about a lot but
didn't really understand very well and
kind of bring this up to the state of
the art or the state of play of where
cannabis patents are today because we
really just want to protect ourselves
and it sounds like our best play is
gonna be to continually work together so
IVA I'm pretty sure that we're gonna
have you back on again because this has
been great to hear your experience and
put so succinctly so thanks a lot Dale I
really appreciate it
it was my pleasure thank you so if you
want to follow up with Dale there's two
places that you can go to if you want to
interact with him about his law firm or
to ask questions or get involved with
the next steps of this international
convention or mutual support pact you
can go to his website at plant and
planet.com
which I got to tell you is now my new
favorite law firm URL and then you can
also clearly Dale was letting us know as
we went along about his blogs and I've
spent a lot of time there already and
they are well worth it and they are
detailed without being overly long so
you can go check out those blogs at
Plante law.com you can find more
episodes of
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shaping fire calm and on
Apple iTunes stitcher and Google Play if
you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you'd leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download your review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango
lowes.com does your company want to
reach our national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host
Shango lows
[Music]