[Music]
for as long as humans have been farming
farmers have had a relationship with the
land that is intimate
mutually giving and high stakes farmers
learn about their land by looking at it
and comparing it to other seasons
they can touch the soil and trees and
fruit and mud
and learn about its health the sounds of
the wind through the grasses and the
bird song
tell their own stories and even tasting
physically tasting the soil and water
tells an attuned farmer
something about its makeup ever since
humans started farming
families in small communities have
literally had their lives dependent on
the crops that were grown
a failed season could be financial ruin
and perhaps starvation and death
similarly a successful season meant more
for everyone
paid off debts and the joy that comes
with physical security
all of this human meaning coming from a
farmer's relationship with the land
during prohibition cannabis farmers had
to know their land
and pray about the weather too and they
had the added threat of law enforcement
and helicopters
trying to provide for my family by
growing fields of cannabis while
avoiding the dea
and national guard overhead has got to
be one of the most stressful jobs i can
imagine
but at its heart farming always comes
back to the land and the weather
that essential relationship that give
and take
demands and openness from the farmer and
a willingness to do what the land wants
to keep her in balance and
fertile as cannabis enthusiasts
we can all benefit from remembering that
cannabis
is flowers and that flowers come from
the earth
and these flowers connect us to the
efforts of farmers
everywhere and so we are all connected
to their land
their homes their families and our
shared earth
if you want to learn about cannabis
health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer
i encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week
and videos too don't rely on social
media to let you know when a new episode
is published
sign up for the updates to make sure you
don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive that newsletter
this month we're giving away two prize
packs each with a bag of happy endings
root stimulation t-mix and ocean bounty
flowering tea mix from our friends at
green bicycles
kevin jodrey turned me on to this about
five years ago
and i've been using it ever since so go
to shapingfire.com to sign up for the
newsletter to be entered into this
month's and all future newsletter prize
drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and
i'm your host shango
los today my guest is nicholas mahmoud
nicholas mahmoud and elizabeth luka
mahmud founded green source gardens in
wolf creek oregon
where they produce cannabis and food
using regenerative farming practices
they were awarded the prestigious
regenerative cannabis farming award at
both the emerald cup in california
and at the cultivation classic in oregon
green source gardens is a dragonfly
earth medicine dem
certified regenerative farm they are
also certified by kind
sun and moon and are a watershed
conscious property
nick is a highly sought after speaker
but he's hard to get because they live
so far up the mountain and are nearly
off grid
that said nick has spoken at emerald cup
and a few other key
events today we're going to discuss
suggestions for
putting your garden to rest in the fall
opportunities for improvement over the
winter
and some best practices for waking your
farm up in the spring
welcome to the show nicholas hey shango
it's great to be here awesome and thank
you i've really wanted to do this show
with you ever since we recorded that
great
video um at your farm and i'm so
grateful for finally getting to it so
thanks for making time in your busy
schedule especially uh you know so early
in the morning today
so let's get right into it you know at
the end of the season
so many of us just want to walk away
from the garden right because we're
tired and we're ready for a break
but fall is a really great opportunity
for gains in a garden that's integrated
with the nature that's surrounding it
so so let's start there in the fall so
i'm sure as you are harvesting plants
you're already planning
what you're gonna do as soon as
everything is hung so
will you walk us along your process for
putting the garden to rest for the fall
sure um first of all it starts
it starts basically in august and and
so it actually begins before harvest um
and it's kind of a preparation for
harvest is
kind of uh it's
preparing for harvest is the beginning
process
of getting ready for the winter and the
way that
um i look at this is is
when people are when we're out
harvesting uh these plants
we're stepping on the soil around the
plants a lot so the first step
that i'm taking that we're taking is
is mulching around the plants really
heavy with wood chips and there's a
reason that we use
wood chips um wood chips are kind of the
most uh
resilient and soil
protector if you will um so when you
actually put wood chips on the ground
and then walk on those wood chips
it prevents compaction and it also
prepares the
the surface of the of the ground for the
winter rains and
and the ability to infiltrate water
into the ground as well as once it
starts to get wet again
um all the microbiology that's that's
kind of
maybe hidden down in the soil a little
deeper in the late summer
because of the dryness is able to
work its way back up to the surface and
beyond into the new mulch layer
so so you know really if you want to
have your garden really well prepared
for winter you start in the summer and
you know i can't i i can't emphasize
enough
that people start their they think about
their care
pre-emptively before the season
everybody wants to get away or
like finish a season and is it's really
you know like
a big time of the year to want to
stop doing anything because all the the
work that's gone into the season but
really
in order to uh really do a good job you
have to think about
the soil you have to think about the
weather that's coming you have to think
about the weather that exists now you
have to think about what happened all
summer
and and one thing that happens in the
summer in a garden space that's
irrigated is a lot of microbiology eats
a lot of the carbon
mulch that is available and therefore
once that mulch is broken down into more
of a humus it becomes more capable of
being compacted
and that's that's exactly why you know
you really want to like
put all that heavy wood chip around your
plants before your workers are out there
harvesting on those plants so that their
footsteps aren't actually doing damage
to the
uh to the soil layer below so
yeah that's that's the beginning process
when you are
placing the wood chips um how
um how far out from the plants are you
going are you are you putting them more
at the base because you're
just trying to protect the the eight or
ten inches on either side
of the stock or are you all like no no
no no
we heavily do the entire bed so that
um so that it's more
liberally protected or do you go so far
as to wood chip
the isle ways between the plants too
because i know you see your soil as
being kind of
one one comprehensive organism
instead of like discrete parts yeah it's
it's a it's all dependent on the
resource availability how many wood
chips do you have
how much mulch availability do you have
um and if you can do the whole bed
and the pathway that's ideal and the
more you can put on
that time of the year the better because
what you're looking at doing
is um you know the the benefits of the
wood chips at that time of the year
are numerous and and preparing for
we have to think about things in terms
of climate so i'm in southern oregon
and i'm thinking about the winter and
and the winter in southern oregon is the
wet season
and therefore there's all this leaching
that goes on in that season
it's different where it freezes really
hard and the ground's frozen all
all winter so a lot less happens in that
scenario but really the soil wakes up in
southern
oregon in the fall when it starts to get
wet again and all that microbiology has
that moisture to be able to
um to to start to do its work again and
so
um you know the wood chips are
a preparation to support the fungal
growth for the wintertime
and the fungal component and the hyphae
and
and the mycelium that uh basically
covers the the soil when you wood chip
heavy
is the protectant layer that prevents
leaching
so the fungal the the way the fungus
works is the mycelium encases
all the organic matter and now when you
run water through it
the water doesn't carry anything away
the the fungal component
actually acts as a filter and so this is
a way to keep the water clean and to
prevent leaching from occurring
it's not the only way to do it and if
you have access to a lot of wood chips i
live in a forested area where there
needs to be massive amounts of thinning
going on anyway so we
generally are able to find access to
good wood chips
but in a case where say your fertility
is already really on point you're in
some agricultural lands
you know you might choose the direction
of just straight cover crop in the
winter where
the the root systems are acting as the
nutrient uptake and the protector of the
soil but in in the case where i
i am uh our fertility is not very high
we
we live in the mountains and on gravely
serpentine soil so
you know what i'm really doing still
even at year five is is i want to
promote the development of humus
and and and continue building fertility
uh for years before i get to the point
where say i was down in the the valley
bottom
and all the silts get carried down um
and and there
it's an endless depth of of really
nutrient-rich soil so
you know in my case i am wood chipping
heavy for
many different reasons but a lot of it
is prevention of compaction
and feeding the soil life and
particularly the fungus we're actually
aiming to acidify uh a little bit
we're looking at acidic more acidic in
the winter
and and more bacterial in the in the
summer but
you know ultimately there's always both
the bacteria
or the alkaline and and acidic
i guess the two different things and the
way that we can think about that is
fungal uh fungally dominant soils
support more acidic soils
and bacterially dominated soils support
more alkaline soils so
we're trying to support a more acidic
soil in the winter and then we balance
that in the spring with the manures
[Music]
for the for the growth of the crop um
right on so um my question about
wood chips would be you know when i was
at your property
your property has got more wood chips
than i've ever seen
on a cannabis farm actually on any farm
period
and i know that most of your stuff comes
from your
the forest around you but you were clear
earlier when you said
you know if you have access to good
chips
so you know in in some ways you're
probably like a chip guru you know
so so teach us a little bit about wood
chips and for
and sourcing and choosing the kind of
chip we're gonna use
well the good thing about wood chips is
they're generally coming from tree
companies who are doing either road work
or
homework and you know people don't spray
their trees very often so
oftentimes wood chips are actually
pretty clean in comparison to other
things
if you're working with people who are
doing a bunch of landscaping stuff on
really
uh you know uh managed landscapes you
then you have to be concerned about what
people are
are managing the landscapes with in
terms of chemicals and stuff
but you know in the case of gathering
from tree services who are
are working on roads and stuff those
wood chips are great um
and i highly recommend people search out
their tree companies
and utilize those wood chips that way
because otherwise they're oftentimes
just being
not not used well they're they're being
taken away from the site in which they
grew
and they're being dumped in a place and
all heat together
and it's just not an efficient way to
maximize our carbon
so you know there's a lot of energy and
and
and and gasoline and all the stuff that
goes into even chipping wood
so you know i personally am not even
chipping that much wood off my own land
i'm just
accessing the wood chips that's already
been processed
in in these cert or these systems that
exist that maybe aren't the most
efficient in terms of gas but
they exist and so we have to intercept
these
these uh these carbon streams that are
being wasted
and and put them back into good use and
and you know honestly wood chips are
probably the cheapest
most valuable input that you could ever
put
on your garden so in terms of what a
good wood chip is like everybody's
always concerned i get the question a
lot about
what type of wood chips do you want to
use and what type of trees are
okay to use and you know my my general
answer
for most of these things is they're all
good um
but they're best when they're they're
diverse
so you know people are like well the
evergreen trees are too acidic and and
all this and
there's some truth to that there's
different chemistry and different trees
while they're living but as they're
dying and being consumed
back into the soil they lose that
chemistry and so even the things that
are say aleopathic
walnut trees and pecans or these kinds
of things that prevent things from
growing doesn't mean that the wood chip
breakdown is going to prevent things
from growing as well
so just understand like old if you've
got wood chips that have been sitting
around for a couple of years it doesn't
matter what kind they are
um you know there is some truth to
redwoods prevent fungal growth cedar
prevents some fungal growth
that's true and if all you have is all
redwood chips are all
cedar chips you might just put those on
the pathway and know that they're going
to take a little longer
and not support a certain component of
your soil
as much as say like an oak tree or a
maple tree or an alder tree
deciduous trees in general might support
a quicker saprophytic fungal breakdown
process so
diversity is always the aim you're
always looking for
you don't want the best you know if you
wanted the best you would eliminate
all the rest and then you would be down
this path of monoculture
and that's the issue that i think this
culture faces is we're always trying to
get the most efficient
best thing that we can because we care
so much about
having the best and and that kind of
mentality is
is the one that takes you down this
narrow path of problems
um because now you're eliminating the
diversity in the system
and you're subjecting yourself to a
really one-sided
imbalanced scenario so a bunch
it's all good it's all carbon it doesn't
even have to be from trees
you know everything breaks down the same
everything
there there's no carbon that's better
than other carbon
essentially right on you know i really
appreciate you nick you know this every
time i
hear you speak whether it was the video
we did together
or or seeing you at emerald cup you have
this wonderful way of taking what goes
on on your garden
and tying it seamlessly into the systems
around you right
like you took that question and next
thing you know you're talking about
uh carbon streams that happen off of
your property and how to maximize them
for the good of the earth
and you know and then suddenly you're
like all the way back over here talking
about uh you know different seasonal
soil types
all while talking about what makes a
good wood chip and and i appreciate that
that holistic
um the headspace of yours so so
so when i originally asked the question
i said you know what are you doing
starting at harvest and you're like well
actually django we start pre-harvest so
our and then we talked a lot about wood
chipping so is there anything else that
you do
pre-harvest that we want to make sure
that we catch on
before we go to the next time block
which will be after harvest
sure pre-harvest you know it's a good
time to gather up the potatoes that are
growing
under and around um and just
to kind of either to to store them for
eating
and or to just break up the clumps of in
groups of potatoes and spread them out
before the mulching
so you can kind of replant your potatoes
at that time
by by harvesting and spreading them out
if you want them to grow big again
if you leave most tubers and stuff they
they form multiple many uh at the base
of
of where they grow and if you don't
harvest and spread them out they they
end up becoming smaller and smaller as
the years progress you may have many
more but they're just the the production
is is sacrificed a little bit and they
get overcrowded
like most things and and you know you
just don't see those
giant big potatoes if you don't take the
time to
take those potatoes out and and spread
them about so
you know if you're going to be spending
a bunch of time pushing a bunch of wood
chips onto the scene
pull your potatoes out first spread them
out and mulch over those potatoes i
don't
ever do anything very systematically
like i'm not making a line of potatoes
or
i'm literally pulling them out pulling
the ones i want to eat
and then the ones that are scarred or
eaten by bugs to some degree i'm just
tossing
into the area i'm not really even trying
to place them
anywhere in particular so spreading some
of the
the food crops out the tubers um
that that might be one thing uh that's
really helpful right before the mulching
applications
uh you know uh so yeah you know it's a
good time to throw cover crop seed on
the areas that aren't gonna be as
mulched
uh so if you if you have some extra seed
laying around or
you know it's also a good time to look
at what has seeded itself in the garden
and if you want that stuff to grow in
different places to cut that down and
just lay it where you want it to grow
and and and that'll kind of increase
your desired uh cover crop potential
um so right on so so i know you to be a
huge fan of having potatoes under your
plants for a couple reasons
for folks who haven't heard you talk
about this why don't you hit on that
briefly before we move on because
it's interesting and it's something kind
of unique to your farm yeah well
i mean potatoes have fed the world for
so long that it's
it's a worthy crop to pay attention to
uh it's also a tuber
and tubers are doing great things for
the soil they're not feeding just
us i mean because they feed us these
these important starches and they give
us
a a bank of food that you can basically
source
all year long it's also feeding the soil
life so
leaving a bunch of potatoes in the
ground it explodes your
arthropod populations i've i can't tell
you how many times i pulled up a
rotten potato that was just heaving with
with millipede life like an explosion of
of certain
you know uh biology that that's
important and so
i look at it at the potato and it's not
just potatoes uh
tubers in general but potatoes just
generally seem to do really good in our
our growing scenarios i can't help but
think that's
that's aiding and helping the cannabis
as well so potatoes have been one of our
favorite companion plants with cannabis
um since for for many many years once i
started honing in on that i i just
understanding potatoes is is an
important piece of
of having a secure food system i guess
you know it's like when it comes down to
it
i eat more potatoes out of the garden
than any other crop
so i consider it very valuable and a way
to
make sure that i'm gonna get through the
winter
if all the stores close down kind of
thing yeah it's a real dual use thing
isn't it right
you can eat them whenever you want but
but also they're
while being respectful to the food
they're also not precious right you can
also put them
you know in the ground to rot as well
and they are doing an entirely different
precious job not being food at that
point because there being food for
all of the complex
living things that are in your garden
and one of the things that i like about
potatoes too
is that it is nutrition that's
accessible
to multiple levels of magnitude
in your bed it doesn't just feed
one level of magnitude um when it's
whole it feeds one group of insects and
then as it breaks down
it feeds all the way down to the
microbiology and um
and it's got so much nutritional value
it just seems to make the entire bed
more abundant
yeah i mean it's it's an amazing thing
and in the spring when you leave the
potatoes in or they've over wintered and
they start growing super early and they
freeze back and then they grow multi-top
they become an amazing cover crop where
i'm actually having to destroy a lot of
vines when i'm transplanting things in
because there's just potatoes everywhere
and that's a good situation to be in you
know because
you know i don't have to worry about how
many potatoes i'm going to grow i've got
thousands of pounds in the ground i
don't ever harvest them all
but in the spring i've got this
beautiful uh
cover crop uh vining
green and potatoes three four feet
tall and five feet bush like by
june so i can harvest potatoes from june
until
uh through the winter so it's really a
i i can't i can't recommend potatoes
enough i mean they're the best
uh they're the best food crop that i
know of
um in terms of they don't eat that much
in the soil you know they're they're
amazing
it's interesting to me to hear you talk
about potatoes as a cover crop because
you know i grew up in detroit
and um yeah you know i think of potatoes
as something that's under the soil
but you're like no man in the in by june
they have grown up out of the soil and
you've got these green tops
and they're producing all these other
benefits that we normally
you know just give to radishes yeah
exactly
and and honestly they're they're
they cover the ground and when you say
cover crop that's what you're looking
for
is something that is acting as a living
mulch layer
uh that protects the soil and and the
rhizosphere so
you know again but the potatoes don't
grow the same way if you pull them all
out and plant them individually they're
much
they're just not as vigorous and not as
bush and cover like
so you really have to like exercise this
idea of
planting way more than you want and
leaving a bunch in and just watching the
process naturalize
and then intervening only when things
start taking over
um and and you know that's a lot of what
i believe is that you want the things
that come back
easily and naturally without much work
that serve a bunch of different roles in
the garden
and ideally it's a it's it's
it's managing the overgrowth in a good
garden versus
trying to get stuff planted in and you
know it's it's really about
it's being the the space is being
overwhelmed by life
and now you just have to make room in
that overwhelmed
space for your little plant that you
want to grow as say a cash crop that we
do like for cannabis so
i'm really in at this point when i'm
transplanting in i am making space
in a very diverse and and and strong
living plant guild um
and just i'm kind of just wrecking the
plants in one area so i can get a plant
into there
um so it bodes well for transplanting
and
it makes things a little more
challenging for direct seeding so
there are some pros and cons to most
practices yeah right on
so that brings us up to actual harvest
right if that's all stuff you're doing
before you're cutting your plants for
the season
let's talk about your routines after the
plants are hung
okay let's start let's so
one of the most important things and i
think is neglected
most of the time is that that time
just after harvest is really the time
that you need to be building
uh your potting soil for the next season
so we don't buy any soils we don't buy
amendments we don't buy stuff to make
our potting soils uh
we we use everything from on-site and
and and and wood chips i mean wood chips
aren't always from on-site but uh
our manures are on site uh my we we buy
hay
uh to bring to the farm so so there's a
couple things that we are gathering
off-site i don't wanna like
try and pretend we're a hundred percent
closed-loop i don't think anybody is
right now i think it's good to
uh be vulnerable and and
and share the processes that you know
are
our reality which is we do have inputs
for our
our potting soils but it's wood chips
and it's manure and and all the manure
that we get is from our own animals and
and so
um we basically you want to get that
into a space that's going to be covered
and and you want to layer that in a way
into a size where it's not going to heat
up too much i think everybody's
been brainwashed in in this
composting process to think that their
compost has to get to 140
for a certain amount of time and i think
a lot of this stems from
kind of the organic certification stuff
where it's like if you're going to apply
compost to your crops it needs to be
having
stayed at 140 for this long but what
people overlook in that scenario is
that's only if you're adding that
compost to the crop
before or within 90 days of harvest
but if you're not putting that
you can put manure directly on your
fields
and it's not an issue as long as you
have 90 days of growth
before that crop is harvested so what we
want to do is prevent
thermophilic composting we want to
prevent the heating of these piles
uh to 140. i aim for
a a range from 80
to 100 and i try never to get up that
much more above 100
and the reason for that is that is this
that is the
temperatures in which microbiology is
most
active and really i'm looking for as
much microbiological breakdown
while maintaining and retaining all the
nutrients
of the stuff being processed so cold
composting
actually puts and keeps the carbon in
the ground
hot composting you lose your nutrients
to the atmosphere
you start to put the carbon back in the
air this is what
we're not trying to do as say this term
regenerative that
seeks to put more carbon in the ground
than it takes out
so so the potting soil is is
done in our hoop houses which were
previously had grown uh plants in and i
do a lot of breeding in the hoop houses
there
um but those gal get cut down and then
everything comes down and i build this
this what looks like a berm inside of my
hoop houses and those are the berms that
i manage
through the winter to biologically break
down
and become stable well broken down
humus that is the potting soil for the
spr for the springtime
and that it's important for that to be
covered by
something you don't want the rains and
the weather to be
working on that pile because you want to
be adding the moisture
and reducing the amount of leaching and
making sure that that process
is happening uh in the right way
so that in the springtime you have a
really good uh
medium for sprouting seeds without
running into a lot of say damping off
and and
and and issues that come with uh things
that are less processed
um having more fungal
stuff going on and damping off is one of
those things that you have to pay
attention to with your
especially your sprouting soil mediums
not so much transplanting once the
plants a little bit older it can take
some of that stuff a little better but
if if you're not trying to create
compost piles
that are going to cook and you are
actually more
relying on time over the course of the
winter
for the manure to age and for the
compost
to increase in microbe life
i would think that your your thoughts
about the inputs would be different too
if you're not trying to get to 140. so
um i i would just guess that you're
using
everything that you find on the farm and
just creating lasagna but but
maybe talk a little bit about um what
these piles consist
of other than the manure that you've
already hit on okay
um first and foremost whenever you're
making a compost pile really that bottom
layer should be the fattest
chunkiest stuff you've got so wood chips
is always a great base layer but
if you've got a bunch of branches that
are smaller
twig like branches that's a good thing
too
basically what that does is it creates
this uh
this sponge for the more nutrient rich
that
because i do do the like the lasagna
layer just because it's kind of like
i can manage the manures the wood chips
the forest matter
um and and put them in the right places
and and anytime
you're creating or building soil of any
sort
this isn't just about compost even
though everything is getting composted
um but just in general you want to build
a bed you want to
you know you want to do things where
you're maximizing
all the potential of the things that
you're putting there
you want your biggest most lignin-rich
source of carbon at the bottom and you
want rich
nutrient uh dense stuff that's gonna
soak
that carbon because that carbon wants to
suck all that in
that carbon wants to hold all those
nutrients and
you know when people talk about wood
chips tying up
nitrogen or saying it makes the nitrogen
not available
there's a there's some truth to that but
we have to look at the benefits of that
that
when the wood chip pulls that energy
into it
now you have a much better food source
for the biology
because there's not just what the wood
chip was but now it's this
nutrient-rich tea that has naturally
infused itself into that so when the
fungus grows it actually grows
uh better so you know you start with
your wood chips on the bottom
and then a layer of manure uh a layer of
forest
leaves i go to the most diverse areas
usually the gulches
in my area where the horse tail and the
the the big leaf maples and the alder
and and the oak um are all kind of close
together so when i
gather the leaves um i'm getting a
diverse
uh mix of forest matter and
and really that's you know that's what
you want is that diversity
i i don't highly recommend people go out
and just start
hacking away into the forest soil and
start bringing that
because unless you're bringing something
to add to that
it's kind of just this taking from a
place and it's actually
maybe not that helpful to the place so
you know when gathering materials from
the forest you want to look at where
materials gather the most
easily and are deposited with the the
water or they fall and the wind blows
them into this
area and you want to be taking from
these basically forest matter deposits
that naturally occur
and that way you know it's going to
replenish in that spot over and over and
it's not necessarily you going out
and finding the best forest soil that
you can and starting to dig into the
soil i
i'm really just kind of gently raking
as much leaf matter and oftentimes my
forest matter that goes into my potting
soil
is me cleaning up our access roads where
all the leaves and pine needles and
and that kind of stuff um are and i need
to clean that because we need to be able
to get up those roads in the winter
to get to the shop so really you know
it's it's kind of a great system in in
that you know we're keeping the roads
uh able to be used there but we're also
getting
all that energy that would naturally
just turn into muck on the roads
into uh a potting soil so um
so you've got your your woody uh carbon
carbonaceous layer you've got a layer of
manure
uh to soak into that and then you've got
a layer of this
forest leaves and then you might wood
chip manure but you don't
the biggest piece of keeping things from
getting too hot is how
big of a heap you make you know the
bigger the heap
with the same materials added will get
to 140.
but i'm keeping this in a long
smaller heap and i'm with a temperature
gauge just kind of watching how things
um how the temperatures increase and
rise and
and if it starts to get too hot i'm i'm
kind of opening it up and spreading it
out just a little bit to prevent that
from getting as as hot so you know the
more you heat things
up uh generally the hotter they get and
quantity
is is oftentimes the uh the the factor
that
kind of gauges what the temperature is
gonna be at so
you know if i i could make the same pile
and if i added three times as much i
might be thermophilic composting
um but you know the other great thing
about doing this in
in my hoop houses is the hoop houses
serve as the nursery
and so when i'm filling pots to do
nursery work it's always from the ground
it's just from right where i'm standing
and so it's really efficient from a
working standpoint i'm not moving soil
very far
all the work has been done in the fall
and now i just have my system
dialed there um and and i have potting
soil
to scrape up off the ground anywhere so
it's real basic it's not that
complicated i'm not putting any kind of
like
intensive uh
inputs outside of the manure to
add nutrients you know if i know the
soil
is naturally low in calcium i might
try to shoot for more oak leaves because
i know that oak is a
a calcium accumulator so
so there's a lot of factors there's a
lot of thought processes there's no
right way there's no wrong way uh
there's just ways and and the way that i
do it is is i i spend a lot of time
thinking about it
and i and i just do what makes the most
sense and and you know i don't need to
nobody needs i don't i don't mean
for it to sound like this is how you
have to do it it's just that
there are some things to consider like
you don't want to lose
everything to the atmosphere because
that's truly what we're trying to
prevent and you get a much more stable
end result
when your biology has been supported
the thermophilic composting supports
pasteurization
it it it heats up to a point where it
kills everything
that's what people mostly want because
they want to be killing the weed seeds
or the seeds that they don't want
but you know i embrace uh all those
all those components as a part of the
living system
and i'm not trying to kill uh and
pasteurize
seeds and i don't worry about uh
pathogens in that scenario as long as
the
biology is strong enough to have done
the work
for a long enough period of time um
i i don't i don't run into a whole lot
of pathogen problems especially as
the years roll by and the soil building
has occurred in the same place over and
over
um right on that's a great explanation
nick i especially like your idea that
this is not the way there are many ways
and when when you talk about it you can
hear the reasoning behind what you're
doing
so farmers who are listening to this
anywhere
on the planet can go okay i understand
how he's thinking
about it and for me and the the plants
and inputs that i've got where i have
where i am and the types of soil
i have i can go through these same sorts
of thought processes
and make a regenerative solution that
works locally for me
now before we go on to um the the rest
of your
your after harvest uh process and move
into winter
let's go ahead and take our first short
break you are listening to shaping fire
and my guest today is regenerative
farmer
nicholas mahmoud of green source farm
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated
it is increasingly important to avoid
the use of chemical pesticides when
cultivating cannabis
beneficial insects have been used for
decades by the greenhouse vegetable
and ornamental plant industry and today
many cannabis cultivators
are moving from sprays and chemicals to
beneficial insects
covert biological systems has the
mites and nematodes microbials sticky
cards and air distribution units
you need to partner with nature to
defend your garden
whether you manage acres of canopy or
have a simple grow tent in your home
cobra is ready to help answer your
questions and help you transition away
from chemical sprays towards clean and
natural solutions
since 1967 culprit has assisted growers
in identifying pests
and devising reliable solutions while
providing healthy insects and mites that
will protect your yield
since the 1990s cobra has been a leader
in cannabis
pest and disease control worldwide and
have highly trained consultants to
assist you in canada and the us
from coast to coast no matter where you
live
covert biological systems can help visit
cobert.com
choose your country and get detailed
information
that's cobert k-o-p-p-e-r-t
for the most up-to-date cannabis related
biological control information
you can also check out their instagram
at covert canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and culprit is ready to help visit
cobert.com today
oxygen is an essential plant nutrient
and keeping sufficient dissolved oxygen
in the root zone is a challenge
gaia's brand of ultrafine bubble systems
will help your garden thrive in ways you
may not have considered
no matter if you grow in soil
hydroponics or aquaponics
gaia's ultrafine nanobubble systems will
increase your dissolved oxygen
and increase your yield often the first
sign of inadequate oxygen supply to the
roots is wilting of the plant under warm
conditions and high light levels
insufficient oxygen results in an
accumulation of toxins
and an insufficient amount of water and
mineral absorption
if oxygen starvation continues mineral
deficiencies will begin to show
roots die back and plants will become
stunted
healthy roots supplied with sufficient
oxygen are able to absorb nutrient ions
selectively
from the surrounding solution as
required in studies
this has shown a 30 increase in plant
growth
not only do ultrafine oxygen bubbles
allow your plants to thrive
but they will keep your drip lines and
irrigation pipes and plumbing clean too
because algae pythium and other invasive
species only survive in low
oxygen environments and the gaia system
only costs about two dollars per day to
run
gaia ultrafine oxygen nano bubblers
are also great for making compost teas
and wild crafted nutrient teas
the smaller bubbles of truly dissolved
oxygen
allow more microbes to reproduce faster
go to gaia's website at h2o5.com
to learn more about using dissolved
oxygen and how to purchase this simple
yet amazing technology
that's h205.com
with the national hemp program in flux
due to stringent thc testing
requirements
brother seth and eric crawford continue
to release seeds to hemp farmers that
will be legal
no matter how you grow them or when you
test them these new varieties from
oregon cbd seeds have substantial
amounts of cbdv
cbgv cbcv and thcv
while always staying below the 0.3
percent thc limit
and guaranteeing compliant crops for
farmers every time
also these new varieties cannot be
pollinated by your neighbor's
uncontrolled pollen
or a rogue male in your own crop either
oregon cbd seeds are non-gmo certified
too
oregon cbd seeds was founded and funded
in 2015 by seth and eric
maxing out their personal credit cards
without outside investment
they continue to refuse outside
investment that would change their
company culture
oregon cbd grows tons of fresh food on
their research farms for local food
banks
literally tons of food they also give
away tens of thousands of pounds of r d
flour to patients
as their company began to succeed seth
and eric started donating money to the
cannabis medicine and hemp fiber cause 2
by giving millions of dollars to oregon
state university in order to establish
the world's leading cannabis genomics
research program
and they treat their employees right
oregon cbd pays for full health and
dental coverage for their employees
a 401k program and their minimum
starting wage is 20 bucks an hour
plus everyone shares food from the farms
seth has been on shaping fire a few
times to talk about novel cannabinoids
you can check out episodes 25 and 37 on
cbd cultivars in the hemp market
episode 66 on triploid cannabis genetics
and the very first shaping fire live
episode 47
with seth and soil expert jeff lowenfels
talking about autoflowers
if you are a hemp farmer and you want to
grow reliable seeds that are sure to
thrive in past testing
check out oregoncbdseeds.com to learn
more about buying seeds for the 2021
season
that's oregoncbdseeds.com
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host shango los
and our guest this week is regenerative
farmer
nicholas mahmoud of green source gardens
so before the break we were talking
about
the late fall after harvest preparations
that you do and we've talked a lot about
wood chips influencing the quality of
the soil
the building of the type of compost pile
that you most like
to prepare your potting soil for the
following season
um is there anything else that we want
to talk about
about putting the property to
bed before we move into you know winter
and forest management and stuff
well you know i think it's just really
important that the soils all get covered
uh that you're thinking about your
your tubers and stuff uh spreading out
you're thinking about what you want it
to look like the next season and you're
just kind of managing whatever perennial
uh stuff you got going on um and that
that varies between the different plants
that are uh
perennialized in the system so you know
those are those are the important things
so yeah we can move
we can move forward all right great so
so at this point
we're getting later in the season we're
we're into uh november december
depending on where we are
um you know the the rains have begun
maybe the
the temperatures have dropped um
significantly
heck if you're at high enough elevation
you might be thinking about snow at this
point
and you know in in my head i'm usually
thinking all right this is the time that
you're gonna be
you know in the house in front of your
fireplace with your family
and some of your celebratory flower from
the summer
and yet um you are outside uh taking
care of things on your property
that you know really are best done when
you don't have more pressing things to
do
so so take us through what you're doing
during doing
during the winter all right um
well you know one thing i like to think
about a big picture ecological
perspective
and i'm always i'm not always
a hundred percent focused on the garden
but i'm i'm paying attention to the
surrounding landscape
and and trying to do my best as a
steward
to maximize what i can do in the right
seasons in the winter time
as the the moisture comes back into the
system and the weather
starts to permit the ability to
start working on force management and
and you know for us we rely on wood for
heat so
um you know in the winter
based on the we have an 80-acre farm i
only
we only grow on a small portion of that
and we're
we're just in this really overgrown this
is common in
in most of managed forests in the west
is that these these management practices
have been
seeking uh production uh first
our forest lands are actually farms for
trees
and and in that process we've overlooked
the
potential ecological uh health of the
system
to maximize profit for logging companies
and
and and just for the land's sake uh
and and and completely um
just are doing terrible things in the
long run
for uh the potential of the place and so
the winter time for me um has been a lot
about
looking at thinning the land that are
overgrown
and and and maintaining the larger trees
on the landscape and and cutting down
the overgrown
understory of of trees that are just
choking everything out and becoming a
serious fire hazard
um and so uh
wintertime is a thinning time and and
that's that's a big part of
the work that is going to go down is
once the fire season is over
i'm thinking about the next fire season
and
and i'm thinking about how to get the
landscape into a position where
if a fire did roll through it wouldn't
be detrimental but rather maybe even a
little bit beneficial
and so truthfully uh the forests have
been managed by indigenous peoples on
the west
for uh longer than we can
understand and to think that it's uh
that there's this uh you have to leave
nature
alone in order for nature to be at its
peak but the truth is is humans are a
part of nature and so we're trying to
you know understand our relationship to
ecology as a species of
participating members in the ecology
and you know so when we look to what do
we do we should be
uh sourcing the indigenous practices
of the area to best uh promote um the
ecological health of the forest uh we
are participating
steward um of the land and so
uh what that looks like is is you know
managing overgrowth and really this is
like
there's um there's some you know there's
written things about everything but
there's this idea that there's this
principle
uh i forget the full-on thing but the
gist of it is
is that there's a lot of things out
there that if
left unchecked will just take over
diminish diversity
and reduce the potential of the ecology
and it's humans that can come in and
help
manage that for the diversity and when
we think about
health in a forest we're thinking about
um
we're thinking about layers uh within
the forest and we're thinking about
light penetration and we're thinking
about canopy and we're thinking about
um fire breaks that impede the ability
for fires to be devastational
um and so we're really
immature in our understanding uh
even just us being uh
myself and my wife and landowners in
general
uh we're really we're at this time
in in the world where the land hasn't
been being cared for that well and the
culture that we come from
doesn't understand what care really
looks like and so
in order to begin the process of healing
that and and repairing some of the harm
that's been
done we really have to look at things
from an ecological
big picture perspective and and
understand that
you know a healthy forest is one that
has big trees that are spaced apart with
with a bunch of different brush growing
underneath and grasses that can grow in
light penetration that can promote the
diversity
and vines growing into the trees and
enough space in between the trees for
fire not to just wreak havoc
so i'm i'm spending a lot of time
you know i do i'm starting the process
of burning more just because the
scenario's so intense you know i went
through a process where i thought well
we don't want to burn anything we want
to sequester that carbon into the ground
and that's you know that's that's a
great idea but
and the reality is um the state of the
forest
and where they're at in this the state
of the danger of the fires
is there's a lot of burning of brush
and stuff that does need to be done if
you could chip it all that'd be great
but the truth is is we don't all have
chippers and how much gas would it take
to do that
and so you know thinking about a
fire breaks and and working on your fire
breaks and
and what that also does is it increases
the light penetration which is
increases the potential ground growth
so you know we like to thin spaces
strategically surrounding the homes
surrounding
our most valuable resources and then
start the process of of getting the
ground prepared to be able to grow
more than just say all cedar trees um
and and hopefully try to increase the
diversity
on the ground level as well as the
canopy level um
and then introducing animals to that
once that's been done
uh really helps but we're in the early
stages you know
i i really move slow in in making these
big decisions because i really
understand that i come from a
a broken culture when it when we talk
about stewardship
and so i try to just not be too hasty
and think i have the answers right away
and
and i i implement small scale and
and watch and observe and and then i ask
myself
as honestly and openly as i can like was
that a good thing for the earth
and this area or was that just me
practicing something i thought was good
based on my
you know my cultural brain washing i
guess
so you know it's really important i
think that we
think about things and be really mindful
and and really have
foundational principles of like what are
we trying to achieve
before taking action into the landscape
uh and and implementing our ideas on
upon the land and you know i always
think about
like the farm design shouldn't be
designed by people it should be designed
by the land that it's in
and that people are just simply able to
understand
how the land is working and promote the
healthiest potential of that space
versus
i want straight rows of this and i want
my square block of this it's like nature
doesn't work that way
what we want to pay attention to is is
how does the water move across the
landscape
what harm has been done previously how
can we remediate some of that harm
how can we increase subsurface return
flow to the creeks and gulches how do we
hold the moisture in the landscape and
and that's what we want to be thinking
about as we're doing these thinning
projects because
if we do say disturb the land in a way
where we are going to bury some wood
we want to do that on contour where the
water then infiltrates and with the wood
gets soaked and it doesn't just
stay on the surface and get dry but
rather it turns into a fungal
thing that's all duffy and is isn't a
fire hazard so
i don't burn everything but i also don't
bury everything so it's it's
there's a lot going on there's a lot of
thinking going on too we do spend time
around the fire i am
inside as well and i am enjoying that
flower so
so you know when we've talked about
watersheds before and how the water
moves across your land
um you know you've talked to me about
how you just go in and move a berm
or or move a swale or you're you're
physical
about your relationship with the garden
and
you know so many times i i tour
farms and and and folks
don't want to move they don't want to
move
the growing beds
and and other things on their property
because they feel
attached to where they are and and
your approach is always the
the water flow changes from year to year
on your property
and so during the winter you often
will reorganize the
farm and where where your growing spaces
are
based on the
how nature is presenting itself on your
property
this particular season would you talk a
little bit about
your willingness to kind of
mess with last year's garden and and
remake it
into this year's garden keeping in mind
what nature is telling you it wants
yeah yeah um this is a great
this is a great question and and a great
topic because
you know so much in the the regenerative
realm and and and the the better
practices we talk about
no till and i think sometimes that that
i use that term
a lot in the past um no till and and
and there's a great reason we we glom on
that and why that is so important is
because
undisturbed uh communities that are
allowed to mature
become more mature and and are able to
evolve into a more
resilient system now um
there's there's some there's some parts
of it that are a little off
too as i evolve in my thought processes
about it as a system becomes more mature
and evolved
sometimes disturbance and that doesn't
mean tilling but
i think about uh disturbance can
sometimes
stimulate and and allow the diversity to
recreate itself
and so i basically am looking at all the
things i did wrong
earlier uh in in my time as a
somebody who is claiming to practice
stewardship
um i'm looking at where i didn't uh
say uh form things in the way where the
water was infiltrating at the best
uh and and i go and i i will disturb
that space
um and sometimes even with a machine
but uh only that that takes a lot
it takes a lot for me to feel like i get
behind a machine and start working on a
landscape and thinking i'm doing any
good
oftentimes that's a that's a people make
big mistakes on machines really quick
and that that's hard to recoup but
as you start to get an eye for it and
you start to see where
maybe some of the places where the con
it wasn't fully on contour you can
remediate
by shifting things around and allowing
the water to then become more
uh able to return to the
uh the water table
subsurface versus uh seeing water
draining
off of something or taking you know
we're always trying to create these
uh sinks uh these places where the water
sinks in and and you know understanding
contour
is really important for that and you
know we did everything on our hillside
by hand the first couple seasons
and then after really getting to know
the land a little more
uh i we started to use a machine in
there just to really help stimulate and
promote
that potential um so at this point i i
don't say
you know don't ever disturb anything i
say once your system has become healthy
a little disturbance here and there is
actually a pretty good thing it starts
to
uh it resets some um ecological activity
which which means that you're recreating
some of the things that might not exist
anymore therefore
you're creating that again in a system
that's mature and now the diversity is
even greater
and really we're seeking for that
diversity i want a place where i can
grow
uh i can have an annual crop amongst a
perennial system
so um you know i
yeah i i think you know in the beds this
year
i've taken and doubled some of them up
and made the berms even bigger
uh i know they'll be more productive and
i know i'll be able to sink more water
in the winter so
um any time you do go in and disturb
things there has to be a
you got to understand that when you do
disturb land
you are breaking it down and and
creating it to be more subject to
to erosion and and so anytime you make a
move in that direction you have to be
prepared with
either mulch or cover crop seed the
timing has to be right
you can't work in machines on wet land
you have to be really mindful of how you
go about your disturbance
to minimize the potential negative
impact that you can
that you can certainly have without
meaning to have and i think
a lot of people have a lot of negative
impact
trying to do good things just doing them
out of tune with
how they should they should be done from
an ecological perspective
and um usually that's uh like the whole
nine to five schedule you can't work
on a nine to five schedule and say i'm
gonna block out this week to do machine
work and i'm gonna
you know take this time to do this work
you have to be flexible with
the climate and the cycles of the of the
cosmos
in order to be the most effective
participant in it so
you know i don't i don't i wait for dry
periods um i
i have a short window of work period i
can
actually put a machine on the hill
without really screwing it
up the hill and maybe losing uh track on
the
excavator because of the mud you know so
it's like
you you have to be very mindful how we
operate especially on a bigger scale
um and in our impact and just make sure
that we're doing
all the pre-planning and staging of
materials um
to to heal that space once we do disturb
it because regardless of how mature and
evolved the system is how resilient it
is
um anytime we do make big disturbance in
a space we have to come in with a
a soft finishing touch that allows the
re-establishment of the life that we
want to continue
to to be maximized so um
so yeah right on so before we finish up
um the winter cycle i'm curious if you
are spending any time producing your own
inputs like you know are you are you
fermenting
foliars or or producing any additives
on your um on your property
we're going to talk more about uh manure
in the next set
but i'm talking about specifically like
you know fermentations or
nutrient teas or anything uh korean
natural farming or
you know do you do any of that kind of
stuff during the winter and and how do
you see those playing a role on your
farm well
i don't see them like from
a conventional mindset of what you
you're talking about like they
like i don't practice any of that stuff
but i
see them playing a role in the systems
i've created i
see the fermenting going on but i don't
actively separate
the things that i want fermented so
really all this takes place in the
rhizosphere
and and the mulches that are applied are
the actual uh fermenting and the teas
that
when the rain falls on these mulches
they
create teas the fermenting happens in
the different
microbiology and the different
temperatures of the organic matters that
are accumulated
and so all that is you know
it doesn't make sense from a production
standpoint if you don't have to be
separating things putting them in vats
creating infrastructure for these
practices that
are maybe not fully necessary maybe
there's ways you can go about these
things where it's happening
and you're actually not doing the work
of making it happen so
i like to think about setting up the
foundation of things so that those
processes certainly are occurring
but it's not me that's in control
i like that answer a lot nick it wasn't
the answer that i thought i was going to
get out of you but
i you know you're you're so continually
not hype
that i like the fact that you're like
man i don't i don't need to do all this
fermentation stuff in the off season
because it's all happening in the soil
it costs money whether you look at labor
and time and
and and these kinds of things it costs
money to create those systems
you know we're dealing with a uh if you
really want to make it
in a farming uh business you really have
to have a low overhead and you really
have to be efficient in your production
and so you know do i want to have a
barrel
here and do i want to go gather this and
and put it in here and stir it and you
know it's like uh
you know it's too big of a scale to try
and do that for everything i think
those practices are likely they're they
all i don't believe they don't work
uh i think they're all very functional i
think they're tried and true in a lot of
cases and i i
agree with the foundational principles
of gathering indigenous microorganisms
and
and all and i know about it all but do i
practice
practice it and physicality as a person
in relation nah
you know i just see it happening uh all
around me and i try to
i try to stack my resources into
positions where
i don't have to be in control of those
things
well you know if a lot of those
processes of fermentation are meant to
increase incubate incubate indigenous
microorganisms
essentially everything we have talked
about today is incubating
you know indigenous local microbes it's
just that you
are doing that right there in the soil
instead of
taking them away from the environment
incubating them and bringing them back
there's no question that you are you are
multiplying your local
you know healthy microbes and bacteria
and fungi and all that kind of stuff
just through these processes
um just in a just in a way that's
happening under a thick layer of wood
chip
yeah yeah wood chips leaves uh
whatever's laying around right on that's
a great explanation nick
all right so let's go ahead and take our
second short break and be right back
you are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is regenerative farmer
nicholas mahmoud of green source gardens
sometimes the topics i want to share
with you are far too brief for an entire
shaping fire episode
in those instances i post them to
instagram i invite you to follow my two
instagram profiles and participate
online
the shaping fire instagram has follow-up
posts to shaping fire episodes
growing and processing best practices
product trials and
of course gorgeous flower photos the
shango los instagram follows my travels
on cannabis garden tours
my successes and failures in my own
garden insights and best practices from
personal grows everywhere
and always gorgeous flower photos on
both profiles the emphasis is on sharing
what i've learned in a way that you can
replicate it in your own garden
your own hash lab or for your own
cannabinopathic health
so i encourage you to follow at shaping
fire and
at shango lows and join our online
community on instagram
as a business owner you are incredibly
busy in reality you are responsible for
everything your company does
you've got so many responsibilities
every single day that often you just
don't have the time to really dig into
your marketing as deeply as you'd like
you know there's more that you could do
to reach out to new customers and
encourage loyalty in the customers you
already have
but you certainly don't have the time
for it and you're not ready to hire
somebody full time for that role either
for you i recommend blunt branding at
blunt branding kirsten nelson and her
team are focused on
improving your bottom line you know most
marketing firms are excited to make your
logo
packaging and website very pretty but
they leave responsibility for improving
your bottom line
up to you they don't want that kind of
responsibility
but that's pretty much the most
important part of marketing right
kirsten and her team will help you
engage new customers funnel them to your
point of sale whether it be online or a
storefront and keep them coming back to
you and telling their friends
now if you happen to be a new cannabis
company or an established company moving
from medical to adult use in your state
kirsten especially can help you not only
is she well reversed in marketing and
finance but she totally gets cannabis
whole plant medicine terpenes heritage
farmers and the particular needs of
startups
check out what she did recently for moon
time medicinals and humboldt
at moon time medicinals.com kirsten and
her team put together a whole brand
package for them
built their website and wrote their
sales materials no doubt this is a paid
commercial spot but that does not mean
they bought my opinion
i've worked with blunt branding on five
projects now for various of their
clients and
every single time they have done more
than they have promised and over
delivered on results
i love how they generate new revenue and
focus on that as the goal instead of
just making a pretty logo
similarly every single friend i have
referred them to has come back to thank
me and that just does not happen every
day
grab a pen and paper because the website
address is coming up
if you want someone to implement
marketing programs that feed your bottom
line
give blunt branding a call they will
share proven techniques to increase your
audience and generate sales
while using cutting edge technology
solutions in the background
that make all of this easy automatic and
trackable
go to shapingfire.com forward slash
blunt branding to find out more
you can also click the link in our
newsletter blunt branding
marketing that makes you money
after you've caught up on the latest
shaping fire episodes do you sometimes
wish there was more cannabis education
available to learn
well we got you shaping fire has a
fabulous youtube channel with content
not found on the podcast
when i attend conventions to speak or
moderate panels i always record them and
bring the content home for you to watch
the shango los youtube channel has
world-class speakers including
zoe sigmund's lecture understanding your
endocannabinoid system
kevin jodrey of wonderland nursery
talking about breeding cannabis for the
best terpene profile
frenchy cannolis lost art of the
hashishin presentation
nicholas mahmoud on regenerative and
polyculture cannabis growing
dr sunil agrawal on the history of
cannabis medicine around the world
erik vlosky and josh rutherford on
solvent-less extraction
and jeff lonefels on the soil food web
there are several presentations from dr
ethan russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system too
while there be sure to check out the
three 10-part shaping fire sessions
series
one with kevin jodrey one with dr ethan
russo and one with jeff lowenfels
and even my own presentations on how to
approach finding your dream job in
cannabis
and why we choose cannabis business even
though the risks are so high
as of today there's over 200 videos that
you can check out for free
so go to youtube.com forward slash
shangolos or click on the link in the
newsletter
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host
shango los and our guest this week is
regenerative farmer
nicholas mahmoud of greensource gardens
so here we are we are back at the
springtime it took us
all this good honest effort over the
fall and winter
also that we are in the best position we
can be on
our property for this time when we are
pulling the garden together and and
setting it off for the summer
so nick what are you doing um
as uh you know nature is starting to
wake up and they're starting to be buds
on trees and you're starting to see
like baby animals and all this kind of
stuff early in the year
what are you doing so that your garden
can be in the best way
possible to produce eventual beautiful
flowers
yeah so you know springtime is an
important time
in and again everybody's climate is
going to dictate their practices
and so i really am aiming to work with
the climate
in the best way possible and you know
uh our manures that are in the barn
all winter under uh preventing from
being leeched and being gathered
continually
you know we feed our animals pretty
heavy in the barn space to keep the
manures accessible to us
so that we can have a big pile to source
from
we start putting the manure on the
garden in march
but you know honestly everything we do
on the farm
because there's you know maybe this is a
good time
to explain like how many people are
actually working
uh for with us and it's not that many so
every process that we go down uh my wife
uh my brother has been working uh we've
got one employee jesse
and and uh and then you know the parents
but they don't do
any labor and that's it that's our
that's our focus and so
um you know what we're doing
never happens that quick right so
getting the manure on the field
only starts in march because i can't do
it all at once
and it starts in march and it ends in
june uh it really takes
months of of pushing of gathering the
manure into a truck and then moving it
up to the space and then wheelbarrowing
it out into the
to the space where we want to grow so
now this is a good time
to just explain why we wait
uh because i think a lot of people put a
lot of manure on their yards in the fall
and i and and that again could be a fine
practice in an
area where it freezes hard all winter
and everything gets locked up
and then doesn't even start its process
of breaking down until it
warms up in the in the springtime
but in our climate it rains and it's
wet and it rarely freezes and so
we lose a lot in the winter and that's
that's why the manure is protected all
all winter and we wait till the spring
um
and then and then that manure is also
going to be bacterially dominant in its
breakdown process
and and so we have a fungally
supported network that's really rich in
fungus up on the hillside from the
winter
of of wood chips and now what we do is
we just
where we want the cannabis to grow we
wheel barrel loads of manure
onto the space and that that that
prevents things from growing there so
that we have a clean easy spot to
transplant things into
but it also balances the bacterial
fungal component and
and starts to create a much more
nutrient rich
uh space now uh
again we do this all the way to june and
and
even beyond in some cases depending on
when harvest time you know we're trying
to always aim for
no manure from the barn uh on the space
uh if for within 90 days of a harvest
and that's just good to keep in mind
especially from a commercial perspective
to be adhering to some of the
important components that you could be
uh
dealing with from a problematic place of
of authority saying you did things wrong
which is kind of annoying but
um but yes so so
you know the manure starts to get put on
the field slowly and surely
into the spaces that we want to
transplant into and and that's
prepping that uh perennials are being
divided
in this in the early spring and and so
like
the daisies are gonna get uh broken up
and we're gonna
expand those if we wanna put comfrey
uh into places that are new we'll go
ahead and break up some roots and
and move them around and and uh yeah so
the
the perennial stuff is just mindful
perennial management
um and then the most important thing
spring is the nursery work i mean for us
we depend on a good nursery for
transplanting it's it's easier for
accounting for
tagging we have this legal system that
makes us just belligerently
uh over tag everything and and
essentially bring a bunch of garbage
into the uh garden
but you know hopefully they'll stop
making us use these metric tags i swear
that metric tags are the biggest amount
of garbage i have
on our garden um so hopefully that
is no longer an issue once things are
mellowed out a little bit on
tracking everything because it's kind of
ridiculous uh
but uh the nursery work is really
important and
and you know the we talked about the
composting for the potting soil well
uh we didn't mention that that's turned
about four or five times
in the winter um and and also it's added
to throughout the process so
like after a bunch of the the cannabis
gets trimmed up at the shop all the
stems come back in
and they go into the potting soil again
so there's also
layers of stems that end up in our
potting soil
to kind of rejuvenate the exactly what
the cannabis plant wants
um and so at that at the springtime
in march when we do start our first
round in like the second
quarter moon cycle in march um
what i what i'll do is i'll do a hot
compost
i'll block off one part of the hoop i'll
come in
i'll i'll layer a bunch and get the heat
way up in that compost
i mean i know that it's losing energy to
the atmosphere but
i'm utilizing the compost as a heater
and i put the tables over that compost
and that heat is pretty good for a
couple weeks
um so i know that if i just wait to the
very end before i start popping my seeds
and i heap all this stuff in there and i
get that temperature to like 140 or even
more
i'm i'm make i'm taking advantage of
a naturally breaking down system to heat
uh the space that i'm growing in we do
have some supplemental heat
as in involved as well but we try to
reduce that as much as possible
with this process of creating the heat
in the compost we need it for that march
round
um and again it's a smaller round and i
keep a smaller space heated so it's
easier to heat it's less energy
intensive
but april is really the round for big
amounts of seeds
and uh you know the the nursery
is is is in the hoop house and it's
it's double tented and it has some
supplemental heat
um through through until may
um when the the temperatures are are
easily warm enough to not need that
over uh the nighttime temps uh to
maintain a certain
level so um so yeah they
you know we're planting some rounds
again all the soil that we're sourcing
is right at our feet
uh so the uh filling of pots for
transplanting is all right there
um you know i'm i'm i'm starting things
in flats
so i can start hundreds of seeds in a
a three foot square uh
and then i'm transplanting into four
inch until
they become established and then i'm
transplanting up into two
to three gallon pots uh until they sex
and so that process usually takes a
month and a half to two months
if all the growing conditions are
adequate for
vigorous growth um in that period um
so yeah so you know
nicholas hold on yeah i'm still thinking
about your answer that you you got them
you you you bring them pot up put up put
up and
into these three gallons and then you
put them there
until they show sex so what exactly are
you saying there are you saying that
they're in these three gallons until
um you know the the end of july
um beginning of august when they're
starting to flower show sex or do you
mean that you
are uh you are determining sex
uh in veg or that you are taking clones
and flowering some
somewhere else and then using those as
your canary
of what what sex these particular clones
are gonna be like to
break that out a little bit okay first
of all we'd never
clone so um that eliminates that
potential
um we are sexing
in in general most genetics
especially when started earlier in the
spring
uh will will show a pre-flower at one
and a half months
to two months if grown if the growing
conditions are
are good there are some genetics that
are super stubborn to show their sex and
you know there's an
you can have a good eye for sexing
plants when they're young it takes a
trained eye
it's it i've done it for other people
i've made mistakes
uh i certainly don't get every single
one
dialed perfectly but in general 95
of of what's going down is pre-sexed in
a veg state
uh once it's matured and so
you will see a pre-flower on most
genetics
uh given that circumstance um but again
the march round the earlier stuff you
start we also don't use any light
manipulations of any sort so
you know you can actually start some
genetics
in like say march and they will go into
flower early and then you can hard prune
them
as the daylight is lengthening so you
can guarantee that it's female
it's starting to crown out and wanting
to flower and then you do this an
insane cut back to a couple nodes and it
stunts it for a minute but when it
starts to regrow now the daytime
length is long enough to stimulate the
veg growth so it regrows into more of a
bush-like structure
it's a technique that i wouldn't say you
should do
on everything but it certainly works
well for some plants that are
tend to go in and out of veg and flower
easy
some some genetics just will not will
not come
out of that phase and you'll have a
stunted plants for months and you just
won't
you'll be disappointed if you start
things too early and they flower too
hard early
with that said you know even if i start
things in may and they're in full
veg some genetics just so show that
pre-flower once they're mature
and and and it's a real easy thing to
see
uh when you have an eye for it but you
have to know where to look and you have
to be
having seen it a bunch before the other
thing was starting plants really early
and and again i've done a lot of
research and develop
like r d on this with planting lots of
seeds
at in february in march in april and may
and and and just for everybody's sake of
understanding the best time
april is your best shot april and may
are you're going to have the least
amount of problems if you want to get
into learning a bunch of stuff and
making some mistakes and having some
issues start your plants in february and
march you're going to have a
a big lesson a lot of lessons you'll
learn
in that process but but one of those
things is
is plants will light stress in that
confused state and herm
uh even uh some genetics that even
aren't that prone to herming
when you put them in a a scenario where
they don't they're not sure
where they're supposed to be they stunt
out they're they're stressed and
their root growth isn't happening and
they might herm
um that same plant once it makes itself
into veg
might not hurt at all its whole
lifestyle it might
these are some things that i e i don't
have any
concrete like oh this will happen for
sure this will happen for sure
all i know is sometimes plants will herm
if they're stressed early
and they won't herm as they finish um
oftentimes i just call anything that i
see herming
just because it's not what we want to
stimulate we don't want
more of that to deal with but i'm
telling you some of the best genetics
out there will certainly herm if the if
the
if they're confused in a in between
state
like waking up and then trying to flower
too early
and and then the daylight's getting
longer and they're confused
they go into this stunted yellowing and
everybody thinks it's a nutrient
deficient
thing it's just it's either temperatures
or it's just the light cycles just
not in a zone where it's understanding
what to do so
there's a lot of intricacies within
different genetics that need to be
understood from personal experience but
if you want to bypass all that learning
you just go straight to april and may
start your seeds and generally they'll
just
go right into veg um right on so
i i'm sure that i am not the only one
who heard in all that that you don't do
any cloning on the property and i would
be remiss if i didn't go back to that
because
you know you're clearly a thoughtful guy
and you probably have got some
interesting stuff to say
so we want to hear it nick i don't feel
strongly against
cloning um but i have a goal as a
a farmer or breeder to
essentially evolve the plant as far
along as it can and i don't believe uh
maintaining the same plant for years and
years is evolving that plant
and so i believe in breeding and making
seeds every year in order to evolve the
plant and i think that's just a better
way to go
for advancing the potential um i think
cloning is actually
hindering the potential by just like
getting stuck
on one certain thing and you know on
honestly
a lot of people who are are breeding
with clone
only stuff might not even know how
good of a breeding stock that clone that
is
so what i'm saying there is oftentimes
some of the best clones that you find
are these poly hybrids
that are new crosses of you know
this cross to this times this cross to
this
makes a wide selection of some pretty
cool genetics to hunt from you get this
one
killer one that has the traits that you
want from all of them
and and now it's this cut only thing and
then people are seeking that
clone to breed with because they think
it's the best but the truth is
by breeding to that clone you're
actually
going into some really unstable stock
and you're you're actually taking
your potential and you're you're
diffusing it amongst a bunch of
different potential
and it gives you another poly hybrid
like situation
where you have to sort through and where
maybe only one of the
100 plants that you see are the ones
you're looking for
and versus
continually breeding filial generations
until the
stock is predictable and then utilizing
that
as breeding stock i think there's a lot
of
people do a lot of back crossing in
cannabis and and they generally are
holding on to some mother and then
they're
running a generation and they're picking
the best and they're breeding it back to
that mother and then they're doing it
again and bringing it back to that
mother and so you get the back cross one
back cross two back crusty
but if that mother is not
good breeding stock which oftentimes
it's not because people just don't
work their generations very far you're
actually breeding
back to an unstable breeding stock and
now you're just
continually taking your line and
diminishing its potential
is how i see it versus taking say
something that's at like
f10 and now using that stock
if you're gonna be holding on to
something in clonal
form and and you hold that to do the
back crossing too
now i take it a step further i don't do
any back crossing to mother plants i
just do
back crossing to the same parental line
one generation further so you know if i
if i put out something that i say is a
back cross
um what i'm saying is this is not back
crossed to the one plant that i
kept over winter i'm saying i'm crossing
it
back to the parental stock that came
from that stock
and i'm only doing that i'm only trying
to back cross
back to really things that are
predictable so i
have some kind of idea of what's going
to come out in the following
generation um so these are some things i
feel like maybe have been overlooked in
the cannabis worlds where people just
are like trying to do these cool back
crosses but the truth is
you keep getting these back crosses that
are expressing
so much diversity you're like well i
thought that was supposed to be
narrowing that
and and i think that the biggest mistake
is you know we're back crossing to poly
hybrids versus back crossing to
work lines um so that's just a little
tangent on that and as far as clones go
again like my main reason for not
cloning is just to strengthen the plant
uh and and and i i grow
from seed for the commercial market so
it's in my best
interest to create seed that is
going to be predictable so that i can
put a a row of one variety in
and know that all that's going to come
down at a
relatively the same time so i don't have
to stagger the harvest like
oh this plant's ready but the plant next
to it needs another two weeks but
the other one you know it's like you're
trying to
gain predictability in breeding so that
when you run
things from seed you have an idea of
what the outcome's going to be
and you can apply the different
varieties to the different situations
now that being said uh if
if you're out hunting for the
potentially the
you know your some new thing you're
going to want to buy some poly hybrids
with the genetic stock
in the background of the things you like
and then you can hunt that out
now if you really want that to be a
stable breeding stock now you have to
breed
and make selections over the next four
or five generations to really
hone and and and isolate the
certain characteristics that you're
interested in
so that when you do breed with that
stock you know that
say this flower is going to be purple or
that the trichome
the exaggerated trichome development is
going to be maintained within this line
because
the parental stock had been selected for
that for
you know five generations and at this
point ninety percent is showing you
exactly what you want to see
uh that's good breeding stock but the
old uh
you know docido cross og cross sfv
cross uh gelato mix
combination that's a great phenohunt but
that is not breeding stock
right on so let's let's go a little
further down this path man because
um i never really thought about this
quite in this way you know
so many of the commercial uh cultivators
they are you know they're buying seeds
for the season around now
they're popping them they're making some
choices
they're they're sexing and then they're
they're making clones
and mass so that they will be
you know ready when it's time to go
outside and
the first place that i found that
actually just grew everything from seed
and then made all their own seeds
every year were the dragonfly folks up
in canada
kelly and josh and and when you know the
first time i was sitting down with them
in a tent and they were explaining that
to me i'm like oh my god
that is i mean a it's badass for
self-sufficiency right i really like
that part of it
and when you get to the point as you
have described where yeah you're making
your own seeds but your
own seeds are of such an advanced um
f generation that they
[Music]
they don't have as many irregularities
you can you can plant 10 of them and you
can know
what the 10 are going to be you know
pretty much looking like so that they
can all be in the same
bag for sale and that they'll be ready
to harvest at the same time
and so hearing you describe it i'm like
my mind is blown again
thinking about the additional thought
and effort it takes
to make all of your own seeds for the
season
so um you've just given us a really
great you know august to
the spring snapshot of what you're doing
for the good of
the property and the microbes and the
watershed
uh holistically for the farm will you
give us a little
little conversation about you
integrating a seed making process
because
you know we don't have to talk about the
basics of making seeds we've talked
about that here
um a lot and and you know most farms are
at least making a little seed to
to experiment and and maybe come up with
a
a house cultivar you know that they can
they can sell
but when you're doing it at in mass
like you are and you're relying on it
for the next season
how does that integrate on your calendar
what are you doing on the calendar to
make sure that you have
seeds for yourself uh yeah this is a
great question
and and there's a lot to illuminate in
this realm there's a lot that we're all
still learning
uh in terms of like how to do this
really well um
i'm i'm i'm beginning to understand it
more
as i do it more and more and and that
makes my
my uh seed creation better and better
every year because i'm
i'm carrying with me last season's
learnings
and every season compounds on every
season
um and so you know some of them really
important things that people need to
understand
um and and i like to be really
vulnerable and let people know where my
weaknesses are
in the process of making seeds you learn
a lot about pollen
and and there is a certain amount of
like pollen contamination that occurs
uh and and i'm certainly guilty of of
you know having some unexpected pollen
hit a place that i don't really want it
to
and and seeing that maybe in the next
generation
as i as i start looking at the plants
growing however
there are ways to and and this is these
are the important learnings uh to
maximize your ability
to manage a lot of different pollens in
a relatively small
area and still come out with
mostly uh you know 95 percent
i don't know statistics really that's
just my guess based on what i'm seeing
um that it's all gonna come out like you
want it to
um and really these these tricks are
about
how to prevent yourself it's mostly
me that is the pollen contaminator i'm
the one collecting the pollen
and i do that separate from the garden
and it's generally inside in my house
just up against the windows
and and there's up maybe too many plants
in one room to be really a scientific
lab
type scenario where i can guarantee 100
all this and that
but i'm also like in a position where i
want to manage a bunch of different
lines
to advance those lines to become
breeding stocks so it's important for me
to be managing males of each variety and
many
um and and what that leads to is an
understanding of how to
prevent yourself from being a pollen
contaminator
in the field so when i go from that room
of collecting pollen
which is happening basically from june
until august um
i'm i'm managing males and and and and
dealing with pollen
i go directly from my gathering pollen
in the early morning
with some coffee and and and to the
field and working
and and that's where i i'm a hairy guy
and
and and you know i sniff all the buds
all the time and that's you know
usually there's a seed on the very top
of the bud because my nose was there and
i was you know so it's like
um but spraying yourself down with a wa
a water bottle a water a spray bottle is
a breeder's best friend
and and and and then making your seeds
in concentrated spots where you know the
pollen that you collected
is on the branch of that variety and
that likely
all of those seeds are going to be that
you might not know what little seed is
on every plant that's drifted and say
there's a couple seeds in a bud here and
there
you can't track that but at least you
can track that one branch and so i do a
lot of single branch pollinating
uh i use paper bags to collect the
pollen i freeze the pollen sometimes
when it's early
and in letting the pollen go before the
flower is ready to be
pollinated and i'm making selections all
over the field but i'm also
concentrating
certain seed production within a hoop to
prevent uh
more pollen contamination and then the
hoop just has a layer of plastic that
that gives me a little more ability to
not
end up uh you know you're paying
attention to wind
you're never pollinating in wind if
you've got at least a barrier between
you and the other plants is less
likelihood
you've got a spray bottle you're
spraying down the area that you just
pollinated
and you're you're doing everything you
can to minimize pollen drift
again i know breeders that are on the
coast where it's so humid they don't
even have to worry about
pollen drift as much so the climate is
going to dictate that and dry
dry climates and that's we're in dry
climate in the fall
or summer and fall is is where pollen
contamination can really be
running rampant and that's where the
water bottle and the
after you collect pollen you you spray
yourself down
uh everywhere the the water will uh
prevent the pollen from one getting
airborne but two it also kills the
pollen
uh eventually if it you know it doesn't
kill it if you already
pollinated the branch you can spray it
and it'll still pollinate because you've
already got it on there
but um something to be really mindful of
there's a whole bunch of stuff i could
go into depth about
when you want to pollinate to get the
best seed production
not waiting too long but trying to find
that sweet spot
i do all my selections on outdoor plants
so oftentimes i end up breeding towards
earlier finishing stuff even within
different lines
so i could take a line that may be
finished in mid october but by the time
i'm four generations down i've done the
sift i've chosen to pollinate the ones
that have shown resin
earlier and now it's finishing two weeks
earlier so
you know there's a whole bunch of stuff
going on in the breeding realm that's
like worthy of exploring
with all the different breeders and
sharing the information because really
what we want to do is not like hold on
to this stuff as like some proprietary
[__] that gives is going to make us
a bunch of money in the future but the
only thing that's really going to
create health and wellness for everybody
in the future
is shared information so that we can all
be doing a better job of what we're
trying to do
and that way we can all be more
successful um
so i don't i don't ever worry about like
you know uh
do i save this information that i want
to tell you
uh for some consulting gig i'm gonna
tell you the same stuff on this
podcast that i would if you wanted to
pay me for it you know it's like
um i don't have that uh entrepreneurial
drive to just like
find the gem that i can just bank a
bunch of money off of because i really
do believe that real capital
is found in the land and in our
practices
and in the health of the ecology and so
by sharing and
and giving the information freely it's
almost like puts the burden on everybody
else to continue to do the same thing
and to stop this process of
i want to get rich off of what i know
um and and think that you know i'm gonna
uh you know just kind of capitalize on
other people's uh inability to do things
you know it's kind of
so so yeah there's a lot there's a lot
in the breeding realm that we all need
to be
uh paying attention to but really
practice is is gonna be the
the most important thing um right a lot
of people
that aren't practicing as much as they
maybe should be
i've got a very specific follow-up
question so we have been talking about
how
um the the the thriving nature of your
plants and the abundance of the flowers
is primarily based in the fact that they
are participating in a complex
organism that is your property
um that is you know incubated with
indigenous microbes
has got you know an abundance of local
varied nutrients a lot of it wild
crafted
a lot of it from your animals so that
you know you've created this matrix
of life support and because of that
your flowers um do so well
how does that play into the seed
creation
because you know we we could go down
this path
and just turning you know turn this
whole last set into a breeding set but
that's not really the goal since we want
to focus more on
on you know this the seasonal impacts on
your property
and how to you know work with that
regeneratively
what kind of hints might you have to
offer us about
um making seeds on
a farm that is using regenerative
practices maybe you can
you know give us two or three of those
yeah so
making seeds you know
you can make here's the thing you know
if you have a space that
actually is that uh life support
uh super resilient uh really diverse
you can take what people consider to be
the worst pot
and grow it and and get something very
good you know something way better than
what
it was when you saw it last um
so there's something to be said for just
the the really healthy rhizosphere
and and heavy mulch buffers the soil
rhizosphere to a degree that makes
things possible that you wouldn't see
elsewhere
um therefore uh
i believe all cannabis is really good
because
i see it expressing itself in a really
healthy environment
and therefore what somebody might assess
and say is just low quality weed
might actually be high quality weed
given the right circumstance
in making seeds in this environment
it's like any other environment truly is
about selections and so the more plants
you have
to select from the the better selection
process you can have the better the sift
um you might it might be called breeders
use the term
sifting through genetics uh and and so
you know really um the biggest
i think the biggest mistake that gets
made and
i've made is is like i just think i know
which one is the best
and i just put put everything on that
and then to come find out at the end of
the season it molded
uh or molds um that's a reality
that's why you can't just only pick the
ones you think are the best i say if
you're making seed
go ahead and make seed on a lot of the
different plants that you have
again not the whole plant and and this
is where the
the details are important but um just on
a branch
just because you don't know how it's
going to finish until it finishes
and so i like to think i can make
all the best selections that's me doing
the work but the truth is
i need to stop giving myself so much
credit
i need to be looking at the plants and
and saying they're all super valuable
i can't make predictions uh before the
end result so i just need to make sure
i'm i'm getting some pollen on all of
them
so that when oh man the one that i
thought
was wasn't the best turned out to be the
best because
you cannot pollinate the plant when it's
done
you know what i'm saying so um
you can't make you you can make your
predictions but they're just predictions
they're not set in stone science you
didn't see it finished so you don't know
so you just i've just learned you've got
to like
you can't just think you know you have
to be really humble in the process
and and just just stay open to the fact
that
you know you have an ego and your ego
oftentimes wants you to believe
you have some kind of valuable
information
more so than other people but the truth
is that's not the case
and really the more broader spectrum
practices you can have
the more likely you'll realize
that you did something that preserved
what it is that you really wanted
um because we don't always know let's
let's hit that another time nick because
like you're talking about the the ego
part of this
and i gotta tell you you know listening
to some
of the
i don't say this negatively but i'm
going to use the word loose listening to
some of the more
loose breeding practices that you've
talked about you know you're like hey
man i
i'm the one who accidentally lets you
know pollen go on my shirt or on my nose
or whatever or
or you're collecting pollen together in
your living room and stuff it's like
like for for people who are coming
to cannabis from a real control place
right a real ego control place
um that sounds like oh my god
that's such poor manufacturing god knows
what's going to come out the other end
right
but but i know what comes out the other
end of your farm right i have
i have enjoyed your flowers i've seen
lots of different flowers at different
times a year
i've toured your property i've grown
your genetics
i know a lot of people who have you know
flocked to your genetics and they rely
on them so
we know that what comes out is pleasing
people
and doing their job and being used
reliably on other people's farms in the
form of seeds
but also it's coming from this
environment that you're working in that
i would not
call um it is
it's like invitations to nature
versus control and i know that that's
pretty much how you live your life
and i can't be the only one hearing you
talk who's having this kind of like
internal being torn both directions
where it's like oh my god his
his work all sounds so holistic i want
to smoke that flower and i want to grow
those seeds
and at the same time i've got the part
of me and going like oh my gosh those
seeds
are not all going to be exactly the same
speak a little bit to just how you
resolve that for yourself
well i i say you know you try out seeds
and
you know it's like uh i'm
i've tried a lot of seeds and so you
know i've seen
what's coming down the lines of all
these other
uh breeders and and and stuff and i love
it all
and i thank everybody for making seeds
um
but once you start getting further down
the filial generation and this
i can only say it comes from experience
like
again i like to give myself the let
people know the vulnerabilities in the
in the places where maybe i'm not
as controlled as people want um but
the proof is in the pudding and i'm
cracking seeds
and i'm reliably getting what i say
is coming from the parental lineage i
can tell
and and again this is about getting
better at it
you know like i'm way better at it now
than i was four years ago
and so uh by staying open and continuing
the process
and watching the seeds grow you can
start to really
dictate whether your practices are
functioning the way that you want them
to
and you know and giving the power
over to nature into those natural
processes is
always going to strengthen your your
stay your stock
and um and and i i would say just like
you can buy or you can acquire seeds
uh for from a bunch of different people
and just grow them out and just
ask yourself what looks similar what
doesn't um
you know truly if you cross something
that's dank to something that's dank
you're gonna get dank
and it might not all be the same dank
but it's dank
you know so it's like that's where i
started when i began the process but
now i'm like oh f1 stock is
so good when you're working with
breeding stock on both parental lines
that it's worth making
sure that you continue the filial
generations on the lines with the traits
that you're looking for
so you can make those f1s later
for people who are in production because
really the f1 stock
is for commercial production this is
where
we have like if you're a commercial
producer and you want to grow things
from seed
you you want to be looking for that f1
stock that is
real f1 stock that means both parental
lines
have been worked for years and years and
are coming out at least predictable and
then when they mesh together
they actually come out really uniform
with some traits from both sides
and the hybrid vigor the hetero
heterozygosity is way higher so you're
getting yields you're getting
terpene results that are way more
complex
it really is where the best weed is
going to come out of is these
uh f1 crosses and you know when you're
working
lines down generations and generations
you might actually even see the overall
return
like become less and maybe the
percentages even become less but that
doesn't mean
it's going to make something that's not
good that
that's the piece that's kind of
confusing is as i take some things into
the f6
generation they're testing lower than
they ever have but their offspring
are combining so well with the others
that it shoots the
numbers up in all the categories so you
know it's it's
it's a game that that we're all playing
and
and everybody gets so uh demoralized
when their test result maybe comes back
lower than they want but hey
if you understand that those test
results can come back lower and you
don't have to grow that one for
commercial production
but if you use that one in making a
cross with another
one that is inbred and maybe doing the
same thing
the result doesn't mean a low percentage
in that case it
i'm finding low percentage inbred lines
combined together make the highest
percentage outcome
um which is you know i look at a lot of
coas and i'm
you know because i have to get tests for
every lot that goes into the market and
all this stuff i'm getting a good idea
of the overall
background genetics and each lineage and
and i'm able to kind of run with that
and then look at like when i take a
terpenoline variety
and i put it on the mirror scene variety
do i see both terpenoline and mirosine
or do i see one just kind of eat out the
other
and the case is is when there
those lines are inbred i'm seeing
both of the parental uh terpene profiles
combining into the offspring i'm seeing
the
thc levels increase and on the offspring
10 higher than either parent uh so
you know there's a lot of things that
i'm just not willing to say we know
yet uh because i i just need to continue
down the process of r d
growing these seeds every year making my
selections
growing those seeds looking at the tests
you know it's it's and there's there's
flaws in everybody's breeding program
and it's important for us to recognize
the flaws so that we can work on them
and that's really where we gain strength
is when we see our weaknesses
we work on those weaknesses we see our
strengths and we understand our
strengths and we
we move forward uh with that holistic
kind of approach of like knowing we have
more
more to learn and that we're not just
all the best breeders in the world um
i want to finish with this today nick so
i've been to your property
and a lot of your examples
you're able to do on your property
because you've been doing this year over
year for a lot of years you've put a lot
of labor and love
and calendar into your property
and a lot of folks who are listening
today um you know
either either maybe they've got a new
farm or they're converting their farm
from from traditional agriculture you
know traditional industrial era
agriculture
practices to becoming more regenerative
or maybe you know
it's a farm that's trying to convert
themselves right to get you know a
quality
um you know regenerative certification
like the
the dread the you know the dem pure
certification or something like that so
you've got a lot of people who
who have got an ideal that they share
with you
but they they're at the beginning of the
game whereas you know
you're you're you know many years
into this game um what words
of reassurance do you have for
folks that um that they should go along
this path
even though the the labor and the amount
of time that it's going to take to get
there
seems so long when you're when you're
when you're teaching
you know you don't really teach as much
growing cannabis right you teach
biological systems and that takes some
time
so so so we'll finish off here by i'll
give you the mic and i'll say what what
message do you have for these folks
who are at the beginning of this path oh
man
um well
first and foremost you have to love this
plant like
i've been obsessed a little bit with
cannabis ever since i
started integrating my experiences in
nature
with being affected by this
cannabis plant so you know most of the
people
that are trying to go down this route if
they're
if they're into it for the money i can
say you're gonna fail
if you're into it because your passion
is there i say
don't get too caught up in uh
uh you know trying to make
a ton of money off of it just get stay
focused on the passionate piece
but also like if you're into breeding
if if somebody would have told me uh
hey like just even even six years ago uh
just hey you're gonna want to pay
attention to
keeping your lines as pure as you can so
it doesn't matter if you get a poly
hybrid to start with but just
keep working those filial generations
until you see something
uh coming out uh more uniform that's
kind of the most
important work and especially from an
outdoor i grow one
crop a year i don't do indoor i'm not
running multiple seasons through the
year and advancing populations very
quickly
um i i want to see the f10 generation
but i've got to wait four more years you
know so like
if you if you're starting and you really
are passionate and you really want to be
developing something that
is is is something you've really helped
steward and shepherd
and and can be feeling really good about
is that you start
the process of of gathering what you
want and
keeping those lines in those lines for a
while before you start mixing them
because what inevitably happens and this
is speaking to breeders
again like if it's it's all it's all
different based on your goals and
outcomes but i'm really like
weighed towards breeders because i'm
really passionate about it
um is that it it's it's like don't get
too wrapped up in like
making a like crossing everything
because there's something so dank over
here and there's something so dank over
here that you just
know that those are the two best and if
you put those two
together and the male pollen you only
have one male that you've selected for
all of your crosses it's like
that's just narrowing your potential and
potentially taking you down a path you
don't want to be
keep your lines going in their own
directions
before you start crossing them and if
you can acquire some
inbred lines that's the way you want to
go you want to buy
inbred lines something that somebody's
worked for a while you could take it and
continue the work
in a different direction within that
line because there's always a spectrum
of what's going to express
uh within a certain line of cannabis we
don't hone every single trait we might
hone a couple of traits that we know are
going to pass on
but in the long run there's all kinds of
there's flower morphology there's plant
structure
there's leaf type there's all these
different traits that you know might get
bypassed
and and look to for only the resin and
flower
um and so there's always a little bit of
a
there's always a spectrum to choose from
even from a work line
but to keep those lines continually
worked and then
start crossing those lines later and
you'll have a much better result
is my belief and i wish somebody had
told me that
you know a long time ago i just had to
like realize that in my journey
of just studying really it's been about
studying uh crops outside of cannabis
um and how breeding occurs in those
crops and then
taking some of those uh scientific
learnings from the world of agriculture
and applying them to the cannabis it's
really it's just a plant as a plant it's
they're all different but some of the
breeding practices can certainly
um result in similar
end results like if you want to grow for
outdoor production you do want real
f1 stock you don't really want to be
hitting the ibl's on that
so i'm going to ask you the same
question but with a different emphasis
right
okay so so you know you won regenerative
gardening awards and
you've you know a lot of people look up
to you and how the you have developed
this property
and for people who may not be breeders
but they're on a new property right they
don't they don't have any hugel cultures
they're just building their first
berms they're trying to figure out
what's in the forest around them
and it all seems like so much right
because
it is it can be so much um
what what words of inspiration do you
have for people who may not be breeders
heck they might not even be
growing cannabis right this is you know
the kind of show we've had today
we haven't actually used the word
cannabis all that much it works for
cannabis but it's also going to work for
for food crops as well and so so
what what kind of like final parting
shots or
or inspiration do you have for folks who
are looking to grow
in their biological system and they're
feeling like oh my god this is going to
take the rest of my life
that's a great question um and and i i
really like to
address this one in in this way that
again it it's probably not what people
are expecting me to say
um but the truth is is if you're gonna
connect with your landscape you have to
take
time to connect with it and so stop
all the research and looking for the
answers online
and looking for the answers through
people like me and looking for answers
from anything but
your land and start the process of of
slowing down and and taking time to
spend
in the spaces that you want to cultivate
and asking the land
uh you know it's not like you go out
there and physically
make a loud noise that is asking a
question but you go out there and you
listen and you observe
and and you pay attention you take time
it's not even like oh land what can i do
to grow you know really awesome things
it's more like what is this land
what is what are we and and meditate
on some of the deeper things so that you
could start to pierce
the veils that have been put in front of
our our
realities and start to really
hone in on this idea of humans
are here and can have really
healthy positive impact on landscape
what is healthy what is
uh what is gonna really make this place
thrive and and so it's really a deeper
internal
uh uh deprogramming
and and and and smoke weed when you do
it
i i guarantee if you you know
utilize cannabis in in the natural
setting
with the right intentions um it really
helps guide you
into the aha moments that are much less
likely
to come across uh watching a youtube
video
on some regenerative farms you know it's
like
um spend your time in nature if you want
to connect with nature
and be a voice for nature you have to
live there
to to to have that understanding
otherwise
you're just trying to find the answer
and and the answers are not concrete
um they are way more philosophical than
we want them to be
this is not a measure your input and
and if you put this down it will work
it's more like
you have to do the work with the with
the world you want to live in
and and it doesn't always look like the
work you want to do but
oftentimes it starts from your within
and it starts
with how you interpret what you see and
so if you're already down the path and
you really want to do good
you really have to start exploring well
what do i think
is doing good and how is that maybe not
so good and what are the cultural
uh problems with this
you know colonial uh consumer capitalist
society that
is all about uh killing life
and and monoculture creating
monocultures
um we have to understand we've been
super
super affected by that culture and we're
still in that culture
and our thought processes are are kind
of geared towards that culture so
when we start getting into the periphery
zone of
of making advancements into the
potential of
our ability to steward land it starts to
look like we're anti
the culture and in some ways it feels
like a path that is very
outside the norm and very feels like
everybody is just uh
on a journey that's just destroying the
planet and we really
you know we really have to connect with
nature again in order to
actually realize how we can help uh the
process of nature
and even understand what a healthy
ecology is
so when we were preparing for this show
nick
you said this one thing that struck me
and i put it in my notes
you told me you don't grow good cannabis
by focusing on the cannabis you grow
good cannabis by being a good
steward of all the biological systems
surrounding the cannabis
and i think that's a recurring theme
that goes throughout this show
is that you know if you're taking care
of the entire living matrix
around your garden that that can only
benefit your plants and it's probably
going to benefit them
more than the rest of the crap you're
doing exactly and it's going to benefit
everybody and every thing on the planet
at this stage you know any kind of work
we can do
towards taking care of our ecology
is work that is worth doing at this
point
right on well nick thank you so much for
taking the time to be with us
especially at this early morning time
we're on farmer's hours today
and uh so thank you for taking time away
from the garden and your family for this
and thank you for sharing your vast
experience
and and most of our thanks for sharing
your heart you know there's a there's a
lot of people who can to talk about
these same topics
in a pretty dry functional way but um
but you know your your passion and
compassion for nature uh really comes
through and i i appreciate that in you
well i appreciate that and i just want
to give a special
shout out to my wonderful family and my
little boy
and my wife for all the support um
because
truly this isn't this wouldn't be what
it is
uh without them and my whole world has
shifted in this last year with this new
little one and
and you know my my desire to
continue the process of caring for the
ecology is strengthened even more by
having
um a little one and so um yeah
uh just big love to the whole family my
brother my parents
uh my wife especially um
so yeah fantastic right on so if you
haven't enjoyed this conversation and
you want to know more about green source
gardens here's the places to do it first
of all you really do want to follow
their instagram
at green source gardens
it's filled with delightful photos and a
bunch of technique stuff
and you really want to go for no other
reason is you want to see pictures of
the pinkleberry
the pinkleberry is a cultivar that comes
from green source
which um it's just a delight to check
out it's really great to smoke too but
the pictures are astonishing so make
sure you go check out
them on instagram at green source
gardens
you can also check out their website at
greensourcegardens.org
there's some info good information there
especially if you know you're in the
oregon commercial realm and you might
want to reach out to them
to carry green source gardens products
in your store
but then also on the green
greensourcegardens.org website you can
also
find the green source gardens seasonal
podcast
from the farm it comes about you know
let's say you know quarterly-ish
seasonally-ish
but there's a lot of down-home
information it's just
an enjoyable listen so you can find that
as well
on the website greensourcegardens.org
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show
at shapingfire.com and wherever you get
your podcasts
if you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download
your review will help others find the
show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for insights
into the latest cannabis news exclusive
videos and giveaways
on the shaping fire website you also
find transcripts of today's podcast as
well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast
that's at shaping fire and at shangolos
on instagram
be sure to check out shapingfire youtube
channel for exclusive interviews farm
tours and cannabis lectures
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts
email hotspot at shippingfire.com to
find out how
thanks for listening to shaping fire
i've been your host shango los
you