[Music]
to the extent that the Cannabis industry
has rock stars Dr Ethan Russo is one of
them his groundbreaking research on
cannabis tpin the Entourage effect endoc
canabo deficiency and phyto canabo in
general are all essential reading for
anyone looking to really understand the
interaction between the cannabis plant
and humans I remember the first time I
invited Dr Russo to speak here on Vashon
Island we had 75 Chairs set up like we
normally would for a Vash on island
marijuana entrepreneurs Alliance meeting
and those chairs filled up really
quickly then we used the rest of the
chairs that were in the closet and when
we were out of chairs folks sat on
pillows and jackets on the floor in
front of the chairs and finally it was
standing room only in the back that
night it was like an old school teaching
everybody was excited to have an
opportunity to hear Dr Russo speak in
person and have their questions answered
see for years it has been nearly
impossible for regular people to hear Dr
Russo speak because he worked at GW
Pharmaceuticals and pretty much only
spoke at high-priced exclusive
pharmaceutical conventions I remember
very clearly the day I received an email
from Ethan saying that he was no longer
at GW and he was now free to accept my
speaking invitation for a simple Log
Cabin gra Hall on Bashon Island he
sounded very excited because you know
Ethan really isn't an ivory Tower kind
of researcher he's more interested in
speaking directly to patients and
working in the field like he had done
previously in Morocco China and Peru Dr
Russo's research paper titled taming THC
potential cannabis Synergy and phyto
canabo turpenoid Entourage effects has
become a Cornerstone of cannabis
medicine for many folks myself included
it was the first time we had read a
detailed paper explaining the interplay
of different phyto canabo in a
conversational tone that anyone could
understand you can find a link to the
paper on our website you are listening
to the shaping fire podcast and I am
your host Shango Los on today's episode
we will go Point by Point through the
entire text of Dr Russo's taming THC
paper and enjoy some rare commentary
from Dr Russo himself if you would like
to hear more candidate interviews with
the cidis industry's top professionals
subscribe to the shaping fire newsletter
to receive new episode announcements we
find that relying on social media to
connect with you continues to get less
and less reliable so I encourage you to
sign up for the newsletter at shaping
fl.com Dr Ethan Russo is a board
certified neurologist and former senior
medical adviser to GW pharmaceutic ials
he served as study physician to GW
Pharmaceuticals for three phase 3
clinical trials of satx he graduated
from the University of Pennsylvania and
the University of Massachusetts medical
school before residencies in Pediatrics
in Phoenix Arizona and in child and
adult neurology at the University of
Washington in Seattle he was a clinical
neurologist in Missoula Montana for 20
years in a practice with a strong
chronic pain component in 1995 he
pursued a 3-month sabatical doing
ethnobotanical research with indigenous
people in Peru he joined GW as a
full-time consultant in 2003 he has held
faculty appointments in pharmaceutical
Sciences at the University of Montana in
medicine at the University of Washington
and as visiting professor at the Chinese
Academy of Sciences he has been
president of the international cannaboid
research society and is former chairman
of the International Association for
cannaboid medicines he is author of
several books on Canabis medicine and
has published over 30 articles in
neurology pain management cannabis and
ethnobotany welcome to the show Ethan
well thank you so much for having me I'm
really glad that you were willing to
make the time to to join us so so let's
start with something pretty basic so we
know that phyto canabo exist and there
must be a reason that they exist in
nature so you know what natural benefit
do phyto canabo offer to the plant that
that makes them exist in the first
place well uh straight out of the shoot
it's important to relate that they're
not there for uh human enjoyment the
plant itself is much older uh than
humans are as a species so yes you're
right they perform an ecological role in
the plant and actually it's more than
one um one of the things is that the
canabo uh protect the plant from genetic
damage from ultraviolet light
exposure uh one of the things we know is
that production of the canabo will be
increased with higher light pressure and
at a higher elevation uh so those two
things go together another interesting
role of the canabo is that uh some of
them are
insecticidal uh so if a bug lands on the
flower there are two ways in which the
bug can meet its demise one is from a
chemical attack by the the cannabinoids
and the other is just the stickiness of
the tricomes will trap them uh finally
the uh cannabinoids also are helpful in
pruning the plant as it's trying to
mature and become fertilized these will
rain down on the fan leaves and uh they
will tend to die so what the plant is
doing near the end of its year of growth
is putting all the uh effort um
chemically speaking into getting
fertilized and Nur nurturing that flow
and the hopes that it will become
fertilized but that's usually thwarted
by humans that want it to remain
unfertilized to get the greater
cannabinoid
production that's interesting to me
hearing you describe it almost as a as a
defense mechanism and as a plant
regulator because you know in our own
endoc canabo system that's the same
thing that phyto canabo do for us you
know a defense and regulation of our
systems um there must be some similarity
at at a nature level where where these
these chemicals are are helping living
things well that's exactly right there's
a increasing appreciation now uh that
these plant defense compounds also uh
extend uh towards effects on humans too
um there's a very interesting book by
Kennedy called plants in the human brain
that goes into these uh relationships in
in Greater depth but that that's it uh
some of these antioxidants that the
plant produces to prevent diseases have
the same kind of protective functions in
humans and uh this is the reason that a
highly varied plant diet uh seems to
help prevent aging help prevent cancer
and things of this
sort right on that's very interesting so
so today instead of talking about
necessarily about defending the plant
we're going to be talking about uh these
different phyto canabo effects on on our
humans and you know there's one um
there's a well there's a bunch of terms
that could be unfamiliar to folks that
we're going to run into today but but
one of them um that I ran into from
rereading the paper now because I
haven't read it in a couple years but um
before we get into the meat of the topic
I'd really appreciate if you would
explain the difference for folks be uh
the difference between an Agonist and an
antagonist because I feel we'll probably
using that quite a bit right well well
we have receptors on our cells uh
probably the place that's most familiar
to people would be in
neurotransmission and other words how
nerve cells communicate one to another
and it is a combination of chemical and
electrical transmission but receptors on
cells are things that help affect a
certain kind of reaction so we can think
of it as a lock and key model in fact
it's a lot more complicated than that
but an Agonist will be like a key uh
that fits in the lock and produces a
stimulation of a certain function an
antagonist goes in the opposite
direction it lowers the function um and
then we've got modifiers beyond that um
there are things called inverse Agonist
which despite the way it sounds uh
actually lower the overall activity so
they're like a super
antagonist uh but we'll we'll explain
these in context as they come up right
on so to to Really simplify it an
Agonist is more likely to increase the
effect and an antagonist is more likely
to decrease the effect that's quite
right great um uh another uh aspect that
you mentioned in the paper a few times
that I'd love to hear broken out before
we get into it is uh um Rafael mulan's
law of stinginess which I love the name
but um I had not heard that referred to
before so if you kind of explain that uh
example before we get into it sure what
he means is uh enzymes which are
Catalyst that uh help bring uh
reaction uh uh onward um may act on more
than one substrate a subst substrate is
a chemical that is turning into another
chemical um so for example uh there are
uh there are two basic kinds of
cannabinoids the propy with a five
carbon side chain I'm sorry propy with a
three carbon side chain and the Pentel
with a five carbon side chain um but
certain enzymes can work on both uh
there are other enzymes that aren't
following the law of stinginess that may
only work on one
compound so right on so so we're going
to jump into the first uh wave of
cannabinoids and and as I was telling
folks in the introduction you know we're
kind of going to go through them as a
list the way that you do in the paper uh
in in a couple of groups the first one
being uh the you know THC CBD and and
the ones that we're more uh familiar
with and then we'll move on to the tpin
then we'll talk about their applications
so I know that I know that we could do
an entire show just on THC but it is the
first uh canono that you go ahead and
explain so let's let's start there with
with the big elephant in the room so uh
if you would kind of review THC and how
relates to phyto canabo activity sure
well TC is probably the single chemical
most associated with cannabis and it is
the primary psychoactive ingredient in
other words um the uh compound that
makes people high uh but it has uh a lot
of very important medical effects uh as
an analgesic meaning a painkiller it's
an
anti-spasmodic it uh prevents spasms uh
it lowers muscle tones tone it is a
muscle relaxant That's the basis for its
use and treating
spasticity um muscle tone tightness that
occurs in multiple sclerosis and a
variety of other brain
diseases uh and that uh that benefit uh
has made uh satx which does contain THC
and approved drug in 27 countries just
not here in the
ask when I'm talking to patients one of
the examples that I give for how THC
actually decreases pain is I said you
know there's kind of uh there's two
paths to it uh the first path is um it's
uh you know
anti-inflammatory muscle relaxation and
general analgesic effect but then also
what I what I've gotten to started
calling uh cascading forgetfulness right
because we we we talk with cannabis
folks and you know you get a little high
and then you forget where you put your
keys and you go on doing other things
and you know that that kind of idea of
shortterm forgetting often has patients
forget that they're in pain it's also I
think why it works so well PTSD folks
because you just get distracted by life
and you get involved and and you forget
that you're in pain so I like to I like
to think about it having these two
different paths do you think that's a a
fair uh way to describe it yeah it sure
is because you've hit on uh two of the
key mechanisms one is a direct effect
against pain that works through complex
Pathways in the brain spinal cord and
nerves out in the body so that's one but
the other is the way it modulates the
emotional part of pain um and so yeah
part of it is distraction but
additionally there have been studies
that show that the emotional factor in
pain is considerably reduced by
cannabinoids and specifically by DC so
that combination uh together is quite
powerful um and doing something that
other drugs just don't do you know I I
can't be the only one listening to you
talk right now feeling a little giddy to
be able to get information directly from
the source you know so many of us are
who are trying to learn about cannabis
we're getting our information from
secondary sources right and secondary
sources are not really as good as
hearing it right from you so so anyway
it's it's a real joy to actually hear it
in your own words so one more thing on
THC before we move on you know um you
know I'd love for you to review a little
bit you know THC you know in isolate is
not the magical thing right we we
understand the Entourage effect and I
talked a little bit about that in in the
introduction but would you talk about
the importance of of not using THC on
its own and that it needs the other
phyto canabo to be there with it right
well the easiest thing would be an
illustration THC as a single compound a
synthetic form was approved in the
United States in 1985 and that was to
treat nausea associated with
chemotherapy um but uh many people
tolerated it poorly almost no one liked
it uh the way that they might like
cannabis um and people who use both said
this really isn't like cannabis cannabis
works a lot lot better um that wasn't
something that everyone was prepared to
hear uh certainly the government had an
investment in the idea that well we've
given you access to THC you don't need
cannabis for medicinal purposes anymore
I can tell you that in my neurology
practice after um Marinol synthetic THC
was Downs scheduled in
1999 I used it pretty extensively for
the next four years in a iety of
contexts and it's u a very tricky drug
it's quite different to cannabis in that
it's likely to produce disphoria so
that's unhappiness as opposed to
Euphoria it's very
distracting uh it's very difficult to
control um and there's a very fine line
between a dose that might help symptoms
like reducing pain and that which
produces unwanted side effects like
raction or anxiety so in other words uh
THC as alone has what we call a very
narrow therapeutic
index now in contrast when there are
other ingredients aboard particularly
canaba or certain of the turpo
terpenoids um you get a great expansion
of that therapeutic index so that much
more THC can be used to better effect
and with without so many Adverse Events
or side effects right on good so before
we move on to CBD let's let's talk
briefly about
thca which is the naturally occurring
acid form of THC now um I think most of
us know that to convert the naturally
forming thca into THC uh we need to add
some heat to uh DEC carboxilate it um
but but a lot of people are looking at
thca um for different therapeutic
effects than THC what what are the
different therapeutic effects between
the two right well they're quite
distinct in their activities thca is
considered non- psychoactive in other
words it doesn't produce the high that
we associate with
THC additionally it is it thca is also
an anti-inflammatory but through a
different
mechanism um it affects a molecule
called uh uh tumor necr is Factor Alpha
that is important in certain autoimmune
diseases uh such as
Crohn's ulcer of colitis and rheumatoid
arthritis uh additionally and this one
needs a lot more work there seems to be
benefit in epilepsy TT uh can be helpful
in epilepsy too but uh there seems to be
a distinct mechanism um that really
hasn't been adequately explored yet so
despite raw cannabis having been used
medically for a long time throughout
history it just hasn't received uh the
research um that THC itself has uh so
it's it's a place where we need to learn
a lot more I'll mention one other thing
that it can do it seems to be very
powerful uh against certain tumors
particularly skin tumors um and so again
this is an area that really deserves
more research attention
so I know that we could probably do an
entire show just uh devoted to CBD as
well as we could with THC but let's go
ahead and review um um canabal uh and
and talk about um how it is uh so
helpful to the human body yeah well
there's this uh dichotomy that's
developed a lot of people tend to think
a canab dial is the good canabo where
THC is the bad canabo and I really
reject that uh both have their place
actually uh for most kinds of problems a
combination uh in other words uh using a
type of cannabis that contains both is
usually a distinct
Advantage but it's really fascinating
because canabidol uh being a different
molecule just by a little bit has quite
distinct features some of its activities
are similar to THC and that both are
anti-inflammatory both are analgesic
painkillers but uh as compared to THC
kabid actually reduces anxiety uh it's
an antipsychotic in other words it's
been used in schizophrenia to treat uh
that disorder primarily um and um a
whole list of other uh properties beyond
that yeah well while we're on that let's
let's go ahead and plug the great
website at projectcbd.org
they've got a great uh page on their
website um you can click on the word
conditions on the website and it lists a
whole bunch of uh different human
ailments that that you might have and
you can click on any uh condition and uh
they will pull up for you the scientific
studies that are showing that uh the
different canab uh the different canono
uh the effect it can have whether you
have you know Parkinson's or or pain or
or asthma or anything so uh that's a
projectcbd.org
so so um so Ethan you know a lot of us
have heard of THC and CBD but there's
all these other cannabinoids is CBD so
popular because it is so unique from the
other cannabinoids or is it because it's
the first one to get extensive
research uh well a combination of of the
two but really uh if you ask me uh in my
experience as a physician and researcher
uh the single most versatile medicine uh
that I've ever encountered it would be
canaba there are at least 30 distinct
activities that it has so it is what's
often derisively termed a dirty drug
however a dirty drug may also be one
that works and the remarkable thing
about CBD is at the same time if he
asked me the safest drug the one with
the fewest side effects that I've ever
encountered it would also be
canaba uh because they're very few of
the things that it does even at very
high doses that are deleterious to to
the human body uh so it's really a
remarkable product and perhaps its
greatest uh attribute is that it's able
to modulate the endoc canabo system now
I know that you've discussed the endoc
canabo system your audience before but
just to to mention again it's a great
homeostatic regulator in other words it
brings various physiological systems in
the body back into balance and since
canabidol is a general stimulant to
endoc canabo tone it has the capability
of improving function in any of a
variety of areas uh of physiology that
might be deranged so if there's pain at
helps with that uh if there's too much
activity in the gut it will reduce it if
there's too little it will increase it
uh so it has a sort of buffering effect
to bring uh physiology back into balance
that's great I think that in uh Chinese
medicine they call that a tonifier it
brings brings you back to the neutral to
the center well that's exactly uh great
a great analogy there sure right on so
we're going to take a short break and be
right back you are listening to shaping
fire and my guest this week is Dr Ethan
Russo now that the health benefits of
tpin have become well known in the
Cannabis industry people everywhere are
looking for the purest tpin without
adulterant the problem with most tpine
providers is that they're not sourced
naturally and instead are made as a
byproduct of refining petroleum and
that's so sketchy the tpin sold by true
tpin are entirely different they are
certified organic non-GMO and food grade
that means that they are extracted from
real plant sources there're no solvents
of any kind they are distilled only with
steam that's right only steam in fact
tpin from True turpins are so pure that
you can eat them not only that but you
can stack them with better results too
what I mean is other companies turpins
have got a few percent of impurities and
when you stack those tpin to make your
blend you're adding a variety of
impurities that degrade your final
product true turpins also have strain
specific turpins for a wide range of
cannabis strains like Durban Poison Sun
at sherbet and Granddaddy Purple true
turpins has robust and supportive
customer service so your questions will
get answered fast and efficiently if
you've shot for TPS before you know how
rare that is so whether you want to cup
your hands to smell some beta caropine
to calm down after getting too high or
if you want to dab some pining so your
lungs feel fabulous and your mind feels
liberated true turpins will provide you
with a truly natural experience if you
are a cannabis product developer these
are the T you want to add to your oil or
edible or capsule or whatever true
turpins are simply the best your money
can buy don't try and make a premium
product with substandard TPS choose true
tpping for a topshelf experience go to
shaping fire.com sltr turpins to find
out more or click on the link in this
week's newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire and I am your
host Shango Los my guest this week is
world renowned cannabis researcher and
neurologist Dr Ethan Russo so before the
break we hit the two biggies THC and CBD
and so we're going to continue down the
list of the other phyto canabo that are
mentioned in your famous taming THC
paper and we're going to start with one
of the very rarely talked about ones CBC
what can you tell us about CBC well this
is one that uh needs a lot more work and
a lot more attention part of the problem
is uh that canab chroming is formed by a
recessive gene uh in contrast to THC and
CBD where the pathways are from dominant
genes so it's a bit of a rarer bird in
most uh
commercially available forms of cannabis
um additionally it has a feature of
being a little more prominent in uh
immature plants so uh if people wait
until maturity there's going to be less
CBC um but uh one of my colleagues from
GW Pharmaceuticals David Potter um used
young plants to to make what he called
an enriched Tricom product which is
another way of saying hash uh he made
this with young plants that did show uh
a predilection towards making um more
canaba chromin
CBC uh and was able to get a good
concentration that way
unfortunately it it's never been used in
a clinical trial yet despite uh having
great promise uh on its own when you say
uh it it appears most in young plants uh
you're meaning young plants that are
early in the bloom right so that they're
forming tricomes as part of the blooming
cycle or do you mean young as in they're
still in
veg uh well it'd be during the flowering
phase as with the other cannabinoids uh
greatest production is going to be in
the capitate glandular tricomes that
appear in the unfertilized female
flowers it would just be earlier in the
flowering cycle as you mentioned right
on I just wanted to make a difference
between that and something like uh can
of flaven right which is actually in a
young plant but also early in the veg
stage if I understand it correctly sure
even in the Sprouts right on fantastic
um so sounds like we definitely need
more research into CBC and since it's um
um uh a less common one aggressive
breeders could start focusing on on on
hybridizing for more CBC sure there'd be
an advantage because uh as CBD is an
endoc canab noid uh uh modulator uh so
too is
CBC uh CBC is also
anti-inflammatory uh it's very active
against uh variety of cancer cell lines
so it it shows a lot of prom
great great so so I've heard of CBG a
little more often and there are um many
Labs that are are able to start testing
for it uh why do we care about CBG well
uh it's sort of the parent molecule uh
to the other phyto cannabinoids so that
alone makes it important normally in the
plant it doesn't stop there it uh goes
onward to either THC CBD or CBC or the
propyl uh cannabinoids um but um again
uh there have been plants bred in
England uh that quit uh at CBG they
don't have the enzymatic equipment due
to a mutation to go beyond it and so in
those plants 100% of the canabo would be
as
canaberal so canaberal um again is one
I'm excited about uh for the future
because again this hasn't been used in
human clinical trials uh but it it uh
has very interesting properties uh it
seems to be a very strong anti-anxiety
agent without being sedating um most of
the drugs that are used that way in
humans like the benzo aines Valium Etc
um are not only sedating but addictive
and uh this is quite different to what
we see with CBG there's no indication uh
that it would be addictive at all uh dis
Al it has some muscle relaxing
properties um it uh interestingly is a
strong uh antibiotic or disinfectant one
of the things it does is it works
against Mera uh that's multiply
resistant stafl coic orius uh one of
those Hospital acquired infections that
uh was rampant um throughout the us a
few years ago on poses a real risk for
hospitalized patient that might be quite
ill so if if CBG is kind of a a parent
canabo does that mean that when it
degrades with time or light that it
could uh degrade into a different canabo
uh no not unless the plant is alive to
provide the enzymes to do it again uh
usually in the plant Machinery of canabo
production it just doesn't stop there it
goes on through uh to the next next uh
item and so usually CBG doesn't
accumulate uh in great amounts in a
given
plant right on you know earlier in um uh
2016 uh
thcv uh was all through the media
because people started talking about its
uh appetite suppression um attributes
and and you know supposedly uh some of
the forms of Blue Dream are heavy in it
and and people love the idea that you
could um use Canabis but also not get
the munchies um you know how how how how
effective is thcv to actually suppress
the appetite does it do it a little bit
or does it really not give you the
munchies uh well in in pure form which
would not be accessible to people it's
it's quite prominent uh in its appetite
suppression uh effects without a speedy
effect that one would get say from an
amphetamine so this is quite distinct um
the trouble is in cannabis uh that's
available in Commerce in North America
usually the amount of tetra Hydra
canaban or thcv is quite quite low uh
but again in England uh there is a plant
uh where over
90% uh of the cannabinoids are expressed
as
thcv um so that one has been used in
humans and it has the added benefit of
being a pretty good
anti-convulsant A drug for seizures it's
beyond the appetite suppressant part it
seems to be helpful in the metabolic
syndrome so this would be the problems
that people get into if they're diabetic
or
pre-diabetic so you know what you just
said there was pretty heavy duty the
fact that the the commercially available
cannabis strains that have thcv don't
really have enough in it to to truly
suppress the appetite so so taking that
to the extreme end and talking about the
example that you gave from the UK where
it's 90% is you know if if you ingested
that strain would it actually suppress
the appetite or does it just make a
really good Target for extraction to
extract thcv out of it to then apply
that to the patient um no that
particular plan uh when it's extracted
even with a little bit of THC in it uh
does have the benefits that I mentioned
uh the point is though that uh at least
in the US we're not there yet in terms
of
optimizing um thcv kavars um the
available ones may produce less of the
munchies but they're not going to have
all of the attributes uh that we
mentioned that have been seen with the
extracts that have been used
in clinical trials so far right on so in
your paper uh taming THC after thcv you
move to
cbdv right well this one also has just
started uh in human use so this is the
um corresponding agent to CBD so as THC
is to
thcv cbdv is to as is as to CBD
um so uh this is looks like CBD but it's
got a three carbon side chain instead of
five and it's being investigated for
seizures of partial onset what used to
be called focal seizures um there seems
to be a good signal there um I really
couldn't say a lot more about uh how it
affects people yet uh except that it it
appears to be non-
intoxicating um appears to be quite safe
uh in the experiments that have been
done so far in the last year uh we've
seen a lot of new products coming out
that are um uh supplemented with CBN and
uh most of them are uh people are saying
well CBN totally helps you sleep and so
and so they'll take their product you
know an edible or something and they'll
they'll add CBN to it uh do you think
that CBN will have that kind of effect
when supplemented into edible
uh I'm not a proponent of spiking things
uh in that manner um my personal bias is
that uh with uh time and attention and
proper selective breeding uh you can get
the effects you want uh from a g given
cannabis kovar without uh needing to add
anything to it additionally there's some
misconceptions about canab andol or
CBN um as a pure compound it really is
not very sedating uh it is THC like but
about a quarter of the potency uh the
confusion may arise because CBN is an uh
non-enzymatic breakdown product of THC
in other words in old cannabis it will
oxidize from THC into
CBN um at the same time you get a l loss
of the monoterpenoids
and you get remaining some of the higher
molecular weight sesquiterpenoids that
tend to be sedating and so old cannabis
tends to be soporific that's a medical
ease for uh saying that it makes you
sleep uh but the CBN uh itself is not
strongly sedating I was going to save
this for the next section when we talk
about terpenoids but let's talk about it
right now would you explain the
difference between monot turp oids and
CES to terpenoids sure um terpenoids are
built up of uh five carbon blocks the
so-called monoterpenoids have 10 carbons
the CES terpenoids have 15 the
diterpenoids have 20 and the
triterpenoids have 30 carbons so that
that's it and uh turpine means um
there's confusion about these terms but
a turpenoid
uh as a broader term and would include
um agents that uh have oxygen in them or
occasionally other molecules a tpine
strictly speaking is has just carbon and
hydrogen right on so what one more thing
on CBN before we move on to to the group
of terpenoids you know it's it's common
said amongst uh Canabis folk that say
for example oh I've I've got this flower
left over from last Summer's grow
um it's all CBN now if you smoke it
you'll just get couch lock and fall
asleep and and you know while that's you
know kind of a rule of thumb uh you
mentioning that CBN is not really all
that sedative um is there is there truth
to the rule of thumb that I just uh
explained or is that is that more myth
well the phenomenology in other words
the description you gave is probably
accurate a lot of older cannabis is
going to be sedating uh it won't be
stimulating
necessarily um a lot of people find it
less uh attractive um but again it would
be from the sedative influences of the
remaining
turpenoid right on so so most of us know
that terpenoids are the smell of the
plant now the aroma therapy if you will
would you explain what exactly a
turpenoid is and why the plant bothers
to produce them sure well these are
produced in the glandular tricomes along
with the cannabinoids and again these
are molecules that the plant makes uh
often in its defense some of these are
insect repellants or
insecticides others actually attract
certain desirable bugs um and they're
often antioxidants and
antibiotics uh but again um we can
leverage uh what the plant has done uh
to help our own
ailments I I know that when I'm shopping
for cannabis I usually shop with my nose
I mean obviously I I I I've like bag
appeal as much as anybody does but
really you know we're we're opening jars
we're sticking our nose in there and
when our body has this reaction of yeah
I want more of this you know we go ahead
and choose that strain is there any um
support or truth to the fact that our
our body when smelling specific
terpenoids knows what its needs and so
our body is self- selecting for the
medicine that's best for us then uh May
well be um you know it's a hard thing to
measure I can say this the situation
that you describe is quite accurate uh
Michelle sexon uh naturopath uh who's
investigated this looked at uh patient
preferences in Washington state and the
number one
Criterion for selection of a particular
cannabis chovar was it
smell yeah that does that doesn't
surprise me at all and you know what's
interesting too is how
how uh strains that have got wildly
different smells can I can be attracted
to both I can I can smell something
that's you know really foul and skunky
and smells like a baby diaper like
perhaps um you know like a funky cheese
and I'm like oh I really need some of
that and then I'll smell you know uh
some some Lemon Diesel with a really
bright Citrus smell I'm like oh I want
that too um it's interesting how we can
be you know our human can be attracted
to a variety of tpin that are very much
unlike each other well as they say
variety is the spice of
life so so um you know are terpenoids
from Cannabis and food and other sources
the same do they have the same effect
regardless of of where they're from when
they're in isolate yeah in general yes
um there are no terpenoids that we know
of that appear only in cannabis there's
certain profiles that are characteristic
but these are part of everyday life um
if you're eating Citrus you you're
exposed if you take a walk in a forest
you're exposed to pining um so they if
you have a plant-based diet you're
exposed to these um but the key thing is
how they synergize with THC and other
canono um this is the real difference so
if the question were will exposure to
terpenoids from food exert benefits yes
I believe that they do uh it's just that
um in terms of the experience one has
with cannabis uh they're really
fundamental uh to the differences that
one experiences
uh one chovar to
another so one more question before we
go to uh to our next commercial you know
uh one of the things that really caught
me off guard reading in your paper you
say that you know the terpenoids
increase with intensity of light but
decrease with soil fertility and that
that really kept caught me off guard
because most of the Growers I know are
trying to make a very ferti living soil
to help the turps uh develop why is it
true that a decreased soil fertility
will increase terpenoids sure well first
off um the rich soil at the beginning is
great but um depletion of the soil
towards the end seems to help the
turboid and this shouldn't be a big
surprise if we consider that our herbs
uh or lavender uh grow best in a sandy
soil uh where environmental conditions
are a little rough uh keep in mind that
the terpenoids are plant defense
compounds and uh so if the environment
is a little more difficult uh your
teranoid production is going to increase
um for uh people growing cannabis um
having a little uh less water uh and a
lot less nutrients towards the end of
the flowering cycle are going to uh
produce the same kind of effect uh it's
specifically you know that we've got all
the Growers attention um when would you
decrease the nutrients and water to get
that effect how many weeks in oh I I
can't tell you that exactly I'm sure
there people who know but um I'm I'm not
sure off the top right on that's fair
enough so we're going to take another
short break and be right back you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
this week is Dr Ethan
Russo for anyone who is paying attention
to cannabis medicine it has become
incredibly apparent that full extract
cannabis oil known to some as Rick
Simpson Oil is the Cornerstone of
healing humans with medical marijuana if
you own a medical dispensary or retail
store you know that your customers are
asking for it every single day and if
you have been working with patients and
seeking out quality full extract oil in
the Pacific Northwest you know the
provider deep green cat Jeter and her
team at Deep green have been making full
extract cannabis oil and setting the
standards for quality and exact dosing
for years in Washington State the Deep
green brand is known by patients and
cannabis media as a premium quality
provider for sick children cancer
patients and others in need at a time
when there are no national standards for
cannabis oil ensuring a product is whole
plant quality assured and lab tested is
often a matter of knowing your source is
reputable trust in a quality brand is
essential when choosing a cannabis
medicine that is going to be used
concentrated and in volume by any
patient and especially those with
weakened immune systems deep green is
looking for National brand Partners to
expand the availability of their legacy
topshelf cannabis oil to emerging
medical and licensed States Partners
benefit from the deep green brand
recognition and credibility as well as
ongoing customer and marketing support
not only that but deep green knows how
to employ the 2 ad tax rule so you can
deduct it all from your taxes working
with deep green can provide the the
trust and authenticity too often pushed
aside in favor of Lifestyle products
your customers can assure themselves
that regardless of the state in which it
is made brand lenses adhere to the same
strict standards that patients
everywhere have come to expect from Deep
green deep green licensing includes
startup and capital planning as well as
operational and Manufacturing
instruction as you'd expect for more
information on how your company Co-op or
medical dispensary can Ben benefit from
partnering with deep green to provide
full extract cannabis oil to patients go
to shaping fire.com forde green to
connect with cat Jeter and her team
that's shaping
fire.com deepgreen welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire and I am your
host Shango Los my guest this week is
world-renowned cannabis researcher and
neurologist Dr Ethan Russo so before the
break we kind of set up the terpenoids
and talked about about what they are as
a group and and kind of what their
attributes are so for this section we're
going to go through the very specific
terpenoids that you talk about in your
uh groundbreaking paper uh taming THC so
let's start with D
limonene yes my
favorite I guess it's good to have a
favorite I
guess yeah U Lyon is a really
fascinating compound and it's pretty
ubiquitous and unfortunately the place
you're most likely to run into it is
walking down the detergent aisle at the
supermarket
um two our senses um the scent of lemon
or Citrus uh denotes cleanliness or
healthiness uh so there's a reason it's
it's there that way it not only makes an
efficient cleaning agent uh but it has a
strong psychological effect um one of
brightness cleanliness and improve mood
and that's exactly what lying uh will
produce when it's there in a significant
amount along uh with the
cannabinoids I tell people who are
unfamiliar with tpin that if they if
they want to have the experience of
lioning to just you know simply cut a
piece of citrus fruit like a lemon and
you smell it and suddenly you feel uh
motivated and happy and um and you know
full of sunshine and joy and that is
that that is the tpin having a direct
effect on you um when you when you cut a
lemon is that lioning and then when you
cut an orange that citrine uh no they're
both primarily
lanine uh the difference between the
various citrus fruits uh almost all of
them have very high percentage of
lemoning in the Rind uh you know if you
take your thumbnail across the Rind of a
citrus you're releasing uh Tri ioms and
lyine uh the differences in the smells
and tastes come from uh much uh lower
concentration uh factors other uh other
terpenoids that are distinct from one
another in the various kinds of citrus
that certainly uh kind of explains why
so many cocktails are served with a uh
with a Twist right because as you're
bringing the cocktail up to your nose uh
you're getting this hit loning that's
making you feel joyous as you're
enjoying the cocktail and and no wonder
we like it sure so the the next one that
you cover in the P paper is uh beta
Meine right um Meine uh is the most
prevalent uh turpenoid in most available
Kars of cannabis uh to me that's
unfortunate certainly there people that
prefer it uh but it has a strongly
sedating Nar otic like effect um and so
if there's a kind of cannabis that uh
makes people unable to move what's
commonly termed couch lock uh it's
likely that uh it's due to a high Ming
content um so that's not always an
advantage if someone needs to sleep or
needs to relax uh certainly it can be um
on the plus side mercine does have
analgesic pink killing properties on a
variety of other properties that can be
beneficial but in general there's a lot
of it out there and maybe more than is
needed for optimal effect uh certainly
for people after work or study uh it's
usually not an advantage to have a high
concentration of
merine so it would be remiss if we
didn't touch on mangoes here for a
moment because a lot of people say that
you know if you if you want to enjoy
your cannabis especially well go ahead
and eat a mango before it because the
mirene uh improves the experience of the
Cannabis how much of that is myth and
how much of that is real Mostly myth um
there's actually a paper that was done
on the uh the turpenoid content of
mangoes and it varies from being a fair
amount to some where there's almost none
uh
additionally a lot of people will say
that mercing helps uh to get THC across
the bloodb brain barrier uh well
normally THC has no problem getting
across the bloodb brain barrier uh both
of these compounds are what we call
lipophilic Fat loving and they all go
right into the brain without any
difficulty um so uh I think mangoes are
really healthy and people should eat
them because they want to or enjoy it
but um I think the likelihood that
that's going to have a material effect
uh on their um exper erience is is
pretty low right on well said well let's
talk about one of my favorites Alpha
pining you know uh when I one of the
first times that I I heard you speak it
really impressed me that you know I love
walking in the forest I love that Nordic
term to take a maybe it's a Japanese
term anyway to take a forest bath to go
I I love that idea and uh and and you
were explaining how you know when you go
into the forest and you're around these
pine trees and it's get they're it's
they're giving off pining and you know
you take a big breath and you fill your
lung sacks and you're like H the forest
and actually what you're getting is a
big hit of pining right yes it is yeah
so uh shinrin Yoku or Forest bathing is
uh just the act of walking in a a forest
uh in Japan um and you know a lot of
people if they've had a difficult work
day they want to clear their head that's
exactly what they'll do particularly in
the Pacific Northwest is take a a walk
in a Pine Forest or in our instance it's
going to be other conifers but they're
all rich in pining so the effect on
one's mood is going to be the same um
but uh it goes further than that uh
unfortunately pining is less common in
modern choar of cannabis it's sort of
been shoved aside by mercing if you will
um but in kovar that have it uh the end
result is an experience that's much
clearer without the confusion and the
short-term memory that people often
equate uh with
THC um clearly THC does produce
impairment of short-term memory uh but
pining is what's called a colon esterase
inhibitor uh it inhibits the breakdown
of acetycholine which is the main memory
molecule on the brain um it reverses
this effect that THC has and uh
particularly for a patient uh who needs
canabus having
pinene uh in the kovar that they're
using is much more likely
uh if they use it it' be much more
likely that they'll be able to work or
study without uh the impairment that can
come in uh if there's too much THC or if
there's too much sedation from merine
for example I see so something with a
lot of pining would be really good for
for daytime because you can be more
productive and a little more focused and
and have more likelihood to stay on task
right and again um I I'd emphasize that
a lot of this is subject to uh people's
preferences um there's some people that
love the mercing couch lock lock effect
and others really dislike it um so taste
does taste comes into this and a big way
yeah I'm I'm actually one of those
people that loves Mir SC uh you know I
can I can enjoy the the most couch loia
strains and still have a good time of it
because I tend to run really hot and
fast anyway I generally stay away from
sativas just because they they tend to
over amp me um and and that's you know
one of the important parts of
individualized medicine right where
where not one one size does not fit all
and and and when people are originally
getting in cannabis they should take
some time to sample a wide variety of
strains so that they can taste a lot of
these different terpenoids and find out
the one that their human enjoys the most
ah sure and again I'd extend that to
therapeutic applications the one that's
going to give them the best uh benefits
on their symptoms and produce the fewest
side effects am I correct that linol the
next turpenoid we're going to talk about
is pretty heavy in lavender and is one
of the aspects that makes us feel so Cal
when we smell it or use a lavender eye
pillow yeah that's exactly right uh
pretty remarkable compound in addition
to having those anti-anxiety effects uh
can Aid sleep uh it's a very strong
local anesthetic uh one of the things I
always like to talk about is uh people
should keep a bottle of lavender
essential oil uh in the fridge in the
kitchen because if you get a kitchen
burn and put the lavender oil on neat
and cover it with a an ice cube uh the
pain will generally go away in a few
minutes and uh almost never blister is
it too um is it too intense straight
would you need to thin it out with
something you know how some some
essential oils will burn the skin right
now it's a good point but lavender uh
oil is safe to use neat undiluted on the
skin right on so um our next One beta uh
kopine I had a really cool experience
with a couple weeks ago uh I was down in
Soma County for Emerald cup and uh I was
staying at a house with a with a whole
bunch of uh cannabis business owners we
kind of just split this this this Wine
Country Villa it was pretty great and I
met uh Ben cassaday from true tping and
and he he was going around the house and
and giving people some beta cophine in
their hands and then and then he was
encouraging us to cup our hands to our
face and it had a faint smell of of
black pepper but the thing that was
remarkable was how incredibly calming it
was and I had never really considered
dosing myself with Tarpin in such a
simple and elegant way as to just put a
little bit in in my palm and then cup it
to my nose sure well you know it's a
direct Pathway to the brain it's
interesting um this is something we need
to explore more um because generally
kopling is considered quote non-
psychoactive un quote but um certainly
it has uh powerful anti-inflammatory
effects and in a situation where someone
had inflammation for any reason uh
particularly in the brain it's uh very
likely going to be therapeutic and that
could manifest itself in a change of
mood certainly um but it's really
remarkable because uh kopine which is a
sesquiterpenoid in other words 15 carbon
mole Ule it's not just a turpenoid it's
a canabo too uh it is a strong Agonist
uh stimulator at the CB2 receptor that
is the cannabinoid receptor that's non
psychoactive and uh is important out in
the body and potentially in the brain um
for pain and
inflammation uh so this is a fascinating
agent and it's it's common in our diets
you mentioned black pepper that's the
most accessible Source but um there are
other uh good examples like Copa Balsam
which has been used in South America uh
to treat uh inflammation sprains and uh
skin conditions uh for Generations by
indigenous people long before we knew
anything about the chemicals in
it which is primarily carry off Lan you
know um I I kind of think that we need
an expanded vocabulary because that idea
of being psychoactive or not you know a
lot of people are talking about THC
being psychoactive and CBD being non-
psychoactive and but and then you know
beta kopine not being psychoactive but I
know that when I smelled it in my Palms
it clearly had a calming effect which
tells me that it is active
psychologically right and so for me it
was psychoactive but it did not have
that that getting high or Stony effect
that THC does it feels to me like like
you know over time we need to develop a
a and widen our vocabulary for for these
experiences I'd endorse that
approach um do you know anybody who's
you know is is there a paper written
about that or or anything that you'd
recommend that I and others read about
about that delineation or has that work
not really taken place yet uh probably
more the latter um there are some
extensive reviews on kry offline um
really looking at the effects that it
has uh on the brain or on mood of Just
Begun um unfortunately a lot of the real
emphasis isn't on kopling but uh trying
to make synthetic drugs that would be
like it that might be more marketable
from an intellectual property standpoint
I uh think that such effort is misguided
when we have a readily available natural
agent uh that's not only effective but
quite safe there's this great term uh
that that we got from Dr Dominic Cora of
Casp when he was on the show uh a couple
months ago uh he talks about whole plant
politics people like myself in this show
and and from what I understand you as
well we believe in the whole plant so
let's let's use the plant let's
emphasize the Entourage effect and let's
not focus as much our research on
finding uh synthetic placements let's
work on the plant even though uh it may
be not possible to patent it and uh as
intellectual property well sure no I I
do believe in that approach um until
about the last 70 years um medicine was
synonymous with plants and it's still
that way for many people in the third
world and Indigenous peoples around the
world so the ne the next um the next
turpenoid I actually have never heard
pronounced so I'm I'm going to butcher
Butcher it and then you can uh uh fix it
for me is it nural nidol neurod dool yes
nurad dool uh please I I have never
learned anything about that um what's
probably not uh that common in most
North American uh cannabis choar it is a
minor component of citrus um it has some
interesting antifungal effects uh it
penetrates the skin really well and can
tend to drag other things in along with
it um but uh it's probably not one that
a lot of people are going to encounter
um in in North America at least in
cannabis is is the reason for that
because it's not popular in you know the
commercial cannabis world or is it
because those cultivars are from you
know uh you know really exotic foreign
countries that we just don't have the
genetics here I mean what's the reason
we don't come across it
I'm not sure if we knew more about the
ecological role that it had I I could
probably give a better answer uh so
you've stump me on that one all right um
so that let's move on to uh kopine oxide
right well uh you know as you can tell
from the name this just has an extra
oxygen uh on it as compared to
kopine um again uh very powerful
antifungal uh this could be the solution
um nail fungus um additionally uh its
real distinction is it seems to be the
chemical and cannabis uh that sniffer
dogs key in on uh to identify uh
cannabis uh at least that's what they
thought when it was examined in uh
auster about 35 years ago uh nobody's
really done any work on it since uh so
there's a research project for somebody
who'd like to look into that yeah we're
actually this is kind of a laundry list
of upand cominging research scientists
about all the all the cool areas of
cannabis that are still just like
waiting for people to dive into um well
yeah the article is uh almost six years
old now and I've made a bunch of
suggestions and a lot of them haven't
had followup so here's your
chance so the so the last one in this
section is spall right well FAL is
pretty Universal um any dried uh herb is
going to have some in it because uh it's
basically a breakdown product of
chlorophyll now what's interesting about
it is it's probably responsible for the
calming effect of green tea even though
green tea has caffeine in it um uh but
uh yeah I mean that that's the main
thing there um so if uh cannabis is
purely flour not a lot of leaf there
won't be much of it and it is a a d
turpenoid the only 20 uh carbon U
molecule that's uh common in herbal
cannabis so before we wrap up the
section I'd like to Circle back around
to uh your suggestion that you're not a
big fan of spiking uh cannabis and
cannabis products with uh terpenoids or
probably any phyto canabo you know uh
folks are now taking products you know
from Edibles to tinctures and and and
they're starting with whole plant which
is great but then they want to they want
to turn up some aspect of it say they
want to make it a little more
stimulating and so they'll drop some
loning in there or they want to say it's
more for for pain uh and so they'll drop
some mcing in there um so long as you
start with a whole plant base so you do
have all the minor canono in there um
what is the reason why you're not so
much of a fan of of spiking just a
little bit of one or the other for its
therapeutic effect well it's it's
multiple reasons first um we don't
necessarily know the source of the
terpenoids whether they've been
organically produced is it the right
stereo isomer um if somebody goes online
uh to a chemical supply house and looks
up lioning it isn't going to be one
they're going to be several um so it's
not a simple thing uh for a person to
pick the right one again most of these
aren't 100% pure um and they're not
designed for internal use um now let's
compare that to organically grown
cannabis uh we know that uh we know what
its side effects are
um but it's very different using a a
synthesized chemical and adding that to
material but beyond that I'd reemphasize
what I said
previously this plant is capable of
doing almost anything you wish
uh given the time and attention to
selective breeding for the desired
components um to me there's no
substitute uh for someone taking the
time and effort uh to get the plant that
they want um sure uh a lot of the things
you mentioned in terms of spiking can be
Illuminating for people to understand uh
the different effects but um as a a
practice uh it's not something i' really
encourage finally there's uh another
important reason and that is a lot of
these are in commercial development of
one kind or another I know that a lot of
companies are pursuing this um you
cannot spike a natural plant and develop
a uh drug out of it um through the Food
and Drug Administration approval process
um that's considered a combination
product um and so you have to do the uh
safety efficacy and toxicity on um the
original material the added material and
the two together so it triples the
amount of Investigation that's necessary
and uh from a financial standpoint it
makes it an
impossibility uh because developing a
drug for FDA approval can be upwards of
a billion dollars at this point from
start to finish one of the things that
you mentioned about spiking is that you
weren't sure if it was from an organic
source and the way I'm taking that is
that that you're suggesting there are
synthetic terpenoids I actually thought
that all the turps that we came across
were either cannabis or food based are
you saying that that that there are such
thing as synthetically produced
terpenoids the vast majority are
synthetically produced a lot of these
are byproducts of uh petroleum products
um so you know the chemical company will
make one thing out of another thing and
again let's say it's 95% pure and you've
got the right um molecule what about the
other 5% you don't know what that is uh
we'll say right on the bottle uh that
it's not designed um uh to be used as a
medicine or taken internally or anything
else um there's a real potential danger
there and I don't want to exag at uh
there is a potential danger there right
on so we're going to take our last
commercial break and when we come back
we're going to be talking about the
psycho pharmacological impacts of these
different cannabinoids you are listening
to shaping fire and my guest this week
is Dr Ethan
Russo if you like podcasts like shaping
fire chances are that you will like Audi
books too pretty much audiobooks are
like podcasts except with less
stuttering better production quality and
more targeted topics yeah I know I make
audiobooks sound better than a podcast
and you know maybe they are but I get
you I like podcast too I like to learn
from people talking to me while I'm
doing something else like you know
driving or cleaning my house or making
dinner or even being at work whatever
here's the thing audible.com has an
offer I want to tell you about right now
they are offering a trial of their
audiobook service for absolutely free
you can go to shaping
fire.com Audible and you will get a free
audiobook straight up you can listen to
it on your mobile device on your
computer or you can download it and
listen to it you know pretty much
anywhere it's really simple you know of
course they really want you to subscribe
to their service forever and enjoy more
and more audiobooks but as cannabis
users you also know how this goes the
first one is free they're going to hate
I've said that but it's pretty you know
I listened recently to smoke signals by
Martin Lee from projectcbd.org
Martin's book is a classic of cannabis
advocacy he explains the history of
cannabis in America uh THC and CBD
cannabis science and why cannabis policy
in America has gotten so jacked you know
if you consider yourself a cannabis
person this book really is a must
talking cannabis we all sound radical
just cuz we're talking about weed but if
you learn the history and science of
cannabis suddenly you become smart and
trustworthy to people the book was
really incredible and there's no doubt
that Martin Lee is the real deal you can
get the book for free just for doing the
trial you know if you don't want to
listen to a canos book that's cool too
there's everything else there's sci-fi
and history biography hell you can even
listen to a book about card counting in
blackjack whatever it's all pretty rad
so here's the deal your first book Is
free it's easy to sign up it's easy to
quit but they do do a pretty good job
making me want to stay every month just
check it out go to shaping
fire.com audible to find out more
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire and I am your host Shango
Los my guest this week is world-renowned
cannabis researcher and neurologist Dr
Ethan Russo so in the last section of
your paper taming THC you talk about
some of the psycho pharmacological
impacts that these phyto canavs have and
so we'll touch on the the same three
that you talk about in your paper so
let's start with their impact on
depression and
anxiety right well you know there is
benefit to THC and certainly to CBD in
some of these mood disorders but they
can really strongly be enhanced uh by
the addition of the right turpenoid and
particularly the pining and loning uh
respectively for cl ity uh from the
pining and uh an anti-depressant effect
uh from the loning um there's a real
Synergy or boosting of effect there
where you get a much much more dramatic
effect in the combination than you would
be with any single uh molecule
alone so so when when they're working
together like this for the Entourage
effect um you're finding that uh they
kind of uh groups these together you
know depression anxiety these are these
are all your endoc
canabidol and so they're working
together to rebalance is is that what
you're suggesting ah yeah that's that's
certainly part of it um another actually
people have this misconception I I'm
afraid it's been uh spread around Al
also by the medical community that uh
depression is a a serotonin deficiency
uh so you need need a Selective
serotonin reuptake inhibitor to treat it
well they can help um but actually that
isn't a good science we should think of
um depression as being a disorder of
plasticity of the brain uh in other
words you've got a loss of the ability
to roll with a proverbial punches um
things aren't working
efficiently um you've lost U uh lost uh
the ability to react uh to the
environment in an optimal fashion um in
fact one of the effects of the canabo
seems to be increase to increase
plasticity of the brain and uh again
with uh mood enhancement from lyine
that's a powerful
combination So when you say plasticity
um is is that a part of the the removal
of plaque that we talk about when using
phyto canab
to to help the brain remove plaque thus
fighting things like Alzheimer's and
causing neurogenesis and acting as a
neuroprotectant yeah it's the
neurogenesis uh the Regeneration of of
nerve cells the uh there are benefits of
both T THC and CBD potentially in uh
dementia like uh Alzheimer disease um
and uh yeah there there is the
possibility
that uh we could help prevent plaque
formation that is one of the Hallmarks
of that disorder you know very often
when I'm talking with patients they're
they're asking me about insomnia it's
like oh my gosh I need help um getting
the sleep and you know it it always um
you know as part as a as part of the
suggestion I always try to find out if
it's if it's you know anxiety and and
they can't seow their brain down or
whether or not sometimes with patients
it's pain and every time they roll over
over it's pain and then you have to deal
with the pain first and then you can go
back and and work with the insomnia but
let's say for example that it's not pain
related and it's you know racing brain
related and we're trying to help people
you know settle down and slip into good
Slumber and you know most of the
professionals that I talk to we all kind
of agree that the that the heavy purple
Indica flowers you know that are packed
with mirene are a good way to go but one
thing I've never heard anybody explain
is that why that why it works well uh
it's uh
multifactorial as we like to say in
medicine part of it is just the
sleepiness the hypnotic effect of some
cannabis components including THC and
merine but uh both of those are also
painkillers um I wrote about this about
10 years ago a review of effects of
cannabis on sleep um in the clinical
trials that have been done on cannabis
based medicine the symptom that is
almost always alleviated is um insomnia
and again it's a combination of factors
number one being that there may be a
hypnotic effect uh from the particular
uh preparation but beyond that and more
dramatic is the reduction of symptoms
allowing sleep in other words if the
person has pain reducing the pain allows
them to sleep if they have restless legs
and those are calmed that allows them to
sleep uh same thing with spasticity uh
increased muscle tone uh definitely the
same thing with lower urinary tract
symptoms um with cannabis it's been
shown that there are fewer uh episodes
of needing to get up at night to urinate
um so clearly that can lead to better
sleep um so it is the uction and
symptomatology that's the most um
Salient reason that cannabis is a sleep
aid that makes a lot of sense um so the
last one that you review in your paper
is addiction and it's become pretty
common for people to use cannabis to uh
to move off narcotics most common
recently um but also alcoholism how how
does that work well it's uh complicated
but a lot of this Works um through
reward Pathways in the brain that are uh
mediated by a neurotransmitter called
dopamine um but um basically they're
different mechanisms operative uh with
THC it's a little bit more mysterious
but it would pertain to modulation of
the reward Pathways uh with
canaba um what has been noted is that a
lot of addiction is is related to
craving that comes about as a withdrawal
effect um and that seems to be mediated
by an area in the brain called the
insula uh canaba has the uh ability to
um chemically turn down the activity in
the insula and eliminate craving uh
potentially so between the two uh there
can be a very generous effect on
addiction issues particularly withdrawal
that makes a lot of sense and and
actually that's a way more elegant
explanation than I've been giving people
the idea that that CBD will decrease the
craving instead of replacing whatever
the person is addicted to makes a lot of
sense so the the last thing that you
cover uh in the paper is that that
sometimes you have more THC than your
body is prepared for and you start to
feel uncomfortable and and I think that
pretty much anybody who has uh
experimented with cannabis or has been a
patient and and you know tried to self
tirate their usage to learn how much to
use I think that most of us have had at
some point an overmedicated experience
which is you know has got the range
somewhere between feeling a little
uncomfortable and you just want to go be
alone all the way to um you know uh uh
your your heart rate increases your
blood pressure drops and you're
wondering if you you should call the
paramedics which is never a fun
experience and so what I what I'm doing
is I want to set up uh for you and I
wish we had the wonderful slide you use
in your presentations but I I would like
you to tell the story that you tell
about uh the perfect had too much THC
meal
okay well this leads us off on a
historical tangent but when I was
writing the paper I was interested in
historical antidotes to cannabis um they
go back uh well almost uh well over
2,000 years uh there have been Illusions
to Citrus um uh as being um an antidote
uh to cannabis and it's been repeated in
different cultures around the world uh
that didn't necessarily have knowledge
of one another uh so lying is certainly
one but we also have evidence for pining
from pine nuts and so um I developed
what I call uh THC overdose Meal which
would be um uh pesto uh with the pine
nuts and uh some basil uh along with
um uh a drink called
lemonada uh or uh AGA lion which is uh
like lemonade but uh in this instance
spiked with a whole bunch of extra uh
lemon rind uh for that uh necessary
lyine uh but uh certainly if someone's
had an overdose of cannabis they're not
in a position uh to make this meal um it
it'd be best to have on hand or someone
else applying
it have somebody there to to make you a
meal to help you come down um great so
let's let's I've got a couple questions
that are kind of just generally related
to phyto canabo that I I'd like to wrap
up with so so one of them is that you
know uh since the tricomes are the home
of the of the oils and the tur
terpenoids um it makes me think that
potentially a product that is just the
tricomes say for example a hash or
something um would be able to be
considered whole plant medicine because
it's all there in the tricomes but at
the same time I I doubt that
interpretation because there aren't
things like chlorophyll in there so so
would you see a you know a dry hash or
and I don't mean extracted I don't mean
like butane I'm talking about a dry sift
hash or an ice water hash would you
consider those to be whole plant
medicine I
do right you know the chlorophyll is uh
an agent on its own is is mainly good as
a laxative um really in terms of
cannabis flowers the real medicinal part
is the glandular triome and its purest
manifestation uh would be hashish uh
again what uh Potter called an enriched
uh triome
preparation um so that is going to have
the full complement of the canabo and
terpenoids uh it might not have some
other elements uh that one would get uh
from other parts of the plants like can
flaven but again those can be had on
their own right on thank you so you know
there was some discussion and even some
experiments in the mid 2000s that
questioned the Entourage effect and in
the end it was generally agreed that the
levels of CBD and other cannabinoids and
the doses that they were using were too
low to actually moderate the THC um kind
of debunking those studies what do you
see as the required milligram dosage of
CBD
to successfully play a role in the
patient's experience well it should be
based on
proportions um uh in the past so some
dispensaries have gotten excited about
very low levels of
CBD uh despite it's being so versatile
and so uh Health promoting um CBD is not
what you call really potent there's got
to be a good amount there generally
speaking you want uh for a preparation
where there's going going to be CBD you
want it at least as much as the THC and
in some instances it's better to have a
lot more CBD then
THC right on that makes the sense so so
at least a one to one and up exactly and
so is there a is there a threshold for
that where um the amount of CBD that
you're intaking is too low to really
have any effect at all on you uh
certainly but it would depend also on
the absolute amount of DHC generally
speaking uh because it's so overwhelming
in its effects one would base the
overall dose on that um
so put it in this these terms um 2
milligrams of THC is a threshold dose or
a good place to start for someone who's
not accustomed to cannabis 5 milligrams
is going to affect most people 10
milligrams is a pretty large dose and
certainly Maybe too much uh for someone
who's cannabis
naive um but uh it would be that amount
of THC with whatever amount of CBD is
available and it could be as much of 30
times as much as THC um with some of the
modern
choar um but say to treat a condition
like rheumatoid
arthritis um or schizophrenia or uh
epilepsy you need uh much much higher
dose of
canaba so so what would that number be
where would you you know much much are
you talking about 10 milligrams of CBD a
day or are you talking about 50 no it
could be a few hundred milligrams of CBD
um and that you know that uh becomes
difficult to obtain and can be quite
expensive um but a lot of these problems
are byproducts of prohibition and
hopefully would be circumvented at some
point in the future so so let's say 100
milligrams of CBD in a day is what's
going to be called for uh is that
something that you'd be able to take all
at once or would that just totally
overwhelm your your your intake and you
actually would need to break that down
into three doses over the day how much
can your body take well it can take uh
in the recent clinical trials of EP
dialects which is almost pure CBD for
seizure disorders they've used as much
as 20 500 milligrams of CBD a day but
that's without any
THC um to answer your question generally
speaking most types of cannabis and CBD
should be dosed two or three times a day
uh if we're talking about orally um and
so it's not just a matter of the total
overall daily dose but how it is a
portioned out um but um 2500 milligrams
is a lot
um at that high dose there can be some
drug drug interactions but at lower
doses those are quite rare with CBD um
as a practical measure though um people
are not using pure CBD and almost
invariably there's going to be some
amount of THC that becomes the rate
limiting factor in what people can
manage uh to take without having
issues so that brings us to the hot
question right because we're talking
about how the market is working and and
being able to afford CBD because CBD
from medical cannabis remains expensive
because of prohibition so I want to set
up this question where I'm asking your
thoughts on CBD derived from hemp
because you know as uh whole plant
people um you know we understand that
without the constituents of the medical
cannabis plants the minor cannabinoids
to create the Entourage effect using CBD
uh in isolate really does not get to
claim the benefits um of all this CBD
Research you know when you read these
papers they they're invariably CBD as
the primary component in the presence of
THC and minor cannabinoids and yet the
CBD from hemp Market is claiming that uh
the stud you know they're claiming the
advantages of these studies for their
CBD in isolate plant from hemp so so
what are your your thoughts about CBD
dve from hemp well I have to be very
critical um that's not a good source and
we're not just talking about hemp we're
talking about hemp refuse uh in other
words the hemp has been processed for
another uh reason and they've done a
chemical extraction to concentrate the
CBD but at the same time they're
concentrating pesticides or any other
contaminants um they're really not using
uh dedicated uh flour uh to produce the
medicine and that's the richest source
and the purest Source um additionally uh
because of prohibition there is not the
quality control in the industry that
would tell you whether this is a good
product or not um so I have to be quite
critical okay so I'm going to take that
another another step and press a little
bit more so so I agree how that position
uh suggests okay we should not be buying
CBD isolate from China because you know
uh hemp is a wonderful Toxin and heavy
metals aggregator and you don't know
what's going to be um what what you're
going to be buying but you know there's
some companies in Colorado now that are
growing uh you know uh environment
controlled hemp uh for extraction for
medical products and and you know
they're they're claiming that the the
ground is clean and such so so if we set
aside the
contamination factor for a moment
um do you think that it is reasonable at
all to and I know this kind of goes back
to the spiking idea but let's say that
you're you're taking some amount of of
medical cannabis so you're getting kind
of like this bed of of THC phyto canabo
including all the minor ones but you
also because let's say you're a
rheumatoid arthritis patient you need a
whole lot of CBD as part of that mix um
do you think there's any efficacy to to
have that base from a a whole whole
plant medicine but then spike it with
say 100 Mig of CBD from hemp uh again
that's really suboptimal uh to me you
know uh proper medicine would uh be
stand on its own merits uh and not need
spiking from anything else and and you
know the capability is there uh the
proper chovar are there they're not AA
aailable everywhere uh at this time but
again um I would hope for uh better
future on which there are good quality
Controlled Products available uh that
are backed by uh solid
analyses uh so that consumer and
physician alike and know uh what people
are getting yeah you know from a from a
business point of view it it sounds like
CBD from hemp is a short short-term
product from a transitionary market from
prohibition I mean the the reason why it
makes sense for so many business to try
to sell it is because you know whole
plant medicine is still so expensive
because it's being controlled um so so
Ethan is it true that you're working on
a follow-up to this paper yes absolutely
as we
speak so so when when when can we look
forward to that um you know I'm not sure
it's uh going to be in um a hybrid situ
ation advances in Pharmacology so it
comes out initially as a book um but
it'll also be available as an article um
and it'll be pretty extensive um cover
some of the same ground as taming THC
with the cannabinoids the terpenoids the
the Cannabis flavenoids uh but the we'll
have a generous number of terpenoids
that were not uh treated uh in the prior
paper um and the uh benefit of an
additional five or six years of research
on some of the agents that we did uh
discussed previously uh so I'm excited
about it I'm doing that uh in
collaboration with Jan Maru and uh I
think it'll be nice entry I'm hoping
it'll be available later uh in
2017 well hopefully you'll accept my
invitation when your paper comes out to
discuss it here on shaping fire again I
be delighted well Ethan this has
certainly been a lot of valuable
information to absorb I know the
Cannabis Specialists and nerds out there
like me um have loved this opportunity
to hear you expand on your
groundbreaking paper thank you so much
for dedicating uh some of your valuable
time to be on the show my pleasure you
can read Dr Russo's paper taming THC
online for free and you can find the
link on the podcast page for this
episode you can reach Dr Russo at his
email address Ethan Russo
comcast.net but I also want to say you
got to remember that Dr Russo is
constantly traveling the world and
speaking at conventions and and working
and so you know sometimes he's not going
to be able to get back with you right
away so um he's he's always happy to
hear from folks but please be patient in
the time frame it takes him to to turn
around the emails you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast And
subscribe to the show at shaping
fire.com and on Apple iTunes Stitcher
and Google Play If you enjoyed the show
we'd really appreciate it if you'd leave
a positive review of the podcast
wherever you download your review will
help others find the show so they can
enjoy it too on the shaping fire website
you can also subscribe to the Weekly
Newsletter for insights into the latest
Cannabis News and product reviews on the
shaping fire website you will also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
for information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango
los.com
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot shaping
fire.com to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host Shango Los