[Music]
British science fiction writer Arthur C
Clarke is known for saying any
sufficiently advanced technology is
indistinguishable from magic
that's how I've always felt about my car
I don't particularly know much about how
my car runs other than the basics sure I
do maintenance but what really goes on
under the hood
might as well be magic to me after
beginning to study soil life in the
rhizosphere in depth I realized that I
had that same regard for water I've
always just kind of watered my plants
without really knowing what was going on
under the hood I had other stuff I had
to do so I just added water and went
about my other business in its own way -
water is indistinguishable from magic
during today's episode we're going to
talk about what water is and where it
comes from water harvesting the
responsibility that water has inside the
pot some thoughts on water quality and
finally some best practices for actually
watering your plants and listening to
the plant telling you her needs if you
want to learn about cannabis health
business and technique efficiently and
with good cheer I encourage you to
subscribe to our newsletter will send
you new podcast episodes as they come
out delivered right to your inbox along
with commentary and a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos - don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates - make
sure you don't miss an episode
also we giveaway very cool prizes to
folks who sign up to really exceed the
newsletter there's nothing else you need
to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shaping fire com2
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into this month's and all future
and newsletter prize drawings if your
company budgeted thousands of dollars
for cannabis conventions in 2020 which
are all now canceled I invite you to
consider moving your marketing
investment to shaping fire for only a
fraction of what it would cost you to
attend just one convention you can
advertise for nearly a year on shaping
fire it has been a busy couple weeks as
other companies have reached out to
shaping fire because their whole year of
customer outreach events was just
cancelled and now they are scrambling
for new ways to reach their customers
the audience for shaping fire is made up
of curious kin
enthusiasts entrepreneurs and home
growers and you can reach them for less
than the price of a postcard each email
hotspot at shaping fire calm to find out
more you are listening to shaping fire
and I'm your host Shango lows today my
guest is geologist and living soil
expert Leighton Morrison Lane has been a
lifelong enthusiast of both aquaponics
and living soil his obsession with
biosphere 2 led him to set up an
aquaculture system with the Rodale
Institute Leighton worked with
world-renowned soil biologist dr. Elaine
Ingham blending his aquaculture
byproducts with traditional compost and
worm castings
to prove that natural inputs could
effectively replace synthetics and
cultivation leighton currently as
founder of kingdom aquaponics and
invented their line of living compost
and compost tea products Leighton is a
sought-after speaker and co-founder of
the series of traveling science of
organic regenerative cannabis
cultivation conferences Leighton was
recently here for episode 54 to talk
about soil is geological origins and how
to mirror the layers of the earth in
your container garden for optimum
microbe life and water drainage after
the recording late and I talked at
length about water and this episode
started to form in my mind I decided
with the outdoor growing season coming
up fast an in-depth discussion of water
would be in order so we scheduled a
second episode together pretty quickly
and today we offer it to you welcome to
the show Leighton hey Shango great to be
back my friend great yeah really happy
to have you back and again so
surprisingly soon I'm sorry I missed my
recent trip down there because we're all
in quarantine but I'll look forward to
seeing you down there and in Southern
California when I can so so let's get
right into it you know one of the things
that that everybody including me really
liked about the last time you're on the
show is that you're not afraid to talk
in geological terms which when you're
talking about soil is really informative
and I figured you know let's jump right
into the deep end of the pool this time
again and start with a you know start
with a meta question that you know we
all are so concerned and aware of the
quality of our water
and how much water that we are feeding
our plants and making sure we use clean
water for compost teas and everything
dude where did water come from
that's definitely jumping into the tape
all right there's two trains of thought
on that one train and that which has
been pretty much typical of science if
up until recently and that was it was
came from comets so it was not an
originally here I mean we know somewhat
of how the planets are formed we talked
about that last time so you know the
surface of the earth was molten rock so
you know how does water stay on molten
rock right so basically the theory up
until recently was that it all came from
comets and we know for sure that there
is a tremendous asteroid belt that has
just limitless comments that are all
water that are trapped up now some other
geophysicists are starting to say that
now no no it came from a material called
carbonaceous chondrite all right and
it's it's one of the earliest known
minerals it generally considered an
asteroid but it the ironic thing is that
it has about 20% mineral content of
water in a solid form that's not ice it
gets it gets complicated alright so the
theory this this theory is that no no no
the water was always here in the for
formed in the rocks it just took up the
heating process and then the cooling
process for that to be set free and to
rebonding to h2o as we know water today
so I mean again science will probably
come up with with more answers for this
as time progresses but I mean science is
so amazing just enough in the few years
that I've known you look what's happened
to you know like the biological kingdoms
have been broken up diatoms are now into
thrown into the algae kingdom flageolets
are now thrown into the algae kingdom
and they're probably all going to shift
again so it's an interesting time to be
alive and
because we have such incredibly powerful
tools that we never used to have even
five years ago so in that regard it's
it's pretty interesting I still got to
believe that that because of the volume
of water on our planet that there was
some kind of terrestrial impacts that
that were brought caused by comets that
brought in that that you know huge mass
amounts of ice and while I don't you
know I'm not a scientist of that sort
but it could also appear to me that it
could be both right that there that the
water came from comets and then also I
mean you just totally blow my blew my
mind that there could be deposits of
water that was solid that was not ice
I'm like oh god I need to go look up the
Wikipedia on that too even you know that
you know not on my show but that is
another buddies science show in and of
itself trying to understand that yeah I
mean it's it's really cool I mean it's
so it's so bizarre that most of the
metals in this in these you know
chondrites are actually in a silicate
oxidate and sulfides form
they're not even metal so that shows you
you know that there's some science here
that we haven't gotten to yet that will
probably answer some of these questions
in better detail as you know we learn
more and more about it but I agree my
gut feeling it was is was it was a
combination of both to answer the
question partly yeah cool so so let's
let's let's bring us up multiple
billions of years to the now and get a
little more grounded in in how water and
how we're using it today so what is the
role of freshwater in this in the soil
of our pots and fields you know I think
that a lot of us including me tend to
take water for granted it's like well
you put the water in and it causes some
life and then we got some plants and if
my plants droop add more water and
that's pretty much like as much as most
of us know but but but I I know from
talking with you that there are act as
there's actual jobs that water has in
the raizou sphere and I think we'd all
be interested in about so
so please wait into that all right water
is the universal solvent in in terms of
pH if we have a acid or a base they do
different things they attract different
minerals to them and and in the periodic
table these elements are available in
different peach ph's some are available
only in low pH some are available in
high pH generally most of these elements
are available in the middle we call
neutral water so understanding that
water is an acid I'm gonna take you I'm
going to take you back to nuclear
science when they originally started
building nuclear reactors to generate
power the first thing that they noticed
was that they would have mineralization
occurring on the rods and the rods would
get thicker and thicker as the minerals
came out of solution and attached
themselves to these rods now if two rods
touch G's touched each other yeah that's
it that's called a meltdown that nothing
good comes from that so they quickly
realized that they could not use regular
spring water they needed to do a scrub a
mineral scrub of the water so then came
reverse osmosis and to understand in
Reverse must Moses technology it's
essentially like putting water in a
rubber glove and squeezing it through
the pores of the rubber how deep is that
dude yeah I think that's just like a
ridiculous level of filtration is the
idea right yeah you're basically
stripping it down to h2o nothing else is
coming through it and again water is the
universal solvent so he eats everything
it can either preserve it or it can eat
it so it's really a unique element in so
many ways not to mention you can't live
without it no life would be created if
we did not have water everything has
water in it every water is the
commonality of all forms of life on this
planet
so in that regards if you take water and
you squeeze it to a rubber glove and you
get just aged
- OH as soon as that water comes in
contact with anything it's gonna
automatically start pulling stuff off of
it because it's it's a it's a solvent
it's does its essence is to transport
nutrients minerals vitamins throughout
the body throughout the plant throughout
the soil system and into the microbes
everything everything has to have water
as as a base for life so it's it's it's
really interesting that the deeper you
dive down that rabbit hole
- just think that this one element this
one thing is the foundation of all life
so so it's role in the soil then is
essentially to what be be a grabber and
a mover it's very existence makes sure
that I don't know nutrition and other
things in the rhizosphere
are not sedentary and move around in a
lot of the ways that I consider like
mycelium networks water is its own kind
of movement network absolutely because
it's a solvent and it's a transporter
and it can release these minerals and
vitamins
consider it a taxicab you know or I love
your you know comparison to you know the
mycorrhizae or saprophytic it's moving
one thing to other places and allowing
whatever is necessary to be brought to
the table um in all life forms is the
only I guess I'll say engine to move the
water gravity so that when we water the
water starts at the top of the soil and
then it gravity is pulling it down until
I guess that it becomes so such a small
amount that it no longer there's no
longer a significant gravitational pull
and then it just stops or even after
water comes to rest does it still have a
tendency to move great question
so we know water has a unique ability to
be in a liquid gas or solid so you
missed one thing called evaporation hmm
and also wicking so in the presentation
I did it humble this year at the
conference I put up a slide showing a
bottle of water with red dye in it and
the gentleman dipped a hemp wick into
the one bottle that was full all the way
down till it got wet you know right to
his top of his fingers and then he
pulled the wick out and stuff that wick
into the bottle that was empty next to
it and what happened over the course of
48 hours was to equal out so that's
water moving against gravity it's going
up the string over and down so water has
some really unique properties that are
very different from pretty much anything
any other element on this planet because
again it can be liquid solid or gas so
in evaporation which is really cool the
water is getting purified it's getting
distilled so the Sun comes out
evaporates the water off the ocean and
desalinate sit and that h2o in a gaseous
form goes up into the up into the
atmosphere it gets cold and it starts to
collect together and to form clouds and
then those clouds get you know very very
dense and compacted to the point where
those molecules start to touch each
other and they start to form raindrops
and then they come back to earth pure
and clean until air pollution right now
acid rain and alkaline rain and all
these other problems with with with the
earth cleaning and cleansing the water
so with with my originally suggesting
that gravity just pulls the water down
in our pots and fields and you now
adding evaporation and wicking is it
possible that after I water and the
water finds its way down to the bottom
of the pot that the dryness of the pot
above it
wick the water back up and is it
possible that during the warmth of the
day the water could evaporate up into
the upper layers of the pot without
leaving the container well remember
that's why we got into that soil system
yeah because the a horizon is the heart
and lungs is the ability for water to
wick from lower back up so without that
if you were just organic matter the
answer is no because you don't have that
tight pore space that's required to
allow wicking to occur so come back to
you know the last podcast we talked
about the horizons and how critical they
are to function in in a natural system
because that's exactly what they do that
the surface dries out due to the Sun and
the wind and naturally because of the
soil system was was built through
geological time it allows that migration
not that wicking to happen and provide
pull the moisture from down deep perhaps
groundwater even lower to be wycked
up into the soil profiles to give the
the surface plants the moisture that
they need Wow all right so so now I have
a better understanding that that water
is not going just in one direction it's
actually moving around based on on
wicking the composition of the soil you
know day and night heat and so so now I
guess this is how it explains to me how
that taxi cab service really works
because as water is being pushed and
pulled in all these different directions
it becomes a vehicle for all these other
nutrients that that since water is
grabby and moves the water is going by
these nutrients that's of solvent it
grabs these nutrients and then it's
pushed and pulled all around the pot and
that's how it's moving around is that is
that a reasonable way to describe it
that's spot on
that's fought on I think think about um
bubble hash right water is the solvent
it's the universal ultimate
all it does everything from breaking
things down to to preventing them from
breaking down if you look at the pH in
the bogs up in Russia where we find
those mammoths that are completely
mummified the reason they were mummified
they were in water but the reason they
were mummified was because of the pH not
the water because then you look at water
at swamps where it's just rotting trees
and and and roots and everything else
down and turning it into organic matter
so it's really again a very very cool
element and it's something to you could
ponder some pretty long and hard about
you know the power of water so the last
question I want to ask you before we
before we start moving on to our first
break is that you know one of the things
that I've realized from being primarily
an outdoor grower is that when I take my
pots at the end of the season and I
throw them in the garage and you know
just just for storage and then when I
bring them out in the spring they're
very dry and and then when I add water
to them there's like you know the breath
of life some sunshine and some water
changes the soil and and granted after
hearing you at the regenerative
conference in Michigan last year I
realized I should no longer be putting
my pots you know in the garage over the
winter I should just let them be outside
let them go through the full year cycle
and then when I come back in the spring
you know they've like totally gone feral
right there's there's there's more worms
and more life and just more everything
in them and I'm like oh great well I'm
just gonna put a little hole in it and
put my start into it and and off they go
on gangbusters but I think that a lot of
folks you know keep their pots like I
used to where we put them in the barn or
whatever and they they kind of fall
asleep right I always kind of think
about it as the soils a hibernating
right and so I know though that a lot of
the constituents of the soil wake up
when we add a little bit of
warmth from the sunshine and and and
some water what does water due to a
dehydrated raizou sphere that brings it
back I'm great question alright so look
at it like this the the reason the
Paco's hydrophobic is because the
bacteria that's colonized on the surface
of the the potting mix or the organic
matter or the sand silt clay whatever it
is cysts so they find themselves in a
hostile environment they do not want to
die so they basically create a wax
coating around the outside of them and
that's why when I did some work way back
when it and down in University of
Arizona I would always be so intrigued
at how soil could float I took grab a
handful of soil throw it in a bucket of
water and it would float and the reason
was because of the biology the bacteria
had insisted and now because it's wax
coating on their outside of it it
basically can't sink it can't it can't
it can't open up and dissolve into
solution so the real answer is that
that's driven by the bacteria and and
the other biology because it has cysts
it and we know for sure that that these
cysts whether they're bacteria protozoa
can live in ice for hundreds of
thousands of years maybe more and we
also know that pretty much life came
from comets and so those comets were
floating around in nothingness for who
knows how long and then come into the
Earth's atmosphere heat up like you said
warm up and that ice melts and all of a
sudden all of those microbes come back
to life again because they've found
themselves in an environment that
supports them and allows them to grow
and I love the fact that you listen to
me and keep your pots outside because
what's happening is in those seasons you
notice there's definitely some ice
forming in there as the temperature gets
colder
so that's forming little water pockets
trapped in that soil mix and then as the
temperature warms up outside things
slowly come back to life so you're not
taking this pot that's completely dried
out dumping water on it and hoping that
the water starts to sink in here it's
gonna take you you know days to get
those to recharge when when you're
allowing them to do naturally in
overwintering outside especially if you
cover them with hay or leaves they're
gonna be just gangbusters ready to go by
the time you get out there with your
with your seedlings so yeah you're
preventing you're preventing life to be
so harsh that the biology has to
completely lock itself up and then take
days to come back to life so that that
idea that all of the life in the pot
when it dries out gets this waxy
exterior is like super interesting to me
you know I when you said that they they
they make themselves become cysts I'm
picturing all of the of the bacteria and
the my coryza and the you know wild
variety of microbes and I don't know
maybe all the living things turn
themselves into cysts and they make this
waxy exterior so that they can preserve
themselves until the you know the bad
conditions are gone so then we add water
to them and some warmth and sunshine
what is the process of them getting rid
of this waxy this this waxy outer shell
is it do they like come out of them like
we imagine a baby chick coming out of an
egg or is it when enough water goes past
them the water acts as a solvent and
breaks down the waxy exterior and says
you know hey all you you know living
forms inside these cysts I'm going to
remove your winter coat for you or
you're dehydrated a dehydration coat for
you and and then they're free or do they
initiate it from within the cyst that is
a great question my friend first of all
let's let's correct one thing
mycorrhizae don't cysts they spoil eight
or so they Creek they create spores so
it's a little different your anymore
into sexual reproduction as far as
fungal going into a suspended state of
animation whereas the bacteria and the
biology do actually sister or the
protozoa actually do sis top and and
nematode cysts as well I'm glad you made
that correction in me dude because I've
been I have been you know speaking in a
way that suggests that spores were cysts
and I didn't realize that they were not
in that family no and you know it's
really cool um and I've talked about
this before but what is occurring inside
that spore there's a whole nother
universe I mean a universe of things
that we don't know how they're how
they're alive they're too small for us
to study we don't understand how it's
like an egg that naturally hatches when
the right environment is allowed or
happens to occurs so yeah I've done some
neat work with my buddy afferent about
you know trying to understand more about
what is going on inside of a spore
versus what's going on inside of a cyst
so to answer your question insists the
the thought is that the the organism has
the components stored in what it's
called their pantry which is part of the
oregano Lowe's I don't want to go too
deep on the parts of a cell or a
bacteria but I'm pretty much it's
storing the materials necessary to
create that coating around the outside
of it so the real mystery is is the
water what's eating the coating away or
is the water soluble izing the coating
so that the cell can pull it back in and
store it for the next time it needs it
or is it kind of melt away and a cell as
it starts to come alive starts
reproducing that and stores it in his
pantry for the next time that it needs
to sis top so that's something that that
we science is going to need to work on
to get a better understand
is it just something that it produces is
it something that it stores or is it a
combination perhaps of both but water
definitely good water and warmth will
definitely allow that bacteria to come
out of cysts form Wow all right so I'm
sure that there are folks who are
listening who now know that they're
gonna leave their pots outside over
winter but that there's probably also
people who are in the situation that I
was in last year when I learned it from
you who had already you know put all
their their fabric pots in the barn you
know and so is there a best practice for
waking up a pot that has gone to spores
ation and cessation was there a best way
to wake it all up oh yeah absolutely
just bring it outside you're gonna get
you're gonna get do you're gonna get
condensation you're gonna get cool at
night warm during the day in the
sunlight so that's that's a gentle a
gentle way to wake in it to pull it out
in spring when you have your starts
ready to go now you're shocking
everything you're shocking your plant
you're shocking the natural you know
order of systems in that soil system so
yeah I would just bring them out you
know a couple weeks early before you
want to plant them if you did store them
and just let them you know sit in the
Sun and and you know don't hesitate to
give a little water but know that at
night you're gonna get do and that
they're gonna gently wake up and and
then they'll be ready for you to plant
instead of trying to force the plant
into them as far as adding the water to
them to kind of trying to help them
jump-start so you don't have to wait for
the rain water do we want to just like
drench the hell out of them and do we
want to use just our regular water or is
this a great opportunity for us to be
using a compost tea instead of a
straight water well I don't know as I'd
I'd put the energy into making a compost
tea because basically it's gonna run off
and I wouldn't I wouldn't want to
overwater it because now you're now
you're washing the nutrients remember
water is the ultimate solvent so it's
gonna be starting to pull things that
you want to stay in that soil system out
so again I you know if if the mistake is
made and they're put into a basement or
garage or a barn then just put them
outside for a couple weeks before and
you're probably not gonna even have to
water them I mean I'm not telling you
not to water them but don't overwater
them because then you're just stripping
stripping things that you want to keep
right on it actually kind of reminds me
of when I had my surgery back in college
and they gave me a general anesthetic
and as they were bringing me out they
were giving me little sips of water
right they weren't giving me lots of
water they were just getting me a little
bit of water to you know get my system
you know acclimated and going so now I'm
thinking like oh you know same thing
with pots you don't want to like just
drown the pot but go ahead and give your
your depending on the size of the pot
give it a couple drinks you know over
the first three days to slowly prime the
pump
absolutely and another thing you can do
too is put all the pots in a you know in
a big square and cover them with a tarp
what the tarps going to do is it's going
to heat up from the sunlight and it's
gonna wick water up through the bottom
and condensate on the surface on the
underside of that tarp so you're you're
pulling you're pulling moisture up
through the bottom of the pot naturally
you're hitting it with this you know
gentle misting that's occurring on the
inside of the tarp you know and so now
you've generally just you've just you've
used nature to you know evaporate and
pump the water up into the pot from the
bottom and then drop it down and drop
micro droplets from the top so I might
be even better way to you know really
get them going if you need to quickly
there we go I knew I would squeeze one
more best practice out of you before
commercial dude all right so let's go
ahead and take our first short break and
be right back you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is soil
biologist Leighton Morrison pre-rolls
have come a long way since the early
days of normalization when you choose
Saints joints you are smoking all flower
top-shelf pre-rolls with
Europeans that will sculpt your high in
a way that dry old pre-rolls just can
whereas most brands release pre-rolls as
an afterthought for the last five years
Saints joints has focused on their line
of exotic curated joints and while some
companies just chase the hype strains
Saints joints goes deeper searching out
hard-to-find strains unexpected crosses
and nearly forgotten land races and
classics and some hype ones too not only
does a joint from Saints Smoke
incredibly well they have fine-tuned
every step of the process so you don't
get runs in the paper the joint is just
the right density to have a nice pull
and that joint stays lit even if you get
a bit chatty Saints joins boxes are
works of art and will spark conversation
when you pull them out at parties Saints
award winning boxes change with every
release feature edgy outsider art and
often raise awareness of important
issues like equal rights Saints boxes
are so desired that many collect them
and display them in their homes ask your
bud tender for Saints joints and have a
premium joint experience now if you are
a licensed cannabis cultivators I have
an extra message for you
Saints is looking for partners in legal
cannabis States to expand the
availability of the Saints joints brand
do you grow exceptional cannabis flower
but are less excited bottle the effort
cost and risk of launching your own
brand Saints joints may be just the
partner you are looking for already
established in California Washington and
Oklahoma and recognized by Entrepreneur
Magazine and green entrepreneur as a
cannabis industry leader the Saints
joints brand will set you apart in your
home market the best thing I can
recommend is for you to visit their
Instagram Saints joints and look at
their patented drawer design boxes
become that brand everyone is talking
about without having to build it from
scratch
check out the Instagram at Saints joints
and then visit Saints joints calm to
find out more there are lots of good
seed makers out there every once in a
while someone becomes legendary the
Mendocino California cannabis breeder
called mandelbrot is one of these people
Mandelbrot was also known as Roz truth
and his cultivars are known as the
foundation for the Emerald triangles
world-famous gasoline scented derping
profile back in the day when it was
really hard to find quality genetics and
education
Mandelbrot was advocating for organic
growing techniques and providing
exceptional seeds that would sell out as
soon as they hit the shelves
Mandelbrot lived too short of a life
dying in 2015 but while he was with us
he created several connoisseur level
cannabis masterpieces like oil spill the
truth and royal cush no matter if you
approach growing cannabis more as a
toker or a breeder you will find
something that delights you in
Mandelbrot selections because while some
strains are better to grow or to smoke
Mandelbrot's creations excel in every
category and that's why people keep
talking about them even today emerald
mountain legacy continues the roz truth
tradition by preserving these coveted
genetics for future generations
unchanged as they were originally
created in the mid 2000s emerald
mountain legacy also creates tasteful
modern crosses to Mandelbrot's classics
these lines work by Mandelbrot's brother
ben further their family's genetics and
a spirit that Mandelbrot would have
approved of check out the emerald
mountain legacy Instagram and web site
to see photos of these plants and learn
more about Mandelbrot and his infamous
strains emerald mountain legacy seeds
are available online from seed banks and
distributors including labyrinth seed
company the regenerative seed company
and pure sativa emerald mountain legacy
keeping Mandelbrot's legacy alive in
times like these when so many cannabis
companies are growing their flower in
gigantic warehouses and fields using
synthetic nutrients it is good to know
that there are authentic California
heritage growers using natural farming
techniques and sunshine to cultivate
cannabis flowers for you California has
produced the best cannabis in the world
for generations and the idea that
massively scaled industrial cannabis
production can provide the same quality
a small batch lovingly cultivated
flowers is just silly moon time
medicinals is located in Humboldt County
on the lush South Fork of the eel River
watershed in the epicenter of the
American cannabis Heartland moon time
medicinals grow
under the bright California Sun in
greenhouses using only natural farming
techniques like Google culture compost
teas whole food fertilisers and
fermented plant juices every part of
their growing process plays its own part
in nature and nothing synthetic is
injected into the process the result is
big beautiful canvas flowers with
wide-ranging terpene profiles that taste
like great cannabis should if you live
in California ask your bud tender for
moon time medicinals and visit moon time
medicinals on the web and instagram moon
time medicinals is also available as
part of the Redwood roots family moon
times whole flowers appear in Redwood
roots curated joint packs alongside
other heritage cannabis cultivators like
lady sativa Farm Ridgeline farms and
others moon time medicinals top-shelf
cannabis grown in harmony with nature
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire
I'm your host Shingo Lowe's and our
guest today is soil biologist Leighton
Morrison so if you're still with us
after making it through our metaphor set
where we talked all about where water
comes from and what its job is in the
second set we're gonna talk about more
things that actually are gonna be useful
in your cultivation process and we're
gonna start by talking about sourcing of
water because there's a lot of different
places that you can get water of varying
qualities and we want to make sure that
you understand what your options are
when choosing where to get your water so
Leighton let's start talking about a
little bit about water tests you know I
know that you know decoding a water test
could be an entire show in and of itself
and that's not what we're doing today
but for most people they know that they
should get a water test so that they
know what's in their aquifer or city
water or the rainfall near their house
or their their your runoff or whatever
so people generally know that they
should get one and and and I've also
kind of have the belief that most waters
are usable but I'd like you to talk a
little bit about
red flags in a water test that have got
to be taken care of for you to be able
to successfully grow a cannabis plant
and talk a little bit about pH as well
okay
again nice rabbit hole let's let's start
with the understanding of how water
moves under the ground okay so everyone
think so I drill a well and I got well
water I got great water in the most
cases that's true but then you have to
start thinking about well where I
drilled my well I've basically created a
opening in the earth that allows the
surface water and groundwater to travel
down into the aquifer so in many ways
you've actually exposed that aquifer to
things that you weren't supposed to Wow
Sokka you could contaminate your own
aquifer during the drilling process it's
happened on Long Island and they drilled
these wells in the middle of the potato
fields and then they fertilize the hell
out of the fields and everybody got
cancer so you know that's just one case
of it and I've I've actually had been
fortunate enough to work with a
gentleman who does groundwater mapping
for basically Superfund sites where they
have these you know horribly toxic
chemicals that are in solution are
moving the water is transporting them
and they're trying to figure out how bad
it is
how deep and how heavy the concentration
is and he basically made an earth rubber
so he made a rubber that is can be as
long as you want it to be and he's
drilled down you know thousands of feet
and it's one contiguous rubber and
basically to what he does is he takes
this he drills a hole and then he based
on that hole he's already prefabricated
this this rubber that he drops into the
hole and fills up with water and as the
water goes in to the rubber it pushes it
all the way down to the bottom of the
hole now the cool thing is on the
outside of that rubber is a special
coating
that turns colors based on what chemical
or compound it comes in contact with so
by drilling a series of holes he can see
which way things are migrating or not
migrating and dot is critical because
you know these sites that have to be
cleaned up they need to know where where
where do you start cleaning up which way
is the water transporting these these
you know horrible chemicals so now you
start to understand that even water
traveling uphill this is just this - I
love this Mount Lemmon in Arizona you
can go travel through five distinct
climates or I want to call succession
airy plant systems from the base your
start at the bottom of the mountain
you're in a desert I mean it's hot 110
degrees very little growth or our plant
life you drive for you know a couple not
an hour maybe 40 minutes now you're up
into these you know the big cactuses the
big three-prong cactuses you see in the
old westerns now you're heavily and
surrounded by them and you've got
leather cactuses and more scrub and sage
and then you move up into now you've got
some some shrubs some deciduous plants
and then move in a little bit further
you're getting into
not just seed you as trees and then
finally at the top of Mount Lemmon
you're in the conifers and it's snow
there's snow on the ground the middle of
summer
interestingly enough that as the aquifer
has gone down the has dropped in levels
down in the desert near Tucson and
between Tucson and Phoenix because all
the water that's been pulled out of it
it has changed the hydrology and now
there's the water is not seeping out at
the top of the mountain like it used to
um there were rivers coming down this
mountain so how the hell did the water
get from the desert where there is no
water to the top of that mountain to the
point where it created streams and
rivers coming down that's pressure
that's that's geology so so the weight
of the earth around it is actually
squeezing that water all the way up to
the top of that mountain and because
that mountain has
a you know a thinner layer because of
geological tectonic plate movements the
water is allowed to squeeze out of that
so in understanding you know how water
moves in aquifers and in the ground it's
critical to do your homework where is my
water coming from another great example
this is Cape Cod Cape Cod's a sandbar
alright it was formed back when the
glaciers were present and as they
receded they pushed all this dumped all
of this glacial till out into the ocean
and created Cape Cod right well
obviously there would be no aquifer in
Cape Cod right not true there's a river
coming out of the groundwater in
Barnstable and that this is a big river
I mean this is no joke one of my good
friends
Keith Wilder where I collect my fish
frost from the oldest trout farm in
America that trout farm was set up in
that spot because of how incredibly pure
that water was and how much of it was
just bubbling up out of the ground I
mean you walk around his property and
you can see water bubbling up out of the
ground through the million-dollar
question is is it fresh the water
actually comes from Canada North New
York and parts of Vermont and it
actually believe it or not it's it's
it's wonderful water the interesting
thing is it's high in nitrate so we'd
have to get along back to aquatic
biology and understanding how organic
nitrogen an organic nitrogen is not in
the usable form but with the
introduction of bacteria specifically
nitrifying I drove actor it'll convert
it to ammonia and then the ammonia
converts tonight right and then the mutt
the nitrite converts to nitrate now
nitrate is harmless to plants and
animals and we can actually use it
whereas nitrite can be toxic and heavy
concentrations so again he's got all of
the aquatic organisms because he's an
aquaculture facility he grows a
tremendous amount of biomass of
so that there he naturally has the
protection against the nitrites and and
after his post water treated the
nitrites are gone they've been
completely morphed into nitrate so he's
actually doing the water to system a
favor by cleaning it with his fish
before it's released into the streams
and into the swamps around him so late
so then let's let's let's bring this on
back home to to the water test so I
think that when you when you started
this this Butte this super interesting
story I think you were starting with you
got to know your waters from for your
water tests and and the idea that the
earth was pressing down on the
groundwater enough to make it go up the
mountain and flow down that super-badass
so so what are the chemicals that if
somebody sees in their water test coming
out of their aquifer that they should
raise a flag and go oh this may not be a
good place for me to cultivate cannabis
yeah cannabis is an accumulator so
anything that's being transported the
water will accumulate in your plant and
that's a problem so backing it up most
water tests are designed to sell you
filters so you really need to know where
you're sending your water test
I recommend micro macro international
Gretchen and her crew of scientists are
there to actually test for minerals
they're not they're not or you know
pesticides residues and toxics heavy
metals all that most water companies or
places that you send for your water
tests short of the ones that the well
companies work with I don't recommend
you send it to them because they're
gonna send some guy out there to sell
you a filter so you know they're not
they're not they're not finding the
toxins those are those are too expensive
to test for and most people don't test
for them well water is a little
different that it's because it's
considered a potable water they're a
little bit tighter on making sure that
they are testing much more stringent
tests
but if you really want to know what the
heck's going on you send it down to
someone like you know macro micro
Gretchen it and she'll tell you exactly
what's going in your water but again you
have to think about all right where is
that water coming from if you're if
you're south of an industrial park or
potentially the water is coming through
there
you want to know and you know there are
a lot of country or a lot of states and
counties have done groundwater migration
studies they're very expensive to do but
especially around polluted areas they've
been forced to map the groundwater so I
would recommend that you reach out to
your local authority and try to find out
hey did anybody map the groundwater and
again the groundwater is just as
important as the aquifer itself and the
groundwater because it's traveling by a
pipe that someone drilled a hole and
down to get down to the aquifer there
were letting all of that potential
toxins down in there now they might not
be getting as much of it because as that
water migrates down that shaft there is
a current in that aquifer so it could be
transporting those toxins away from
their pump when they're not using it of
course when they're pulling water
they're gonna get a little bit a little
bit of it up the pipe that they're
drinking out of but for the most part
anything that's coming down the sides of
that shaft are gonna are gonna get
pushed into the current so imagine you
know you throw a tennis ball in the
ocean well is it go is that is the ball
getting pulled out with the tide or is
it is it getting pushed up against the
shore same thing is happening on the
groundwater level as well as the aquifer
level so you really got to know your
business as far as you know if you're if
you're going to rely on you know the
well to to water your cannabis if you're
in a industrial area like down in LA or
San Francisco or San Diego you've got to
be really careful I would almost tend to
say you're better off to use calm water
and tie up the chloramine then you are
to trust the well unless you've done
your homework and or sense it off to get
a real hardcore water test
analysis right I'm cool so so let's hold
off on the chloramine discussion first
sec because we're gonna get to that in a
little bit but um so I'm starting to
kind of like tease out three different
threads here as far as like how we would
be using the water test so so far we've
been kind of discussing the kind of
research you're gonna want to do before
you buy a parcel to grow you know either
either a THC cannabis or hemp on so if
you're gonna be growing cannabis sativa
do your homework about how the water
moves and where the water is moving from
before you buy your parcel because
cannabis is an accumulator and you could
end up growing plants that of God you
know arsenic or something in them and
and you don't want to deal with that so
so do your homework first before you buy
then then there's a second thread which
is lots of folks who are growing either
commercial or for themselves and and
they're already on their parcel and so
you know chances are a lot of these
people would already know if their water
was contaminated and hopefully it's not
and so they they already know that their
water is good enough to grow and then
and then there's the third category
which are people who are on city water
and you know unless you are you know
living in kind of like a failed water
system like a Flint Michigan or
something generally I would think that
most of the city waters are you know
while while maybe not epically good
they're at least passable for pouring on
to our cannabis plants I hope that's the
case and so then that kind of leaves the
Bugaboo of pH because any three of those
categories you could be dealing with
water that pH is poorly for growing
cannabis so so address that specifically
like I know that they like there's so
lots of products on the market to pH up
or pH down which are like you know I
generally consider them a hassle to have
to equalise you know all the all the
water that I'm going to be offering the
plants
how far away from optimum is too far to
be doing that all the time and you just
need to find a different source like
like how far from optimum is too far
would you say all right turn the scale
pH is logarithmic so say you have a pH
of 6 6 1 is 10 times greater than 6 6 2
is now 10 times greater than 6 1 so it's
logarithmic so people don't get that
that there's like huge differences
between 6 &amp; 8 I mean it's it's
monumental 8 is considered too much it's
too alkaline for plants to grow there
are some some some some plants that can
get away with it Pete for one but for
the most part it's the majority of
plants cannot tolerate about pH above 8
or below I think it's like 4 or 5 4
point 5 so again there are some plants
that can tolerate that but they're few
and far between so the vast majority of
plants we want to keep in that neutral
zone and that's where they're gonna do
great now another thing to take into
consideration is that the plant can
adjust pH in the rouser we know this
because the plant will excrete it
exudate a certain type of bacteria will
grow out and that bacteria is job is to
mine this mineral or that mineral and it
might be slightly off of the pH that the
plant or the soil has present so by by
adjusting the the specific bacteria that
it wants to grow out it can adjust the
pH to allow that mineral to be mined and
brought back to the plant through
through the nutrient cycling system the
protozoa eating the bacteria etc so
those are your outside parameters of pH
and and that will allow a plant to grow
but also something to take into
consideration is as you pour that water
on the soil and that water moves
the soil you're adjusting the pH I've
done a tremendous amount of work with
people that have high pH soils or low pH
soils and they need to get them adjusted
and the way I generally do that is with
compost you know I can get compost it's
more acid or more base and so I just
tell them that right you know you're
gonna have to either tail this in or
you're gonna have to dig a hole and then
blend the existing soil with this
compost and then that will equal out so
I you it's kind of like if you take a
soil system of six and a compost of
eight and you mix them fifty-fifty
equally you will end up with a pH of
seven that that works because of these
because these numbers are logarithmic so
that's something to keep in mind now as
far as as far as the the water systems
are concerned
generally speaking city waters are safe
they are forced to test for heavy metals
and pesticides the the one place that
they get a little bit problematic is
that nitrogen cycle where you have the
ammonia that they use to mix with
chloramine our Klara chlorine and
ammonia mixed together and make
chloramine so if you have a high level
of nitrogen nitrogen I trow backer or
nitrogen fixing biology you're gonna
start that process of breaking that
organic matter say the little tiny leaf
or you know something that got pulled
into the pipe from the reservoir that is
going to actually start to morph out
start to pull off the ammonia leave the
chlorine in place and then convert the
ammonia to nitrite and then tonight
trait so really depends on where you are
in the pipeline and to how long or what
what level of biology got into the
system to determine you know you know
whether you're drinking nitrite water or
nitrate water so that's that's the only
concern I have with with city water for
plants now human consumption will get
that's another hole right yeah totally
so let's continue talking about city
water because that's where I was gonna
move to next anyway so you know one of
not one of the number one question that
I get from people about their city water
is how to take out the chlorine and
normally I have to explain it on them
like oh well the chlorine is is easy you
just take the you pour your water and
leave it out overnight and the chlorine
off gases and if you want to do it more
quickly you can stir it for a bit or you
can put a bubbler in it and chloramine
it's it's volatile and it goes away very
quickly but then I also have to tell
them I'm like man they don't really use
chlorine as much in public water works
anymore and they're using chloramine
instead and unfortunately we're not able
to just mix that stuff out it's it's not
as volatile and it stays in the water
but I'd like you to go ahead and repeat
the great solution that you offered us
last time on on how to neutralize the
chloramine in your city water yeah no
problem and you know I did want to back
up on one point and you know when you're
using town water or not time water well
water for feeding your cannabis plants
and then you test your cannabis plant
because you're supposed to or you have
to on a commercial scale that cannabis
plants gonna tell you if your water is
bad or not as long as you understand
that you didn't put anything else into
your system and the water was the only
input that you use so that means you
know if you're growing with mineral
salts or something like that the toxins
could have come in that way so you
really now you have to test all these
different things but if you're you know
again it's this is more important in any
suburbia
urban environment than it is in a rural
environment rural environment you're not
gonna have to worry about your water as
much but if if you did use a hemp plant
to test your water I think it's a great
idea because if you're just using water
only that plants gonna tell you if your
waters toxic or not because it's gonna
fail a test for a metal or something
so anyway moving on to tying up
chloramine so chloramine is is basically
chlorine and ammonia so if you can and
ammonia gas is off really
and chlorine gas is off really easy so
all you have to do is break it break the
bond because chloramine is an ionic bond
so it's a really really strong one
pretty much the only thing that can do
that from an electrolysis can but but
more importantly biology and biology
does everything which we know we've
talked about that in the last show so if
you introduce a humate or a humic acid
or even even a good compost tea that's
been concentrated um what that's gonna
do is that's going to get in there and
it's gonna break that molecule apart and
then through aeration it will gas off
and you'll be fine so other than
sometimes you can have what's called a
disinfectant by-product but those will
not hurt plants but they are harmful to
animals and humans so to get to the
nitty-gritty of it somebody who wants to
add some humates to their water it's as
simple as just taking some matured
compost that you may have and putting it
in you know an old nylon or cheesecloth
tying it off and and just dropping it
into your water reservoir right I like
to take it a little bit different path
because you really want to get that
humic acid out of that compost so I
would take the compost I would saturate
it get it really wet and then put it
inside of say an old washcloth or a
towel and and then dump it on the towel
and then wring the towel out as hard as
you can
now you're getting pure humic and pure
folic acid concentrated whereas if you
put the bag in in the bubbler and brew
it you're not going to get that fast of
a release of the things that you really
need the pressure and squeezing really
helps to get what you're looking for out
of out of that compost as fast as
possible
then add that into your brewer and brew
your water but the key again is you need
to brew it you need to move air up
through the water column to help break
off the any of the leftover gases that
are trapped in the water
away from your out of your water column
and into the atmosphere so if that's a
little trick for you yeah that's it that
is a good idea so I know I'm not the
only one who's weighed this in my head
in my early years of personal growing
for my medical I'd be like oh my god
trying to add compost tea to my water
and bubble it in my apartment is such a
pain in the ass and so will you give us
the real breakdown of how necessary it
is I mean it so many people on in
cannabis forums they are totalitarian
right they are you know you you must do
everything perfectly but you know when
it comes to us alone with nobody around
in our garden you know very often people
will cut corners how bad is it really to
use your city water with chloramine to
water your plants I mean clearly it
doesn't kill them because people are
growing plans with city water that's
untreated all the time what are we
actually losing you're losing the
microbial life so that's it I mean we
know that when these things come in
contact with biology and not all of them
you know this was this was the work I
did back at Rodale and I would bring in
some some city water that I had and I
was on the end of a pipe and it was I
mean the chlorine was just so brutal
they just burned your eyes when you
poured a glass of water and I brought
that down to try to do you know side by
side tests at different dilutions to
determine you know what is killing the
biology and it does it definitely
seriously reduces the biology not all of
it but especially the Predators they
take they take the big hit and fungi
takes a big hit the bacteria most of it
can survive but you're gonna lose
diversity for sure so how bad is it to
use it it's fine if you're using salts
if you're using a living soil system and
you got a problem because you're gonna
you're gonna constantly need up the the
biology life in that soil because you
used that chloramine
water and it's not like you're just
watering at once it's like you know
every day or every other day you're
hitting it with more chloramine and more
chlorinated more alarming so so Eve even
if you are only killing 10% of the
biology when you water well if you kill
a varying 10% throughout the entire
summer or throughout your entire cycle
if you're in a tent well you're you know
you're losing a lot and your plant is
living unsupported from the proper
biology agreed you're where you're
losing it is you're losing potency
cannabinoid production terpene
production can of an all production so
you know that's where your that's where
you're losing you're still gonna you're
still gonna get some good weed you're
still gonna be able get high off of it
but you're not gonna be getting what we
call plant potential and if you're
looking for plant potential you really
want to get that plant to give you
everything that it wants to give you
then you shouldn't be using chloramine
water you should figure out another way
you know you can boil it but but now
you're concentrating fluoride you can
use you know go down and buy bottled
water that's probably your easiest way
out of this you know I love compost tea
but you know based on years of
experience traveling the country looking
at people's compost and having them say
oh my god I make the best compost my
compost is amazing and I microscope it
and there's no life so again it's
nutrient rich yeah it's it's great stuff
I'm not knocking your compost but you
didn't make it biologically active and
that's the key so if you're gonna make a
compost tea your goal is to try to get
the biology into the soil with the tea
the the key is the vehicle for getting
living biology advanced current
predators into your soil system and so
if you're brewing with compost that has
no biology in it what are you really
doing well you're getting humic acid and
folic acid but you're not increasing the
biological level in that soil so that's
where that's where it gets hairy when
when you try to talk about hitting full
plant potential that's where you know
you need a microscope or you know a
trusted soil food web source for getting
your microbes tested so you know where
you are
your compost tested to make sure that
you actually have biologically rich
compost before you try to make a tea
with it so you know all these things are
need to be taken into consideration but
if if your goal is just to grow
something to smoke and you're happy with
whatever the plant can produce then
don't stress about all these things just
you know life goes on it this plan is an
amazing durable strong unique plant and
can survive and you know some of the
most harsh conditions on the planet can
throw at it so you know again I think
you need to draw a line and say am I
going for full plant potential do I want
the best this can possibly do then I
gotta get serious about it if I'm just
trying to grow and I don't have time for
all of that
you know these intricacies then I'm just
gonna just add the water and don't
stress or or use town use bottled water
because you know it's not you're gonna
need you know 100 gallons of water if
you get 5 gallon jug it's probably
enough to water your 10 plants you know
for at least a month right yeah and it
and then you can just go and refill that
mmm bottled water up at your local
grocery store
one of the things I like here in Seattle
you know I live on Vashon Island across
the water from Seattle the the the
Seattle Aquarium actually sells their
reverse osmosis water out of a little
spigot on the side of the building we
used to use it all the time when I was
into breeding fish and and so that was
that was cool to be able to get very
cheaply the only reason I point that out
is you know we don't really want to
encourage people to use bottled water as
like buying a new bottle every time I
agree my friend and I should have been
more specific I was talking about those
ones those big jugs that you can do
exactly that you bring them back to the
machine you stick them in there and it
fills it up there was yeah so um but
another thing I do want to mention is
that reverse osmosis as great as it is
it has demineralized water so it's not
particularly good water to grow cannabis
or anything else to consume I mean the
studies that are coming out of the
Middle East right now because everything
is D salad
over there there's a huge iodine iodine
deficiencies in the humans in the
population and they're getting very sick
because they've been drinking this stuff
for years and there's no minerals left
in it so I'd prefer you use spring water
over RO water or if you're going to use
RO water you've got a riad two minerals
back into it it's like RO water is not a
whole food no no no I mean it has its
purpose I mean you know and people do
drink it I mean look in in most
sailboats
they have a little ro underneath the
sink and that's their source of water
and it's fine but you if you live on
that water you are stripping minerals
out of your body because remember this
water is the ultimate universal solvent
so it will actually if it has no
minerals in it and it's stripped and you
drink it it will pull minerals out of
your body so that's that's the other
side you want your water to be
mineralized that's very important for
consumption and for plants too I mean
it's better that you're you're giving
them those those you know trace minerals
cool so let's go on to our third a
fourth of four sources we talked about
city water and we talked about aquifer
water I know that you are particularly
honored for water harvesting as am i I
really only ever think about rainwater
myself but but then I heard you talk
about it and you know you start ticking
off the list of all these different
places water can be harvested so so
let's wade into that pun intended
yeah where are good sources for
capturing water wildcrafting water
alright now we're going back into the
deep end again alright so most people
would be able to identify a wet spot on
their land and it can be at the top of
the land it could be at the bottom of
the land it can be you know a little bog
or an area where the soil is always
moist what that is is that's a artesian
well or a ground water source that the
waters you know losing out of the rocks
so those are one of the areas that I
would I love to start with this whenever
I'm scouting a client's property which
is the first thing I do I'm always
looking for the wet spots and then I can
say okay we have we have a good source
of water that we want to now direct and
manage and harvest so that's one place I
love rain water but you know one of the
coolest things is seeing all these
satellite images of what's going on in
the atmosphere during this coronavirus
and you know I was horrified to see how
bad the air pollution was in the
tri-state which is New York Connecticut
and New Jersey and all of that air was
generally moving northeast up the coast
so you know we all have talked about
acid rain you know back twenty thirty
years ago but no one talks about it now
because it's not a popular topic topic
so if I was in a situation where I
wanted to collect rainwater in my old
state of Massachusetts or Connecticut I
would be a little bit more concerned
about making sure that I filtered it
properly and by filtering and I meant I
mean that I would want to run it through
other accumulator plants the hemp is a
great one but there's plenty of other
ones there's all kinds of aquatic plants
that do accumulation or clean the water
so that so there's a little bit of a
different spin that if you you should
know your atmosphere you know like the
small coming out of LA blowing up into
the valley like I would not want to
harvest water up there without purifying
it or having the having the water have a
time to to go through the root systems
of plants that would are known to clean
the water so those are two sources and
then the other thing is that everyone
collecting rainwater you know I love
these you know cisterns outside people's
houses and that all the gutters go in
there and that's great the only problem
with that is you've collected the
rainwater during the time you don't need
it but you're gonna run out of it real
quick when you start using it and it's
not raining anymore so beyond that I'd
you know set up your cistern for sure
you know bigger the better but where the
water comes out
of your cistern when it's full that's
where you really want to get serious now
you want to have a swale going through
your property you know obviously you got
to take topography into consideration
and if your perfectly flat
it doesn't matter there's still a slight
pitch to it you just have to get out
there with a laser level or a hand level
and figure out where that pitch is and
build a swale and better yet a bioswale
so you take a gentle channel and you
fill it with chips and then you've
covered with a little bit of dirt and
then you plant it and what those chips
do is they slowly suck all that water up
and during during the rainy season and
then as the as the rain stops coming and
the soil starts to dry out they wick
that back into the soil system like we
talked about earlier on so basically one
of the coolest things that I've worked
on was where we dug a well a groundwater
well to see how deep the groundwater was
and I'm a big fan of this so we found
that we found a lowest point of the
property we dug a groundwater well lined
it with stones I went down till till we
hit moisture till we hit you know losing
water then dug another couple feed and
again lined it all with stone and then
watched it and we could watch the
groundwater going up and down during
different seasons well after we
installed all of this water harvesting
you know these swales and smiles that's
another one which is going to be hard to
describe without a drawing
they basically raised the groundwater
because as the groundwater went down
naturally due to lack of rain now of a
sudden all that water that was being
stored in those vias whales was slowly
being let back into the soil system and
accumulating in the well and the coolest
part about it was it's like we could
pump water out of that well to do
emergency watering and that actually
forced more water to come back into the
well so it's it's you know it's a
combination of managing your soil
systems putting as much carbon as you
possibly can into it to hold the
moisture so that when it when you're
desperately needing the summer it
slowly leaching out and going back into
either your well so you can monitor it
or just knowing that it's naturally
leeching out into your plants and that's
where you kind of like get smart you
build this bio soil right through the
middle of your field so that you know
that the plants on the left and the
right of it are getting the moisture and
you can actually you know think of like
a river and you know creating all these
different Forks coming off of it so that
you're you're getting these you know
water storage units in the soil in the
form of a carbon an old ship or
cardboard or paper whatever
and again you're planting the top of it
so that evaporation cannot happen that's
that's really important I don't don't
store water in an open pond because
you're gonna lose it during the summer
you're gonna store it underground under
cover and and you'll you'll she'll see
such a big difference in the amount of
watering that you actually have to do
that you'll realize oh my god I should
have done this years ago
when you say stored underwater do you
mean I mean big plastic reservoirs like
don't worry those no I meant underground
oh no you don't have to you don't need a
lining you just basically need to dig a
swale fill it with chips take the
leftover dirt spread it on the top
couple inches and then plant it with
with a cover crop a ground cover and
what that does is that prevents that
like if you if you just put the chips in
and you dump the water into those chips
the air the wind and the Sun would
naturally wick that water out and
evaporate it so by covering it putting
it under ground under soil and then
cover cropping that soil so that the
soil doesn't blow off in a road and also
again and then the soil could wick the
moisture out of the chips and up out
into the surface if you don't have
ground cover to protect it the soil so
is the only is the way that you access
that water for your plants by planting
your cannabis plants there because so so
no no basically what you're doing is
you're thinking along the lines of
wicking so basically you're storing the
water there but that water is being
waked out laterally horizontally upwards
even up gradient as necessary so you're
basically you're
concentrating the water in one spot
knowing that it's going to wick out and
spread out in an of greater area than
where the water is concentrated at that
point in time that a little bit depends
on your soil system you know in a clay
soil it's not gonna wick as fast in a
sandy soil obviously it's gonna work a
lot quicker so there are some other
considerations to think about but what
it's doing is its raising the moisture
level in the soil it's not it's not
watering the plants it's not like it's
you know you're you're using it to
surface water you're just allowing the
roots to have greater access to
subsurface water and moisture I
understand now
so whereas a pond you can actually
siphon the water out of the pond with
the hose and pointed at your pots or
your drip line and there you go you're
talking about we want to capture and
keep as much of the water on our parcel
mm-hmm exactly using the soil to do the
work for you
you know in I love I love the guys that
have those water tanks uphill and they
use you know obviously gravity to to
water your plants well it's the same
idea except for it's the soil now so the
soil is actually because you dug the
Swale you put all those chips in there
and when your sister and overflowed it
overflowed into that Swale and that
swells slowly the water moved down by
gravity to the end of it and those all
those chips got what we call field
capacity they got as wet as they
possibly can and now they've held all of
that moisture there for you so that as
as the ground dries out around it
because there's no longer rain coming
down the ground around it is now pulling
that water out of that Iowa's whale and
supporting a moisture level that it
needs for the plants to grow right on I
understand that and I actually saw that
a great example of that gosh was the
beginning of last summer or the summer
before but anyway at a ladies sativa
farm in Humboldt they they live at the
top of a mountain and you know most of
us go through a drought season and
they're like listen during the rainy
season we have to capture as much of
this water here at the top of the
mountain because it's really
to go down the hill and so they they you
know they use swales and ponds and you
know a whole variety of techniques that
we actually go through with the with the
interview with Rio from ladies sativa
that's on the YouTube channel that you
can check out and and you know his goal
like yeah he's a he's a cannabis farmer
but he's all like man he says I spend
more of my time sequestering water and
growing cover crops and and and making
the water work to leave my property
as much as he's growing cannabis which I
found really interesting let's um let's
let's talk about this the other category
of folks because certainly in the
regenerative agriculture scene which we
love so much there's a lot of these
permaculture techniques that have made
their way into the scenes so people
aren't just directly pumping the aquifer
but let's answer this question in
another way for folks who are you know
just growing their you know there's six
personal plants that are available in a
lot of states up to like the 15 that are
available in a lot of states for medical
if you don't have property if you're not
trying to sequester all of this water on
your acreage and you just don't want to
use your city water
I recognize that we have to be a little
bit aware of where our rainwater is
coming from and what it's made up and
you know especially if we live in an
industrial city what would you consider
a simple and effective way to capture
rainwater cleanly you know just to be
just to be working on your 6 or 15
plants that's a good one I mean again
one of the things that I said earlier
about capturing rainwater I mean if I
was in one of those industrial zones or
in a city I would want to be running
that water through you know some mosses
or some other plants that actually do
clean the water so now I'm making it too
complicated for these guys because now
I'm saying okay yeah captured capture
the water off the gutters but then take
it and you've got to store it somewhere
most people literally are taking it off
the roof or they've got a big tarp and
they're funneling it into a rain barrel
and they've got a rain barrel with a
spout and then they fill up their
watering can with that and they go put
it on their plants I mean I would say
that's the default setting for most
people
small cropping and and capturing
rainwater what do you think of that
setup is that like you to what degree do
you need to add this step where you you
put it through some grasses or something
again it's now we're hitting you know
we're dividing the hair between full
plant potential and just plant so so it
you know if you want to go to the next
level then that's what I would do is I
would look at you know these different
plants another thing you can do is could
be old canary in the coalmine throw a
couple goldfish in there and if these
goldfish die you know you've got a
problem but if they're thriving and
living then you're okay so you know that
might be a quick easy way for people to
know that the water that they're using
or collecting harvesting is safe because
you know the canary in the coalmine is
50 goldfish dies you got a problem
another thing that the goldfish would do
too is if you feed it it's gonna make
some poop for you which is aquaponics so
a couple birds with one stone there yeah
there you go so hey let's go ahead and
take our second commercial break you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is soil biologist and all-around
good guy late Morrison one of the
reasons why no-till cannabis growing is
so valued by farmers is because the
mycelium networks in the soil remain
established from year to year and we
know these fungal networks are essential
because they are the nutrients
superhighways that extend far and wide
in the substrate to feed your plants
the trouble with growing in new soils or
blended cocoa substrates is that it
takes most of the plant's life just to
create these mycelium highways Dino
Michael endo mycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the current leading brand in the US
at 900 propagules per gram of to fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation this new product
called Dynamite Co is the result of 30
years of research and trials at the
volcano a Greek ultra Research Institute
in Israel it has also been vigorously
trialed by cannabis and food growers
across the US since the product first
arrived here last year you may have
already even heard about dynamite go by
its original name dynamite now Dino my
Co is available at grow shops and online
in the United States for the first time
I love using dynamite go to both speed
up the growth of mycelium networks in
the soil but also as a bio stimulant to
make clone cuttings more virile you can
see side by sides showing the
comparative growth on their Instagram at
Dino Mico if you demand reliable growing
results and appreciate the importance of
an active root zone in creating a
thriving plant I encourage you to check
out Dino myko at Dino my cocom and find
out where you can get yours that's dy n
oh my co.com whether you are starting
with new beds or pots or if you want to
add some zing to tired soil choose
dynamite go to maximize your plants
potential Dino my co endo mycorrhizal
inoculants if you listen to shaping fire
and you grow your own cannabis chances
are high that you are very particular
about the inputs you use for growing
people like us painstakingly
self-educate on cannabis nutrients and
techniques so we can cultivate the best
tasting and cleanest flowers possible
and when we go to purchase those
nutrients we want to be sure that our
supplier shares our values and is
providing exceptional quality this is
why I recommend build a soil calm to my
friends who care about quality build a
soil empowers organic growers to do
their best work by sourcing and shipping
only the finest cannabis growing
supplies from organic inputs soils soil
testing and pots to Lights growing tents
sprayers and cover crops build a soil
founder Jeremy Silva does
just stock his store with what's
available he goes deep to personally vet
each product for quality and determine
that there isn't a better version of the
product that he could be selling because
of this arduous process you know that
your options on build a soil dot-com
have been carefully curated to create
the results you are looking for not only
that but the build a soil way is a
philosophy that will permeate your
interaction with the company from
website designed to pricing and shipping
to after purchase support Jeremy and his
team always strive to do their best and
give you the best customer service in
the business
checkout build a soil dot-com today for
top tier quality cultivation supplies
and a friends and family buying
experience and check out their
educational videos and extraordinary
social media while you're there to
quality organic growing supplies at
build a soil calm for 20 years Humboldt
seed company has been family-owned in
providing reliable high yielding seeds
originating in Northern California while
the current trend is to slap one super
male into a line of hype strains
Humboldt seed company continues to breed
with precision and care by doing large
sips and back crosses to emphasize the
absolute best traits that a line has to
offer this kind of breeding takes time
talent and space to work no matter what
kind of aroma you are particularly in to
Humboldt seed will likely have something
you'll love if you love fruit you can
choose from banana mango apricot papaya
blueberry blood orange melon and lemons
across their various strains they have
all gas glue and classic Sour Diesel
lines as well of course there are the
heritage California strains like OG Kush
Jack hair and headband and their
award-winning blueberry muffin is one
that delights just about everybody's
palate
especially when concentrated Humboldt
seed company is proud to bring to market
the infamous freakshow cultivar - which
has a great THC high but looks so much
like a fern that some folks can't even
identify it as cannabis it's a plant
that really needs to be seen
believed if you're looking for
well-balanced CBD seeds Humboldt seed
company can turn you on to CBD strains
that actually have flavor like the dill
and pepper terpenes of Willie G's
Lebanese landrace whether you are
looking for regular feminized or Auto
flowers Humboldt seed company has the
gear to make this your best growing
cycle ever visit Humboldt seed company
comm today to check out their line of
vigorous genetics download their
catalogue and find out where you can
pick them up you can also check out
their instagram at the Humboldt seed
company to check out their gorgeous
flowers and the extraordinary freak show
plant Humboldt seed company let them
know Shango Sencha welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire
I'm your host Shengo Louis and our guest
today is soil biologist slate Morrison
so here in the last set we are going to
be talking about best practices for
watering because you know for something
that seems so simple there are a lot of
ways to screw it up so Layton what
factors determine how much to water I
know for a lot of folks we kind of just
think well you know let's just drench
the hell out of it and then that way I
know that it won't dry out before the
next time I come back to my pot but
that's not very strategic so so leaning
on the biological knowledge what's the
actual way for us to figure out how much
the water listen to the plant it'll tell
you if the Sun leaves are tracking the
Sun or the lights in your tent and
praying to it you know the moisture is
perfect so when they're drooping that
usually means that they're either
lacking moisture or they have too much
moisture and over-watering definitely
moves soil particles down into the
profile as well as washes out nutrients
so I'm a big fan of those blue mats you
know you can regulate it moisture meters
are helpful but eventually you'll get
used to it you'll just be able to stick
your finger in there and if you can feel
it you'll know you're in a good place
and if your plants praying to the Sun
you know you're know you're in the sweet
spot
yeah man there's nothing quite like when
the when the plants are praying and
they're all you know up there reaching
and they're tracking the Sun or the
light and they've got that slight
inverted taco look oh my gosh when I see
that I'm just like give myself a little
pat on the back and I'm all like thank
God I'm doing it right today tells you
everything you need to know you're just
gonna learn how to listen to it so what
are the some of the factors that are
going to play a role in how much we're
gonna water I'm assuming heat and
humidity are gonna play a big role how
should we think about that humidity is a
huge role because if it's too dry if
it's the winter and you've got your heat
on and your HVAC system is pushing heat
all over the place yeah it's gonna dry
out and that's where I recommend if
you're in a tent you get one of those
little tiny humidifiers they're
inexpensive and it will help to put
moisture into the air and you won't have
to water nearly as much so that's a
great way of preventing the soil from
wicking the moisture out in and letting
the air pull it out because you guys all
have fans too you have to move the air
around so when that wind is blowing
across the pot it is pulling moisture
out of it so that humidifier is a great
trick and then of course cover cropping
on a big fan of no soil left bare so
that those leaves are covering up every
square inch of that pot and what you'll
notice when you flip the leaves over and
look at the underside there'll be a
little condensation so it's preventing
that moisture from escaping from the
surface of that pot great way to prevent
excess water excellent I think it's good
for us to point out momentarily you know
cover crops do not steal nutrients from
your pot no they do not and they build
miles of Rio sphere which crosses the
roots of your other cannabis plants
there's all kinds of wonderful exchanges
that are happening there as well as
nutrient cycling you're getting extra
extra protozoa extra bacteria that are
all functioning for you at a high level
so they're not stealing nutrients
they're actually adding them back to you
fantastic so you know a lot of us are
slowly but surely converting over to
fabric plots and
you know there's a lot of reasons why
black plastic pots are questionable
everything from the fact that they're
plastic to the fact that you know they
tend to get a little sludgy at the
bottom if people don't you know have
rocks in the bottom there's a lot of
good reasons to go to the fabric pots
and then you know and then you've got
like you know companies like like grass
roots that are actually lining the
inside of the fabric pots so they lose
less air out to sides but in your
experience Layton do we need to water
fabric pots more often oh yeah they
definitely leach out moisture out the
sides of them it's the same thing it's
like if you're in a plastic pot the only
thing where you have to be concerned
about is the top of the pot with a
fabric pot you got the sides as well
that's where I always say you know you
need some kind of vapor barrier to
prevent that moisture exchange glad to
hear that the pot companies are actually
taking that into consideration now
because in the past when you see these
the sides of the pots would go
hydrophobic so you pour the water on the
topic room right over the sides and
right down the sides and you couldn't
get the moisture in there and you see
you talked about that last time about
how you saw a huge difference with the
cover crops now you can't cover crop the
side of your pot but you can do things
like put hay bales against them foam if
you have extra foam so that you prevent
that water or the air from stealing the
moisture out of the side of the pot and
and also temperature we don't want the
sides of that pot to get to get warm
because that's going to directly affect
the biology so by insulating it and
putting a vapor barrier in on the sides
of your pot you're gonna be able to use
those and I'm a big fan of those fabric
pots I really like yeah I'm actually
really excited they're calling these
living soil fabric pots from grassroots
pots they actually sent me out a couple
to trial and and so I'm actually
trialing the their pots but then also
they're fabric beds they've got liners
on those too because they're like hey
you know we all know that we're losing
water out the sides and fabric pots are
not necessarily as effective as
pushing the so the the water down to the
the bottom of the pot because so often
it just evaporates out the sides
no so anyway there's a lot of people who
have used them because these are you
know they've had they've abused have
been out for a year or two already
I'm just getting around to it so so I'll
tell you more of my thoughts and they'll
fall on that so so okay so let's next
talk about hydrophobic pots so um I can
copy this right I'm I have been the
worst I did not even realize what was
going on in my pots until I heard you
speak at the Michigan region event
because this and and I just know that so
many people are gonna like oh [__] that
happens to me too I would hand water my
pot and I would watch the water bead
slide across the surface of the pot and
then go down the sides and I'm all like
dammit
oh man I want the water to go into the
soil and yet it was going away you know
he was just sliding off as if it would
like the soil was a solid structure and
it was after listening to you and dr.
Elaine Ingham that I realized that I
needed to add a cover crop to create all
of these opportunities for the for the
water to go inside and now I don't have
that problem but I know there's people
who are listening who have that problem
so so go ahead and hit on what makes a
pot go hydrophobic and and and I'm
assuming you're going to but talk crap
about peat moss to you know how much and
I've been blessed to have worked with a
company called pittmoss back ten years
ago or so in trying to develop a product
Mott Hadley you know was grinding up
newspapers because he saw his
grandmother use newspapers to line her
soil in her outdoor gardens and he
realized wool way they have a great
moisture holding capacity if I shredded
it maybe maybe I could get away from you
know using peat and he started this
company and through the years you know
he's gone ups and downs and finally just
recently a group has come in and really
started to grab this thing by the horns
and they're developing some wonderful
products I'm on beta testing a bunch of
them now I'm actually working with them
on formulating one specifically for
living soil systems which I'm really
excited about it's gonna be mushroom
compost it's gonna be core believe it or
not they've got a great source of clean
core ground-up paper pulp cardboard pulp
which is an amazing fungal food the
biology that I've seen in in so far and
the products that they've sent me I
either see a tremendous amount of spores
or I see a tremendous amount of hyphy
could you imagine being able to buy a
soil that was loaded with hyphy out of
the gate what a jumpstart
hey what's funny too is pittmoss has
reached out to me as well to send me
stuff because they heard through the
grapevine that I talk a lot of crap
about you know taking peat moss out of
the environment because it's not
sustainable and now hear that they've
reached out to you somebody over there
is doing a good job actually not to
folks like us yeah I give actually a lot
of credit she she heard me on a podcast
and and hit me up because I was bashing
peat and so it's it's wonderful I'm
ecstatic to be you know back in touch
with them and and back in doing some
trials to see how they're performing and
how we could formulate better ones but I
didn't answer your question so so
hydrophobic is is basically that you
have organic matter which is what the
plants growing in and the outside of
that organic matter is completely coated
with bacteria and those bacteria go back
into that system as they dry out and
they create that wax surface which
doesn't allow the water in so in a
situation where I have a hydrophobic pot
I don't have cholera crop I would take a
wet towel I get a towel soaking wet and
then I cover it and so that that water
slowly wycked out of the towel and
worked back into the pot and so that
would be the way to quickly as quick as
possible take the hydrophobic component
out of the
the surface of that soil now the
interesting thing is with pittmoss it
has a similar side effect that I've
noticed in my starts that it does it
does go a little bit hydrophobic on the
surface but as soon as you break through
it you could feel that it's nice and
moist inside so that's one of the things
that we're talking about it's like all
right how do we prevent the soil from
going hydrophobic on the surface and you
know explain to them the reasons why
we're playing with a organic based
wetting agent that's going to prevent it
from happening but you know again would
we need some more time to really get
these kinks out of it
product development aside though we have
the answer right it's it's you've got to
have a cover crop you know and like
whether it's you know whether it's
grasses or clovers or radishes or you
know the build a soil like cover crop
mix or you know there's a lot of really
great options but the point is you got
to grow other stuff in your pots
monocultures are not natural yep
no you're absolutely right that is the
answer but there are still people
there's holdouts that don't wanna you
know don't want to have to fuss with it
with the other crops because they can
inadvertently become banker play or not
banker plants but try plants and and
bring in other pests into your your
atmosphere well you definitely need to
choose your cover crops carefully that's
that that part is shirt for sure but but
it's hard but it is hard to go wrong
yeah and again you know if you're in a
situation where you don't want to deal
with cover crop just get an old towel
soaking wet and you know put that around
the top of the pot so that so that it
holds the moisture in and that will
prevent that hydrophobic problem in the
first place so so you're what causes the
pot to go hydrophobic like like what is
the thing that people need to not do
we've talked about solving it we've
talked about using the cover crop and
we've talked about putting the blanket
on it but you know we can even like say
me for example what did I do to cause
the top layer to go sis
and and have that waxy top what did I do
wrong that caused it other than just not
having a cover crop humidity and Sun
humidity Sun and wind that's what's
causing it when when when the wind blows
across soil I'm it the amount of
moisture that it pulls out of that soil
is crazy I mean I used to do these
monster landscapes you know for these
billionaires and you know we'd be
working right straight through whatever
season it was and we'd always get like
and so if we got the spring you know mud
season it was a nightmare to try to
spread soils so I would have to be so
careful to have the blender not blended
when there was a rainstorm coming or or
even in some cases not try to spread it
on the surface of the existing soil
until the wind came in and dried it out
I mean I'd shut job down a number of
times because of these conditions and
the Builder would freak the owner would
freak and I'd be like look you guys if I
don't do this I'm gonna turn this into a
mud bath and then you're really gonna
have a problem because everything's
gonna be rotted and you're gonna be
killing plants and so that moist out
wind going across the top of that soil
surface is probably the biggest thing
second would be the Sun and of course
lastly the humidity if you do not have a
relative humidity meter in your tent or
in your greenhouse then you never know
how much moisture is being stolen off
the top of that pot because of lack of
humidity in the air so those those are
the three reasons wasn't you it was the
environment it was wind is on or or
relative humidity so how much does it
matter the temperature of the water when
we water the plant oh great question I'm
a big fan of room temperature so you
know if you're in a greenhouse I would
just let it sit out in the greenhouse
before I used it if you're in a tent you
know you you're probably at 68 degrees
again room temperature you don't want to
shock anything it's like if you poured
cold water on your plant it's not gonna
like it or if you pour boiling water on
you
it's not gonna like it so you want to
have that water as close to the
temperature of the soil as you possibly
can get so that's that's a that was a
really good question so is there any
advantage to bubbling the water first to
aerate it I know that some people do
that to get rid of you know the chlorine
and I know that other folks do it
because they're actually gonna make you
know put some compost tea into it
but then I also know some people that do
it because they're like oh I want to
take more oxygen down to the root zone
so I'm gonna bubble by water to extra
aerate it before I put it in there and I
don't know if that's scientifically
sound what do you think oh absolutely
absolutely sound you can build the
dissolved oxygen in a water column
through aeration and that's why you do
it in a fish tank because the fish I'm
getting into biology again but the
breakdown of those you know the nitrogen
cycle is creating co2 and so the only
way to get the co2 dissolved the oxygen
level up high enough to support the fish
life depending on the amount of biomass
obviously the more fish the more
bubblers the more air stones you're
going to need so know I'm a huge fan of
bubbling the water first and then
applying it because yes you are bringing
down a higher level of dissolved oxygen
into the soil system I think I touched
on this last time I did an experiment
way back when where I measure dissolved
oxygen in a raindrop in a sprinkler so
one of those rotary sprinklers that come
out of the ground and go and water in a
pipe and then water in a drip irrigation
tube it was amazing the dissolved oxygen
level in the raindrop was 23 parts per
million in the sprinkler I think it was
15 I'm out of the faucet it was about
eight and in the end of the drip
irrigation pipe it was six anaerobic six
five to six so it was anaerobic so we
know you can build that water molecule
up I mean there's a stairs of great
video showing what happens to a water
droplet as it travels through the
atmosphere and it rolls over on itself
don't it so it's constantly pulling in
oxygen as it's tumbling through the air
so no big fan of it definitely aerate
your water if you possibly can because
that will help to support the life in
the soil especially if you have a really
good living soil system and you don't
have earthworms or a way for that soil
to really build the tilth out of the
gate then bubble your water so that your
help to feed those those organisms that
extra oxygen so they can in turn build
that tilt and allow that soil to
respirating let's talk about a method of
watering you know you know everybody
said Larry I shouldn't say everybody
there is a certain contingent in the
home growing scene that demands hand
watering and and I and you know some of
that is because of the effect of the you
know hand watering and just giving the
plant as much as it needs but I also
think a lot of it is that people like me
who believe that a plant thrives more
when you spend a little time with it
every day and you you know you're more
aware of your pest pressure and you know
changing color of leaves that might show
that you might be missing some nutrient
but all that comes with the moment that
you spent with that plant but we also
you know while while I have not used
blue mat yet you know my friends are
saying great things about them but then
when you scale up it's much much
difficult much more difficult to do hand
watering and and people shift up to
commercial scale drip lines and things
like that is there really a difference
to the plant which one you use or is
this really simply economies of scale
and and how this impacts your labor does
it really matter to the plant what which
one we use the only problem with hand
watering is seeing consistency unless
you're sitting there counting each plant
how long it you took to water it then
some are gonna get a little bit extra
water and some are gonna be a little
less water I get the concept of being
you know out there with the plant and
I'm a big proponent of being a farmer
shadow-like
you guys need to be in you with your
plants all the time there are the
extremists that say oh just leave the
plane alone let the plant do its work
yeah I get that too but in in a mono
cropping situation you're asking for
problems I mean if you're if you're
highly regen and you've got all kinds of
different plants and diversity around
your cannabis you're gonna be okay
you're not gonna have the kind of pest
pressure that can happen with a mono
cropping system and I believe that the
hand watering comes in because it's
forcing you to spend time with each and
every one of those plants so it's a good
practice sure but you've got to be
careful because humans are humans and if
you start daydreaming for a minute and
lose your count well now you're gonna
overwater or underwater so you know it's
it's a matter of being a more diligent
in in spending your time but in this
case the reason I love the blue mats are
is because they're non-mechanical it's a
lights it the only thing that's driving
it is that ceramic when that ceramic
gets to a certain level of moisture it
either calls from warm moisture or it
shuts off and prevents more moisture
from coming out so it's a brainless way
of maintaining a certain way soil
moisture level that's that's unique to
anything I've ever seen on the market so
that's why I'm a big fan of it because
it takes the guesswork out so this
should be good in the category of
guesswork you just said if you get
distracted and you lose your count when
you're hand watering dude I don't even
have a count I didn't even think about
that as you know I I hand water and I'm
watching it and I'm like man looks about
right low and I'm thinking to myself oh
my god no wonder I've got watering
issues all the time so so how do you
come to a water how do you come to a
count basically you got to start with
obviously sticking your finger in the
soil and if you're not good at if you're
not good enough at that yet another
trick is to take a handful of the soil
and squeeze it as hard as you can and if
you get water dropping out of it it's
too much water you should be able to
just get a little bit of a slick spot at
the bottom where your
squeezing it but it shouldn't drip out
of it and it obviously it should hold
together it shouldn't just you know
crumble or span back to its original
size very quickly so that that's a great
way of determining the moisture content
of where your sweet spot is but as far
as as hand watering that again depends
on your soil system if you're all
potting soil or we call it the soilless
medium that's gonna take more moisture
and again problem is surface it's gonna
go hydrophobic and the internals gonna
go anaerobic so that's why I push that a
horizon is so critical in this and that
a horizons gonna help you maintain an
equal moisture profile from the bottom
of the pot to the top of the pot so
again it depends on your soil matrix as
to you know what the count might look
like but it's pretty easy to you know if
once you start to realize what the
moisture should feel like you'll get
comfortable with it you'll be able to
just walk up stick your finger in the
pot up this one needs a little moisture
and go to the next one this one doesn't
because you know another thing too is
that these plants are going to react
differently one might transfer eight
based on the cultivar differently than
another one you know what some of them
are used to higher tolerance of heat
some of them are less you you know you
know all this I mean the cultivars are
also going to drive you know what that
moisture level looks like but I'm start
with that squeezing trick that's a good
one and and then eventually move into
that being able to just stick your
finger in there until you feel that that
moisture level and you'll get
comfortable with it yeah I think what
I'm gonna do is I think I'll go I'll go
down the line of pots and and give them
different counts and then go back in ten
minutes and do the squeeze test that you
described and then I'll know what my
right count is cuz that'll be the pot
that's reacting properly yeah and and I
would even wait longer I'd wait a couple
hours you know to let let the moisture
you know migrate down into the into the
bottom of the pot and then feel it so
turn water them wait a couple hours and
then go back and check it out and
so certainly people water in compost tea
right they'll they'll do some compost
tea first and then they will water their
plant to water it in what do you think
about like having your water be compost
tea is there a need for the fresh water
in addition to just compost tea or like
add they both have got water in them um
they both have water in them but I you
know I if I'm using a concentrate so one
of my products is a liquid concentrate
then I definitely water it in
I mean I've turned grasp purple like
literally purple because I put so much
on it cuz I wanted to see what was gonna
happen and the colors of the grass came
out and it just screamed it turned so
dark green that it was almost purple and
I was like wow look at that
yeah the clients not gonna like that I
better water but again you know going
back to compost teas as long as you have
biology then I would say yeah it's not
gonna hurt to just give it a spritz
after to try to move those droplets of
compost heap down into the soil profile
where they belong cuz they don't belong
on the surface yeah on the surface
they're just gonna die from the air in
the UVs and everything else so no I
totally get the the practice of watering
in when I was doing a lot of
installation of product what I would do
is I would make you know obviously my
concentrate I would add 10 gallons the
concentrate then I would add you know
110 gallons water a little bit of foods
and then I would just go apply it but I
would apply it heavily so I would do a
soil drench so some of it was getting
the the continuous spraying on top of it
would push the the first spray down into
the soil and I would just be like yeah
you know whatever whatever evaporates or
whatever you v's kill these little guys
I'm not going to be concerned about it
because I'd rent the soil so I
inadvertently moved those the organisms
down into the lower profile that I
wanted to
fantastic well Layton thank you so much
for sharing your time I know you're
you're on the road and consulting a lot
actually maybe you've hit a little bit
less right now in quarantine actually
you might actually be home quite a bit
right now you you are normally traveling
a lot are you even gonna be home enough
to put into a food garden this year
funny you should say that I have done it
I mean it's it's been God 32 years more
since the last time I had the
opportunity to plan a garden so yeah
I've been planning gardening with
Pauline and our dog he's out there
helping me with the soil I mean it's
hilarious and so I'm actually enjoying
the quarantine I'm definitely not
working as hard or earning as much as I
would like to but you know it's this is
all gonna you know Peter out eventually
and I will be able to get back on the
road and help other folks out across the
country but for right now I'm enjoying
it I mean I'm so blessed that I can
still support myself I've made enough
money that I'm not gonna be you know
freaking out that I can't pay my bills
so I'm taking the time I'm meditating
playing in the soil taking walks and you
know life is great I'm enjoying the
quarantine I'm sorry for everybody out
there that suffering because I know
there's so many people that are you know
that we're living paycheck to paycheck
and are totally screwed right now and
it's sad it's it's horrible
but uh you know I'm taking it with
stride and I'm trying to stay positive
and send out good vibrations to
everybody but yeah I'm actually I am
growing a food garden it really is
interesting to see the revival of the
Victory Garden right the long-term joke
is that cannabis is a gateway to
horticulture right and there's all these
like new home growers that are suddenly
going well I was able to grow a little
bit of weed let me see what else I can
do and all that all the seed companies
are breaking new records for seed sales
and you know even though there's the
vast majority of what's going on
with the pandemic is obviously terrible
it does make me feel a some measure
better that people are learning how to
grow their own foods which we should
never have lost that skill and and
hopefully that is something that can
continue
moving forward for all of us and thank
you for bringing that up that is such an
important point you know we all should
be having at least nerve garden if not
at least a few veggies and it's it's not
a lot of work it's not that hard to do
this whether it's in a pot or or it's
planted in the soil and that's providing
food security and you're right about the
seed companies I mean they're out of
everything and so you know I gotta
believe that the vast majority of people
across this country are growing these
Victory Gardens which is great and
hopefully that never changes because we
can control the inputs of what's going
into these veggies and we know that
they're healthy
so no I'm glad you brought that up that
was great yeah well it wasn't intended I
just kind of stumbled into it cuz cuz
that's how we are so right on so thanks
again Leighton I look forward to talking
to you again in person when we can all
right brother great to speak with you
again
and have a wonderful day if you want to
hear more from Leighton Morrison I
encourage you to go on back to shaping
fire episode 54 if you haven't heard
that and it's all about soil how soil is
built soil horizons meaning the
different layers of soil and how to
properly build a container of soil that
mimics the planet it's an absolutely
fantastic episode and you will get to
enjoy not only a whole bunch of good
scientific information but also the
gleeful storytelling that Layton shares
with us also if you want to find out
more about Layton's business and his
various products you can check those out
at Kingdom aquaponics llc.com and his
instagram at kingdom aquaponics LLC you
can find more episodes of the shaping
fire podcast and subscribe to the show
at shaping fire calm and on Apple iTunes
stitcher and Google Play if you enjoyed
the show we'd really appreciate it if
you'd leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well
information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango
lowes.com does your company want to
reach our national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaving
feiyr.com to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host Shango Lowe's
[Music]