[Music]
it doesn't matter who you are really
modern life is stressful and causes
various forms of anxiety in all of us
there are so many recommended actions we
can take to help reduce that stress
exercise meditation eating Whole Foods
to keep our gut biome happy and working
directly to resolve the source of stress
are all proven to work very ious
Pharmaceuticals come and go in
popularity and supposedly help but most
are either addictive or eventually
debunked as
ineffective and then there is cannabis
humans have been turning to cannabis for
anxiety relief for thousands of years
and there are several different ways
that we can use cannabis to relieve
stress and we will discuss several of
them today today we're going to focus on
a brand new scientific study published
just last week looking at the
cannabinoid canaberal known as CBG to
reduce anxiety and the results are truly
remarkable and will absolutely influence
the direction of anxiety medicine
research going forward and how we as
cannabis enthusiasts avoid anxiety
too if you want to learn about cannabis
Health cultivation and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on on social media
to let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we're giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter so go to shaping fire.com and
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shaping fire and I am your
host Shango Los welcome to episode
116 my guest today is Dr Ethan Russo
Ethan Russo is a board certified
neurologist and former senior medical
adviser to GW Pharmaceuticals he has
served as study physician to GW
Pharmaceuticals for three phase three
clinical trials of satex he has held
faculty appointments in pharmaceutical
Sciences at the University of Montana in
medicine at the University of Washington
and as visiting professor at the Chinese
Academy of Sciences he has been
president of the international cannaboid
research society and is former chairman
of the International Association for
canab medicines in 1995 he pursued a
3-month sabatical doing ethnobotanical
research with indigenous people in Peru
he is author of several books of
cannabis medicine and has published over
30 articles in neurology pain management
cannabis and ethnobotany he is presently
founder of katos science where he works
to formulate cannabis Therapeutics for
the good of all Dr Russo has joined us
before on shaping fire several times
episode 22 on treating traumatic brain
injury with cannabis and mushrooms and
episodes 11 and 27 about his famous
research papers on cannabinoids and
terpenoids episode number 67 about
treating migraines with mushrooms and
cannabis episode 80 on canono
hyperemesis syndrome episode 83 on the
canabo CBG episode 103 regarding the
life's work of Dr Raphael mulam episode
110 taking a good look at Delta 8 THC
and of course the shaping fire sessions
on the shaping fire YouTube channel
during the first set today we will
review what we know about CBG kabaj
gereral and look at the results of Prior
CBG studies we'll also discuss using
isolate versus whole plant preparations
during scientific research in the second
set we will review the mechanics of the
study and look pretty closely at the
various ways participants were made to
be anxious and the battery of skills
tests participants were given while
anxious and using CBG and during the
third set we will look at the
groundbreaking and really remarkable
results from this study and compare
using CBG to other cannabinoids like CBD
and THC for reducing anxiety welcome
back to shaping fire Dr
Russo well it's good to be back with you
excellent so Ethan you know why don't we
uh do something new and why don't we
start with um um giving some respect to
your other co-authors on this
paper ah sure happy to do that uh well
this was led by Dr Carrie Cutler of
Washington State University who's an
assoc a professor of psychology there
and has done fantastic work on cannabis
over the last several years also her
graduate student Amanda stuber did a lot
of the interviewing uh for folks in the
study and uh then Zea Cooper who's a
professor at UCLA and heads the Cannabis
research program there fantastic thank
you you know the more and more I get
into the science side uh depth in
cannabis the more I realize how
important every single person on a paper
is and so I think I I think I like this
and I think I'll I think we'll start
plugging those other uh co-authors as uh
going forward so thanks for that so
let's let's get started by creating a
little bit of context for canaba gerall
for folks who are relatively new to CBG
as a canabo now clearly throughout this
entire show we're going to be talking
about CBG in uh significant detail but
for the moment would you just give us a
General understanding of CBG as a
canabo yes happy to do that so uh let's
go back to 1964 that was the year that
Rafael mulam and yil goni um identified
finally uh THC tetr Hydro canaban as the
main psychoactive ingredient in cannabis
but that same year uh they also
discovered canaba gereral and were quite
preed in identifying it as a precursor
to all the other major
canabo uh so it it started there uh
interestingly all the attention was
focused on
THC uh canaba uh had been discovered or
identified with
clear uh idea as to it structure only
the prior year in 196
63 but because there was not this um
overt psychoactivity to some of these
other compounds uh they got much less
attention and that was certainly the
case with canaba gereral so there were
some initial studies looking at what it
did in animals um uh but uh it really
didn't get the attention it deserved for
perhaps another 30 years or
more what would have caused the interest
in CBG to
increase well you know along the line
people did take a look at uh certain
things uh in the 70s it was shown that
uh CBG is an uptake inhibitor for Gaba
uh which is an inhibitory
neurotransmitter why that is important
is that it could account for muscle Rel
LAX in activity and certainly for some
uh activity as an anti-anxiety agent
which we certainly be talking about more
uh additionally in 2006 it was shown
that uh there was an anti-depressant
effect in tail suspension models and in
rodents uh along the way uh it was shown
that there is a mild effect of CBG to
lower blood pressure and also to lower
intraocular pressure the way THC does on
glaucoma um
subsequently uh during this
interval in the early 2000s there was a
lot more
investigation uh some of this was
spearheaded uh through support of GW
Pharmaceuticals where I was working at
the time on they had a uh program of
selective breeding for the so-called
minor canabo and one of those was
canaberal uh the chief breeder there
attend deer actually developed a CBG
only plant um and uh so that there was a
good bit of basic research going on um
among other things it was shown that um
CBG
stimulates uh several trip channels on
especially trip M8 m is sort of like uh
it's named for Menthol so this is a a
temperature sensitive receptor trip M8
is important because uh certain tumors
especially prostate cancer and some uh
breast cancer lines uh would be targets
for this um uh
additionally um there it was shown that
uh there were antibiotic effects a
strong effects uh against methylin
resistant staus orius that was shown by
appendino at all um this is an important
result uh because at the time there were
all these Hospital acquired infections
and many deaths related to Mera us s
remains in area of great interest so two
of the big things were this uh effect on
certain cancers uh and I should point
out that CBG like just about all the
other canabo shows a a great selectivity
and its ability to kill cancer cells
while being preservative for normal
cells this is an important distinction
because standard chemotherapy agents
tend to be toxic to cells and General so
it's always an issue of can you kill the
tumor before you kill the patient or at
least make them very sick in the process
so anybody who's been through
chemotherapy or has a family member or
friend that has is familiar with this
concept so with the canabo we have the
prospect of having much more
selective ability to kill cancer without
producing
overt
toxicity the study reminds us a couple
times that there are nearly no CBG
studies that involve humans and yet we
know you know quite a bit about CBG and
have um pretty good ideas about other
things we want to research in humans it
gives me kind of a vibe that that there
is a a bit of a sea change as far as
human research into CBG you know as
somebody who is doing this research on
the front lines do you feel that as well
that we're at a transition point where
um we're we're moving out of of purely
rodent studies and moving more and more
into CBG um studies in humans yes quite
true so why is that again uh for better
or worse there's been all this attention
on THC and then uh starting about 15
years ago CBD came to the four mainly
because of its utility in epilepsy uh
which is welld deserved but uh I think
people would understand that um CBD has
sort of peaked in terms of interest that
it it certainly is a very versatile
therapeutic molecule but um perhaps it
hasn't quite uh panned out uh from a
business standpoint that's certainly
true from many companies um so it's
pretty much everywhere but um again lost
in the shuffle were other candidates
particularly
CBG now that has changed recently
because certainly um on the west coast
of the US there has been selective
breeding again leading to CBG
predominant or CBG only kovar of
cannabis um this really started the
Northwest particularly with Oregon
CBD um and slowly uh CBG interest and
breeding has diffused to the rest of the
United States and around the world um so
along the line uh along the way
certainly there've been a lot of people
particularly in the Northwest us that
have been using CBG for some years now
um and so we have their what we'll call
what the scientists call anecdotal
experience What patients and consumers
report uh but it's only recently that
there have been the formal clinical
studies um and we' like to think that
we've been at the Forefront of that uh
with our surve survey study that was
published in 2021 and now this which was
the first study to examine a randomized
control trial the effect of CBG on
anxiety I have to agree with you Ethan
that it is no small impact that the CBG
dominant cultivars from uh Seth and Eric
Crawford there at Oregon CBD down in
Albany Oregon has really made a
difference here in the Pacific Northwest
because up until their CBG dominant
cultivar mostly we were getting CBG in
um THC dominant Cult of and it's really
hard to tell anything either in a
controlled study or just anecdotally
when THC is the primary ingredient but
when you can strip that out and make a
CBG dominant hemp cultivar where um you
know it's nearly entirely CBG this opens
up not only the ability for um that
plant material to find its way to
research scientists like you but also it
really gives a lot of strength to what
you know some call anecdotal evidence
some call citizen science the the whole
idea that that it gets its hand uh uh
CBG gets itself into the hands of
caregivers who are who don't don't
really have the same constraints as as
legitimate science do and so a lot of
the initial you know grunt work about
what we should even look for can happen
and I'm really grateful for those you
know single canabo dominant cultivars
and and hopefully we'll continue to be
seeing more of them a uh yes certainly
um you know this is the kind of
selective breeding that took place at uh
GW Pharmaceuticals unfortunately because
there was a concentration on development
of satx and
epidex CBG again never got into clinical
trials um despite the availability of a
CBG only K of our uh clear back uh you
know in the early
2000s um so it's just one of those
things that got lost in the
shuffle you know uh you may not be able
to speak to this and and and and my my
awareness might not even be true but
it's it seems to me that that there's
probably a whole bunch of really
interesting cultiv ours at GW that that
just like you said kind of got lost in
the mix and it isn't until similar Cult
of ours are are rebred in the public
that we see a lot of those cuz most of
the pharmaceutical companies you know
defend that cherished IP I would
assume right yeah so you know you've
been researching CBG for years and you
and I have been talking about it for
years now and this particular study
though um seems like it's a direct
follow-up to another one that you did
just a couple years back again with Dr
Carrie Cutler at Washington State
University uh a bit more of a general
study but it absolutely sets this one up
would you summarize that study and its
results so that we can all have a better
picture of what we're building on top of
uh sure so at that time we weren't in a
position yet to do a randomized control
trial first um I thought that we really
needed a survey a decent survey of what
people were reporting with
CBG uh
preparations um to lend some Credence to
the idea that number one this could be
used therapeutically number two that
there weren't any Associated problems so
we initiated a survey study and had 127
folks that
um the stipulation was they had to be
adults and they had to be using a
preparation that was at least 50% C CBG
so that was a mixed uh sort of sample
some of the people were using CBG only
products but a lot of them um
were CBG with THC and as you mentioned
that creates a a few
complications but uh for the most part
we got some very useful
information um so uh yeah let's let's
talk about what people saw mhm first um
what I expected was um something we did
see that a lot of people were using it
for the big three which are treatment of
pain help with sleep and uh mood
particularly um anxiety uh so these are
the same things for which many people
turn to cannabis uh of one type or
another but when we started asking about
condition conditions that people were
treating we got a list of 30 different
conditions and what was really
surprising was uh people reported that
the CBG preparations were highly
effective and often much more so than
conventional medicines that they' used
for the same
purposes um and we got uh very highly St
statistical significance with claims of
benefit on pain uh sleep anxiety but
also for some
hardcore uh medical conditions like uh
inflammatory bowel
disease uh
endometriosis now some of the numbers
weren't big on those specifics but when
3/4 of the people are saying that this
is the best medicine that they've ever
used uh for their condition you know it
is creating a s signal that deserves
attention um now at the same time uh
people were really not reporting side
effects to speak of some people reported
dry mouth sleepiness increased appetite
but certainly that would suggest that
those were preparations that had some
THC um in them um and this is born out
subsequently when we looked specifically
just at a CBG only
preparation similarly uh in the
survey um 84% reported no withdrawal
symptoms when they stopped um so you
know our conclusions were first this was
the first study that really looked at
therapeutic use of of CBG in
humans uh again anxiety pain depression
and insomnia were the most commonly
reported Target symptoms and people
reported a very high efficacy with uh no
Adverse Events to speak of um and you
know the the main thing was we thought
that this is a good indicator that CBG
would be safe for future randomized
control
trials um now we were immediately
interested in taking this forward but it
it took a good long time um as these
things often do uh recruitment for the
new
study which was again a randomized
control trial of a CBG only kov
extract um and its effect on
anxiety um this took a while to recruit
it it was confined to people in
Washington state because uh that's what
the institutional review board wanted um
but um it it came together nicely
um so why don't I stop there for a
second see if you have an interim
question because I could just go on sure
sure sure so um I find it interesting
that it was challenging to uh recruit
for this study I mean not only were you
limited to Washington which has you know
got its own challenges as since you've
got a national audience but even more so
after reading the study um I can imagine
that it that it may have been
challenging to find people who met your
stipulations because in one hand for
somebody to be open to participating in
a cannabis study they need to be open to
cannabis but then the study required for
them to not be using cannabis or any
other air quotes illicit drugs during I
think it was a two or three month window
and and so many people you know were
they they they may have had cannabis or
they may have been micro doing or may
have done a lot of things so this this
this actually continues to make the pool
of people possible much smaller right
well that's a problem in general in this
instance we ask that people not use
cannabis um for 24 hours oh um so you
know in some studies they're much more
stringent about that um we also wanted
people that were cannabis familiar uh
but not necessarily heavy users um so um
and that's that's walk in a line right
there well sure you know there are
always exclusion criteria uh we wanted
to exclude people that might have felt
that they had us CBG before and had a
bad reaction they couldn't use um harder
drugs within 2 months um they couldn't
have a serious psych psychiatric
condition like schizophrenia or
bipolarity uh they couldn't be pregnant
or
breastfeeding and they couldn't have any
chronic neurologic disorder or history
of a a serious head injury um uh so I
mean those were the the kinds of things
um and um
oh they also uh had to be fluent in
English they had to have a smartphone
because one of the tests was done on an
app uh on a
smartphone and as mentioned previously
uh just in Washington state so there
were no issues about shipping product
over state lines so that might have
attracted Federal interest let's say
yeah well there was um I found it
interesting because you know when you
reached out that that you were going to
be working on this study I was excited
to participate and then and then I
didn't get through the first sifting
process because my uh my my association
with cannabis and and other influences
were were far too high for the study but
I am happy to say that we let uh shaping
fire user or not users shaping fire
listeners uh know about the study and
and uh you have some of them in your
study so thanks to everybody who who
chose to participate so so we talked
about the the the the Baseline study
that you did with Dr Cutler uh over
there at Washington State University
that that laid down the base and so then
you worked with Dr card to design this
new study what were the objectives for
this new
study um it it was again to see if um in
a sort of
manufactured situation creating anxiety
that we could show that cpg made a
difference compared to Placebo and I I
just wanted to go back uh for a second
to um the demographics of um people's
canabus use um because this is important
a lot of studies um you know for
instance in the survey obviously wanted
people that had used CBG
before uh in this one it we hoped that
we'd get some people that never use CBG
and uh because this is really important
what's the reaction of it to somebody
that's never had it before so as it
turned out
65% of the people in the study which was
34 had no prior experience using canaba
jural uh again all had been cannabis
users in the past uh the average was
about 3 and half half days a week or 18
days a month okay but with that in mind
um you know again um what were the what
was the premise of the study um well
I'll just read from the purpose to
examine the acute effects of hemp
derived CBG on anxiety stress mood and
memory as well as positive and negative
subjective drug effects in humans and
the design is what's called a double
blind meaning patients and the
administers of uh this didn't know who
was getting what at the time Placebo
controlled that means that on one
occasion people got the CBG preparation
on another occasion they got a
placebo um and it was called a crossover
study because uh they had to take both
in separate trials and it's called a
field trial because um this was done
over Zoom with patients in their home
environment um and
um someone asking the questions on the
other end at Washington State
University I can imagine that um asking
people their questions at home actually
gets rid of an entire uh layer of
anxiety related questions that that you
don't have to do anymore since people
are often made to feel anxious just by
coming into a facility right that's
called white coat anxiety oh and we use
that to Advantage wait wait wait did you
say white coat anxiety yeah that's
that's apply named okay go ahead sure we
use that to Advantage though because uh
part of the testing was I mean some of
this is diabolical how do we make PE
people anxious uh well one of the things
was um they were told that they had five
minutes to
prepare um to say um what their ideal
job would be and how they were qualified
for it and um you know they were
expected to talk this whole time and if
they stopped talking they would um be
prompted to continue um and um the exam
Amer uh did a thing of starting out in
civilian clothing and then coming back
in a white coat and then there was a
thing of a calculation usually uh the
usual calculation when you're testing
someone cognitively is to trct subtract
seven from 100 this is much worse it
started with a very high number
subtracting
17 and every time a mistake was made
they were told to go back to the
beginning um so these are the Diabolical
ways that you induce anxiety in a
laboratory setting yeah well um it's
amazing how how effective they are for
being so gentle right because you're
you're not actually putting them under
threat but it sure can feel like it and
and we'll be talking more about those in
the second set too because this battery
of test that you gave people um were
something else um for this set let's
finish with this though you know most
studies
um that are happening on cannabis
nowadays they default to using isolate
um even though I prefer whole resin most
studies are using isolate because um it
is uh you know just one specific
molecule instead of being the Cannabis
resin which has got lots of components
in it um and yet we know that uh
generally speaking a using resin offers
better benefits from isolate which has
got its own problems why did you choose
to go with a whole plant CBG dominant
resin solution in the tincture for the
study instead of going with isolate
which is probably more easily available
and also is what you know what all your
peers and pharmace pharmaceuticals are
doing well we wanted Real World
Experience now again this the study drug
was a cpgxy extract that has been used
by a good number of people uh in the
Pacific
Northwest uh so we knew a little bit
about what to expect from it uh that was
a big Advantage we definitely wanted uh
CBG only preparation to the extent that
there'd be no THC no significant amount
of CBD or other
canabo and in fact um each milliliter
the study drug had 10 milligram of
CBG a little bit of
cbga um there were barely any THC
01 milligram of
THC and the only significant turpenoid
was. 35 Mig of
caropine which we don't expect to be
overtly
psychoactive so each
person in the study drug uh set um got 2
Mill of this material in a glass of
water so that was 20 milligrams of CBG
and not a lot uh else now it was a real
challenge to figure out a placebo so the
placebo would be something that wouldn't
be psychoactive to any great
extent but it it should look like the
study drug and and have a taste uh that
might be hard to tell apart so I racked
my brain this was part of my
contribution to the study um what could
we use that would have this
effect um so I wondered how about an
herbal preparation but one that wouldn't
have canabo in it and um we want
something that's sort of green like the
the Stu drug so I I thought about the
lur
chartreuse for people who don't know
chartreuse is um uh from Europe hundreds
of years old originally made by monks
said to be made uh with somewhere
between 50 and 100 different herbs it
has a distinct herbal taste and it is
green um so we use that um as the
placebo
um uh when when I read that in the study
Ethan I just howled sitting in my living
room um because number one it's it's
really humorous to see chartreuse so out
of place and in the wild like I'm you
know I was a bartender uh in my 20s and
30s so I was of course very familiar
with chartreuse but I didn't expect to
see it in the study while I was I was
reading it and then it makes so much
sense because uh even though chartreuse
has got a certain sweetness to it it is
so herbal and when you watered it way
down I totally see how it could become
an
effective um you know Placebo that that
act that looks and and and acts like a
tincture without the Active Components
uh did you find that it worked out
pretty well because I would think that
that would be a home run uh sure you
know I nobody said uh that I'm aware of
um that we know this is the drug and we
know that this one isn't um so and you
know again uh people were sent vials
that had a color code on them um uh uh
and the person administering didn't know
what was what um you know this is a way
to maintain the Blind and we think it
was quite effective in this instance
right on and you know since since the
name of the individual is in the study
we might as well go ahead and mention
who provid Ed the CBD tincture for the
study they might find that
novel uh yes this came from when
Shango oh
me yeah well I I was happy to do my bit
for science Ethan so I am grateful to
have
participated so um all right so let's go
ahead and take our first break when we
get back we're going to talk a lot about
the battery of tests that were given to
um the research participants because
since this study is pointing
specifically to um how CBG helps with
anxiety um it's going to be very
interesting to look at these different
tests and figure out how they tease at
anxiety different ways so you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is neurologist Dr Ethan Russo and
you know without these advertisers
shaping fire would not happen so please
support them and let them know you heard
them on shaping
[Music]
fire this message is for folks who grow
cannabis I'm talking to homeg Growers
patients and Commercial Growers too I'm
probably talking to you when you plan
out your next growing cycle be sure to
check out Humbolt CSI seeds at Hult
csi.com Caleb inspecta and his family
have lived in Humble County for over a
100 years for the last 40 years three
generations of his family have
cultivated extraordinary sensome at
cannabis in Humble mesino and Trinity
counties because of his lineage and the
hard-earned experience that comes from
growing up smoking and sifting large
populations of cannabis plants in
Northern California the seeds you'll cop
from CSI will be winning genetics based
on longtime Heavy Hitters and updated
and re sifted to bring out new and
exotic traits and better yields go ahead
and ask around Caleb also known as
inspecta and pirates of the Emerald
Triangle is a breeders breeder he
reaches way back and works with
significant strains recreating them in
new and interesting ways that you'll
love as a toker and a grower as well as
offering you some surprises that will
Delight serious seed Traders and
cultivators Humbolt CSI goes a further
step and selfs all these kavars so you
know all the seeds will be female these
are not experimental feminized seeds
humbold CSI releases some of the best
female seeds available anywhere and it
will show in your garden folks grew
quite a bit of CSI humble genx last year
here on Vashon Island and everyone was
pleased the patients had beautiful
female plants and didn't have to call
half of their Garden as males the folks
growing for the fun of getting high grew
colorful flowers with exceptional bag
appeal and great highs and breeders had
seven out of seven females in a pack
which gave them a lot of phenotypic
choices take a moment right now and
visit humbled csi.com you'll find an
update menu of both feminized and
regular lines along with photos and
descriptions that's humbled
csi.com
[Music]
businesses everywhere are striving to
reach people through advertising we all
know though that trying to reach a
cannabis audience with a quality message
is pretty difficult that's why many
people choose to advertise on the
shaping fire podcast advertising on this
show allows us time to talk about your
product service or brand and a way that
really lets people know what sets your
company apart from others bold people
who own companies know that getting into
relationship with their customers is
essential and that is what we offer we
will explain your service or product
what sets it apart as desirable and help
our audience get in contact with you
it's pretty simple really advertising
does not have to be all whizbang smoke
and mirrors nowadays I find that people
prefer just to be spoken to calmly
accurately and with good intentions if
you want to make your own commercial
spot well you can do that too during
these pandemic days conventions and
cannabis events are pretty poorly
attended but podcast listening is
skyrocketing with a commercial on
shaping fire you'll reach your customers
in the privacy of their headphones right
now and will continue to reach new
listeners as they explore the shaping
fire back catalog of episodes again and
again for
years a spot on shaping fire costs less
than a printed postcard per person and
the shaping fire audience is full of
smart cannabis enthusiasts cultivators
and entrepreneurs who are always curious
to learn do yourself a solid and contact
us today for rates on podcast and
Instagram advertising email hotspot
shaping fire.com to find out
[Music]
more fish poop brand fertilizer is an
all-natural fish poop concentrate with
nothing added real fish poop is
extraordinarily complex not only are you
adding the nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium your plants need to build mass
transport nutrients and enhance flavor
but fish waste is also packed with
biological activity and
micronutrients when you add fish poop to
your irrigation water you are adding
life force probiotics and active
microbes these microorganisms include a
wealth of various bacteria and protozoa
which further enhance nutrient
availability for the plant
because plants are limited by the
absence of any essential micronutrient
these Trace nutrients are the difference
between having a decent garden and
having a garden that makes you feel
really proud of your efforts fish poop
is a naturally complete solution that
fills in the cracks in your fertilizer
program to ensure you offer your garden
a broad base of nutrients not all fish
poop is created equally most products
with added fish waste don't reveal their
sources or lab results fish poop brand
fish poop however generates their own
fish waste as a byproduct of their
organic aquaponic cannabis farm where
they raise ornamental koi and tilapia
you are even invited to tour their Farm
in person or on their YouTube channel to
look for yourself this sort of
transparency is wildly rare in the
fertilizer Market the folks behind fish
poop are also lifelong medical Canabis
producers who have deep Connections in
the community donate more product than
they sell and support support cannabis
prisoner veteran and patient collectives
and Charities to get your bottle of pure
fish poop go to fish poop.com and to see
their entire line of cannabis products
go to ounce ofh hope.com that's fish
poop brand fish poop welcome back you
are listening to shaping fire I'm your
host Shango and my guest today is
neurologist Dr Ethan Russo so before the
break we were talking about um the study
that this new study was based on um the
various advantages that we're starting
to see teased out of CBG and
specifically this study how it looked at
the anxiety of patients and cvg's
ability to decrease that anxiety and it
how the study is designed is remarkable
because what it has to do is is subtly
push people's buttons in different ways
and see whether or not um they can
handle have their anxiety buttons pushed
um with the study drug versus the
placebo which we now know was just very
watered down sh Truse so the study
consisted of two interviews between the
research assistant and the participant
one week apart via Zoom so before the
interview the research subject ingests a
vial of either 20 milligram of whole
plant CBG tincture or the watered down
chartreuse place IO then when the
interviewer starts some baseline
demographic questions are asked just to
kind of like get him talking but then a
whole battery of tests take place and I
got to say Ethan reading about them in
the study they really seem numerous and
varied and designed to stress like any
kind of person out in a way that doesn't
do any permanent damage so um I know
we've got you know a handful of them and
they all work in slightly different ways
so I think I just want to hand you the
mic and let you walk us through these
bious tests and teach us what they are
and and what their goal was sure so uh
at the zero point they had Baseline
assessments mood anxiety stress and drug
effects uh it may seem strange to ask
about drug effect questions when
nothing's on board but you you want to
establish uh
comparison um before the drug is
administered so at that time as you
mentioned they take the CBG tincture or
the uh chartreuse
Placebo um then they take an online
survey using uh up some time and the
first testing was at the 20 minute Mark
and I want to mention here we got a
criticism uh from One reviewer about you
know why did you start then probably
wasn't doing anything but in the interim
there was a pharmacokinetics study done
pharmacokinetics is what are the effects
uh how long does it take for certain
effects to appear and we were able to
show that when people took CBG
orally uh that the effects begin
um and are seemingly well established by
the 20 minute
mark So at the 20 minute Mark there were
tests of mood anxiety stress and drug
effect
ratings then um they take the thing
called a trior social stress test they
be get more uh ratings of all those
parameters at 45 minutes um and then um
between 45 and 60 Minutes they'd have
the California verbal learning test to
which assesses memory impairment and
they'd have the Druid application uh
Druid is an app that's designed to
assess motor and reaction times and
whether someone's impaired um and you
know this is something that's been
validated and it's done on a smartphone
and then uh at time 3 it's 60 minutes
again the mood anxiety stress and drug
effect ratings so there were different
time points and as you mentioned these
different types of of testing um to see
uh What uh would
happen so in choosing these studies did
you approach them as okay these are the
studies that are always used by
scientists um who study anxiety like
where this is a preset battery or you or
did you as the designer of the study
have to go and choose these yourself off
the shelf um because they're the ones
that you respect and the ones that are
were going to tease out the kind of um
data points that you wanted to look at
I'm just trying to figure out whether or
not these are like boilerplate studies
or whether or not um this is more of a
custom or deal well you know there are
always differences but uh these are well
accepted um types of studies to look at
these
parameters um so basically what I could
say if you looked at studies from Johns
Hopkins like the lyine and THC study we
just did lot of overlap in the tests
that were done uh and that's for a
reason these are - tested measures uh
that are well accepted uh in the
scientific Community when you you look
at these tests uh and H I think I want
to come about this a different way we
know that anxiety comes in a lot of
different forms and and you know people
on Vashon Island here where I live have
been taking CBG tincture for a couple
years and and the results that people
speak back
anecdotally they they review different
types of anxiety that the tinure helps
with as you were designing the study
what were you looking to pull out of the
various um the V various tests that you
were giving folks and and I'm not asking
you to necessarily go through them all
but but so we can understand how to
scientifically think through these tests
would you maybe compare two or three of
them and say well this one is looking at
this type of anxiety versus this one's
looking at the different type of anxiety
because unfortunately most people who
who have anxiety they just say I'm
anxious without the ever having had the
opportunity to think about what kind of
anxiety they may have yeah well there
are different types uh free floating
anxiety so-called would just be feeling
anxious in general situ situational
anxiety would be I get stressed when I
have to go
outside um but um
again and I although I was a psych major
in college I'm not an an expert on this
but I can assure you that Dr Cutler and
Dr Cooper are um but uh again um one of
the tests is called a state
anxiety um and um another is more
specific for
stress um as as might be precipitated by
subtracting 17 from a high number and
having to repeat it um so I don't think
I've given you a great answer but um
what I can say is that over time we saw
these statistically significant
differences in the these folks tested
twice between their uh experience on the
CBG and their experience on the placebo
and because you know it wasn't always
one before the other it was random as to
which came first you can control um so
it's not a matter of well you know I'm
not stressed because I I knew they were
going to subtract SE have me subtract 17
from a high number and it wasn't as bad
the second time um in general um these
are set up in a way that uh there
shouldn't be these big practice
effects um I want to poke at that a
little bit the the term practice effects
is one I'm unfamiliar with so that might
be what I'm asking about but okay so
let's assume that the tincture that is
was the CBG tinure presented a certain
way and then the chartreuse presented a
certain way and they both seemed like
they could have been the CBG tinure
which was the goal so that's great but
we those of us who who do use CBG
regularly it really has a a huge effect
on on anxiety in my own personal
experience I I have experienced this so
do you have a data point that speaks all
to um to what
degree uh the the test subjects were
able to determine which one was likely
the study drug not not based on
presentation but based on based on oh my
God this works so much better than the
one other one I had the other one must
have been the
placebo well uh you know I we didn't
record people's reaction that way um you
don't want to probe too deeply at this
point when you're trying to get two sets
of data points and again you might get
varying degrees of response in an
individual but you need numbers in this
instance 34 folks to see what the
overall effect is and whether it has
statistical significance so my answer to
your very pertinent question
is we rate the benefit in terms of
statistics um
and now I need to give a little primer
on
statistics
um statistics the the lower the number
is the more significant it is something
is considered medically
significant if it has a probability or P
value under
05 what that means is there's less than
a chance One Chance in 20 that the
results occurred due to chance meaning
that when it's 05 or less we consider
that likely a real effect and then as
the numbers are smaller it's more
statistically significant so in this
instance um the subjective
anxiety uh ratios there was a moderately
large size significant effect of the
condition meaning one versus the other
that P value was
034 so under the
05 and over time it was very significant
so uh P value of
0.001 that means one chance in a th000
that this could be just a chance
occurrence that's a real effect anytime
there's one chance in a th000 uh that
you know
this it it it really is highly
statistically
significant um similarly the stress
ratings um the effect over time uh P
value of
0.001 um and um a large siiz simple
effect of the condition on the change in
subjective stress ratings again a
032 it's under the
05 um but at the same time there were
not major changes in in
mood um the thing called the state
anxiety scores uh again showed a large
statistically significant main effect
over time
.1 now if we were looking at the graphs
from the study you can see that there's
a
clear demarcation there's space between
the effects on Placebo and the effects
on CBG and the bigger the space between
those the more significant it is um in
these you can see that the differences
are pretty clear um you know again this
wasn't a situation where we asked people
for a lot of
introspection on what they thought was
going on it it really had to be
objective meaning what did the test show
um uh so you know it would have been
interesting to ask people more about
their
reactions so that's one thing we showed
these clear
statistical and significant changes
looking at anxiety and stress with these
standardized
measures um but um at what cost in other
words were the people impaired when this
happened I mean you can make someone no
longer anxious by sedating them um so
what would really be important is to
have benefit on anx anxiety without
sedation so we looked at other measur
meur es one was a measure of
intoxication so this is a a place where
if there were a lot of THC you'd expect
you get significant difference between
that preparation and
Placebo um we also had drug effect
ratings and this is asking people about
their
reactions and um how much they like the
drug uh so most often cannabis users in
a clinical trial setting will report
that they liked a certain amount of
THC so three measures there but we saw
no significant differences between the
canaberal and the placebo at any time
point with respect to intoxication
ratings there were almost straight lines
same with drug effect and same with drug
liking so no space between the lines at
the three time points 20 minutes 45
minutes and 60 minutes this is really
remarkable because if you test any other
drug used for anxiety like azod dipene
Valium
diazapam um almost always there's going
to be significant sedation or other
complaints and we just didn't see that
and then there's another dimension
here
um I'm sorry I want to talk a little
more about uh subjective drug effects um
so these are rated zero to um zero not
at all to 10 extreme um and again there
were no significant differences between
CBG and Placebo at any of the three time
points 20 minutes 45 minutes or 60
Minutes um
then uh again if we have a drug that's
good for
anxiety um we want to make sure that
it's not producing any impairment so
memory tests were part of the
trials um then a very surprising and
important thing happened which was
people on the CBG actually did me better
on memory tests and this was St
statistically
significant um so there was a moderate
size significant effect of the condition
uh and that's at the the probability 05
level and a large statistically
significant effect over time meaning
looking at all the time points and that
P value was 0. one so that supports the
idea that on this verbal memory test
that the performance was significantly
better on CBG than it was on Placebo
this is not what you expect um from most
studies of this type especially on
cannabis yeah exactly but again lacking
THC cpg is a different kettle of fish it
really is distinctly different in what
it does
um and to me this might be the the most
uh
surprising finding yeah it was
definitely surprising to me reading it
it was actually kind of like a plot
twist in a book as I was reading the
study I'm like oh I I didn't know that
was here and I didn't certainly didn't
expect it coming I I I believe that this
next question is outside the scope of
the study but as a neurologist and as
somebody who has spent their life
studying cannabis I bet you have an
opinion which is do you think that the
improved memory um was more related to
um something the something that CBG was
doing to actually improve memory
function or do you think it was because
um memory was increased in the absence
of the anxiety which the CBG had solved
for right well it's likely the latter uh
that the reduction in anxiety and a test
situation led to better performance
however that might not only be it um
there could be Memory enhancing
properties and that is going to have to
be teased out in subsequent studies so
there's plenty more to do um I did want
to indicate that there was one final
thing that we tested that was again very
important and that was the question of
impairment of any type type um and um in
fact again um
CBG showed um lack of impairment uh
participants performed significantly
better um and the trial times two and
three after um taking CBG than they did
on
Placebo um so uh again uh something that
may not really have been expected but
what I like to say is what the world
needs now is an effective drug for
anxiety that doesn't produce impairment
or sedation or addiction and we may have
it in the form of
canaberal Amen now there's a big
statement that I can get behind my
goodness all right so um uh unless you
have anything else to add regarding the
conclusion I of the study I'm about to
go to break and we'll after after the
set break we will we will talk about
ramifications and next steps but do you
have anything else regarding the
conclusions of the study that you want
to uh tuck in here before we move on
well I could summarize now or after the
break all right well since you're going
to summarize let's summarize uh after
the break because we'll be summarizing a
couple different points so um you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is neurologist Dr Ethan Russo
[Music]
one of the challenges with buying
Autoflower seeds is that often you'll
have as many different fenos as you will
have seeds in a pack that can be fun
sure but so many varieties in one pack
is a sign of an immature seedline that
hasn't been worked enough I prefer my
autof flowers to be worked enough that
each pheno in the pack really captures
the aspects that the breeder was
intending this is why I recommend gnome
automatics to my friends and listeners
who grow automatic flowering cannabis
seeds
gnome automatic seeds are not just
crossed and released they are
painstakingly sifted again and again
tested in a wide range of conditions and
taken to a level of maturity that each
plant will be recognizable by its traits
traits that were hard earned so that you
can have your best growth cycle ever
over the last 10 years gnome automatics
founder Dan Jimmy has become a trusted
breeder and he continues to pour His
passion of breeding cannabis into every
variety he releases for you to grow
check out the gnome automatics Instagram
_ automatics to see the impressive
plants folks are growing you can score
gnome automatic seeds in feminized or
regular at your favorite seed provider
listed in the vendor section of their
website commercial cannabis Farms across
the country love growing gnome
automatics because of their consistency
from seed de seed short grow times THC
percentages and colorful bag appeal
Farms interested in bulk seeds of more
than a thousand should reach out through
gnome automatics.com
while on the website be sure to check
out the gnome automatic shirts and other
merch section too if you want reliable
seeds handbuilt from effort expert
selection and experience choose gnome
[Music]
automatics sometimes the topics I want
to share with you are far too brief for
an entire shaping Fire episode in those
instances I post them to Instagram I
invite you to follow my two Instagram
profiles and participate online the
shaping fire Instagram has followup
posts to shaping fire episodes growing
and processing best practices product
trials and of course gorgeous flower
photos the Shango Los Instagram follows
my travels on cannabis garden tours my
successes and failures in my own garden
insights and best practices from
personal grows everywhere and always
gorgeous flower photos on both profiles
the emphasis is on sharing what I've
learned in a way that you can replicate
it in your own garden your own hash lab
or for your own canopic health so I
encourage you to follow @ shaping fire
and Shango and join our online community
on
[Music]
Instagram you've heard me talk about the
award-winning cannabis seeds that come
from the analytical breeding program of
Seth and Eric Crawford who founded
Oregon CBD seeds in fact Seth was a
guest on shaping fire in 2020 to talk
about triploid genetics Seth and Eric
are now releasing high THC seeds for
homeg Growers and Farms as grow the
revolution seeds at GTR seeds.com their
high THC seeds are extraordinary and
that they will start to flower at 16 1/2
hours of daylight instead of the typical
14 1/2 hours of daylight that means in
most regions your plants will start to
flower outdoors in the middle of July
instead of the middle of August August
which means these photo period plants
finish in September and not October
totally upending the photo period Seed
Market Seth and Eric took their prized
early flowering CBG line and bred it to
some of the most desired verified
genetics out there including Sour Diesel
triangle cush wedding cake chem dogs
Skittles and others these crosses all
Express powerful photo period tarpine
profiles and THC giving you a great High
GTR seeds has a new thcv line with
plants like double Durban and Gigantor
that boast one:1 THC to thcv and people
want that
thcv GTR seeds are very consistent true
growing inbred f1s from stabilized
inbred parent lines these seeds are
nearly homogeneous and the plants should
all grow the same there is only one
phenotype in every pack available as
diploids and triploids Seth and Eric's
company is still family-owned patient
employee Centric and partially powered
by their two acres of solar panels
everyone can purchase these seeds and
the entire catalog of Oregon CBD seeds
at GTR seeds.com go to GTR seeds.com
today and choose something revolutionary
for your next indoor or outdoor run
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire and I am your host Shango
Los and my guest today is neurologist Dr
Ethan Russo so here we are in the big
third set wrapping things up and you
know Ethan the throughout our
conversation the thing that really send
tends to Glow big in this study is that
78% of the participants said that CBG
works better than their pharmaceutical
or other traditional medication and that
is a staggeringly successful number in
my eyes that nearly 80% of people said
that CBG was better than whatever they
normally use does this stand out to you
as a research scientist too being like
an oh my God
moment uh yeah it was a surprise to me
that it was that high but
um
perhaps in retrospect with uh 3 years
since then it's less of a surprise to me
because in our formulation work we've
been using CBG
extensively and uh the results bear this
out it is an
extremely versatile medicine that uh
really contributes greatly to
therapeutic
effects and it just feeds into your uh
your statement right before we went to
commercial about how how big the impact
of this can be in you know reducing
human suffering from anxiety I mean it's
a big deal even even though you and I
are becoming increasingly comfortable
with it right yes yeah so um one of the
attributes or one of the aspects that I
think is worthy of looking at is that so
many people presently use CBD and or THC
for their anxiety now and and CBD CBG
and THC have all three of them got
different um modes of
operation um approaching um anxiety as
you mentioned in the last set one of the
magical things that not magical one of
the impressive things that CBG does is
decrease anxiety without intoxication
which as most of us know is is exactly
the mode of operation for why THC works
it sedates people and for many people
that handles you know their major type
of anxiety and it decreases so would you
please do us the favor of comparing CBG
versus THC for anxiety and then CBG G
versus CBD so we can tease out a little
bit more what is unique about CBG
compared to these two which are very
common commonly used in the Cannabis
World sure
so THC is a very strange one in this
regard it's it's well known that uh it
THC can be helpful or hurt anxiety and
it's really a matter of dose so very
very small doses have an anti- anxiet
effect whereas higher doses can
certainly induce anxiety or even Panic
um and this is an effect that's been
known for 4,000 years because it was in
the ancient Assyrian literature on
relation to cannabis it was said to be
for or against panic and again a matter
of dose is is that the biphasic nature
is that the is that the vocabulary it's
called a basic dose response with THC
now if CBG induces anxiety I don't know
what the dose is um we know anecdotally
that people have taken very high doses
and not um had this problem
um so I don't know what the upper limit
is
um in this instance CBG probably is a
safer bet if the target is an xiety
because um we know that there's a dose
range that seems to be effective and uh
without the intoxication that can occur
if the te dose gets too high um uh you
know so how about the two together well
again um in our formulation work we're
using CBG with uh low doses of THC and
uh seemingly it's a really use full
adjunct thing to add that improves
clinical
response um so there seem to be these at
least additive or even synergistic
benefits on pain sleep and mood um and
having CBG aboard may increase What's
called the therapeutic index of THC
meaning the amount that you can use
without producing side effects uh and
making the overall effect that much
greater so the idea is that adding CBG
tier THC May relay may relieve some of
the negative outcomes of THC and
therefore helping THC do its job while
CBG is doing its job quite right and
we're we're seeing this where we have
situations of people rating their
effects of different kavars and we know
know what the certificates of analysis
tell us about the proportions of the
different components it's it's easy to
see these patterns uh one of the things
we're hearing consistently is when
there's a significant amount of CBG in
the preparation along with the THC that
it's much better
tolerated um that people have a good
experience or benefit on symptoms
without THC Associated side
effects we've seen some of that
anecdotally as well here on Vashon
Island because um since the the CBG
dominant cultivar has been grown here on
the island for a few years um people who
historically had a strong anxious
reaction U dysphoric response to smoking
cannabis um even if they used you know
Edibles or Oils or things like that some
folks you know they just smoking doesn't
work for them because it it shoots them
up really fast and and some some folks
don't like that people started um uh
mixing CBG flour um in with their THC
flour and and and a lot of those um you
know sharp increases in anxiety were
relieved and you know that those are
those are very small number of people
but again shows the potential for use
for folks who are also needing THC for
some other issue that they're dealing
with but CBG can take the the edge off
definitely do you have do you have
compar similar comparisons of CBG versus
CBD used for anxiety okay so let's look
at why people use them we we've
mentioned that uh the survey patients uh
use CBG to treat pain anxiety and Aid
sleep we we often hear the same claims
for CBD but we have to purse this out if
we're talking about
CBD as an
isolate it actually is alerting at low
and moderate doses it's only at extreme
doses again this basic dose response
that CBD actually
um produces any kind of
sedation um with respect to anxiety
we know now after these studies that
there's a distinct
difference CBD was studied in this um an
article by buram masi at all in Brazil
some years ago they looked at Social
Anxiety which is akin to what we were
doing here it required 400 milligrams of
CBD isolate to produce a significant
anti-anxiety
effect we got the anti-anxiety effect
with 20 milligrams so that's a 20 fold
difference in
dose uh meaning that it appears that CBG
is much more potent as an anti-anxiety
agent 400 mgram of CBD is going to be
quite expensive no matter what kind of
preparation whereas hopefully with a CBG
only
kovar um 20 milligrams is is just not
that much uh should should be much more
economical and I suspect more effective
overall uh do we know enough about the
mode of operation of CBD versus CBG to
know what they may be doing differently
certainly based on the the size of dose
um it it suggests we should move in
towards CBG but but having used both
independently um for my anxiety I just
simply find CBG to be wildly more
effective than CBD which makes me think
that it's doing something different than
the CBD uh quite likely and again some
of this gets into some really he heavy
effects uh in different areas of the
brain and and
neurotransmitters um what I believe and
we'll need to have subsequent studies
like functional MRI or uh pet scans to
look at this but um this is likely
affecting um uh the lyic system uh
emotional areas of the brain um and yeah
likely are a lot of distinct differences
but um that's going to require more
investigation yeah that sounds like a
great shaping Fire episode too so uh
soon as you've got that research done uh
make sure you let me know
e yeah it might be a while um another
thing that I want to point out uh you
just compared uh the 20 Mig of whole
plant CBG dominant tincture to 400 Mig
of CBD isolate and we've already talked
a little bit uh on other times that we
have spoken about the difference between
isolate and whole plant
preparations um one of the ideas that
the paper puts forward is that
um one way to tweak the study to look
for uh additional benefits would be to
increase the dosage of the CBG from from
the 20 Mig that was delivered up to 25
to 50 mg because some of the other
science that is being done at this time
are is using isolate up to 50 milligrams
but to me someone who's very much into
whole plant medicine um the efficacy of
isolate and whole resin aren't the same
and time and time again we see um CBD
isolate for example not showing the same
efficacy as whole plant how do you weigh
for yourself um you know 20 mg of whole
plant tincture that was used in your
study versus 25 to 50 milligrams of
isolate being used in a different study
it seems to me like those are it would
be very hard to compare those because
they're not apples and apples yeah it's
a problem and this is why um certainly
when I'm reviewing uh big acting as a
peer reviewer on other studies I want
specification on what's being utilized
in other words we want to see studies
where there actually is a certificate of
analysis as we provideed here
um in contrast where you've got studies
where uh let's say you're looking at
pain um and um there are a whole bunch
of different preparations they might be
THC predominant or they might be type
tws with uh THC and CBD different doses
different modes of administration it's
very hard to parse out what's doing what
and you come up with generalities like
cannabis helps with pain that's nice but
um science really demands more
specificity um and that's why I believe
believe that studies of this type where
we have a
defined uh
preparation uh we can it's it's much
easier to to make these claims
particularly since we had so many
significant
results I think that a lot of Citizen
scientists and caregivers like myself we
we find ourselves running into an issue
where um the studies that are being done
right now are being used are being done
with isolate because isolate is just a
single molecule of the
cannabinoid and um it's very specific
and and and it's also those studies uh
transition very easily to to
pharmaceutical research um your research
on the other hand I Harald because you
have the audacity to use the plant um as
it's grown and using a whole resin and
it in ways that that actual patients
actual humans have been using it for
thousands of years um but I can see that
since you choose to not use isolate you
might get some push back from either
people who want to use your work for
pharmaceutical applications or folks who
just think that a a plant resin is too
wild if you will there's too many
variables because there's cannabinoids
that don't even show up in the COA but
but those of us who are into whole plant
medicine we we still hold on that that's
where the future of cannabis medicine is
so you know as somebody you um who has
been a long time uh proponent of the
Entourage effect and whole plant
medicine how do you see it personally as
as why you choose to use whole plant
medicine versus
isolate uh well the number one reason is
I believe in the Synergy of the
different components um however I've
been on the other side of the fence too
keep in mind uh the study we just did
with loning um isolate with THC isolate
sometimes you require a deconstruction
and
reconstruction to understand what the
differences are so I see a a place for
both in research when it comes to
Therapeutics I'm firmly in the camp that
you want an extract and not an
isolate right on that sounds good for me
and it seems to work best on uh on the
things that we're trying to do with with
real people so Ethan do you have any um
other uh summary or or impact that you
would like to share before we wrap up uh
sure you know going back to the study uh
that we did I'd like to run through some
key points if May yes okay so this was
the first study of canaba gereral
looking at anxiety in humans um so we're
very pleased with that and it's often a
Race Against Time to get these things
published before somebody else does it
so um we're pleased with that um so
canaural
reduced anxiety and stress in this sort
of manufactured setting um you had asked
about the degree I have another figure
that we can utilize here so there was an
average decrease in .95 out of
10 um uh that's a 26% reduction in the
anxiety and stress scores that were
already low to begin with um so you know
what does this mean to somebody who has
a clinical anxiety disorder um we can't
say from this but you know and I know
from people that have utilized CBG
preparations that they're usually very
pleased with the
results uh another Point uh in this
study CBG actually enhanced verbal
memory and it did that with no
significant impairments either in memory
or motor functioning that's psychomotor
speed and balance that was what the
Druid app looked at uh so the CBG Dr
Druid score was lower and comparable to
Placebo and
Baseline um again we saw no evidence
that CBG was
intoxicating um the intoxication and
drug effect ratings were under one on a
10-point scale and Drug liking remain
neutral throughout the study um and in
terms of side effects negative drug
effect ratings like dry eyes rapid heart
rate dry mouth uh those remain low and
did not differ from Placebo uh so all of
these really indicate that this seems to
be have an extremely benign profile at
the same time that it's producing
significant effects on Stress and
Anxiety well that's a great summary and
you know on a on a real human level I
can only imagine that you and Dr Cutler
are pretty stoked with how this survey
turned out or how the research turned
out uh yes um we're definitely going on
from here we have immediate plans for
two more studies um one would be similar
to this but done in the lab uh which
allows for greater objective measures um
you know measuring blood pressure
measuring cortisol a stress hormone uh
measuring reactions to pain on a thing
called the cold pressure test so that'll
be up uh coming up and we also have
plans for a clinical study uh where uh
CBG
preparation um would be looked at uh uh
in terms of a a an actual
disorder mean like a one like you'll
Target one yes exactly I see good well
Dr Russo thank you so much for uh being
a guest today again on shaping fire I
mean you've been on the show so many
times over over the years now I think
this is going to be 115 episode 115 and
every time you do we learn we learn
something new and great and and usually
on the cusp of the science so um we
really appreciate you taking your very
valuable time and joining us and and and
letting us know what the latest is and
and what it means to us well always
pleasure I really welcome this
opportunity so dear listener if you
would like to follow along with Dr
Russo's research there are two good
places to do that um the first one is
you can follow along with uh Dr Russo's
research organization katos scientific
so that's k c d
o- science.com or in even better places
to um get familiar with Dr Russo's
library of research online at Ethan
rouso so R Us sso.org
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast And subscribe to
the show at shaping fire.com and
wherever you get your podcasts if you
enjoyed the show we'd really appreciate
it if you would leave a positive review
of the podcast wherever you download
your review will help others find the
show so they can enjoy it too on the
shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for insights
into the latest Cannabis News exclusive
videos and giveaways on the shaping fire
website you also find transcripts of
today's podcast as well be sure to
follow on Instagram for all original
content not found on the podcast that's
@ shaping fire and @ Shango on Instagram
be sure to check out shaping fire
YouTube channel for exclusive interviews
farm tours and cannabis lectures does
your company want to reach our national
audience of cannabis enthusiasts email
hotspot shaping fire.com to find out how
thanks for listening to shaping fire
I've been your host Shango Los
[Music]