[Music]
i'm not really a big fan of holidays
ever since i was a kid everyone around
me had these huge expectations on what
they wanted their holiday to look like
it created an ungodly amount of pressure
to perform for the delight of others and
to soothe them when their childish
desires were not met
it is exhausting and i've only realized
how much it has impacted my life in the
last couple of years during quarantine
because of all the time i've had for
self-reflection and a bit of tick-tock
therapy too
i shared this with you as a cautionary
tale about keeping your expectations low
because on this episode on shaping fire
i'm the special guest
today on shaping fire we are sharing my
recent appearance as guest on the
curious about cannabis podcast the
show's host jason wilson is absolutely
delightful and we share a similar vibe
the interview covers my thoughts on
using outdoor regenerative cultivation
techniques indoors the rocky transition
from medical to recreational markets for
cannabis patients at the state level how
to form local growers collectives and
how i form the one here on vashon island
the rise of autoflowers of course and
some behind the scenes thoughts about
shaping fire the podcast among other
topics it's a whole lot of good stuff in
there
and jokes about the holidays and low
expectations aside i'm sharing this
interview because i'm actually proud of
what jase and i produced i certainly
don't share all the podcasts where i
appear but this one is especially well
done and i think you might enjoy it
for those of you who prefer video you
can watch the curious about cannabis
video recording of this interview today
on the shaping fire youtube channel
i do want to note that i get the
sniffles at one point and for those of
you not watching the video i'm actually
recording my side of the video outside
on my deck and it was pretty chilly that
morning and i got the sniffles
so i hope you have a delightfully
tolerable holiday weekend by yourself or
with loved ones and enjoy this episode
66 of curious about cannabis hosted by
jason wilson with special guest me
shango los hey everybody this is jason
with curious about cannabis thanks so
much for tuning in once again
today i am really really excited because
we've got kind of a convergence of
cannabis podcasts here
but i'm connecting with somebody who
i've been told repeatedly by guest after
guest that i've interviewed that this is
a person i need to connect with
i've been told that um
a lot of the people that interviewed
that i remind them of this person so we
finally made it happen um i'm here with
shanghai los of the shaping fire podcast
shingo thanks so much for being willing
to take the time today to connect and
come on the podcast
hey jason well thanks for having me
thanks for the invitation i'm happy to
be here absolutely and you know right
off the top i want to say
um
thank you for the work that you do
because as
you know uh a scientist in this field
and and kind of crawling out of my cave
into media and trying to connect with
the outside world you know i definitely
recognize that that your work has been
some of the best that i've come across
in terms of trying to
uh connect lay people
with technical information in a
digestible way that's relevant
um so my hat's off to you man um thanks
so much for the the great work that
you've been doing so far
well thank you very much um i really put
my heart into it i'm always doing my
best and i really enjoy it as well yeah
and um and now that the show has grown
you know that we're in our fourth year
now of shaping fire it's gotten to the
point where uh it can support me now so
so that is nice it was a lot of a lot of
years of doing multiple jobs um but but
i'm at the point now that i can i can
really focus on the show and you know um
i'm very grateful for the opportunity
that's yeah that's so awesome and
hopeful for me to hear because i'm only
you know we're just past like a year and
a half or so of curious about cannabis
um running and so i'm in that period
right now working like multiple jobs
balancing this too and trying to to make
it all happen so i can totally
totally relate to that that hustle
um and i know that a lot of my listeners
because they've told me a lot of my
listeners do already listen to shaping
fire but to those that are unfamiliar
don't know who you are do you mind uh
providing just a little bit of
background
into um
you know first what shaping fire is and
then i want to work backwards and just
talk about kind of your relationship
with cannabis and and uh your general
story
all right well then i guess i'll just
start with talking a little bit about
shaping fire and then you can lead me
wherever you want to leave perfect after
that
so um
shaping fire is a audio only podcast
that focuses on uh cannabis health
cultivation
and uh solventless extraction techniques
and so
it is in the early days but for the
first year
i was focused to a great deal on
cannabis business but over time um not
only were there a lot of other people
covering cannabis business but i i
realized that after
medical cannabis went away in my state
of washington and my national clients in
medical started converting to rec that
um the vibe changed in the scene
and i wasn't as excited about covering
business anymore i was really much more
interested in
cannabis patients
different uh cultivars um um how working
with them in different preparations
helps uh human health
and then
um after
uh you know after i learned how to make
um uh ice hash
and then once ice rosin came on the
scene
i realized that that most of us can do
all the things that we need for cannabis
at home without even
interfacing with the licensed market and
while and while i wish the licensed
market success and i've got lots of
friends in the licensed market
um uh i found that that wasn't the part
that i was most excited about the part i
was excited about
was um small cannabis communities home
grow
and and you know people trading cannabis
so that so they had greater variety so
so that's essentially what uh shaping
fire covers now um we have got uh you
know some of the best um guests in the
whole world available to us
we're pulling in
you know
botany botanists um scientists from the
lab folks who are you know neurologists
um
also cannabis breeders uh you know a
master uh master hashmaker sounds like
that right yeah but but folks are very
talented and experienced with making
hash and and so um i bring him on the
show and
and we talk a lot of specifics the idea
of the show was always
to give people enough um uh information
to be able to take action it frustrates
me when i listen to a podcast that is
supposed to be teaching me but it leaves
all these big gaps and so i really do my
best to
provide content that gives people a nice
full package so that they can either
make decisions or or do the technique or
or understand their health better in in
one nice tight 90 minute package
and so uh so so that's that's the nature
of the show and um
you know i like to say that uh shaping
fire with shaping for your get educated
while we respect your time right um i
don't spend a lot of time like you know
i don't get high on the show i don't i
don't talk about my guests with talk to
my guests about what cultivars they're
smoking like there's different shows
that do that and that's cool and
and it draws a kind of audience that
wants that kind of
um
um i don't know bro vibe right yeah like
hanging out yeah
yeah totally and they'll do these long
shows but but the kinds of folks who
tend to listen to shaping fire tend to
be you know cannabis uh enthusiasts who
also have got other things they've got
to get done maybe they run companies
maybe they are you know made their
decision makers uh or they're just like
people who are busy yeah and so i try
not to waste folks time i try to get in
get the point get people the information
that they're going to need on whatever
the topic and then and then end the show
and you know in a cheerful way
absolutely well and that's that's
something i really respect because
that's been
um a big part of my approach too and
part of that comes from just like my
analytical thinking as a scientist but
i'm like yeah i don't get high on the
show just it's really just what's the
the core piece of information that's
interesting and and making that
digestible and i noticed that in your
marketing you know that uh we're trying
not to waste your time um and i i love
that um and i also appreciate what you
just said about watching the
this transition and the vibe change from
as things switch from medical to wreck
because i definitely
experienced the same thing here in
oregon you know i was involved in the
medical program
i was a medical patient and also working
um you know building this lab to try to
help people understand what was in their
products and we were dealing mostly with
patients a lot of medical patients that
were make growing their own cannabis
making their own products and wanting to
understand whether they were safe to
consume and what the potency was and
that sort of thing and then you do see
this shift and now
all of it is just so so different
and it's hard i think for some people to
appreciate just how substantially
things have changed if they weren't
involved in the medical systems before
you know everything started to come
online especially in other states that
you know are taking a little longer to
to make some of these changes to their
laws
um so can you speak to that a little bit
uh just to expand a little bit more on
your perspective
on just exactly how things changed from
uh kind of the early medical days into
um you know the legal systems that we
have now what were some of those changes
you started to pick up on
sure um i've got three that i think are
probably good to hit on the first one is
we've already hit on a little bit which
is
the the players changed who was involved
uh during the medical days um you know
there were there were more heritage
cultivators and heritage medicine errors
who were involved um who were not uh
they were fringe folks because there was
a lot to lose back in the metal medical
days too when they were still still
being raids and and things and the laws
were changing and so many people were
working in the gray market
that um you know most of us had some of
the people in law enforcement who were
supporting our our you know ability to
create medicine and put it in the hands
of cannabis patients but there were
other folks in law enforcement who were
not ascribing to that and so uh it made
it very risky and and you know
once it became
more safe for capital
um
and licensing started to happen
the the capital came and with that comes
a different kind of risk assessment and
different um
different uh bureaucracy for the the
players and a lot of the the heritage
cultivators they didn't have the the the
credit score
to to rent a loan a legal location or
they didn't have the business acumen
because
at their heart they were farmers right
or alchemists how they saw themselves
not really as business people
and the people who were organized and
did have capital to be able to to rent
legal places and go through the state
bureaucracy and end up getting the
licenses and know how to hire out for hr
and know how to sell to investors those
are a different kind of person and and
again i don't intend and it's not my
goal here to diss those folks because i
think that uh increased access in every
state is important and access is is a
priority
um it very much changed from a
we're in it for the patients and i've
been around cannabis all you know for
years and we're trying to do our best by
the patients into being something that
has
more
neon lights and and finer packaging you
know yeah and now the vibe changed and
and and for you know and so so that was
a significant difference um the second
thing i'll point out is that the
the the varieties of products change now
certainly
now that we're many more years in um to
legalization in or at least licensing in
some states there are beginning to be
more
patient-focused products
but
just about every state that has medical
first and then they go wreck there is
this sudden dearth of medical products
when the licenses uh come out
because licensed folks know that the
things that are always a reliable sell
are high thc flour and so that's what
everybody starts with you know and i had
plenty of clients who are making this
transition they're like all right
start with the high thc flower once we
get that established then we're going to
roll out the other products well for
patients who had gotten off their their
pharmaceuticals
that gap could literally kill them um
either because they had to go back to
pharmaceuticals and they were dealing
with those side effects or um they had
gotten to a point where the body had
healed enough in certain ways that they
couldn't go back to those same
pharmaceuticals without it being a bumpy
ride of getting your body back attuned
to a pharmaceutical solution instead of
an herbal solution
and so um
so uh you know a perfect example for
that is um full extract um cannabis oil
so an ethanol extract most of us know it
is rso so rso usually disappears from
the market
during the transition from medical
to recreational and then when it does
start to show up in a wreck market
you'll find companies who are like
selling their co2 rso right which is not
you know you know
it's not the same thing right
because it's more economical for them to
run it you know through a co2 machine
than it is for them to do the more often
laborious
um ethanol extraction
and um and so the
there's this there's this little variety
of
uh products are gone however with the
legal market some really cool things
have come about like um really uh great
dispensers
um for for rso
and some of the inhalers are pretty
incredible um certainly the uh the
advancement of vaporizers has just
wildly expanded so there's been a lot of
things that they could that have come
with the licensed market too but i think
that's more to do with the the idea that
um
it's easier for these cannabis companies
to get funding now for their novel
products where um you know uh medical is
pre-capitalist capital right and so
there was it was a lot harder to for for
those companies and my third example
also involves rso the uh the full
extract oil you know back in the day
if you had if you needed rso because you
were sick um you could go to
at least on the west coast you could go
to some kind of uh you know patient
cannabis exchange of some sort right
and you know they they were often you
know straddling the gray market and you
know they they were they're often you
know kind of straddling legality but the
heart was there and the quality was
there often and um the people were
smiling and there were lots of hugs and
it felt like a family thing
and um and depending on where you were
regionally you could get um a one
milliliter syringe of high quality rso
for between 15 and 60 bucks 15 or 50
bucks depending on where you were
and and here and here is the example
part is that
you know just about everybody i knew who
made rso had a discount for people who
were doing a 60 milliliters and 90 days
cannabis protocol right yeah because if
you if you had cancer and you had found
yourself um you know gonna try rso
you're either already kind of like an
herbally minded person yeah or you were
already broke because the western system
had already taken all your money the
doctors are already taking them all and
so you were you were at your last bet
and you were gonna try cannabis right so
usually you know the people who had
cancer and were ready to try rso were
already broke and we all felt bad for
them because they had cancer right yeah
terrible terrible thing to have to deal
with and so you'd get people who
you know would give somebody a huge
reduction
say say if they were selling their
syringes for you know fifty dollars
normally
they would you know if you're gonna buy
60 we'll drop the price down to 25 bucks
right we'll do it half price and like
sure some of that is like you're buying
in volume right everybody you know
volume discounts are good but but really
it was more than that there was a lot of
heart in that price
and um
the the licensed market is not able to
do that kind of price reduction
and so uh you know there is not bulk
purchasing really in the license market
like you know if you if you need
multiple syringes of rso you buy one for
72 dollars and another for 72 dollars
and then another for 72.
and so people who need cannabis to live
it has become harder for them to
purchase at reasonable prices in the
wreck market which of course is keeping
the um the alternative unlicensed market
very much alive throughout the country
and um and you know the the the rocky
transition from the medical markets in
most states to the wreck um markets
um it has
it's kind of done bad for both it's it
was bad for the medical heritage
processors it's also bad for the
patients and also because
you know this black market is still
being kept alive because it's so needed
it's also bad for iraq so mostly
you know the state's mismanagement of
these transitions from medical to
licensed recreational has just uh given
us a a a worse
of all options
yeah everything that that you just
brought up it brings out a lot of
memories for me thinking about oregon
and the transitions that we saw you know
going from medical
to
to recreational and one thing that i
think about from a patient perspective
particularly when you talk about the
reduction in the diversity of products i
remember
how much experimentation was going on
with cbd thc ratios
leading up to like 2016 or so and
obviously it's still happening but um
in the medical system
you know uh
if i
went to somebody and said i was looking
for a certain ratio or
once dispensaries became legal because
for a while they were kind of in this
weird gray area um
yeah once they became officially legal
you know you could find four to ones
three to ones two to ones one to ones
like you could find all of these things
you know there wouldn't be a lot of them
but they they were solid and uh for me i
have these spinal cord injuries and i
found you know like a two to one to four
to one is uh very nice for that
i noticed that when things went uh
recreational you really don't see a lot
of that anymore um
you know you might see some one-to-ones
um but that's that's most of what you
see and it's either high thc
high cbd is now kind of getting
relegated to hemp but you still see that
in dispensaries um from time to time
um
but but that's it and so for someone
like myself that is a medical patient
that no longer has a card because it's
now legal
um
that uh that was a big change um
and so i i definitely um
have seen a lot of those those same
changes too and hearing you talk about
it you know it's obvious you have a lot
of passion for the patience and a lot of
passion for that you know like you're
saying the
um the kind of source where all of this
you know is is really coming from so
to kind of rewind quite a bit um
do you mind sharing
uh how did your relationship with
cannabis um get started is it something
that goes back into you know teenage or
early 20s for you or is it something
that you discovered later how did that
relationship come about
um i would say i had i had two
beginnings of my relationship with
cannabis because uh the first time was
um
my freshman year of college um
i went home he lived in new york he went
home for christmas and he came back and
he brought some joints
and i had never had access before um
and and you know had never you know seen
it around or anything it just wasn't
where i lived and yeah you know uh
suburbs catholic school that whole thing
and um and he brought it back and you
know i for whatever reason i was
immediately interested in like there was
no second thought he's like oh you want
to try this i'm like yeah let's try new
things you know yes and so we tried it
and i immediately thought it was great
from a an um an experiential
you know
both recreationally because it was fun
um but also i you know i immediately got
the idea of the mind expansion part yeah
i'm like oh wow i really it really
shifts my perspective in ways i can
consider my mundane life in new fresh
ways so i thought that was really cool
and you know it took me you know
about four weeks to get my first bag
after that and then i don't think i've
been without it ever since you know you
know 1990 now or whatever one of the
funny things is um i learned how to you
know smoke canvas um during the first
season of the simpsons oh man wow wow
that goes way back we used to we used to
all get together on i don't know if it
was tuesday or thursday nights but we
don't get together and sit on the floor
of the dorm room and all smoke and watch
that first season of simpsons and that's
that's how i you know was get you know
smoking with friends all the time and
i'm like you know i think i need to get
some of this for myself
so
so then we've got like just like like a
lifetime of being somebody who enjoys
cannabis myself
but then um
2011 came and um i was in a car accident
i suffered a dual concussion resulting
in a traumatic brain injury
and um the neurologist actually told me
off the record he says you know um i
recommend
that you um you know
consider
uh
using mushrooms
to help rebuild your neural net and kind
of soothe the the the overactivity that
i was getting the over stimulation
and he says um
and he said you know i also recommend
that you move out of the city and so i
moved out to vashon island where i live
now
and and and he also said i understand
that there's some you know healing
properties in cannabis he says i can't
recommend any of this for you officially
he says but but if you're you know um
like look into this stuff and i was
astonished right because you know back
in back in those days you know 2011 um
you still like didn't tell your doctor
right right cannabis and i was i was i
was a daily cannabis user at that point
and um and so i'm like huh edison huh
all right and so i started looking into
it and um started you know reading the
early research mostly coming out of
europe and everything i'm like wow there
really are medicinal properties going on
here
and um
and then and then my dad got really bad
knees and so um so so i had already
learned how to make a cannabis tincture
for myself
to help keep my
my nervous system calm and then i
wouldn't get over stimulated
um but then my dad knees got really bad
and and the the pharmaceuticals he was
using for anti-inflammation really had
some bad side effects
and so um
i i said hey i bet you i could put my
tincture
in some like like body lotion or hand
cream or something and whip them
together and boom topical right and so i
tried it and it worked and my dad put it
on his knees and he's all like oh my
gosh this works so much better and for
so much longer
than this like ugly pharmaceutical that
he was one and i don't mean to diss all
pharmaceuticals right sure there are
there are appropriate pharmaceuticals at
appropriate times but in this case an
herbal remedy was much better for my dad
and um he was very enthusiastic about it
and um and that made me feel good about
it as well because um you know my
parents were historically um
discouraging me from yeah
cannabis or you know like drugs in
general right sure yeah parents and uh
but but at this point i'm like wait a
minute something here this is helping me
soothe my brain injury and heal and now
it's helping my dad too
what else is going on and so i dove into
both um
like learning about
cannabis medicine from you know any
sources i could and also trying to learn
uh herbal preparations um i live here in
seattle i live pretty close to bastyr
university yeah and so my whole area is
just like dripping with herbalists
they're everywhere and so you know if
you're you know if
you're nice to them they will tell you
their secrets and so and so that's that
that's when i got my rebirth in the in
the cannabis medicine
in in 2011
and um
and then of course you know things
things have continued uh since then
yeah and and how did that i mean first
of all i want to say
um i get why people wanted us to talk
because
in some ways we have some
big parallels between the the two of us
because
i went through a similar experience with
my mom so after i had all these spinal
cord injuries and trying to figure out
how to get control over
you know myself and and the things that
i was dealing with
um
i had been a regular cannabis user just
like you had described and then you know
kind of discover this new perspective of
looking at it and then uh my mom had
really bad fibromyalgia and you know
arthritis and stuff and very similarly i
gave her some extract that we mixed with
a uh like a coconut oil based um topical
this yeah i can't remember what it was
just really simple just mixed it in
there and likewise she's like oh my gosh
this is better than any pharmaceutical
i've ever taken for
you know for these these problems
so it's funny
those parallels
i can
um totally relate to
and how did
so you you know you start to understand
how cannabis is affecting you and
helping you find this kind of new
balance that you need in your life
and then that's bleeding out into loved
ones and seeing the effects that
cannabis can have on them
um
when did your passion for
education
start to really manifest where you
really started to move forward in
sharing
all of these things that you were
learning with other people because
you've been doing i mean beyond the
podcast you've organized uh all sorts of
events um on vaishan island and other
things like that and i definitely want
to talk about
the work that you've done to really
bring the community together um to learn
and share knowledge and everything so
what were the yeah
how did those seeds i guess get
germinated if you will to bloom into a
lot of the education
i see where you're going yeah um so so
the way the way the timeline went out is
um
hit my head in 2011
started making my own preparations and
you know when you're making tincture
and and it's working for you and and
people your friends and loved ones find
out you're making it suddenly they're
using your tinctures
and then and then their loved ones are
and and then medical
got going uh more significantly in
washington
um or at least my participation of it
was was increased and my tinctures um
became being sold through the the
washington medical market nice and it
was great um i was able to
make these tinctures and share them
through um you know legal dispensaries
and um
it was at that point that people started
asking me questions because at that
point they're all like okay which of the
four tinctures do i want why do i want
them you know what you know which which
ver which cultivar what preparation is
going to help me now versus something in
high cbd that is designed to strengthen
your endocannabinoid system and will
help me long term you know like like and
and that was when i first got into
thinking about and teaching dosing
strategies to patients
and so i loved that i really enjoyed
that and um and you know the the medical
days were a heyday right not not only
because everybody was so not not
everybody but the vast majority of
people were very nice um
but also the margins weren't as tight as
they are today
and so you know you could actually do
this and and and support yourself and
and while i never got to that level
right um uh we you know the market
transitioned yeah to legal before you
know i i had like a business business
right my volume was never of units where
that was never
significant but people liked it right
people and that that buoyed me and i
started teaching so then when there was
the um
when when the market started to um
well before we talk about the market
pivoting it was at the same time that i
um began
reaching out to the the underground
cannabis growers on vashon
because uh vashon has been known for its
high quality cannabis all the way back
to the 70s you know bands would come
through seattle and they'd try to like
get their vashon hookup and pick up some
weed for the rest of tour and all that
kind of stuff and so i knew that these
these cultivators were here on vacheron
but i also knew they were very much
still in the underground
and but but because there were so many
people producing on the island um
prices for ounces on the island were
just like ridiculously low you know and
um that was great if you lived on the
island but it was really bad for the the
cultivators who were trying to support
their families on it and
and i realized that um there were all
these dispensaries
a short ferry ride away in uh in seattle
that um would love to have the produce
from my island
but none of the none of the cultivators
wanted to leave the island i didn't want
to i still don't know right
you know once you moved here you're like
you're like ah i don't want to go to
babylon yeah right yeah
i don't want to go to that it's noisy
and everybody's driving crazy and
everything's good here we'll just stay
in place yeah
but um but because i was you know i was
more recently on the island than these
cultivators who grew up here um
i wrote a one-page invitation talking a
little bit about
um this group that i wanted to form on
vashon um called vimeo
which stands for the vashon the vashon
island marijuana entrepreneurs alliance
and i wanted to know what they
wanted as far as representation like
what what can you use as a cultivator
what would help you in the underground
and so i made up a bunch of these
letters
and i started giving them out
to the kinds of people on the island who
i thought would know cultivators so
particular types of farmers certain
types of community organizers i'm like
i mean like you don't have to tell me if
you know a cultivator but if you know a
cultivator would you give them this
letter and they're like huh that's
interesting
yeah and so
these these these letters went into the
underground i made like 25 of them
and these these um these black market
cultivators started like showing up at
the oddest of times too because nobody
was calling me i would just be you know
you know
at a baseball game or a softball game
you know and somebody would come up to
me and say like you know you're shango
right i'm like yeah i'm like hey i got
your letter
wow wow
and they're like you want to go for a
little walk i'm like yes and so we'd go
and we'd talk and and you know the the
universally everybody wanted secure
right everybody was afraid to get busted
for their grows
and so i knew that um normalization on
the island was one of the important
things that vimy was going to do
um
and then and then the other thing was is
that everybody um was spending way too
much money on inputs yeah all the
impulses fancy ass inputs are expensive
and so um
so the very first thing i did when i
formed vimeo was to um start essentially
a media i guess propaganda campaign that
was pro cultivator
and um uh you know thing things like um
um you know
we were you we back in those days we
were using words like pot and and
marijuana a lot more than we were now
right so so we would do thing you know
we would put out things like you know
hug your local pot grower you know you
know um uh uh uh pot growers are local
farmers too yes um you know uh uh pot
cultivation is a family farm things like
this right which which got the rest of
the island to realize that um you don't
have to look at cannabis as a scourge
these are members of the community and
and we should embrace them and then the
second thing i did is i started pulling
together more of these cultivators and i
said um
you know this is still in the old days
when people were uh throwing away their
soil after every run right yeah instead
of keeping it and aging the soil and you
know more of a no-till kind of regen
thing right back in these days people
were just dumping their soil and thought
they had to start with new soil
so so you know we started bulk but we
started bulk purchasing soil and just
having you know a higher quality soil
than was available generally on the
island and we were just having it come
and be dumped at one location and
everybody would come with their truck
and fill up their truck and then head on
home and you know we got these hugely
better prices well after that people
were all like all right chango what else
what else you got for us you know and so
we started doing you know some other um
you know soil amendments we started
buying bulk
and um
you know this was this was well ahead of
my awareness of the more serious
regenerative scene which i am you know a
big part of now but in these early days
i knew i liked organic farming because i
i grew a little bit of organic food um
but i certainly didn't have like the the
regenerative whole mindset um i i was
just very stoked that we were using
natural amendments and i knew how to
make compost tea right yeah like that's
good you know just the idea was like you
know like let's let's try to like get
people off the bottle yes
that was a thing that early
um
and so we started doing that and people
really liked that well
at this point the the the underground
growers started to trust me more and i'm
learning a whole lot about what it means
to be a cultivator because i had i was
not a cultivator i was an enthusiast and
then and then a patient
and then um
and so
i started going to these some of these
folks that that we had a more trusting
relationship and i said hey you know can
i can i shop
some of your flower
into seattle
and and they're all like you want me to
like
front it to you and i'm like well i
guess in a way but i i just want to
borrow it for two hours three hours
can can i can i have you know a couple
pounds and i'll go over
to the dispensaries and try to sell it
and either i will bring you back money
or i will bring you back the flower i'm
not gonna it will not be in my hands
tonight one way or another and they're
like
all right let's give this a try
and um i took it over there and i came
back with money
and so when i
and i got them
about 150 of the price that they would
normally get on the island nice that
made me very popular yes
you know and so they're like wait you're
saving us money on the inputs and you're
bringing us home more money and setting
up these relationships and then
eventually once they
they got set up
you know the the the cannabis was
finding its way off the island which
honestly was making the cerned parents
people
a little happier you know
because i was a public figure since i
wasn't a cultivator i could be out front
more and so i was out front saying nice
things about cannabis farmers explaining
their needs and explaining that this
organization i had started was helping
filter a lot of this cannabis off the
island which that so caused them to
embrace my new organization a little bit
more but the farmers were also thrilled
and um because they were able to get
more for their products so
so so this all happens but then
everything falls apart at the end of
medical um so we we you know we got
together um as vimeo as a group a few
times to go through the regulations when
it came out like the the how to apply
for a license i went and i read it all
and i marked it all up and then got
together all these people who are
interested in getting licenses and
essentially talked
the regulations to everybody
and the more and then we met three times
like this and the more we got into it we
more we realized that this sucked yeah
and that this was this may this was
going to be really expensive
and didn't really have the needs of the
cultivator at heart
and um you know a couple of people tried
um almost no one
succeeded and um because they again they
were they were wanting to give their
money to a different kind of license
holder yeah than people who were
participating in the medical kit and so
i had to make a decision at that point
because um
you know i wasn't going to be involved
with the medical market anymore
and um i what didn't look like i was
going to move into the licensed market
so what are we going to do and it came
back to my first love which was teaching
patients teaching dosing strategies and
creating a safe place for cultivators
and so the the initial meetings that we
had just to learn about regulations
became
uh patient outreach meetings and so they
became like you know um you know uh
you know one doctor would come to well
actually we're very lucky to have dr
ethan russo i was gonna say yes
neurologist lives on the island he's my
neighbor yeah and so and so dr russo
like you know came and talked at one of
these events and explained the
endocannabinoid system and everybody's
all like you know this was very new
information for for the people yeah
right
but also if if you are a an event
promoter and you're trying to book
speakers
if a cannabis um
doctor scientist celebrity whatever if
they know that you've already hosted dr
ethan russo right like
they're figuring that you're pretty okay
and i got all these yeses from
international like cannabis talent who
would come and i tell them that we're a
patient outreach organization we don't
charge any money to attend we're
donation based only we do not pay our
speakers but
you know we'll um
we had a sponsorship deal with the one
uh hotel on the island i said you know
if you come to the island overnight i'll
put you up for the night
but really you're just coming because
you care about patients and you want to
talk to the real deal people
and people flocked to vashon and so
suddenly now we've got this scene which
grew from vashon to seattle to the
pacific northwest you know we we've had
people flying from colorado and from the
bay area for different different events
we've had because the the variety of
teaching at these events was very down
home
good vibe stuff
and um so that's where that's where the
education of the circle always around
your question that's where the education
came in is it was it was originally
let's organize cultivators because i'm
interested in them and i wanted to be
helpful on on this new island that i
called home
and then and then i saw things that i
could do to be of service to them and so
i did those things which helped my
reputation as being somebody who was
trustworthy
and then and then we pivoted that into a
patient organization to the point that
you know i speak here at the senior
center a couple times a year and i'm on
the local radio station as a guest
regularly and been on the front page of
the newspaper you know it's like um
there's i've got i've developed this
niche for myself where um
like i have been referred to as like the
weed guy or the podca a guy a gazillion
times but not because i was selling bags
right right i don't sell flour
i'm i'm it's because i'm teaching
everybody and then telling people where
they can get the stuff that they need to
feel better whether it's in the wreck or
unlicensed market i just you know um so
so that brings us you know pretty much
to where we are now with vimeo where you
know um unfortunately we've been on
sabbatical because of covid right yeah
um and vimeo will be the last group to
get people coming back together because
we're all patients right
and so like we are at the most high risk
and also you know
there are a lot of people in the
cannabis scene who um who are resisting
vaccination yeah and so
um i can't i'm certainly not going to be
that guy who checks everybody's id at
the door that's that's not really how i
roll yep
so we're just going to have to wait
we're going to have to wait until um the
risk has decreased it enough that we can
bring together a room of a hundred
patients and not have it be super
dangerous so you know we won't have
meetings until you know at least spring
of 22 which is a bummer right yeah for
sure
good two years that's gonna leave us
with a good two years without meetings
um but you know gotta keep the patients
safe exactly i mean it's it's the weird
situation we're in i mean i i felt the
same thing i used to
do in-person workshops pretty regularly
on cannabis science topics
uh was doing guest lectures at
universities and everything and it's
been i mean pretty much once everything
kicked off around you know february
march of 2020
you know it's like i have a daughter i
also regularly see you know my parents
who have all sorts of medical conditions
you know
myself and my wife have medical
conditions so it's we've been basically
you know just being very strict on um
in-person events and having to get
people together and it's
um it's been interesting because i've
had to rely on virtual communication
um leaning more on podcasting leading
more on on that sort of thing
but it does feel weird because you like
to be with people and there's there are
these interactions and moments and
knowledge sharing that happens in person
that's so hard to
um
to get those dynamics captured in a
virtual setting i'm sure you've
experienced this where you see the
knowledge sharing the questions being
asked the looks on people's faces these
different subtleties that come out in
in-person events um
that's really really special um
at least you know those are the kinds of
things that
lead me to want to do those things more
and more and seeing all that happen so i
yeah i can imagine it's been hugs yeah
yeah hugs
hey like like
you know it's like it's that simple like
you know i live on an island i'm a
single guy i live in a house by myself
on the water right but i am not getting
enough hugs yeah and you know
at first when kovid came and all the
conventions were canceled
i must admit it was nice to get like six
months to a year of a travel break right
because i had been traveling two three
weekends a month to to speak at events
and to teach and whatever
and um
that had gotten to be a lot i was i was
getting tired of being you know being a
road warrior all the time yeah um
but
i really really like my
my my national and now international
group of cannabis family like the people
i would see at events
and so it was cool to have a break for a
while but now the break has gone longer
than i've needed
um i am um you know i uh because i'm a
i'm a high risk patient because i've got
severe asthma um you know i'm not
rushing to go like you know uh mj biz is
you know coming up soon and like you
know like i'm certainly not going to
that this year right um
because i am an at-risk patient right
but but i really wish i i was going to
an event you know i really wish
cultivate cultivation classic in
portland you know the hall of flowers
too
yeah i i skipped that too
so
so um but i miss those hugs man i really
miss seeing the cannabis people
and being you know smiling with them and
and you know going outside and talking
and then walking around and talking with
vendors like i really really miss the
extended community and i love my vashon
community too and i have been very
focused on you know working on stuff
here but um but it you know
it would be nice to to go some cool
places and do some cool stuff yeah i
totally feel you yeah it's
i'm ready whenever the time is right um
and this is a a good
uh time to
kind of switch a little bit here you
know we've been talking about
um
how
all of this is developed and the work
that you've been doing but i do want to
spend some time
just talking about you know the
the show the curious about canvas
podcast i want to talk about what makes
you curious about cannabis
um
and so uh you know
i'll just lay out one basic question
related to the podcast and then spend on
other things but
um what are some
insights that stand out to you
that you've gained from all of the
people that you've talked to you know
over the past four years or so on the
podcast what are some notable things
that stood out to you that um
uh maybe
changed your perspective a little bit or
that you just were totally unaware of
that that kind of blew your mind but
what are some uh kind of the more
significant insights that you've gained
from doing shaping fire
well i would
one thing for sure would be
understanding how
different each human's body is this idea
of individualized medicine yeah um i
really kind of thought that cannabis was
the same for everybody and that's like
wildly untrue
um how how people react to different
terpene profiles how people um you know
cannabis is is biphasic right meaning
you can take a little bit of thc
which will reduce your anxiety but if
you take beyond your personal threshold
it will cause anxiety right and because
of cannabis byphasic nature um we're all
we all have different thresholds
and so um you know somebody big get the
relief they need with the tiniest little
puffy puff whereas somebody else is
going to be like pulling tubes and
blowing clouds to get where they need
based on what you know how many
receptors they have and and
how busy those receptors are and so
the understanding that each patient
needs to be addressed
uniquely and without carrying over too
many assumptions
that was good for me to learn as a as a
health educator but it was also good for
me
for just generally realizing that i
should
not generalize people
entirely
um to respect each person's individual
nature
um and i kind of got to that through
trying to help people relieve their
you know their but their body issues and
just realizing that oh
you know um
everybody's different and on a lot of
issues not just their medicine and not
to assume i know folks so that was that
was a breakthrough thing for me um
another one was i had no idea i was so
interested in soil science ah yeah um
[Music]
when when i first started cultivating it
was just like take the bag soil put it
in you know throw in some kind of
nutrients from the store and grow a
plant that's great um but then i started
you know talking to
um
what would become known as the
regenerative scene people and realizing
the back of all the biological life in
the rhizosphere and the protozoa and the
microbes and how these folks get along
and how for me one of the first things i
realized was that um you know we get
cold early in the season right so so
we've already had it's it's it's like
the second week of october coming into
the second week of october now i've
already had 50 degree nights for four
weeks
and and i did until i started learning
about soil that i realized that the soil
and the containers were going to sleep
the microbes and everything were cysting
up and then the plants would just go to
mold so it wasn't that oh my my plants
were unhealthy
and then i got mold it's that the soil
went to sleep which signaled to the
plant that that were done for the season
and so you should mold for the cycle of
life
well that was fascinating to me and so
next thing you know i'm i'm reading
everything i can on
soil science and regenerative
you know growing techniques and and and
um
creating your own inputs on your own
property
and uh you know when it comes to shaping
fire the guests that i have um very much
are based on what i'm interested in
learning next
um you know yeah and uh and luckily the
show the show's at a point now where um
you know everybody everybody takes my
call right so it's cool i can i can i
can reach out to whoever and say hey
would you come on the show and talk
about this thing that i would like to
learn about and you know everybody's
like yeah that would be great and um and
i think that
i think that because i don't fake that i
know all this stuff before the show um i
think the audience digs that because
people it's very common for people to
say um i like that we're learning so
much together yeah and cause like you
know you know some some podcasts they
pretend that they know everything and
they you know they'll even talk over the
guests and try to tell
like tell the guest story it's like i'm
much more of a like
get my mom ke i keep quiet and try to
let the guest to tell their truth and
then ask good questions um
and then when i learned something like
you know it's common for me to go like
oh
i never got that before and yeah
and then you can almost feel my audience
going oh me too yes
and so um
you know um i'm not i'm not gonna front
for a second that i know all of this
stuff you know after doing you know four
years of my own show and then another
105 episodes before that for
entrepreneur.com
you know i've done over you know 200
episodes and i've been doing this for
like five years or so i know a lot now
um but i learn new stuff on every
episode because that's why i do those
topics so i can learn
that's that's perfect i mean and having
that
lifelong learner mentality um i think is
great i mean that's something i'm always
trying to
promote um that regardless of whatever
niche you've specialized in that you
know a lot about there's always so much
more to learn
um
and uh to maintain that curiosity
um is great it's humble too exactly yeah
humble too yeah so as soon as you start
you think you know everything
you know not not only will you stop
learning but you'll probably also start
being a prick exactly yes that's uh yeah
some of the biggest [__] you'll meet
in the industry are those that have a
little bit of knowledge that think they
know a lot
um absolutely i think that's called with
the like dunning-kruger effect or
something there's actually a
um a model for that that you can look up
there's a graph anyone listening that
wants to look it up you can actually see
uh this theory
related to knowledge acquisition and
confidence
and um you know when you get a little
bit of knowledge you often overestimate
how much you know when you have a lot of
knowledge you generally under represent
how much you know because you've become
humbled um and recognized that you know
even the things i think i know a lot
about
you know who knows there's
always more rabbit holes and and new new
things to shine light on and everything
um and one thing i wanted to make sure
that we spent time on because i know
that you're really into regenerative
agriculture now
and something we talked about before we
started recording that i found really
fascinating was that you've been trying
to figure out how
it might be possible to take
you know permaculture regenerative
agriculture principles
and take them from the outdoor
cultivation environment and find ways to
integrate them in the indoor cultivation
environment
so before we wrap up i definitely wanted
to make sure to spend some time
speaking on that so i know we've talked
about a little bit already off camera
but um can you share a little bit about
your recent
indoor
cultivation foray and um what you
learned from that experience
yeah so i've got to admit i um i have
evolved my thinking and um again another
thing that makes one uh humble yes uh so
so for years i have been a proponent of
only outdoor
um i think that the quality of the
medicine that comes out of outdoor
plants that are grown under the sun is
higher than indoor
because the wider spectrum of light
means that we are
creating a wider terpene profile a a a
stronger cannabinoid profile and just
generally the plants thrive better um
i understand the appreciation of indoor
from its uh connoisseur level rag appeal
and beauty but that's a different topic
i really like the medicinal value of
outdoor plants and i also didn't have a
place to grow indoors and so i was i was
you know i was an outdoor guy because
that's all i had access to
and and i you know i believe the gospel
of northern california outdoor that
that's like you know
that's the best way to go
and so that's what i've practiced um you
know and
and over the years i have increased my
soil knowledge and using natural inputs
and you know natural farming techniques
and knf and and so i've got a you know
i've got a pretty good sense of what i'm
doing outdoors now and um and keeping my
soil alive over the year and and using
that same thriving soil the following
year so that's great um
however
it became important to me to
um
do two things number one
i needed new things to explore on the
instagram the shaping fire instagram you
know i've got i've got like what like 11
000 followers
and um
and you know i'm trying to always
provide helpful tidbits yeah well that's
a lot harder to do if you're an outdoor
grower during the winter yeah and i'm
like you know
let's see if i can let's see if i can do
this stuff indoors
and so um i uh
in this new house that i moved into last
year i've got i've got a little bit of
room so i just set up a simple 4x4 tent
and i'm a big fan of letting the plant
roots talk to each other yeah and so
instead of making individualized
containers i set up a really nice four
foot by four foot by um
20 inch deep bed nice and then i used
the um the layered biomimicry soil
technique that um was taught by that
stopped by leighton morrison um on my
show and and so i asked him to get
involved to make sure i did the bed
right
and i wild crafted all my
inputs
which was a pain in the ass
i it's funny i highly recommend it for
quality of flour
but i don't recommend it for the amount
of hassle um like i never realized that
wild crafting silt was gonna be so damn
hard and so and so anyway so i wild
crafted everything for the bed
and built it out
and um and then
um
because in my head like i understand
that there are indoors there's lots of
options right there's you know there's
there's hydro there's rockwool cubes
there's all this other kind of stuff but
but none of those are really how i do
things i um um i like the uh
you know um
jeff lowenfeld says you know if if a
worm can't live in it it's not really a
growing medium and like i i know that i
know that it's it's up for argument and
and you know and and i'm not trying to
pick a fight with the with the rockwool
people but but for me that's where my
head is is i wanted to use real soil
biology because i'm a soil nerd yeah and
so um
so i wanted i started bringing in as
many of the techniques that i could find
from outdoors indoors
and um did you know did my first run
and i found um i i i found lights that i
really liked i like their spectrum i
like the the company's philosophy um and
that's uh that's bios lighting they make
they make really good lights for both
humans and for and for cultivation
they're actually a nasa spinoff company
that their scientists helped developed
the um the led growing setups for the
space station which is as a as an odd
thing i actually used to work on i was i
was gonna say yeah
yeah that's a funny thing to mention
back i used to live in colorado for a
while uh in late 90s
and i worked for a technology company
that was making rfid devices for a space
hob what was the original name for the
space station and so um
you know stuff that i have touched um is
you know theoretically still up in the
space station so that's cool that's
super cool
got off the got off the the point but
the the
the first run out of the tent was like
the best things i have ever grown in my
life and like i i recognize how
difficult that is too as a as a devout
outdoor guy that i grew this stuff
indoor that is without a doubt the best
weed that i had ever grown
and honestly it was like the top
five things i had ever even smoked wow
and i'm like oh
and what i realized was how limited i am
by how short and crappy our summers are
where i live here in the pacific
northwest
um
you know
if you think about it a simple
eight-week flowering period if
if if the plants start to flower here
around august 15th that's october 15th
we are soaked and cold by october 15th
yeah so really we only really get about
five weeks of growing season before
things start going to hell and i
realized that um i'm actually a lot
better grower than i thought i was it
was that i was trying to grow well in a
poor environment so as soon as i took
those same regenerative techniques and
brought them indoors
i hit it out of the ballpark well that
made me feel really good you know yeah
year after year of getting beaten down
by the bad weather right yeah i feel
like a schmuck you know i'm like ah you
know someday i'll be decent you know
i'll just i'll just keep on learning and
keep on plugging away and then i grow
once indoors and it's like holy smokes
and and so that that made me feel good
um
and so um i'm still torn right because
it really it was really satisfying to me
to grow
flowers that i could never finish here
indoors and have them finish beautifully
like really finish not like oh it needed
10 more days outdoor right but we can
take it now that's what i've been
yeah
well that stuff still you know that
stuff's still great to process into
tinctures and rso and stuff like that
but it's not like fun to smoke yeah
um
you know because it's it's just not
there but the indoor stuff is definitely
there so so i'm at this new point now
where
um i am absolutely a lover of outdoor
but because of where i live
i absolutely see the need for indoor
but if i'm going to do indoor i'm not
going to be using bottles and rock wool
and a and b formulas and stuff right i
am going to be using like like
whole nature
soil additives
wild crafted when i can do it
responsibly but otherwise you know
you know
build a soil you know gives out you know
cells a lot of really great inputs you
know yeah and you know get stuff from
like there and um
and then
leaving the only real problem for me the
fact that i'm using electricity right
right for my lights
which um
you know
i try to you know have a small carbon
footprint and i'm somewhere in between
a i use so little electricity in the
rest of my life
and my carbon footprint is so small that
if if i'm going to choose to
spend my allotment electricity on the
lights
that's my decision to make yeah and and
so i do that but even more importantly
um i am aggressively researching and
continuing to talk to um
uh solar people because i think that
when the day comes that we can
um you know capture the sun and put it
in batteries and have that push enough
juice to run led lights it will
absolutely remake the home grower
industry yeah i totally think so um i i
believe that that time is soon i don't
think it's far away and so um so you
know am i totally comfortable with you
know using lights to grow indoors no
but i picked good led lights that don't
use a lot of electricity i am producing
my own medicine which i think is legit
and as soon as there is a a
real opportunity to you know
teach
using solar at home for home grow
i will have that show first yes
i will be all into it so
so
so yeah i'm in this transition place
where um i am a devout outdoor grower
who now has fallen in love with indoor
and uh you know i'm like wildly excited
about my second cycle coming up here so
that's super cool and what did you uh
what did you grow for your um for this
first round of indoor experimentation
yeah so um
so
before i go into it um people will be
like probably shocked that i'm gonna
name five plants
um this was part of my learning curve
five plants is way too many for a four
by four tent
so we will we will definitely cause you
know
tie that up to
a learner's error and that's right i
just wanted variety i wanted to finish
five different things so i could try
five different things but it was
it like overgrew like crazy oh sure yeah
um with it with that um the the
i grew the the the hot hot bicket og
that has been it was bred by nick
reiston at lime rising farm that's a
cross of uh gmo and cherry pie
it is an absolutely delightful strain
and then um
i was uh given seeds um that were bred
by my good friend and a very popular
cannabis guy michael hinden
who um
who died a year ago now um um as a
matter of fact i was on my way to pick
up these seeds when i found out that he
had been murdered um the prior day oh my
gosh and um i was like at the airport
going down to meet with leighton
morrison in in
in southern california then we're gonna
drive to
house and then i found out that that he
asked and and so there's a lot of
grieving there
but then um
you know his business partner
you know
uh widow um brianna reached out to me
and she said hey you know um
i knew it was going to do this thing
with you and he was going to give you
seeds for the patients on vashon
and i still want to continue on with the
things that that michael wanted to do
and so
she sent me um
almost a complete set of of the modern
epigenetics first release and they're
all runs crosses
and so that became extra special right
because not only are these crosses that
i was hot to grow
but it's like michael right this is
michael's work and so it became a real
um
um you know
labor of love for lack of a better term
and so
um we grew um
i grew uh michael's secret stuff which
is gmo runs
and then also um
um
uh
uh jet fuel og runs
uh called private jet
and that's a stinker that's a really
great plan the michael's secret the
michael secret stuff is a good plan
because i like gmo but the jet fuel og
runs it was just like nasty and caustic
and stony it's really great
and then
and then the two opposite corners
grew a um
land race uh acapulco gold oh wow um
which
which was okay it didn't turn out as
nicely as i had hoped it would it was
beautiful it just didn't have a lot of
nose to it yeah and then um and then i
ran csi humboldt's uh uk cheese skittles
cross oh nice
which is really great so i'm not you
hold on i'm not uk skittles uh obama
okay yeah um because i've always liked
the obama strain so anyway so yeah but
the the funny thing is is that you know
g is just a monster yeah right
you
in a four by four and it turns into a
cage fight yeah you know the bike it
like overgrew everything else and you
know oh so that was really difficult so
so i'm very much excited i'm going to
i'm going to scrog this next cycle yeah
nice i think i'm just going to stick to
three plants which is probably still
more than i should have but my goal is
to to grow them and then just weave them
back and forth yeah see how that goes
you know one of the cool things that
like since since i'm not cultivating for
profit i'm cultivating for medicine and
so that i have like things to take
photographs of to put on the instagram
um
um i can embrace my screw-ups yes yeah
yeah it isn't like oh if i did this
wrong i can't pay rent well i'm not
using that to pay rent i pay rent from
the advertising on your show you know
yeah and so um i i can really embrace my
mistakes and go oh well i effed that up
you know right and let's all learn from
it and then po yeah yeah look at this
stupid thing i did
you know because i was i was naive i
just didn't have the experience and so i
use those you know those things to teach
but um
very very much love indoor
now and um and now and now i'm like you
know plotting what plants i'm going to
do this cycle after the next cycle yeah
you know i've got indoor fantasies now
you've been hooked yes
i have absolutely been hooked
and constantly now like even though i
don't have any more room in my house
other than this four by four tent i'm
already thinking how can i how can i do
a whole room like
two or three plants is great but i'd
really love to do like a full patient
card of 15. right yeah yeah but you know
that's that's not where i'm at right now
so that's okay
we'll see where it goes
and have you absolutely have you played
around with um autoflowers at all
oh yeah well um i've i fell in love with
autoflowers and became a big proponent
of them about three years ago um as soon
as i learned what an autoflower was
um by uh you know by by going into the
fields in oregon actually in oregon near
you um oregon cbd seeds oh yeah yeah
seth and eric crawford right good
friends of mine
and so their first auto was a was a um
all cbd hemp cultivar called rna really
nice auto and when i was there and they
explained to me how that's how they're
not dependent on the sun they're
dependent on you know their length of
light and that they automatically mature
and flower
i'm all like holy hell
patience everywhere that is not
california needs these yeah because um
so many of the genetics are designed for
california weather and then and then we
don't have california weather in most of
the rest of the country
and so
the idea that um
you know we can start something yeah
june 1st and harvest it middle of
september when we're all still in
drought
that was like
and so i immediately dug into that hard
um
i started hunting out autoflower
breeders and putting them on my show and
um hunting out seeds so that i could
grow and take pictures and learn myself
and um
hooked up with jeff lowenfels who
put out a book on autoflowers
and uh told him that when the book came
out i wanted to have him on on my show
for his first interview and that was
cool he actually invited me to write
something for the jacket
on the jacket of nice so that's cool
and uh and
as we talked earlier you know i did a
lot of traveling to teach about cannabis
and i was usually being booked to talk
about something patient oriented right
and so
my i guess this would have been two or
two three years ago i don't know covet
days everything matches
yeah but but but
you know about a year and a half before
we started all the covety stuff um i was
just touring going to conventions and
teaching autoflowers which you know
historically have a pretty bad
reputation because the past seeds have
been very low yielding pretty pretty
weak but like the new generation of
seeds are fantastic and you know they're
not going to get to be monster plants
that you know we all still love
but like most people don't have the
weather to grow those monster plants or
at least to finish them right yeah you
might be able to grow a monster plant
but are the plant are the flowers ever
going to finish yeah not most places in
the country so anyway i kind of took the
the autoflower
gospel on the road
and um
and i reached out to lots of autoflower
seed companies and i said hey do you
want to sponsor my talk
and all it takes for you to sponsor the
talk is to send me a box of seeds that i
can give away to patients after the
talks
and of course they're like hell yeah
shango and so all these all these folks
sent me seeds
and i you know i asked everybody hey you
throw in a couple extra for me so i can
grow them and and put pictures on on
instagram and i'll send you traffic
they're like yeah we're good with that
so
so i would go to all these all these
cities and give my talk about
autoflowers and then say
you know
if you are a patient come up and get a
seed pack if you have if you are not a
patient um don't come get a seed pack go
go buy one from one of these seed
providers go out on the floor and buy
them at the show but if you know if
you're if you consider yourself a legit
patient come get packs it was great like
patients are usually neglected right you
know especially at trade shows because
they've got no money to spend usually
right yeah and so suddenly they're
they're they're the ones getting the
free stuff and it was like high quality
good seeds
and um so that was really good and i
mean and it felt good it's good to be
the conduit for that kind of love from
the from the breeders to the to the
patients
and um and so i'm very grateful that the
autoflower community has embraced me
and even though i'm not a breeder all i
want to do is is help spread their
gospel and and why you should buy their
seeds so you know um
and um
and
i think they get that my heart's in the
right place you know i'm not i'm not
trying to take anything from the scene i
i just want to make what i want to make
their
art history more popular and and we've
done a great job so that's really great
i am um you know even though um
autoflowers still tend to get a lot of
flack by a certain kind of grower um i'm
really honored to be you know one of the
people um at the at the forefront of
teaching autoflowers absolutely i mean
it's super fascinating to me for some of
the very reasons that have come about in
um just talking about your
experimentation with indoor and
everything um
just thinking about how you translate
cannabis cultivation to other places
other than california and the lower half
of oregon
you know we have to
expand
our
conceptions of you know of all of these
things and recognize like you said that
everywhere is not california um having
that sort of arid environment and these
long you know summers and everything um
that's not gonna be the case and i
mentioned before the interview started
that i'm from the southeast and so i'm
keeping my eyes on
you know tennessee north carolina
arkansas all these places that are the
hemp's starting to get big so they're
jumping into large fields of cannabis
cultivation and are recognizing like oh
no
like this doesn't this doesn't quite
translate everything i've been reading
and all these books and everything it
doesn't quite
match up um and so
seeing experimentation with
autoflowers um i find particularly
fascinating from that perspective how
can autoflowering
varieties be used in places that
typically do
get a little more humid that the rainy
seasons start really early
or in places where you know you get
these cold fronts that come really early
seeing how that can be a bridge to
especially because as places legalize
cannabis
they usually don't let you bring
cannabis from other places uh other
states and so you're stuck with you know
in whatever state you're in once it goes
medical or you know full adult use legal
you've got to work with the climate and
situation you have which is one reason
why people often
retreat i say retreat that's not the
best way to put that but they they tend
to default back to indoor because they
just figure outdoor isn't even an option
so
it'll be interesting to see if
autoflowers as they get
bred and improved upon because they've
definitely changed a lot since like the
90s um i remember back in the day like
the old um like high times magazines and
stuff you know you'd start to see
advertisements for
auto flowers for closet grows um you
know so that the plants would be small
enough that you could keep in a
a little grow box or you know people
used to grow in like uh pc cases you
know that they would outfit uh to grow
plants in and so seeing
autoflowers come from that you know kind
of
early start to where it is now is just
really fascinating to see and it's got
me really especially from a scientific
perspective i'm like i want to do trials
with autoflowers and start to look at
the biochemistry of these things and and
see if we notice any interesting things
in some of these genetics that we don't
see in other things because you never
know until you look
um
so um yeah that's all fascinating and
something i definitely wanted to to
check on because it seems like for
a place like washington that would
definitely be the way to go as far as
outdoor cultivation
for sure i mean the the some of the
early autoflowers that i was growing
were like 100 days but but this summer i
got to grow a bunch of 60 days wow
wow
like that's wow fantastic fantastic
autoflowers over 60 days
and you know they're not big plants but
you know just like we were talking
earlier about individualized medicine
for patients
you need individualized genetics for
growers yes
you know a lot of patients you know okay
great it's it's wonderful that they
could potentially grow a 12-foot plant
but how the hell are they going to take
that down you know people with mobility
issues yes or who are growing in a
backyard and they don't want to get
their stuff ripped right yep for their
there are particular growers that
growing a
two and a half three foot maybe a four
foot plant that's going to stay short
but maybe they grow a few more of them
so they have some variety
there are people who who don't need the
traditional monster plant because that's
not what they need and so in the same
way that we talk about
individualized medicine i like to talk
about individualized cultivation yeah it
isn't that one's one seeds are
necessarily better than the other it is
the the seeds highest use for that
particular cultivator and um you know i
think it's another other way that we as
educators
can encourage people to uh you know be
be in service to
you know the people that we're trying to
educate whether or not they be you know
people who identify as patient growers
or just home growers or
or you know
extractors right it's it's all about you
know being in service and
so that the individual cannabis
enthusiast can choose which attributes
of our scene work best for them yeah
it's i
it drives me nuts when people compare
like growing styles like how you are
growing is wrong like dude you're
talking to this guy on facebook or
instagram how do you know anything any
of the details of this person's needs
right
like like person will figure out what
works best for themselves don't worry
about yelling at them that they're an
idiot
absolutely i think that's that that uh
yeah kind of goes across the entire
industry in general um i think as the
industry's like kicking off um
and people are much more public
with their cannabis usage and growing
and everything yeah you see so much
typical human dynamics bickering and
posturing and comparing and everything
and it is important to make that note
that everyone
has their own
relationship and specific
uh situation that they're in that
they're gonna find things that work for
them
and there are lots of options
um and so
getting caught up and trying to
understand what's best um right away is
just kind of a
kind of a fool's errand um it's yeah
what's best for you
um is is definitely a great message to
get out there i also just glanced at the
time just noticed between
our cuts we've probably gone on for like
an hour and a half here so i want to be
respectful of your time i apologize for
not
noticing that sooner
but
this has been a wonderful conversation
chango and
i wish we could go on for another hour
and a half or two because um
especially as we get going here and
comparing stories and stuff um there's
so much that's popping in my brain
memories and things from
the past 10 years or so um
that uh yeah there's there's so much to
learn from uh from where we've come from
and and where we're going and i guess
the last question i'll pose to you is
what do you hope to see from the future
um as cannabis you know i say the
cannabis industry but when i say the
cannabis industry i really just mean the
widespread proliferation and
normalization of cannabis you know
broadly whether that's in the legal
market or home growing or you know
whatever manifestation that has but what
do you hope to see from the future of
the cannabis industry as we move into
you know the next several years five
years or so
well start with the most uh difficult
thing that i would like to see and um i
would like to see
um
more
states
adopt and hold a one acre cap like they
were supposed to have in california
but then the lobbyists got beaten up so
that people are now stacking licenses in
california because originally there was
supposed to be a window of opportunity
for small heritage growers and family
farms to get well established in the
market before the big commoditized
cannabis companies were supposed to be
able to to do anything in california
and um effective lobbying by
big money
totally made that disappear just one
night in the morning it was gone and no
one was willing to talk about how that
happened yeah and so i'm hoping that um
as we see the the rise and strength of
these msos these multi-state operators
which are essentially like you know
mcdonald's for weed right right that the
quality is is is not you know what it
could be
and um it really commodifies the whole
thing
i hope that that many states learn from
the california mistake
and they create situations in their
states
that that is the opposite of what
they're doing now which is
trying to beckon these multi-state
operators so that they can deal with
fewer providers
and just make the whole thing easy for
themselves instead of doing the thing
that should be done which is
letting small players grow in their
state and then
exporting those companies to into other
states that did not do a one acre cap um
i'm asking a lot in that i know um but
that's the that's the number one thing
for me is i would love to see something
happen where the small guy can start to
compete more effectively with these with
these msos
um second no surprise i'm super excited
to see the future of autoflowers yes and
um and um you know because we're still
very early in the process and and so
much has happened in such a short amount
of time
and now that this is the pool that i'm
swimming in more and you know then then
photo periods um you know i still keep
my hand in photo periods but but really
i think um for for the the regular
homegrowner and patients the future is
autoflower
and so um i'm very excited to see what
happens there
and then
i'm also uh excited with the
um what do you want to say like like the
standardization of cannabis knowledge
because right now there's still a lot of
bro science in the teaching of the
endocannabinoid system and you know
people you know like uh you know people
they thinking they need an indica for
this and a sativa for that when
indicative is a is a false thing it
doesn't even exist in reality right it's
just shorthand because people aren't
educated properly enough
and as as uh you know prohibition
continues to melt away into some kind of
normalized thing
i look forward to people
more uniformly understanding how
cannabis can help them and relieve their
symptoms
so that people are doing less trial and
error and more oh i'm using the best
practices that we've already learned and
shared yeah so i would say those three
things are the things that um you know
are three of the things that i'm most
excited to see come
yeah i mean those are huge you know that
first one you mentioned i know it's a
it's a big ask but i
completely agree because once again i
mean i saw similar things happen in
oregon you know like
starting in these labs and getting to
know these medical growers and these
small farms and small businesses
you get emotionally invested in wanting
to see them succeed as the industry is
starting to come about and then when you
see them get totally crushed and
basically no hope of being able to
participate in any way
um i mean it's not just sad like it's
it's wrong it's just wrong
um and
so i'm i'm
i want to just echo that that um
absolutely that's something that needs
to get more
attention as more and more states um
uh changed their laws um because i i do
worry that
we're already kind of knee-deep in this
process of kind of excommunicating
all of the folks who
got us to this point basically the
people that
took the risk early on uh participating
in either straight out black market or
gray you know gray market areas that
stuck through medical all the way up to
recreational and now we're trying to
decide what to do
to make a living because you know it
doesn't seem like growing is going to do
it anymore those i'm i'm sad to hear
more and more and more of those stories
as more time goes on a lot of people in
oregon i know lots of good great growers
that have abandoned growing
because
the money's just not there anymore um so
um yeah i i totally feel that so that
one in particular i just want to make
sure people are really thinking about
especially if anyone listening to this
has any um
sway in any of these states that are you
know currently discussing legislative
changes
yeah all great things um
and
you know i also want to uh make sure to
give you a chance here in the last few
minutes let everybody know
um how to find shaping fire the website
social media accounts it's all fairly
easy because if anyone looks for shaking
fire they should find you um but i'll do
the i'll do the plugs anyway yeah dude
do the plugs
yeah the plugs uh so uh the the center
of the shaping fire universe is at
shapingfire.com
you can listen to podcast episodes there
you can sign up for the newsletter there
as well
um
we do cool contests for people who are
subscribed to the newsletter so i
recommend that you uh you sign up for
that um the the at shaping fire
instagram is incredibly popular that's
where i do
you know most of my teaching both
successes and failures and um you know
let you know about some of the stuff
i've found in um you know regenerative
growing technique or
or new products that i'm into whatever
so the instagram's um uh pretty popular
now i also have a personal instagram at
shangolos that's also got you know 10
000 followers or whatever and that's a
little bit less about the show and a
little bit more about you know farm
tours that i've gone on
and um
um just like inter more interesting
things about like me as another cannabis
enthusiast that stuff that doesn't
necessarily fit the shaping fire brand
um i also want to plug the shaping fire
youtube channel which is really
different because um even though there
are certainly um
the audio files from
the the shaping fire podcast are there
for you to listen to as well
the reason people love the shaping fire
youtube channel is because that's where
i post all of my random videos from
doing shaping fire so
you'll get you know lots of farm tours
farm tour outtakes when i go to
conventions everything that i see at the
convention
i i record all of those speakers and
bring them home for people who don't
have access to it the youtube channel
was nothing that i like intended to do
it was just that when i got home from
traveling i had all these videos where
the hell am i going to put them and so i
just started dumping them onto the
youtube channel and now like you know
um there are there are hundreds of
videos there and um you know we've got
you know 10 or 13 000 subscribers and um
and i think we just recently hit like
you know our one millionth viewer so
nice so it's really popular and so so
that's kind of fun and um yeah i think
that's it so but the center of that
universe is shaping fire.com and
honestly if you just put shaping fire in
google you'll find it all yeah
um before we go i also want to thank you
jason you know i i i absolutely see why
you got feedback from people that you
and i should talk yeah um i have enjoyed
i have enjoyed this interview a great
deal which is not something i can always
say when i'm on shows
but you're
you're um we do have a similar warm
cadence and thoughtful approach to
interviewing and i absolutely see why
people uh suggested that we meet because
i too
share your your experience of of feeling
an immediate kinship with you and like
we could talk for hours and hours so so
hopefully when when all this cody
[__] is done um we can have time to
get together and do that oh yeah
absolutely i mean something i'm
uh
planning to do whenever it's safe to do
i i'd actually plan to do it the year
coveted hit was i i wanted to
hit the road and travel around meet with
a lot of people that i had already been
meeting for the podcast and everything
do some on-site you know live videos and
all that sort of stuff and you know that
came crashing down and then i was like
okay maybe 20 21 that'll happen
um no
it didn't happen again
so we'll see about 2022 but at some
point i will be getting on the road and
trying to connect with folks and um you
know it would be great to have you up
here for a vimeo meeting yeah yeah once
we once we restart those i think you'd
really enjoy the vibe scene it even our
meetings are even in an old
log grange hall yes nice
it's very it's very old-school royal
romantic dude it's really great yes no
definitely definitely when we start
doing those i'll send you an invitation
we'll start those back up absolutely and
then um you know there's definitely when
in person curious about cannabis events
start uh getting going again once again
whenever that happens um i'll definitely
be reaching out to you to um connect
over that kind of stuff too because um
yeah i'd love to be able to talk to you
again and work with you any way we can
it's been a great pleasure on my end
right on i feel the same way thank you
very much for the invitation absolutely
all right everybody that's listening uh
thanks so much for tuning in as always
and if you want to learn more about
curious about cannabis similarly if you
search for curious about cannabis you'll
find us our social media tags are all
over the place um
but
instagram is really the main place to
find us at curious about cannabis and
the website cacpodcast.com
and then we also have an app out
now too where you can kind of stay
connected to all of the curious about
canvas ecosystem stuff
and you can look for that
otherwise everyone out there as usual
stay curious and take it easy bye bye
everybody