[Music]
for decades there have been two families
in cannabis the outdoor growers who use
a sunshine and indoor growers who used
lights they each developed their own
approaches both dabbled in synthetic
nutrients but indoor growers really
approached synthetic and process
nutrients as an art form outdoor folks
generally were using less process inputs
but certainly not always and both groups
tended to use chemical pesticides when
needed over the last 20 years as people
became more aware of eating organic food
health-conscious cannabis farmers both
indoors and outdoors began reducing
their synthetic inputs and using more
raw natural materials very generally
though it was the outdoor folks who were
leading in that direction and indoor
growers were still focused on bottled
nutrients especially hydroponic folks
all of that has been turned upside down
as more cultivators in every part of the
industry began to use more natural
inputs and then with state taxation of
cannabis came regulations that nearly
demanded the exclusion of many of the
traditional chemicals growers would use
as a person who's dedicated to living
soil you can imagine my curiosity and
glee when I came across images on
Instagram of grow operations in just
about every legal state beginning to
bring living soil techniques indoors the
lushness of the poly culture and
companion planning but done indoors in
raised beds or on tables I started
talking to other folks like me about
these amazing photos I was seeing and
they were all jazzed about these new
possibilities to a bright future of
climate controlled indoor growing but
with real living soil and worms instead
of mechanized hydroponics if you want to
learn about cannabis health business and
technique efficiently and with good
cheer I encourage you to subscribe to
our newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos to do
rely on social media to let you know
when a new episode is published sign up
for the updates to make sure you don't
miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter there's nothing else you
need to do to win except receive the
newsletter so go to shaping feiyr.com
and sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shaping fire and I'm your
host
Shango 'lose my guest today is Joshua
Stein's 'land Joshua's teens 'ln is a
lifelong cannabis cultivator and
educator he is presently lead cultivator
at freshwater farms in Oregon he also
has a very active YouTube channel where
he teaches cannabis horticulture
formerly he was a hydroponics store
owner with a heavy emphasis on customer
education and has himself evolved from
using synthetics to using organic
bottled nutrients and is now dedicated
to living soil no-till and raw
amendments today we're going to talk
about all those things
welcome to the show Joshua hey thanks
for having me oh I'm so glad to have you
on so let's start by giving a little
context of folks about where you come
from kind of I don't know
philosophically so how did you find your
way to indoor polyculture like were you
an indoor guy who wanted to be more
natural or were you an outdoor guy who
then you brought your outdoor skills
indoors for work yeah I'm actually it
always been an indoor cultivator and I
just I'd never had the space to do it
outdoors and always just I was really
intrigued with the idea of being having
a controlled environment and being able
to control all those different various
variables and and eventually just kind
of gravitated towards wanting to do
things in a more natural fashion and
that's how I ended up where I'm at it's
really interesting because you know for
so long you know a lot of the indoor
folks are like listen you just can't use
these outdoor techniques indoors they
just don't make the transition and for a
long time people kind of you know some
people believe that and now suddenly in
the last few years people like you are
actually doing it so when you first
started you know
implementing this stuff and you know
telling your buddies about it did you
get some disbelief and pushback and you
had to push you know you know prove them
wrong or were people like hell yeah man
go that direction uh there was a fair
amount of healthy skepticism and and as
I just kept progressing and kept pushing
forward people were seeing the results I
was getting and they're they're kind of
speak for themselves yeah they sure do I
mean that's that's what started all of
this with me reaching out to you is I
just started following you on Instagram
and the the the images of your
polyculture tables at fresh water which
is like astonishing it was you know just
like looking them and making the picture
big you know and so that you can look
really closely and going oh my god he's
actually doing this so that was all
really exciting so so you know aside
from the cannabis team of ours that
you're choosing how did you go about
choosing your companion plants because
you've got a lot of options to choose
from how did you think through that that
that challenge that's a good question I
mean there's a lot of really good
information and there's a lot of great
companies like build a soil that put
together cover crop blends that are kind
of pre-made for living soils that have
lots of clover and you know
nitrogen-fixing companion plants with
that avail that kind of information
available readily available it was
really easy to kind of just dive in and
start learning what was happening below
the surface you know not with just the
cannabis roots but with the roots of the
other plants and and even like the
foliage with the dynamic accumulators
like comfrey and whatnot that I just
really just douve in and started looking
into what all those what all the
benefits are and everything that I kept
coming up with was diversity is key you
know you really you really want to
diverse population of companion plants
too because they all do something
different they all have their their
little part to play in this symphony and
it just seemed
to me that the more parts and the more
things are allowed to play their part
the sweeter the music oh right on that's
nicely put so so how many notes do you
use you know this may be this may be a
question that you don't actually know
but do you know how many other species
of companion plants you've got outside
of the cannabis oh my goodness it's it's
pretty considerable I started with the
twelve seat cover cropland from bill to
soil and then from which says you know
like 60% clovers different clovers and
and vetch and whatnot and then I started
adding other things like daikon radish
beets broccoli we have and and I've
recently learned that broccoli might
actually not be good because of a
potential fungal inhibiting component of
its of it so I have to some research to
do on that but so we're always learning
you know we're all I'm forever educating
myself and if I learned that something's
not good for the bed like if I learned
that broccoli is not good I'm taking it
out for sure but I've got so many so
many things in there I'm really just not
afraid to throw anything in there so so
so alright so the broccoli may not make
it or may not stay but have you already
experimented with any other plants that
you decided don't work for you to be
honest with you know you know everything
tends to the things that some things
just don't come back from the flowering
period because the canopy gets so dense
there's a relatively large die-off that
happens underneath so during the
vegetative stage when there's lots of
light penetrating the cover crop
flourishes and then your companion
plants flourish and then the canopy kind
of overtakes things and you get a lot
less light down there to the soil
surface and then there's this die-off
and sometimes things just don't come
back like I've had comfrey die-off and
not come back and I don't really foster
or worry about it I just figure if it
the conditions weren't right for that
particular one to come back then I'm not
really worried then that's really
interesting I've never really considered
how the the dense canopy of a cannabis
plant would block out the light from the
unders and suddenly it's like you know
like when you visit the the giant
redwoods right it's mostly just ferns
and and you know Duff on the ground at
that point and so a lot of the plants
that when the plants start when the
cannabis plants are young they're
getting full light suddenly they're
gonna get choked out its have you ever
like replanted or added low light plants
like when you start bloom um no that
that's a that's an interesting
consideration I really have I haven't
though I do reseed occasionally like if
we get a significant die-off and for one
reason or another sometimes the the
large leaves likes a specialty of
comfrey
they'll die off and they'll completely
choke out any light from the soil
surface so you end up once the comfrey
leaves have been kind of consumed by the
soil biology you're left with a bare
spot and so occasionally I'll have to
reseed those bare spots and but us
making specific light low light plant
considerations I just haven't done that
I've really kind of appreciate the
nutrient cycling faction factor that
happens when the cover crop flourishes
it's got all this nutrient capacity in
its leaves and then the flowering period
starts and then so it dies off and
creates like a multi layer over the soil
so it's just building to the human heir
it's contributing to a nutrient cycling
and more importantly it just allows me
to spend less time in the garden and
just allow that kind of little micro
ecosystem to do its thing so I certainly
get the value of when you get the
die-off that that that nutrient nutrient
cycling is natural and good I've got
I've got to I guess really specific
questions about that so the first one
would be you know if if having the cover
crop with one of the benefits
of it is that it creates this like mini
rainforest down near the bottom so in
holds in moisture and and in water vapor
down towards the the top of the soil so
that your microbes can live closer to
the top of the soil does it do you worry
at all that if you've got these patches
that you're losing that advantage or
over the over the size of an entire bed
it doesn't really matter that much I
think when you take the whole bed into
consideration its it's not as big of a
factor and that that's the benefit I
think of having a larger soil volume
I've often used the analogy of aquarium
keeping your fish tanks and that I used
to keep little nano reef tanks and 55
gallon tanks and and for obvious reasons
the smaller the tank the harder it is to
keep things in equilibrium you know and
the larger the volume of water in the
tank it's a lot easier to keep it pH
stable and and everything so it's really
similar in soil beds if you've got a
larger 4 by 8 you got 1.2 or 1.3 yards
in of soil in your bed little pockets of
KCA anaerobic bacterial activity or you
know little pockets of areas that are
running less than optimally aren't
aren't such a big deal right on imma
take a little sidebar here
you mentioned aquariums and and I too
have got a background in aquariums and
actually after my brain injury one of
the only things I could do was raise a
specialty aquarium shrimp and sell those
other aquarium people and you know not
only do like you know stoner folk just
like looking at fish right but other
than that I find that people who are
into aquariums and building that kind of
natural and yet artificial environment
also take quickly to growing cannabis
because they are similar similar ideas
where it's like okay I want to make this
as natural as possible but I want to do
it in this artificial environment and
encapsulate nature you know in
side my home it was that kind of an
experience for you to absolutely I've
said I've had similar conversations with
people about this very topic that and at
the time at one point in time I was
really big into hydroponics and
recirculating deep water culture and and
I very often just kept feeling like it
was back in my aquarium days because
we're really in both of those instances
you're just water keepers you hit your
water tenders and it's here and it's
your job to keep the water you know the
water conditions perfect and so there's
a there's that obvious correlation there
and I think you kind of touched on it
too that there's this kind of desire to
recreate something natural and and do it
you know in the most pristine way
possible and there's just there's kind
of this intrinsic reward there I like
your idea of aquarium being where water
keepers it reminds me I mean it reminds
me of the famous natural farming guy
Joel Saladin who always said listen I
don't I don't farm foods and chickens
and cattle he's like I'm a grass farmer
and so long as the grass is healthy you
know and pesticide and chemical free all
the animals that live upon it will do
well and I always thought that that you
know related really well to regenerative
cannabis growing as well where a lot of
what we're doing is is where soil
farmers we're microbe farmers and as
long as that soil is bountiful it will
offer the buffet of all the nutrients
that are cannabis plants need and then
they just do it on their own without
question it's it's a it's a wonderful
beautiful miracle that we've been you
know that we've been given and I'm a
really proud and impressed to see the
speed at which people are starting to
kind of reclaim this old you know this
old ways you know there's like this
revival of the old ways people are sick
of you know being lied to and being
poisoned and and and you realize that
there's just a simpler way and if you
just take care of the soil it takes care
of you
so circling back to when we were talking
about some of the spots of the
her crop dying out do you ever find that
that is helpful like a canary in a coal
mine where if something's going on with
your cover crop and maybe it's it's like
letting you know of a problem early that
you might experience with the cannabis
plants themselves yeah I mean I think if
you allowed yourself to kind of hyper
analyze things you could definitely kind
of postulate what's going on I tend to
I'm really tend to be very very very
hands-off I'm very Fukuoka esque in I
like to just observe you know once once
the plants are in once things are going
it's really just our job to observe and
kind of do gentle steering and guiding
and and that's what really works for me
my days of being kind of the mad
scientist in the grow room and spending
hours in there you know fussing over pH
levels and all these other things those
are over those are long gone okay so to
get to your question is when I see bear
spots on there it's usually always been
because of a thick patch from the
die-off and if it and when I Reeve edge
if it doesn't get kind of repopulated by
there the reap the bloom of regrowth
then I'll you know the next cycle I'll
reseed it and I really don't worry or
concern myself too much because you know
it's a it's a really simple process and
if you long as you follow a few a few
simple rules it's really hard to go
wrong so this next question I'm gonna
I'm gonna suggest three categories of
poly cultural planting and and you are
clearly more advanced than I am on this
so I mean I'm gonna suggest this theory
and then I just want to hear your
thoughts on it even even if you
vehemently disagree so sure so I find
that I've so far in my learning about
poly culture planning they seem to fall
into three categories like first is
companion planting of plants that seem
to encourage cannabis plant grow
and then there seems to be inter
planting which is just simply green
filler to cover soil so that the
moisture is higher up in the soil
towards the surface and they Gen you
know they participate in a generally
healthy raizou sphere and then and then
there's I guess there's four categories
IPM planting of plants that it has
something to do with keeping pests away
and then some people add a fourth
category which is as food right so if
you're gonna go throw this this effort
you might as well get some you know you
know some cherry tomatoes to eat while
you're there or to the extreme example
you know Nick and Liz over at green
source Gardens where where they're
getting huge amounts of food out of
their outdoor Gardens so so with this in
mind you know how do you think about the
different categories of polyculture
plants when you are strategizing well
that's a really good question and I've
just got to give huge shout out to green
source Gardens those guys are just the
shining example of regenerative
homesteading and I just you know what
they have is something we should all be
striving for you know it's just they've
got a really beautiful thing and I can't
say enough good things about what what
they do
I second that good the two I got there
this summer floored me it's like this is
the gold standard for what we're all
trying to do yeah without question
without question they are this shining
example of the tip of the spear and they
they deserve all the alkaloids that that
come with that as far as the poly
culture you know at all the categories
that you mentioned I think we should win
when participating in this cultivation
style we should try to achieve all of
those things in the beds you know I
think at first my first concern was
maybe just kind of nutrient cycling and
moisture retention so there was a time
when I just used rye grass one time I
just planted a bunch of rye grass just
just specifically to kind of eliminate a
lot of the composting material that I
had because I had a problem with wood
louse of roly-polies and so I was trying
to eliminate
their food source you know is just kind
of messing around with things and I
didn't I didn't really like how the how
it felt and then what I what I got in
the end when the die-off happened I
ended up with just this huge Madoff
ryegrass and it just didn't really work
for me and and I've really learned that
the once again the greater diversity I
had the healthier things seemed to be
and that's when I started to include the
food crops that I don't really harvest I
just leave in to rot like the beets and
the daikon parsnips and those kinds of
things you know I think they're just
just wildly valuable to the soil that's
interesting that you leave them in
because I can see the advantages from
that of course as well I mean I like the
idea of of growing the food and being
able to extract extra value out of the
garden and also you know that the
novelty right oh hey look what I grew
next to my cannabis plants indoors right
that's kind of cool but the idea of
letting it go through its lifecycle and
then rotting there in the soil of course
that's going to create the opportunity
for so many micronutrients that you
wouldn't normally have so I mean now I
want to play with that sure yeah I think
of it as just varying the kind of the
new [ __ ] volumes in the earthworm
castings that with the natural earthworm
castings that we get you know if we give
them various food sources you know then
the the quality of the castings that we
get fresh from the source and the beds
it's going to be better so so you know
when we design our our arc of light if
we will for the cannabis plants and you
know I think I think you do 18-6 a lot
of folks do eighteen six and then we we
switch to twelve twelve for the bloom
but that's not really a true for a lot
of the plants that we are putting into
our poly culture and I'm curious what
your experience has been finding these
other plants these multitude of plants
that you're putting alongside the
cannabis
how do they react to 18 six and then
twelve twelve and specifically when you
flip because I would think that while we
do that to kind of startle the cannabis
plants to suddenly bloom that may well
freak out a lot of the companion plants
but I've never grown it at the level of
you have to like you know have a good
set of data no that's that's a really
good question I mean I what I've
observed over time is the like for
instance the broccoli never flowers it
just for whatever reason and I don't
know enough about how broccoli works
necessarily that it just is all it just
stays in this perpetual vegetative state
and so that's the one one thing that
I've noticed different it's hard to tell
what difference is what the differences
are attributed to when we flip flipped a
flower because the canopy is so dense by
that time that changes have kind of
already started to happen at the lower
levels before we even flipped it to
twelve and twelve because of the reduced
light so it's really difficult to say
you know there's a pretty drastic and
pronounced die-off you know late in veg
once the canopy is thick enough you know
to initiate flower at that point in time
they've been under reduced light for
several weeks and it it's really hard to
say what what light is doing at that
point yeah you got a lot of variables at
that point and no control group yeah
that's absolutely so as far as water
usage goes you know I find that
generally the way that I've done it in
the past kind of pre polyculture since
this is new to me as well but I have
found that indoor generally needs to be
watered more than outdoor but when you
companion plant this much you know
you're retaining a lot of water and the
plants create that moist rainforest
effect at soil level so how does
planting polyculture impact the water
requirements it's it's incredible how
little water is needed for for a four by
eight bank
it's when it's properly cultivated the
the companion plants do such a good job
or even if you just used a straw mulch
and you weren't even companion planting
the anything covering the soil is gonna
help retain that moisture and help
prevent you know the transpiration of it
and and yeah so I get by like my home
grow I got three four by eight beds and
they're fed by a like a seven gallon
reservoir to bloom at drippers and if I
had to turn the water off that seven
gallons would last me four or five days
maybe even a week so the water
requirements are so nil and I think it's
just insanely valuable especially as we
you know when we start thinking about
conservation yeah that polyculture plus
bloom at really is a nice system
game-changer yeah totally so hey uh
we'll take our first short break and be
right back you're listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is Joshua
Stein's 'ln lead cultivator at
freshwater farms living soil and
regenerative cannabis agriculture are
surging in popularity and to implement
these biological solutions real science
education is vital if you are interested
in all things probiotic growing you will
probably want to attend the upcoming
science of organic regenerative cannabis
cultivation conference
Joshua Rutherford of Dutch blooms has
lined up an incredible array of
educators for the traveling event the
teaching staff includes Leighton
Morrison and Elaine Ingham on oil
biology Chris Trump talking Korean
natural farming Kevin Joe jury on
cannabis genetics Kelly and Josh from
dragonfly earth medicine Suzanne
Wainwright the bug lady dr. Robert Faust
on natural biostimulants Steven Rae's
neuron aquaponics and chip Osborne on
soil testing and even more folks will be
there there will be a grower panel a
breeding panel and a Dem certified
farmers panel joshua has even built in
significant informal time for you with
the teachers as well the teaching staff
is just as excited to work with you as
you are about attending and there's no
advertising at the event no vendor
booths your tuition is what is paying
the
so they'd all be very present and
attentive to you not a corporate sponsor
even better the conference is not just
for folks on the west coast
Humboldt California is hosting one event
for sure but the show is going on the
road to Vancouver British Columbia
Portland Maine and Ann Arbor Michigan
get out your pen now because I'm about
to give you the website this is a
fabulous opportunity for you to hear
from an array of nationally recognized
top shelf soil educators all in one
place not only that this isn't just
beginner stuff like you get at most
conventions this is an intensive for
people like us who totally nerd out on
the rhizosphere the website is
regenerative organic cannabis calm
that's regenerative organic cannabis
calm you can also find a link on the
shaping fire Instagram a newsletter cut
through all the misinformation out there
and don't miss this opportunity to learn
real soil science as a listener of
shaping fire you already understand the
importance of living soil when growing
cannabis when you have active microbe
communities in your substrate you go way
beyond simply fertilizing with nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium having active
microorganisms in your substrate
supports vigorous plant growth
throughout the plants root zone making
for higher yields and thriving flowers
mammoth pea is the first organically
derived microbial inoculant that focuses
on your plants nutrient cycling
processes to release soil phosphorus and
other micronutrients from they're bound
forms making them more available to the
plant increased levels of phosphorus
will also keep internode shorter and
focus your plants energy on bud
production not only that but the
microbes act as a defense shield for the
plants rise fear by out competing
potentially harmful pathogenic microbes
pretty cool right
mammoth pee not only unlocks the
nutrients in your soil but it also helps
protect your plant from disease mammoths
peas beneficial bacteria act like
microbial reactors
continually producing enzymes that
release nutrients mammoths pee was
developed at a u.s. university has been
extensively tested by Colorado growers
and independent laboratories mammoth pee
is proven to increase growth and enhance
blooming one of the great things about
supplementing with microorganisms is
that they won't come
Keit with whatever fertilizer program
you're already running simply dose on
top of your fertilizer schedule for
increased benefits to learn more and to
find out where you can buy namma pee
near you check out their website at WWF
microbes calm partner with
microorganisms to create beautiful
thriving cannabis mammoth pee welcome
back you are listening to shaping fire
and I'm your host Shango Lowe's and our
guest this week is Joshua Stein's 'land
lead cultivator at freshwater farms so
before the break we were talking about
the variety of polyculture plants and
the positive impacts that they offer in
your indoor grow I'm really curious when
you are choosing your plants for
integrated pest management did you
choose for all potential pests that
could happen or did you choose plants
that would be helpful for the ones that
you usually have to deal with locally in
your bio region well that's a good
question I didn't give it a heck of a
lot of consideration aside from just
just basic knowledge like I meant I use
mint and marigold
at times mint has been my main kind of
IPM companion plant but but mainly I
tend to use companion plants less for
IPM and more for pests kind of like the
canary in the coal mine for pest ID I've
learned that clover flower when it's
allowed to flower really a the thrips
really like clover flowers so once you
have flowering clover if you it they're
gonna threats are gonna attack that
clover first spider might seem to really
like clover over cannabis as well so I
mean these are the those that's kind of
a low hanging fruit so to me the
companion plant is really more of an
observational tool to to kind of help me
see where we have a potential hot spot
and and then and also just knowing
things that like clover flower attracts
thrips you can take some preventative
measure
you're preventive IPM measures by adding
the proper beneficials say before your
clover is flowering to tackle the
potential influx of thrips I like that
idea of the plant as the canary and coal
mine because you know I had not really
considered that perspective in for when
planting companion plants to for ipm
normally it's either okay I'm gonna add
this plant because it gives off terpenes
that Ward's off pests right so that's
one kind and then and then just simple
trap plants which is kind of what you're
talking about about the clover flowers
because it will attract the thrips to
your clover flower instead of to your
cannabis but but this ID this additional
idea that oh it's a third you know these
these trap plants are actually a
thermometer letting me know how how much
my my pest infants infestation is
because you know as as all of us living
soil folks know it's not about having
zero thrips
it's about keeping the thrips you have
in balance and never letting them you
know overrun the grow and I think that's
a really novel idea yeah it's it's it's
one of those things that you know clover
spider mites like the clover it doesn't
mean they're not going to make their way
on to your cannabis but they certainly
hit the clover first and same definitely
with the thrips and it's just one of
those deals where like I said the
low-hanging fruit and you if you're
observing that that's usually where
you're going to start to get your first
signs and indications and it's been an
insanely invaluable tool over the years
while we're talking about pests let's
let's talk about the use of of essential
oils so a lot of folks you know there's
there's a there's an ongoing debate
right people say that if you foliar feed
certain essential oils that the the
pests don't like it and so they'll avoid
your cannabis plants and certainly we're
talking about you know veg or only in
the first you know maybe week of flower
or not talking about late and flower but
but then other folks right the other
folks will say
nah nah you don't want to spray
essential oils on your plants because
the oils plug stomata and make it more
difficult for the plants to breathe and
and I've watched enough of the videos on
your fabulous YouTube channel to know
that you've got a pretty strong
understanding of cannabis botany itself
so so what were your thoughts to be on
this ongoing debate um well I think I
think context is important here I mean
if if if we're talking about just you
know you're like if we're talking about
like say a method one PPS which is
essential oils and I think a little bit
of alcohol you know I have no problem
with those I I think that there is a
potential before cuz they save me Moyles
or some just really heavily applied
essential oils to clog the stomata
especially if you're using them in in
succession like you're just one
essential oil spray after another yeah I
think there's a potential for buildup
and and impossible stomata blockage but
I think that if you're if you're IPM
practices we're such that you're hitting
it with an essential oil on day one
and so maybe day three doing like an
aloe rinse on your leaves or whatever as
a foliar like that those if you're
practicing your IPM in that fashion I
think if that's drastically gonna reduce
the possibility of that happening I
think that if you went with kind of a
commercially produced oil product those
tend to be really light in the oils it's
going to be your DIY guys that might go
a little heavy with the oils and whatnot
or and they could run into potential
issues but I think I think adding a
rinse is important yeah I have been that
place myself when I was more of a rookie
than I am now where it's like well if it
says this much is good if I add three
times that amount it's gonna be triple
strength you know but in the end it
doesn't really work and like most of
these ideas that we're talking about
it's about balance right so an error
moderation is what I meant to say
moderation so so yeah if you're going to
use these faux layers
mmm use them in moderation don't plan on
leaning on them to do to do all the
lifting definitely definitely less is
more
aye it's easier to add than subtract in
situations like this if you've overdone
it it's especially with foliar feeding
or with with IPM or even like if if
you're feeding some kind of bottled
nutrient regime it's it's always you
always want to start with less because
it's easier to add the things that maybe
you didn't get in the first time than it
is to kind of take it back once you've
applied it to the plant yeah it's way
hard to take so you know pretty much
everybody has been in the situation
where they're they're late into bloom
and you get a pest infestation at you
know the worst possible time and and
granted you know if if you've got a
clean room if you've got you know IPM
plants planted if you are are doing
foliar zin in vegetative state if you
are you know if you're doing all of this
stuff your likelihood should be very low
however you know sometimes bad things
happen to good people
so so if you were to get an infestation
let's just pick spider mites but you can
give you know whatever example you most
appropriate to you but something like
that in weak safe or where you're not
going to be doing a lot of these sprays
because it'll mess with the taste of the
flowers and then could potentially risk
molds then because the the flowers will
be getting wet what are your go-to
solutions at that point where everything
is so limited our options yeah I mean I
think if nobody wants to be in that
position and it's um
you have to kind of just gauge how how
severe your infestation is and in the
the beautiful thing about about this
situation is is it if you've had had
good practices like you were saying up
to it's up to four weeks and you just
got kind of an incidental exposure back
and that could be pretty easily fixed
with a heavy dose of beneficial
predators you know that that's pretty
much your only go-to in this in this
instance and you know if if you're at
week four and you have a severe
infestation with webbing and whatnot you
messed up somewhat so so there's some
serious user error so if that week four
you've got just kind of a light little
hotspot in your grow you know things to
consider are hitting it with a very
heavy dose of it like you know facility
really like very hungry predators or
just kind of rooting that spot out and
cutting it out and cutting your losses
so if it's one or two plants in the back
of your greenhouse or one or two plants
in one of your beds it might be worth it
to just kind of cut your losses get rid
of the ones that that could be
problematic but I tend to want to throw
live stuff at it and and try my luck
with that I'm glad you mentioned the
beneficials because I've become a big
fan of beneficials and this year was the
first year that I used them heavily from
veg all the way through the end with
three different applications and it was
it was delightful I didn't have any pest
issues this year which was like
astonishing and fantastic so did you
find that your companion plants
especially the trap plants we're also
attracting your beneficials or were you
able to choose trap plants that were
more interested that the pests were more
interested in them than any of the
beneficials you are using well that's a
good question I I think that any time
that I've had that experience where I've
seen it on the clover we took really
quick and decisive action so we didn't
really don't give it much time to to
observe whether it liked the cannabis
more or what are the Predators had more
of an effect at first the first sign of
any kind of nonsense we just throw an
obscene amount of bugs at it and and and
that you that every time has done the
trick you know I really think that I
would love to be able to do a no spray
IPM on the commercial scale and I think
it's dual
I think that no-spray IPM is is really
the most ideal way to go about that way
you can just focus on your foliar
feeding and and know that your pests are
are handled by the Predators but
unfortunately a lot of times like in our
situation to freshwater farms we are in
or we're surrounded by hemp fields and
we're also surrounded by other cultivate
cultivation facilities and so it it
became really apparent to us in our
first cycle that we were not going to be
able to get away with a no spraying IPM
that because the influx of bad guys was
just more than we could throw bugs at
that's an interesting idea the idea that
you know if you were by yourself over
there that you would not attract nearly
as many from all the dirty ass forearms
around you yeah absolutely absolutely
well you know and I've got no you know
no no problem with anybody else I think
that there's just kind of a natural
thing that happens to you know you get
that many cannabis plants in one area
they just send a signal out you know
they the bugs just know like oh in that
building there's a bunch or there's a
huge hint field so everywhere in the
area they're just kind of migrating that
way and they just find their way into
the facilities so during the first set
we were talking about water and how
between all of the companion plants and
the blue mats that your water
requirements are actually really low I
wondered what your thoughts were about
nutrients because for folks new to
companion planning it's a pretty common
push back for them to say well you know
my nutrients are really expensive and I
don't want them to be all taken up by
the companion plants and and and I get
that I usually start with hmm what
nutrients are you're buying that are so
expensive right
but but to their point I was curious if
you find that to what degree the
companion plants swipe nutrients from
the cannabis plants and so how does that
impact your feeding sure that that's a
that's a good consideration to have I
mean I I had the same thoughts when I
was first getting into this and I think
I think we as a whole don't really
understand the vastness of what's
available in the soil and and in a
properly amended soil so like in my
situation we don't I know that tad would
keep it simple he always recommends that
we remanned every cycle and and I really
value his opinion but I I really hold
fast to my minimalist approach and we do
it every other cycle and and we're still
finding that even though we're waiting
you know six months basically are
amending our beds twice a year that
there's plenty to go around in that six
months and you just kind of have faith
you gotta have faith in the in the
process and the system and know that
those those plants they're there they
are up taking some minerals and some
nutrients but they're also going to give
it back in that cycling process you know
and even if you were cutting down your
cover crop and then fermenting it and
applying it back to your soil as a tea
you know you can you can capture all you
can capture a percentage of those
nutrients that the plants took and give
it back or just allow the plant to give
it back when it when you go through your
die-off process so going further down
that line of thought you know when when
when people ask me about the nutrients
that the companion plants take up and
and it's taking away from my cannabis
plant what I normally tell them is if if
you are going to go to the point of
having companion plants and to be
feeding the whole bed a natural diet
whatever you are out financially for the
nutrients that the companion plants are
going to uptake you will end up
receiving far far more from the
additional micronutrients and nutrients
that are germane to the soil that will
be created because you've got all these
additional plants and and and the
mycelium that comes with it and they are
you know all the additional microbes so
so you may be putting in some new
and those plants maybe taking them up
but the symphony like you were talking
about will actually cause far more
nutrients than you paid to put in the
backs absolutely it's over unity it's an
investment you know it's just like in
the old days when I used to own a
brick-and-mortar hydroponic shop in
Southern Oregon and you know the thing
we would always say is you know if
you're in here spending a thousand
dollars you shouldn't feel terrible
because that thousand dollars is going
to earn you ten thousand you know so
it's kind of a similar thought process
you know what you've got to sacrifice a
little but in the bigger picture you
know you get more in the end so that's
really really well put I like that so
along that same vein my favorite part of
poly culture is the interplay of the
roots of the different plants right and
and you know my science knowledge is is
growing but I would still call it
somewhat limited so so at a certain it's
like when when you know people say any
justifiably evolved technology is
indistinguishable from magic
you know it's for me soil science still
I since I consider myself still a novice
at a certain point I get down a level of
a detail and then it's just magic right
so so one of my favorite parts is the
interplay of roots and mycelium and the
soil through the soil and the
rhizosphere of speaking you know these
these networks where they're they're
moving around nutrients and then they're
sending signals about pests that are on
the other side of the bed and for some
because of some reason this the symphony
as you put it it really seems to
increase the thriving nature of the
entirety of the bed even though this is
mostly invisible to us so over time you
know I know that you spent a lot of time
with your beds and you've got you know
at this point decades of experience so
as the cultivator over time can you
sense any of that activity below the
soil and since you're with them for such
long periods of time yeah I mean without
sounding too you know starry-eyed youth
there's definitely
there's something that happens when you
like when you feel like you've achieved
homeostasis and everything is just
firing on all cinder cylinders your
plants and your yourse there's this kind
of iridescent that happens with your
plants the lipid layers on your cannabis
are thick and beautiful and and it's
when you show people pictures they're
just like oh my gosh supreme health like
it's that feeling you get when you look
at a plant that's just you can tell that
it's at its maximum genetic potential is
expressed you know there's just a
feeling that happens and and I think
that's what caused a lot of us to this
living soil process it allowed a lot of
us to kind of put our ego aside cause
it's really hard really to take credit
for the cannabis that I've that I grow
in these systems because I literally
don't do anything I literally plant them
in and observe I mean I'll lop I'll thin
a little bit but I'm not in there
fussing over things and I'm not and I'm
just observing in that and that's that's
when having the trust in the in the
process and having faith in that magic
that happens because I'm no I'm no soil
scientist I'm a high school graduate and
I went to I went to school for I went to
a trade school for audio engineering so
you know I'm Pro Tools certified I have
no idea about the soil science right I
just know what has worked and from what
my you know very basic understanding and
I think you know your actual soil
scientists themselves like dr. Elaine
Ingham in and lo and fells they'll be
the first ones to tell you that we're
only at they are only at a ten percent
knowledge of what's happening so there's
still a lot of magic that needs to be
deciphered there so even though that you
say that you you don't mess with it much
and then earlier on you said that that
you're kind of past your days of
bothering about pH because of how you
grow your pH is going to be correct and
stable I'm curious where you fall I mean
how regularly do you test your soil this
is something that I wanted to tighten up
on my regime at my home grow I've never
test
in my soil so my soil has been in I know
Todd has been really wanting me to get
oil samples in just just to kind of get
the data because I've been I'm over
three years on these beds and I just
have kind of like if the plants look
like they're doing good I'm not fussing
about it but now that we're on this
commercial level of fresh water we're
going to start to implement you know at
least twice a year
soil samples and soil analysis so we can
kind of see what's being consumed what's
being left behind and then maybe move
forward with kind of a more
conscientious amending as opposed to
just kind of throwing a basic amending
kit that's kind of got a little bit of
everything you know
it's a soil analysis I think it's
crucial for data and crucial for moving
forward and keeping costs down and those
kind of things because now that we're
not black market or medical you know
we're really concerned with cost of
goods produced and all these type of
things so analysis and data is crucial
taken another step down this this
science path you know when when in
medical days in each state before the
heavy regulation and taxing comes along
we all had a lot more flexibility in our
grow locations and so places that I have
worked in places that I have visited
very often we I would see two stations
there would be a dab station and then
there would be a science station and and
and and you know they'd have a rig on
one side and then they'd have a
microscope on the other side so I was
curious you know clearly you know you
can't have the dab station anymore under
under the new regulations but but
perhaps you are the kind of guy who
keeps a microscope station in case you
know maybe maybe to check out your bugs
or what everything so I was curious if
you if you keep a microscope in the grow
we I have a like your little USB 400 x
scope that you see lots of folks have
and I think that sometime in the next
six months to a year I'm definitely
going to be interested in taking some
actual
courses on microscopy because Elena
Ingham has some really good courses and
I'd like to get into that because I
think that that's kind of that's the
next level is being able that's why one
of the reasons why I don't like doing
aerated compost teas because I just
don't you don't know what you're getting
really until you can get in there and
look at what you're actually cultivating
in that tea and so I've been hesitant to
go down that route simply because my
skillset just kind of didn't didn't
allow for me to know exactly what was
happening in the soil I think it's a
very very valuable skill to have and
it's something that I'm definitely going
to be putting into my future toolkit
isn't it cool that so much what what
I'll just throw in one big basket and
called soil science that this stuff is
becoming so much more available to all
of us you know when when cannabis had to
be you know in the dark and in the
Prohibition days and even farther back
when all we could find was you know a
column or two in High Times magazines in
the Stone Age right nowadays though not
only can we talk more publicly about
soil cultivation and soil science as it
relates to cannabis but now like you
know you mentioned Elaine you know you
can you can take her classes you can
take her online classes there's uh
there's that great traveling science
classes that Joshua Rutherford is
running what is that organic
regenerative cannabis calm I think but
he's you know he's taking these soil
scientists and you know taking them
across the country so people you know in
Michigan and and Maine can get the same
kind of stuff too it really is a game
changer I think from everybody from you
know the high commercial level who
certainly needs it but really you know
so many patient and just you know
enthusiastic home growers are diving
into the soil science which always
brings me back to the idea that that
really cannabis cultivation is a you
know is an entryway to all sorts of
horticulture yo absolutely yeah I really
love what Joshua was doing I went to his
first one last year in in Portland and
he's he's got such a great vision and
really proud to know him and happy that
he's doing that because you're right
this is uh it's a very interesting time
because you've we have a lot of people
we touched on it earlier a lot of people
that are just kind of sick of the system
as it is as it's been presented and are
realizing that there's a safer way to
produce your medicine or to produce your
cannabis and and not have to sacrifice
yields or or anything you actually it's
a win-win you're producing a safer
higher-quality medicine and it's and
it's a better product than you would
otherwise
and and in doing so I've seen lots of
people go from cannabis and now they've
got Hugo culture vegie beds and and
they're they're taking this living soil
idea and bringing it once again back to
the old days like this is how we grew
you know before commercial fertilizers
so that so it's people are just really
reclaiming our past and there's this
kind of maybe this inherit nostalgia
that happens you know when we when we
participate in that yeah I want to I
want to go back and fix the URL that I
put out cuz I'm sure that that Joshua is
out there listening to this going you
gave the wrong domain because I wasn't
planning on mentioning it so it wasn't
in my notes but but it's regenerative
organic cannabis dot-com and so he's
doing four or five of these that are
gunner going across the entire US and
he's bringing people like you know Kevin
Joe jury and laying Ingham with him
across the country that's super cool so
so let's go ahead and take our second
commercial break you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is
Joshua Stein's Lindh lead cultivator at
freshwater farms now that the health
benefits of terpenes have become well
known in the cannabis industry people
everywhere are looking for the purest
terpenes without adulterants the problem
with most terpene providers is that
they're not sourced naturally and
instead are made as a byproduct of
refining petroleum and that's so sketchy
the terpenes sold by true terpenes are
entirely different they are certified
organic non-gmo and food grade that
means that they are extracted from real
plant sources there are no solvents of
any kind they are distilled only with
steam that's right only steam in fact
terpenes from true turbines are so pure
that you can eat them not only that but
you can stack them with better results -
what I mean is other company's terpenes
have got a few percent of impurities and
when you stack those terpenes to make
your blend you're adding a variety of
impurities that degrade your final
product true terpenes also have strange
specific terpenes for a wide range of
cannabis strains like Durbin poison
sunset sherbet and granddaddy purple
true terpenes has robust and supportive
customer service so your questions will
get answered fast and efficiently if you
shop for tips before you know how rare
that is so whether you want to cup your
hands just smell some beta Kari awfully
to calm down after getting too high or
if you want to dab some pining so your
lungs feel fabulous and your mind feels
liberated true terpenes will provide you
with a truly natural experience if you
are a cannabis product developer these
are the Terps you want to add to your
oil or edible or capsule or whatever
true terpenes are simply the best your
money can buy don't try and make a
premium product with substandard terms
choose true terpenes for a top-shelf
experience go to shaping fire calm board
/ true terpenes to find out more or
click on the link in this week's
newsletter as a business owner you are
incredibly busy in reality you are
responsible for everything your company
does you've got so many responsibilities
every single day that often you just
don't have the time to really dig into
your marketing as deeply as you'd like
you know there's more that you could do
to reach out to new customers and
encourage loyalty and the customers you
do have but you certainly don't have the
time for it and you're not really ready
to hire someone full-time for that role
either for you I recommend blunt
branding at blunt branding Kirsten
Nelson and her team are focused on
improving your bottom line
you know most marketing firms are
excited to make your logo packaging and
website very pretty
but they leave responsibility for a
proving your bottom line up to you they
don't want that kind of responsibility
but that's pretty much the most
important part of marketing right
Kirsten and her team will help you
engage new customers funnel them to your
point of sale whether it be online or a
storefront and keep them coming back to
you and telling their friends now if you
happen to be a new cannabis company or
an established company moving from
medical to adult use in your state
Kirsten especially can help you not only
is she well versed in marketing and
finance but she totally gets cannabis
whole plant medicine terpenes heritage
farmers and the particular needs of
startups check out what she did recently
for moon tine medicinals in Humboldt
County at moon time medicinals calm
Kirsten and her team put together a
whole brand package for them built their
website and wrote their sales materials
no doubt this is a paid commercial spot
but that does not mean that they bought
my opinion I've worked with blunt
branding on four projects now for
various clients and every single time
they have done more than they've
promised and over delivered on results I
love how they generate new revenue and
focus on that as the goal instead of
just making you a pretty logo similarly
every single friend I've referred them
to has come back to thank me that just
doesn't happen every day grab a pen and
paper because the website address is
coming if you want someone to implement
marketing programs that feed your bottom
line give blunt branding a call they
will share proven techniques to increase
your audience and generate sales while
using cutting-edge technology solutions
in the background that make all of this
easy automatic and trackable go to
shaping fire com forward slash blunt
branding to find out more you can also
click on the link in our newsletter
Blount branding marketing that makes you
money welcome back you're listening to
shaping fire and I'm your host Shango
Lowe's and our guest this week is Joshua
Stein's 'land lead cultivator at
freshwater farms so Joshua you know in
addition to all this groundbreaking
polyculture stuff that you're doing and
the fact that you're doing it indoors is
even more mind-blowing
you're also no-till and no-till is
becoming exceptionally popular and so
would you just take a moment and
explain a little bit about how you're
implementing no-till in your 4x8 beds
and what you're planting and harvesting
processes look like yeah yeah yeah no
toe has really become kind of a buzzword
as of late over the past couple years so
when I think of no-till I literally
think of not tilling so you know I try
to when I plant my my crop plants my
cannabis I will put them in the ground
in a small container as possible so if I
can if I can take my cuttings in clone
form as just rooted cubes or rooted
cuttings I'll put those directly into my
beds because I don't want to displace
any of that soil that were we were
talking earlier about the the fungal
components and the bacterial components
you don't want to disturb that delicate
system like if we had 1 gallon pots and
we had 24 or 18 plants in a 4 by 8 bed
or even 12 in a 4 by 8 bed you're
displacing 12 gallons of medium that was
in the beds happy doing its thing and
you just tearing it up and displacing it
you know and and I think ultimately
that's not it's not the end of the world
your beds will recover but I think over
time there's this cumulative benefit
that happens to really just allowing
that soil structure to remain intact you
know if you haven't disturbed areas of
the bed for over three years you can
imagine the the strength of that
communication network that resides in
there is gonna be pretty fast yeah it's
like it's like oh we've got all this
mycelium superhighways why on earth
would we break that up and then start
over every year when when we already
have all that maturity in the soil
exactly yeah so so ok so if if your
optimum situation is just to create a
little opening and put a bare root it'ld
start
in there how do you go about amending
your beds without disturbing the soil
sure yeah I tend to just top dress and
so when I amend I I once again I tend to
under amend I know that it's been
recommended that you do about 14 pounds
of dry nutrients and minerals per 4 by 8
bed I do about seven and so I do half of
what's been recommended from tatak kiss
and then we've been doing quite well
with that once again and I just top
dressed top dress and maybe sprinkle it
a little in and then what happens is the
cover crop will kind of grow over it and
that the soil life just kind of pulls it
in oh that's interesting good Wow hmm
well that that actually speaks to my
next question which was how do you
actually do it because all right so
let's say that today your you harvest
and you're going to start a new cycle in
just a couple days what a lot of people
will do is is top dress and then kind of
flood it with water to to cause the
nutrients to soak in more but then
you've got a really wet bed and so you
need to let that even out a little bit
but I like your idea that you are using
a less top dress over a wider area
watering regular and then the idea that
the soil comes up and and sucks it down
you know it takes it itself right yeah
that's that's kind of the the the
visualization I have is like is that
really just like the worms will make
their way up to the surface they'll
they'll know that the kelp is there the
crab meal is there they'll come up there
they'll start to consume it the process
of them making their way to the surface
and then and then heading back down
again is going to pull some of that down
and then just the natural person a
chiral microbial activity is going to
just break it down and and you'll get
like a kind of a precipitation so let's
select so we talked about the the
beginning of the cycle for no too
let's talk the end of the cycle of
no-till so so what does your no-till
Harvest look like sure um it's just like
any anybody else we I don't do I want
don't do it dry out or any kind of weird
stressing
I shouldn't say weird cuz some people do
it and they like it it's just for a
living soil bed it I don't like to
stress temperature stress the plants
because I don't want to affect the soil
temperature and obvi for obvious reasons
I don't want to dry out or over you know
over stress that that soil microbiome so
with no-till it's literally just cutting
the plant right at the soil level and
then proceed with your dry and cure
methods as normal and then after that is
in my particular methodology in my
minimalist kind of water only thought
process and our methodology is we just
will re amend at that time once we have
no cash crop in the bed at that time
we've harvested then I'll do my area
mend mean amendment if it's after the
second cycle and then I'll let it sit
for about a week before I transplant the
clones in and that's just kind of the
ease my mind I don't feel like the
nutrients amendments that we use are
necessarily hot or would or would be a
detriment I just kind of like to give
the soil time to acclimate to its its
new influx of nutrients and minerals
before putting the plug in the plants in
do you pull the root ball and plant in
its place or do you plant beside the
former root ball we plant beside the
former root ball once again we don't
want to disturb that kind of that that
delicate infrastructure in there and the
the roots become worm food and they also
leave air cavities in there for aeration
and water to flow it's just a really
good thing to leave in your soil I
always I just drove by a hint field
recently and they had 15 or 20 people
out there digging the root balls of
their hemp crop out and I was and piling
it in a big pile and burning it and I
was just like
Oh what are you doing not only are you
wasting man-hours and labor you're
wasting a valuable resource and you're
depleting your soil use their just it
pains me and if and if it was medical
grade hemp instead of fiber hemp there's
actually really valuable medicinal
properties in those root balls as well
what a waste
absolutely yeah it's really a shame
unfortunately there's just still a lot
of funky cultivation practices going
around yeah yeah for sure so so I
haven't done enough volume to have an
informed opinion on this with or
experience when you plant next to the
old root ball will that root ball break
down and nutrients cycle back into the
soil within one cycle or will it be
there for a couple cycles now the the
delicate parts of the root ball will go
away pretty quick as you can imagine so
like the finer roots and whatnot those
tend to go really fast and I would say
that those are gone from after the first
cycle and and I've never done I've never
sliced into my soil to look I mean would
be really interesting to kind of see but
all I can judge is by what the the stem
and stocky material that's above the
soil line that I've left after clipping
its it sticks around and is visible for
about six months but if you went in and
touched it it would be spongy and you
could break it apart really super easy
so my guess is that the stuff that's
below the soil is long gone after your
second cycle after the second cycle
post-harvest if the stuff that's above
that has access to air that tends to
stay around a little more but if you
touched it or it was stepped on or
anything like that it would just be
nothing it would it would break apart to
nothing right on right on
so um mm-hmm in preparation for a fur
chatting with you you know I spent a lot
of time on your YouTube channel which is
really easy to do and one of the videos
informs this next question you know raw
inputs like kelp and crab meal cannot be
eaten directly by the plant and so one
of two things either has to happen
either you have to purchase a
predigested you know nutrient in a
bottle or you have to introduce the
whole kelp or crab meal or whatever and
give the microbes time to digest it
which will then be picked up by the
cannabis plant what are your views on
this which do you prefer and why well I
mean I I clearly prefer the kind of the
amending I don't like the plant ready
soluble bottle nutrients simply because
you're not allowing the plant to
regulate its own uptake at that point so
when you have it when you have a soluble
plant ready nutrient it's the plants
just gonna take it up because it's it's
designed to be absorbed readily by the
plant and and it typically my my very
rudimentary understanding is that is
that the root exudates play less of a
part when you're dealing with those kind
of water-soluble synthetics or even like
a water soluble organic nutrient that's
just plant ready this this came up
because people there there was a
question in the community of whether
no-till beds need to be flushed and so
so this came about a basically from that
there's that there's a group of folks
who think that all plants need to be
flushed in that because if you check the
runoff of a no-till bed it's got 3 or
400 parts per million that that that
means that it's you know your plants
aren't flushed properly and I think that
that's where that kind of video came
from was me kind of addressing that
aspect that you know a rock help is a
lot is a lot different in the soil than
a water soluble plant ready nutrient and
so I definitely am on the side of the
fence that raw nutrients and minerals
that you you
Wow the soil biology to process and have
their exchange with the plant you're
gonna you're gonna get a your maximum
genetic expression your maximum terpene
expression and that's just based based
on my experience I cultivated for 15 16
years with synthetic nutrients and
organic bottled nutrients and plant
ready nutrients and the second I
switched to living soil there was a
marked improvement the quality of the
product was outrageously good and and
and it was now I was never turning back
it makes a really good case to for not
swapping out your soil every cycle -
right I mean oh my gosh you know you
know in the older days it was like oh we
want fresh soil and and nowadays that
seems so foolhardy because we spent all
this time and effort building this
rhizosphere and all these healthy
microbes into mycelium and everything
and and then you throw it out and you're
like ah you know it but nowadays you you
you know with living soil you not only
are giving your microbes say for example
kelp but they may not process it all
during this cycle and so you might get
some advantages from that kelp next
cycle because you kept the same soil
absolutely absolutely and that's the
other that's the other benefit of this
kind of this process is that you're
allowing the plant and and in one of my
youtube videos the no-till tox series
that I kind of did that which was based
on a lot of people just asking me to
explain my minimalist kind of water only
approach and so I'd like to think of
that interaction between the soil and
plant is this sacred union and so when
the plant is interacting with a healthy
microbiome in the soil it's asking it's
calling for only the stuff that it needs
and nothing more and that's that goes
back to that why we don't have to flush
is because it's not over feeding itself
the plant doesn't have a capacity to
over feed itself it's a it's a highly
finely tuned mechanism in itself
allows it to only ask for what it needs
and only receive that so there's never
like an over it doesn't over feed itself
nitrogen ever so when you allow that
natural kind of process that was
designed in the plant that it evolved in
the plant and you're not bypassing that
I think that's the one of the
contributing factors to getting plants
that so clearly are exhibiting maximum
genetic expression you know their
genetic potential is fully expressed
because you're allowing those little
those little micro mechanisms in the
plants to play itself out I mean they're
there for a reason when you put it
elegantly like that it really points out
how you know the soil has an
intelligence and a heart and and a
strategy for itself and and and mostly
so long as we can set up the soil to
succeed it will do its work absolutely
yeah so kind of changing gears a little
bit I've seen from the fantastic
freshwater farms Instagram which
unfortunately was deactivated but but
we've got a new and we'll give you the
address for in a little bit but
freshwater farms uses LED lights what's
your experience been using LED oh boy
I'll tell you what I was a really hard
sell
I've been an HID cultivator from the
beginning so over 20 years and I just
had never had any personal experience I
hadn't seen any flowers grown with LED
and having been a former owner of two
brick-and-mortar kind of indoor grow
shops I am intimately aware of the vast
quantity of snake oil that permeates the
industry and this kind of no Rd products
that hit the market where the consumers
end up becoming the research and
development size I was really really
weary of stepping into this realm and
looking towards other large scale
cultivators that just simply never
having even to this to this date haven't
made the transition because they're
skeptical and weary
of the technology and that whether it
had arrived or not so I was extremely
extremely trepidatious moving forward I
had I looked to grow mouse I don't know
if you're familiar with him he's kind of
a really popular DIY LED guy who's
working with killed Ellie D now and he's
I really value his value his opinion and
so I reached out to him when I connected
with Mike at freshwater farms you know
when he was like we were discussing how
we wanted to go about setting up his
facility and long story short he put me
in contact with the current light
company that we use now lighting company
for LED and it took about six months of
talks and visiting places that were
using them and and just getting
assurances from folks that I knew were
using similar technology and getting the
results they were getting you know it it
was enough for me to move forward and
try it out so that being said we're
really impressed with LED tech I think
it's arrived you know we're getting to
the point where we have lights where you
have independent spectra tuning
abilities you're allowed to tune your
Reds your yellows and your blue whites
independently so you can actually affect
this how your plant grows the nodal
spacing the lateral growth all those
types of things so there's a there's a
bit of a learning curve for folks like
me who's just used to hanging you know
HIV really high and letting it fly
so there's if there was a bit of a
learning curve on my part but I really
think that you know the the the the
chance for LEDs to kind of overtake the
HID lights in the industry it's not if
it's when it's happening like where
we're seeing we're seeing yields you
know that are you know three pounds two
and a half to three pounds per 700 watts
of LED fixture you know which is
privileged is pretty impressive and and
then it's
sacrificing terpenes we're not
sacrificing any of those things i think
i think as we refine our abilities with
the lights will start to that they'll
start to be a greater appreciation of
what the leds can do there's got to be
some people out there who are begging
that you name drop the the kind of light
that you decided to use so do you do you
want to plug your lighting fellow yeah
absolutely
we're going with the protec evey seven
hundredths they're a really great
company and the light that they have the
fixture that they have in all of our
research we went around and i'm not
going to name the ones that we didn't
like but we saw and talked to many many
LED lighting manufacturers and they all
seemed so cheap and they seemed so
flimsy and this this unit from prokhor
tech is really durable sturdy it's
completely waterproof if there's a lot
of a lot of benefits to this fixtures I
highly recommend people check them out
all right fantastic so you know before
we wrap up Joshua I want to I want to
give you a nice big open question kind
of a fishing expedition you know I have
folks with a depth of experience like
you on the show and and sometimes you
know I can put together a question path
like I did for today but but I'm really
curious what what did I not ask you what
what what do you know that you are
excited about that people in the scene
just aren't talking about yet and I'm
not experienced enough to ask you so so
I just want to like you know open it up
for you to say what are you excited
about that we should know about that you
want to break down for us sure sure well
I think that I don't think there's
anything really that you haven't touched
on but I do think that what I'm
personally have been excited about over
the past six months or so is diving into
biodynamic cultivation practices and in
looking into that I don't it's almost
like thinking of your sort of thing
of handling your soils in a homeopathic
fashion so really very thick very small
powerful kind of head sounds starry-eyed
again it's kind of like you dealing with
energy almost more like so there's
things like a horn manure and horn
silica where they take manure and cow
manure and pack it into cow's horn and
it's specifically a cow's horn they've
tried to use other horns like goat and
and ibex and it just doesn't have the
same effect that they'll bury it for the
winter and then what happens is this
transmutation takes place and you're
left in the springtime when you dig
these things up you're left with this
ball of rubbery humic material that's
pleasant to smell it doesn't smell like
manure it's and it's a highly valuable
resource for your soil for your soil
microbiology and you can use super small
quantities of this to refight revitalize
a very large amount of area and and so
that there's this horn manure there's
horn silica where they'll take quartz
crystal grind it up put it into the horn
cow horn bury it in the summertime and
then dig it out and then use it as a
foliar application to help maximize like
if you have a in a cloudy day and you
don't have don't have very much light
it'll help maximize the light that you
do have and there's a lot of really good
research validating a lot of these
things and that's just a couple of the
inputs the biodynamic inputs there's a
lot of them and some of them are pretty
strange when you get down into it but
the science behind it is really really
interesting and there's a lot of people
like wine producers that are switching
to this biodynamic cultivation because
they've noticed the difference in their
in their grapes that there are more wild
tasting and the more rich and the flavor
profile is is very high so I would like
to kind of take this into the cannabis
realm you know when the first part
putting the compost in the horn and
burying it
I'm like all right that sounds different
and unique but but I can see how there
could be some subtle science that we
haven't learned yet there but then your
second example you're like you know
grinding crystals and I could almost
hear like everybody in the audience kind
of together roll our eyes yeah but at
the same time you know I'm not so cocky
or full of myself that I think that I
know all the ways that the world works
right and so if if people are getting
you know qualitative if not quantitative
positive results and lots of science
supports the energetics of crystals well
alright
there's a whole lot of things that
science hasn't unearthed yet and maybe
there's something to that but but holy
smokes right tell me about it I most
hesitant to talk about it for that very
reason because it may mediately put you
in this class of like starry-eyed hippy
just kind of like you know oh that guy's
really like you know he's on one or
something but when you look into it
Steiner the guy who developed this was
was knows was no hacky he really was a
really intelligent man who's very gifted
and when you start looking into some of
this biodynamic stuff and you can get
past that kind of weird feeling is like
we were talking about earlier with the
soil like what what looks like magic to
us there's science behind it we just
haven't found it yet and so I think
that's what we're dealing with when
we're talking about bio dynamics now I'm
no expert I'm just now starting to kind
of wet my whistle
in that regard but it's wildly and
insanely fascinating to me and you're
clearly a soil adventurer right you know
so so this is this is novel and kind of
weird and potentially works that sounds
like a recipe that like will totally
attract you personally as a cultivator
absolutely so the only thing that I had
ever heard about biodynamic really up
till today I mean I see biodynamic on
bottles of wine
for sure but but you know you'll get
people arguing back and forth on forums
like the probiotic farmers Alliance on
Facebook and and and people will talk
about either popping their seeds or
harvesting with different moon cycles
and stuff like that and and I don't I
don't personally have an opinion one way
or another because I don't know enough
to have an informed opinion but is that
part of your bigger picture with
attraction to by net bio dynamics are
you are you popping seeds with the moon
not not just yet I haven't drank the
kool-aid that much I mean I think I
think that look the moon clearly has an
effect on bodies of water on the planet
and so the when you think about how it
affects the tides you know and you think
that we are a very large percentage
water the plants have a large percentage
of water in them it would stand to
reason that if the moon is affecting
large bodies of water like the ocean
with tides that there's some kind of
effect on anything that is water based
on on this globe so you know I can get
with it I can I can I can see where
they're going with it I just haven't
gone that far down the rabbit hole I
think you can incorporate some of the
biodynamic principles without having to
go that far into it in planting and
harvesting according to you know
astrological signs and whatnot
but once again who are we to kind of say
that there's nothing there you know we
just we simply just don't know we can
just shrug our shoulders and be like
yeah that sounds crazy
but until we actually practically apply
it if there's we can't really formulate
that opinion what we do know is that
there's lots of people who do utilize
this lots of commercial farms operate
under these biodynamic principles and
they crush it they're they're their
vegetables and fruits are routinely more
nutrient and mineral dense than
conventional even organic practices so
there's something there's some something
that that's there that deserves a
right that's awesome I'm so glad that
you were willing to go there with me
Joshua that was that was a really
interesting section so so before we sign
off I want to give you props because it
just came out this week that we're
recording this the week before Emerald
cup and one of your photographs was
while it did not win it you've got
information that you were a finalist
right well I placed in the top 30 so
it's really kind of a funny thing I saw
that they were doing the photo contest
and I was like oh man I just
I'll just throw something in and see oh
so I really didn't give it much thought
I just picked a photo that I really
thought was was great and sent it in
with no expectation of any
acknowledgment whatsoever and they got
back and said that I was in the top 30
out of a couple hundred entries so I was
I was impressed I felt I felt humbled
yeah well hey it's it's nice to get
those kind of unexpected kudos man so so
congratulations on that so so Joshua
thanks so much for being on the show
not only do you have a wealth of
experience but you're just totally a
delightful dude so so thanks for coming
on and I look forward to talking with
you again I really appreciate it thank
you so much for having me on right on so
so if any of you want to get in contact
with Joshua or just follow along his
totally awesome Instagram you can get
that at Joshua Stein's land all one word
and Joshua is pretty easy but Steen's
'ln is st e e NS la ND Joshua's teens
Lindh
all one word and then also even though
his farms his farms IG got removed they
are reset up but they aren't there it's
only like 15 or 20 photos there
somewhere so far but you're gonna want
to follow that anyway and that's
freshwater farms and then to underscores
so freshwater farms and then with two
underscores and and you don't want to
miss that and then finally you
definitely want to subscribe to Joshua's
fabulous YouTube channel where he
records a lot of live stuff he answers
questions he does how to's in his garden
at home
and that's fabulous and and for that you
just want to search Joshua
Stein's 'land on YouTube you can find
more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast and subscribe to the show at
shaping fire calm and on Apple iTunes
stitcher and Google Play if you enjoyed
the show we'd really appreciate it if
you'd leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire i've been your
host Shango lows
[Music]