[Music]
the best farmers are connected to the
land physically emotionally and
spiritually the relationship is
incredibly intimate as the farmer tends
to the plants and the soil and the Earth
returns food fiber and flowers the
farmer integrates themselves into the
living system of the field and becomes
one with Nature's cycles and rhythms
this is the style of cannabis farming
that is the pride of the Emerald
Triangle area of Northern California
between humble mesino and Trinity
counties it's the heart of America's
Heritage cannabis farming and this
region is spoken of with reverence by
cannabis enthusiasts all over the world
today we're going to speak to one such
farmer alen adinon is an internationally
respected proponent and educator of
probiotic growing techniques he has
developed large scale anerobic solid
state fermentation for both the US dairy
industry and the Cannabis industry going
back decades he was mentored by both the
revered Eddie LEP and the late Jack
herrer whose microorganism research and
development Allen carries on to this day
he is co-founder of the probiotic
Farmers Alliance Group on Facebook and
is also founder of grok Kashi a
specialty living fertilizer provider he
lives in a banana belt region of the
Emerald Triangle near Leonville
California I'm your host Shango Los and
Today's Show is packed with insight into
both plants and humans historical
context going all the way back to Roman
times and some awfully fine storytelling
so sit back slow down and enjoy this
week's episode of shaping fire welcome
to the show
Alan hey I'm glad to be here thank you
for inviting me yeah absolutely so you
know before we go into the meat of the
show uh I totally want you to talk a
little bit about where you live because
you know in the short time that we've
been getting to know each other um
you've been telling me about where you
live there in Northern California and it
just sounds like a totally amazing place
to will not only live but grow cannabis
will you just tell everybody about it a
little
bit okay um I live in what's known as a
banana belt region here in mesino
California in a town called lonville I
live at the bottom of a peak called kado
Peak and uh our let me think four or
five of your past Emerald Cup winners
are my uh neighbors here in our
neighborhood and uh on the back side of
my property is probably a a one of the
most well-known uh Vineyards in the
region too and so um you know that many
great Emerald Cup winners are coming
from that area is it are people trying
to come there to grow because of the the
additional Sun that you get or is there
something special with the local soil or
or do you just get less um you know less
Mist so that's less likely to get mold I
mean what's the what's the magic there
well I think that 45 100 foot Peak
behind us the the onshore flow splits
and goes around us and so the
microclimate here is very unique and uh
that's what makes it possible to go grow
grapes in this area I imagine it would
be a great region also for uh you know
how like shade your own coffees and
things like that are preferred yeah I
think we have kind of the same type of
clim here and uh when I first moved here
the property above me it was um
dominated by the cartel grow and after
the landold had gotten in trouble a few
times they needed uh some uh people that
could move onto that that property and
you know exclude you know the cartel
from coming back that's where I brought
in uh I put are you familiar with uh Leo
stone from aici in a yeah totally Leo
and Jean yeah okay so Leo was working
for an old friend of mine and they their
partnership was just splitting up and
you know Leo was in the Army so I uh I
put Leo and another friend of mine that
was ex Special Forces on the property
above me and that's where a fishing was
born wow that's a great story I'm really
glad I asked and you know that there
there's something about having your grow
in this in this uh shadow of the
mountain or you know essentially being
protected by the mountain since the
mountain is splitting the clouds there's
a there's some romance in that yeah it's
I I don't know what I did to be so
blessed as to have the universe you know
let me have the property that I I'm
living on now but it it's a beautiful
place and I'm just honored to be here
right on fantastic so let's let's talk
some probiotics so you know we talk a
lot about probiotic growing on this show
but you know for a lot of Growers uh
still using bottled nut nut that term
may not actually mean anything I mean
they know that it's some kind of natural
growing but because they're so used to
using bottles and may not have done the
research yet they you know the term
doesn't mean much for them would you
explain the frustration that many
cannabis Growers have with bottled
nutrients and why a probiotic approach
is
different well one thing that many of us
realized is that because I mean most of
us I'm I'm not excluded I came from the
bottle background too
I I originally came here from Sacramento
and I worked for uh and with Dale and
Molly fry they taught me how to grow
with like Earth Juice but when I moved
up here you know I kind of fell in like
everyone else and started you know using
bottles cuz they were so easy to use and
the the appearance you know the bag
appeal was incredible you know what came
from some of like the original 321 mix
from General Hydroponics created some
incredible incredible crops you just had
to really have your your flesh game on
you know strong so that you know it
wasn't so noticeable that they were
grown with
synthetics after a while though you know
um especially if one has any kind of a
vision or anything like that it kind of
keeps you from from going that route any
longer I I'll tell you a story okay
um I come from the dairy industry I I
was in the dairy industry for roughly 2
years in the Sacramento Valley and up in
the Yakama Valley in Washington I I ran
my dad's subsidiary company up north and
uh one of my customers we were we we
covered silage pits they they say that
we were instrumental in you know um
getting the farmers to adopt solid state
fermentation with their their feed for
silage that's a fancy way to say we
covered it and fermented it you know I
was working at this Mega Dairy
uh up in Washington state called the or
dairy and Henry or um he decided that he
wanted to have the runoff from our
fermenting of the silage pits uh go into
his manure
Lagoon and what happened is instead of
the Manu Lagoon you know being the the
typical one with you know everything
Dead all around it his manure Lagoon was
it was starting to attract um you know
frogs Ducks things like that
and uh we the only thing we could figure
was that maybe it was because the the
runoff from using the lactic acids and
things to ferment the silage was in some
way bio remediating some of the toxins
in the manure lagoons that um you know
keep Wildlife from coming typically
around
them and we did some scientific testing
and fairly quickly uh the or DA's uh his
manure Lagoon and his Dairy was no long
you know regarded as part of this toxic
super fun site that's where we kind of
developed you know way back I mean this
is like
1993 or 4 the theory of beneficial
runoff coming from these silage pits
that we were uh inoculating and
fermenting with lactic acid bacterias
and I I worked with some of the best um
nutritionists from UC Davis because
through fermentation we could make the
food more bioavailable for animals
also well we took in we used the same
Theory I I started working uh with uh
Reverend Eddy Le you know at the healing
Fields the the famous healing fields and
he wanted to buy this 40 acres and
across the highway from his main
facility and and grow the huge Garden
that everyone knows you know it was so
famous
now
and we he asked me Allan how do you
think we should irrigate it and I said
well you've got that Canal right there
that runs through the middle of the 40
acres and goes directly to Clear Lake
and he said yeah but if we do that then
you know we're going to get in trouble
with EPA from the runoff from the fields
I said well wait a minute let's let's go
back and use you know some of the
technology that I used in the dairy
industry and claim beneficial runoff and
then what we'll do is we'll test the
canal and prove you know uh that the
runoff from the crops uh was beneficial
to Clear Lake it proved out to be true
we we basically made um a 40 acre eban
flow that's pretty radical actually you
know I mean not only reputationally
since cannabis runoff has got such a bad
reputation and agricultural runoff
generally has got a bad reputation the
idea that your runoff could actually be
beneficial to the natural environment
and not throw it out of balance that's a
pretty radical thought well I mean not
only that um it we in my opinion proper
risk management right test your runoff
and prove scientifically that it's
beneficial for the local ecology and
that way if some State regulator or
someone wanted to come and pull your
licensing it would give you standing in
a court of law to to you know keep them
at arms length and keep your operation
running yeah that makes sense and I
think it's probably worthwhile to unpack
the idea of um the fermented materials
that you're were putting on top you know
essentially what you're doing
is you are adding uh microbial
communities to you know both the grow
and then the surrounding areas and so
instead of just pounding your your crops
with NPK that when it runs off it throws
nature out of balance instead of just
adding those you're actually adding the
you know the basic communities of life
and so when they run off your property
they're just help you know they're just
providing the basic community of life in
a different place exactly exactly
although I would add one thing to it you
don't want to just um add the microbes
you want to add the microbes and the
prebiotics that are necessarily to uh
while they're breeding you want to to
meet every epigenetic need that they
might have you want we want super
microbes so what kind of diet you know
what what what are these prebiotics that
you add that U you know gives them this
Buffet so that they can go Hog
Wild Well if you understand Oneness with
the soil and the microbes and you
understand that you yourself or you're
predominantly made of
microorganisms then I thought I'm going
to treat my fermentations and my
microbes the same way that a
naturopathic doctor would treat a a
female with a fertility
issue so when I make like our grow Kashi
product I I add a multivitamin mineral
comp complex and lots of other you know
like fresh Juiced uh beet juice and
things like that all organic and I
really go out of my way I treat my 300
lb fermentation Barrel nutritionally as
if it was a person and we were treating
that person for a fertility
issue that makes sense to me you're
you're you're creating a beneficial
environment for growth yeah and so if if
the prebiotics that we use in our in our
solid state fermentation aren't used up
during the
fermentation then they still are
basically in the toolbox of the microbes
to be handed out later
on yeah that makes sense to me so so
we're going to talk more about um the
particular fermentations that you prefer
in the second set but but before we wrap
up the first set here you know we
started by talking about the bottles and
the 321 and the like the really
beautiful um you know uh uh bag
beautiful flowers that you got with that
and then you said you shifted to the you
know the probiotics so I'm sure that
there's a lot of Growers who are
concerned that they'll have lesser
yields or that the flowers will have
less bag appeal from moving from bottled
nutrients to nutrient teas and such that
we're talking about today you know what
have you seen from others who have
gotten Brave and made the jump from what
they're you know they're comfortable
with in the bottle to something more
natural that we're talking about today
well first can I tell you that I didn't
just make the jump because of ecology
although that's a very strong point I
made the jump because um I was an
emerald cup judge and I was thinking
what in the
world is the difference in the winners
because I mean I'm pretty competitive
guy you know and so I was thinking that
it might mean nutrient density you know
because in wine that's the difference
between something that has you know
complex uh Aroma and taste is you know
High nutrient density is everything in
wine you know you know what a low
density uh uh low nutrient density wine
is called no I don't it's vinegar oh so
anyway I I said how can I test this I
called up a a company called natural
check and I talked to the CEO and he
actually owns theany too but he um he
said you know Alan I have been waiting
20 years for somebody from Cannabis to
call me and what I want to share with
you is that in my 20 years in the field
I've never
seen anything grown with synthetics
reach a high nutrient density level and
I said oh my God that's interesting I
have access to all of these entries from
the emerald cup what if we you and I
could figure out a way to uh
reconstitute the the herb and then I
could get uh use your refractor meter to
to get a bricks rating on it and he said
okay that's great we did that and what I
found is that all of our winners had a
very high nutrient density content
compared to the rest of the
contestants so they were they were super
packed with I mean life force for lack
of yeah they they had they had a way
more trace minerals in them than the the
you know the the plants that and the
entries that you know really uh never
stood out mhm so I thought huh well
what's H how how can I reach this
nutrient density level you know and well
it's through natural farming practices
through basically allowing the plant to
live in symbiosis with these mycelium
and these probiotic uh microorganisms in
the soil and so
uh you know fast forward a few years I'm
I'm working with uh
Eddie and well how do I say this without
sounding
crazy just go for it we're good with
crazy here okay so I'm working with I
knew Eddie for seven years and I hung
out and I watched people come and go and
Eddie had this famous poster on his
stairs that showed all the Illuminati
families and he was always like those
are the bad guys
and I was like yeah but Eddie you see
that Keller name right there I'm a
Keller I go we're no different than the
microbes you know those families 5% of
those families are good people because I
fully believe that we're no different
than the microbes we're made out of 5%
are you know roughly of us are uh
pathogenic so basically you know
sociopaths and Psychopaths 5% of us are
probiotic you know like uh people that
are more empathic and then 90% roughly
of us of our species are uh well they're
opportunistic just like the
microbes it's sad to say but I believe
this and so he said well what do you
mean I go well I'm a Keller look on your
thing there you're saying that all those
families and everyone in them are bad
and I'm saying you've known me for how
many years you do you really think that
you know I'm an evil person just because
I come from one of those families he
said no matter of fact I want to share
something with you I'm like okay goes be
back here next uh next week and and
people that are in the know know that at
Eddie's Farm um seasonally they had like
a tea
ceremony where it was like a a tea for a
Southwestern
Shaman you know mushrooms and such yeah
yeah and so I go I went back down there
and I'm a guy who uh I'm you know old
Bouncer and stuff I I had only smoked
pot and uh drank
alcohol I always steered clear of hard
drugs and I had never done mushrooms or
anything like that and so I brought uh I
brought my wife down with me because
Eddie wanted me to stay the night you
know and do this tea tea ceremony at
midnight and I also was a guy who had
built you know three three companies
previous to getting into you know the
Cannabis game and so I did that you know
with like Tony Robbins using his
programs and so I know that if you're
going to go meet someone important you
know the very best way that you could
honor them is to try to uh come up with
a great question for them that you think
they might want to
answer well I don't know you know I
guess if you're going to do mushrooms
and have a mushroom tea maybe you're
trying to meet God or something or
nature and so earlier in the day my
brother who was doing great with these
sub irrigated Planters these Earth boxes
he said um Allan I I think uh he's
pretty intuitive my brother he said I
think these uh Earth boxes have
something to do with like the technology
behind the Hanging Gardens of
Babylon so I go down there and I'm going
to go to this tea ceremony and my wife
and I go upstairs to go to sleep we come
back down do the Tea Ceremony go back up
to go to sleep you know at about 1:00
and I wrote down on a piece of paper uh
how did the Hanging Gardens of Babylon
operate and I fell asleep to what looked
like um a stack of different color
moving back and forth and I just had
this weird the the first of all it was
like a mission it was like if you should
accept this Mission you know and okay
I'm down uh and I had this dream and it
was like you know how uh in a computer
when you put a zip Drive in like
nothing's there and you put the Zip
drive in and it's all there mhm and I
kind of saw I didn't kind of saw I got
like the the business plan on on how
those Gardens operated and how they used
solid state fermentations cuz those
people in those times were the kings of
fermentation and how they used um these
sub irrigated Planters but the sub
irrigated planter really represented a
gut and what you did is there was like a
fairly soilless medium in the bottom you
built a melal mat on top of it then you
put your manure on top of that but then
they they covered it with a skin so that
the mycelium and the things that are
normally light pruned are no longer
light pruned and so that because they
were in a desert region the thing used
about a third of the water that any
other type of farming would use it took
me two years to talk myself into trying
it but when I when I did try it it it
not only worked but it worked
exceptionally well and so we started uh
Eddie was in prison about that time and
we started doing a methodology patent
for what it meant to be probiotic
farmed and um
let's see where I can go from
there we were working with a a patent
attorney down in the Bay Area who um
apparently talked to some friends about
the work we were doing and the next
thing you'd know we had uh some people
from the alcohol in and tobacco industry
contacting us and they were all friendly
at first they wanted cuz we were doing
this patent methodology patent in the
name of humanity because you know you
don't want like information like that to
be taken and shelf
away and so they contacted us and they
wanted to give us like $5 million for
Eddie's likeness and All rights to
prootic farmed in the methodology patent
um but they would not in any way
guarantee that they wouldn't shelf the
technology oh wow so we told them no and
then all of a sudden they started
mentioning some friends of ours that
were in um free energy that had had um
gag orders and things placed upon
them and they were kind of threatening
that they could not only place a gag
order on us somehow but they could make
Eddie's time in prison rougher I mean at
first they're like yeah sign with us we
we could put the legal team on and maybe
even get Eddie out of prison a little
early yeah they changed their tune at
this point no matter of fact they just
became dicks about
it and so I called Eddie and Eddie said
um Allan I want you if you're down go up
to because I was headed to the emerald
cup that day and he said make it public
knowledge um Tim allowed me to uh do a
quick
workshop and I just taught everyone
everything we knew right then and
there wow that's a that's a very
fortunate thing I mean not only for
everybody who was there and for the
ideas behind the tech but gez I mean
that could have gotten bottled up from
that point forward that was a pretty
brave move just to decide to tell
everybody all at once and uh and get
that information out
there yeah we had some plants that were
grown there's some videos that you saw
on Discovery Channel where um Tim Blake
was walking through one of his green
houses and he was petting this one plant
in the middle of the
greenhouse that's the plant that that I
planted that
day right on well hey I want to hear
more of the story but we need to take
our first short break and be right back
you are listening to shaping and my
guest today is Alan Atkinson founder of
the probiotic Farmers Alliance and grok
Kashi if you like podcasts like shaping
fire chances are that you'll like
audiobooks too just like with podcasts
audiobooks speak to you tell you stories
and teach you stuff here's the thing
audible.com has an offer that I want to
tell you about right now they are
offering a trial of their audiobook
service for absolutely free you can go
to shaping
fire.com Audible and you'll get a free
audio audio book straight up you can
listen to it on your mobile device
computer or download it and listen to it
you know like anywhere it's really
simple of course they want you to
subscribe to their service after the
free trial and enjoy audiobooks forever
but you don't have to all you have to do
to get the free Audi book of your choice
is to just check out the service for
free and the service is pretty great
there are whole sections on permaculture
sci-fi history um biography hell you can
even listen to a book about card
counting in blackj back whatever it's
all pretty rad so that's the deal your
first book Is free it's easy to sign up
it's easy to quit and their online
library of free books is pretty
incredible so just check it out go to
shaping
fire.com audible to find out more or
just click on the link in this week's
newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire and I your
host Shango Los and our guest this week
is Alan adinon founder of the probiotic
Farmers Alliance on Facebook and Gro
Kashi so before the break we were
talking about you know the history of
probiotic growing coming to the Cannabis
world and and how you essentially made
that information you know open source at
at an emerald cup but one thing I want
to hit before we go into what you know
some of your preferential uh nutrient
fermentations are is you know there's a
lot of people who are going to be
weighing using synthetic nutrients to
get really bag worthy you know you know
flowers with really great bag appeal
versus going the probiotic route which
takes a little bit more effort and um
and you never really like locked down
about the flower itself why you think
it's better than the synthetic stuff so
so if you if you'd hit that for me
before we move on I'd appreciate that oh
sure okay it's my opinion that when you
let a melal mat dictate the delivery how
how much nutrients and exactly what
nutrients and Trac minerals are
delivered to the plant that's when you
can achieve these these very high
nutrient density levels I think that
some people they fall victim when they
first try to go organic and they don't
understand that it's going to take your
soil one two sometimes maybe three crops
to get up to its full
potential by the time your second or
third people in noil know this you know
but by the time your soil gets up to its
second or third crop that's when you
really start competing heavily with the
same yields that we would have attained
from uh our our bottled crops now I will
say this um when I first started doing
this to get traction with people um we
called it anerobic hydroponics through
probiotics and I put on a series that
you can find if you go into the
probiotic Farmers Alliance and you type
in dep on a dime I showed people uh
every day I said okay here's what we're
going to do we're going to show you
every day what we did on the
crop and uh we were able to
uh grow a crop of the syx we had some
other plants but synx was mainly what I
was working with because it had been
heavily tested by uh SC labs and other
labs so we knew what to expect from it
when we grew it out using our probiotic
methodology or what we call probiotic
farmed with the sips it it set new
records for tpin and to this day now
that was around a year and a half ago
and one of the top clubs up here is
owned by Tim Blake and it's the healing
Harvest Farms Club um we we've held the
uh the top price point for a year and a
half with the the synx from that crop
that we grew in front of everybody so I
wanted to um alleviate people's fears
that they would not be able to compete
you know if they took this
route right on that's that's what I was
looking for and so um you know is the is
the bag of feel the same like visually
cuz like sometimes when describing um
you know uh uh synthetic and indoor
versus probiotic and outdoor it feels
like you know they they both produce
decent flowers but but the the indoor
synthetic stuff is kind of like like
looks like an Olympian and sometimes
looks a little strange because it's
so um grown in a super uh un
unnatural um artificial kind of way but
the product you get is still amazing and
wins insane Awards and is enjoyable to
smoke um but then but then you got the
other kind of folks like think of maybe
like a high school cross country Runner
also super fit but they run on country
roads and you know they're obviously a
fit person but they um you know they're
they're a little more natural right and
so they're these are both incredible
athletes but they they they appear
differently does the probiotic stuff you
know even when it smells good does it
still have the Toleration that you get
with um with synthetics or do you give
up a little bit of that for a nose and a
taste that'll blow everybody
away no we surpass the synthetics right
on but you know one of the one of the
statements that we made early on um is
the the truth is in the
smoke now in our community one of the
cool things about our community is I
don't care who is in the smoking Circle
I I could be standing there with Kyle or
Ed or you know rest Soul Jack or Eddie
any of these people and we're not like
uh typical wine snobs if some new if
some kid walks up to our circle and has
an herb that'll blow our mind that's
what's cool about cannabis you know a
lot of people in our industry talk the
talk but if you can show up with herb
that blows people's minds that's walking
the walk yeah you know and it's not just
you know I I was able to be successful
you know doing that but now with like
the PFA we're coming up on 20,000
members there and there are people that
are actually using our logo uh growing
probiotic to uh establish themselves in
their local markets because people are
looking you know they're going around at
the clubs looking and asking okay where
can I get robotically fired materials
and when we say the proof is in the
smoke if it wasn't they would call
[__] on us and they would have a
long time ago yeah that makes sense and
you know I if if I saw a fa logo um on
somebody's grow I would be attracted to
that I mean in a way it's a it's kind of
like a seal of approval um the things
that I've learned and let's be real
clear the probiotic Farmers Alliance is
a group on Facebook um about you know
20,000 people strong um where everybody
is discussing in detail um these
techniques that were we're merely
skimming the surface up today so so
that's where I got turned on to
probiotics and and and and met Allen
luckily um so anyway you should check
that out if you're into this topic that
we're talking about today but but your
logo itself the the purple triangle if I
saw that on somebody's grow I would
immediately be into that stuff because I
know that it's grown in a way that I you
know that I aspire to grow better at and
it probably tastes great and I know that
it's not going to have any garbage in it
right and even the logo you know the
group designed the logo the group
started as just beta testers I took 25
testers um and when you say that I'm the
founder of PFA that's technically I I'm
a
co-founder um Michael Fong people know
him as uh m4k uh at Gage green I was
working with them at the time and and he
and I started it with uh the 25 first
people in what's now the PFA they they
were from the gug green testers MH and
uh when when we were done beta testing
we had 3 or 400 members members by then
of gashi cuz we had the members help us
formulate it we wanted to know of the
top Growers what what would you want in
your Bashi if you were going to have a
dream
Bashi so he helped me form that and and
that's where it all
started right on cool well thank you for
clarifying that I always like to have
the oral history to be straight so so
hey so we've got about um oh about four
or five minutes here before our next
break um and I'd love to have you
describe how to make you know I know
there's lots of different nutrient tees
that can be that can be made would you
just give a a simple recipe um that
people can start with um so that they
can you know find see what it's like to
make their own fermentation and Tre
treat their plants with it so that that
you know so we have like a a place to
start for people and then hopefully they
get excited by the results and then they
you know they start researching more and
join the probiotic Barbers Alliance so
so give us something simple that people
can start
with it depends on what's local in their
region I mean if you
had these skills can really be looked at
as um a survival skill what would I do
if I only had horse manure or what would
I do if I only had rabbit manure or
llama or alpaca you know I you would
make a tea out of it and and basically
make a beverage that you're going to
feed to the Earth you'd use a one
problem with
um manties and things like that
is there there could be a pathogen
hiding in it so we depend on competitive
uh exclusion to out compete those
pathogens by using our favorite
probiotics which is like the lactic
acids and the lactic acid
bacterias so you know look and find
what's what's around you like Jack har
wanted me to use um sugar sources from
different uh crops grown locally around
Clear Lake at the time too for
biodiversity you know sometimes we had
plums available to us and all this but
later on we decided to use beets because
I mean a beet is a sugar source that
basically Grows Right in the myal layer
and so I also thought uh I wanted to
make sure that the streptomyces was in
our Bashi so I knew it was going to be
in the wheat because I use a menonite
grown organic uh hard red winter wheat
brand but then as a backup because my
theory is one you know one is two is two
is one one is none so I knew that if I
Ed the Beet and the wheat I'm going to
make sure that I have plenty of imos and
especially the streptomyces in it and
that streptomyces and the lab are going
to out compete any pathogens that might
be hiding in uh other components that
you can find to put in your
tea so to so to break this down even
more basic so are you saying that you
take you take a you know five gallon
bucket and cut up some beets and um put
your your hard winter wheat in there and
and fill it with water and put a in it
and let it sit for 3 days and let it
start to ferment I mean is it is it that
simple no I put it all in my solid state
fermentation
first and then after that I can take my
solid state fermentation and put it in a
in a bucket and I really wouldn't use a
a bubbler because these are these are
more Anor robic microorganism it was it
would be like if you were making a beer
or a kabas you wouldn't use a bubbler I
understand now and when you say when you
say solid state is that more of what I
think of like traditional compost like
just meaning no no added liquids just
mix no there there's added liquids but
it's at roughly a 60% moisture
content so you mix it up until it's good
and wet you know
but a A good rule of thumb would be when
you make your solid state fermentation
add fluid until you can just barely
squeeze some drops of water out of it I
mean it was the same indicator that we
used for silage when when I was working
with the the nutritionists from Davis
they would tell me Allan check the
silage while they're bringing it in from
the fields and and let me know if you
can squeeze water and it rolls down your
wrist your wrist call me because I'll
have the truck stop harvesting the crop
from the
field I see so so I would um so you mix
the beets and you mix the wheat and you
add just a little bit of fluid and you
get it all turned up and you just let it
sit how long would you let that sit and
ferment before you go ahead and and put
it into um water to make your
tea you know with a solid state
fermentation uh the best way to tell if
it's done is uh wait for the pressure to
stop number one and then number two when
you take that material add water let it
sit overnight and your pH goes to four
or just under four you know that you've
had a successful fermentation mhm would
you break out that part you said um you
fermented till stops what what exactly
do you mean by
that well you know when you're making a
fermentation like beer or anything else
like that you know the pressure that is
that is the the off gassing that occurs
yeah wait for the off gassing that is
occurring to stop I
see one way is that I mean in the old
days I used to put a balloon on the
barrel you know on a Barb and it would
blow up the balloon and then when the
balloon stopped blowing up and it
contracted I would know the fermentation
was compl complete nowadays I I just you
know I know in these food grade barrels
how many days it takes me so I don't I
don't have to you know do that research
anymore yeah right on and when I when I
make um you know uh sauerkraut and stuff
I use a plug on the top of my Carboy
that uh you know it's it's an scurve and
it's got water in it so I can tell that
there's bubbles going through it so you
just throw one of those on top and then
when when that stops giving off gases
you know that you're you're good to put
it in some water so when you do you just
immediately put it in water mix it up
and put it on the plants because I would
think that going from the dry uh state
to be in the in the water state if you
don't use it right away um that you're
going to choke off the microbes that are
living in
there yeah um what you want to do at
that point is dry it and then you can
store it you know like you've got these
how how did Joseph make the wheat stay
good for seven years for the pharaoh he
fermented it and then he dried it and
then they put it away that's what we do
with this
stuff I see and so so once it's on the
Shelf when you want to reactivate it and
put it on your crops do you take it out
and just put it you know mix it right
into your soil or are you making even
even bothering to make a tea out of it
at that point well what we want to do is
have a multi-purpose product and so we
could uh if we make a tea out of it then
um we can apply it foliarly but if we
apply it you know as the tea we're we're
not really putting down the trace
minerals onto the soil surface so we you
could go both routes make a tea out of
some of it and then go in and broadcast
your bokashi onto the soil surface
roughly every 10 days to two weeks
depending on how big the plant is
because we're not just giving the the
plant and the the soil the probotics
that it needs we're giving it the
probotics that need it needs and the
prebiotics you know the food for the
microbes to keep the microbes happy and
very uh active if we if we can keep the
like the streptomyces In Bloom and we
can see it growing then we know that uh
it is both making the plant's immune
system and the soil's immune system
everything that it can be at its Zenith
and also the the photosynthesis will
occur at the highest rate possible
right on I follow you so before before
we go to break I just want to say that
you know there is a you know hopefully
at this point we have gotten folks
excited about okay that there's
alternatives to the bottle that you can
create these you know these Ultra Rich
um uh microb communities and mycelium
communities in your substrate and they
will make the most amazing plants that
you've ever grown though it might take
you a cycle or two or three to get your
soil up to speed but but the goal here
is to to to let people know to have
faith that there is another solution
other than the bottle um you'll have the
best grows of your life and you know you
should read some and probably join the
probiotic Farmers lines Facebook groups
so that you can learn and share
information with others and you know you
know You' be producing a much better
flower that's better for the people who
smoke it and and um you know you get to
have some fun learning along the way so
with that let's go to our second
commercial and then come back and talk a
little bit about the the business side
of of probiotics um you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is Alan
atkison founder of the probiotics
Farmers Alliance and Gro
Kashi using pesticides when growing
cannabis has been common for a long time
nowadays though we know better we know
that most pesticides formulated for food
crops have never been tested for use
with cannabis they've been tested to be
eaten in tiny doses they have not been
tested to be inhaled and especially not
concentrated ated into a cannabis oil
chemical residues from pesticides are
not healthy for anyone but they are
especially dangerous for patients for
commercial cannabis Growers this has
become very impactful cannabis
enthusiasts and patients have gotten
educated enough that they avoid Growers
who used pesticides not only that but
States across the country have begun
making pesticide testing mandatory on
all licensed cannabis crops the time has
come to find a better way to fight
Garden pests than covering your cannabis
and chemicals and there is a better way
let some good bugs fight your bad bugs
beneficial insects and predatory mites
have come a long way since we were
buying ladybugs online and putting them
in the growroom and just hoping for the
best natural enemies biocontrol can help
you solve pest issues without using
chemicals natural enemies founder Shane
Young learned best practices from
working in the ornamental plant industry
and has fine-tuned those strategies
specifically for large cannabis crops
Shane works with commercial cannabis
clients across the country to ensure
that they keep their crops safe and pest
free without the use of chemicals
natural enemies has proven solutions for
spider mites aphids thrips russet mites
broad mites Shor flies white fly and
others too you can rely on natural
enemies for expertise and excellent
service for more information go to
shaping
fire.com sln natural enemies or simply
click on their Banner in this week's
newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I am your host
shangala and our guest this week is Alan
Atkinson founder of the probiotic
Farmers Alliance and grok Kashi so you
know I know that you uh your life's work
as far as probiotics go was the
development and the releasing of gashi
which is you know your own special blend
of bokashi and you know I had never
heard of Bashi before I joined the
probiotic Farmers Alliance to learn
about it so why don't you take a moment
and kind of explain what it is and how
it works to kind of bring people up to
speed cuz you know I know when I first
when I used it for the first time after
you gave me a sample of at Emerald cup I
I freaked out a little bit because like
all this stuff I had never seen happen
in my soil you know all this out of
control mycelium and unidentified
microbes and colorful but beneficial
molds it was very strange so why don't
you go ahead and just talk a little
little bit about what Bashi is uh from a
probiotic level and we'll kind of just
take it from
there okay the Bashi would be a
supplement that you add to your soil you
know so that you could take advant
advantage of competitive exclusion out
on the crops in the
fields in Roman times you know it was
used um you know how you had the
different deities one of the deities in
Roman times one of the Gods was called
lacus and tus was in you know we know it
as lactic acid bacteria but it was in
charge of the safeguarding and the
storage of
crops um the other one the streptomyces
melum we're talking about I'm still
looking for more links so that I can
really nail this down but um it was
known as uh St Anthony's snow and
everyone knows about St Anthony's fire
you know what I mean it's ergotism and
things like that and it it gets into the
joints of people well the cure for St
Anthony fire was this St Anthony snow
this actinomyces
streptomyces and what we know is that uh
when all the wheat back in those days
was put put away you know there was a
labor force that had to uh ferment it
and put it away and one of the reasons
why it it was done by hand is that as
these Roman soldiers were returning what
let me say this to you when you create a
soldier you must create a psychopath
because that Soldier has to be able to
kill to reindo that Soldier into society
what you need is some sort of an
empathogen you have to reinstall empathy
in into that Soldier and that's why they
would have had this work done uh By Hand
by these soldiers that were having
problems that were coming back the you
know direct exposure to the hands and
the feet with the lactic acid bacteria
and by the way we can go to Google
Scholar and look this up and find that U
PTS treatments there are they are
scientifically valid uh PTSD treatments
that include these these probiotics that
we're talking about especially lactic
acid
bacteria it it reinstalls empathy in
people wow so my thought is well let's
do the same thing I I will get myself a
a I'll surround myself with with
veterans that you know have have had or
still have PTSD and uh have them make
these products and watch the out come
and what I've watched is a a real
turnaround in a lot of these guys so I'm
I've worked with uh small business
administration and will continue to to
uh provide therapy to these to these
guys through their involvement in in
this bokashi or gashi making it's also
nice because um you know we're we're
always looking with the veterans to
provide retraining when they come back
so working in solid state fermentation
Tech Technologies is a that's a great uh
Avenue for them to go you know into yeah
and you're getting these these these
folks who are you know skilled and
really good at project management and
and getting things done and you're
you're teaching them how to use those
skills in a way that's you know good for
the Neighbors good for the neighborhood
good for the environment what an amazing
retraining program and um just the idea
that them working with the the the the
labs and probably handling the soil with
their hands as well the fact that that's
all healing them and and regrowing
empathy in them I mean that's really
profound I didn't actually know you were
going like that far with this and that
that's that's pretty heavy duty stuff
I've never heard that before I I want to
I want to share some news that I got
just this last week now one of my I'm
folding the grok Kashi company in and
grok Kashi is going to be a product
under the plant candy label uh plant
candy also uh we'll have liquidates that
are revolutionary because our partners
hold like 170 patents in the gold mining
industry and one of the problems with
liquid humates is is heavy metal content
so when we run these these humates
through gold mining equipment we can
pull out most of the heavy metals and
get them out of the
way now what's cool is that one of my
partners has a direct Avenue with four
of the largest oil companies right now
so imagine if you
oil
pipelines you know they're they're prone
to rupture it
happens so if we found the average
amount of oil that was spilled from one
of these uh and we know that like Bashi
have been used Ian bokashi have been
used like on on the Exxon bdes uh or no
I think it was the Costco Busan here in
the the Bay Area to clean up oil so if
we figure out the the amount of oil
that's regularly spilled and we have the
veterans make uh that much bokashi you
know three times the amount of the
average spill and have it on site then
it provides retraining for the veterans
but we're getting great involvement with
the oil companies
because wherever the rupture
occurs we go there and we will train the
veterans and have the veterans in that
area make the the grok Kashi for the
next oil spill so the area that was
ecologically
impacted they're also going to get
funding in the form of you know those
veterans in that area are hired and
retrained to make the Bashi uh for the
next oil spill cleanup so if it was
10,000 barrels that they spilled we're
going to make 30,000 barrels of Bashi In
that
region and so it's it's
um you're you're adding to the local
economy too yeah absolutely and and and
getting training for those local vets we
we found a way with these corporate
sponsors you know uh I pray it goes
through the way we we hope it does but
it looks it looks like it it is going to
become a reality that we're going to be
able to open up shop wherever these oil
spills
occur yeah it feels very much like a um
a kind of a Johnny Apple seat as the as
the environmental blight happens you're
suddenly coming in and teaching the
local vets how to um make Rashi which
then fixes the environment and also
creates new local business and retrains
the vet it sounds like it's a win-win
winwin like everybody involved gets a
win exactly it's it I hate to be uh too
simple at it but or stating it but it's
like threatening them with a good time
because it's it's the best public
relations that they could ask
for right on so hey I really appreciate
you taking the time to be on the show
alen you know um even though we're
reaching the end of the show here I can
tell that you've got stories for days
and we probably could have had a show
that three times as long but um thanks
for taking the time out of your busy
schedule to to share with us your vision
of probiotics and kind of break it down
at you know not only a scientific level
but you know you really gave a lot of
the history and romance of it too it um
even though I I read your posts all the
time um you gave me a new perspective of
of working with um fermentation as well
so so I I appreciate you and and and
sharing what you
know thank you you I'm honored just to
be here some some of my closest friends
you've interviewed and you've impressed
me every time oh I like to try to
surround myself with people that are so
smart that they scare me well one thing
with this show is I'm I'm able to
surround myself with people that know
more than I do and because I'm uh uh you
know I'm in media I'm able to reach out
to you know folks like you who inspire
me and happily yall are willing to talk
to me so uh it it's a it's a benefit of
what I do so thank you very much Alan
Atkinson is founder of the probiotic
Farmers Alliance Andro Kashi you can
connect with Allen at grow
Dashi
docomo D
ki.com um or you can search for the
probiotic Farmers Alliance Group on
Facebook there's also links on the
podcast episode page and in this week's
newsletter too you can find more
episodes of the the shaping fire podcast
And subscribe to the show at shaping
fire.com and on Apple iTunes Stitcher
and Google Play If you enjoyed the show
we'd really appreciate it if you'd leave
a positive review of the podcast
wherever you download your review will
help others find the show so they can
enjoy it too on the shaping fire website
you can also subscribe to the Weekly
Newsletter for insights into the latest
Cannabis News and product reviews on the
shaping fire website you will also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
for information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango
los.com does your company want to reach
our national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire.com to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host Shango Los