[Music]
the more we learn as students of living
soil
the more we uncover what we don't know
and desire to learn
we move from simple concepts to harder
ones
always building a bigger picture of the
world for ourselves
during shaping fire episode 79 with joey
burger
on creating soil amendments and natural
pesticides from local plants
i stumbled into a gap of my own
understanding right there during the
episode
joey was explaining the challenges to
using aerated compost teas on compacted
low
oxygen dirt and i realized that i really
didn't have a good context for what he
was saying
i mean i learned on every shaping fire
episode
but in that moment i realized that while
i use aerated tea and could discuss
aerated versus anaerobic inputs on a
convention panel
that i really didn't have it solid in my
head from a regenerative perspective
how to use it as a regenerative tool i
laughed it off during the show and kept
going like i'm supposed to as a host
but when the show was over i immediately
got on the phone and called up my buddy
soil scientist leighton morrison and
interrogated him for an hour and a half
on aerobic and anaerobic inputs and
their uses
and at the end of that conversation i
realized how useful
and entertaining this information really
is and i figured you might get off on it
too
if you want to learn about cannabis
health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer
i encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week
and videos too don't rely on social
media to let you know when a new episode
is published
sign up for the updates to make sure you
don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive that newsletter so go
to shapingfire.com to sign up for the
newsletter
and be entered into this month's and all
future newsletter prize drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and
i'm your host shango los
today geologist and living soil
scientist leighton morrison returns to
shaping fire
layton has joined us before for episode
59 on water and watering
and also for episode 54 on geology and
biomimicry in living soil cultivation
leighton is a lifelong enthusiast of
both aquaponics and living soil
his obsession with biosphere 2 led him
to set up aquaponics experiments at the
rodale institute
leighton has worked with world-renowned
soil biologist dr elaine ingham
blending his aquaculture insights with
traditional compost and compost tea
strategies
to prove that natural farming techniques
can replace modern synthetic agriculture
layton is currently founder of kingdom
aquaponics
and co-host of the living soil
conversation show on future cannabis
project
leighton is a sought-after speaker and
past co-founder
of the science of organic regenerative
cannabis cultivation conferences
today we're going to talk about aerobic
and anaerobic living soil environments
and how to effectively use each to build
your soil
welcome back to shaping fire leighton oh
it's great to be back shango it's always
a pleasure to chop it up with you
fabulous fabulous so let's get right
into it man so
um the discussion of the day is aerobic
versus
anaerobic growing environments for
cannabis and
you know it's kind of cheesy to start
off a discussion
with a you know a definition it's but
but you know
when it comes to it anaerobic and
aerobic environments
are just at the fringe of the science
that a lot of cannabis folks know
for for natural farmers and for
you know serious experienced cultivators
the idea of throwing around
you know aerobic and anaerobic as terms
is something that they do every day
but most consumers and probably a lot of
everybody else is not
going to be as readily uh comfortable
with those so
so let's start there would you define
the difference between
aerobic and anaerobic growing
environments
sure shane god be my honor um so
anaerobic means void of oxygen
so that would be zero parts per million
in aerobic to the best of our
scientific explanation at this point
would be eight parts per million or
greater
now there is a top end of that
which is problematic if you get to 12 to
15 parts per milliliter
in a parts per million of oxygen in a
aquatic environment you'll actually
start doing damage
to uh fish their eyeballs their
their slime there's you know the biofilm
on there
on their scales so there is definitely a
top end and i'll give you a quick short
story
um when i was down at rodale working
under a lane
she had a brewer that she was frustrated
with uh wasn't getting to work properly
and i saw she asked me to take a look at
it and i basically said well
your air pump is undersized that's why
you're having problems growing out
these organisms and it made me start to
think like oh man what if i brewed with
pure oxygen
what would happen so i got a tank of
oxygen
um and i figured out a way to cool it
because or warm it i should say so i
didn't subject the water or the
organisms to
you know ice cold liquid oxygen
and i started brewing with with oxygen
and i killed everything very quickly
so that's a fun little fact that yeah
there is there is a point of
too much so so we want to find this
particular
uh balance where our tiger our target
microbes can
can most survive or most thrive i this
this eight parts per million
uh threshold um where does that come
from
you know with most things in science
it's not usually just like put somewhere
randomly
does something happen at more or less
than
eight parts per million um of oxygen
that allows some process or disallows
some process why is that the threshold
point
you know that's a great question and i
think it probably comes from
um larger organisms not micros
not microbes um so fish
you know we've been studying animals and
uh mammals and
fish for a long time now and i think
that there was some realization
that you would not get certain species
of fish and again i'm staying in the
aquatic environment for right now
um that could live in lower than eight
parts per million in oxygen
so you know like uh trout or temperature
sensitive fish
for the most part would not do well
in less than eight parts per million so
i think that's kind of where
that boundary got set and it's
interesting because if you look at
swamps
where you have stagnant water and low
levels of oxygen
you end up with more reptiles turtles
snails salamanders snakes
so again i think that that science
decided that at
eight points or eight parts per million
was
the sweet spot for definition of aerobic
environment so um
you know i i my next question was going
to be like do we consider
aerobic environments to be living in
anaerobic environments to be dead
and i knew that i had a little bit of
problem with that definition because i'm
pretty sure
that the rice patties um well where they
grow rice
are anaerobic environments and yet they
look healthy and they grow things and
now you just named another
anaerobic environment a wetland that i
hadn't considered
and and they can be teeming with life
right
and so so would you give some examples
of anaerobic and aerobic environments
so that we can kind of picture them in
my head because i honestly the only
thing i pictured as an anaerobic
environment was just like you know
a sludgy pool of water
in some city concrete with filth right
but but but but i'm getting over this
idea that anaerobic does not
mean uh unalive it just might mean
off-putting to the human
palate and knows well said my friend
well said
so you know a lot of this stems from
the soil food web camp and the natural
farming camp
and it doesn't have to and i personally
try my best to
make everybody realize that it's all
life
and i don't care where it comes from and
you know the definition of
a ferment is basically the use of a
biological process
with zero oxygen so there's still
biology in there
and i'm sure we'll we'll go down that
rabbit hole deeper but
here's here's some things to think about
zero oxygen ice cold
no atmosphere um no gravity
and yet the tardigrade can live in outer
space
and they most recently harvested some
bacteria
off the outside of the international
space station
in a test that they started about three
years ago
and that biology was still alive so
there's a
extreme environment um here's here's the
even more extreme bottom of the sea
floor
under incredible pressure that would
just ex you know
compact a submarine off of these
volcanic vents so you've got
super hot super cold no light no oxygen
and yet you have organisms growing
that would be another prime example of
of an atmosphere
or a condition or environment that was
void of
everything that we think of as alive
so the obvious one is you know the other
end of the spectrum um and again i'm
going to stay in aquatic environments
because
you know the we're breathing air yeah
the examples are a little easier
in aquatic environments too and also
shout out to the to the tardy grade
right
water bears got a lot yeah i'm part of
the fan base
so so let me let me ask this in a
different way then because um
um if i so so my first time coming
across
a um a anaerobic
ferment was one of my friends here on
vashon trevor he's the first person
actually he's the first person for me to
really be aware of
trying natural farming here on the
island and he had these five gallon
buckets
that were you know filled halfway with
uh
invasive plant material from his
property and the rest with water
and then he had some aquarium bubblers
in a couple of them
and then he had most of them that were
just
in my eyes just rotting in the sun
and and they smelled really um
well i could be nice and say pungent but
they smelled like crap right
i didn't like how they smelled they were
off-putting right and so
i couldn't believe that he was gonna put
this stuff
in his um in his plants but his plants
always looked really good he's a he's a
very talented uh cultivator
and so i wonder to myself i wonder
myself now
if if it's inaccurate for me to say
anaerobic environments are dead
they are just maybe the ones that i
don't prefer is it possible that i
it's just because as a human i'm a
species that is
oxygen loving that i am naturally
um uh discouraged or pushed away from
anaerobic environments because they are
environments
like it's in a whole ecosystem that i
don't interact with
like i want less of that and more
aerobic because that's the kind of thing
that keeps me alive
um any does it make any sense to that
yeah yeah no you you actually touched on
something in the last
little uh comment about your nose
so humans have a natural defense
it's called their nose the nose nose so
we wouldn't eat something that would
make us sick
and so therefore we're naturally turned
off
or ratch or remove ourself
from places that do not smell aerobic
so it's it's a primordial defense and
and again
even in a ferment even in an environment
with with
zero oxygen it's still live there's
still biology that lives there
it's just again not something that we
would typically
want to stick our hands in put our nose
near
drink or eat because of that
primordial defense mechanism of you know
don't play with this because it smells
funny or smells bad i think that has
made me i mean like i'm
realizing it right now that i think that
this has made me prejudice against
anaerobic fermentations and inputs in
general
because they smell bad and so in my head
i'm like oh they smell bad that's death
i don't want to pour death on my plants
and that's that's just wrong that's
that's bro science
of the worst kind
well i love the way you said dead uh
because let's face
it when when life leaves the body
uh animal plant or or human um
generally there's not a very nice smell
for a period of time until
um the complete decaying process or
fermentation
is over and you know
when i first crash landed back here and
march 4th two days before the shutdown
2020 um i
i was you know looking around going oh
my god this place
you know oxnard is amazing you know
ventura county look at all these
different plants it's all tropical
then the lockdown hit and i really
didn't have
anything to do all my jobs dried up um
the whole world was reeling as to what
this meant and
what was gonna happen and so i decided i
was gonna you know at least continue my
work
and so i decided i was going to make a
compost pile the only problem was i
didn't have any inoculant
nor did i have any fish frass to
to get the pile going so what i did was
i
collected greens and browns scrounged
them again diversity diversity as much
different browns as many different
greens as i could clip
and i poured them and i put them in a
cylinder made out of
6x6 wire and some insect screen
and i wet them down and
then i went to the beach and i collected
some
kelp and again you know as many diverse
types as i could find
threw it in a 5 gallon compound bucket
and sat it in the sun for five days
and watched it and when it started to
foam um
i whipped out my microscope and took a
look at it and was like bam
look at the life in here and it had
just turned to a funk
it didn't smell putrid it didn't smell
like poop
but it didn't smell like it did when i
first collected it when it was not
anaerobic
and it smelled fresh now it was
something in between and i poured that
on my compost pile
and within two weeks it was some amazing
organisms
uh growing in there so
our our thought of that something bad
means automatically is dead is is
incorrect
you know there's still a lot of life
there as we've just discussed
so again it's you know a primordial
instinct
to reject something that does not smell
um like something we want to consume
but that doesn't mean that it's dead all
right so
so if we if we now understand the
difference between aerobic and anaerobic
environments and we get the idea
that you know generally one is not
necessarily
better than the other they're just
different expressions of
life um but we are talking about our
favorite plant cannabis
and so will you kind of like bring this
on home
and talk about um you know
what is the nature of the cannabis plant
in that
we as cannabis cultivators are trying to
create
aerobic environments because that's
where our
our cannabis plant thrives
ooh that's a good one all right let's
let's reel it back in
where were the original land races
coming from
they were coming from the jungle in
india and they were coming from
mountaintops in
afghanistan and pakistan with no
moisture
and the other was coming from extreme
moist
i mean the interesting thing about
perhaps let's let's go right to the
amazon the jungle
um if anyone's ever been there they'll
know exactly what i'm talking about
it's just such a weird place where
everything is rotting around you
so fast like the soil is just
teeming with death and life and the air
is is crisp with oxygen
um but you're living in a place where
in the soil everything is is going
through rapid decay
so that would be an anaerobic
environment or an anaerobic digester
and the absolute opposite is happening
in pakistan and afghanistan where you
have
zero humidity and very little rain
so this plant has proven
many different things to many different
people but her
ability to live
in an environment that is so hostile
it's not funny and i'm not even talking
about rudy alice
that's another one but each in the
cannabis family
but it triggers its own flowering
because it doesn't get the light cycles
so you know that's why i think that so
many of these different practices
from natural farming fermentation
to soil food web
growing in super soils that are super
aerated
both methods show efficacy
so so let's see here let's unpack that a
little bit you took that in a way that i
wasn't expecting because what i thought
you were gonna say
is that um the the
the microbe life the rhizosphere that
the cannabis
plant has evolved to interact with right
where
the cannabis plant is getting sunshine
it is
photosynthesizing that and turning it
into
exudates that come out of its root
structure
and feed the microbes and at the same
time
those microbes are living and excreting
nutrition that the plant needs and so
they've got this back and forth
i thought you were going to say that for
the cannabis plant
it it has that relationship with
oxygen loving microbes so cannabis is
always going to be best grown in aerated
soil
but it perhaps that is untrue
um will cannabis grow
just as effectively in an anaerobic soil
you had to go there
what i love about you shango ah no punch
is held
uh let's let's talk about alan atkins
work all right and the earth boxes
um kevin daughtry's got some
videos up documenting um the saving of a
um an old cultivar i believe it was a
skunk plant
and he used allen atkins anaerobic
let's let's get it right because alan's
great allen adkison
i'm horrible in that enunciation i can't
spell because i come from new england
and i can't announce either
well wait wait until you start saying
rio's sphere
horizon sphere yeah all right so go
ahead allen
all right so he he's proven um
that it is possible um and in some cases
you can actually
um hold back
uh viruses and or genetic drift from
continuing
in an anaerobic environment and i
remember
distinctly this was the first regen
conference
in humboldt
at beginnings and elaine
myself joshua went to see um
kev and kevin was excited to see lane
and right away this earth box came up
and to be a fly on the wall and know how
much elaine preaches
of the horrors of anaerobic environments
i was just enamored that he was
explaining how
he had basically saved a plant i forget
the name of the virus
that that causes dudding
but had had stopped this or saved the
plant
stopped the dudding and was actually out
able to now
grow the plant out to some degree of
success by exposing it to full sun
and an anaerobic root base um it was
i thought elaine was going to fall over
but there's you know there's also um
sips
where you're using um anaerobic water
um underneath soil and having the roots
push through
and down into that anaerobic water and
there is some efficacy there so
you know again i think that you have to
look
at what cultivar you're growing
yeah because if you took a plant or a
cultivar with a
strong dominant history that came from
perhaps
afghanistan and through it in in a swamp
or
amazon i don't don't think that it would
perhaps do very well although you know
nature proves us wrong all the time
so you know in that environment i would
say that you know
again personally speaking
i i prefer the the middle ground um
biomimicry and we all know that
in nature you get extremes more so now
than ever
and so in a natural setting
um perhaps you would get a drought
during the summer
and a deluge deluge in spring and fall
so both in spring and fall you would be
thresholding on anaerobic and in the
summer you would be obviously
extremely aerobic as things dried out
now believe it or not but as the soil
structure dries out and the biofilm
cakes
and turns to flake soil structure can
easily collapse especially if it's
exposed
to pressure either from a foot
or from an extreme rain so that
aerobic summer soil all of a sudden gets
pounded by a deluge in the fall before
harvest
that soil structure is going to collapse
and now you're back in an anaerobic
environment and there's nothing you can
do to change that because over time
it will happen naturally but you're not
going to instantly turn
compacted soil into aggregates so what
do you do
if you follow suit now now's a good time
to start using your
fermented plant extracts to finish the
plant
even though its roots are basically
soggy and not in an aerobic environment
now something else that you need to take
into consideration too and that is that
the ability of that root and the
rhizosphere which is the coating around
it where all the magic happens
um interestingly enough can
produce organisms that eat
certain elements and excrete oxygen
and vice versa it can also
change the ph of the soil around the
rhizosphere
so there's a lot of magic happening in
this
microbial plant soil interaction
that science hasn't completely caught up
with i mean
yes we've identified these
five phosphate solubilizing bacteria but
in nature
they're in a community and there is
what i want to call biological
succession exactly like there's plant
succession
you go from the swamp zero oxygen or
very low oxygen
all the way up to the redwoods very
oxygenated highly fungal
the other the swamp is bacterial
dominant
same thing is happening in a in a
biological world you are you are moving
through succession
on a constant basis this the whole
system is in flux
never stops so in that
if we're taking that into consideration
i again don't think that there is a
right or wrong way
um but again i would i would
caution you to use common sense
and biomimicry and not just you know
waterboard your cannabis plant
definitely give it give it some time to
dry down if you're going to over water
it i mean i know
people that water stress and they have
good results
so again i think it's comfort level as
to what
you feel is your best methodology for
growing cannabis
but i've seen extremes and you know
they've shown efficacy now whether they
got full genetic potential
i don't know that's that would be have
to be done in a side by side
and every time i've tried to get a
cannabis cultivator to do a side by side
it starts out great but the
documentation at the end
never seems to quite happen yeah totally
there are there are
documentation challenges with citizen
science i may be a big fan of it but
even i don't like to document everything
so yeah it's a lot of work so i want to
talk about one more aspect before we go
to our first commercial break we're
going to when we come back from the
commercial break we're going to talk a
lot more about
taking your soil from an anaerobic
environment
to becoming aerobic and and how to
condition the soil and such so we're
going to hit that but
but the last thing i want to hit here is
you know in this first set
giving people a picture of what
anaerobic anaerobic environments are
looking like we just
pinged the extremes right um
that's not how most of us are farming
though
so most of us are farming with um
you know like maybe it's new young soil
or maybe it's last year's soil
but let's just say unless you just
bought a parcel
and and you are working on
terrible soil or if you just brought
your pots out of a dry garage and they
were all stacked on top of each other
so they're like dry hydrophobic and
compressed let's say like generally
people are using fluffy soil
and and even with these extremes
that which should be considered the
i don't know i guess i could say gold
standard but our default setting
is to grow in aerobic environments with
a
with oxygen loving microbes because
we're growing an oxygen loving plant
right
i just want to like back up if we've
confused anybody because
we we kind of our examples were pulled
from extreme examples
and and i want to make sure people
understand you don't have to suddenly
start
growing in an anaerobic environment to
to have the plant thrive like these
we're
we're looking at the entire picture but
really we're still saying grow in
aerobic environments
correct um you know super soil or
soilless mediums are
by nature you know oxidative they're
they're very aerobic there's a lot of
pore space
we consider them low tension soil and by
tension i mean
the ability of water to hold pressure in
the soil
so yeah when you're pulling out those
pots
after been sitting in the winter
over the winter dry and with no plants
in them you are going to have
hydrophobic issues and so the question
is how
best to land a inoculant
on that material that can
hold and take uh take take
uh footing take hold to it and so
you know that's where your your best to
try to get a lot of the material back to
a hydrophilic state
so that you're not fat fighting it and
everything you pour on it
just runs over the top and off the side
and so
you know there's some there's some
tricks um there's
uh yucca extracts which is a
surfactant so it helps the water
uh coating or helps the water
coat instead of bead so we've all seen
you know
water droplets beat up on the on the
hood of your car
um but you've also seen when water just
glazes of something
and that's where these surfactants
really play a good role in you know
creating that
uh moisture bond to the material that
has basically has a coating of wax
around it
um so i think in the past shows we did
talk about
what that really means hydrophobic and
it's basically when the bacteria
are not in an environment where they're
they're happy
they will go into a cyst form or insist
and basically what that means is
they create a wax coating around the
outside of them
and that in turn because there's so much
of them and
there's obviously biofilm that biofilm
helps to insulate it for a period of
time although eventually that biofilm
will flake off
um but those organisms will have
by then prevented moisture
from getting into that material and so
therefore that's why you have that
hydrophobic uh condition
yeah i'm um i used to have big
hydrophobic
problems until until you and i did the
biomimicry episode
and uh and i'm happy to say that the
last two years
i haven't had any issues with that but
god i it was it was at the top of my
list of
issues back in the day so so let's go
ahead
and take our uh short break and when we
come back we'll
we'll talk about taking um you know
compressed
hydrophobic anaerobic soil and and bring
it towards
turn it away from the dark side and and
bring it to the um the aerobic
environment
and and for folks who uh uh uh
wanted to hear more of what alan
atkinson's experiments looked like
um you can go ahead and listen to
shaping fire um
episode 15 called open source probiotic
growing
um and uh and alan and i discuss
um his earth box and and the
attractiveness of of lactobacterias and
he's actually a historian so you
actually get to hear about how
um labs and and and inoculated kashis
were used all the way back by uh roman
soldiers uh to help
calm them and when they came back from
war so that's all
incredibly interesting you are listening
to shaping fire and my guest today is
soil biologist
leighton morrison
[Music]
for years organic cultivators have been
looking for a replacement for using peat
moss
peat moss has long been the go-to soil
amendment for water retention and
container growing
but organic growers know that peat moss
is an unsustainable resource
and the mining of peat bogs destroys
habitat and releases sequestered carbon
but peat moss works so well that many
have continued to use it
but now there's finally a revolutionary
replacement for peat moss that shares
the same benefits
while also being sustainable pit moss
sounds and axe like
peat moss but instead of being mined
from fragile ecosystems
it actually is made from upcycled
organic paper and tree bark
pit moss is excellent at retaining water
in your substrate and creating air
pockets and
tiny living environments for microbes
pit moss
instantly increases aeration nutrient
absorption
and water conservation too carefully and
locally sourced
pit moss is the result of decades-long
research into the use of recycled paper
fibers pit moss has the fluffy nature of
peat moss
and handles exactly the same and like
pit moss is inert so it won't change
your ph
available in a range of preparations
including a nutrient enhanced blend
a coco coir blend and also as an organic
soil conditioner with no added nutrients
pitt moss is also available as an animal
bedding
so go to pittmoss.com now to learn more
that's o
s p-i-t-t-m-o-s-s dot com growing
healthier
more sustainable plants pit moss
[Music]
with the national hemp program in flux
due to stringent thc testing
requirements
brother seth and eric crawford continue
to release seeds to hemp farmers that
will be legal
no matter how you grow them or when you
test them these new varieties from
oregon cbd seeds have substantial
amounts of cbdv
cbgv cbcv and thcv
while always staying below the point
three percent thc limit
and guaranteeing compliant crops for
farmers every time
also these new varieties cannot be
pollinated by your neighbor's
uncontrolled pollen
or a rogue male in your own crop either
oregon cbd seeds are non-gmo certified
too
oregon cbd seeds was founded and funded
in 2015 by seth and eric
maxing out their personal credit cards
without outside investment
they continue to refuse outside
investment that would change their
company culture
oregon cbd grows tons of fresh food on
their research farms for local food
banks
literally tons of food they also give
away tens of thousands of pounds of r d
flour to patients as their company began
to succeed
seth and eric started donating money to
the cannabis medicine and hemp fiber
cause 2
by giving millions of dollars to oregon
state university in order to establish
the world's leading cannabis genomics
research program
and they treat their employees right
oregon cbd pays for full health and
dental coverage for their employees
a 401k program and their minimum
starting wage is 20 bucks an hour
plus everyone shares food from the farms
seth has been on shaping fire a few
times to talk about novel cannabinoids
you can check out episodes 25 and 37 on
cbd cultivars in the hemp market
episode 66 on triploid cannabis genetics
and the very first shaping fire live
episode 47
with seth and soil expert jeff lowenfels
talking about autoflowers
if you are a hemp farmer and you want to
grow reliable seeds that are sure to
thrive in past testing
check out oregoncbdseeds.com to learn
more about buying seeds for the 2021
season
that's oregoncbdseeds.com
[Music]
there is no doubt that autoflowering
cannabis plants have finally come
in to their own and night owl seeds
works tirelessly
bringing you autoflower genetics that
are reliable thriving and with
extraordinary terpene profiles
night owl seeds is an industry leader
because of the focused work of their
founder daz
daz is passionate about the cannabis
plant and pushing what autoflowers can
do
and cultivators know that these efforts
show through in his seeds
and night owl seeds really are
extraordinary just take a look at the
thousands of photos
by fans on instagram the proof is there
and obvious
terpenes are complex and rich plants
have vigor
if you are a fan of mephisto genetics
like i am you'll likely also love night
owl seeds
night owl founder daz worked with mitch
mephisto to build the mephisto brand for
years
including breeding mephisto's much-loved
sour stomper and cosmic queen cultivars
i'm growing both night owl and mephisto
this year because i want the best
and night owl seeds knows how to
cultivate community too
daz puts out great stickers exclusive
packaging for limited runs
and desirable freebies he really draws
you in if you love creative branding
night owl even has the secret owl
society text club
just text the word night owl one word to
760-670-3130
for early announcements and exclusive
opportunities
of course you can see lots of photos and
find out about upcoming drops by
following the night owl seeds instagram
too
at daz.nightowl that's
d-a-z.nightowl you can get your packs of
night owl seeds at several distributors
including dc seed exchange insane seeds
and hemorrhage genetics that's night owl
seeds
there's a difference because we're
different welcome back you are listening
to shaping fire i am your host shango
los
and our guest this week is soil
biologist leighton morrison
so here in second set we're going to
kind of shift gears a little bit during
the first set
we all talked about the nature of
anaerobic anaerobic environments
some examples how to think about them
they're extreme examples
so you know so far you kind of got a
good picture of of
you know these different ways of growing
um
but the second set we're going to kind
of go through um
kind of a specific example of of working
with
your soil when you're coming from an
anaerobic
abused soil what most of us would call
dirt right
before before it's teeming with life
it's compressed and
and there's not much going on there and
and most of us would call it dirt and
then we build it in the soil
but this all comes specifically from i
think it was three episodes back
i was interviewing um joey burger
and i was using for an example about how
i use these you know
incredibly aerated teas in my garden
every summer and and you know i love my
brewer
and and and and how i like you know
bubble it up
and then i go and i and i pour it both
as a as a
root drench and foliar leaf for most my
plants you know you know food and
medicinal plants
and he pointed out something that blew
my mind
and he pointed out he's like well you
know you are pouring
your highly aerated compost tea
full of oxygen
loving microbes into
a soil environment that's anaerobic
because
in this example the the soil was
unhealthy
and and he's all like those those you
know those soil loving microbes or
excuse me the oxygen loving microbes are
going to have a rough time of it
and it it really blew my mind because
i really thought of um
aerobic compost teas as kind of being
the universal superhero
perfect for any situation and when
and and now i get the idea that oh when
i when i pour it on this anaerobic
environment i'm actually just creating a
bunch of death and sludge in the area
because these microbes are going to
immediately die
and then they're going to have to be
removed from the you know from the
rhizosphere
and so and so i called you layton
and so and so you explained to me the
the subtleties
about the type of aerated teas
slash ferments that were that we need to
use so
so let's kind of go through that process
if if you would with me leighton so
so in our example um we
have got ourselves an anaerobic dirt
environment
and i am happily about to dump a whole
bunch of ultra aerated tea
on it but there's a better way you know
what is the better way
all right well let's let's quantify some
stuff here all right so
one of the greatest spiritual lessons i
ever learned
from a friend of mine john at the lake
yeah
right to define something is right
is to automatically define everything
else is wrong
and i think if you let that resonate in
your head for a minute
you'll understand more about what i'm
trying to explain
one of the greatest strengths
that i've found in taking
dirt and converting it into
aerobic soil is the use of fish frass
now i started this journey a long time
ago
as a kid um but later to pick it up
after a divorce
and at the time i was working with um
aquaculture uh companies to harvest
their
fish manure and work with it and
i want you to think about this for a
minute so that manure went from
aerobic as it came out of the body of
the fish
in a water column of 8 to 10 parts per
million
sank to the bottom where it started to
go through
an anaerobic digestion for lack of
better words
to a point where it was screened out
through a filtration
where it went a hundred percent
anaerobic
and then i would take this material and
i would aerobically stabilize it
until i had this sweet smell
which i associated with certain biology
because i was able to do the microscopy
to verify it
and if you think about that that went
from aerobic to anaerobic back to
aerobic
so what type of organisms will be
present
and the answer is all of them because if
the environment isn't right they will
assist
so now i have this incredible
toolbox full of anaerobic aerobic
and facultative or oxygen tolerant
anaerobes as well as
low oxygen uh tolerant aerobes
and everything in between
so in in my work here's a a great story
an example
a dear client of mine harvey hubbell
whose father
the telescope was named after called me
about a
cornfield that had been in production
for 60 years
and it was horribly beat up he had tried
to convert it to a hayfield
with little to no success called me and
brought me in
so first thing i did was obviously soil
testing
uh infiltration um
deep the deep pit percolation test
you know the deep pit was so i could map
out the horizons
chemistry saturated paste tests and
obviously i put some under the
microscope to take a look at it
once i got all the test data back i took
into consideration what it would cost
to just zero this field chemistry wise
uh
it ended up that i would have to spend
twenty four hundred dollars
per acre to put the chemistry back
in complete balance so that would been
twenty four
thousand dollars for a ten acre field to
grow hay in it
and i explained what i found to to
harvey knowing clearly he wasn't going
to spend that kind of money
but it opened the door to allow me
to do a little bit more experimentation
and bottom line was i said okay
obviously you've got sparse grass or
hay you've got clumps and patches of
dirt
it's horribly compacted i you know took
my finger out and i tried to press it
into the soil i said look i can't do
anything this is this is compacted
so in my experience i'm going to use
a not completely
aerobically stabilized fish manure along
with
a slightly anaerobic compost
to initially land the first round of
soldiers
to begin to convert this soil
or dirt toward soil
i also asked the farmer that was doing
the hay
to get a little bit more diversity in
the seed mix like
you know clovers and some flowers and
stuff that would not hurt the uh
the the consumers the cows and the
horses and
so we uh we did an application um
actually i had him cover or seed the
whole property
see the ten acres and right after he
seeded it i came in and applied this
uh biological concoction or mayonnaise
and then i uh
asked that uh i
have the ability to come back in in
mid-summer
and do just a biological food which is
essentially a
uh water molasses and kelp
and that after the first cutting that i
be allowed to come back again and apply
a completely aerobically stabilized
uh compost extract as well as the
fish manure by the way that company is
called fish brew
on cape cod fishbrew.com if you guys
want to get this product it's amazing i
cannot
speak highly enough about it because
again what i said earlier you are
getting
a complete suite of biology both
anaerobic aerobic and everything in
between
and needless to say i came back
just before the second cutting and i
brought harvey out into the middle of
the road and i pointed him at the field
that we treated
and i said what do you see harvey he
goes wow you know it really looks
healthy you know the
color's nice you know i like the
diversity of the
of the hay and i don't have any patchy
spots and
so i spun around to look at a field on
the other side of the street that we did
not treat
and i said can you see the difference
and he he looked
and his jaw dropped and he spun his head
back and looked at the field we treated
he said oh my god that feels alive
look at all the bugs look at all the
birds that thing is
teeming with life and i said exactly
and that was three applications and that
field
is highly productive the people that
purchased
the hay requested the exact same hay
uh in more of it from the farmer and i
believe they've started the process
of getting another feel going so that
the same thing can happen
but it goes to show once you put nature
back in play
it it just compounds it just gets better
and better and better with age
so let's focus in a second on the best
practice there
because the story is good but i think
that the the part of it that i want to
tease out
seems to be this um this active point
where
where as i had suggested in my
conversation with joey that we just put
a super aerated tea
on anything and it works for anything
in this particular example you took
a compressed and tired field of dirt
and you put um
partially aerated or
somewhat oxygen loving microbes so
so somewhere in the middle they they are
they are
i mean is there a middle ground between
anaerobic
and and aerobic is there like
yeah we kind of like aerobic and we kind
of like anaerobic i mean like do those
microbes exist where those are the ones
that you would incubate
and i think you called it your your your
first wave army or whatever into the
field
are those is that an actual array of
microbes that you could go for
absolutely and that's that's the beauty
of fishberry tell us about that
yeah that's that's that's fish proof
that's because right because it went
from aerobic
to anaerobic and then back to aerobic
based on my work toward it and
and in this particular example i didn't
i didn't
fully stabilize it to eight parts per
million i left it at about four
so i was teasing out that whole middle
ground that you're talking about which
is
from one part per million to seven parts
per million
so that's a big gray area and that's
where all the magic happens and
you remember this right you you talked
about throwing your
aerobic loving organisms in and and
they're going to just die
yeah well they're not going to die
they're going to go into it's going to
stop
yeah i get it now or they're going to be
consumed
um and if if if you if you did
actually kill them all so say you did
or obviously some are going to die some
are going to get into a situation where
they can't cyst
up fast enough and they're gonna they're
gonna pop
and they're gonna release nutrients so
we call that a nutrient solution
the goal of putting aerobic compost tea
on soil is to inoculate the soil right
you want these organisms to
to grow out and thrive well
in the case where you murdered them
um you basically have created a nutrient
solution that's plant available
but it's mobile and that's the problem
as soon as you water it
all of that you know organ uh
aminos all of those peptides all of
those
metabolites tertiary metabolites that
are inside the ectoplasm of the cell
which are all valuable sources of food
for plants
are now mobile and when you water
they're going to wash beyond the roots
or
some of it is some of it will obviously
be caught by the roots
but not all of it so that's why we don't
use um you know
we don't make aerobic tea and then and
then quickly turn it into an anaerobic
so that
so that we kill off the vast majority of
them because now we're
we're creating a mobile nutrient
solution and that's
the cause of all of the pollution that
we have now
in our environment is due to you know
those
mobile nutrients is it accurate to use
the term
uh uh folklotative when it comes to
those
partially oxygen loving and partially
not oxygen level let's let's hit on that
for a minute all right and
remember science is going at light speed
now
and the document documentation of
science
is is at a crawl so what we're learning
is so
outpacing our ability to document it
it's not funny so what we know
is that the word facultative anaerobes
has been thrown around for a long time i
prefer the term
oxygen tolerant anaerobes so these are
anaerobes that live
and thrive in zero parts per million
but can function to some degree
perhaps not thrive in a
semi-aerobic environment and the same is
true on the other end of the spectrum
so you have anaerobes that thrive in
aerobic environments
that can still tolerate low oxygen
environments
so you gotta you gotta kind of like
overlap these ideas of
oh it's just an arrow or oh it's just an
anaerobe no
there's it's it's similar to the new
understanding
that the 80 percent of terrestrial
biology can live in an aquatic
environment
and vice versa you know
you got to just kind of wrap your head
around how
nature is has inherently
created this ability to live and
and work and grow in environments
that are not necessarily the ones they
are associated with
all right so so if if our optimum
natural expression is through
um having both microbes that are that
can
succeed in in aerobic and anaerobic
environment
this is a big case for us to
have as diverse soil as possible
dumping a wide range of of microbes and
nutrients and all this
because really if the environment has
both
anaerobic and aerobic microbes
whatever happens with the evolution of
our pot
even if it goes south and it goes
anaerobic
on us sure we're going to have like
hydrophobic stuff to deal with
but the plant would still be able to get
into a nutritional relationship with the
anaerobic microbes even though the
aerobic microbes have cysted up is that
true
yeah yeah wow wow
all right now you don't want to leave
that
plant in a sustained anaerobic
environment right
like this isn't the goal right but right
but the diversification is going to
totally backstop a failure on the plant
if you
screw it up oh man this is it this goes
back to the horizontal soil system
you know again these are methods to
take the extremes out of the situation
um so you did over water no problem it's
stored down on the
horizon as the top horizon dries out
it'll pull the moisture back
up via the a horizon and the same is
true with
with the work that i've been doing with
microbes
i mean that was that was the you know
accidental amazement or amazing thing
that happened
when i started playing around with with
fish manure
was that i was by default catching
this incredible suite of organisms that
again
eighty percent of them can survive in a
terrestrial environment
and they came from both aerobic
anaerobic
conditions and then i stabilized them
back to aerobic
but if i didn't they still worked
so you know it's again using biomimicry
in understanding perhaps bigger picture
like
before the great human expansion there
was mass migrations
and these migrations were you know
thousands of ducks that darkened the sky
that
landed in that pond and ate and [__] and
thrashed in trash and then
bailed out of there well they just
turned this gorgeous beautiful clear
water pond into a mucky nasty smelling
anaerobic cauldron right
but what happened that pond came back
roaring back again
and this this is on buffalo deer moose
fish fish would come in and just thrash
a harbor and then the prey fish would
come in or the predator fish would come
in and just thrash and trash and take a
bite out of every fish and leave
carcasses everywhere so this kind of
anaerobic aerobic
back and forth is part of nature
it was part of the beauty of the garden
of eden
before we put an end to it through our
mass
expansion again biomimicry
all right so i find it really
interesting that the the
the what did you call them oxygen
tolerant microbes
are um oxygen tolerant anaerobes
anaerobes excuse me yeah and and i knew
that didn't sound right
that they're from the the water food for
water food web
primarily that you've just we've
discussed so far and
for anybody who's not familiar with the
water food web you should go back and
check
shaping fire episode 52 with uh steve
rasner
and that was the first time like i've
been in love with the soil food web ever
since i started really caring about
cultivation of cannabis but to find out
that there is a
a an entirely uh different food web
that takes place in water like you know
it really blew my mind
but but now you're talking about the
water food web and bringing
these oxygen tolerant anaerobes over to
help us
condition soil to bring it to take it
from a zero
oxygen to a medium oxygen so we can make
it to a high oxygen and
slowly but surely you know rejuvenate
this soil
most of these oxygen tolerant anaerobes
in the water food web or are those just
your preferred
ones to use because of their ease of
accessing them well that's a great
question
but the answer is um you ever made
stinky compost
i mean not intentionally if my compost
stinks i failed
right but it happens so those are
those are terrestrial biology that
are um oxygen tolerant anaerobes
right because they didn't just happen
they they were there or present and they
became
uh active due to either lack of oxygen
as it went down or vice versa as the
oxygen went up as things started to
break down and you moved from
thermophilic to mesophilic they became
active again
so again you can't look at it like it
only goes in one direction because it's
constantly going back and forth well the
bigger picture that i'm getting out of
this
is that so long as we're not working
in a non-natural
sterile-ish environment like
um like uh synthetic hydroponic right
where where you know places where worms
can't live right
so so long as we are are using
natural practices there will always be
in all of the water all of the soil in
every rhizosphere there are going to be
both anaerobic and aerobic
microbes because of the natural
diversity of the soil
and actually what we want to do is we
want to move our soils
from being compressed dirt
like anaerobic to be increasingly
aerobic but the goal is never to get rid
of the anaerobic microbes we just want
them to cyst up and hang out in case we
screw up the pot and we need them as
part of our save
yep amen it's called a buffer
and you know i think that there is there
is
a warning here that putting on
an anaerobic stinky tee um
in quantity on a
very aerobic and aerobically stabilized
biology is that the
primary nutrient cycle in the anaerobic
world which is called the ciliate will
buzz around
and consume flagellates as well as
bacteria
now he is nutrient cycling on a scale
that's
mind boggling compared to amoeba and
flagellates
i mean he's he's he's nutrient cycling
at
10x of what they can do
but if he's consuming all your
flagellates it's going to take
longer for that soil to rebound back
because you have lost ground so that's
why i
never encourage anybody to use a high
quantity
of aerobic or anaerobic
compost tea or ferments
on a highly aerobic environment because
you are going to step
back at a point where you've lost a lot
of your buffer
now if you want to take a fermented
plant juice
which again is being fermented
biologically
therefore it is being loaded with
anaerobic organisms
but if you want to take some of that and
dilute it out
in the natural farming methodologies
there's no problem whatsoever with that
you're not landing
billions of hostile ciliates
are you getting a few sure i'm no doubt
in my mind that there's going to be some
um but again you know diversity is
is a wonderful thing in nature um
you don't see just one type of thing
you always see you know diversity it's
not like you're
it's not like the soil even the most
aerobic
natural soils on the on the surface of
the earth the living skin for lack of
better words
is not going to have anaerobes in it of
course it's going to it's going to have
anaerobic pockets
i mean we see that even within
aggregates so aggregates are
basically a bacteria comes along
and lands on a clay platelet divides
grows out biofilm to protect him that
biofilm touches a silt
particle they keep expanding out now
that
now that biofilm is expanded onto a sand
particle and
this bacteria is growing kids dividing
left and right
and before you know it you have a micro
aggregate well
eventually that turns into a macro
aggregate
and this is something you and i have
talked about in the past
into a rhizos sheath which is the big
clump that you pull up when you pull up
a weed that's just a giant sheath
inside of that sheath on a microscopic
level there are going to be anaerobic
pockets it's not going to all be 100
aerobic and that's kind of the the
the mythology of of um
understanding you know the whole bigger
picture of what's going on
biologically in a soil system is that
you know you are going to have anaerobes
and you
may actually really need them at certain
times like over watering
or underwatering you know where you have
the arrows that are going to come out
and do the
you know the heavy lifting for you so
it's again it's
diversity diversity diversity and
everything and
everything i've heard you describe that
um
that bio film i don't know trajectory
before and i've always liked it where
if i get it correctly you described a
a a microbe finally getting a good
living environment and so it removes the
hard
cis protection of it and it starts to
engage more with its environment
it excretes a biofilm which is like a
gooey substance that protects it from
unwanted uh other microbes and sticks
and sticks sticks and so it's sticky so
so
this one microbe like now is now
bacteria
bacteria thank you so it's one bacteria
and now it's sticking to another
bacteria and now maybe it's sticking to
uh you know another life form and then
maybe a food source
and so um in my head this is how the
where the word
aggregate comes from which is like a
collection of
you know unrelated things that become a
bigger thing as
community right and so and so this is
building a more and more complex life
system of all these different bacterias
and their biofilm and occasional food
sources and
i'm a guessing protozoa and amoeba and
stuff in there and so it's making this
big gooey sticky ball and then
that aggregate atta attaches to another
big aggregate of the same thing and so
now they've doubled in size and so you
can see
how this is you know increasing at a
geometric grate
and that is what we want to do as soil
builders and
is that process that we just described
is
that the heart of building soil man
and now that's not super soil because in
a super soil or a soilless medium
you don't have sand silt and clay so
you're very limited
for biofilm to actually occur it's only
going to
occur on each individual fiber so it
can't really start to bond the fibers
together to make
aggregates you follow me yeah for sure
well the funny thing is
is in in my head i'm like well yeah who
cares about the soilless medium
but of course lots of people grow that
way right well most people in
pots do you know i mean since you did
that
uh or we did that podcast uh episode 54
where you know the was the first time i
didn't get laughed off a stage about
talking about horizontal soil systems
you know i've gotten incredible feedback
on instagram thanking you know thanking
and saying how great it works and
you know it was you know it wasn't a
great great idea it was just copying
nature
but you know traditional cannabis when
it came
you know when when camp came around and
they were forced to go
indoors or into containers and diesel
grows
they weren't lugging you know the
natural soil into the container they
started growing in pots
and of course they didn't want to carry
a 300
pound pot down into this container
buried underneath the ground
or into their house and cave the floor
in because the floor wasn't designed to
take
thousands of pounds of of soil
so it was obvious they went to peat moss
and
koi or that was probably just peat moss
and compost and
and other aeration because of its light
weight
and then of course now you did not have
that biological interaction
so all of a sudden those um you know
organic
raw nutrient blends the stone dust and
crab meal and oyster shell
that no longer worked so they went to
bottled noots
and this this soil profile or soil
system
the soilless medium was a great way or a
great
medium to hold water and to hold
nutrients so it didn't lose it
and so that was like the natural
progression into
these soilless mediums was by default
based on you know the government
cracking down on on
you know the free loving cannabis
growers
and so you know that's why i
continuously use
the term soilless medium or or super
soil because there's still a tremendous
amount
of people out there using this and now
they can go back
to using meals and teas with their super
soil
although the originals were just growing
in soil they really weren't amending
the soil that much i mean they didn't
want to haul bales of peat moss up into
the hills to grow their cannabis so they
just planted it in the ground
so you know that's that's where all of
this
struggles come in uh in in understanding
you know the difference between tension
soil and low tension soil and the
limitations of both
um you know low tension soil has its
limitations
and regular soil has its limitations
because you unless you fluff it up or
unless you have a highly aggregated soil
you're not going to get the plant to
push like you want because those roots
can't
bind or pound their way through that
compacted soil
so that's where time takes place you
have to
cover crop you have to get that soil
prepared for the the growth of the
cannabis plant if you want to try to
you know get your yields and get your um
you know full genetic potential you
can't you can't be planting in hard
compacted clay plants not going to do
well that's the that's the
most cogent and generous description of
soilless medium that i've ever heard
you know like like you know sometimes
i'll i get on my soapbox and i'm all
like well you know i like the way that
jeff lowenfels thinks about it where why
would you want to grow in anything
where where worms can't live right
because that's
that's at the you know the basis of so
much biology
but your description not only explains
the
you know the socioeconomic and political
impacts that
that caused the cocoa but the idea that
you know using a a a non-soil cocoa
blend is comparatively better
than unbuilt soil you know just crappy
dirt right
you know but but then it takes more
effort and
natural farming techniques to really
breathe
life into compacted soil
i see again how i can't make the uh like
a wholesale claim like that because
it really depends on where you are
what resources do you have what natural
inputs do you have what is the legal
environment where you are
how strong are you are you an immobile
patient
all of these speak to what is going to
be best
for you and i think that's very humbling
and a good reminder
you know when when so many of us want to
judge folks for their growing style
online you don't know their whole big
picture so stop
so stop thinking that we know better
yeah it's again it goes back to defining
something
is right yeah even even if you never
intended to
to say that you're do someone else is
doing it wrong you did
by defining oh this is the best way to
do it no there's
everybody's situation and circumstances
are different and like you
so beautifully or eloquently put you
could be a patient in a wheelchair
you you could have no access to
core or pit moss or or nutrients
you know you may be forced to cover crop
just because you don't have anything
else
you don't have the money to go out and
and buy all these inputs
so you know there's there's a method for
everybody
or maybe i should say there's a madness
to the method of letting everybody grow
in a manner that they
are most comfortable or due to resources
and then encourage them and find find
ways to help them
um to better achieve the end goal of
growing uh you know some dank ass
cannabis
nice well said well let's go ahead and
go to our uh
second commercial break and when we come
back we will talk about
um corollary uh strategies for building
the aerobic nature in your soil
uh you are listening to shaping fire i
am your host shango lofts and our guest
this week is soil biologist
leighton morrison
[Music]
for 20 years humboldt seed company has
been family owned and providing reliable
high yielding seeds originating in
northern california
while the current trend is to slap one
super male into a line of hype strains
humboldt seed company continues to breed
with precision and care
by doing large sifts and back crosses to
emphasize the absolute best traits that
a line has to offer
this kind of breeding takes time talent
and space to work
no matter what kind of aroma you are
particularly into
humboldt seed will likely have something
you'll love if you love fruit
you can choose from banana mango apricot
papaya blueberry blood orange melon and
lemons across their various strains
they have all gas glue and classic sour
diesel lines as well
of course there are the heritage
california strains like og kush
jack hair and headband and their
award-winning blueberry muffin is one
that delights just about everybody's
palette
especially when concentrated humboldt
seed company is proud to bring to market
the infamous freak show cultivar 2
which has a great thc high but looks so
much like a fern that some folks can't
even identify it as cannabis
it's a plant that really needs to be
seen to be believed
if you're looking for well-balanced cbd
seeds humboldt seed company can turn you
on to cbd strains
that actually have flavor like the dill
and pepper terpenes of willie g's
lebanese land race
whether you are looking for regular
feminized or autoflowers
humboldt seed company has the gear to
make this your best growing cycle ever
visit humboldtseedcompany.com today to
check out their line of vigorous
genetics
download their catalog and find out
where you can pick them up
you can also check out their instagram
at the
humboldt seed company to check out their
gorgeous flowers
and the extraordinary freak show plant
humboldt seed company
let them know shango sent ya
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by farmers
is because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year
and we know these fungal networks are
essential because they are the nutrient
super highways that extend
far and wide in the substrate to feed
your plants
the trouble with growing in new living
soils or blended cocoa substrates
is that it takes most of the plant's
life just to create these mycelium
highways
dinomyco endomycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the other popular brand in the us
at 900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically
for cannabis cultivation dynomica is the
result of 30 years of research and
trials at the volcani agriculture
research institute in israel
it has also been vigorously trialled by
cannabis and food growers across the u.s
dynamico is now available at grow shops
and on amazon in the united states
i love using dynamico to both speed up
the growth of the mycelium networks in
the soil
but also as a biostimulant to make clone
cuttings more
virile you can see side by side showing
the comparative growth on their
instagram at dinomyco
if you demand reliable growing results
and appreciate the importance of an
active root zone in creating a thriving
plant i encourage you to check out
dinomyco.com
and use the store locator to find out
where you can get yours
that's d-y-n-o-m-y-c-o
dot com shaping fire listeners can get
10 percent off any size of dynamico
on amazon or dynamico.com by using the
discount code
shaping fire one word no cabs
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some zing
to tired soil
choose dinomyco to maximize your plant's
potential
dinomyco endomycorrhizal inoculant
[Music]
get your tickets now for the 2021
autoflower cup this weekend
august 6th 7th and 8th in little whip
washington just outside of seattle
if you are a regular listener of shaping
fire you've heard me motivate you to
grow some autoflowers and compete in the
cup
then i shared why i support the
autoflower community and
specifically this friends and family
event
all there is to say now is to come come
on out and have some great outdoor fun
and let's get high the autoflower cup is
an over 21 event presented by camp
ruderalis
there is something for everyone no
matter your interests
stunden glass hookah lounge pop-up
magical butter chocolate shop
waterfront marcus place with an array of
vendors there will be an
old school autoflower seed swap joint
rolling competition
cannabis cooking demos solventless
squishing demos
and late night documentary screenings of
fantastic fungi
chef sebastian carosi's award-winning
classics like elk chili
kobe beef kimchi dogs oyster po boys and
razor clam chowder
wild oyster harvesting mushroom foraging
s'mores around the campfires each night
dan jimmy of mandalorian presentations
psilocybin mushroom presentations
camping glamping rvs and airbnb
there are a few really swanky glamping
packages still available too
you can grab a four person glamping
package for only 1200 bucks
and a two person package for 8.50 and
the tents and furnishings are really
snazzy
i just posted a photo of one on shaping
fire's instagram if you want to check it
out
so check out camprootoralis.com for
event details
and follow the instagram at the
autoflower cup 2021
and i'll see you this weekend at the
autoflower cup
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and our guest this week is soil
biologist
leighton morrison so during the first
set we made sure we had a good
understanding of
what the nature of aerobic and anaerobic
environments
are their definitions how we should
consider them and some examples
during the second set we talked about
this this question of of of
putting an anaerobic ferments
into an aerobic environment and
we understood that the the key to this
is is putting the right kind of
of tea or ferment into
the soil at the right stage so so as
you're building your soil you're going
to be
changing the nature of of your root
drench as well
well here we are in set three we're
gonna talk about um
some other well we're gonna talk about
how to do that in a best practice but
also
we're gonna talk about some of the
strategies for building the aerobic
nature of your soil
so so leighton let's start with um
with with how to add or how to collect
these oxygen tolerant anaerobes um
and that we're going to put into our
into our substrate now you've already
plugged um
a fish brew which i'm excited to learn
more about but you know
we continually push to get off the
bottle here on shaping fire
and and also to decrease costs by
collecting this stuff on our own
properties if we can
so so teach us a little bit about
collecting these
facultative or um oxygen tolerant
anaerobes in ways
um that we can do a natural farming
style on our own parcels
sure sure but i just wanted to clear up
one thing real quick and that is
i plug fishbrew.com for a reason because
it is an inoculant
so as long as you're not letting your
pots completely dry out
or you know if you're in a tent i always
encourage people even though you're not
growing there in the summer
leave a house plants cover crops
something in there
periodically water it don't let it come
completely dry
if you do that then you're going to
maintain that rich diverse microbial
community
at are ready to go um so and again i i
plugged him not because i want you to
continuously use the product i just want
you to use it
uh you know once or twice to really get
that
boost because those organisms
are key to building those soil
aggregates
so let's talk about collecting our own
or uh wild crafting
so i already mentioned the kelp and one
piece of the puzzle i did not
mention is that when that kelp
had that white foam on the top of it
that was the key moment to use it it
wasn't to let that foam crash
which it would if you let it continue to
sit out there
it's going to get really nasty smelling
and that is completely anaerobic
so you're trying to catch it in the
middle
at a low oxygen so around four or five
parts per million and at that point when
you stick your
nose in there you're going to smell it
and it's going to be just funky like an
old musty closet or something
it's not going to smell horrible and
when you stick your hand in there
your hand is going to be covered with
biofilm
and that is the key to quickly turning
plant matter into the composting
process without going all thermophilic
thermophilic is when the biology heats
that pile
up to a point where it kills the weed
seeds um it basically kills the vast
majority of the biology off because it's
getting up to temperatures where
things just explode the cysts even even
the strongest of these organisms cis
can't handle temperatures at 160 degrees
so that's why it takes almost a year for
that compost to come back
to a point where you've got those
diverse organisms because it's happening
naturally
through uh transf uh transference from
air
and from the soil that that's underneath
the compost pile
so let's talk about inoculants so
another another thing you can do you
don't live
near the ocean is go to a healthy
pond or stream and
look for aquatic plants algae is a great
one
there's other plants and again you know
i i encourage you to
wildcraft responsibly and with respect
so if you're going to go pull up you
know
some aquatic plants don't rip them out
of the soil just
cut them take small amounts don't take
the entire plant
perhaps bring something in as a blessing
to
to gaia bring a little seedling in and
plant it right at the edge of where
you've done your collecting
you know do a kind act uh to the
environment
you know pick up trash on the way out
whatever whatever whatever
feed your soul um but that's
another method is to you know collect
those aquatic plants i'm going to give
steve
raisner a plug from
potentponics he came up with what he
calls his sponge tech
which is basically buy a clean natural
sponge
tie you know something to it that to
weight it down
and throw it out into this aquatic
environment and let those organisms
naturally uh colonize that clean sponge
i thought that was a really smart way of
you know collecting
these initial inoculants um so that's
that's one way to get these you know
what i want to call oxygen tolerant
anaerobes
um the other is is the the silt the the
mud at the edge of the
waterway you know there's all kinds of
riparian zones
a lot of them are polluted unfortunately
so you really have to do your homework
to seek out a place that you know is
like in natural farming
the least disturbed you can possibly
find within a reasonable amount of
um you know reasonable traveling
distance from where you are
or do this on vacation and ship at home
i mean there's
there's there's ways of doing it um
so that's that's one way uh another way
is to
take compost that you know you're uh
that's highly aerobic and that you're
really happy with
um and over wet it um you know start
pushing it toward the anaerobic
environment
and then maintain it and and watch it
now this is kind of like growing out
imo 3 it's very easy to screw up
so imo 3 you're basically adding all
these food sources
and then making sure it never hits the
temperature 120
and if it does you turn it and you have
to continuously do this
until you break the thermophilic
phase and it pushes into a mesophilic
um and that's where you're going to
really get that rapid
um protozoa uh and fungal growths
so and actually it's it's it's more
fungal in the imo 3. it's not really
protozoa until you get into im04
but i'm not going to hang on that too
long so again it's it's biomimicry it's
the understanding of
like where do these organisms live in
nature
and then either harvesting them there
or recreating that environment at home
let's uh let's uh let's tease some of
this apart so let's go back to the first
one where
you said like okay number one is collect
seaweed so that's great so if i if we
were to collect seaweed which i
am going to because i happen to live
near salt water
so i'm going to go down to the beach and
this is our time of year that we get
lots of
bull whip kelp that gets washed ashore
and so i take some bull whip kelp and
cut it up and put it into you know fill
up a half
of a five gallon bucket with it am i
going to then cover it with fresh water
or do i need to cover it with
salt water since that is where those
microbes are from um no you're just
going to use regular fresh water okay
and
you know i encourage you to leave you
know i don't even cut it up to be honest
with you i just throw it all in the
bucket and i
i let the sand be all over it i you know
if there's a root attached i leave that
in play um and then once i've done the
ferment
then i will chop it up and and blend it
into the compost as well
um but for the fermenting process i
don't even chop it up i mean you can
i don't see any reason why to not or two
because really what you're trying to
gain is those
transitional organisms as well as that
biofilm that's really going to help
to create the perfect environment for
this biology to really grow out
all right so so we've got the seaweed
we've got the fresh water
and um you know we learned from that
prior episode with joey berger that that
creating these ferments you need to
leave
these plants in a different for a
different amount of time
depending on how bulky they are and
seaweed's pretty damn bulky
how long would you let let this ferment
sit before you used it so i did
i've done three of them since i've been
here um
and generally speaking and again the sun
has been at different heights
so i think the the first one was
10 days the most recent one during
summer was
was seven days so it's really a key is
again you're looking for the white foam
and you may have to do this a couple of
times to get it right
you're looking for that foam production
and you're looking for that smell
to turn from like fresh kelp to this
funky like something that your nose goes
what the hell is that it does it doesn't
recognize it as bad it doesn't recognize
it
good it just it sends a warning to you
like i
don't recognize this i don't know what
this is
and when your nose tells you that then
you know it's right yeah because
you'll have that and you'll have the the
bubbles on the top and you're like yeah
i'm done
the foam right and so and so i would
assume that that is also the same
technique for
like the general aquatic plants right
usually probably freshwater plants
that are you know around your ponds or
vernal ponds or whatever where you live
you'll go and and you'll put those in
and fresh water
put them in the sun for seven to ten
days and remove it when you
when you smell the beginning of funk and
you see some of the bubblization
but how what are you gonna do that with
uh silt and mud that seems to be a
pretty different substance
right that's the opposite so instead of
adding water you're adding air
remember how i told you to harvest your
silt
when you were building your pot right i
told you to let it dry out
yeah don't just spread it all out on a
big uh
so the exact same thing you're spreading
it out
to a point where it's a little bit
easier to work with
and it doesn't have that stink to it
because if i don't know about you but
i've
done plenty of hiking in and around
swamps and rivers and
you know you find those oxbows or where
you get an
eddy where the water actually swirls
backwards against the current along the
edge of the
banks and you step in that and you'll
sink to your knee and mud and you pull
your
foot out you're like oh man that's not a
rank yeah
right so you don't want that rank smell
but you want that funky like your nose
doesn't know what the hell this is
so you're doing the opposite of adding
water you're adding
air so you're spreading it out i don't
probably suggest using the sun because
you'd really have to be
on top of this to catch it at the right
point
but you want that silt to go from
squishy like you grab it it squishes
through your fingers
to the point where it actually starts to
clump up
now you've you've you've aerobically
stabilized that
anaerobic silt
and then and then am i going to
put it back in the water or that's it no
no it's done
and so and so my top dress with it top
dress with it blend it with your compost
um blend it with your aeration the
blending part
is probably pretty valuable because i
can imagine if you just
top dress with with it that it would be
tempted to shift back to anaerobic as it
gets
soppy wet again well no i would i would
recommend taking a um
uh like a a little bit coarser than a
window screen yeah and making a little
screen box and then taking that clump
and just screening it so you're breaking
it all apart
into little pieces right over the top of
whatever your top dressing or
screen it into a bucket outside and
bring it in and then just you know
throw it on with your hand but no it
won't it when you when you've micronized
it
um it's kind of like saying well i made
you know
flour meal or oyster meal it's going to
go back to a shell
no it's never going to go back to that
original state it's
it's permanently broken up it's
permanently destabilized or micronized
all right and then um and then the other
variety you suggested was to
take if i understand it um uh
aerobic compost and then
try to add a bunch of water to it and
then squeeze it out
no just push it push it toward anaerobic
so i'm sure
most of the audience has come in contact
with stinky compost
so the reason it's stinky is because
it's anaerobic
or low oxygen so again
you can in all of these examples it's so
easy to screw them up it's not funny so
you really have to
learn the craft don't expect to be a one
in
master you're really you're looking for
certain things
you're using your common sense and
intelligence to understand that
no i don't want to put a huge clump of
stinky mud on top of my plant
or no i don't want to let this ferment
to a certain point that it becomes a
stinky nasty
smelling thing i'm trying to catch it at
just the right time
where it's in transition and it's going
to help me transition my soil
so in the case of a super soil or a
soilless medium
that that kelp ferment or that aquatic
plant ferment
you're going to know because it's slimy
it's like
you feel it's like gelatin it's almost
like uh
aloe when you put that squish that stuff
out on you
that's the biofilm that's going to
create the environment
to for the rest of the biology to
explode
so again this is this is a delicate
process
and your the chances of screwing it up
are far greater than getting it right
especially the first time
so you need patience and and again if
the more you monitor it the more you
love it
and pay attention to it the better your
chances of a success will be
so again you're trying to push this nice
aerobic
fluffy compost toward an
anaerobic environment and you know if
you want to do it
mathematically that's that's probably
the best way to learn how to do it so
that you can repeat it
so add a cup of water into this aerobic
compost that's in a compost bin a five
gallon bucket
and watch what happens and then add
another cup and then add another cup
until the point where you turn it stinky
and then rewind to the point where
you've added four cups
not five mm-hmm uh and then repeat it
so once once you've got once you've
added the right number of cups of water
and it has just started to turn where
you're going like ah there is the
telltale funk of transition
that's what i want to capture are we
going to put that through a screen and
make small morsels of it like we did
with the other side
i think that would be i think that would
be probably the smartest approach and
again
you know if you're starting with an
unscreened compost
i would recommend you screen it so it's
at least easier to
break like maybe you screen it first
right
right whenever possible screen at first
so you don't have to try to do it when
it's wet
right with all these clumps sticking
together yeah so you know start with the
screen compost and then
after you get to that point re-screen it
with the same screen now you've now
you've broken it apart again
all right awesome all right so those
were
uh one two three those are four
different varieties
of collecting um oxygen tolerant
anaerobes
um facultative anaerobes
and the other way too you're getting
arabs that are low oxygen tolerant as
well so you're getting both
both both teams that play in the
middle environment and do well on the
other end of the spectrum
but they come together and play in the
middle so let's let's finish off with
any other strategies that you may have
for
increasing the aerobic nature of soil
right i mean the whole point of this is
that
we're moving our soil from anaerobic
environment
to being less aerobic and being
um excuse me we're moving it from being
less anaerobic to more aerobic
by adding new microbes and bacteria that
play around in the middle area
what else can we do to build the aerobic
nature of the soil to help this
this aggregation process on okay so
this would be do this would be field
soils because obviously
soils medium is going to be already
completely aerobic
because it's got so much pore space so
we're in a field condition
um and we have highly compacted soil say
we just bought a farmstead
and we're growing our six plants or
whatever and it was old farmland
or ag land or or just you know well-used
lawn or or whatever
i would say that the the easiest
but the thing that takes the longest is
a series of cover crop rotations
so something like a jackhammer radish i
think they call them daikon
radishes are wonderful for breaking up
compaction
i've actually seen stuff that was so
compacted that the
the radish actually pushed itself out of
the soil
which is you know pretty unusual
but it was a highly compacted clay soil
so it is understandable
but by using root crops
and crops that have known deep tap roots
there's there's a number of
i don't like to call them weeds because
i don't believe they are
i think they're what we call
successionary plants that they're
basically
providing or building the soil for the
next succession of plants to come in
by pulling out certain minerals that are
deficient in the soil
bringing them up to the surface and then
dying as a plant
and releasing them on the surface so the
next plant the next succession can come
in
but that takes time humans humans you
know we have
a hundred years uh mother earth thinks
you know
100 years nanosecond so
we want to do this and have it right now
so when you're in a situation where you
don't even have the opportunity to cover
crop for a year
which in all honesty personally i'd like
to see people build soil
for three years to really get that
to the point where you can just take
your whole hand and just stuff it down
into your elbow
without any resistance whatsoever that's
beautifully aerobic soil that will send
cannabis plant roots
flying through this through the matrix
but that's
takes time um and perhaps amendments
like you know tilling in compost
so your strategy is is is
dependent on your again resources and
the time
that you have allotted so in in the
situation where i have a highly
compacted soil
and i want to grow cannabis plants this
year
in this spot i would say all right so
what you want to do
is get yourself some really good compost
and you're going to do mound culture
kind of like hugel culture but basically
you're just going to build a
half of the horizontal soil system right
on top of the soil
that way you'll get your fast rooting if
your seeds your tap will have the
ability to push down into the
existing profile i would highly
recommend that you do
a soil chemistry test and a saturated
paste test
because a lot of these imbalances
cause compaction go figure right so by
adding some of these
required micronutrients and or
macronutrients
you are going to naturally put into play
the soil chemistry
this is probably the most important
thing i can teach anybody
you need to look at soil in three
different lights
and and where those three circles come
together is
the sweet spot number one physical
sand silk clay and organic matter what
are the relations what are the
proportions
really important second soil chemistry
without the right chemistry you're going
to have all kinds of other battles you
have to fight
and finally biology all three are
equally important
and again where the three rings come
together that's the sweet spot where you
want to be
so now that we've got a a fast growing
kind of soilless medium on the surface
we have
our you know natural drainage and our
sand salt clay below that
we've put our chemistry into play now
it's a matter of putting the biology
into play so a good inoculant whether
it's
your own compost extract as long as you
know that you have good organisms
i've traveled the country a number of
times worked with men
women i've been baking compost 50 years
i know what i'm doing i have the best
compost i put it under the microscope
i'm like yeah you've got great compost
it just doesn't have any biology in it
it's a great nutrient source and that's
you know that's another thing that
awareness for compost and and taking
that word and breaking it apart
what is compost not all composts are
created the same
i can take ground up organic matter and
call it compost
i can take biodynamic mayonnaise and
although the texture of both of them are
opposite ends of the spectrum
right so we really need to define that
word a little bit better
but anyway so back to the point now now
i have this
you know super soil soilless medium on
the surface for fast rooting growth
i'm going to put the biology in play
yeah the biology is probably going to
wash through
a lot of that that top matrix but it
will establish itself
as soon as it gets into that zone
between the two
of what you piled on top and the
existing soil and then it's going to
start building soil structure
and then i would cover crop all the way
around the outside of this
raised bed uh or mound culture
so that those roots from the plants that
i planted in the indigenous soil start
to push
in underneath that pile and co-mingle
with my cannabis plants
again the more plants you can put into
the soil
into play the faster you can build
aggregation
aggregation is is a key or
is is a direct result of glues
and i'm glad that we you asked me that
question because
one of the things i did not cover was
other types of natural glues so sap
robes
are past known as saprophytic which we
can't call them anymore because
phytic means plant and fungi's are not
plants they're fungi
so saprobes excrete a
glue called glomulin and it again is an
incredibly strong glue for bonding
soil particulates and silt and clay and
organic matter together
so the fastest way to get aggregation
is to have a high level of biology
especially if you're using like this you
know medium
oxygen environment biofilms
and you know increased the bacteria
make sure you do an inoculant of
protozoa which is
what's coming from fish brew and
again you want to get a really good
fungal
presence and that's why you know elaine
dr elaine ingham speaks so much about
the fungal
f to b ratio is because you're missing
50 percent of the entire soil kingdom
if you do not have mycorrhizae and
saprophytes
or saprobes doing the work for you by
excreting
uh acids and building glues and pushing
nutrients and cycling all over the place
i mean the new work coming out on
mycorrhizae
insane there are relationships of
bacteria that move
in and out through the wall
of the hyphy internally into the fungi
to perform processes and
also move back out and travel down it
there's some incredible new
videos showing uh with some incredible
new microscopy
techniques showing just colonies of
bacteria
moving up and down the channels of the
hyphy as if it was a super highway
and they're not all going in one
direction they're they're going at each
other from both directions and moving
around
each other it's crazy so if you do not
have these
these organisms in play you're losing
50 of the potential uh
of of you know plant genetics
and again if you're going to use
mycorrhizae
and you're going to use it in pots you
gotta have plants growing non-stop in
that or that
mycorrhizae is gonna die and if you use
any soft
rock phosphate you're gonna disassociate
that plant with the mycorrhizae and the
mycorrhizae is gonna die
and remember it takes 90 days for full
colonization so that means
from the root to the source of sand silt
and clay to mine
so again if you have a super soil and
you do not have sand silt and clay
don't waste your money on mycorrhizae
inoculants you're just throwing your
money out the window
but those guys are what is going to
speed up that aggregation process
and in the case of a mound culture in
the fall you want to plant it with a
winter wheat you want to plant it with
something
that's going to continuously
feed your biological kingdoms
throughout the course of the winter or
until they go dormant now
if it freezes and it goes dormant that's
fine everything is going to be in play
in spring
just like it is in nature so you know
those are the those are the key ways to
to build
um soil in a un ideal
dirtish environment right on that's
great you know that um
the the mound style um
is actually what you taught during the
water and watering episode
and tip for me to get over my
hydrophilic
soil right because the this is
hydrophobic
yes hydrophobic you got it um the hydro
the the soil top had gotten the point
where when i poured my water on it it
just like
slid right off like it was on the um the
hood of a car
it just slid off to the side and then
down the side of the pot
and during that episode you're all like
heck you know cover
cover all of that with compost and make
sure it doesn't dry out just keep it
nice and moist and
you know maybe it took two weeks for the
constant
interaction and of all that the compost
and the moisture
and the microbes the bacteria in the
compost
it just like woke up all of the assisted
biology in my bio
hydrophobic soil and and it just like
melted away
and i can see how if you had a pile of
that
um and they were you know they were
placed nearby each other
on acreage how it would have that same
effect you're
you're essentially softening up parts
of its protective you know
sheath and incurred coaxing some of the
life to come back
and wake up again um until that it can
then spread itself
spot on and remember like any time water
moves horizontally and laterally it's
eroding
and you do not want that and that's you
know that's the biggest problem we have
as a
as a species right now is is the loss of
soil through transportation all
80 of all the soils on this planet came
from transportation so that's wind or
water
and to have bare soil i mean i live out
here in oxnard and every time the wind
picks up you get dust devils and
everything is caked with dust all the
time
because these guys are just constantly
plowing and rotating and they're never
cover cropping
um and they don't give the soil a chance
to to heal itself
they just pound it with more friggin mpk
[Music]
and that's a result of you know that's
why the salt the soil is just blowing
away and they're down into subsoil now
i mean lucky for them that the the soil
that they have here is this amazing clay
sand clay silt relationship it's really
silty clay sand and
the nutritional value of it is insane
the problem is
that again we have very dry environment
and it's windy
and they don't they don't
i shouldn't say they don't have the best
practices they have
the practices that they utilize
because they're producing so much food
all the time
and you know that's the necessary of
what i want to call manufacturing
farming
where you just constantly put in another
row another another round of plants
another round of plants another round of
plants
you just never get a chance to stabilize
and build aggregation
but you're spot on i mean you could put
uh
this mound um out in the middle of your
backyard
and you'll see i mean it's gonna it's
gonna soften the soil probably within
five six eight feet of that pile once it
gets going
and that's why i said you know plant
plant all the way around it because that
too is gonna help
to soften even further out and deeper
down as those roots penetrate
and and build rhizosphere and and
introduce all those microbes
into that soil matrix they'll start
building aggregates i mean they're
they're
hardworking little guys fantastic
well we have reached the end of our time
leighton thank you so much for
sharing your insight as usual you know
as you know i love coming to you
as a soil scientist because not only do
you have
the hard earned data
and science to break down but also
um you know you're uh you're a
rambunctious storyteller so
so you're you're a lot of fun to hang
with too so my pleasure
django it's always a pleasure to hang
out with you right now we'll so we'll
see you next time
so if you want to follow uh leighton
and the new things that he is learning
the best place to do that is by
following his instagram
where he's pretty active and that's at
kingdom
aquaponics llc
um he also has got a website at the same
address
kingdom aquaponics llc
and if this is the first time that you
have uh heard leighton i
strongly encourage you to go back and
listen to
the other shaping fire episodes where he
has been my guest
of episode number 54 on geology and
biomimicry and that's the episode
where we talk about the um the layering
technique of creating substrate for
containers
and pots and raised beds and and then
also shaping fire episode 59 on water
and watering
explaining how water moves itself around
the rhizosphere
and how to determine how much water is
enough
when watering your plants you can find
more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast and subscribe to the show at
shapingfire.com and wherever you get
your podcasts
if you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download
your review will help others find the
show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
exclusive videos and giveaways
on the shaping fire website you will
also find transcripts of today's podcast
as well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast
that's at shaping fire and at shango
lose on instagram
be sure to check out shaping fire
youtube channel for exclusive interviews
farm tours and cannabis lectures does
your company want to reach our national
audience of cannabis enthusiasts
email hotspot shippingfire.com to find
out how
thanks for listening to shaping fire
i've been your host shango los
you