[Music]
you and I have spent so much time and
effort defending cannabis from pretty
much everybody first we had to explain
to people cannabis was medicine and not
an addictive drug and then we had to
illustrate that Stoners were not
necessarily lazy or unmotivated we have
vision and take action we had to prove
to our politicians that it somehow would
benefit them just to even get it
normalized and now with all the state
laws favoring indoor cultivation we have
to consider the very real issue that
cannabis cultivated indoors might be bad
for our environment electrical grid
stability the Cannabis economy and the
Cannabis Community as well ouch that is
just not something I want to think about
if you're listening to this episode you
are already a good person in my book I
imagine lots of folks might skip this
shaping Fire episode simply because they
don't want to think about how much
energy cannabis
consumes but being in cannabis
Enthusiast means looking at everything
to do with our favorite plant and having
the backbone to know when decreasing our
carbon footprint emissions and
fertilizer runoff is a very important
consideration yes we will mostly be
talking about indoor cultivated cannabis
today but outdoor and green houses have
some energy aspects to consider too
whether you are an environmentalist an
outdoor cultivator an indoor cultivator
looking to decrease your bills or
looking to make a case to start growing
Outdoors this episode is for
you if you want to learn about cannabis
Health cultivation and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we're giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter so go to shaping fire.com to
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings if you like
what we do and want to put something in
the tip jar you can venmo at Shango
Los you are listening to shaping fire
and I am your host Shango Los welcome to
episode
120 my guest today is Dr Evan Mills Evan
has an exceptionally prestigious resume
and you can read it fully on his website
here are some
highlights Dr Evan Mills is a retired
senior scientist at Lawrence Berkeley
National Laboratory one of the world's
leading research centers on energy and
environment he continues his
collaborations with the lab as an
affiliate and is also a research
affiliate with the energy and Resources
Group at UC
Berkeley he consults widely for Private
Industry and the public sector he has
published 372 articles and reports
including contributions to 17 books and
has spoken in 21 countries in 2007 Evan
shared a Nobel Peace Prize as a member
of the United Nations intergovernmental
panel on climate change Evan has worked
as an energy and environmental systems
analyst on projects ranging from local
to Global scales in the mid 1980s he
studied and taught about green buildings
before the term was in Vogue he received
a master's of Science degree in 1987
from UC Berkeley's energy and Resources
Group and a PhD in 1991 from the
Department environmental and Energy
System studies at London University in
Sweden while in Sweden he worked closely
with the Swedish state power board and
the Swedish national board for
industrial and Technical development on
National energy planning projects his
Specialties are Energy Efficiency in
buildings and Industry and the
intersection of energy technology global
climate and risk management Evan
frequently writes for popular and trade
Publications including Forbes the LA
Times slate Salon technology review and
the Washington Post and his work has
been covered pretty pretty much
everywhere including the Atlantic
Bloomberg The Economist the financial
times High Times National Geographic
nature Popular Science Rolling Stone
Scientific American and wired Evan now
lives in the Redwoods on the Northern
California coast and is an organic
vegetable Gardener and as a novel side
note when Evan was a kid he attended the
Halloween parties that chichin Chong
through for their kids in 1970s Los
Angeles today we will be discussing the
ways that cannabis cultivation uses
energy and the places you can save money
by changing to energy efficient
Alternatives during the first set we
will talk about the overall size of the
energy footprint of us cannabis
cultivation and then dive into lights
HVAC and other big ticket energy users
during the second set we dig into drying
Transportation packaging and Retail
along with a bunch of other sleeper ways
that we waste energy cultivating and we
finished the episode looking at cannabis
delivery and energy efficient cultivars
along with the market and political bias
in favor of indoor cultivation and the
possible impacts that interstate
commerce and National legalization might
have on cannabis energy use welcome to
shaping fire Evan hey good to be here
thank you awesome so Evan like let's
let's let's repeat what I've already
said in the introduction once since you
work have worked for with so many
Heavies that that that you are here on
your own capacity as a consultant and
that um this work and your opinions
today do not necessarily reflect those
of the companies or institutions with
which you have worked for and you are
here talking just for
yourself yeah that's fine thank you
excellent so you know it's fun to be
chatting with you um your your name has
been on my lips for for like almost a
decade right um Dr Dominic Cora turned
me onto your work in like 2014 or 15 or
so and uh I've been repeating it and
watching it um and and watching for more
ever since so then last week when I saw
your paper come out it was like it was
like a long missed returning friend Evan
even though I don't know you and so um
it was nice to uh connect with you via
email and uh I really appreciate you
being here today so thank you oh my
pleasure Dominic put together a great
book A couple of years ago with you know
30 or so chapters from different experts
all around the Cannabis industry all
kinds of issues and we had the pleasure
of contributing a chapter to that as
well and I have read it it it was
excellent and and then when uh when
Dominic put it out he was actually on
shaping fur and we talked about that at
the time and I bet you your name came up
during that episode as well so um so but
we are here today because you have
recently updated your work um you have a
newly published paper in one Earth
called Energy intensive indoor
cultivation drives cannabis industry's
expanding carbon footprint which pretty
much uh like the sauce is in the title
right we know exactly where we're coming
from and so today I was I wanted I to
invite you on the show so that we can
tease out um all of the places or or at
least many of the places where cannabis
companies can reduce their energy
usage and um and and and reduce their
carbon footprint now there there's no
question you know reading your paper
that you're making the pace for outdoor
cannabis of which we are huge proponents
for here on shaping fire um we also
recognize that many of the companies
have got themselves into the indoor side
um financially and they might not be
able to transition out right away and so
so maybe in the interim we can at least
start with um uh Electrical uh being
used less often and and start moving us
all the industry as a whole in the right
direction yeah I appreciate the the
vantage point and you know I'd say for
uh for me in particular you know my home
field my work is around uh Energy
Management energy analysis Energy
Efficiency and where I started here on
this spectrum you know almost 15 years
ago was uh you know let's raise Energy
Efficiency and indoor cultivation and
and we can achieve whatever we need to
by doing that and over time I found how
uh virtually impossible that is to
really get to a zero net carbon so I I
didn't start with the assumption that
outdoor was the only really tenable you
know Direction I I came to that very
slowly because it it again uh my my
hammer is Energy Efficiency and all my
Solutions all my nails are Energy
Efficiency usually you know in the world
but this is a very different kind of uh
very interesting Rich uh you know
sandbox here where there are a lot more
options the other thing just to to uh
footnote is that we uh it's important to
talk about energy as distinct from
electricity it's it's not often the case
certainly not always the case that a
given grow uh outdoor or indoor is all
electric there's fossil fuel used in a
myriad of ways that doesn't mean in
every single grow but like in my study
where I'm looking at the whole life
cycle uh not just the cultivation phase
uh half of the total energy nationally
at the end of the day is fossil fuel
directly not even including the fossil
fuel going into the electricity
production itself uh so uh it's
important to think in terms of uh think
think widely and look widely at at where
energy in all its forms might be used
excellent thank you for pointing that
out because I I definitely used the word
Electrical uh earlier and and and
honestly I will probably slip and use it
again so I I appreciate you uh using
that Clarity and and I apologize for
when I I miss it again it's fine it's a
it's a common thing and and you know
maybe another thing just to layer in
here and we can come back to it later if
you want is that you know while that
like you said the title of the paper uh
you know Flags or signals one of the
main findings it is nuanced wording and
that uh on the one hand outdoor is not
intrinsically uh the solution or fully
sustainable and indoor you know
similarly there's a big spectrum of
emissions and things you might get so uh
there can be plenty of problems around
energy and sustainability more broadly
with outdoor so it's not simply a matter
of flicking a switch and uh going to uh
especially the current industrial scale
Paradigm of of outdoor it's more than
that would would be needed to really
address uh climate you know let alone
all the other environmental things that
we're aware of I was really surprised in
the new paper of all the places that you
illustrate where uh energy is being used
intensely and and is a is a place that
we can either decrease our energy use or
or get rid of it completely by replacing
it um I actually find more interest in
that than even in the lights but but
let's go ahead and start with that
because everybody pretty much considers
that to be the elephant in the room is
is that when we when we bring the plants
indoors we have to create a man-made sun
and and we do that by throwing Lots of
jewels at them and um um in in instead
of me uh trying to tease out the
specifics I know that you have answered
this question many times so I'm just
going to kind of hand you the mic and
ask you to describe the problem with
using so many so much energy in cannabis
indoor
cultivation sure and and we can start
with lights cuz that's where you wanted
to start and and I agree it's where
every one goes and some people okay say
on the lay person end of the spectrum
thinks that's the only en energy use
which is a fine you know mistake or
whatever for general public but uh it's
big lighting is Big we're talking I mean
of course there are different lots of
different growing contexts there's a
spectrum so you can have the the plant
Factory that's windowless and all the
lumens all the photons are electric you
can of course have uh I hate the term
mix lighting cuz it's like jargon and
you know Regulators use it but let's
call them green houses and green houses
can be also no electric photons or they
can have some electric photons and most
industrial uh cannabis green houses do
use electric lighting uh but anyway
lighting is uh you know Loosely like a
third of the total energy use total
carbon footprint it totally depends you
know where you are and and what uh
genetics you have and uh what what the
facilities like but you know lighting is
Big um and whether it's LED or hid or
some or uh something else uh metal
halight it's uh it's still a lot of
energy you know and uh people look at
the Led as this Panacea and it's rolled
out uh reflexively all the time in
conversations and I'm a big fan of LED
my house is all LED you know it's what's
not to like no Mercury you know Energy
savings but uh remember that to replace
let's call it 1,000 watt HID light it's
that's a 600 watt LED it's still like a
small floor heater under your desk it's
incredibly energy intensive and you put
you know few thousand of those in a big
greenhouse and you need a lot of air
conditioning to deal just with the heat
off the LEDs so yes it saves energy uh
but it only moves the needle so much and
it's only addressing a third of the
energy use and yes you may get some
cooling savings you may also get some
increased heating energy need uh so it's
you know it's a system we always think
about buildings as systems whether it's
a you know a school or an office or a
cannabis grow their leg bones connected
to the hipbone and lighting affects
Cooling and and you know um all the uses
are are connected in important ways uh
so I I don't know I hope that that's
helpful as far as lighting can talk more
about it there's it is I've got a
followup for you so so when we go to
conventions the lighting manufacturers
um are continuing to impress us with or
or seeking to impress us with um their
uh increase energy conservation and
things are getting better and and every
new model is is going to to use less
energy and and save the cultivator um uh
pocket money which is great um do you
see um uh exploratory science in
cultivation lights that is forthcoming
that's actually going to be helpful
because I get what you're saying right
now about Led is yes yes it's better
than metal Halli but really it's not
moving the needle that much and and if
if I wanted to keep my LEDs and wanted
to keep running indoor my first response
would be well the technology is almost
there and and it's about to be better
and so we just need to put our energy
into LED research instead of trying to
move us Outdoors
yeah this is a broader you know just
kind of conceptual problem or challenge
or opportunity depending how you want to
look at it in energy management at large
there there's never a silver bullet I
mean Data Center
cement factory cannabis grow house I
it's it's a Orchestra you know of of
measures that you need and want and are
prudent to pursue for all kinds of
reasons so there's never one thing
that's going to solve a problem there
really isn't uh even you know you look
at a car like an electric car well
there's you know 30 different Energy
Efficiency measures going on within that
that car so there's always a
constellation of things um with lighting
uh Ju Just to foot note a little bit
what we were saying a minute ago it's
also you know it's very uh I don't like
the word strain I know everybody uses it
but it's not actually the word that's
used in Agronomy you know more broadly
their their their crops you know or
their cultivars U cultivars uh there's
interest they're interesting papers not
enough of them uh but I in my paper
figure five brings the data together
from one of the studies and they looked
at uh uh multiple strains under LED
versus HID lighting and it's sobering to
see
uh that some of them don't save any
energy or much very little energy and
others Save A Lot and so there's like a
factor of strain and genetics and
cultivar in the lighting performance
also there's a problem again more
broadly in energy called the takeback
effect that uh actually gets kind of
embraced by uh climate deniers and so on
a lot by saying that well if we save
energy in one place we're just going to
use more somewhere else and I'm not that
person I don't subscribe to that and the
evidence doesn't support that but you do
see a lot of places where cannabis grows
and you'll you know in the trade
literature you'll see the advertisements
from the lighting manufactures brighter
than the sun not just as bright as and
people will increase the the DLI and
increase their yields and so we have to
think about energy per unit yield rather
than energy per square foot and so on
but it is often happening that people
because they're saving so much money on
lighting energy bills that they will
pump more light in and so that's not the
expected you know Behavior with Energy
Efficiency and so one has to look
carefully at how much energyy is being
saved and how you're measuring you know
those savings um so it's just a little
bit more in light uh you can steer me
back around if I if I uh didn't actually
answer your question that's a good
answer so my follow-up question now I
recognize that um that you are here to
raise the flag of using too much energy
and it isn't necessarily also your
mandate to solve them all and to solve
the policy questions behind them as well
so so with that in mind I'm still going
to ask you a Solutions policy question
um just because you have had this
conversation with many people and
perhaps you have heard something but um
you know you're you're not you know
you're you're you're a friend of
cannabis and and um you're aware of the
indoor outdoor cannabis debate about
quality and um you know I and generally
the guests on this show love you know we
stand with sungrown flower as as having
a wider um Aroma profile and uh
healthier plants and you know more
resilient higher yields all all of this
kind of business but there is something
um that is quite special and unique
about a flower that is grown indoors
it's aesthetic value and also to get um
outdoor cannabis that competes with the
quality of indoor um there are only a
handful of places in the country that
can do that naturally and and and so a
lot of people just aren't interested in
this uh discussion at all because they
want to grow the best cannabis in their
region and they don't live in
Garberville right and so um and so
people say hey I'm I'm going to turn to
my indoor do you have any idea of how we
can resolve the the people wanting to
grow good cannabis in places where the
weather is not Northern California yeah
great question it's so important and
some of the answers are counterintuitive
I think and I don't pretend to have all
the answers but it's it's such an
important line of conversation and and
uh if you you probably have already but
if not uh you know I think a whole show
on really drilling into the quality
question is important I'm I'm uh you
know there's a lot to it right what
defines quality there's you know the
visual there's the aromatic there's the
medical effect there's the uh
inebriation effect you there's so many
vectors of quality they're all
legitimate I mean they're all things
people are seeking just like a good wine
uh but there is debate there for sure I
mean there's a lot of and including in
the science literature looking at CBD
profiles uh that you know outdoor is not
necessarily inferior at all by you know
many metrics and and when you look at
and I'm not saying it's Superior either
I'm just saying one can't just have like
a blanket uh concession you know that
indoor is superior uh and certainly when
it comes to potency I mean that itself
is a whole hour right and you know is
35% higher quality than 25% you know is
is that really how we look at this uh
and obviously when you're making oil
then that's not or any kind of extract
right that that's not even the thing
anymore so higher potency to me is one
of the weaker arguments you know
certainly uh U Aesthetics are there um
going back to what we were saying a few
minutes ago you know there is this
spectrum of growing environments and you
have people like you know Jeremy mberg
out out there in the Eastern east of
Washington growing in you know I don't
know the right word hoop houses or
whatnot getting you know extraordinarily
beautiful I think you know award-winning
cosmetically flowers and and I'm sure
many other you know people around and
like you said some people uh are very
successful but it is an art it is not as
easy as most people think uh but I think
you know that's doable and um I think
also there is the baked an assumption
you know in what you're saying which is
fair that everyone wants to be able to
grow it everywhere does everyone grow
pineapples everywhere does everyone grow
cranberries everywhere does everyone
grow kiwis everywhere does every
everyone grow you know corn everywhere I
mean I live on the mesino coast I can't
grow freaking corn I'm not going to
build a greenhouse to grow corn you know
you can't really succeed at that anyway
so there is there is a kind of swimming
against the tide there I did one of the
many little calculations in the paper
was uh how much land area would it take
to grow all of the Cannabis you know
24,000 tons roughly of cannabus that
Americans consume every year in the US
and the answer is
0.003% % 3,000 of 1% of all us Farmland
so you know we could clearly grow all
the Cannabis that Americans want and it
could all be uh you know in almost you
know the ideal climate I'm not saying
that's happening tomorrow you know
that's a whole hour about interstate
commerce and pros and cons of that and
so on but uh there is a kind of an
implicit you know requirement that it be
grown everywhere uh and that said um I
don't know I mean there is outdoor
cultivation in every State and I don't
you know Alaska you name it and I don't
know you know what the best producers in
each state look like but there is a lot
of room there um and I don't I'm not
aware that anyone has found like a
medical element that is only achievable
by indoor but maybe that's there and if
there's a need for medicine you know
these things are are all nuanced uh in
all spectrums and and if there's a
really a need that's demonstrated for
indoor uh for some particular reason you
know then that that should be looked at
and supported and then it goes to what
you were saying a minute ago so what do
we do here and how do we make that more
efficient because also you know it's
easy for me to say well in a perfect
world uh this cultivation more of this
cultivation would be outdoors than it is
now and and you know remember a lot of
cultivation not just at small you know
uh uh artisanal scales but at industrial
scales is outdoor already and I know
most of that's headed for oil but anyway
um there's which is a shame right like
it's it's really a shame that so much of
the outdoor is just air quotes just
headed for oil I mean o oil is Honorable
but but it's it's it's really amazing to
me that people um treat outdoor as such
a a a a mediocre commodity when when I
go down to California I'm only
interested in finding Northern
California regenerative outdoor to
purchase and they want to put all this
mass-produced indoor block on me and and
it's really surprising that that the
outdoor what I consider the higher
quality regenerative stuff is discounted
because people don't want it it
astonishes me how that market Dynamic
works yeah certainly you know one uh
participant in this whole ecosystem are
the bud tenders and their level of
literacy or interest in the relative
merits of the two in the carbon
footprint uh is you know small in almost
all cases and of course there's no
product labeling which is ironic right
there aren't many industries that have
as much product labeling the sense of
CBD profiles and THC and and and uh
differentiation on cultivars you know
you don't go to the market and and have
all the different uh you know uh types
of corn labeled by their cultivar uh or
you know there might be a little bit of
that so you know that's an issue I think
consumer awareness I mean we're getting
away from the technical into the human
and into the consumer level but you know
consumers are not aware you know that
one pre-roll emits you know 5,000 times
its weight in CO2 that one pre-roll is
like driving 65 miles in the best
plug-in hybrid that's out there that one
pre-roll is as much of a carbon
footprint as 300 cigarettes and um I
think things like that are you know
consumer awareness is important people
talk a lot about free markets and
markets functioning well and not needing
regulation well one of those assumptions
is that the consumers have perfect
information about everything and are
making decisions
with a full you know visibility of their
choices and so that's uh you know we're
we're straying from the quality issue I
guess it's still you know it's consumer
choice but there are a lot of attributes
and quality is one of them and you could
also argue that the environmental
footprint is an element of quality and a
given consumer could look at it that way
or they could not but without knowing
what it is have no choice to weigh it in
yeah and and you can't expect that they
all ever would like just like with
everything else I mean uh it's you know
consumers are not trying to optimize our
planet for environment um you asked uh
you know you asked a bit about you know
lighting and then going Beyond lighting
and and so let's say lighting is roughly
a third and your mileage may vary a lot
but uh you know there's heating there's
cooling uh dehumidification is huge you
know the plants are of course
transpiring and releasing a lot of
moisture and if you're growing
hydroponically uh there's a lot of water
coming out you know around on the plant
and that you know obviously creates a
big risk of of mold and and uh other
issues and so there's dehumidification
which is very energy intensive and then
you know moving air you know there can
be 30 40 50 60 air rotations in in an
indoor grow in in an hour you know by
for contrast a house has like one or two
or half of an air change per hour lot of
energy moving that air you're you're
irrigating you're have pumps you're uh
possibly treating that water you're
possibly heating that water or even
cooling that water depending what
climate you're in I bet down in coella
Valley they have cooler uh you know
water chillers that are chilling the
irrigation water and uh if you have your
own water supply you're pumping and uh
so just as far as energy uses and then
there's curing and then often there's
extraction on the site and then uh you
know there's a lot of cold storage now
in the industry there's you know vast
overproduction like vast p over
production in the industry it's more
well documented in Canada than here but
definitely happening here and so that
stuff is going into refrigerators and
freezers and I'm just saying like it's
it's back to the earlier Point there's
no Silver Bullet but all of these things
use energy and they all have Energy
Efficiency options you know they're all
manageable to a point and they should be
you know if they're used they should be
done as efficiently as possible and so
those are some of the ones that are in
my numbers there for people who are
concerned about oh Evans numbers are too
high
there's a heck of a lot of things I left
out because there were no good data you
know to include them and and there's a a
figure I think figure one in the paper
that kind of has this map of the the
whole kind of carbon uh system you know
around cannabis and which things I've
been able to quantify in which I haven't
but you know on there's you know in
energy there's you know managing your
carbon dioxide there's UV disinfection
these all things I couldn't include odor
removal uh not necessarily so much in
cannabis but you know in other indoor
egg which I'm also studying there's soil
steaming and cleaning soil to use again
there's recovering water out of your air
conditioning or your HVAC uh exhaust
stream uh in some climates there's snow
melting again that's more for other
crops but that really happens uh you've
got your infield farm equipment talking
about outdoor there's data people want
to use Ai and robots you know I mean
this industry is automating very rapidly
right again not at the small boutique
grower level but where most of the
cultivation happenings and and as we we
know you know AI uses a lot of energy
and and mechanization uses energy and
instead of human labor and you know the
list kind of goes on but just to say yes
there there is a lot of other energy use
besides lighting uh the good news is
that they all are manageable to one
degree or another in terms of of Energy
Efficiency I've got one more question
for you before we go to the first break
Evan and and that is you know you
mentioned early on um where moving from
traditional lights to LED lights is you
know it's it's good to move in the right
direction but it doesn't really move the
needle and um you know you guest gave us
a a healthy laundry list and and we'll
we'll we're going to dig into more of
those during the second set but um you
know you gave us a a laundry list of all
these other places that are uh energy
intensive in the indoor cultivation Zone
if I if we went and got the energy
efficient version of all of these the
the energy efficient you know water
cooler and the energy efficient um you
know lighting and the energy efficient
um you know Automation and if we just
went down the list and got them all yeah
would that move the needle or are we
just kidding ourselves it would but it
won't because it would but it won't yeah
because uh yes you can kind of uh play
God in the sense of specifying all this
stuff and then we haven't even talked
about solar yet and you know you could
make a zero energy grow
but the the obstacles to that the the
resistance in the market itself is
enormous I mean the the surveys the
market surveys done of The Growers say
they want about a three-year payback
time on any Capital Investments more
than half of them want a three-year
payback time or less so you can't even
though that's 33% of return on your
investment I wish I could get that in
the bank uh that's not going to get you
far at all there was a big study that
came out in Canada and there's been a
few that have tried to look you know we
call it kind of technoeconomic studies
you know how about this technology how
much does this cost how much to save
payback and they're getting numbers like
you know 10 to 20% Energy savings
potential in cannabis grows again you
can't just pick lighting right I mean
LED is hard enough to get it to pencil
but you know you have to look at all
these end uses and so you know while
there may be a technical potential for
let's just say 75% Energy savings which
is what I stipulated in 2012 in the
first paper um no one who is trying to
earn a profit you know who has investors
is going to ever be able to get anywhere
near that and so and then with solar the
problem is that the land use becomes
untenable uh I'm doing analysis now uh
it's looking like cannabis facilities
depending on climate and um location but
sorry climate and facility type and like
you said you know people want to grow in
harsh climates right because they want
to grow in their state or in their town
so it can be as bad or even worse than a
100 times the roof area in solar and you
know the best I've seen are like 20
times the roof area or maybe 10 times
the roof area and so all of a sudden
you're using more
land than you would be with outdoor
cultivation and and land sparing or land
savings is one of the top you know
arguments that are used for uh indoor
agriculture more more generally so there
are these kind of real world
inconvenient you know constraints around
it and meanwhile the industry is
opposing not opposing that's not fair
but you know like the California energy
commission was putting out uh public
comment requests for Energy Efficiency
standards on indoor grows and the
industry comes out of the woodwork with
all kinds of opposition to it you know
and and the uptake of LED is still
pretty low to be honest you know in the
market and so it's uh it's hard you know
it's got to be done willingly or ideally
it's done willingly and if it's not not
done willingly then The Regulators come
in and people don't want any more
regulation on cannabis but they won't do
it on their own enough you know uh so
it's it's rough uh and so I use the the
term uh optimizing the suboptimal yes
you can optimize these things you can do
better and and Lord knows people are I
mean I'm not here to criticize and say
the industry is not doing anything the
LED look their heat pumps are coming in
people are you know trying to use Ai and
things to optimize Water application
minimize water use and therefore pumping
energy so there efforts are being made
uh but it's just uh you're not getting
that far and uh so we're optimizing the
the suboptimal it's so much more elegant
technologically and economically to grow
outdoors uh if you can address the
quality issue and and still do that
sustainably because there's plenty of
inputs you know to outdoor cultivation
all right so hold on that because I'm
going to pick up on inputs in the second
set but but I I want you to follow up on
one thing before we go to commercial
which is uh earlier in the set I I said
okay if we if we do if we change
everything to the energy efficient
version will it move the needle and and
and and and it and is is the technology
in LED just not um up to the standard
yet and we're about to so we can just
research our way out of this I have this
same question about the solar panels
because um solar has always been one of
my things that will save indoors in my
head right um without being a solar nerd
just hoping hoping that to be the case
and um do we see technological
advances that are coming down the pipe
in research that might be able to
increase our efficiency so it wouldn't
take 20 to 30X the the roof space in
solar panels to feed a cultivation
Center or or are are are we not um
foreseeing that in any kind of immediate
future yeah I don't not in our lifetimes
and not not even in a longer time frame
not not sufficient at all I mean LED is
incredibly efficient yeah they're still
working on it I mean solar is incredibly
efficient the best panels are you know
there's been huge progress it'll
continue but it's not it's not of this
the magnitude that you need you know
you've got factors of 10 and factors of
100 improvements you need here I think
there other domain like strain see there
I go uh genetics cultivar uh huge
differences you know actually that
figure five in the paper shows just the
energy use for different cultivars and
that's an area where you might get 50%
savings or 50% increase you know
depending where you're moving between so
you know there there's also a broader
array of possible uh things to do rather
than changing One widget for another you
know in your growing process uh that
that's something to uh you know to to
look at excellent all right so let's go
ahead and take a short break and we'll
be right back you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is
energy and environmental systems analyst
Evan
Mills you've heard me talk about the
award-winning cannabis seeds that come
from the analytical breeding program of
Seth and Eric Crawford who founded
Oregon CBD seeds in fact Seth was a
guest on shaping fire in 2020 to talk
about triploid genetics Seth and Eric
are now releasing high THC seeds for
homeg Growers and Farms as grow the
revolution seeds at GTR seeds.com their
high THC seeds are extraordinary in that
they will start to flower at 16 1/2
hours of daylight instead of the typical
14 1/2 hours of daylight that means in
most regions your plants will start to
flower out doors in the middle of July
instead of the middle of August which
means these photo period plants finished
in September and not October totally
upending the photo period Seed Market
Seth and Eric took their prized early
flowering CBG line and bred it to some
of the most desired verified genetics
out there including Sour Diesel triangle
Kush wedding cake chem dog Skittles and
others these crosses all Express
powerful photo period tarpine profiles
and THC giving you a great High GTR
seeds has a new thcv line with plants
like double Durban and Gigantor that
boast one toone THC to thcv and people
want that
thcv GTR seeds are very consistent true
growing inbred f1s from stabilized
inbred parent lines these seeds are
nearly homogeneous and the plants should
all grow the same there is only one
phenotype in every pack available as
diploids and triploids sethan Eric's
company is still family-owned p employee
Centric and partially powered by their 2
Acres of solar panels everyone can
purchase these seeds and the entire
catalog of Oregon CBD seeds at GTR
seeds.com go to GTR seeds.com today and
choose something revolutionary for your
next indoor or outdoor
run revenue is tight for cannabis
businesses right now there is no
question about it and when Revenue
tightens businesses need to spend
Smarter on Advertising
instead of throwing obscene money at
Hanging your company's logo from the
rafters at your next convention perhaps
consider placing commercials on shaping
fire and if you are a very small
business there is simply no better bang
for your buck than commercials on
shaping fire especially if your products
are for regeneratively minded
cultivators advertising on this show
allows us time to talk about your
product service or brand in a way that
really lets people know what sets your
company apart from the others bold
people who own companies know that
getting into relationship with their
customers is essential that is what we
offer we will explain your service or
product what sets it apart as desirable
and help our audience get in contact
with you it's pretty simple really
advertising does not have to be all
whizbang smok and mirrors nowadays I
find that people prefer just to be
spoken to calmly accurately and with
good intentions if you want to make your
own commercial spot you can do that too
with a commercial on shaping fire you'll
reach your customers in the privacy of
their headphones right now and will
continue to reach new listeners as they
explore the shaping fire back catalog of
episodes again and again for years a
spot on shaping fire costs less than a
postcard per person and the shaping fire
audience is full of smart cannabis
enthusiasts cultivators and
entrepreneurs who are always curious to
learn and right now in the New Year We
are booking the few open spots we have
for the rest of 24 I'd love for you to
be one of our new advertisers do
yourself a solid and contact us today
for rates on podcast and Instagram
advertising email hotspot shaping
fire.com to find out
more this message is for folks who grow
cannabis I'm talking to Hom Growers
patients and Commercial Growers too I'm
probably talking to you when you plan
out your next growing cycle be sure to
check out humble CSI seeds at Humbolt
csi.com Caleb inspecta and his family
have lived in humbal county for over a
100 years for the last 40 years three
generations of his family have
cultivated extraordinary sensia cannabis
in Humble mesino and Trinity counties
because of his lineage and the
hard-earned experience that comes from
growing up smoking and sifting large
populations of cannabis plants in
Northern California the seeds you'll cop
from CSI will be winning genetics based
on longtime Heavy Hitters and updated
and rifted to bring out new and exotic
traits and better yields go ahead and
ask around Caleb also known as inspecta
and pirates of the Emerald Triangle is a
breeders breeder he reaches way back and
works with significant strains
recreating them in new and interesting
ways that you'll love as a toker and a
grower as well as offering you some
surprises that will Delight serious seed
Traders and cultivators humble CSI goes
a further step and selfs all these Cho
cars so you know all the seeds will be
female these are not experimental femin
seeds humbold CSI releases some of the
best female seeds available anywhere and
it will show in your garden folks grew
quite a bit of CSI humble Genex last
year here on Vashon Island and everyone
was pleased the patients had beautiful
female plants and didn't have to call
half of their Garden as males the folks
growing for the fun of getting high grew
colorful flowers with exceptional bag
appeal and great highs and breeders had
seven out of seven females in a pack
which gave them a lot of phenotypic
choices take a moment right now and
visit humbled csi.com you'll find an
up-to-date menu of both feminized and
regular lines along with photos and
descriptions that's humbl
csi.com
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I am your host Shango Los
and my guest today is energy and
environmental systems analyst Evan Mills
so at the end of last set we were
talking about the um all the different
places that energy usage can be tamped
down or stopped in an indoor cultivation
environment and um you know I have heard
people push back before Evan and say we
love cannabis it makes life livable why
are you harassing cannabis cultivation
when there are so many other things um
that we should be harping on and I I
know there's a logical fallacy there
because the F the fact that we should be
doing something about energy in a
different sector doesn't really say
anything about not doing it in our
sector except for the fact that we all
love cannabis right um but I've heard I
bet you've heard this quite a bit and
and what do you say when people push
back like
that yeah I I say that that it's and not
or you know we just like you there's 20
ways to save energy in a house there's
also 20 ways to save energy in an
economy or on a planet and we need you
know we need to reduce carbon dioxide
emissions by 90% or more on this planet
to save ourselves you know and you can't
do that with one thing you can't do that
just going after cars or steel making
you know it's just it's got to be it's
got to be taking every opportunity and
the you know the dirty secret is that
cannabis is actually benefiting from a
double standard you know it's it's
arguably one of the last Industries to
come to Energy Efficiency and
sustainable energy because you know by
virtue of the illicit Market history it
hasn't been uh exposed to or eligible
for you know energy tax credits or
energy education even or utility rebates
uh and the you know the stealthy nature
of it uh you know and the low
capitalization doesn't provide the money
to invest you know those days are gone
and you know in California where I live
excuse me in California where I live
it's uh you know it's been a quarter of
a century since we've had you know legal
medical and since cultivation been done
legally we've had a lot of time the
industry's had a lot of time to figure
out how to do this well so um I don't
know if that that helps but those are
those are some thoughts I think it also
matters in aggregate you know if this
was a tiny tiny amount of energy tiny
tiny then yeah okay why it shouldn't be
a priority I mean we've only got limited
time limited money but it's really
stunning how how big it is and how big
it's become in my since my 2012 study
the consumption of cannabis in the
United States has tripled so the
cultivation has tripled it's even more
than tripled for subtle reasons but the
so the the energy use now because I in
the paper you know I look at the per
square foot or per kilogram more
importantly you know energy use but I
also look at the macro the national
level and the carbon footprint now today
even including all these uses that I've
left out is equal to that of 6 million
homes 6 million average American Homes
10 million average American cars it's
more than than um crypto mining wow it's
four times I mean I was stn I had to
more than crypto mining because we're
all hearing about crypto mining uh
inputs and and and our cannabis is more
and and so it's part of that double
standard it it's gotten less attention
than it merits not more I would argue
and the other thing that was stunning is
that it's four times the energy use of
the pharmaceutical and Medicine
manufacturing
sector and so putting all other
commentary and things aside as a
medicine you you know that needs to be
owned you know that needs to be owned
it's four times the food and beverage
industry which manufacturing these are
National statistics from the US
Department of energy uh and that
includes beer and wine production food
and beverage and it's the same as this
one is stunning like it's the same as
all outdoor food crop
production how can that be wait all wa
whoa whoa it is equal to all of the food
crop production in the United States all
of it yeah that's an
absurd comparison because that's that's
outdoors I mean only 1% of the Cannabis
carbon footprint is due to outdoor
cannabis cultivation right so it's the
indoor I mean I'm doing my next papers
on indoor growing of cucumbers and
tomatoes and lettuce and all the other
food props there a problem too not
nearly as bad as cannabis but they're
you know hundreds of times more energy
than outdoor lettuce production outdoor
tomatoes and so on so it's just the
energy intensity is so extraordinary and
outdoor cultivation you know it uses
relatively little energy per acre I mean
you've got your tractors and your water
pumps and a lot of food doesn't require
you know drying or curing and you
there's lots of reasons why that is um
but cannabis is 300 times at least as
much energy as indoor lettuce is so it's
just a lot more energy intensive and you
know and then for the those are big like
abstract numbers I mean they're helpful
because they're in contact I think the
comparisons actually help more they do
so then the like to to thicken that
broth I also look at just to help this
be accessible you know or put in
perspective uh what about from the
consumer perspective I mentioned a
little bit before about cars and driving
here's another one if you look at the
know different tiers of consumers
obviously so you look at the daily or
near day user which is like I don't know
15 million people or something in the
states um their carbon footprint if they
consumed just indoor grown at average US
conditions outdoor grown it's a
different story they consumed indoor
grown their carbon footprint from their
cannabis consumption is half of the
carbon footprint of their entire home
meaning their fridge their cooking their
Heating and their Cooling in average US
conditions it's like three CrossCountry
road trips per year in in a plug-in
hybrid it's like 100% of their annual
food consumption so if you look at the
energy footprint in their other food
including meat eaters it's roughly on
par with the carbon footprint of their
food consumption and we're just talking
about you know a couple of grams few
grams whatever a day of of cannabis and
it's not much better if you're a healthy
uh uh healthy vegan or vegetarian but
it's you know the the difference is is
even greater um so it's just it matters
you know and and we can't we have to do
everything it's an all Hands-On deck
climate emergency you know and so we
just need to look at everything and it's
not you know blaming and making bad it's
you know more in the spirit of what you
were saying before how do we do better
what where are the inefficiencies and
where where can we be more um you know
have a a lower smaller footprint in in
this industry I want to Pivot uh a bit
until to to start talking about post
Harvest um because like you said we
could spend hours going through a
detailed checklist of all of the
different um parts of cultivation where
we could um uh strategize differently or
use different technology but um it's
it's arguably just as ugly after um the
flower has been dried and cured and is
on its way out the door too um one of
the things that you know I'm not it's
not like I'm the only one but but but
one my big pet peeves are Dube tubes and
the the idea that we're we're you know
creating all these Plastics and future
micr Plastics and and then if it's a
it's a if it's a really highend maybe a
a hash infused or something um uh
pre-roll or canar then then they're
adding extra stuff like they're they're
adding plastic based sticker and then
like some kind of like
um cool seal and and then maybe even a
box around the outside right abely and
and it's like there's only you know
there's only a gram or to a weed inside
that joint and there's all this
packaging to give it Vibe so that it
sells and um I I imagine that the
packaging is just ugly in the
numbers yeah there is a new paper I know
out about that in in particular and it's
you know I looked at the solid waist
streams I mean a lot of that is is just
plant residue but it's also you know
spent mineral wool and it's the plastics
for the cultivation and it was like I
think 15 times the weight of the flower
or something and just that Solid Waste
part uh you mentioned Vape cartridges
and the like and you know one thing
that's uh so sad there is that Vapes
have tiny lithium batteries in them and
they go to the landfill and lithium is
recyclable and reusable and we have a
crisis and a lot of the you know also
the uh people on the right you know like
to say that you know lithium is hurting
the environment and electric cars are
bad and so so on and the reality is we
can recover and reuse our lithium and
that radically reduces the environmental
footprint of lithium but we don't want
to be sending it into the landfills
there are actually landfill fires that
are starting now because of all the The
Vape concentrations and probably other
lithium batteries too but there if you
Google lithium fires landfill you'll
you'll find uh that that's happening
just saying and they're nice and evenly
distributed throughout the landfill
right yeah so it is a problem uh I think
you you missed a couple of important
ones I mean there there's all the solid
let's call it broadly solid waste and
what is the carbon footprint of that and
some of that's included in the paper and
there's certainly other literature you
know as a whole discipline of looking at
life cycle assessment uh but uh there's
a kind of a gray zone between
cultivation proper and putting it on the
truck and that's again like I mentioned
before Refrigeration curing and also uh
Downstream of that is extraction and
that is huge area that we know almost
nothing about be it just hasn't been
studied and written about I really tried
to bring that into the analysis and I
think it will be coming I I know some
people who are trying to do more
research on that now uh but I did do one
vignette that's in the supporting
appendix of my report you can get online
it's not in the National numbers because
I don't know on scale but I looked at
Super critical CO2 which was the one
extraction process I could find
information on and it was was stunning
um about uh the CO2 footprint from the
extraction process was about 50 times
the weight of the flour so 50 kg of CO2
to the atmosphere per kilogram of flour
going into the process and that um that
you know is about actually it's more
than that I'm sorry it's about 150 times
uh but it depends so if you look at like
what is that as a fraction of indoor
footprint it's like a 10% increase 10%
Adder to the footprint we are talking
about but if you look at outdoor it's
30% increase right because outdoor less
less carbon intensive those are
percentages but it is arguably an
outdoor grower can make a bigger
marginal footprint on their you know
impact impact on their footprint by
extraction and and we just don't know I
mean there's so many processes and we
don't know the the national magnitudes
but it's something that's just crying
out for uh being looked at it's not more
important than the things we're talking
about but again everything matters um so
I don't know if those are helpful kind
of conversations be you know to address
your your question I'm happy to keep
going yeah it is uh I I I would like us
to uh move a little bit further down the
chain um to um so what it's gr and it's
stored and it is extracted and it is
packaged all things that we've hit on so
far but let's let's pick it up from that
point so um uh at this point we're in
transportation so why don't you pick up
the storyline there yeah so it's it's
harder to look at Transportation because
again data you know one thing vexing
this whole process is there's no you
know as a result of national
criminalization and whatever else where
funding is there's there's not nearly as
good a data on cannabis industry as
there are on other Industries and and of
course part of that problem is also the
industry itself not sharing you know its
data but you know there there are
numbers out there and ways to look at it
and so I do look at that in the paper
and it's uh you know there's lots of
Transportation going on right through
the whole life cycle I mean there's
upfront transportation in the building
of the facility of course in the
delivery of all the inputs the
fertilizers the the Plastics the Clones
the whatever uh and then there's people
working and coming to and fro there's
landfill so these things are broken out
you know in the report and then like you
said at the end of course it goes into a
distribution chain and uh some people
have complained about the regulatory
landscape making this worse because
cannabis and that's is going to vary you
know by state and by jurisdiction right
but the more times you have to move it
because of chain of not chain of custody
but like the way the the uh stewardship
you know is is dictated uh it may have
to go to to one level of distribution
and then to another and certain uh
processes in the in the uh product life
cycle are separated to different
locations whatnot but there's
Transportation there and like one one
emerging thing that I just mentioned but
there's no you know I couldn't get a
handle on it with numbers is uh
door-to-door delivery I mean if you want
to really look you know at the whole
ecosystem you have to look at how it
reaches consumer that's the life cycle
and uh certainly door-to-door delivery
is increasing what is the net effect I
don't know I mean you can argue uh that
it might save some energy and certainly
it's going to defay some consumer trips
but you know there's a lot of talk now
about the faster that people want their
delivery the more carbon footprint there
is cu they send single items out in a
giant truck and you know we've all had
the experience with Amazon and you order
something and it's at your door the next
day and that means you know there were a
lot of inefficiencies in getting that to
your door because they're not they're
not moving Goods large amounts of goods
in one trip to one ZIP code they're
they're racing around with it one piece
of data you dropped that astonished me
was that home delivery is 50% of
cannabis sales now and and you know I I
I've never had delivery not that I
wouldn't have it but I live on on Island
that's small in the PES sound right and
and but but I I was astonished that
there's so much of it just being
delivered um and and you know I kind of
I kind of simmered on this I'm like okay
so the the cannabis store is sing
sending somebody to me with my cannabis
but but in the old days I used to go to
the house of my dealer and so one way or
another somebody had to drive and so um
I can see how we put this on the
industry as a whole but to be fair I
don't I don't think we should we need to
it'd be fair to put that on indoor no I
agreed and I tried to be careful in
saying what is the net effect of this
because you have to look at the net
effect and you know the the what is the
alternative and is that more or less
carbon and and we don't know uh but
again if something you know if you're
taking a 2,000lb car to deliver you know
an eighth somewhere and that's your only
trip that you're making as opposed to a
person who was ideally integrating that
with some other trip and there's
obviously a difference but I don't know
also just a small correction so that 50%
that's a thought experiment in the paper
to see well what effect would that be
and that would I if we got to 50% we
don't know what share I don't know what
share somebody does that's a good
clarification so there's a lot of
scenarios in the paper the the uh the
policy scenarios and the market
scenarios saying well what if the market
evolved in this way or that way good or
bad just how much do certain things move
the needle so that one like if 50% of
sales were eventually conveyed by
delivery services total emissions would
go up by about 4% okay from the total
carbon footprint so it's not the end of
the world this isn't you know the big
knob at all but we just have to look at
all these things and and also like which
ones are big and which ones are small
and the only way to do that is to go
through you know exercises like this so
deliver is not in my study in in the in
the numbers because we don't know uh how
much of it's going
onif how much is saved by uh what the
difference is between individual consum
consumers going and getting it or of
course there's the whole home
cultivation part of this as well which
is its whole you know separate
discussion and that's included in the
study and and there you you know you
save a lot of emissions and so the if
I'm remembering right the home
cultivation is about half the carbon
footprint indoor cultivation is
something like half the carbon footprint
of of industrial uh for a lot of reasons
and one of them is you you you know you
have less Transportation going on uh you
have you know you're not landfilling
things like that well that's an
interesting spin Evan that I did not
pick up my first time through um that's
actually a decent I you know I live in
Washington where we're not allowed hom
grow we're like one of the only people
yeah and um you know the the fact that
it never occurred to me that that
individual home you know a 4x4 tent hom
grow is going to be more efficient for
my own cannabis needs than it is for me
to buy it from uh from a store and all
the
extra energy that's used by that
cultivation I usually just compare it
the the indoor that I would buy at the
store versus my outdoor but the idea
that my indoor um is more energy
efficient surprises me can you tease
that out a little bit more yeah sure so
so let's be sure to say can be can be
fair enough okay the devil's always in
the details uh but uh and and still from
my numbers it's still still about half
the carbon footprint which is still
2,000 times its weight in CO2 so you
know keep it in perspective it's an
improvement I mean there we go back to
your conversations it's like well what
can we do you know and so this is
something ostensibly that would make a
big dent in it but you're still left
with a problem you know that's
extraordinary um but the reasons are you
know not everybody's air conditioning um
there's less volume you know these
indoor grows as you see you know in the
big pictures the industrial ones they're
incredibly voluminous and so you're you
know you're not just lighting plants
you're Heating and Cooling and
dehumidifying you know giant volumes of
air so you know that's a factor um the
you know it also depends on the
efficiency like if you know you're using
a heat pump at home and the indoor
grower Greenhouse is using gas heating
that's at 80% efficiency uh you know
that makes a difference uh you don't
have the interdiction or at least to the
same level and you know interdiction I
mean there's a lot of work up front in
this paper of looking at how much is
grown versus how much makes it to the
market because what doesn't make it to
the market I'm not really changing the
subject but you know it's a part where
it's a part of this indoor grown thing
again it's colorful right and so you
know you have to take all the energy
used to cultivate and divide that by the
energy by the quantity of cannabis
consumed at the end of the day right
that's the carbon footprint you have to
count all the energy whether it ends up
in a given consumer's product or not
because that's CO2 to the atmosphere and
energy being used and so you know you've
got so many forms of loss including at
home I mean if you lose a crop because
you're you're not skilled you know and
all of a sudden you're 4x4 is full of
mold you just wasted you know 60 days of
of electricity to get there but also you
know there's like the product testing
which again I'm not I'm not against but
product testing results in destroyed
cannabis and you're not product testing
when you grow at home uh the the
transport some of the transportation
involved there's no dispensary being lit
up I mean that's a small contri oh that
was a nice pun did you get that one yeah
I got that um so those are some
factors uh not everyone has
dehumidification you know you don't have
the large amounts of moisture all being
concentrated maybe you dry it in your
shower and you don't have showers off uh
you don't have you know an electric
drying uh environment with dehumidifiers
running so you know it's those are the
kinds of reasons why it seems like the
home footprint and then you're not going
to landfill you know the laws that
require and you know I'm not the laws
that require landfilling also increase
carbon emissions it's very small very
very small but I had to calculate it and
just look and when you put a lot of
biomass under the ground especially if
you have uh wet you know soaked mineral
wool full of full of uh uh P um
fertilizer residues and roots and so on
you get methane you know and that's a
greenhouse gas and lands are not not
catching all the methane so anyway
that's not happening with with home
cultivation uh as long as you compost it
and it doesn't go anerobic you know
you're okay that is an interesting thing
you said about interdiction um you know
raising the uh the energy consumption of
overall cannabis because um they're like
hey it was it was grown and and if they
just take it and let it mold in some
closet somewhere um that that it's not
getting it's not meeting needs in the
market and so it's they're essentially
letting electricity usage mold and so so
interdiction is not good for the
environment is a catchy idea and it's
not yeah and it's not just uh
electricity it's the fossil fuel but
it's also it's also all the but and
Beyond energy it's all the other inputs
uh you know to make the fertilizers and
build the facilities you you have to
allocate all that energy somewhere so uh
and the same token uh you know product
contamination which is the
responsibility of The Growers results in
destruction of product when that's
intercepted and overproduction is a
gigantic problem and that's not you know
the the the uh you know the government's
fault I mean there probably certain ways
to blame the public sector on that but
but when you overproduce and it doesn't
get to Market I mean canab Canada is
destroying you know thousands of tons of
cannabis every every year that's just
cuz they're over producing and you can't
keep it you know more than a year or so
it loses THC and the CBD profile changes
and I mean that's a whole separate
conversation of why is this over
production happening and I'm no expert
in it but I'm observing it and I have
not folded that into the study because
we don't know how much of that's
happening but if you look there's a lot
of it discussed in the appendix of the
paper a lot of specific numbers and
examples and Industry reports and it's
giant amounts and so you know you you
have to look at you there's a lot of
reasons that more is grown than is uh
consumed and then product recalls you
know is something that happens and I
don't think it's happening much which is
arguably a problem but uh but it's not
uh that's not again a giant to digit
effect but it's just one of you know
it's an example of how to think about
the gross production versus the Net
consumption and and who where that
energy and and uh emissions burden gets
allocated and then it brings us to an
point about legalization which is you
know a question that is everyone wants
to ask as well does legalization at the
national scale solve uh climate problem
and we can talk about that now now or
later but the uh one thing it does avoid
is the interdiction product Destruction
part of this puzzle which again is a
minor effect on the overall footprint
but it's not a trivial one we'll come
back to that uh during the third set I
want want to finish off this second set
with um a uh a a short discussion on um
fertilizers um specifically um on
shaping fire we are always teaching um
wildcrafting uh regenerative agriculture
making your own compost um you know
using uh local inputs um you know things
like that and and you know of course
we're we're we're encouraging people
we're trying to coax them away uh from
uh synthetics and a+b fertilizers and
petroleum derivatives and and you know
th this kind of uh
synthetic of of cannabis fertilizers and
um and and and certainly there is some
uh energy usage with a regenerative as
well you know it's still getting
packaged some way it's still being
shipped in most cases not everybody's
wildcrafting so so some of that is same
between the both but but but uh you know
I I have an assumption that most of this
uh
regenerative um soil amendments because
they are often in the form that they
were in nature you know maybe we need to
crush the crabshell but but it but it is
not like um you know building an a+b
fertilizer profile that's just going to
like supercharge the plant and so I I'm
wondering how do how do those compare
the the the the growing inputs
specifically that are related to
nutrition yeah important point and I
would refer your um your listeners to
the the widely uh talked about article
by Haley Summers and her colleagues from
Colorado a couple years ago and and that
was the first real serious so-called
life cycle assessment of cannabis where
they went through you know am modium
nitrate and triple super phosphate and
pottassium chloride and other soil
amendments and also you know uh uh neem
oil and fungicide and other things so
they did all that math and uh I bake
that into the work I'm doing and so for
the way that comes out oh and by the way
let's talk about carbon dioxide which is
actually the largest single part of the
non cultivation energy carbon footprint
so that's another input and you have
that carbon dioxide is made industrially
and I don't want to hear about like
citing grows next to breweries yeah okay
you know do that here and there it's
fine do it if you can but we're just
we're not going to have anheiser Bush uh
you know putting cannabis grows next to
all its U uh crappy beer factories um so
so the I got my spreadsheet uh spun up
while you were asking me this question
so the in this study the carbon
footprint from all these inputs that I
just rattled off also there's the
mineral wool right which is what melted
freaking Rock so so there's a lot of
carbon and because there's a lot of
energy in spinning mineral woil into
these cubes that are used once and are
generally not recyclable and go straight
to landfill um that's actually the
second
largest well no sorry there's there's
other ones that other soil amendments
are more important but at any rate the
um so if you look at the inputs as a as
a percentage as a ratio to the energy
carbon for cultivation the inputs add
are about a third more so it sign ific
if you look at the whole bwax all the
transportation everything about 20% of
all the national
emissions from Cannabis are from the the
inputs that's actually also averaging
together indoor and outdoor and all of
it so certain sub slices might be uh
might be more or less so it does matter
but bottom line it certainly matters and
the um you know and again you're also
sending stuff to landfill instead of
composting so there's other reasons that
you know better than I do of why closing
these Loops can can really help you just
want to be sure not to make methane in
your compost pile because then you're
really shooting yourself in the foot if
it goes anerobic because it methane's an
extremely potent um greenhouse gas uh
but like I said the biggest problem is
CO2 and you know it's it's the biggest
single additional carbon footprint uh
you know element beyond the the
energy itself the creation of these uh
petroleum based fertilizers I must ad I
don't exactly know how they are um made
because they've just never been
attracted to me attractive to me um um
how does that fertilizer creation
process compare with you know the
regenerative way of just collecting
natural items to mix into our
soil yeah that's above my pay grade I
don't it's not my specialty but it's
there's a lot of literature out there on
it and you know and there's a lot of
fossil Fuel and you know the the making
of nitrate you know in particular is a
is known to be you know very energy
intensive uh process I bet you that
there is a rich area for study down that
rabbit hole too yeah so okay so let's go
ahead and take our second commercial
break when we come back in set three um
I want to talk more about some of the
perspectives um that are needed and and
some of them that you mentioned during
the first set which I found to be very
valuable so so uh you are listening
shaping fire and my guest today is uh
energy and environmental systems analyst
Evan Mills and you know without these
advertisers shaping fire would not
happen so please support them and let
them know you heard them on shaping
fire one of the challenges with buying
Autoflower seeds is that often you'll
have as many different fenos as you will
have seeds in a pack that can be fun
sure but so many varieties in one pack
is a sign of an immature seedline that
hasn't been worked enough
I prefer my autoflowers to be worked
enough that each feno in the pack really
captures the aspects that the breeder
was
intending this is why I recommend gnome
automatics to my friends and listeners
who grow automatic flowering cannabis
seeds gnome automatic seeds are not just
crossed and released they are
painstakingly sifted again and again
tested in a wide range of conditions and
taken to a level of maturity that each
plant will be recognizable by its traits
traits that were hard earned so that you
can have your best grow cycle ever over
the last 10 years gnome automatics
founder Dan Jimmy has become a trusted
breeder and he continues to pour His
passion of breeding cannabis into every
variety he releases for you to grow
check out the gnome automatics Instagram
_ automatics to see the impressive
plants folks are growing you can score
gnome automatic seeds in feminized or
regular at your favorite seed provider
listed in the vendor section of their
website commercial cannabis Farms across
the country love growing gnome
automatics because of their consistency
from seed to seed short grow times THC
percentages and colorful bag appeal
Farms interested in bulk seeds of more
than a thousand should reach out through
gnome automatics.com
while on the website be sure to check
out the gnome automatic shirts and other
merch section too if you want reliable
seeds handbuilt from effort expert
selection and experience choose gnome
automatics fish poop brand fertilizer is
an allnatural fish poop concentrate with
nothing added real fish poop is
extraordinarily complex not only are you
adding the nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium your plants need to build mass
transport nutrients and enhance flavor
but fish waste is also packed with
biological activity and
micronutrients when you add fish poop to
your irrigation water you are adding
life force probiotics and active
microbes these microorganisms include a
wealth of various bacteria and protozoa
which further enhance nutrient
availability for the plants because
plants are limited by the absence of any
essential micronutrient these Trace
nutrients are the difference between
having a decent garden and having a
garden that makes you feel really proud
of your efforts fish poop is a naturally
complete solution that fills in the
cracks in your fertilizer program to
ensure you offer your garden a broad
base of nutrients not all fish poop is
created equally most products with added
fish waste don't reveal their sources or
lab results fish poop brand fish poop
however generates their own fish waste
as a byproduct of their organic
aquaponics cannabis farm where they
raise ornamental koi and tilapia you are
even invited to tour their Farm in
person or on their YouTube channel to
look for yourself this sort of
transparency is wildly rare in the
fertilizer Market the folks behind fish
poop are also lifelong medical cannabis
producers who have deep Connections in
the community donate more product than
they sell and support cannabis prisoner
veteran and patient collectives and
Charities to get your bottle of pure
fish poop go to fish poop.com and to see
their entire line of cannabis products
go to ounce ofh hope.com that's fish
poop brand fish poop
[Music]
sometimes the topics I want to share
with you are far too brief for an entire
shaping Fire episode in those instances
I post them to Instagram I invite you to
follow my two Instagram profiles and
participate online the shaping fire
Instagram has follow-up posts to shaping
fire episodes growing and processing
best practices product trials and of
course gorgeous flower photos the Shango
Los Instagram follows my travels on
cannabis garden tours my successes and
Fa here is in my own garden insights and
best practices from personal grows
everywhere and always gorgeous flower
photos on both profiles the emphasis is
on sharing what I've learned in a way
that you can replicate it in your own
garden your own hash lab or for your own
canopic health so I encourage you to
follow shaping fire and Shango and join
our online community on
Instagram welcome back you are listening
to shaping fire I am your host Shango
and my guest today is energy and
environmental systems analyst Evan Mills
so Evan you know I have had to hold
myself um as host several times during
the show because I have gone my whole
life defending cannabis from from people
who wanted to tell me it was a a drug
with no medical use and and people who
said I shouldn't be around it because of
the law and then people who are telling
me that we shouldn't grow it because I
don't have a license and then you know
it's it's it's it's one thing after
another where I have been trying and and
all of those with me right all of all of
my cannabis family we're we've all so
used to defending cannabis and defending
ourselves and defending our rights and
and trying to get people to understand
that this herb is healing of the mind
soul and body and and so you know
talking about cannabis in the way that
we have today I I'm also Pro the
environment but also Am Naturally kind
of knee jerky wanting to to just defend
cannabis and and and I think that part
of the big shift that has to happen is
is messaging to come through for people
to understand that we can still love
cannabis swear by it defend it and also
be responsible for the energy usage that
our you know favorite plant is using and
and you know unfortunately the poor way
that it's being implemented
bureaucratically but I think at the core
of it somehow those of us who love it
need to split from identifying the
Cannabis as
ourselves and instead understand that it
it's time for us to work um with the
plant in a way so that we're not abusing
the environment to get the part of it
that we
like you just answered your own question
beautifully what's the next question
no give it your own context
pleas you set that up really well and
rationally and look you know I grew up
uh I was born in 1960 I grew up in the
fabled Laurel Canyon I used to go as to
chich and Chong's kids uh Halloween
parties I live in Northern California
now in the Redwoods I'm a organic
Gardener not of cannabis but of you know
I love my garden uh I not against the
plant or against uh you know people who
who want to use it uh it's you know J uh
the um Henry Ford one of his you know
many famous quotes was everything can
always be done better than it
is be done better than it's done now and
that's part of what leads to Innovation
and there's you know the sky and you
know you earlier you were asking how LED
lights can be done better and that that
is a valid thing and it is something
that's being chased so I think just
having the attitude of uh
let's be creative let's be smarter let's
be sure we're current um let's be not
let our protectiveness you know I I was
listening to another podcast and the guy
uh was in the industry and he was
opposing Interstate
transport uh because he wanted to
protect his local market and you know
it's a free country at least for the
moment just we have to be care you know
think big you know think about the big
picture uh do we really want to oppose
interstate commerce to
protect with you know without any kind
of counterweight to it cuz that's that's
potentially going to have an energy you
know climate con consequence is it worth
it
um so I don't know if that's helpful but
you know those are some I think some
thoughts uh I the industry is also to be
honest uh starting to do some of this on
its own uh you look at like there been
some years now you know canopy growth in
can closed gigantic indoor warehouses
and transitioned you know to greenhouse
and you know there's more and more
Greenhouse coming that's been one of the
big changes since the 2012 study
obviously at that point there was you
know very little of these you know
prodigious you know 300,000 square foot
you know green houses happening now
they're no Panacea and it's too bad that
they have the word Green in their name
because they use a lot of the
humidification most of them use a lot of
electric lighting um and still the
artificial the uh fossil based inputs
and and all of that but there is less
energy and there's and that there's a
lot of optimization potential there for
sure in the greenhouse type you know
daylight I mean we're using daylight in
our buildings you know there's a whole
science around daylighting for humans
and use making more use of that and the
potential uh for that pales compared to
you know the Cannabis potential so
getting smarter with green houses I
think is a big one they they lose so
much energy and they're almost always
heated with natural gas you know that's
that's more the convention and uh why do
you have all this glass facing north and
on and on you know so there are people
out there who are you know have been
working not just in the Cannabis space
but in indoor egg more generally to try
to optimize uh green houses but you know
the cost of I I guess one thing I would
add is that there's an enlightened
self-preservation argument here too
because you know I mean it C here in
Northern California the out the Growers
used to call our local electric utility
PG their 20% partner because they were
paying 20% of their revenues to PG for
their monthly energy bills and uh it's
become a huge issue with profitability
and I would argue it's some paper I
haven't written yet but I think the
bankruptcies that we're seeing in the
Cannabis space are often tracing back uh
not necessarily solely but in
significant part to the energy spend you
know you spend a lot of money up front
for all the capital I mean these
Lighting systems these HVAC systems and
then if you want to try to be green and
putting in solar on top of that and
water recovery from your waste Air
Stream uh so it's become and then you
operate and you're spending millions of
dollars a month can be on energy so it's
a real pain point so you know in part
industry is discovering this kind of the
hard way but I would I would hate to see
a big boom and bust where we have all
these you know abandoned warehouses with
all this equipment that nobody else
needs in them and uh so the boom and
bust I think is on on the menu for uh
California because it's already
happening right I I hope that we see
this better in other states and um
earlier in in in this last um run of
words uh you had mentioned that um you
know some of the things that um the
industry is doing to improve and it's
really startling how low the bar is for
a lot of the folks to make an impression
for example um you know I was down in
California as I often am and you know I
picked up some regenerative uh cannabis
flower from Soul Spirit garden and I was
just I was overjoyed and and made an
Instagram a post because they use um
compostable Dube tubes and and um uh
some kind of uh compostable paper ink um
you know for their for their boxes and I
was just floored to see something that
existing because you know I I go into
places all across the country and i'
I've not seen anybody do that that
actively and and here I am overjoyed and
and you know all all love and support to
Soul Spirit but but we we need to see
that from just one farm right we need to
see that with in entire States um moving
in this generation or in this uh general
direction um I was also curious earlier
uh during Second set you you talked
about some inherent Market bias towards
indoor that wasn't coming from the
consumer and uh and I wanted to hit on
that before we wrapped up so would you
would you kind of color that in for us
cuz I like to hear those points sure
it's yeah it's pretty uh interesting and
disheartening to dig in a bit to like
how the Market's working in the
regulatory sphere and and other aspects
uh one is that that we see here in
California and it's probably true in
other states I know it's true in other
states uh varying by state is that some
of the legislation defers to well first
of all some of the legislation like for
a while Illinois was only allowing
indoor cultivation
full stop in California the legalization
the recreational stage uh left it to it
was it was legalized Statewide but it
left it to the jurisdictions meaning
counties and cities
to to color in you know what the
policies were going to be and half of
California by land area forbids outdoor
cultivation so they can't make it
illegal because the state allows it to
be legal but they can force it to only
be indoors and one can have a
conversation about why in the world that
is at the municipality level yeah it
could be city or county so that's that's
a a distortion and then you have um this
whole world of financial incentives and
I'm the first person to defend and argue
for financial incentives for Energy
Efficiency and and Renewables uh we
typically think of them as utility
rebates for better LED lighting in this
industry but there can be yeah rebates
for rebates for sungrown and exactly so
you put your finger on it that's what's
not happening and so instead you see I
mean you Google around you'll see
Growers being handed these large you
know uh table-sized cardboard checks for
a million dollars for putting in LED
lights okay maybe but what you're doing
is you're subsidizing them to a large
degree I mean these are giant rebates
and you're making their product even
more competitive to to uh outdoor gr to
Sun Fe feeding the wrong solution yeah
and so imagine if indoor sorry if if
outdoor producers were sorry if current
indoor producers were given an incentive
like that to not get uh 10% Energy
savings but to get 99% Energy savings by
shifting to outdoor cultivation and
maybe that million dollar check should
go to them and at least level that
playing field you know have no subsidies
if you don't like subsidies or you know
make it make it fair and reward all the
good behavior and not just one so
there's that and then I think lastly you
know there's this issue of cities and
the trend towards Urban
cultivation and you know you don't I
mean you may notice because you're in
the industry but the average person
driving around in a neighborhood with
warehouses doesn't realize that there's
you know a Walmart sized Warehouse that
they're driving by that's all cannabis
and they're there you know for some the
wrong reasons they're being given you
know sweetheart deals on their taxes or
you know lower fees whatever and the
cities want them there because the
cities are getting uh local taxes and
local permit free so it's a conflict of
interest and I don't pretend to know how
often you know that swaying things but
the cities have a conflict of interest
be in wanting the Cannabis facilities
there which kind of by definition have
to be indoors if they're in the urban
Fabric in this world you know in this
country and uh and then but they're
blowing up their carbon footprint uh at
the same time by by drawing these
entities cuz there are like there are
outdoor Growers from California who've
moved to Oakland you know and then
sometimes these
Growers uh you know get on a Jag and
they blow out the PE the utility um
Transformers and they bring in diesel
generators to run you know their grows
in these low-income environmentally
overburdened areas and I'm getting off
track from your question but it it's a
the urban urbanization of cultivation
but Denver's got 200 Factory scale grows
in the you know in the core of Denver
Oakland has about 200 in their so-called
green
zone so I think that's an issue and uh I
think we can do better you know in that
that The Regulators have a role to play
in uh leveling the playing field and and
not throwing obstacles in front of in
front of Industry doing the right thing
you mentioned that um you mentioned
interstate commerce earlier and uh you
know we've all been joking since the
since the med early medical days that um
it's kind of California versus everybody
right like as like like if if you want
to have a cannabis company in your state
you need to get up you need to get
efficient and you need to lock in your
customer base before
Interstate uh sales is allowed because
as because California's going to eat
everybody's lunch and um you know and
there's there's a lot to be said for
that and and then there there's a lot of
challenges to be said for that too but
but you've looked at the numbers and and
and what do you see in your crystal ball
as far as the impact of interstate
commerce on the you know overall energy
consumption uh for the Cannabis
industry I haven't been able to put
numbers on that at this point there's
just not enough data but there's a long
discussion in the paper about how to
think about it and all the kind of
unexpected counterveiling factors there
and you know how much we would save or
how much we wouldn't save uh you know
there's a lot of as you mentioned
California is the big gorilla and you
think of all the uh all the Cannabis
already I mean I think California
produces like three times as much
cannabis as Californians consume
something like that so all that's going
to other states California is one of the
cleaner States because we have a clean
grid and so if you do the thought
experiment and say well now we have
interstate commerce and we're going to
say all this carbon by having more local
production you have to subtract that you
may just be bringing in the same
cannabis that's just now on the legal
side so it's pretty tricky this is
pretty tricky but I do that said I think
you know the the there's so much of the
US that's suitable for uh lowc carbon
outdoor cultivation and you know
interstate commerce is an obstacle to
that and being able to flow uh
everywhere and I just you know I can't
put numbers on for you but it's a big
one we did look at legalization more
broadly kind of adjacent to the question
you're asking uh how much carbon might
that save in its own right and it's
rather small you know it's difficult to
model difficult to think through but
basically the big benefit of
legalization is less landfill and or I'm
sorry there's more landfill that's an
offsetting effect right because mandated
landfill happens in the legal Market not
in the other one so there's uh there's
some ways in which it can increase
emissions all the packaging is one that
you mentioned before you know there's uh
one new paper says there's more
packaging in regulated markets than in
the illicit market and in Pre uh
pre-regulated markets um but also on the
upside uh you have um from legalization
you have you you're taking the
interdiction out of it and so all that
cannabis that's destroyed and all that
embodied energy in carbon is principle
you know in in a rarified case uh not
happening anymore so that's so it's
something like an 8% reduction in
National carbon footprint from
legalization in its own right but that
said legalization is kind of a necessary
but not sufficient uh mile poost on the
route to all kinds of other policies
right you can't incentivize better
practices in an illicit market and today
right now about the carbon about little
more than half of the national carbon
footprint is in the elicit Market and a
little less than half is in the legal
Market by the way so there's a lot
there's a lot to address still yeah that
is a lot to address on the other side
but it's interesting how that comes out
uh it's not necessarily obvious that it
would break down like that much more of
the production is in the illicit Market
but also the elicit Market has a much
larger share of outdoor than the legal
Market does so that's part of why um
even though you know 75 80% of the
production is in the elicit side
nationally the uh the carbon Footprints
are more more 50/50 is because there's
more outdoor on the elicit side
um so to to wrap us up here um we have
given folks a whole lot of data points
and perspectives and so many of them um
you know they they're lubricated and
they've got pivot Points and they depend
on these so so it can be it's very much
a you know a complex web and and as you
address this then the other part moves
and so let's let's let's distill this
down to um some I don't know marching
orders or or suggestion is probably a
little less
authoritarian um so for for the two key
groups who who we're talking to now
right because obviously we'd have a lot
to say for the politicians but they're
probably not still listening to the
episode the people who are listening are
cannabis consumers and um and uh the
Cannabis business owners the cultivators
and so um let's take the business first
and then we'll talk about then then
we'll talk to the consumers so so you
know
if if if if a indoor cultivator and
they've got their heart in the right
place and they have just heard our
conversation and they're like damn I
think that at the very least I need to
start doing stuff to decrease my energy
consumption it'll be better for the
company and it'll be better for the
environment and I I want to help there
be a planet for my kids okay so they're
they heading their hearts in the right
place but they already have an indoor um
they already have an indoor cultivation
and so what would you give to them as
the first steps on a path that are
attainable yeah good good questions and
and I have to say uh you know I've had a
lot of emails and things from producers
over the years and uh more than a
handful have said they've changed their
business model you know they've looked
at this and over time they've shifted
their their industry towards you know
greenhouse and then outdoor so you know
strategic longer t term way there's no
shame in that and it's something that's
done all the time and you can look at
the large Industries and they're
definitely shifting their you know their
center of gravity from from indoor
towards outdoor so there's that the
longer term I think uh nearer term you
know look at geta energy audits you know
really look at your processes uh think
about I don't want to say greedy but
like maximizing yield you know is it
everything numbers more carefully
because maximum yield isn't necessarily
maximum profitability you know like
things are you know it's expensive to
push you know a crop and I'm not
pretending I know more than these
cultivators who've spent their you know
their professional lives you know
dialing this in but but be sure you've
got good info good
advice think twice at it think twice
about you know your your current
practices think about Henry Ford and how
you can do better um so I think that's
as a as a near-term about as good is we
can get and
um and then then how about the consumer
then because you know the consumer it's
interesting because the consumer is both
the most powerful and the least powerful
they're they're at the end of the long
chain so it's really hard to influence
any of it but because it's all being
made for us it actually does empower us
but I definitely don't think that uh
consumers are using their power at all
so so what would you say to us as
consumers about some kind of action we
can take to to to to move the the the
the percentages in the right
direction yeah I think the consumer is
doesn't realize their power in as in so
many cases right energy climate more
broadly and and all kinds of other
issues so I think talk to your bud
tender ask questions be curious uh ask
for uh you know ask for data on your on
the different products make it known
that it it matters to you and you know
consumers can change their behavior and
that changes the market and there are
consumers uh it sounds like like
yourself you know who who uh prefers
sungrown and uh hunt for the product
that's just right for them or I mean I
don't think it's even necessary but come
down and not and quality whatever it's
just or make quality part of your
definition of sorry make environment
part of your definition of quality right
it's that doesn't seem like a stretch
like what is quality what is quality of
life isn't part of quality of life being
you know not having our our homes burned
in Wildfire seriously you know so so I
think the consumers you know being aware
and educating themselves and it's hard
right because there's very little
information out there for them and and
it's not being provided by industry I
think also being aware of greenwashing
you know there's a lot of greenwashing
unfortunately I have a page on my site
that your listeners are welcome to look
at with examples of the greenwashing
that happens and it shouldn't be on the
consumer to root that out and uh clean
that up but
unfortunately there aren't really
Regulators you know going after this but
that that's a a problem for consumers is
uh even like the notion of Terre you
know like so we've got cannabis grown in
a windowless Factory not in soil with no
sun no rain in California in in uh
Arcada you know and it's called humbl
you know like what is what is that so
maybe there's something there that I'm
not understanding you know I guess the
water uh but the water's been so heavily
treated by the time it gets there so I
think that's something for consumers and
you know and back to the producers for a
second I think another thing they can do
is I mean it's under this Banner of
being curious and inquisitive and also
forthcoming you know share data work
with
researchers um comp you know benchmark
your carbon footprint against your
competitors and see like well how am I
doing because benchmarking is a really
powerful tool to see well what what are
other people what are the best practices
out there and you know go for those
there is a lot of documentation on best
practices within indoor within
Greenhouse so I think that's something
to do and
consider product labeling especially if
you're doing better you know then get
the word out there and work with the
dispensaries and work with these the
value chain to get transparency for
consumers and if consumers are asking
for it and producers are pushing it uh
then consumers will start to be more
informed about you know about carbon
footprint so that's something that
everyone you know all the actors uh from
The Regulators to The Growers to the
consumers uh could do more and because
it's pitiful you know there's just
there's such an information vacuum
facing uh everybody you know all from
Soup To Nuts there right on well thank
you Evan you know um we easily could
have done a couple more hours on this
topic um but we you know the goal was
not to inundate people too much but but
to really
illustrate to folks um you know how how
tenacious energy consumption is all
through um the chain and to start having
us think about it whether our our end
goal is to actually get outside or to
just decrease our electrical usage in
our present operation as step one um I
think that is you know it's an honorable
Pursuit and uh and even though we don't
want to look at anything that is you
know chastising of cannabis well I I
think it's I think it's damn time so
thank you so much for giving of your
personal time to join us today on
shaping fire and to to share your like
wildly indepth understanding of the data
behind our industry your your your
stories your Insight and definitely your
good cheer are definitely appreciated my
pleasure uh thanks for your great
questions excellent so dear listener if
you would like to follow up uh and learn
even more for from Evan Mills um uh the
best way to do that is to go to his
website which is is kind of like a um
it's kind of like a repository of of his
research and the the graphics there are
just absolutely educational and um
illustrative and fantastic so so even if
you're not even if you want to know more
but you're not in the mood to read a
whole bunch by goodness gracious go to
his website and look at the graphs
you'll learn so much so fast so um the
website for that is e v
n- Mills m i l
ls.com Evan mills.com and also um uh if
you are driving or something um you can
um definitely go to the shaping fire
website for this episode um number 120
and um and you can grab the link there
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast And subscribe to
the show at shaping fire.com and
wherever you get your podcasts if you
enjoyed the show we'd really appreciate
it if You' leave a positive review of
the podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too on the shaping
fire website you can also subscribe to
the newsletter for insights into the
latest Cannabis News exclusive videos
and giveaways on the shaping fire
website you'll also find transcripts of
today's podcast as well be sure to
follow on Instagram for all original
content not found on the podcast that's
@ shaping fire and @ Shango on Instagram
be sure to check out shap fire YouTube
channel for exclusive interviews farm
tours and cannabis lectures does your
company want to reach our national
audience of cannabis enthusiasts email
hotspot shaping fire.com to find out how
thanks for listening to shaping fire
I've been your host Shango Los
[Music]