[Music]
the community of cannabis cultivators
has always been tight we had to be for
most of our Lives we were persecuted and
in some jurisdictions we still are that
persecution meant that we couldn't
access many of the botanists we'd like
to talk to and that meant there were big
parts of cannabis cultivation that was
kind of in a biological Black Box we
couldn't see what was happening inside
all we knew was what we were doing and
then what was coming out the other side
now though between the creeping personal
legalization we've got and the internet
we can now access the minds of
scientists who support our efforts to
grow magnificent thriving and medicinal
cannabis plants
today's one of those episodes where we
get to look inside that black box during
today's episode we will examine the
relationship between the cannabis plant
and the soil life and get a better
understanding of how they talk to each
other and how they work together for
Mutual benefit in this intimate
relationship
if you want to learn about cannabis
Health cultivation and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple most important
news items from the week and videos too
don't rely on social media to let you
know when a new episode is published
sign up for the updates and make sure
you don't miss an episode
also we are giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter there's nothing else you
need to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shapingfire.com to
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shapingfire and I'm your
host shangolos my guest today is plant
biologist Sarah Lane Sarah Lane is
wrapping up her PhD in plant and
cellular biology at University of
Victoria her work primarily focuses on
route exudates that are involved in Iron
uptake in plants and their potential
medicinal benefits
Sarah consults for licensed cannabis
cultivators in Canada and is an avid
living soil cannabis home grower due to
her University Research needs she is
also very experienced in fog ponics and
hydroponics
Sarah has a wicked large Plant
collection and is currently designing a
specialty terrarium for growing Cloud
orchids
during the first set of today's episode
we will focus on what exudates are their
biological mechanics and how they
interact with microbes and other
residents of the rhizosphere during the
second set we will talk about the
relationship between exudates and fungal
Networks
signaling varieties of exudates and
address the challenges of a 24-hour
light cycle
we finish up the third set discussing
exudates and salt-based fertilizers
exudates and soilless growing mediums
like Coco coir and the misconception of
using unsulfured molasses to replace the
nutrition that exudates provide
welcome to shaping fire Sarah
hey it's great to be here thanks for
having me oh yeah thank you so much for
joining us and sharing your expertise so
let's Jump Right In you know I think
that most people who cultivate cannabis
who have even heard of exudates
um only really know that exudates are
something that the cannabis plant gives
off and that the microbes eat and like
that's pretty much it it's the it's the
food it's the the plant feeding the
microbes and that's about it and and you
know we know that that's actually overly
simplistic and misses the big picture so
so why don't we start by kind of getting
everybody on the same page and if you
would explain what exudates are
okay so exudates are basically all of
the different molecules and components
that the plant makes in the roots that
are like given off to the rhizosphere so
there's a bunch of stuff inside the
plant cells and inside the root that
happens and then eggs dates are
everything that the plant makes
specifically to to transport out into
the soil and there's lots of different
types of exudates they can be sugars
they can be amino acids they can be
um specific types of secondary
metabolites which are not used for
nutrition and there's many many
different functions of them as well
so just to give us an idea of of like
how many different exudates there are
are we are we talking about like like
there's there's there's like five
buckets or 50 buckets or a hundred
buckets like how many how many varieties
are there just just in general
oh goodness that's a tough one there
there honestly are so many different
types of exudates and we're just
scratching the surface of what exudates
actually are like off the top of my head
like functionally there's probably like
20 different groups of exudates that I
know of personally but I think exudates
are extremely hard to study because they
are in the soil and The Roots so I think
we'll probably keep finding new ones
over time this is Kai I get the idea now
that this is kind of like asking you how
many uh types of bacteria are there
there's just like a ton in nature and
and we're constantly finding more as our
technology gets more sensitive so true
yep that's definitely the case all right
so um like to help illustrate uh what
some of these exudites are can you give
us like like three different examples of
exudates that you know maybe you
particularly like just so that we can
kind of wrap our head around
um you know
what what they do
sure um so so I mean the ones that I
work with specifically are called
finally
they're actually sort of a group of
molecules that come from the process of
building up lignin but they have lots of
different uses
um and those include things like some of
them are complicated ones or chlorogenic
acid which is actually found really in
high amounts in coffee so people might
be a little bit more familiar with it
there's also amino acids like um that
not only are used for protein building
but plants can make special non-protein
amino acids that are really useful in
finding out things like fishing out iron
out of the soil and that kind of thing
and then the other one is flavonoids
there's actually a bunch of different
types of flavonoids which is a big huge
super group of different types of
molecules and they're involved in
everything from antioxidant Behavior to
um even signaling to mycorrhizae and
things like that all right so so you've
mentioned um uh I think that I think
I've pulled out like three different
categories from your examples there
there would be like um like this the
only ones I was aware of the nutrition
right um and then it said and then
you've mentioned signaling a couple
times and then and then um you you
sounds like there are some that actual
like process
um
uh like things like nitrogen and things
like that they're like more like kind of
like worker bees
um is that do do all of exudates roughly
fall into these three categories or um
or are there many more categories to
like what they do
interacting with nutrients directly
which is kind of where my expertise is
um there's signaling back and forth like
talking to bacteria or fungi or that
kind of thing where they interact with
the microbes and the microbes interact
back and then there's another big group
that are almost like anti-herbicidal
or or a herbicidal story and those ones
are responsible for sort of clearing the
way for the plant to grow
um I'm sure there's more than that but I
think that's kind of like the big huge
groups so I think I have an overly
simplistic understanding of the back and
forth because the way I normally think
about the relationship with the plant
and the uh the microbes and the rest of
the life and the the rhizosphere is that
during the daytime the plant will
um uh be fed by the microbes and and the
rest of the players in the rhizosphere
during the day and then during the dark
period the plant will then turn around
and send uh the the required nutrition
back into the rhizosphere and so it's
like a it's like a back and forth like a
tide thing dependent on
um you know whether or not it is day or
night cycle for the plant which is kind
of quarterbacking this back and forth is
how I generally think about it but um
but that may very well be way too
simplistic so so will you kind of
explain how it goes back and forth
yeah so I think like the basic idea of
signaling is is a little bit like
texting it's it's not so much that the
plants are providing nutrition directly
to the roots although in some cases from
the roots to the microbes although in
some cases it is and it's not always
that the microbes are providing
nutrition back to the plant there's a
lot of signaling that's going on and
that's kind of like if you can imagine
um you know being at home and hey can
you pick me up some milk from the
grocery store but it could also be like
hey I've got cookies when you've got
home when you come home and that kind of
thing so that's kind of what I mean by
signaling
um and that signaling happens all day
every day at any time so there is some
regulation with light interacting
obviously the light drives
photosynthesis and that kind of thing
and when the plant is on it's often
needing a lot of different types of
activities like nutrient acquisition and
maybe it's doing some you know stress
responses to help against pests or
something like that and a lot of this
happens in the daylight I don't think we
know enough about whether or not it
happens in the dark
because the roots are always in the dark
technically sure does that make sense
yeah it does um you know the way that
you described it this kind of like all
these different
microbes and uh and
protozoa and then the plant exudates all
kind of calling out to each other and
signaling you know pick up milk or I
have cookies when you get home and like
and if everybody is doing that I
suddenly got this idea of like this
cacophony of signals back and forth and
like shopkeepers calling out what's on
sale and kind of like some kind of like
big Turkish Bazaar and like everybody
trying to you know give everybody's
attention
um is that a is that a reasonable
picture of of what's going on it's a
beautiful picture of what's going on I
really do think that's exactly what's
happening because they're like we often
think about it being just the plant and
the microbes interacting with each other
but the microbes interact with each
other too and with fungi end with
different um organisms around like it is
just a huge web of different organisms
talking to each other and sometimes that
is like you know selling your chips on
the you know or the hot dog stand or
whatever and maybe it is advertising for
sale and it's very very very complicated
and it's something that I think we wish
we knew more about but trying to dissect
what each of those components is
contributing to the soil life or even
just how the plant is growing in the
soil is really complicated I like that
though yeah and it's strange too because
like I've always kind of thought as of
the soil as while a violent place often
um uh you know pretty calm actually like
it's it's kind of serene in there but
it's probably because of the level of
magnitude I'm like I'm living on this
human level of magnitude but if I could
see really closely under a microscope
I'd be I'd be
seeing all this activity in the
rhizosphere and so it's only quite
because like I I can't hear it
absolutely it is very barely Controlled
Chaos down there let me tell you
so do we have a any technology or any
way to gauge the amount of
you know rambunctious signaling that's
going back and forth like there is is
there any kind of like a you know
anything that we can like put into the
soil to gauge signaling that's taking
place in the soil
um I think it's it's pretty complicated
but there's some interesting things that
go on so like I guess it depends on what
level so what we're talking about right
now is on the chemical level and really
the the way that a lot of people are
doing this is either bulk so they take a
big sample of soil and then measure it
for different types of organisms or
different types of signals that they're
producing but then trying to tease that
out we can tell differences like maybe
between different types of soil or
different types of communities different
types of plants that kind of thing
um but I think it'd be really hard to
pick out which one is responsible for
exactly which one and so the other
option is to take an individual plant
and an individual organism and see what
they do together just the two of them
and it's one of the real challenges with
like soil ecology or or like ecology in
general is just trying to pull out you
either have to treat it as a whole and
just accept that you don't understand
the individual relationships
um or you have to get in there and try
and tease them apart one by one does
that make sense it does so let's talk a
little bit about
um a couple of these different varieties
so um the the one that we've talked
about the most so far is are the
signaling and so we understand
you know what they're trying to Signal
like like I have this type of nutrition
or or maybe I need this type of
nutrition
um how are they doing that are they
doing that um primarily uh chemically or
is an electrical charge or what is at
that um very small level what is the
mode of communication
it is it is chemical I mean there for
the most part
um it is like plants if we go back to
the exudate thing like these plants are
making these very highly specific
molecules they're basically in some
cases like an invitation and then those
are actually like taken up by the
microbe in question
um and that changes what the microbe can
make so it actually interacts um after a
long signal being Cascade inside the
cell it'll interact on the genome and
then they'll be able to produce
different types of molecules based on
that information and then that ends up
getting made and exuded out by the
microbe and then maybe that's an RSVP
response card back to the plant and then
they kind of do this back and forth or
sometimes it might just be like they
actually make a different molecule and
that molecule has been transported into
the plant cell does that make sense yeah
and it's super cool actually I mean the
idea that that the the the the signaling
exudate kind of like combines with the
microbe and between the two of them they
developed this superpower that's the
only way that what is necessary is
produced
I mean that's pretty cool that's a very
complex complex yeah
I think it's awesome I think I think
it's also important to note though that
what we're talking about there is like a
pretty symbiotic relationship
um and there is going to be some
opportunistic stuff too because you know
plants are making stuff that maybe it
has one purpose but the microbes can use
it for something different so
it uses it for something different it
produces some other stuff and those
different types of molecules have like a
happy accident to the plant could use
some of them too like sometimes it is
more like a a free bin than it is
something that's like really organized
but um yeah there can be both happening
all right I like this idea of invitation
microbes too
um all right so so if they are all
speaking to each other through subtle
chemicals
um for for those of us who are you know
we're adding things to our soil all the
time you know this fertilizer or that
fertilizer or you know some kind of soil
trench with like an fpj in it or
something
um how easy is it for us to disrupt that
chemical signaling back and forth
um just like let's say that you know I'm
talking with a friend in my yard and a
plane flies over you know relatively low
because I live near an airport and we
just have to like stop talking for a
minute and wait for the plane to fly
over is there anything that that we
could potentially do as cultivators that
would be so air quotes loud in the
rhizosphere that everybody have to talk
stop talking for a minute because we
just dumped something in the soil see I
think unless it's water like probably
everything we add is disrupting things a
little bit it's a bit like getting a
shipment you know everybody stops to
bring in the delivery kind of thing I
think that is also true of microbes
because they're responding to the to
whatever you've added as well but I
think I think all of them are going to
be disruptive I think it's more how long
because like for example if you're just
adding water or some nutrients like
depending on how light or how much
nutrients you're adding it might be like
really short term and they can use up
those nutrients pretty quickly and then
they're back to doing whatever or maybe
it's more long-term and you've really
altered the soil chemistry enough that
like maybe something dies off or those
kind of things I think those are all
things that could really disrupt and I
think especially with nutrients because
a lot of what we're talking about is the
plant signaling four nutrients or
something related to nutrition
um that that's probably one of the
things that would turn off signals from
a plant like they don't need to get it
from the microbe if you're providing it
um and I think that that might be
something else that would really I don't
know that would definitely be a plain
overhead situation sure I want to take
one more step along this disruption idea
um
specifically with with water I mean
clearly the soil requires uh water so
that things can have Mobility
um but sometimes you know a a cultivator
will just over water terribly and um and
it can you know drown lots of varieties
of microbes or or you know cause them to
cyst up and depending on the on the
variety can we drown exudates to to the
point where you know we kind of like
wipe out a whole I don't know generation
of them and and the what the soil that
needs to dry out and then the plant
needs to restart
I think I think yeah like if you're if
you're like uh watering to run off and
stuff like that there's certainly stuff
that's leaching out of the soil and some
things are kept more by the soil than
others so when we talk about these
molecules
um a lot of them are charged and some of
the charged like the positively charged
um types of molecules tend to stay in
soil better than negatively charged ones
do
um so you could definitely like flush a
lot of things out that way but I think
the time scale for production of
exudates by the plant it can replenish
pretty quickly it's not um it's not on
like the you know days weeks or months
sort of situation like those cells are
making a lot of stuff really rapidly and
some of the responses can happen within
seconds I don't think it'll be seconds
to make the exudates again but the idea
that they might need to make more of
them is a pretty quick one so I mean it
you might you might disrupt it like
really temporarily I think the biggest
danger with over watering is probably
damage to the roots or like promoting
the growth of anaerobic bacteria or
pathogenic species that kind of thing I
follow um so so that was we were just
talking about the signaling variety and
so let's talk about the nutrition
variety and it sounds like some of the
signaling ones actually do end up
playing a role in getting nutrition for
the plant themselves as well
um what's the difference between like
that kind of activity and the ones that
we were putting in the nutritive
um exudates bucket
I think those ones are more direct so I
mean everything is happening at like a
chemical level so the chemistry of the
molecules can interact with the
chemistry of the soil and just
completely bypass the microbes so for
example I work with iron iron is really
hard to get out of the soil there's lots
of it but it's kind of like it's locked
up like a rock
um and so the plants will actually make
molecules that can go and sort of fish
it out from the Rock and interact
directly with iron molecules and then
that is brought over to the root and it
can be taken up that way some of things
like nitrogen and phosphorus and things
like that I think there's certainly like
either they're making it a more
favorable environment for those ions to
just kind of like those molecules to
just be available for uptake
um or they're actually able to like drag
it in some some plants those non-protein
amino acids that I was talking about
earlier
um some plants like grasses will make
those and they actually just kind of
pick up the iron like a little basket of
eggs and actually bring it inside the
cell so they can they can interact
certainly with molecules to Signal back
and forth to tell them to make other
things and bring it in but they can
actually just interact with the
nutrients directly as
um as that molecule and bring it in as
well does that make sense it does so
when um when cultivators kind of like uh
Loosely say you know oh this this
fertilizer is is plant ready or that
fertilizer needs to be you know
processed in the rhizosphere before the
the plant can take it is is it these
exudates that that we're talking about
that are doing that work of coming
across you know nutrition or minerals or
whatever in the soil and the exudates
are what are you know breaking it down
and and putting it into a form term that
can interact with the actual root Zone
that's certainly part of it yeah for
sure and like one group we haven't
talked about is low molecular weight
organic acids
um which are like really really small
basic
um uh that's one that I can think of off
the top of my head
um
like citric acids and things like that
plants can make those and that will just
make it easier to take up is that sort
of what you were talking about yes yeah
yeah
um because you know most of the time we
just talk about that uh you know you
know casually using like contemporary
language and and not the science
specific language so to kind of like
you know accidentally come across it
it's kind of been kind of exciting it's
like oh this is what we're talking about
all the time and we don't know what
we're talking about that's great
like this big component of like when we
talk especially about living soils and
things like that there's there's
everything at the end of the day is
assault even if it's from an organic
material or something like that it's
being broken up into these little tiny
ions that we call salts and um and the
the I guess it's just a matter of
whether it needs help to get to that
state or whether we're providing it as
that state and anytime we're talking
about these like exudates helping like
they're basically trying to put it into
that form so the plant can take it up
so then um the third bucket we were
talking about
um were
um I don't know for lack of a better
term I'll say allopathic they're they're
kind of like like I don't know almost
military they're where they where they
go and they are hurting the plant
enemies is that like the general idea
sort of yeah
um so allelopathic chemicals are these
sort of now herbicides that some and not
all plants make them but some plants
make these types of exudates that
basically act as like a herbicide or a
fungicide or something like that to
clear the way so it's made by the root
The Roots going through the soil and
like leaving this material behind that
is really toxic to some plants and that
kills off neighboring roots and that
kind of thing and lets it grow better
and invasive species are often really
good at making these kind of things in
the plants that are here already don't
have any defense against them and so it
just kills them off so I know I asked
you that question in kind of like a
general way have we found cannabis
plants making this particular kind of
War making exudate yet do we have we
seen that in cannabis I mean I know
we're still just learning what cannabis
puts out but have we found that yet not
to my knowledge they're pretty unique
situations when this is a thing um like
for example walnut trees black walnut
trees you cannot grow anything under a
black walnut tree for a huge radius
because that's how toxic it is but
cannabis you can plant quite a few
plants right next to it it doesn't seem
to do anything so if it is it would be
on maybe like
I don't know maybe it would be
anti-fungal or something like that but I
don't think it actually has anything
like this that would kill off plant
roots like that that's a great example
because that's actually what I was
thinking about I was thinking about oh
maybe maybe this is why some of the
companion planting that we put with
cannabis is more successful than others
maybe the the cannabis plant is actually
trying to choose its neighbors
it certainly can and like all these root
things that we're talking about like it
influences the soil environment and that
environment is going to be hospitable to
some other plants and less hospitable to
others maybe not because it's directly
killing off the plants but just because
maybe that plant doesn't enjoy those
kind of conditions the same way all
right so we talked about the signaling
kind and we talked about the the the the
the allopathic kind and we talked about
the the processing that are going to go
and you know free up nutrition in the
soil and then I think the last category
that we haven't covered is is are the
exudates that are themselves nutrition
so so what kind tell us a little bit
about the exudates that the plant puts
off that is nutrition itself
these ones are kind of complicated
because I guess it depends on what what
isn't necessary but a lot of things that
are carbon based because carbon is
basically what we talk about like like
sugars and things like that or what end
up being used to make energy so I think
that a a lot of different types of root
eggs dates could be nutritious to other
organisms provided they can break them
down and use them
um so I think like
um a lot of the metabolites I work with
we think might be getting
um eaten up by bacteria which are like
the the acids and things like that
anything that has a sugar attached
because a lot of these molecules are
combinations of these different types of
groups so you can have an acid that's
attached to a sugar for example like all
of those would be possible nutrients
since you brought up carbon
um I want to ask you a question it's
kind of a
I don't know where this might take us is
what I want to say is that last night I
was talking to a soil biologist Leighton
Morrison on the phone about how excited
I was about our interview today and he's
like oh exits are great they're like
liquid carbon
and and I wasn't sure what he meant but
I figured I would ask you about him and
say are exudates like liquid carbon
a little bit actually so a lot of um
like there's there's a huge number of
atoms out there in elements um but the
ones that are most common in organic
chemistry and and life are carbon oxygen
nitrogen phosphorus
um hydrogen and sulfur and so most of
these tiny like it's just those six like
there's and obviously there's other
things like iron and plants need
manganese and magnesium and all these
other different Metals but like a lot of
these molecules that we're talking about
today are based off of those
um those six so when we're talking
liquid carbon like the a lot of these
molecules have a carbon skeleton so
they're mostly carbon and as long as
something can break the carbon apart and
use it in their in their biology though
that's food does that make sense I get
it so so I want to talk a little bit
about the the nature of the signaling
I'm curious to know whether it's more
more push or pull
um when the signaling happens and
perhaps it's both is it more like
putting out a sign that says you know I
have cookies for sale if you want
cookies come over to me or is it more
like placing an order where one one side
of it either the microbe or the plant
will will put out a request to the other
side for what they specifically need
I think it's it's sort of both and it
really depends on which specific
interaction you're talking about but I
kind of like to think of it more like a
conversation like there's going to be
some asking questions and like I need
this but there's also going to be like
I'll give you this too
um and so I and it also happens over
multiple Cycles so it's not just like a
one message in one message back sort of
thing like these Cycles can have
multiple signals back and forth does
that make sense yeah it does so where in
the plant are the exudates made are they
made like in in one particular exudate
Factory or is it like made all all over
the plant in in many places
I think to be honest I think it's
complicated I think that our general
understanding of where exudates are
produced is usually the root tip because
that's the growing part of the root and
it's the one that kind of has to be the
most responsive to the different things
it's encountering as it's moving through
the soil
um as far as like where on the root like
it's it's going to be on the surface
cells mostly because they're the ones
that are directly next to the
rhizosphere which makes sense but I
think a lot of different types of
molecules and signals to make those
molecules can come from all over the
plant too like different parts of the
root can ask for different things
um different parts of the shoot like the
growing part of the plant that we see
all the time
um that can also trigger different
things to be made as well
um but I think like the cells right on
the outside of the root are the most
responsive to that kind of stuff and
it's different too because above that
growing zone
um there might be there's still exits
being produced but they might be
different because there's different
needs if you're already there
um with all the different needs and all
the cacophony and how small this is I
can imagine that there are so many
exudates next to each other next to each
other next to each other that they're
nearly tripping over each other because
there's so much activity happening yeah
a little bit of a soup yeah
um so the um are the exudates like stuck
where they are and they they're only
mobile if there is water around or do
they have some kind of solution for
Mobility for themselves that that kind
of depends on the chemistry so like in
general they're going to be mostly right
next to the root and then they're just
going to kind of diffuse
um to places where there's less of them
same as like if you were to dump a bunch
of salt into the glass eventually the
salt would all dissolve into the water
but they would be most concentrated in
the bottom unless you Stir It Up so it's
kind of like that if you imagine the
bottom of the glass is like the cell so
it's being made right at the bottom
there and then kind of diffuses up and
eventually it'll get pretty far away but
but not too far
um and then it depends on the type of
molecule because
they're mostly water soluble but there
can be some that are kind of more
lipophilic or like oil loving that might
move differently they might be more
likely to stay next to the cell that's
more like that and maybe don't don't
travel as far away from the root does
that make sense yeah it does and and it
doubly makes sense because
um you know the theme of all of your
answers have been it's complex and it
depends on which one and I'm starting to
realize that you know most of most of
the generalizations that we might make
about exudates
um really don't apply to everybody like
it's hard to make generalizations about
exudates so so I guess I guess we'll
kind of like wrap up this first set with
um what is it about exudates that make
them
uh be exudates because if if they all
act in different ways and move in
different ways and signal in different
ways and do different things there's got
to be some thing that they all have in
common that makes them exudate so what
what is that
honestly it's just location
um I think is like the the biggest thing
that connects all of them because as you
say we have there's lots of different
functions for them there's lots of
different types they have lots of
different different jobs and interact
with different things but they're all
outside the root they're all made by the
plant specifically for being out in the
rhizosphere and that's the thing that
ends up connecting all of them so so the
exudates are created outside of the root
or or it's made in the root and then
it's shoved out of the root it's made in
the root and shoved out like like I was
saying earlier like those those cells
that are right on the surface of the
root they're making them inside and then
packaging them and then sending them out
into the rhizosphere that kind of
reminds me of the uh of the um
endophytic bacteria that we talked about
a couple shows back about you know the
thing that makes that makes it a
bacteria endophytic is that it spends
some amount of its life inside of the
plant and so it goes you know it'll go
in and out of the plant and so perhaps
exudates are you know things that start
in the roots and then and then they are
pushed out
that's as good a definition as any all
right great okay let's go ahead and take
a short break and be right back uh you
were listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is plant biologist Sarah
Lane and you know without these
advertisers shaping fire would not
happen so uh please support them and let
them know you heard them on shaping fire
thank you
online cannabis seed Distributors often
seem to be all the same but Multiverse
beans constantly Works to provide you
with cannabis seeds and a buying
experience that you won't find elsewhere
Multiverse beans Works directly with the
Breeders to secure as many packs of your
favorites as possible so that they have
your favorite beans long after others
have sold out some shops simply buy
breeder minimums but I get messages all
the time from breeders saying some
version of Multiverse has to buy my
entire run
at multiversebeans.com you can find rare
cannabis seeds from Night Owl seeds
including the dark owl sub label
Mephisto genetics Square One genetics
Robin Hood seeds and Ethos and so many
others
Multiverse also initiates projects with
breeders to secure exclusive packs that
you simply won't find elsewhere
Multiverse founder Paul lall sees
himself not only as a curator of the
best cannabis seeds available but also
as a collaborator with breeders trying
to bring novel crosses to the market
that his customers are asking for
Multiverse beans also creates exclusive
stickers for their popular seed
varieties that are available free only
when you order those seeds from
Multiverse
check out their stickers like the badass
recent slap for Mothman by gnome
automatics on Instagram at Multiverse
beans and finally the freebies as you'd
expect Paul sends quality freebies with
every order and when you spend at least
150 dollars Multiverse allows you to
choose your freebies from their special
selections
you can get a 10 discount off regularly
priced items when you use the discount
code shaping fire all one word at
checkout
sign up for their mailing list to be
eligible for their monthly seed giveaway
worth 250 dollars
so go to
multiversebeans.com now for a buying
experience you won't get anywhere else
[Music]
for years organic cultivators have been
looking for a peat moss replacement peat
moss has long been the go-to soil
amendment for water retention and
container growing but organic Growers
are recognizing now that peat moss is an
unsustainable resource and the mining of
peat bogs destroys Wetland habitats and
releases sequestered carbon but peat
moss works so well that many have
continued to use it now there is finally
a revolutionary replacement for peat
moss that provides better benefits while
being a sustainable choice
pit Moss sounds and acts like peat moss
but instead of being mined from fragile
ecosystems is actually made from
upcycled organic paper and cardboard
headed for landfills pit Moss is
excellent at retaining water in your
substrate and creating air pockets and
Tiny living environments for microbes
pittmoss instantly increases aeration
nutrient absorption and Water
Conservation too
carefully and locally sourced pittmoss
is the result of decades-long research
into the use of recycled paper fibers
pittmoss is lightweight and easy to use
and pit Moss is an earth so it won't
change your pH
available in a range of preparations
including a nutrient enhanced blend and
an organic soil conditioner with no
added nutrients pit Moss is also
available as an animal bedding for
horses chickens and small animals
you can save 15 percent with the
discount code shaping fire one word no
caps when shopping on pitmoss.com so go
to pittmoss.com now to learn more that's
p-i-t-t-m-o-s-s.com growing healthier
stronger more sustainable plants pit
Moss
[Music]
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by Farmers is
because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year and we know these fungal networks
are essential because they are the
nutrient super highways that extend far
and wide in the substrate to feed your
plants the trouble with growing in New
Living soils or Blended cocoa substrates
is that it takes most of the plant's
life just to create these mycelium
highways
dynomico endomycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the other popular brand in the U.S at
900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation dynomica is the
result of 30 years of research and
trials at the volcani agriculture
Research Institute in Israel it has also
been vigorously trialed by cannabis and
food Growers across the U.S
dynamico is now available at Grow shops
and on Amazon in the United States I
love using dynamico to both speed up the
growth of the mycelium networks in the
soil but also as a biostimulant to make
clone cuttings more viral you can see
side by side showing the comparative
growth on their Instagram at dynomico if
you demand reliable growing results and
appreciate the importance of an active
root Zone in creating a thriving plant I
encourage you to check out dynomico.com
and use the store locator to find out
where you can get yours that's
d-y-n-o-m-y-c-o.com
shaping fire listeners can get 10 off
any size of dynamico on Amazon or
dynamico.com by using the discount code
shapingfire one word no caps
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some Zing
to tired soil choose dynamico to
maximize your plant's potential
dynamico endomycorrhizal inoculant
welcome back you are listening to
shapingfire I am your host shangolos and
my guest today is plant biologist Sarah
Lane so during the first set we talked a
lot about kind of exudate mechanics and
and what they are so that you know we
could get an idea of you know get our
heads wrapped around this this
interesting chemical that's in the
rhizosphere and and what it does and so
on on during this set we're going to
focus more on on what they actually do
and how this I don't know
cacophony or Symphony takes place so
how specific are the signals for either
nutrition or the the signals to telling
exudates to go out in like you know mine
some manganese or something
um Are there specific exudates for all
of these processes or or is it like when
when you tell somebody hey would you
pick up bread but I don't tell them what
kind of bread I'm trying to get an idea
of how specific the the requests are
oh another theme of the day it's
complicated
um
I think that in some cases it's
extremely specific especially when we're
talking about symbol like symbiotic
relationships like rhizobium or in
legumes or mycorrhizae and that kind of
thing it's like very specific to the
point where it's species specific it's a
specific molecule that has one job and
that is to go and signal to a
mycorrhizae fungal um interactions and
things like that so it can be that
specific but there's also some that have
sort of more of a like a broad like it
has multiple different types of
chemistry
um it might be maybe a more complicated
molecule where one end does one thing
and the other end does another thing
um and sometimes the plant can make
multiple things to do the same job so
some of the the tasks that that the
exudates do especially the the ones that
are sent out for nutrition and probably
similarly the ones that are sent out for
uh like like inert things like manganese
or iron or whatever
um those jobs sound familiar or similar
to the role of mycorrhizae and and you
know we often talk on the show about how
the fungal networks are like super
highways that are that will go out and
soars these different
um nutritions that are needed by the
plant and then kind of uh bring them
back and there's there's this
relationship there I would think that
since this this task is very similar to
the exudates or at least how they're
described there's probably a lot of
exudate interaction with the fungal
network is this true
yeah I would say that's true so I think
there's like there's two components like
one the exudates can do a similar job
but on a much more
um tiny scale because they don't travel
very far and so if they need to go
farther out for the nutrients then the
exudates would interact with the
mycorrhizae directly and a lot of that
is basically initiating infection it
sounds weird to say infection when I
don't mean pathogenic but essentially
the plant has to invite the mycorrhizae
especially uh Endo mycorrhizae to infect
it and that's a very specific signal
that's sent out to interact with the
with that fungus to allow it to come and
join the plant and it has to be in a
situation where the plant would need
that so I think
like if the plant is deficient in
phosphorus for example it might interact
with mycorrhizae more whereas if it's
not that deficient or if there's plenty
of phosphorus next to the root maybe it
interacts with that less and the
exudates that it makes for itself will
do the job does that make sense yeah
that does make sense
um is it possible to like over tax the
exudate system so if the plant is
you know making these exudates and and
everything that the plant
uh does takes some amount of I don't
know energy or life force or effort
depending on what level we're looking at
um if the exudates are so busy
um Can the exit 8 speed be working so
hard that it makes the plant uh less
thriving
I think that kind of depends so I think
if the plant is unhealthy that might be
true
um we often talk about things like a
carbon budget though so there's a
certain amount of carbon that a given
amount of plant
um can fix uh and there's a given amount
of nutrients it can take up just based
on its biology and Physiology
um and so carbon budgeting depend that
that means that different parts of the
plant will be allocating carbon to
different places so if for example it's
suffering a massive thrip wave it will
be busy making carbon
containing compounds to deal with that
and it might make less exudates but if
it's perfectly healthy all things
considered it will make what it needs
um and it'll make the amount that it
needs does that make sense yeah it does
um so it
so where what I was going to ask was
that you know are there things that we
can do that would stress the exudate
process and and signaling exchange and
then you threw the thrip thing on the
end so perhaps the answer to the
question that I was going to ask is like
anything that stresses the plant is
going to call on the exudates to have to
do more work so don't stress your plant
basically yeah or it's going to divert
the resources of the plant elsewhere
um I think like there's a certain amount
we call it basil or base there's a
certain amount of like maintenance level
things that the plant makes everywhere
um but it will respond to different
stresses by taking as much carbon and
nutrients as it can to whatever that is
so if it's if it's happy and healthy
then it can like pump up those base
levels and everything's great if it's
really under stress somewhere else it
might take what it would normally make
in The Roots it might take some carbon
from that and and send it somewhere else
and that might mean that you have
there's still probably going to be some
exudates there but it'll probably mean
that there's less of them does that make
sense yeah it does and so for somebody
who's listening to what you're saying
like me and and my brain goes to
um you know what can I do to not stress
out the exudate creation like that's a
that's nice that I'm thinking about that
level of my plant but really that's
that's not really necessary I really
should go up a level of magnitude and
and think about not doing things that
stress out the plant and then just let
the exudates manage themselves
essentially yeah like I think if you
take care of your soil and you take care
of your your plant and and they're both
in good shape then you shouldn't have to
worry about it for sure okay I mean
making sure that your soil is healthy is
definitely a big part of it I'm making
sure the plant isn't you know being as I
said mulled by thrips or something like
that is also helpful I don't think
anybody wants that anyway but
um those kind of things making sure it's
getting enough water it's not over
watered
um you know all those all those things
that we generally try and make sure our
plants have anyway if your plant is
healthy there's not really anything
extra that you need to do
um I think we we've I think compost teas
are one thing that you can do to kind of
help with soil life and things like that
um and that might help with the exudate
situation but most of the time it's
really out of your control
well it's kind of nice to have something
that you know we're learning about this
process but it isn't another thing that
we have to like technically worry about
right if you do your if you do your
regular
um
your regular living soil kind of stuff
like like this will take care of itself
which is great because we already have
enough to worry about right yep um we'll
talk more about uh compost tea a little
bit later but I want to wade into
um a uh a pretty Fierce debate in the
Cannabis world and um and I'm a pretty
heavy participant in it and I have been
looking for someone like you to weigh in
on it so so I'm going to pull you into
this debate and this is on 24-hour light
cycle
so the the the debate is generally about
um does the 24 hour light cycle is it
best for the plant or does it uh starve
the the soil from nutrients and the idea
kind of goes like this
um uh some Growers like to use 24 hours
light because it causes the plant to
grow more quickly and you can either
grow a bigger higher higher yielding
plant
um during that time or during you know
its regular life cycle
um because
um
um you know because it's just getting
more light
um or you can actually shorten the cycle
by using more light which you know
allows you to perhaps get in another
growing cycle over the year and so a lot
of people use 24 hours of light now the
flip of it which happens to be where I
stand is that no 24 hours of of of light
indoors is not going to create the best
plant because while it makes it grow
faster
um you're not allowing the back and
forth of the the the light phase and the
dark phase both both phases are
necessary so that the the the the
exudates and the signaling and all the
processes that happen when the the plant
is awake with the light it needs to have
some dark times so the contrasting uh
signaling and exudates can happen so you
you need both so all varieties of
exudate signaling can happen and and all
of the varieties of of nutrition and and
those things can go back and forth so I
have a feeling that the the answer is is
probably somewhere in the middle
um but specifically to this 24 hours of
light question how does 24 hours of
light impact this relationship between
the plant and the rhizosphere as far as
the exudates playing a role
oof that is a spicy debate isn't it yeah
um I think again to the theme of the day
it's complicated
um I have not ever seen anybody be able
to because of the complexity of the
rhizosphere and all the stuff that's
going on there I haven't seen anybody
actually be able to put this into a
scientific study where we're able to say
definitively if you give a plant 24
hours of light the eggs dates suffer
um so it's really in the middle I think
um there's a couple different things
that I can think of off the top of my
head if if it's okay if I ramble for a
second no please no we want to get into
this so go ahead perfect okay so light
cycles
um light cycles I think lots of things
are turned on by the plant rather than
off when light is on and that's because
light is driving water transport and
nutrient uptake and it's also driving
photosynthesis so I think that too much
dark is as bad as too much light light
is if that makes sense
like you're seeing the growth and the
yield increase because the plant is
doing a lot of stuff during that time
and there is a circadian clock in Plants
where there are different things that
happen in the daytime and in the night
time and they actually are different for
the root part and the shoot part so they
actually operate on different clocks but
they do talk to each other so
um I guess where I'm going with this is
is that
there is a circadian rhythm but we don't
know enough about it to be able to say
that that having light on the top of the
plant
is going to affect the roots in the way
that I think this debate kind of goes
um because if you think about it the
roots are always in the dark they're
never in the light they're not like
there might be a small amount of light
that makes it to the to the root but not
enough that it should matter but they
can still sense it a little bit
um
man that is that is a very so but but
yeah it is and and so when if if the
maybe I'm thinking too top down about
this because even though the light
doesn't specifically reach their Roots
right during the light mode the plant
I'm I'm I think of it as the plant is
giving commands through the roots and so
even though the roots aren't
um lit up the roots are responding to
needs and commands from a plant that is
actively
photosynthesizing and then then in the
dark cycle those those commands and
needs of the photosynthesis are no
longer taking place and so I imagine
that the the roles and the tasks of of
the root zone change when the plant is
is is changing modes from
photosynthesizing to you know the the
processing of nutrients that it does
during the dark
exactly I think that's and I think the
key word there is change because if they
take up a bunch of nutrients during the
the daytime then a lot of those exudates
that are helping with nutrient
acquisition should be active like
they're they're actively like you know
fishing out the different components
that it needs and putting it into the
plant so the plant can continue to grow
and those would change if the light is
gone and they do have like we even know
from like but you know those green
potatoes like Roots themselves can sense
light
um both outside like sources of light
but also the inside sources that we were
just talking about like the light like
the light that the plant above is
sensing is also like notified they
notify the roots that they need stuff
right
um I think this is I think this next
question is is is the is the seal the
deal question that I've been looking for
so
so if the if the root zone is doing
different tasks
when the plant is experiencing light
because the plant is asking for things
involved with you know photosynthesis
production during the day those types of
tasks and then and then when the light
is gone the root zone changes to
different sets of tasks
that would seem to suggest to me that it
needs a dark period so those dark period
tasks can happen so maybe maybe I'm
right but for the wrong reason for for a
reason I didn't realize I thought that
during the dark the exudates would stop
and maybe that's not it because exudates
happen around the clock maybe it's that
the exudate and signaling that happens
when the plant above is experiencing
dark those differentiated tasks need to
have an opportunity to happen too to
have a thriving plan yeah yeah I think
that could be a reasonable way to go
about it I think that there's also two
things I guess there is dark reactions
and they're like evening onset
um types of of things that change in the
plant that are responding to a lessening
of light at least when we're not talking
about like growing light when we have
actually like changes in light over the
daytime as well
um you know you're plant on the balcony
or whatever
um but there's also light independent
reactions that tend to happen kind of
at any time and what I mean by that is
like photosynthesis is light driven like
you absolutely have to have light for
that whole series of of chemistry
reactions to happen
um whereas the like other types of
reactions don't need light like that so
they might be happening 24 7. what I
really think for my own personal opinion
definitely an opinion um is that uh a
little bit of Darkness helps because one
thing that light is is a stressor it
creates all these like Fast happening
reactions it's quite powerful it can
make really reactive molecules that if
they're present in too much they can
damage the plant
um and those kind of things so I think
having 24 hours of light constantly
would yeah maybe mean that you don't
have the down time that you need to take
care of any kind of damage that's coming
from light and that kind of stuff so for
I guess my my weigh-in on this would be
like a little bit of dark is helpful I
think does that make sense yeah it does
and I'm grateful to hear it
um so um this idea that there can be too
much light
um is is interesting because you know
most of us or folks who grow indoors
anyway
um you know while I've been historically
an outdoor grower I've been I've been
dabbling in indoor just to learn new
stuff and
most of the time
cultivators are looking to blast the
plants with as much light as is possible
without bleaching or burning the plant
and what I'm hearing from you is that
there really is a a top end of how much
light we necessarily want to give the
plant
um because there is there is too much
there's a there's a top level
yes there is um I think especially
especially most of my experiences is
growing inside and I think there's
different things to think about because
you can definitely have too much light
inside but it's not like an overall
amount of light there's all these focal
lengths that come with bulbs and it kind
of it's like shining a laser you know
the magnifying glass on the you know
something flammable and in the sun kind
of thing like it focuses all the light
from the bulb to a single point and if
you're growing in that point it's really
strong but like just for that little
area and that's too much light but
there's so much sun out there I don't
think any indoor bulb at this point has
ever gotten to the point where it can
compete with the sun um it's just too
dim the Spectrum isn't strong enough and
a lot of the damaging wavelengths that
we think of with light like UV b or c
are just not present in the same
quantity unless it's like you know a UVC
light or something like that does that
make sense yeah another there's too much
Point light and then there's too much
General light yeah I was making an over
generalization about the too much like
as if it was all sunlight but that's
that's true like all you know no matter
what kind of bulb uh we are talking
about
um it is it is some degree Less Than
Sunshine and so that's probably those
those that gap between sunshine and
whatever the personality of the bulb is
that's probably where the hitch and the
Giddy Up Is Right is is somewhere in
what the bulb is lacking when compared
to the Sun yeah so I think in indoors
like most of the light stress that I've
seen is like you turn the lights on
right after you spray something on the
planets and you get some like lens
burning where the lights just kind of
magnified and focused at a point so you
get like little Point Burns outside you
can definitely see a lot more types of
light damage and stress because it's so
bright right out and if it's hot too
like the plant just has a really hard
time managing that level of light in in
that those poor little photosystems get
a little stressed
when when we talked on the phone the
other day kind of preparing for this
discussion
um you used a term that I I really liked
and I don't know if it's if it's it's a
scientific term or if it's just
something that you were using to
describe to me because you you've you
used such fantastic examples but you use
this phrase a free living microbes and
and I remember talking to you I remember
like oh wow I never I never really
thought about microbes that were in the
soil but weren't really interacting with
the plant would you just talk about
pre-living microbes for a moment
absolutely so essentially when we think
about ecology and like what's happening
in the in the soil there's we definitely
talk a lot about microbes that interact
with the plant but there's a couple
different levels they can do that
there's symbiosis where they need each
other and then there's kind of like
opportunistic sort of interactions where
they don't so when I talk about Free
Living microbes um we generally use that
term to mean things that kind of that
are just they're in the soil too they
don't have to be next to a plant they
don't like if you remove the plant they
go on living they they do their thing
and and they they it's not the same and
if anything like maybe the plant needs
them more than they need it if that
makes sense but if they're free living
they they can complete their entire life
cycle
um without a plant if that makes sense
so so that also brings up an interesting
question about the opposite so so you
said oh there are some of these microbes
that that wouldn't exist without the
plant
um is is this one of the reasons why it
is it is so helpful to the cannabis
plant to have
other companion plants around because uh
these these other plants are are helping
support these these uh Free Living
microbes and it just makes the entire
rhizosphere more complex and more
thriving and more abundant
oh I'm sure that's true yeah because
like
cover plants for example essentially
what they're trying to do is is improve
the soil life and that happens either
through like providing a matrix like all
those roots provide basically housing in
a lot of ways like a little scaffold for
different things to live on and in and
under
um but it also might help with for
example maintaining humidity longer
um so that if there's microbes in the
soil that prefer to be wet all the time
and they don't like drying out then you
might have that layer is is happier
because there's a plant there keeping
the moisture locked in
um maybe they don't like a lot of light
and they're kind of shading the surface
of the soil a little bit so maybe the
fungus can get a little bit more close
to the surface or something like that
like I'm sure there's dozens of
different things that a companion plant
and we also plant like I personally
plant a clover because it tends to also
it has an interesting relationship with
bacteria that actually lets it take on
and fix more nitrogen than a lot of
other plants do but it also brings the
benefit of having that nitrogen fixing
relationship with these bacteria that
also benefit plants around it so the the
cannabis plant itself doesn't do this
but the fact that there's a plant near
it that does improves the Nutri
nutrients in the soil one of my favorite
reasons and and the first reason I
started companion planting
um uh for my cannabis is I had it
earlier in in my cultivation history I
had a tendency to water incorrectly I
was doing uh too much not often enough
so I needed to water less more often but
less and I had a tendency to get
hydrophobic soil and and for folks who
aren't familiar with that that means
that the the top of your soil container
gets kind of hard and then when you go
and you you hand water the water just
kind of slides off and and goes down the
side instead of actually soaking into
the soil and this happened to me all the
time and I eventually learned during the
shaping fire water and watering episode
that if you use a a companion plant or
in this case what we would consider a a
cover crop with that has lots of roots
say for example a clover or or you know
some types of grasses
um they not only can provide like the
the the the the the canopy if you will
to create this little moisture Vapor
area between the tops of its leaves and
the soil so the soil just generally
stays more moist but also I was going
for the fact that all these roots that
go down in the soil all are providing
like small Tunnels for the water to
actually go into the soil itself and you
know I actually solved my poor watering
just by adding
um a a multiple root
uh planned and then that that problem
just went away
yep that's and and the other wonderful
thing that you're doing is you're also
introducing different types of exudates
which improves your your soil life
um so then you're just getting it's just
more all the way around uh so so are
there are we aware of any
um you know either either companion
plants in in cannabis of course we use
these we use the idea of companion
plants to often be the idea of like a
bigger plant that's we're planting
nearby like a you know like a like a
cabbage or potatoes underneath it or
whatever and then and then we kind of
use the term cover crop even though we
most of us in cannabis use that term not
how it's traditionally used to talk
about
um lower plants that there's a lot of
them
um I'm kind of backing into this
question but what I want to ask you is
um are there plants that you are aware
of that share
um exudate flavors complementary exudate
flavors with cannabis plants that we
should grow about can around our
cannabis plants simply because they
increase the vibrancy of the kinds of
nutrition our cannabis plant is going to
want thus suggesting oh you should grow
these plants because it too will attract
the kinds of nutrition and and make it
more buffet style for your cannabis
plant
oh I think
scientific realm like even just to
identify exudates is super challenging
because you can't you can't even grow
them in soil to be able to collect them
so all of my experiments for example are
done in a fogponic setup that I made um
so that I can actually access the roots
without the soil because of course
otherwise you capture all the eggs dates
from all the bacteria too
so I don't think that we could get that
that specific but I do know that they've
been doing a lot of interesting research
with
um with crops and companion plants and
crops and the running theme there is
usually
um something that fixes nitrogen really
helps because it brings in not only the
the nitrogen fixing aspect which is
usually the limiting factor in plant
growth
um but it also brings all of its its
symbiotic bacteria with it
but I think as long as you as long as
you have a cover crop as as we were just
talking about that's improving your soil
texture or soil Health in general I
think that you're good and so for me
like the the anecdotal answer would be
something like we plant
Clover partly for the nitrogen fixing
but we also plant things like basil or
marigolds that can act like trap plants
to kind of give us a sense of of whether
or not we have test things to worry
about
um and that kind of thing or anything
that helps like pollinators come in and
that kind of thing because that usually
I don't know more life is better usually
does that make sense yeah I follow that
you know this the example that you gave
um I had not really considered how
difficult your research must be because
I figured there was just some way for
you to you know grab the exudates you
know scrape them off scrape pull up a
plant and scrape some off the The Roots
You know that were in soil but but but
that's right there's all everybody else
who's in there too especially the
bacteria they're all laying out exudates
too and so it's just like a mess and you
can't tease them out and so you're using
this fogponic system so the so the roots
are just dangling and there's not soil
life interacting with it so in an odd
way you're you're like an exudate
Rancher like you've got to you've gotta
you've got to do this [__] pond so that
you can collect them first yep that's
correct yeah we have a couple other ways
but they're all like really they're all
complicated
um you can do sterile culture like um
tissue culture
um but then the necessity of that is you
have to have a plant that can you can
grow in tissue culture and if I was
working with with um cannabis I think it
would be easier because it it does grow
in tissue culture uh which would be nice
and then you can just sample the media
and and extract the meat that exudates
from the media but there's lots and lots
of plants out there that don't like to
culture that won't grow in a little tiny
box or or trees some which I'm working
with right now that that just defy defy
hydroponics in general so yeah you got
to get clever about it for sure and it
is very much like ranching
right on all right cool
um so let's go ahead and take our second
break uh during the third set stick with
us because we're going to be talking
about
um uh salt-based nutrients and exudates
hydroponics and exudates and unsaltured
molasses in and exudate so come on back
um you are listening to shaving fire and
my guest today is plant biologist Sarah
Lane
[Music]
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated it is increasingly important to
avoid the use of chemical pesticides
when cultivating cannabis beneficial
insects have been used for decades by
the greenhouse vegetable and ornamental
plant industry and today many cannabis
cultivators are moving from sprays and
chemicals to beneficial insects
copert has the beneficial insects mites
and nematodes microbials sticky cards
and air distribution units you need to
partner with nature to defend your
garden
whether you manage Acres of canopy or
have a simple grow tent in your home
culprit is ready to help answer your
questions and help you transition away
from chemical sprays towards clean and
natural solutions
since 1967 culprit has assisted growers
in identifying pests and devising
reliable Solutions while providing
healthy insects and mites that will
protect your yield
since the 1990s covert has been a leader
in cannabis Pest and Disease Control
worldwide and have highly trained
Consultants to assist you in Canada and
the United States from coast to coast
with their Global Network of grower
support covert can help visit copper.com
choose your country and get detailed
information that's covert
k-o-p-p-e-r-t.com for the most
up-to-date cannabis related biological
control information you can also check
their Instagram at covert Canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and culprit is ready to help visit
coppert.com today
[Music]
once you've discovered the benefits of
using cannabis it's a very small step to
start making your own Edibles gummies
lotions tinctures and concentrated oils
at home
magical butter has been helping cannabis
consumers become self-sufficient for
over a decade with the easy to use
magical butter countertop Botanical
extractor you can create high quality
cannabis products to your exact
specifications at a fraction of the cost
of store-bought edibles
I talk a lot on this show about the
importance of Home growing so you don't
have to rely on others to feel healthy
well the magical butter machine can
Empower your personal health by putting
you in control of how you use cannabis
in your daily life
I've been making my own Butters and oils
on the stove for years and I much prefer
the ease of using the magical butter
machine I just set it and walk away with
the Simple Touch of a button the magical
butter machine grinds Heats stirs and
Steeps your herbal extract all at the
correct time interval and temperature
for the perfect infusion every time as a
result you achieve your desired infusion
easily safely and consistently check out
the magical butter Instagram to see the
machine in action and don't feel like
you have to go It Alone there is a huge
community on Facebook called magical
butter users United sharing recipes and
best practices so you can learn at your
own pace from others who are already
doing it successfully now is the time to
get your own magical butter machine and
save money while enjoying cannabis use
the discount code shapingfire one word
no caps to get 10 off visit
magicalbutter.com today
[Music]
after you've caught up on the latest
shaping fire episodes do you sometimes
wish there was more cannabis education
available to learn well we got you
shaping fire has a fabulous YouTube
channel with content not found on the
podcast when I attend conventions to
speak or moderate panels I always record
them and bring the content home for you
to watch the shangolos YouTube channel
has world-class speakers including Zoe
sigmund's lecture understanding your
endocannabinoid system Kevin Jody of
Wonderland Nursery talking about
breeding cannabis for the best terpene
profile Frenchy cannolis Lost Art of the
hashishan presentation Nicholas Mahmoud
on regenerative and polyculture cannabis
growing Dr Sunil Agarwal in the history
of cannabis medicine Around the World
Eric vlosky and Josh Rutherford on
solventless extraction and Jeff lone
Fells on the soil food web there are
several presentations from Dr Ethan
Russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system too while there
be sure to check out the three 10-part
shaping fire session series one with
Kevin jodry one with Dr Ethan Russo and
one with Jeff lowenfels and even my own
presentations on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose Canada's business even though the
risks are so high as of today there's
over 200 videos that you can check out
for free so go to youtube.com forward
slash shangolos or click on the link in
the newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shapingfire and I am your
host shangelos and my guest today is
plant biologist Sarah Lane
so let's talk about a couple of the
applications of of exudates
um with with common situations that we
deal with as cannabis cultivators and um
the first one I want to talk about with
you Sarah is is salt-based nutrients so
you know on this show we we generally
not generally we very specifically
support living soil
um you know a biomimicry of of you know
the natural world and um are not big
fans of salt-based nutrients generally
but you know I always know I need to
give them a fair shake when it comes to
science because that's that's really
what we're listening to is the science
not my own biases so
um I'm curious to know what kind of a
relationship that that using you know
bottled salt-based nutrients has on the
exudates
um and then their ability to communicate
and the and the community I guess
I think that's
um I think most of the time when we're
talking salt based nutrients like it
doesn't really go very well in living
soil which is my preferred method of
growing too so
um we're on the same page there I think
um with salt-based nutrients there's
sort of two things that happen one is um
like we were talking about earlier it
can really disrupt the signaling
um or at least that's my my theory
because you're introducing a huge amount
of nutrients to the plant
um that it would have been making all
these wonderful little eggs dates to try
and tease out from as we were saying
earlier microbes or or the soil itself
and you're just flooding it so I think
that it would pretty significantly
disrupt the eggs date type at least of
what's being produced
um the other thing it does is it really
kind of messes around with the chemistry
of the soil so um like if you're only
feeding salt-based nutrients you end up
with salt buildup and stuff like that
and that can happen in a living soil
system too and usually those conditions
aren't really conducive to of microbial
life or root health and you end up just
getting a lot of compounding problems
um so so it's it's less about
um the salt-based nutrients somehow
masking the the chemical signatures or
anything that it's just that
um the the people who are normally uh
giving off the exudates and receiving
the exudates they're generally just not
there
yeah like I think I think the plant if
if it's got all the nutrients it needs
it's going to put its resources
elsewhere and um and I think if you're
compromising the soil life at all then a
lot of that signaling would would be as
as we were saying earlier probably
dampened would be my guess dampen that's
a good word yeah
um you know a lot of the um you know a
lot of people are playing with soilless
mediums that are increasingly more and
more uh uh you know cocoa based Coco
coir to the point that some folks are
just like like they don't have soil in
their substrate right it's it's not
really hydroponic it's but it's just uh
it's it's cocoa and it's nutrients and
um I'm curious if these these types of
cocoa and soilless mediums have any
impact on the on the signaling capacity
of these exudates
um I guess what I'm asking is is the is
the soil component
um key to the ability of the exudates to
be able to do their job
the previous question was there are
circumstances so I think the real
problem I have with sulfate nutrients is
if it's in combination with living soil
because they're in living soil you're
relying on this microbial life to help
provide nutrients and it just gets all
out of whack but like for example in my
research I have to use salt-based
nutrients because I need a very defined
set of nutrients that um to be able to
repeat my experiments
um and in that case with the fog ponics
and that kind of thing it's it's not
necessarily like the exudates are going
away it's just that the types of
exudates that I'm looking at are
nutrient based and not microbial based
so I don't notice a difference and in
that case I think in cocoa or peat or
something like that as long as you're
not relying on the bacteria that or or
fungus that are present to assist you in
the nutrients it wouldn't make as much
of a difference I I think it would
change the expression of the exudates
though like the types of exudates that
are produced would be different does
that make sense yeah because you're
still going to be producing them and
it's really interesting for you as a
living soil cultivator at home but
needing to use salts in the lab
it puts you in a unique position to be
you know comparing and contrasting them
let's talk about like if if you're using
a if you're using salt fertilizers in a
you know in a soilless medium like cocoa
and you just said that if you were in
that kind of environment it wouldn't
that the exudates wouldn't be there it
would be that there would be nutrition
based exudates
um you would just be changing the
variety of exudates that are there that
are being expressed my question would be
would that impact how the plant
expresses itself it seemed to me that if
we are are changing the exudates that
are you know part of the cacophony in
the soil that we're going to get you
know uh different colors on the plant
different terpene profile maybe a
difference in quality of thriving it
seems like the plant would Express
itself at the top level is there is
there any weight to that
yeah I think so I think like if we were
to go back to our bizarre metaphor from
earlier when you when you feed
salt-based nutrients it's kind of like
putting in a really big box store or
something like that it really changes
the flavor of what's happening in that
location and I think that changes the
personality of of the soil and I think
like to borrow a I don't know
personifying my soil now but you know
like the like the the conversations that
are happening
um and the types of players that are
there changes pretty significantly and I
don't doubt that that would also change
the the plant itself the plant is very
flexible it's going to do its best to
grow and to thrive in whatever
circumstances that you put it in but
when you change those circumstances it's
going to change itself to fit and so um
and and I know lots of people that
anecdotally say that terpenes are
different and and like cannabinoid
profiles are different when you grow in
living soil and stuff like that whereas
like when you're feeding salt based
maybe you're going for weight and the
plant is forced into putting more weight
on because it's got all those extra
nutrients and maybe it makes less and I
don't know that for sure because I
haven't studied it myself but I think
that anecdotally I've seen that happen
right on so so even even though you
haven't seen the science for it it makes
it makes intuitive sense if
it's complex it's it's kind of a fun way
to think about ecology too in in a pot
you know
um but it the plant is really able to
pick and choose a little better than
kind of I don't know for speeding at
Salt if that makes sense yeah for sure
and we talk a lot on on shaping fire
about the importance of you know a a
complex and thriving rhizosphere to have
a complex and thriving plant so that you
have a complex and delightful terpene
profile and and the more you're
simplifying what is in
um the pot say for example using a cocoa
soilless medium and salt-based nutrients
um I think the example you used was just
putting them in a big box store so
you're going to get big box Terps out of
it and not necessarily the a full range
perhaps yeah I think that's totally
reasonable and again like this also ties
into carbon budget because when you're
when you're forcing a plant to grow in a
specific way you're also asking it to
allocate all its resources in that
direction too which generally means it
has less for other stuff which maybe is
stuff that we want like terpenes right
on
um uh let's talk a little bit about
um I think what I think I can probably
group Hydroponics and fog ponics
together but if not tease them back
apart for me
um I'm curious because uh you know we've
we've talked significantly on this show
about the soil food web and then
somewhat about the water food web and a
Hydroponics solution and a I'm assuming
a fog solution we're talking about the
water food web and
um I'm wondering if there
the quality and number and variety of
the exudates that are in those systems
sound like there's going to be less
since you initiated this by saying oh I
use I use a fog ponics because we're
trying to
Ranch these particular exudates and in
soil there's just too many so I'm
assuming that in Hydroponics and in in
in fog ponics that there are going to be
less exudates based on what you had said
earlier and so with Hydroponics with
this same idea
um crossover from the soilless mediums
that that there may be reasons you want
to use Hydroponics but in the end there
are going to be less varieties of
exudates and you know signaling
conversation taking uh uh take you know
going on and nutrition so you would run
into the same problem with hydroponic
systems that you're
not aggressively
um supplementing I guess so yeah yeah I
think that's fair I mean for me the the
difference between fog ponics and
hydroponics just quickly would be just
like the um
I don't know dryness if that makes sense
because uh the fog ponics is even though
it's nutrients it's very dry like the
roots aren't sitting in water they're
not um they're not like soggy so
anything that's really intolerant of
flooding
um I've been able to grow more
successfully in thought ponics as
opposed to Hydroponics where a lot of
Hydroponics your plants are really
sitting in water or constantly sprayed
by water or a lot of stuff like that but
it's a really subtle difference I think
because the nutrient solution I use for
both um is the same
um so as far as like it Compares pretty
well to soilless I think the biggest
difference at least for me wouldn't
necessarily be in exudates it would be
more in like root architecture because
um the plants in a in a like peat or
cocoa it's it's more like soil for like
how they can grow but on the exudate
level I think that the same is probably
true there's going to be a more defined
set of exudates they're probably coming
mostly from the plant and you you miss
out on some of those interactions with
bacteria and fungus and stuff like that
and there's still maybe some that can
grow in those kind of conditions but a
lot less than would be growing in soil
at least as far as I can tell right on
um I also want to add a little something
for all my Hydroponics people who are
listening who are now like pissed at me
because I'm I'm I'm underselling their
craft I want to be clear that I do
understand that that some Hydroponics
um there's a lot of varieties of
Hydroponics I mean we had we did a
really great soil food web show a couple
years ago with Steve Reisner and and you
know he does that you know first of all
he is heavy into uh bringing in uh you
know water with uh with malm and fish
poop in it so there's a lot of
complexity there and um and and he was
describing you know the the great
flowers that he pulls from his setup but
but he also has some soil in the mix
right so he's he's like flooding and
draining the soil and he's got the fish
pooping so he's making this like
incredibly biologically active
environment that makes you know flowers
with terpene profiles that um that he
says we we don't even get in in a
straight soil medium so I want to be
clear when when I'm talking about the
limitations of Hydroponics I'm talking
about you know the kinds of stuff that
people are generally either doing you
know in their in you know in the extra
room in their house or at you know wild
scale of corporate cannabis I absolutely
appreciate the fact that there are
really tasty ways to do complex Plex
hydroponic so
makes sense and I would like to add
there that like each of these growing
methods has its place and the plant will
grow regardless
um and so I I know I've had some really
good hydroponic weed before I know that
I've had some really good living soil
weed like they they all have they all
have their way of doing things and I
also think that there's ways to make
Hydroponics more accessible to bacterial
life and like you were just saying with
a different terpene profile that you
don't get with either of the other two
and that just kind of goes to prove the
point that what you're putting on your
roots does change and and same with the
type of life that you're growing changes
what the plant is able to do and
sometimes that's for the better
depending on which method you're using
so definitely like whatever you're
growing your plant in is better than not
growing your plant at all yeah there you
go and you know that's one of the
challenges that we ran into
um during these like 24 hours of Lights
debate people are like I grow a huge ass
plant that was absolutely beautiful and
totally got me high and and and every
all my friends bought it from me and
that was great and they're all like why
are you telling me that I shouldn't be
using 24 hours and and and my response
is always it's it's not that I'm saying
that you can't grow plants and that your
plants are going to suck if you if you
do you go 24 hours I'm saying that
you're probably leaving some quality on
the table
um by doing it 24 hours and your terpene
profile could be better and the plants
could be better and you could be more
more pest resistant if you just uh gave
it four hours of of sleep or six hours
of sleep it would be helpful
um but you know internet debates are
rarely that nuanced you know oh it's so
true and I I do think that like even it
doesn't really at the end of the day
matter if you're growing a plant that
suits your tastes like however you're
doing it is great I mean unless you're
dumping like illegal pesticides on it or
something like that maybe maybe don't do
that but you know like I think at the
end of the day everybody's gonna have a
way of growing that works for them and
there's absolutely these debates are all
like try trying to tease out the the
finer ways of growing and like the best
way to grow and that's going to be very
much personal preference at the end of
the day and I personally prefer the
taste of living soil weed but I've had
really good weed that's been grown in
every other condition you can imagine so
I'm you know yeah here as long as you're
growing a plant it's fine yeah I'm with
you there and and it also gets me when
when people are demanding that you know
their their recipe of how they grow is
is the best and one and only and I'm
like that's that that shouldn't even be
coming out of a out of a cannabis
cultivator's mouth you know it really
depends on what your particular needs
are and your resources and your location
and you know I would I would love to
grow differently than I do but I also
don't live in California you know no
totally fair yeah which which pushes me
towards things like short flowering
thing and autoflowers right
um you know if I lived in California I
would probably still be focusing on my
own cultivation on photos so all right
so the next thing I want to talk about
is
um is unsolver molasses so it is it is a
pretty common in
um in living soil for for folks to
um think that they can make up for not
giving
I guess I'll call it like whole
nutrition like whole amendments like um
let's say like um like like fish meal
and and crab shell and
um maybe alfalfa meal all of these
amendments that we love to use in living
soil
um to have an abundant variety of
nutrients there for the uh the I guess
the exudate processors to chew through
and then give to the plant so and and so
the exudates come back and then they
feed the microbes and this is beautiful
relationship and it is not uncommon for
people to say well you know I don't I
don't need to do all of that to take
care of my microbes because
I just I just feed the microbes with
unsulfured molasses and and you know
that that pains me because
um I I have a gut feeling that just
pouring sugar into the soil
um is not a great idea and and and
molasses is kind of unidimensional
whereas microbe life is so uh so vastly
complex and I get where they're coming
from right because when we are brewing a
compost tea we will often add a bit of
unsulfured molasses to that so that the
um the microbes have have something to
eat so that we can incubate them and I
have a whole bunch of them in a small
place that we can then pour onto our
plants so so I get where they got the
idea but I think that is a
misapplication of the understanding of
what effect molasses has on the microbe
life in the rise those here so so as
somebody who who has an intimate
relationship with exudates what are your
thoughts on and adding unsulfured
molasses directly into the substrate as
part of some sort of nutritive root
drench
I am going to go back to the theme of
the day which is it's complicated and it
depends I think
um I think that if you are trying to
recover your soil life just with
molasses that it really depends on the
health of the soil that you're adding it
to because that molasses just like it
does in compost tea is does have sugar
in it I'm sure things will like to eat
what's there and grow but that means
that anything in your soil you're adding
it to is going to grow too so if you've
got some nasty you know anaerobic
bacteria in in your soil already like
that's going to love it as much as the
next thing does
um and the other thing is like a lot of
the Amendments we add
um provide different
um
I don't know different opportunities for
different types of microbes to come in
so if you're only feeding molasses and
that's how you're getting your microbial
life like it might get there eventually
but it's also going to be the microbes
that specifically like molasses and
you'll miss out maybe on some of the the
kelp or the crab meal type and again
this is all kind of conjecture because
truthfully the science isn't there to to
be able to specifically identify each
different bacteria that come with each
of these but
um that's that's what my gut feeling
would be
um if you're already if your health of
your soil is really good and you're
already adding compost teas and things
like that if you're diluting a little
bit of molasses in water I don't I don't
think it's it's harmful
um but again like I do think that the
biggest Factor on whether that's a good
idea or bad is probably the health of
your soil to begin with does that make
sense yeah it does so um you know is
there anything that we can do to
encourage healthy exudate creation by
the cannabis plant I mean we've talked
we've talked a bit about like just
generally keep your soil healthy got it
but is there anything that we can do
like a uh is there is there any kind of
uh uh a a a a a a fermented plant juice
or a supplement or or in anything that
we could do to encourage exudate
creation because they really do seem to
be a um a baseline to a thriving plant
where
um if if you've got poor exudate
activity everything that happens more
complex than that is going to be limited
by the the sad exudate system so is
there anything that we can do that's
pro-exudate that that we should consider
oh that is a good question
um I mean I think
the best answer is probably no and yes
um no there isn't a magical thing that
as much as it would be nice to just like
promote root health and the healthiest
Roots you've ever seen just like Sprout
out of the
um out of the soil and you're good to go
um because really it actually ends up
being about root health
um and that's where the yes part comes
in because you can support root health
by um like the type like you were
talking about earlier proper watering
technique
um where you're making sure the roots
aren't like super dry and they're not
super wet or anything like that you can
promote root health with soil texture
you can add these compost teas and
things like that like we've been talking
about to promote the type of microbes
that you want to be there
um you can give them lots of space to
grow obviously more Roots equals more
exudates so if you have a nice big root
ball I'm a big fan of big root balls
though because it's my thing so
um that that's probably what I would say
is like good good root health and so
um yeah I think that's that but I mean
again it's so hard to say how to get
good root health and it's sort of trial
and error So philosophically speaking
these kind of conversations help too
because you'll find people all over the
place that have different ways of making
sure they have healthy roots and maybe
one of those ends up working for your
particular strain or type of plant no
surprise that you're a big fan of root
balls being up there in BC the land of
Natasha Riz who's been on the show
talking about root balls as well
my Canadian friends all love the the
love the Cannabis root ball and Roots
equals good plan totally it's so nice to
come to an end of an episode without
anything new we have to do you know
usually when we go through these
episodes at the end there's like okay I
need I need to learn about this and I
need to start adding this and I need to
learn how to start you know making this
Korean natural farming prep but really
at the end of the story we've learned a
whole ton about exudates today so so a
we stop repeating Bro Science and B we
have like a more intimate relationship
with an understanding of the biology of
our plant but really if if you're
already
studying living soil and trying to have
a healthy soil like the exodies will
take care of themselves and it's it's so
delightful to just be able to get new
understanding without new tasks
it's true root health is just you know
what just keep doing what you're doing
and grow the healthiest plants that you
can and uh and the plant is very good at
taking care of itself so if you give it
the opportunity to then you won't have
to worry about it fabulous well Sarah
thank you so much for sharing your time
and and expertise with us today on
shaping fire you know I mentioned this
in the introduction to the show that um
you know you really do have a a rare
specialty and to find somebody who is
you know doing this at the at the PHD
research level and also is a home
cannabis cultivator makes you
exceptionally unique to be able to
bridge between the academic science side
of exudates and our beloved cannabis
plant and so thank you for you know
taking two hours and sharing it with us
so that uh that we can all become more
familiar with exudates it's been
absolutely my pleasure pleasure thank
you so much for having me fabulous so if
you want to keep up with Sarah Lane the
best place to do that is uh through her
Twitter and her Twitter account is
exudetrudely so that's exu
[Music]
d-e-t-t-e-r-o-o-t-l-y so that is a great
place to keep up on her research and her
interests if you happen to have a like a
more of an elaborate question or comment
perhaps than a you know a Twitter
account will allow
um she also uh invites you to send an
email if you'd like and that is s lane
s-l-a-n-e at
uvic.ca so that's u v i c dot c a
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast And subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts if you enjoyed the
show we'd really appreciate it if you
would leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your view
will help others find the show so they
can enjoy it too on the shapingfire
website you can also subscribe to the
newsletter for insights into the latest
Cannabis News exclusive videos and
giveaways on the shipping fire website
you also find transcripts of today's
podcast as well be sure to follow on
Instagram for all original content not
found on the podcast that's at
shapingfire and at shangolos on
Instagram be sure to check out
shapingfire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shapingfire I've been
your host shangolos
[Music]
thank you