[Music]
if you listen the shaping fire show
pretty often chances are that you're at
least somewhat familiar with the soil
food web that is the term I use pretty
universally to describe the transfer of
energy between species in the ecosystem
of soil we're talking about all the
plants bacteria fungi microbes protozoa
and nematodes and arthropods and then
birds and other animals they exist from
the tiny guys deep in the soil all the
way up to where the soil stops and our
feet start those of us who study and
create living soil have become pretty
familiar with the soil food web by
learning from thought leaders like dr.
Elaine Ingham and Jeff Lowen Fels and
other folks it's actually one of my
favorite things doesn't even think about
imagine my astonishment when I learned
that there was another food web
mirroring the one that we have for soil
but taking place in water of course in
retrospect that there would be a water
food web is pretty obvious but I had
never given it much thought and the idea
that there was a twin to my favorite
topic of living soil made me very very
happy the water food web consists of
phytoplankton algae zooplankton small
fish crustaceans and all the way up to
bigger fish and corals and eventually
whales
the water food web describes how all of
these life forms exchange energy and
compete and form a complex web similar
in many ways the ones that we know for
living soil and it's totally badass if
you want to learn about cannabis health
business and technique efficiently and
with good cheer I encourage you to
subscribe to our newsletter we'll send
you a new podcast episode as it comes
out delivered right to your inbox along
with commentary and a couple of the most
important news items for the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter this is the last week to
sign up for the newsletter to win one of
the five prize packs of the Nuendo
mycorrhizal inoculant from dynamite
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive that newsletter so go
to shaping fire com2 sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month's and all future newsletter
drawings you are listening shaping fire
and I'm your host Shang golos today my
guest is cannabis aquaponics expert
Steve Reznor Steve designs and builds
commercial scale aquaponic systems he
builds them for lots of different
purposes but he especially enjoys
building them for cannabis Steve is a
sought-after speaker on the range of
cannabis growing topics and shares his
knowledge via his potent ponics podcast
and in person through classes he hosts
he's also built a very educational
youtube channel also called potent
ponics with a range of content from
instructional videos to Google Hangouts
with topic experts today we're gonna
talk about the water food web welcome to
the show Steve thanks for having me
Shengo yeah so glad that you could peel
off a little your time there in Oklahoma
off your project too to chat with us so
let's get right into it and you know
aquaponics and the water food web while
it is the center of your world and
certainly it's increasing in popularity
I think that it's kind of on the fringe
of most cannabis people's experience and
so let's start off by giving people like
a context of about what we're even gonna
be talking about today so you know
talking about it at a global level if we
were talking about the the water food
web we would be talking about saltwater
and freshwater and estuaries and and
everything from phytoplankton all the
way up to whales and things like that
but but today I'm figuring that it's
probably better for us to talk about the
water food web as it applies to
aquaponics your specialty so so let's
start with this word aquaponics the
words aquaponics hydroponics and
aquaculture are thrown around and I
think incorrectly used synonymously back
and forth would you kind of like give us
some depth on how to use these words and
what we're actually going to be talking
about today
sure so I guess traditionally
aquaculture would be the growing and
raising a fish for the mainly food
purposes but sometimes other utility
purposes they also use them for skin
grafts and even filtering wines and
years they used fish bladders and things
like that and then you also use so for
hydroponics you know everyone's pretty
familiar with hydroponics listens to
your show using mineralized salts in an
aquatic environment and just delivering
a non soil or soil this environment
traditionally most of the time but not
all the time in hydroponics are doing so
in a sterile or as sterile as possible
aquatic environment and then you have
aquaponics where we use fish and fish
waste similar from an aquaculture system
to raise fish and a hydroponic system
although they are different chemically
than traditional hydroponics in many
different ways because of the
mineralization process and how much more
we rely on a much wider range of
microbes than they would in a hydroponic
system sometimes ones that can cause
problems in a hydroponic system actually
are very beneficial in an aquaponic
system if they're maintained in proper
population levels you know in the right
balance so so today so saying that a
different way hydroponics is going to be
more kind of you know bottled salt based
a plus B kind of stuff which may not be
organically natural but they get the job
done feeding the plants to a degree
aquaponics is going to be way more
analog chunky organic natural which is
great for the plants but if you tried to
use those solutions in hydroponics all
your sprayers if we get clogged with
nature right absolutely yeah so things
like really fine sprayers you know fine
water lines all of them would have
clogged with bacterial mats and other
issues that you know anyone that's run
those even without biologics has run
into those those issues as well so from
listening to you speak before I've heard
you talk about the split biome and
that's probably a really great place for
us to start because when I first started
doing my research for this interview
today I actually thought that that
aquaponics had the cannabis plant bare
root in you like in my head was
essentially an aquarium so it was like
the roots dangling in water and I'm all
like how do
they how do they breathe you know
because when it comes to soil we don't
want to overwater because it'll choke
out the plant and like I don't know how
these how these roots are gonna live in
water but then but then you know I hear
you say split biome and I'm like oh wait
a minute it's both water and either a
soil or maybe an inert substrate so so
would you describe that and kind of
explain the idea behind it sure so what
you were first describing as well as
referred to as DWC or deep water culture
which is bare root and water and where
there's a lot of people that have done
tests in the past different aquaponics
companies and they it simply doesn't
allow the proper flour structure and
proper plant structure and and no
density as well as a few other issues
with the plants so we use a method
called dual root zone planting where we
have pots where they have the top half
is soil and a layer of burlap and the
bottom half is either lava rock or
hydrogen and this allows us to have
terrestrial microbes mycorrhizae and etc
and different you know terrestrial
microbes they all of you guys have you
know familiar with from from soil and
the soil food web and I'm sure you've
had other amazing guests on talking
about that and then we have the aquatic
microbiome where we have all these
aquatic microbes that can mineralize all
these different nutrients in their own
ways some very similarly to the ones in
soil but they do so in radically
different ways chemically and what this
allows us to do is stimulate the immune
system of the plant in a way that is is
radically broader than at just a soil or
just an aquatic environment there was a
study done by NASA a few years ago where
NASA was trying to do a broad microbial
study of aquatic microbes and
terrestrial microbes so they could
figure out okay well if we go offworld
what microbe groups do we need to bring
with us if we're gonna grow a garden you
know what do we need a bottle and bring
with us to make food and crops and
whatever else they need to grow what
they found was when they did the
commercial aquaponics facilities around
North America I did over 50 of them none
of them at the same microbe webs across
any of them I believe it was no more
than seven percent
molarity is across microbes across all
these different ones sorry so you have a
what that means is that you know you
have radically different microbes
species that are making iron available
or silica available or nitrogen
available or potassium or phosphorus etc
and and none of them are the same and
all of them had kind of different
processes for it so it's just really
cool that you have such biodiversity but
what that means is that we can get
increased terpene expression increased
cannabinoid expression and our plants as
well as accelerated growth rate is what
that translate institute is for his
bottom line for the grower all right
there's a lot there to unpack so the
first thing I want to unpack there is is
where the path is for the roots so if if
we've got the cannabis plant planted in
soil and so we are getting a more you
know traditional what we think about is
the is the the rhizosphere and living
soil and the plant is growing down
through that and then and then we'll get
to the burlap a bit in a minute and then
rocks so so to a certain degree this
sounds like building a traditional you
know pot with the different horizons
like you'd get in the Earth's crust so I
get that so at what point does the
cannabis plants roots hit the water are
the roots going down to the water table
so that the the ends of the roots are
hitting this this specialty aquaponic
water with fish in it or is this just a
regular pot that's being watered from
the top with water from an exterior tank
so so after day three or four once we
transplant them into that soil there the
the plant finds that aquatic layer and
I'll have a noticeable increase in the
speed of growth the plants really seem
to use the nitrates better you know and
much faster than the night you know
typical ammonia in the soil and that
really helps with the growth
accelerating growth as well as the
additional air exposure because those
roots are flood and drain they have much
more air exposure and between the air
and the in the different form of
nitrogen it really aches
the rates that growth rate so they grow
straight through that burlap and into
the water so that the plant has both a
network in the soil and in the water and
when I was back working at the aquaponic
source a long time ago where I used to
work in their lab and we did all kinds
of experiments and we found the woodier
the crop in aquaponics the more it
relies on mycorrhizal fungi and the more
lignin it has I guess to boil it down as
a general rule of thumb again not
definitive but as a general rule of
thumb in aquaponics you need a deeper
soil layer for the woody air of the crop
so if I was doing fruit trees or
something I was going to do and
definitely maybe I'll do more of a 2/3
soil to 1/3 of flood and drain where as
what cannabis plants we're going to
about a 50/50 instead do should people
resist the temptation to have a drip
irrigation with aquaponic water from the
top because we want to encourage the
cannabis roots to explore the deeper
aquaponic layer downwards and because we
want to encourage them to to expand sure
so actually top water all the all of our
soil layer our flood and drain layer
actually leaves about a half inch of
where before the soil we don't want it
to touch or wick and then we top water
about twice a week and that a view
absolutely you could use an automated
system we have for our larger systems we
use a completely automated array I've
actually designed in my own manifold
that allows us to water as many plants
as we need to simultaneously within
about 10 milliliters difference across
all the plants a simultaneously so this
way we don't have to worry about over
watering and having that water go
through so in a dual root zone we're
gonna take their water and say it takes
16 ounces of water to fully saturate
that upper soil layer which will we'll
test before we put the pots in the bed
with with you know we'll just say for
the sake of argument we have an 8 ounce
party cup well it takes two of those for
me to water for that water to drip
through the soil and go out through the
bottom I'm going to reduce that amount
by half and in the future if I need to
top water I'm only going to do is with 8
ounces of water so that I'm not dosing
so much that it's leaching out into the
aquarium and this allows me to you know
maintain moisture levels in that upper
layer between the humidity coming off
the bottom of the the bed and then the
the top watering we can maintain you
know Pleasant moisture levels for the
root system and do some minor feeding
that the plant waste are that sorry the
fish waste provides around 80 to 85 to
90% of the nutrients the plants need and
then we just amend that last 10 percent
through the soil layer either through
minerals that we make in the initial
soil compost mix that we use for it or
through top feeding depending on what it
is that we needed a given time when you
are top watering are you top watering
with water from the aquaponic system or
are you using I don't know terrestrial
water I guess I'll call it you know
regular water so we actually use water
from the aquaponic system with one
exception would be the second half of
flour but in veg or certainly the first
half of a flour we would absolutely use
system water it's just a matter of in
late flour you're really trying to cut
back on the nitrogen as much as possible
so we don't want to put any more on so
that probably the only time that we
don't use water from the system itself
otherwise we're just recirculating water
from the system for our top feeding we
just pump it into a separate
mineralization tank some water from our
mineralization tanks which we can talk
about and and then we also amend it so
if I have a the pH is too low we'll add
potassium silicate or calcium carbonate
or you know whatever pH up that we're
going to use at the time and amend it
that way and before we add it back in
but this way we can add some mineral
rich nutrients back into the system that
all you know all come from the system
awesome great explanation so my second
question on that is you know I live on
an island right and one of the
challenges that we've got is I live on
an agricultural island and and and
people are constantly saying don't put
too you know don't overnight Rijn
nitrogen york your fields because when
it runs off the island it goes into the
Puget Sound and it causes you know the
too much algae and red tide and all
those kind of stuff I wondered to what
degree do you have to for example avoid
using compost teas in the
plants because as these nutrients go
through the plant they end up in your
aquarium your aquaponic layer and might
throw off your balance there I mean are
you only supposed to use the aquaponic
or you know clean non treated water or
can can I go ahead and use compost teas
and because it doesn't really matter
oh no use teas and ferments as part of
our mineralization process we also use
ferments as a way to biocontrol for
pathogens we actually use lactobacillus
ferments labs I'm sure you've had many
people on the show talk about the
wonders of labs yeah but one of the cool
things of labs is in an aquatic
environment is Italy you call by
salmonella listeria and other things in
the controlled lab environment that I
can quote I can't say it work on a
person all the time on your farm legally
but the fact that in a laboratory it
works not and and you know it works very
well in practicality as well so you can
use these types of things not only to
keep system clean but to eliminate
pathogens and still use all those
wonderful compost to use and ferments
we're a bit real huge on horsetail
foreign ferments there's a great one we
also use we'll use occasionally fruit
juice ferments as well in flour for top
feeding so all the stuff that you guys
have you know use already for your soil
mixes absolutely can be used for
aquaponics and many of them actually
have some radically additional benefits
in aquaponics the one exception of a
yucca
extract and any kind of wetting agents
are you know plant-based wetting agents
steppin ins and some other things like
that those are all fish lethal so you
always have to be careful just because
it's organic doesn't mean it won't kill
your fish right on yeah because it is
while while it may not be you know an
organic toxin it's gonna throw off the
balance enough that it's no longer a
good living environment for the fish oh
no say phonons are straight up fish
lethal the Indians and the Indians in
California used to our natives I don't
know I guess that's the correct term now
the natives in California used to
collect yucca root extract yucca root
they'd squeeze the juice out of it
concentrate it and evaporate it off pour
it into streams during the salmon run
and
the salmon and then dry them and and you
know this happen and once it's cooked
and everything is perfectly fun for
humans but it kills the fish and like
you know parts per billion levels in a
river so man that's a mad science right
there to know that so early on without
an analytics lab yeah with no chemistry
knowledge or you know an idea of even
what chemistry was you know to come up
with that's pretty wild so it really
makes you it's really any interesting
sometimes they look at some of the
ancient solutions you know some of the
interesting stuff I've done with amino
acid isolation actually came from like
sixteenth and seventeenth-century die
making techniques that I kind of adapted
to make plant food and some other cool
stuff so there's always you know really
neat things sometimes going back in
history and looking at how we used to do
things you know is all sometimes even
better than looking forward so um so
what I'm hearing from you I really
thought that it was kind of like a
zero-sum game you either did you know
living soil growing or you did
aquaponics growing and it really sounds
like aquaponics is supercharged living
soil growing because you're doing all
your your regular living soil stuff that
you would do to create this healthy you
know raizo sphere in the upper layers
but then you're super charging it with
the water food web that we're going to
talk more about in the second set as the
roots reaches down to the aquaponic
layer absolutely yeah and again it gives
you benefits of both worlds and you
absolutely could do it just a soil and
do in a wicking bed but with this we get
you know radically increase in speed of
growth we get radical increase in speed
of a bunch of different mineralization
methods and we get a radical increase in
disease resistance a radical increase
and interpret expression as well and you
know all those combined really makes a
big difference right on so let's go
ahead and dive into that during set two
and wrap up this one now so we're gonna
take our first short ret break and be
right back you're listening to shaping
fire
my guest today is aquaponic cannabis
expert Steve Reznor living soil and
regenerative cannabis agriculture are
surging in popularity and to implement
these biological solutions real science
education is vital if you are interested
in all things probiotic growing you will
probably want to attend this year's
science of organic regenerative cannabis
cultivation conference for the third
year in a row co-founders Joshua
Rutherford of Dutch blooms and Leighton
Morrison of Kingdom aquaponics have
lined up an incredible array of
educators with all new content for the
travelling event they're calling it
version 2.0 going deeper down the rabbit
hole
this year's teaching staff includes
Elaine Ingham on soil biology Chris
Trump and Wendy Kornberg talking Korean
natural farming Kevin Jo Durie on
cannabis genetics Kelly and Josh from
dragonfly earth medicine Suzanne
Wainwright the bug lady chip Osborne on
soil chemistry and many other thought
leaders rotating in and out for
different cities so consult the website
to knows who specifically is coming for
each location there will be a breeding
panel a QA panel with the entire
teaching staff and on Saturday night
there will be a bubble hash discussion
as well Joshua has built in significant
informal time for you with the teachers
the teaching staff is just as excited to
work with you as you are about attending
there is also no advertising during the
event the only vendor booths are for
cannabis seed breeders your tuition is
what's paying the staff so they all be
present and attentive to you not a
corporate sponsor even better the
conference is not just for folks on the
west coast humboldt california is
hosting one event for sure but the show
is going on the road to Vancouver
British Columbia Portland Maine and
Whitmore Lake Michigan get out your pen
now because I'm about to give you the
website this is a fabulous opportunity
for you to hear from an array of
nationally recognized top-shelf soil
educators all in one place not only that
this isn't just beginner stuff like you
get at most conventions this is an
intensive for people like us who totally
nerd out on the rhizosphere and growing
and living soil and if you attended last
year be assured that this year is not
simply a repeat of last year every
speaker will present different material
than they did last
the website is regenerative organic
cannabis calm that's regenerative
organic cannabis calm this year tickets
will be limited in a number to preserve
the intimate experience and will only be
sold in advance online
there will be no ticket sales at the
door so don't wait and miss out on your
chance to attend this important
gathering of the regenerative cannabis
community cut through all the
misinformation out there and don't miss
this opportunity to learn real soil
science regenerative organic cannabis
calm this message is for folks who grow
cannabis I'm talking to home growers
patients and commercial growers - I'm
probably talking to you when you plan
out your next growing cycle be sure to
check out Humble CSI seeds at Humble CSI
dot-com Caleb Inspectah and his family
have lived in Humboldt County for over a
hundred years for the last 40 years
three generations of his family have
cultivated extraordinary sense of Meah
cannabis in Humboldt
Mendocino and Trinity counties because
of his lineage and the hard earned
experience that comes from growing up
smoking and sifting large populations of
cannabis plants in Northern California
the seeds you'll cop from CSI will be
winning genetics based on long time
heavy hitters and updated and Reese if
today bring out new and exotic traits
and better yields go ahead and ask
around
Caleb also known as Inspectah and
Pirates of the Emerald triangle is a
breeders breeder he reaches way back and
works with significant strains
recreating them in new and interesting
ways that you'll love is a toker and a
grower as well as offering you some
surprises that will delight serious seed
traders and cultivators Humboldt CSI
goes as further step and selfs all these
chemo VARs so you know all the seeds
will be female these are not
experimental feminized seeds Humboldt
CSI releases some of the best female
seeds available anywhere and it will
show in your garden folks grew quite a
bit of CSI humble gen-x last year here
on Vashon Island and everyone was
pleased the patients had beautiful
female plants and didn't have to call
half of their garden as males the folks
growing for the fun of getting high grew
colorful flower
with exceptional bag appeal and great
highs and breeders had seven out of
seven females in a pack which gave them
a lot of phenotypic choices take a
moment right now and visit Humboldt CSI
comm you'll find an up-to-date menu of
both feminized and regular lines along
with photos and descriptions
that's Humboldt CSI comm welcome back
you are listening to shaping fire on
your hosts Shango losan our guest this
week is aquaponic cannabis expert Steven
Rae's 'nor so Steve during the first set
we we pretty much got a little bit a
grip of what we were even talking about
right because there's a lot of
misperceptions coming into aquaponics
about what's even going on and so so now
that we understand that we've got this
split biome and we're getting to take
advantage of advantage of both the the
magic of having a living microbe life
rhizosphere of a living soil but then
also this added benefit of the the water
food web that the the roots are
extending down into that's what I where
I want to emphasis now because when I
first heard you speak about the water
food web at Joshua Rutherford and
Leighton Morrison's traveling
regenerative cannabis series like my
mind was blown man like I did not it
never even occurred to me that all the
cool stuff that we were talking about in
the soil biome could also be happening
in water and and I just I just listened
to you with my mouth at gate B I like
surprised so so before I go into like my
series of questions why don't you just
kind of like dive into your explanation
of the soil food web and why the
inhabitants of a healthy I dare scald
living water I don't know if that's the
term but like who lives in the living
water that's adding so much more value
versus just using living soil so I guess
the the quick and easy answer is we
don't know what one's doing any research
on on which microbes are doing what and
the
environment because everyone's so
focused on soil because of mass
agriculture there's there's next to no
research being done on freshwater
aquatic microbes in relation to you know
mineralization so that's that's the
quick answer but so so how I like to
explain it is so with our method we have
that we call it the dual root zone so in
your your upper half we have soil so we
have micro rise a fungi we have you know
micro arthropods you know all your
different worms all your different you
know mites all the different creatures
that you know we're all familiar with in
the the soil and they have their own key
components and I'm sure there's many
different wise people that have shared a
lot of that critical information on your
show in the aquatic environment we have
we do have mycorrhizae and there are
fungi and fungal networks that will grow
aquatic Lea but they're not that they're
very miniscule in terms of total
population they're generally five
percent or less of the total biomass in
the aquatic environment whereas we rely
much more heavily on bacteria and
rotifer and protists and what's the name
of the other one begins with an a
they're like bacteria anyways
I'll think of it but so you have all
these different aquatic microbes that Oh
ma'am for whatever reason that it's
bugging me okay I remember the name of
it I'll think of it you know pop it'll
pop up at some point inappropriately
down the line and then just say it out
loud archaea thank you archaea archaea
so you have all these different aquatic
microbes and we have a much more bio
diverse matrix so imagine if like all of
your air could it was a really good
environment for microbes and there are
microbes that live in the air but it's
not quite the same as the water in the
water we can have much much much higher
microbial densities than you can in soil
and on average in aquaponic do root zone
set up has a hundred and sixty seven
percent more microbial biodiversity in
the root system compared to the even the
most diverse living soils and and
hydroponic systems it's not even
comparable so but even your most of our
soil we're at one hundred sixty seven
percent more microbes in the root system
about 70% of the microbes an aquatic
environment can also survive in
terrestrial environments which is why we
need to do a lot of research on these
because a lot of these you know we know
that for example CBD almost across the
board will express higher in aquaponics
all things be considered equal that in
terrestrial expression we also know
given certain stimuli that we can
increase THC V expression significantly
past most soil controls as well all but
two controls we've done so far so and
that's mostly just having to do with
cult of our difference but there's all
these different genes that are being
activated and do we know nothing about
because we've never activated them in
soil because there's aquatic microbes or
other stimuli through the aquatic
environment that's stimulating them and
triggering them and we don't know it you
know there could be terpenes or
cannabinoids that are only found in
aquaponics or there you know it could be
a way to you know especially with some
of the minor cannabinoids it seems like
you know we can pretty radically
increase production of you know certain
cannabinoids compared to our soil
controls so this is a wildly under
researched area with a lot of room for
growth for folks who are getting into
the scene and and want to start doing a
research in something that's fresh and
new to them oh absolutely and and I want
what I guess one takeaway I want people
to take from this is that you know think
about you know you don't even have to do
do root so in aquaponics with your soil
just think about how can I increase the
microbial biodiversity in ways they're
non-pathogenic and non you know negative
to the the rest of the microbiome you
know don't go dumping a ton of
Trichoderma on your system it's not
going to work but you know if you had
horrible Pythium that might make sense
you know it just depends so it up so so
you and I were talking like before we
got on air you and I were talking about
we both have backgrounds in aquariums so
I can I can really hear the person out
there going I've got an aquarium like
like when we do water changes regularly
right where you've got to remove some of
the water and you replace it with fresh
for the good of the for the good of the
inhabitants of the aquarium you know
could somebody rep you and their home
grow just by simply taking a gallon or
whatever or a couple cups out of their
aquarium and pouring it into their pace
grow or whatever or or is that there's
that overly simplified oh no you
absolutely get benefit from that I would
not do that in Flour you know especially
late in the flower I wouldn't do that
because you don't want the nitrates from
that but you could absolutely when
you're doing your water change to take
that dirty water especially for veg or
for you know a first week or two a
flower absolutely that would be great or
even take your when you do a water
change take the water let it settle pour
off the clear water and use that just
for regular watering for your veg and
stuff and then take that thick heavier
stuff and throw an air stone in it and a
little bit of a little bit more you know
maybe the only drain about half way
throw an air stone and mix it up like a
really concentrated compost tea maybe
throw a little bit of your favorite
microbial mix um you know recharge or
mammoth pee or whoever it is that you
you like or even some of your own
compost
inputs or whoever whoever it is uh you
know your your special blend or your
secret mix throw the microbes in there
let it mineralize and then put that back
on the plants and let that unlock you
know 80 70 80 percent more of the
nutrients that are in that fish waste
that are just locked up in a non plant
available form this can be a great way
for organic people that have you know
large aquariums or even large ponds that
have you know lots of muck and stuff in
the filters use it it's great plant food
you're seeing mineralize it the way you
would with compost tea oh man I can't
imagine how that I threw away just down
the down the drain all that fantastic
Malm that used to gather at the bottom
of the aquariums you know that all the
all the fish waste and old plant matter
and all that stuff on the bottom which
in those days was was filth right that
none of those bad stuff and we would
pull that out with the vacuum and now
I'm like oh man if I could just you know
have all that stuff for my plants that's
got to be you know pure gold so in the
is so in the water web you know since
there's not mycelium networks like there
are in soil what plays the role of
moving nutrients around that the
mycelium does in the soil is it simple
wat simply
water flow it's not only water flow but
you have just a much higher density of
microorganisms you have seed shrimp and
lots more nematodes and all different
types of amoebas and protists and
rotifers and and all kinds of things
that are just swimming around moving you
know and transporting nutrients around
at a much higher rate you also have the
fact that a lot you know there's a lot
more nutrient capacity and in water
period to hold a lot of these nutrients
and and to dissolve a lot of these
nutrients in a way that is quickly
usable both by the microbes but also by
the plants themselves so that you know
it doesn't even have to be in that you
know solid form either you know a lot of
its just in the aquatic environment so
you've used the term flood and drain a
couple times would you go ahead and
break that out for folks who are new to
it sure so we have tables generally
twelve by 4-foot tables in in long rows
and the and the water comes up and it
floods about the bottom five to six
depending on the type of setup inches of
water and then it has a bell siphon
which was actually first invented by
Pythagoras you can look it up the
Pythagorean cup or the Greek Cup which
was designed to spill out all the wine
if you overfilled the wine cup of wine
but what it does is as the water comes
up to the top it creates a vacuum at the
very top of the Bell and that sucks in
the air and allows the water to drain
and then once the water comes all the
way down to the bottom of the Bell
there's a couple of slits cut that break
that and then what this allows us to do
and then the water stops and then allows
the the it drains the bed completely it
allows the bed to fill back up again
what this allows us to do is run one
pump and continuously fill 3,000 square
feet of grow beds or even six thousand
square feet of grow beds off of a single
pump you know with one failure point you
know I can put a redundancy pump in
there if that one goes down it turns on
the other one and it just makes it
really simple to make sure nothing bad
happens even in the event of some kind
of catastrophic failure so what's
happening is that one or a couple times
a day
this floods and and as the water level
rises you're introducing all of these
all this water food
web nutrition and microbes and various
guys into the the rhizosphere from the
roots that are hanging down below the
pot and then also some of that it's
getting sucked up into the soil as well
and so you're doing this feeding in this
way how many times a day are you gonna
do this this this flood and drain so the
flood and drain is on a cycle and if
floods depending on the size of
dimensions of the bed anywhere between
seven and 18 minutes and just drains and
floods again and fills again
continuously so this is why having those
roots then this is why they're not
getting choked off of oxygen because
it's they're never living a hundred
percent of the time in water it's just
the water comes up and touches them and
gives them a feed and then it recedes
and then it comes up again so it creates
this really nice analogue rhythm
absolutely and most plants that give it
as long as the dissolved oxygen level is
high enough most plants are around the
three to four parts per million
dissolved oxygen level as long as you're
above that they'll build you okay
obviously it'll do better if it's higher
than that but that's kind of the minimum
I know lettuce you can get it as low as
2.2 parts per million which is super low
but most other plants really do want you
know to be significantly higher you know
most the time you're wanting for a 5 or
above you know bar minimum so so in in
the soil food web we use soil amendments
to increase the soil viability and you
know in a perfect system that we're
talking about a you know something that
is no-till with with with some aged soil
that has mycelium networks already set
up but but you know if if somebody
doesn't have a no-till setup they've
they've put together a soil and they've
added some soil amendments to increase
soil value ability are they're healthy
additives when you're working with the
water food web as well and and and and
those inputs can we wildcraft them like
what are you doing to to develop the
healthy the healthy and vibrancy of this
water sure so we use things like dtpa
iron
for iron and that's iron and potassium
and calcium kind of our big problems
because they either get exported by
large amounts by the plant material or
they are oxidized in the case of iron
you know fe2 gets converted into fe 3
unless it has some kind of chelation
around it so those are kind of I guess
our big problems and so we've managed
usually handle the calcium and potassium
through pH up our pH will gradually go
down over time so we'll use potassium
silicate and calcium carbonate to amend
that to fix that and add you know
potassium silica and calcium as well as
some loose carbonate so there's a lot of
really bad information around aquaponics
that you know you shouldn't have any
carbonates you actually need to maintain
at least 40 parts per million carbon
it's ideally higher or you will actually
cut your microbial replication and a
half and as we all know for soil or
aquatics you know you don't want to ever
cut your microbial replication in half
so you know and that's one of the
biggest problems you I know we before
the show we talked about it you know
there's not a there's a lot of
information on aquaponics but a lot of
it's just really bad and there's a lot
of stuff that's just any anyone with a
scientific mind that reads it's just can
can see that there's problems and that's
been one of the big reasons that it's
held held up the aquaponics movement is
just the fact that there's only a
handful of people that really know what
they're doing to begin with
well that brings us back to the drum
that you beat every time I hear you talk
which is there's just not enough proper
education and cannabis yet you know
everybody needs to get more educated the
growers the breeders the end consumers
and you know more and more people are
getting indicate education but that
doesn't mean that the quality of the
education is high there's a lot of
people just repeating myths and our
whole scene could do a lot better when
it comes to education so absolutely I
know I effect I've actually spoken at
three churches in Oklahoma where we had
a pastor come in and one someone that
can talk about it and it's really funny
to go into a place there you know who
would have thought that I'd be walking
into a church in southern you know at
Oklahoma to go talk about cannabis like
what happened Wow like what what she
like what you know I just feels like one
day all of a sudden everything
okay and you know that just to go from
where we were you know when we were in
high school to where we are now or you
know I'm able to go in and speak into a
church in Oklahoma it's just some days
you just got to sit back even though we
have a lot of struggles right now I know
especially with with some of the legal
stuff and people trying to patent things
and all this other mess that people get
headaches but you know sometimes it's
nice just to sit back and go like wow
like this is just crazy how much how
much you know different it is now that
we even have churches that are taking
talking about it and there's there's a
certain amount of humor to in the fact
that even though like you know the
historical Jesus would not have been
white you know your long-hair hippie
looking guy like you on the stage you
probably did not look all that different
from then the guy on the crucifix so
moving right along from that before I
dig myself a hole so you know one of the
things about aquaponics that it's like
one of the main things everybody knows
is that there's fish involved right and
and so let's talk about the fish
themselves we're in this system do the
fish live and how do you choose what
fish to have sure so we generally choose
the fish based on the temperature of the
system and then the market marketability
of the fish and then whether or not that
particular region will allow us to get a
sorry meat processing license so in most
states the United States in fact all of
them you cannot have a cannabis facility
and a meat processing license because
the meat processing inspection guys are
all federal and federally answer to a
federal board or whatever so they can't
deal with anyone who deals with cannabis
until the federal law is changed so you
have to either have your fish processed
by a third-party company that has meat
processing or you have to sell it
through the pet trade which can be a
more lucrative option so depending on
again your particular climate and things
like that it oftentimes it's it's
cheaper to and and more economical to do
koi or some of the more larger exotic
aquarium fish era Juana's or PACU or
some of the more exotic plecos you know
makes a lot more sense financially to
raise those and flip them you know every
12 to 24 months
than it does you know to sell meat fish
and so if you do choose the meat fish I
mean the only one that I'm thinking of
that that people use our tilapia but are
there other meat fish that people are
using in aquaponics absolutely so for
for cannabis in particular you know
channel catfish PACU yellow perch we've
done trying to think that I know there's
a few others a bluegill and then you
know you could do anything that's
regionally appropriate there was another
group we did snake heads over for a
vegetable grow over in India you know
and you can also do cold water although
you shouldn't do Salman 'add or anything
like that with cannabis in particular
because the potassium levels we have are
fine for most fish but most fish that go
from saltwater to freshwater when they
regulate that salt the potassium seems
to become a much bigger problem with
tilapia being the one exception so that
it tends to kill them pretty quickly
that when they get into the you know the
ranges were in for cannabis so them and
white bass would be the one that we had
some trouble with when we were doing our
testing so I would avoid those so so you
know in a when I'm when I see the
illustrations online explaining a system
very often they will simplify it and
they'll just have what looks like a fish
tank below the table but I imagine that
that's not actually how it is because
these tables are large and there's many
of them is how it works in the real
world that that somewhere near the table
set up in the warehouse or wherever it's
gonna be there will be a you know
several hundred gallon tank and it is
filled with the fish and then you're
simply piping the water over to the
table yep yep so a lot of people think
that the fish are actually living in the
plant roots which is not the case they
will happily eat the plant roots in most
cases it's a it's a cool thing to
picture in your head though right the
idea of the oh you're swimming between
the roots that sounds cool but yeah
you're right having them munch on their
roots that's not a win you know what
does work really well though we talked a
little bit about this in the past is the
little colorful shrimp that you like
alone yeah the Neo karabiner I heard a
hetero pota
yeah they were great in the to keep the
root systems look full exfoliated and
keep the detritus and the algae out of
there they're they're awesome but so but
yes so we actually have some tanks
everything flows back to the sub tanks
the beds pump up from the sub tanks and
go into the beds the water goes into the
beds and then back down where the from
where the plants are and then we have a
separate loop where we have the
aquariums so water pumps up from the
same some over to the aquariums that
goes from the aquariums gravity feeds in
through two sets of filters and then
goes back down into the ground and then
we can reroute that depending on where
we want it to go generally we'll keep a
mixture of a couple you know a bunch of
different tanks so that when we're
rotating fish out if I have a bunch of
fry obviously they're not going to
produce a whole lot of fish waste so we
can balance that out with you know
another better or another fish tank or
two so that we can maintain you know
pretty even nutrient levels regardless
of our harvest cycle with the fish you
know so making sure you have you know
extra fish tanks and it can work a
rotation like that is one thing they
often see people don't don't do well on
the larger commercial operations but I
know and there's other stuff too
people put UV sterilizers on them which
you shouldn't do you know it causes
mineral issues and boron and some other
stuff I mean there's a lot of just goo
for people that tell you you don't need
filters or you know all kinds of goofy
stuff out there so one thing I remember
from when I was raising these shrimp you
know I had like 35 aquariums and I would
often share water between the aquarium
and then if one aquarium went south on
it and got out of out of balance I did
not want to share that water in my other
tanks because I didn't want the disease
or imbalance whatever the problem was to
spread to my other tanks well in this
case we're directly feeding from the
aquarium into the flood and drain tables
how much hassle or or potential for
disease transfer is there from an
imbalance or disease in the aquarium to
then be transferred to our plants so
today there is known
own plant pathogens that have can go
from a fish into a cannabis plant Wow
there you could absolutely have things
like in theory you could have e coli or
Salmonella or some other things like
that but actually the University of
Hawaii did seven years of study well
they were intentionally infecting
infecting systems and had no you know
tissue samples test positive in in
aquaponics and that includes you know
intentionally introducing pathogens at
University Arizona University of
Wisconsin have also done pretty
extensive food safety Studies on that as
well and then university of kentucky
states actually done stuff on probiotic
mitigation with that using lactobacillus
fermentation microbes and then
introducing those and and using those
actually to eliminate even
non-pathogenic e.coli lots of aquaponic
systems will test hot for e.coli it's
not an e.coli that's human pathogenic
you could drink the water you won't get
sick it just it's a species of e.coli
and it will give you a false positive so
you can absolutely use that even to
eliminate those false positives as well
and it's just it's a really good way to
do something in a way that's not going
to imbalance your whole system as well
so there's lots of different solutions
depending on what you're doing but we
actually on all the systems I design we
can reroute any of the beds to any of
the stumps and the fish tanks any of the
Sims so even if we have you know six
fish I can bring that fish tank offline
and everything else will still operate
just fine you know maybe you have to do
a little bit more balancing with some of
the flow rates but it's not a big deal
and this allows you to have that kind of
control if I have you know somebody
dropped something and breaks a valve or
goes to turn a valve and it snaps or
these things happen so you have to have
that kind of ability to compartmentalize
and shut down things or maybe you have
an earthquake and it breaks you know how
part of the you know treat falls down
and breaks part of the system but the
rest of it's okay you need that be able
to isolate the system and keep as much
production online as all times as
possible so we plant all that into the
the design and you know that would be
the one time we'd break out a UV
sterilizer or an ozonator or something
like that it would be just to put on an
offline tank just to treat the fish that
are in there because you know we
generally don't want to use anything
that we have to you know we'll treat
them with lactobacillus
we'll give them there's a
all medication you can use as a last
resort called prohibit there's actually
four aquaculture that can be used for a
fish for human consumption later on I
believe it's a 90-day cooldown time or
100 or 180 days if you're in Canada so
so you know hearing you describe that
I'm imagining a whole lot of plumbing
and you know with with regular soil
cannabis I mean pretty much you you can
take a flower pot throw soil and put
your seat in it water that baby and
you'll have a plant of some degree of
success right and then and then from
that point on as you learn more you can
make your plants better and better
aquaponics though like you need to have
a certain depth in what you're doing
just a plan and strategize and build one
of these in advance I would think that
you know especially in the idea of
measure twice cut once like the the
install is probably by far the biggest
hassle of the whole aquaponics process
oh yeah yeah absolutely the I do a lot
of design work for different companies
and in design farms that's mainly what I
do these days is design them or or help
people that have already built them that
they need help with their SOPs but but
absolutely yeah it's a lot of plumbing
and if you don't know what you're doing
or design it wrong I know there's a
company out there right now it's one of
the bigger aquaponics companies that has
a cannabis specific system that has
given me a lot of business which I'm
thankful for right on they they get the
out of the box so they get the boxed
solution and they're like oh we need we
need better than the box yep yeah so
since we're talking about a
lactobacillus acid serum I
I told you and since it's trending so
much I got to ask is there are there KNF
korean natural farming applications for
aquaponics absolutely yeah we actually
use I am a one liquid IMO we don't use
FFA we don't use IMO three just too much
sugar you know and
stuff like that you know it wouldn't
make sense but you know anything that
would make sense within an aquatic
environment is if it works perfectly
well you know we'll use o hn and all
those things are perfectly fine to use
in your aquaponic system in fact you
know what's interesting with o hn and
people talk about alcohol dosing so you
have a cito bacter bacteria that live in
your soil and acetobacter love to feed
on nitrogen so you can actually use I
like it on a reef tank and I don't I
don't know how much you remember this
from aquariums but and in aquariums you
can actually do something called vodka
dosing where you can dose with vodka to
feed the acetobacter x' to break down
the nitrogen and make it non lethal to
the the fish and bind it up so you could
actually do very similar dosing with
soil or aquatics for plants as well in
terrestrial it's not quite as extreme as
it doesn't an aquarium but it'll still
give you a reduction to nitrogen de so
that you're not ending up with too much
end coming into flower so when I was at
the regenerative cannabis conference
that you were speaking with that back in
Michigan this summer Alain Hingham said
you know she pointed out the importance
of of having real sunshine hitting the
soil of our plants because you know this
the sunshine hitting the plant of course
is going to give us the widest terpene
profiles and let the plant express
itself most naturally but then also how
the this the sunshine hitting the soil
around the base of the plant was having
all this interaction with the soil
microbes directly and the warming of the
soil and like you know all this analog
magic that was was happening when the
sunshine hits the soil now people will
will fake the Sun with lights indoor but
those lights don't fake out the soil and
so there's a certain amount of microbe
activity loss because it's not you know
authentic sunshine how does that cross
apply over to aquaponics is it is it
very easy to do an aquaponics setup
under artificial lights or are you
needing to do this under glass roofs or
in greenhouses or something like that
we've had equal success both the naka
and Indore and with greenhouses I
personally I think anyone who's not
doing greenhouses at this point is
wasting money on cultivation because
you're not going to be around you know
that when the price comes down
ultimately there's just your you
shouldn't be investing in Indore at this
point unless you're doing breeding or
really specific cultivars or something
like that where it really makes sense
otherwise for commercial production
you're just gonna get priced out the
market pretty quick yeah so last
question before we go to commercial like
you know I'm a big fan of poly culture
and companion planting and we talked
about a lot on this show are there
opportunities for doing companion
planning in aquaponics oh absolutely I'm
a big fan of companion planting as well
we're big on purslane watercress time
majorem creeping lavender creeping
rosemary we've got all different types
of stuff in our aquaponic systems we
find that you know really helps with you
know just a healthier root systems in
general do you find that it's helping
both the you know we know about poly
culture and how it's good for the soil
and good for the plants and they're in
there and the rise of spheres talk to
each other all that good stuff
do we find that companion planning helps
with the thriving of the water as well
or keeping it balanced or are there
advantages to companion planning to the
to the living water
you can definitely especially when
you're coming in to flower if you plant
them you know about second half of edge
so that they're really starting to take
off when you're coming into flower can
really help reduce the nitrogen levels
in the system especially locally around
the plant which can be really beneficial
for flower and that's probably they
guess the biggest benefit from them we
also love to do a chamomile which is
another one just because it's such a bug
magnetman right on that's totally cool
all right let's go ahead and take our
second short break and be right back
you're listening to shaping fire my
guest today is aquaponic cannabis expert
Steve razor cultivators who grow in
living soil are very particular on what
inputs they use in their soil they
educate themselves and painstakingly
create compo
to nutritive teas to create thriving
soils that will produce the very best
expression of the cannabis plant many
living soil farmers now believe that
over time seeds become acclimated to the
kind of substrate they are grown in for
example a seed that was bred in
synthetic fertilizers may not
immediately know what to do in a living
soil environment slowing their growth
and decreasing yield the regenerative
seed cooperative is a different kind of
seed bank the regenerative seed
cooperative only provide cannabis seeds
that were bred in living soil and using
probiotic growing techniques that way
when you germinate in soil the seeds
genetics will recognize the environment
and immediately start interacting with
microbes and fungal networks these seeds
are described as bio intelligent the
number of cannabis breeders
participating in the regenerative seed
cooperative is rapidly increasing
already signed on our bamboos stock and
bean pacific northwest roots ello s
Gardens dragonfly earth medicine ital
foundation Bob hemp hills cricket and
cicada Dutch blooms heart Rock Mountain
Farms pride of Lyon Sebring seeds and
Mount Baker highway with more being
added every month these seeds are
regulars Auto flowers and hemp varieties
a significant amount of the profits go
to cannabis seed preservation projects
available to everyone do you want to
take every advantage that you can when
growing in beautiful healthy soil then
consider buying your seeds from the
regenerative seed cooperative at
regenerative seeds calm that's
regenerative seeds calm growing cannabis
in greenhouses is taking over the
cannabis industry an efficient and
effective blend of sunshine grown
terpene profiles and the controlled
environment of indoor greenhouses can be
the best of both worlds
for many greenhouse operators though
building their greenhouse before gaining
insight into how cannabis greenhouses
differ from ornamental crops can be the
start of a world of hurt
Eric Branstad and his team at greenhouse
advisory group have the experience and
technical know-how to help you avoid
these pitfalls Eric Branstad has been
helping cannabis growers find locations
design build and equip their greenhouses
for over a decade
starting in Northern California but
expanding over the last five years to
helping clients throughout the world he
has an impeccable reputation
for both depth of knowledge and kindness
and communication you can hear Eric
explains some of the challenges facing
cannabis greenhouses and how to overcome
them in episode number 41 of the shaping
fire podcast no matter where I go in the
country good people with smart
backgrounds still are making the mistake
of building without knowing cannabis and
it causes them to burn through capital
and time fast everyone has their own
failure point for some it is improper
ventilation planning for others it is
surface temperatures of the building or
the plants leaves or both some folks
that build their greenhouse from scratch
make really basic errors like placement
of the greenhouse on the property or not
understanding the natural environment
where the greenhouse sits
some have even built a decent greenhouse
but are inefficient in their deployment
of light deprivation techniques and
never really hit their target yields
it's great when you learn from your
mistakes but it's even better when you
learn from the mistakes of others when
you bring on green house advisory group
you will learn from the mistakes of
their many clients and you'll take
advantage of the best practices
developed by Eric Branstad over his
years of working with clients just like
you from location development to
choosing a builder and tricking out your
new greenhouse or retrofitting or
rescuing your failing green house Eric
will help you through it
visit green house advisory group com to
learn more and connect with Eric and his
team that's green house advisory group
welcome back you're listening to shaping
fire and I'm your host
Shango Louis and our guest this week is
aquaponic cannabis expert Steve Reznor
so during the first two sets we figured
out what the hell aquaponics are and
during the second set we really got into
what's going on on the science and
biological levels well here on the third
set we're going to talk about what
happens when things go wrong and you
know Steve from the from the first two
sets it seems to me that the the biggest
problem is when things get out of
balance because just like the soil food
web when one input category or chemical
category or microbe category when one of
them gets you know to overabundant
or or or to lacking it it really mess
with the different the different layers
of magnitude the different trophic
layers of life and then the whole thing
just kind of starts to crash i'm
assuming that this is what happens as
well in aquaponics absolutely and we use
a combination of you know organic
mineral salts as well as working more
towards fermented inputs as well a big
shout-out to Patrick from soil King is
that amazing excel sheet over on his
website of all the different mineral
inputs and different plants that you can
mineralize through compost teas or
ferments to extract that and we're doing
a lot of testing on that now and a
couple of different facilities that
we're working with to try and replace
even some of those minerals that are
using but we use a lot of you know
potassium silicate and calcium carbonate
for pH up dtpa for iron and then you
know other other you know sulfates and
some other stuff for you know
organically certified of course when
possible to address some of these issues
but for the most part again we're
getting 85 to 90 percent of them with
the aquaponics and just doing very minor
changes or unlocking them through other
means like we talked about with the
ferments or T's the way that everyone
you know is traditionally familiar with
and doing a hybrid of those two really
is the the solution for those and one of
the big ways that I guess maybe we're
different is that we're testing our
nutrients in the aquatic environment
every two weeks and most of our
facilities that I'm working with some
people are down to every four weeks just
because it's is down pat with the
cultivars that they're running but most
people are again every two weeks they're
sending out their water just to find out
hey what's going on and you know where
are we at with with micronutrients and
we're just making really tiny material
adjustments so that you know even when
we are dosing with something it's it's
you know 3 or 3 ppm s or 5 ppm s
different something real small just to
keep it in range and to keep everything
rockin because again the fish waste is
providing the vast majority of what we
need we're just amending the little bit
that we can either put through the fish
or stuff that would be oxidized or you
know otherwise would be harmful if it
went through that adjuster try
the fish so in my experience aquariums
go bad quickly now granted you know my
aquariums you know I probably had thirty
five forty gallon breeder aquariums so
forty gallons is is not a lot of water
mass if you will total volume to buffer
itself so so if something got out of
whack it really got out of whack quickly
so I got a two-part question for you
number one what is the normal range for
the size of these aquariums even if you
have multiples of them that you're
you're pulling your water from and does
the amount of water plus the fact that
it's filtering to a certain degree
through some amount of soil does that
all just kind of like buffer it all and
and make it way less likely that things
are gonna go bad really quickly because
like every other you know testing every
other week doesn't sound often enough so
the there's kind of two two parts to
that so one the main systems that I see
people growing cannabis and is you know
two IBC systems which is around four
hundred gallons of water for the home
grower and that's kind of the normal
size I guess that I see the most just
two of those IBC style aquaponic systems
that there's lots of public information
on and how to build and then for the
commercial systems I'm mostly seeing
stuff that's in the thirty twenty
thousand gallon to 30,000 gallons size
systems oftentimes split into either
five to ten thousand gallon sections
that are that are loops on their own
that can all be either cross plumbed or
separated into individual systems
depending on you know the needs and
desires of the the system operator at
the time but that I guess probably isn't
the the the - the - I guess layouts I
know most of the systems that I'm
designing are right around 10,000
gallons between 8 and 10,000 gallons per
loop which is a sub tanks fish tanks and
filtration in grow beds and that
generally provides a you know a 3,000
square-foot Bay sometimes we'll get
maybe a 4,000 square foot betta again
depending on the greenhouse dimensions
and so
this this sheer size just slows down the
speed at which any imbalance can
proliferate oh absolutely so the in an
aquarium what happens is that you have a
high nitrogen the ammonia and and fish
waste build up and cause it gets
converted by microbes into nitrates and
nitrates get higher and higher and
higher and then they can dissolve down
or they end up dissolving the alkalinity
or dissolved carbonate hardness which
then when that gets super low causes an
instability in pH and then the pH
crashes which in a very large volume of
water it becomes almost impossible to do
that without having to go to pretty big
extremes I mean it's absolutely possible
but you have to really strip the water
down or use RO water from the beginning
or or something else that has no
stability to it but a healthy system
will have carbonates especially if
you're dosing with the right nutrients
you know if you end up low in carbonate
so you can always dose with potassium
bicarbonate again you can get that Alma
recertified able and and then you're
adding you know to carbonate sand one
potassium for everything for every dose
I was thinking about you know the the
likelihood of the the aquariums to go
south on me and then it occurred to me
that that really the even though the
aquarium and the fish are there to serve
the cannabis grow what essentially the
cannabis grow is is a big badass filter
for the aquariums and makes it way way
less likely than you know a traditional
aquarium to go south on you just because
you have this elaborate living filter
absolutely the the biggest pitfalls I
guess the short to go back to what your
original question was is is pH and
temperature if you're maintaining your
pH and you're maintaining your
temperature either through heaters or
chillers or a combination thereof
depending on your climate it's going to
be pretty hard to have an outbreak short
of someone dosing something into the
system it shouldn't be in there or loose
electrical current or
your neighbor over sprays with
glyphosate but in a commercial facility
yeah it turns the if anyone's curious in
aquaponics glyphosate will turn the
plants ivory from the top down they go
from green to ivory in about two days
Wow that sounds really interesting I do
you think I need to pull up a picture of
that online to check that out so so one
more question here but before we move on
to this new interesting project that
you're working on so you know when we're
talking about soil there are ways that
the soil can no longer allow us to tend
to it and and what I mean specifically
is we can get a compaction layer right
that becomes hydrophobic and we go to
water and the water just you know goes
off the the side of the top of the pot
and down the sides and right out the
holes on the bottom and so we are drying
out our pot because the top layer is
hydrophobic
similarly somebody's pH could get all
screwed up and and we'll get what people
generally call nutrient lock out and so
these are these are both ways where
we're trying to do our best for the
plants but the the ecosystem is saying
oh we're too far down this path is there
anything like that in hydroponics is
there a way that the system can can try
to lock you out from making your changes
absolutely so I would say the biggest
similarity with that would be if you
don't have adequate filtration you could
end up with sludge buildup in your
stumps and your grow beds and that can
absolutely lock up nutrients and things
like that and one of the ways we
mitigate that is again through healthy
microbes lactobacillus and other compost
tea amendments but I into your beds
occasionally but also with one of my
favorite creatures we have in system
which are black worms which if your
aquarium person I'm sure you remember
those little tiny black rooms you got
the pests or the live feed your tropical
fish well when you put them in your
aquaponic system they love to feed on
the bacteria and things like that they
go in those little little anaerobic
pockets so they'll actually go out and
seek that out and tunnel through them
and bring oxygenated water into those
and break them up and actually seek out
those areas like little you know
anaerobic he see
missiles that go and break up those
areas so I actually put them in all the
aquaponic beds and they're one of this I
guess secret weapons I guess that I
would use say that we use to eliminate
sludge because they do such a good job
and they'll kind of maintain their
population based on the amount of sludge
in there and if they end up blowing
through and they have some baby fish
there great fish food too so you know
they're there they don't really hurt
anything and they're just like a great
way to clean it along with your red
wigglers and your earthworms that you
would have in your grow beds you can I
have three different sizes and they can
break up all that waste and keep
everything nice and flowing and and
again to keep the biologicals going as
long as the dissolved oxygen is high
enough even those worms don't care about
being submerged right on right on so
let's finish up talking about these cool
projects you've got going on like your
you have a unique situation because
since you design and design-build
aquaponics for folks you essentially go
to where the work is it's not like you
have setup where you know where you live
and then you know you set up your grow
and then you kind of like stay put you
are a traveling guy and so from what I
understand right now you're in Oklahoma
but then you know you've got some great
news that you're going to share with us
you haven't talked about publicly so so
why don't you tell us just like what
you're doing in Oklahoma and then a
little bit about this project before we
wrap up sure so I'm here in Oklahoma
there's a couple of different aquaponic
producers out here that I've been
helping do both design work and an SOP
work and some troubleshooting work for
some guys it got started a little bit
before I came out here and really do it
you know helping get that munch on back
on track and kind of helping the guys
out here get used to the the normal
regulated market that we've all grown to
love and Oregon and California and
Washington and you know who doesn't love
hours of paperwork so you know and just
crossing your eyes and dotting your
cheese and you know doing that whole
thing but depending on when this episode
airs you'll be the first place to this
guess announced is uh we're gonna be are
gonna be part of a company I'm gonna
leave out the other people that are on
it just because I don't know when this
is launching because of that part can't
be out before the press release but I
can I got permission to say the rest of
this but we have a company called a
Jillian and we
to have one of the as far as I'm aware
one of the largest we currently have one
of the largest licenses on the planet we
have in terms of how many thousands of
hectares it is but we're going to begin
starting in about three or four weeks I
don't know what the yeah about four
weeks from now we'll begin planting in
South Africa we have one hundred and
forty seven thousand square foot
facility we're going to be bloating out
as phase one and then rolling into
thousands and thousands of hectares once
or that facility is basically good a
function as a nursery for for our
thousands of hectares that we're going
to be producing out of South Africa
which is going to be a lot of fun
it's a lot of fun working on a project
that's this scale and working with some
of the amazing people that are on our
team we have people that you've had on
your show before that are part of our
team and it's really going to be awesome
to kind of do something that's not only
large-scale but you know we're
generatively minded and sustainably
minded but also you know gives back to
the local community as well we'll be
looking working hand-in-hand with local
farmers and making sure that a lot of
the local farmers as well are getting
you know a large percentage of the
profits back into the country and that
it's not just getting exported out of
there like a normal situation so we'll
have a lot more details coming on out on
that one in the press release along with
the groups that we're working with and
some of the other big names that are
part of the project but I'm super stoked
on that and will be once the
constructions are on the nursery as far
as I'm aware we'll have allergic largest
aquaponics facility on the planet wow
that's a good ragging rates right there
and then it's going to be cannabis
that's awesome you know you know what if
you would hit on the equity aspect of it
because you or telling me about that a
little bit earlier and I still think
that cannabis equity is is new to a lot
of folks and I think that's a really
interesting aspect of your project sure
so we have a couple of different
licenses that we have under that but
part of those licenses are half owned by
the African Farmers Association over
there and so I'm sure I'm mispronouncing
the actual name of the group again I
don't have the paper in front of me at
the moment but um well
we're gonna be donating it to them which
is going to be awesome so they're they
own half the license and we'll be
working hand in hand with their farmers
to get breast practices as well as um
you know a way for them to export it
back out of there we're also working
with a track and trace program that
we've developed that's going to be part
of our system for that so allow farmers
to get paid directly as well from people
and even allow people to pay ahead of
time for those runs you know if you have
a farmer and he's really skilled and you
have someone overseas that wants to put
money down on their next run because
they thought the last one was bomb and
was really good this allows people to do
that and allow these farmers access to
money that would be totally off limits
or or it would be filtered out by the
guys at the docks or the ports or all
the other 10,000 ways that these guys
get ripped off that we all know about
and a half of us have had done to
ourselves so it's going to kind of
streamline all that and move the banking
directly into that kind of system and
remove a lot of the potential for the
middlemen and just work out solid
contracts for transport and simplify and
get rid of a lot of the the riffraff and
a lot of stuff that both scares away
investors but also really screws over
the farmers that are actually the dudes
that are growing the we that have the
skills and the knowledge to give us the
medicine that we want in the first place
and we all know how much those guys get
screwed in these four I mean anyone
that's been in Jamaica or any of these
other places knows how badly those guys
get screwed over and and robbed in a lot
of cases as well so this is going to
help really break through a lot of that
and and you know it's going to be really
awesome so we'll have a facility at both
in Cape Town and then over in East
London for phase one and then we have a
rollout and a couple of other areas in
the Phase two how exciting that's going
to be might you know two things come to
mind right away is that number one just
the the cool cultural aspects of being
in South Africa and the beauty and the
different insects and the cool trees and
the different sunsets and and the
different smells and like just being
somewhere exotic that's gonna be really
cool but also to be living there for a
while and to get your hands on all these
like varieties of African land races
that you're gonna have your hands on
because you're gonna be meeting cool
people who live there there are also
cannabis folks I mean my god dude you've
got to be so excited
oh dude I am super stoked I'm not even
more stoked because the cultivars that
have been doing the best in Oklahoma
actually have been the malawi the Swazi
and the Durban crosses that we have so
it's been funny that like I've been
growing those pretty much all summer and
now I'm going to be going and growing
them again and a couple of weeks here
we're gonna been begin planting November
first but we got to do a little bit of
setup and training with the guys what
one interesting thing is when you go to
these more far-flung places as a lot of
times you have to redo all of your
education material into Ikea directions
because a lot of these guys don't they
know a little bit of English on reading
and writing but they don't know a lot of
reading and writing so you have to
basically redo all of your manuals
instructions and SOPs and is something
with pictures because or video otherwise
you can't just rely on not to be forever
like so a resource so that's definitely
a challenge that I've found especially
working in Jamaica I ended up going back
home for a couple weeks and coming back
with my whole DVD collection you know a
bunch of the Jorge Cervantes DVDs and
mr. mr. green thumb' and all the old go
ones and the vehicle VHS and I gave them
out I was like here watch all these
because frankly they did you know it's
the easiest way to try and you know wrap
their heads around some of the concepts
that otherwise can be quite difficult to
explain without having visualizing you
know without visualizing it and that's
been another challenge I found you know
both in South Africa and working with
some of the guys down there but also in
Jamaica again it's not like pooh-poohing
them for for not knowing that it's just
a challenge that comes with the industry
especially with farmers that have been
you know hey if you're a really good
farmer and you're crushing it and you're
doing well on food production we you
don't really need to learn to read you
know at any point is if you're trained
well I mean you obviously you do for
self growth but I mean if point of
reliance you can get by in a lot of
parts of the world you know just fine
yeah I understand that right on dude
well Steve thank you so much for taking
your time to share all this with us and
I gotta tell you you know it's it's very
exciting to find out that you know this
thing that I love this the soil food web
and that I've been studying that now
there is an equally sized if
deeper and more unstudied rabbit hole to
go down in this water food web and and
it's just fantastic that you you know
helped us open this door up for a lot
more people so thanks so much for
sharing your expertise absolutely thanks
sir thanks for having me on and yeah if
anyone's a college kid looking for a way
to make a mark for yourself for a way to
develop products get into the aquatic
mineralization stuff there's there's
probably billions of dollars of
microbial products in there you know
worth of research you know it's a wide
open field and something you can
definitely do well for yourself in and
and they do you mind if I mentioned the
podcast you know no go ahead I was gonna
plug it but you go ahead and go yourself
yeah sure so uh so I also have the
growing with fishes podcast is inspired
by people such as yourself that go out
there and put out a hardcore education
on and try to get you know the realm
away from the Cheech and Chong and more
into academia and more into science as
much as we love the old old ways doesn't
really help us get taken as seriously by
the agricultural field and advances and
you know in the sciences so it's really
awesome to have you know more science
oriented podcast and we have a podcast
every week on Tuesdays and Thursdays at
6:30 p.m. and we have a guests from all
over in fact Shengo was just on it not
too long ago and you can check out his
interview on there as well and yeah I'm
just trying to put out education every
week that circus around regenerative
soil and aquaponics so if you want to
hear more from aquaponic canvas expert
Steve razor and you know you do you can
check out the growing with fishes
podcast that it's going to be on your
favorite podcasting app you can also
check out his incredible YouTube channel
at youtube.com forward slash potent
ponics and there you will find
instructional videos from Steve as well
as videos of the growing with fish's
podcast as a video including Hangouts
with a whole cast of interesting
characters and if you're really into the
education aspect and you want to find
out more about Steve Reznor's education
classes you can go to his website at a
p.m.
class.com and you can find out about
upcoming classes there you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shaping fire
comm and on Apple iTunes stitcher and
Google Play if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you'd leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where i will be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host
Shango lows
[Music]