[Music]
happy New Year it's been so cold over
the entire country this week here on
Bashon Island where I live windchill got
well below zero and some of the Southern
States had windchill of like -40 and
-60° fhe that's ridiculous when it gets
this cold my old house is miserable the
poor insulation here just lets the cold
right through and I have to bundle up
and keep moving until the weather
changes several parts of the country are
without power too cold and no
electricity makes life dangerous and
unbearable the parts of my Island that
have no power have put their freezer
foods outside in the icy cold to stay
fresh some folks are grilling their
defrosting expensive meat and seafood so
they can enjoy eating them before losing
them in case the weather warms before
the electricity comes back some folks
are even leaving town to stay with
relatives and believe it or not this is
the theme of today's shaping Fire
episode just like humans get miserable
and crappy weather so does the microb
life in your cannabis soil too much
water too little water not enough
Sunshine Too Much Sunshine Too Little
carbon too much carbon too hot too cold
Frozen yikes I imagine the microbes also
putting all their little Foods out in
the front yard and having the
neighborhood over for a big freezing
barbecue yeah that's right get ready for
a lot of anthropomorphizing of microbes
today because microbes are people
too if you want to learn about cannabis
Health cultivation and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make make sure you don't miss an
episode you are listening to shaping
fire and I am your host Shango Los
welcome to
episode2 my guest today is Michael Deli
Michael Deli earned his masters from
Colorado State University's
Horticultural Department in 2020 where
he researched different facets of plant
microb interactions including nematode
biocont control methods microbial
legacies resulting from replanting
Fields And even the caterpillar gut
microbiome now serving as the director
of microbiology at impello biosciences
his research surrounds the overlap
between biological and biochemical
agricultural inputs targeted towards
both crop and soil Health properties
Cannabis sativa is one of their model
organisms for agriculture research and
one of Michael's projects is to examine
the functional bacterial species
recruited by Cannabis sativa in the
rizosphere during the first set today we
will discuss bio stimulants and plant
growth regulators and how to approach
them as regenerative cannabis
cultivators in the second set we will
discuss the care and tending of
microlife in the rizosphere and during
the third set we will choose companion
plants for soil diversity and finish the
episode with an indictment of the
24-hour light strategy welcome to
shaping fire
Michael hi sheno thank you so much for
having me I'm very grateful to be here
awesome really glad that you made time
for us so let's get right into it you
know um cannabis farmers are always
looking for like a leg up something
winning to add to their recipe and um a
lot of us look for different things that
could be determined to be bio stimulants
and then a subsection of those people
are are people mostly who follow this
show who are uh regeneratively minded
Farmers so so they're they're they're
looking for natural bio stimulants
versus synthetic ones let's start out
the show by talking about what bios
stimulants are generally and then we'll
start to tease apart the synthetic ones
from natural ones so so that's my first
question for you um what are bio
stimulants and um and what are the kind
of kinds of attributes that we look for
them to impart on our cannabis
plants absolutely yeah um so I mean I
like to think of biostimulants as a
really large umbrella term with several
different kind of facets of of products
or inputs that people can use or they
can take advantage of that might be in a
natural system um but I guess in essence
you know they are they're very much
performance enhancers for plant growth
and
metabolism is how I kind of Define bio
stimulus so when so when we say
performance um um are we talking about
specifically like the the um the
Gathering of nutrition the processing of
nutrition uh improved photosynthesis
essentially all of the plants um
biological systems get get kind of like
tweaked up the governor is turned up on
all of them so they're running either
more efficiently or faster is that's the
idea yeah I think that's a really good
way to put it and you know different
parts of Bio stimulant will uh
upregulate different parts of the plant
metabolism or or growth uh rates and
things like that um but yeah I think uh
the uh primarily I look at these as you
know biological products things like
microorganisms and and biochemicals um
things that are usually plant derived or
discovered in nature and then used uh um
to upregulate the plant metabolism
whether that's with hormones or um amino
acids fulvic acids things like that I
like this term up regulate um uh I've
heard it before but I don't use it
regularly and um I like it both for the
biology conversation but it also sounds
like a great um euphemism for getting
high like like oh man I need to go up
regulate that's awesome I like that a
lot so so let's let's let's tease apart
now the synthetic and the and the
natural bio stimulants because we're
we're mostly going to be talking about
um natural bio stimulants today um so
what
when I discuss bio natural bio
stimulants with other regenerative
Growers we're usually talking about um
you know this or that plant that we are
going to you know do a a tea of or an
extract of or or a or a you know a top
dress of something like that because we
want uh some U naturally occurring
biochemical that's in the plant we want
that to seep into our biosphere and then
when at the conventions when I talk with
the synthetic bio stimulant sales guys
their products have always got these
like multi- cabic names that that um
sound very scientific and sometimes
they've you know they've also been named
at some marketing name and so they have
got a a real different vibe to them um
perhaps they're perhaps the natural ones
and the synthetic ones are both trying
to do the same things but I'm I'm
guessing they have got different
attributes that that you can share with
us yeah absolutely so I I would think
like um a lot of times when I when I
think about synthetic bio stimulants
whether that's something that is you
know uh discovered through a natural
process and then you know one compound
is isolated it really seems a lot to me
like the pharmaceutical industry we find
one active ingredient we purify it you
know it shows in a lab and on the bench
that this is effective at whatever we're
trying to uh alleviate um and then all
of the uh you know medicine is built off
of that compound um and that's kind of
how I look at like the synthetic aspect
of that where potentially there's a
there's a chance of missing some other
minor chemicals or you know metabolites
that might be from a natural product
extract um that would be missed uh when
things are just synthesized in a lab
versus uh extracted through a natural
process like making it compost tea or or
breaking down other um forms of of
organic inputs like uh fish waste or
even you know corn waste things like
that hearing you describe it it actually
reminds me a lot of how we talk about
the Entourage effect and the difference
between isolates and whole plant it
sounds a lot like the synthetic um the
synthetic bio stimulants are often like
isolates they are an isolated
biochemical that we're going to apply
the plant one way or another versus the
compost tea kind of flavor that's more
like taking a whole plant medicine
because we're getting all these these
random uh plant constituents that um
that we may not have even researched yet
but we know that as a symphony they they
interact really well with the human body
um what do you think about that yeah I
would agree with that I think it's
really similar to how people talk about
the Entourage effect of of cannabis and
you know turboid and things like that um
the same thing goes for you know whether
these these compounds whether a
synthetic or natural bio stimulant is is
directly influencing the plant there's a
there's a good chance it is it's also
really helping out like the soil
microbiome most likely uh things like
you know the upper regulation of theism
can be a factor of uh an increased rate
of you know soil respiration or soil
organic matter or just general
beneficial soil ecological components um
you know things like amino acids uh of
the things or one of the um smaller
terms underneath the larger bio
stimulant umbrella can become building
blocks for protein synthesis in both
plants and microbes um so by providing
that source that might be you know
deficient in the soil or um you know out
competed by other mic Gres if a a grower
can add that in there um whether that's
helping the plant directly or the soil
ecology the whole system is benefited at
least um from what we've
seen so um you know I I re I do
recognize that I've got a certain amount
of prejudice against synthetic bio
stimulant simply because they are
synthetic and I know that um that is
often unfair of me just to uh discount
things because they're synthetic um you
know outside of the fact that just on
its face I prefer organic gardening and
organic food and organic seeds because I
like to um you know have my garden be as
close to Nature as possible um is there
really any you know a priori reason to
discount or not include synthetic bio
stimulants um and and what what I'm
going to compare it to is you know we
often talk about you know B bottled salt
fertilizer on this show about how they
kind of force feed nutrition to cannabis
plants and by doing that um you know you
might get a robust plant but you're also
getting a plant that is out of balance
and over the long term is more
susceptible to plants and can have all
sorts of other problems because you're
you're forcing it right now um is there
is are there any mechanisms like that
with synthetic bio stimulants that are a
reason to reject them because of how
they function instead instead of just me
being Prejudice because they are not
organic no I understand where you're
coming from with the um the synthetic
Prejudice and I I kind of adapt similar
principles like in my own gardening and
and things like that um I guess I want
to ask you a question about uh what
might be considered I guess synthetic to
take a step back here um I'm familiar
with a process uh for an amino acid
product that is um taking waste from the
fishing industry so lots of shrimp
shells and and crab shells and things
like that and then they're put into a
reactor uh a couple enzymes are added to
break down the the fish waste or the you
know the crustacean waste um and then
the end product is both uh you know
amino acids and and kiten and other
things like that um so that is you know
synthetically the the breakdown process
is synthetically increased with these
enzymes in the reaction um but if you
were to kind of slowly compost you know
shrimp and crab shells and and things
like that in your soil you might have a
similar uh endpoint product or you know
beneficial effect of the soil system um
so I guess how do you feel about that
kind of process is that would you call
that more synthetic kind of Towing the
line between the two of them or just is
that purely synthetic cuz you know lab
equipment and bioreactors are involved
yeah it's an interesting question to
kind of tease the definition um uh
definitely at at from the top I'll say
the word synthetic is a messy term cuz
it it's it's kind of like a it's it's
it's a bucket of ideas that are
different to pretty much everybody who
hears the word and it is best applied on
a on a Case by case basis based on what
you are you know based on this little
example though um it sounds like that is
a um a a
non It's Tricky right yeah it is tricky
it sounds like it's a natural process
right it's it sounds like you're you're
just processing by adding other natural
processes so it's you've got you've got
natural natural naturally occurring
product a and you're adding naturally
occurring products B and C and you know
you put them together and it causes the
breakdown to happen into a you know a
usable nutrition faster um you know if
we were to if we were to go long on this
and make it the you know the the brunt
of the show I would probably have to ask
a bunch of questions about what are the
natures of the inputs and and where that
line might be drawn between um you know
adding adding inputs that that um either
inhibit natural reactions or create
non-natural reactions
to get whatever you're trying to you
know produce produce but but um that's a
slippery slope right there of course
right absolutely yeah um and yeah I
think I mean you know the processes
would would uh you know um theoretically
occur in nature just a little bit longer
time for those enzymes to unlock some of
the the polymers like things in you know
the exoskeletons of crustaceans um but
yeah we are synthetically or you know in
this type of process development uh
somebody would be synthetically
upregulating or increasing the rate of
decom to make these things um you know
in a more plant usable form that way the
plants and the soil microbes have to
expend less energy um on breaking down
things and they can just be you know
slurped up and used uh efficiently um so
yeah I think it kind of tells the line
between synthetic and natural but one
thing that is is kind of cool in
processes such as these um I know
there's similar ones for corn and soy uh
based bio stimulants um they do put a a
use an end use product to things that
might be considered waste material prior
to um these types of
reactions and I guess we just want to
make sure that that waste material is
handled in a responsible way if if we're
going to produce it at all absolutely
and you know when it is not waste
material when it's you know host
material for a a crustacean farmer or a
corn or sore farmer we want to make sure
that uh those plants or or animals are
being treated and uh you know uh the
management practices of cultivating
those are also not going to influence
the inputs that we want to feed our
plants later MH mhm so um so let's talk
a little bit about um some of the the
natural bio stimulants that come up uh
the most often in cannabis cultivation
I'm thinking uh humic and fulvic acids
seaweed extracts uh different types of
microbial inoculants and then amino
acids which you've already mentioned um
are these all are are these different
types of natural bio stimulants working
on um different um uh bi iCal systems of
the cannabis plant or are they all
essentially acting on the same system
but in different
ways yeah they would definitely um act
on you know the same system as a whole
the plant the soil the microbes and
whatnot but every every part everything
you just mentioned has a slightly
different uh effect on the biome from
what I understand um you know humix and
fvix can be great sources of organic
matter for both the plant and the soil
microbes to use as inputs uh whereas
things like seaweed extracts often
contain plant hormones like cyto content
and um um I think some phosphorus or
potassium as well um so we get a little
bit of Plant Nutrition from there as
well as some you know plant hormones
applied outside of the plant body rather
than being produced within it um
microbial inoculants I think these guys
uh really depends on your soil and the
history of that that system or your
indoor cultivation system um but those
were primarily you know uh if they're
administered in a drench be uh
benefiting the root systems of the
plants as well as the neighboring
microbes that might already be there and
then we have you know foler spray
microba inoculants too that help um out
compete things that might be negative to
plant performances like molds and stuff
like that um so yeah it it really is a
whole system of of uh effects you know
different different building blocks U
from the bio stimulant world will help
different areas of the plant as you
mentioned and um yeah it's it's it's a
fun big umbrella term because there's so
much going on underneath the the
umbrella that is bio stimulant mhm it's
also sounds like it's a very fine line
between bio stimulant and nutrition um
because some of the you know some of the
positive attributes that you mentioned
from seaweed extracts are different um
you know
nutritive um substances is is there a
line is there a scientific line between
nutrition and bio stimulants or or do
they kind of like SE into each other a
lot of times
I think the line is maybe dotted as
opposed to uh you know less of a
gradient less of a firm line um where
that where a lot of biostimulant
compounds can have some form of NPK or
even micronutrients in there um but then
when we look at Plant Nutrition those
are products with NPK is almost the
biggest number on the label besides the
product name for the most part um so
that's kind of how I see the separation
between you know nutritional inputs
versus bio stimulant based inputs but it
is kind of a gray area or a gradient
where you have some trickling effect of
of the um you know amino acid type bio
stimulants having some some form of NP
or K in them as well yeah at using that
definition it bio stimulant becomes
really really close to
um like like Trace nutrients and trace
minerals it's like oh if if you're not
talking about NPK and you're just
talking about everything else you're
you're talking about you know bio
stimulants um including things that we
don't get in in you know kind of
targeted generic fertilizers that we add
because we want to round out the ri the
risos spere with with um essential
micros yeah absolutely and um one other
thing to mention too is is you know
whether or not uh well another another
reason I guess that the the line between
nutrition and bio stimulation is maybe a
little bit more blurry at this point in
science uh is because things like um
certain bacteria have enzymes to unlock
uh unavailable forms of phosphorus such
as calcium phosphate so unavailable for
plant uptake um so you know there's no
nutrition in in that type of bacterial
product but it can help unlock nutrition
that might already be in your soil um
things like mizal products too I think
from what I've seen um also sometimes
have a a phosphorus content as well so
um you know somebody might apply a micro
risal product for the first time and see
a really great uh you know flowering
boost in their cannabis plants and it's
hard to attribute that to the mic rizy
being present or the The increased
amount of phosphorus being also
available for the plant or or probably
both yeah I wish that when we tried a
whole bunch of new things at the same
time and we get good results we could
just straight up ask the plant which one
caused it my
friend that would be amazing and yeah I
want I want to talk to the soil
microbiome as well I'm looking forward
to those developments maybe with AI
there we go so uh before we move on from
bio stimulants um Let's uh let's bring
this conversation and make it like real
um real rubber hits the road so for for
the cultivators who are listening um who
are like okay I understand the
difference between the synthetic and the
bio stimulants as much as we can get to
definitionally I like the idea of
offering natural bio stimulants to my
plants um what are some that you
recommend from the natural world that
regenerative farmers can um use at home
that will have you know reliably good
effects you know some of some of the
stuff is so obscure and its impact is so
small that you can have a debate about
whether some of these did anything at
all in particular but but what are a
couple like tried and true naturally
occurring bio stimulants that um that
our listeners can um you know explore
for for pretty assured benefit yeah I
mean I think a lot of it really depends
on where your plants are going to be
going if it's going into a hydroponic or
controlled environmental system um
versus a soil system um you know plays a
role but but I am biased to the the soil
microbes and the root adhering microbes
or the plant growth promoting microbes
so we're we he at shaping fire so yeah
absolutely uh so yeah I mean from what
from what I've seen in both research and
at home cultivation uh the sooner
microbes get introduced to a plant rout
um I like to think about it as a really
good protective and enhancing form uh
one of my favorite analogies here is
think of that that radical that that
firstly emerged plant root from your
seed or your clone um being like an
empty seat at a table with you know
let's say 100 seats um the the plant is
going to be exuding root exibits all
over that table and um through the roots
and those are basically like adding
different types of food sources to the
the table here um the sooner that those
seats of the table can be colonized with
plant benefiting or soil ecology
benefiting or even just free living uh
microorganisms um maybe not colonized
but present and taking up space and
competing for resources the more likely
um the cultiv Ator uh would be you know
not seeing things like plant disease um
the if the seats can be full filled with
things like plant- benefiting
microorganisms um whether they're from a
compost system living soil uh indigenous
microorganism cultivating uh or even a
biological inoculant you can buy on a
shelf I think that is probably the best
way to really Prime young or new plants
for uh you know a successful Harvest
cycle um filling those seats up with the
table uh allowing resources to be used
by things that are maybe symbiotic or
mutualist with the plants to you know
the benefit is is a feedback loop um
whereas a pathogen might only you know
consume a root exit it until it can get
in high enough numbers to penetrate the
plant cell and then become pathogenic uh
the less seats at that table that are
for things like fusarium or phyo or
pythium um the less likely uh you know
that plant is going to have a negative
effect I really like that seats at a
table uh um example that I can really
Envision that and so so your first
answer is to you know add a bunch of uh
you know of of indigenous microbes um so
that the seats of the table can get
filled with um with probiotic folks
before anything pathogenic shows up and
um you uh and there's a you know there's
a there's a there's a range of ways that
we talk about on this show to add
microbes and and and you're like just
you know add them add them right away as
soon as as soon as the plant starts um
for the second one is there something
that might be more nutrition based
instead of like having good neighbors
based like microbes that you would also
recommend as a um naturally occurring
bio stimulant yeah so I think my my bias
is really going to show with this answer
but um uh you know I talked about the
probiotics right I also think the
prebiotics are just as important
especially in in soilless systems or or
you know uh near sterile systems right
Hydroponics and things like that um
plants evolve roots with their
relationships with microbes uh Dr White
and all of his research surrounding
riseof Fiji has really been a beneficial
disruption in in agricultural research
and I think that uh a lot of Growers
have tried really hard to maintain a
sterile system which you know your
plants don't want sterile systems
they're often you know exuding uh cakes
and cookies sugars and carbon into the
the surrounding soils to try to get
microbes to colonize there so uh a long
way to answer your question I think like
prebiotics things like organic materials
humic fulvic acids um we know what those
can do to benefit the plant and and how
they are benefiting the soil microbiome
and how that's benefiting the plant is
still being kind of flushed out um but I
do think that uh your plants are going
to benefit from these compounds that
you're applying whether or not they're
for the plant or the bacteria and uh
usually the application rates from
things whether you're whipping up a
compost tea or doing like a a plant
extract or purchasing something um
there's enough to go around for both the
plants and the microbes fantastic I love
that when we keep on coming back to you
know grab plants that are already in
your yard and let them um decay in water
you know spin that for 36 hours and then
pour that back on your plants I love
that cycle bringing back um you know
what's already in your yard the plants
the grass clippings the forest Duff
whatever it is incubate it for a little
bit to make those microbes super
abundant and then just pour it back on
your
plants yes absolutely yeah I mean that
and it's it's always you know a fun term
is like kind of bioprospecting being out
um in in soil in the woods in the forest
or anywhere that you know it's okay to
kind of I'm going to use the word sample
from um I know you guys have talked
about indigenous microorganisms here um
but yeah like the the ability to kind of
collect some microbial diversity um from
maybe a forest or uh somebody with a
better historical soil Health practice
than maybe the plot you inherited um is
also a great way to you know add that
microbial diversity um if you you know
we have these like Notions of of plant
micro symbiosis uh in science where you
know we want to look at a really happy
cannabis plant and then collect some
soil microbes from its roots and then
take that home and apply it to our
cannabis plants so they do well too um
but there's a lot of functional
redundancy in the the risos spere
microbiome World whether that's a tree
or a cannabis plant or some grass um so
you might even be able to get some type
of beneficial microbial function from
sampling something like grass uh and
applying it to your to your home grow or
you know making a compost tea out of it
or a soil slurry right on so uh so dear
listener if you're very interested in in
moving uh these microbes around um sit
tight because we're going to be coming
back to this topic again with set two or
in set two so Michael um I want to move
us on past bio stimulants now uh to what
I consider one of their cousins that I
know less about which is uh plant growth
regulators and you know I I first got
turned on to uh plant growth Regulators
kind of as a as a slur as a disc when I
would come across like really rock hard
um indoor rockwool Buds and that that
you know I I would squeeze them and as a
you know as a as a lifelong outdoor
grower when you squeeze my flowers
there's there's some give to them
whereas these were like like literally
rocks and I was all like what what kind
of cannabis is this right and people are
like you know because I tend to hang out
with you know organic farmers they'd say
something like ah it's those pgrs that
they use you know and I'm like I don't
know what those are but but I I
certainly don't want any part of that
and and over time I realize it's true
that synthetic pgrs and and what they
have a tendency to do to the plant are
not something that I'm normally going
for but then I started to realize um
while while studying the soil food web
that there are actually naturally
occurring um biochemicals in plants that
um you know that we can Wildcraft that
also are pro um plant growth Regulators
so that maybe you can get you know
harder flowers that have got a a market
attraction and an aesthetic attraction
in ways that don't also um
you know injure the plant and make it
you know need to be grown in a sterile
environment instead of the yard so so so
I'm going to ask you number one would
you would you would you explain for us
what plant growth Regulators are and um
where we may find them in uh the natural
world yeah um so the way I kind of
understand plant growth Regulators would
be just kind of um hormones uh the the
plant hormones things like oxin
gibberellins cyto canines and uh you
know natural sources of those things
like seaweed is a really U common input
used for cyto in uh pgrs um I think um
like we talked about a little bit
earlier uh you know when you do the
wildcrafting and you do the natural Pro
uh process and and take your plant
inputs or get materials and do the
extraction yourself you are likely
getting things that might be missed as
opposed to when an oxin is purified in a
lab and dried out into a powder and then
you know mailed to you in a tube to dip
your plant roots in before rooting them
um yeah I mean the way I kind of see
them would just be plant hormones uh
whether they're natural or synthetic I
think they can be helpful for Growers
and you know helpful for making uh
deadlines and yield improvements and
quality improvements and things like
that um but uh yeah I I still kind of am
in the school of thought of you know
these these natural processes like
breaking down uh organic inputs um would
we're probably missing something when
we're applying just the pure com
compound but uh further you know science
needs to prove that so so for talking
about you know getting these oxin and
cyto and gibin and and and putting them
on and they we're getting them from
Plants it sounds awful lot like we're
talking about bio stimulants again and
and and and perhaps there is an argument
to be made that plant growth regulators
and natural bio stimulants are all in
the bucket of plants that have got
chemicals hormones and Nutri
that are also used by the cannabis plant
that we just want to Wildcraft or what's
that term you used
bioprospect um you know on our
properties and and then just allow them
to either degrade in their basic form or
incubate them with you know oxygen and
then apply them to our plants it it
sounds like it's the same system just
using different vocabulary yeah I would
agree with you on that I do think like
you know the pgr term fits fits nicely
underneath the umbrella term that is bio
stimulants in my world um and maybe the
world uh but yeah you know you think
about um how these compounds
um mainly you know the plant is
naturally producing these things when it
needs Roots there's oxin being produced
inside the plant um to to Signal those
Mar stem cells to turn into Roots um but
having you know furthered science in
agriculture we as Growers can can use
these things to get effects that we want
to I know um in a lot of the ornamental
crop industry things like uh anti-
gibberellins are sprayed on you know
flowers to keep them like tight and uh
you know not too laggy or stretched out
from the pot that way they make a nice
compact bushy you know poinsetta or
Zenia or something like that um so yeah
it's interesting to think about the use
of pgrs in products that are going to be
consumed by people rather than just
enjoyed by uh like aesthetically like
flowers and and things like that um and
I think
um I need to do more reading on on you
know the the the uh the consumption of
things that might be residual on flour
if the plant wasn't able to use all them
and or even just surfactants to get them
to spread as well so when I had talked
with other regenerative Farmers about
the naturally occurring pgrs that they
use I only have ever gotten one response
either either the farmers don't think of
them in that way and so they're just
using degraded plant you know compost
teas or or spun erated teas so they
they'll either say nothing they don't
they don't use one intentionally or they
will say banana peels and so so um are
is there any oh this is kind of a nice
pun is there any lwh hanging fruit that
you recommend where where we can go for
um the the hormones that have the effect
on the cannabis plant that we're looking
for so we don't have to go to synthetics
for example if if we want tighter
flowers and a more compact overall plant
uh do we want to go to a banana peel or
are there things that we may have access
to that you think might be um you know
better for us to go after yeah I think
ultimately I don't have any sort of
materials off the top of my head on on
things like anti- gibberellins I know
seaweed is a good one for cytokinin um I
think people have used uh you know
Honeys for for auxins whether that's I'm
not sure if that's actually a root
increaser or if it's just a good
antimicrobial for or uh you know
pathogens that might infect the plant
before it can root um but yeah I mean I
I'm a huge composter um and I'm a big
fan of vermac compost as well yeah um so
I think you know doing that stuff in the
backyard when space allows uh there's
indoor systems that are really great too
I have a a friend that did like a three
bucket stack system where the worms were
in the the bottom the new food waste
went in the top and when they ran out of
food they would kind of dig up and kind
of make it a closed loop system so there
are ways to kind of get those organic
materials broken down depending on um
the space you might have um yeah I you
know the other kind of school of thought
too is when I was a lot younger I I was
always told you know dig a whole six or
seven feet underground bury a couple
dead fish there and that's where we'll
plant our cannabis plants the following
Spring right in the fall uh and it's
been cool to kind of enter more of the
sciency realm of this kind of stuff and
seeing like oh well yeah the fish breaks
down into ammonium or some form of nh4
or 3 um and the emulsions and you know
they they provide nutrition from those
break down products um so I just just
one thing that I love about the Cannabis
science Industry is or just cannabis
science in general is kind of seeing um
you know old school of thought Growers
with these really wise practices that we
are just now starting to understand uh
and can be measured scientifically with
with you know how does a fish break down
in the soil and what types of plant
inputs does it turn into yeah all all of
this old school um cultivation magic you
know eventually science catches up with
it and it's like oh oh yeah I guess I
guess you know the old hippies were
right in what they were doing absolutely
it's like yeah yeah everything old is
new again so right on well uh let's
let's wrap up this first set here um
we're going to take a short break and be
right back you are listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is
microbiologist Michael
[Music]
Deli revenue is tight for cannabis
businesses right now there is no
question about it and when Revenue
tightens businesses need to spend and
smarter on Advertising instead of
throwing obscene money at Hanging your
company's logo from the rafters at your
next convention perhaps consider placing
commercials on shaping fire and if you
are a very small business there is
simply no better bang for your buck than
commercials on shaping fire especially
if your products are for regeneratively
minded
cultivators advertising on this show
allows us time to talk about your
product service or brand in a way that
really lets people know what sets your
company apart from the others bold
people who own companies know that
getting into relationship with their
customers is essential that is what we
offer we will explain your service or
product what sets it apart as desirable
and help our audience get in contact
with you it's pretty simple really
advertising does not have to be all
whizbang smoke and mirrors nowadays I
find that people prefer just to be
spoken to calmly accurately and with
good intentions if you want to make your
own commercial spot you can do that too
with a commercial on shaping fire you'll
reach your customers in the privacy of
their headphones right now and will
continue to reach new listeners as they
explore the shaping fire back catalog of
episodes again and again for years a
spot on shaping fire costs less than a
postcard per person and the shaping fire
audience is full of smart cannabis
enthusiasts cultivators and
entrepreneurs who are always curious to
learn and right now in the New Year We
are booking the few open spots we have
for the rest of
2024 I'd love for you to be one of our
new
advertisers do yourself a solid and
contact us today for rates on podcast
and Instagram advertising email hotspot
shaping fire.com to find out
[Music]
more as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated it is increasingly important to
avoid the use of chemical pesticides
when cultivating cannabis beneficial
insects have been used for decades by
the greenhouse vegetable and ornamental
plant industry and today many cannabis
cultivators are moving from sprays and
chemicals to beneficial insects copert
has the beneficial insects mites and
nematodes microbials sticky cards and
air distribution units you need to
partner with nature to defend your
garden whether you manage Acres of
canopy or have a simple grow tent in
your home copert is ready to help answer
your questions and help you transition
away from chemical sprays towards clean
and natural
solutions since
1967 copert has assisted growers in
identifying pests and devising reliable
Solutions while providing healthy
insects and mites that will protect your
yield since the 1990s copert has been a
leader in cannabis Pest and Disease
Control worldwide and have highly
trained Consultants to assist you in
Canada and the United States from coast
to coast with their Global Network of
grower support copert can help visit
coper er.com choose your country and get
detailed information that's copert k p
pt.com for the most up-to-date cannabis
related biological control information
you can also check their Instagram at
copert Canada you know getting away from
pesticides is good for health and good
for business and copit is ready to help
visit ct.com
[Music]
today there are so many seed banks
nowadays that you really really have
options in who to choose not only that
if you pick the wrong seed bank you
could be in for a really sketchy ride
and that's only one of the reasons I
recommend Gas Lamp seeds to my friends
and listeners who are looking for a seed
bank you probably already know Gas Lamp
seeds as hembra genetics hembra recently
changed their name to Gas Lamp seeds Gas
Lamp seeds is not just another seed bank
gas lamp is a female operated Boutique
cannabis genetics provider that only
sells thoughtfully curated seeds from
the top names in cannabis breeding with
over 60 breeders and over a thousand
strains to choose from you will
certainly find something you'll love Gas
Lamp seeds has something for everyone
with over 650 feminized strains 300
regular varieties and over 200 autof
flowers to choose from names you know
you can trust like compound genetics
humble Seed Company Night Owl inhouse
fast buds gnome automatic and Ethos and
we both know that there are other seed
banks who will take your money but have
no customer service I invited Gas Lamp
to advertise on shaping fire after
hearing so many good stories about them
from my friends they have A+ customer
service with Lightning Fast Response
times in most cases holen and Caitlyn
will get your order out the same day you
place it most seed banks are simply not
this organized or interested in getting
your seeds to you so fast but gas slamp
seeds cares you even get free seeds with
every order Helen and Caitlyn get it
they have been in the Cannabis growing
scene for over a decade want some extra
freebies use the code shaping fire all
one word at checkout and they will give
you an additional set of gas lamp
provided freebies that's an extra $30 in
free seeds buy seeds from good folks who
will send you great seeds reliably every
time visit gas Gas Lamp seeds.com today
that's Gaslamp
seeds welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I am your host Shango Los
and my guest today is microbiologist
Michael Deli so during the first set we
talked all about um bio stimulant and
where to find them and nature as well as
um the idea of plant growth regulators
and we kept on coming back to this idea
that um what we want to do to help um
our cannabis plants the most is to help
the isosphere to make sure that the
nutrition and variety of microbes are
incredibly varied um are are indigenous
so that they survive in our local
natural environment and that we can
bioprospect them all over our own
property and near us uh by just going to
other plants that we already have
locally and um not only does that save
us money but we know that these plants
that are already surviving locally are
already covered in um indigenous
microorganisms M so saves US money and
is exactly the tool for the job to help
you have your best grow ever so here in
set two we're going to talk about the
care and tending of the microbe
Community that's in your rizosphere
right so these are these are um all of
the residents of the rizosphere the root
Zone um that make up the the the the
soil food web that is within the soil as
we all know the the soil food web also
is above the soil and it also takes
place in water but specifically we're
talking about this this neighborhood of
the roots of the cannabis plant so when
I was listening to Michael delie on um
our friend Leighton Morrison's show um
um uh he and I guess I guess I'm talking
to the audience Michael and to you kind
of third person you you were talking on
leighton's show um about your um uh uh
love of of bi bio which we're big fans
of on the show as well and and um and
and I really liked how you kind of
anthropomorphized uh the microbes CU you
were talking about how um uh how biochar
has got all these like you know ridges
and places to live and and they've got
these um these these environments that
the the microbes can set up housing and
and and where their nutrition grows and
and how it just kind of makes like for
this perfect neighborhood and and I
always like to think about my pots that
way too or or you know the soil that
that I want to make a good neighborhood
for my plants to grow EV been as well so
so so you you and I clearly enjoy
anthropomorphizing microbes which which
I can support um let's go ahead and
start just kind of generally with this
idea of of creating neighborhoods that
have got the kinds of attributes in the
soil that um that these neighborhoods
can build on what is the nature of soil
structure that makes good rizosphere
I think a good balance of um sand silt
and Clay obviously is is a great way to
you know that definition of soil makes a
good structure for the microbes to
colonize but I think a really important
thing that is often overlooked uh would
be things that we call Max Mac
microbially forms of accessible carbon
or microb accessible carbon um your
plants are you know constantly
depositing these things into the soil
through Ro exits uh as well as you know
any organic matter um and different
types of breakdown processes in soil or
other systems um can provide these forms
of Max uh carbon sources food sources
for the microbes to be in there um you
know biochar being carbon based is a
really great form of this other things
like full urines and um um different
like you know cellulous breakdown
products are another great way to kind
of feed microbes in the
soil so um so is the
primary uh is the primary I'll say the
first not the only but is the primary
attribute of creating a good
neighborhood making sure that there's
lots of these Max around so there's
always high quality carbon for them to
eat like at the top of the list I would
I would put that at the top of the list
just because uh if you apply something
like a biological to a a near sterile
system I I'll never call a hydroponic
system sterile um just because there's
microbes everywhere microbial ubiquity
uh but we do have you know the the
notion of a lot of that stuff can be
wasted if there's not food sources to to
feed the microbes you know you hear
about with your gut and gut health
prebiotics with probiotics um that's you
know feeding also the things that might
be resonant to your system whether or
not they're applied uh from a bottle or
from uh indigenous microorganism
hunting so so what are um sources of
these Macs that we can Wildcraft and and
how do we how do we process them into it
I mean the you know the biochar um you
know we can use as a soil amendment and
some people like to crush it up and and
um and you know top dress it into their
water so it slowly Works their way in
but give us give us some more idea of
how to think about these Macs and and
where we can bioprospect them into our
cultivation absolutely yeah I mean I
think um I'm going to do a call back to
bio stimulants right there's a lots of
Max uh in different tiers of BIOS
stimulant products or or uh things that
you can get or proc naturally with
wildcrafting um and essentially you know
the uh the plant is also feeding your
microbes so as long as your plants are
Health uh maintained Optimal Health and
nutrition there's going to be some
source of of Max in the system from the
roote exodites too um but you will you
know plants also can re-uptake root
exodites uh so there is a degree of
plant microbe competition for these food
sources um but going back to that kind
of old uh wisdom cultivation uh you know
thinking um people that I hear a lot of
people have really strong opinions about
applying molasses as a as a input and
during flower um and I've always kind of
understood that as we're feeding the
soil microbes rather than we're you know
giving sugar to help increase flour
synthesis or something like that yeah
yeah we've we've talked on the show many
times how you know the adding of
molasses into the pot um what you're
doing is throwing your your um your pot
out of balance what you want to do is if
you're going to use the Molasses is feed
the feed the micro in your in your air
rated compros Brewer let them eat the
Molasses there and incubate them so now
you have a whole bunch of them and then
put that compost tea That's not hot
anymore into your your rizosphere is is
that the are those the steps that you're
referring to yeah yeah I think that that
is probably the best practice to do it
um for those who you know aren't able to
kind of have the lead time to brew up a
compost tea and and feed it sugar and
whatnot I think um just a very diluted
form an irrigation solution can also
kind of benefit those those microbes
that might be in your roots right on I
want to push you a little bit on
specificity because you said that there
are um you know various plants that we
can Wildcraft where we can get the max
from um just for examples to get us
started because we all know that we can
like you know Google it or ask GPT or
something but from you will you give us
three Mac Rich plants that we might be
able to Wildcraft just so you know
people who just want to jump on it know
what where to
start you know I think um I'm always
going to go back to compost and those
breakdown processes um I I would when I
say you know you ask for specific plants
I don't know that I have any of those
off the top of my list but um I I think
you know carbon and nitrogen sources uh
essentially um can help increase
available Max uh whether whether or not
they are being added to your system or
the nutrients you know the compost pile
or something like that provided um but
in terms of kind of going out and and
foraging up a bunch of plants and making
a tea out of that I uh I would have to
do somewh research right on you know
your your hesitation kind of like
suddenly Rec contextualized everything
for me is is it potentially the answer
to the question I asked that um these
Macs are in everything because carbon is
a building block so so long as I'm
starting with a a local healthy thriving
plant it's going to have Max in it
so just use whatever I have a lot of
around me and use a variety of plants
that are around me and then if I want to
up it will then go ahead and do some
online research and find out the types
of plants that are more rich in Mac but
it it I'm starting to get the idea since
we keep on coming back to compost that
the Macs are everywhere and and so just
use whatever you have yeah yeah I would
agree with that thank you um and another
kind of way to put it you know is or
another I guess using whatever you have
should should be used with caution a
little bit as as a lot of people know
you know if you look for broken down
dried out plant material um you want to
make sure that didn't come from anything
diseased uh obviously you know you'd
want that to be fully broken down in a
composting system or a heat breakdown
type of format uh before you add
something that might be you know
degraded a you know a leaf loss due to a
zanth theonis bacteria in the leaf or
something like that right we don't want
to reintroduce that to our system but um
you know plant health is very important
too when you're when you're kind of
wildcrafting right on all that to say
all right so so when we're talking about
the care intending of microbes obviously
we want to include a lot of these Macs
so that there there's a a varied Buffet
all through the rizosphere um for for um
uh for all the varieties of of of
residents to eat so so let's go um so so
long as you think we've covered that
well enough let's go beyond the
nutrition for the microbes eating the
carbon and let's talk about some of the
other um attributes of soil structure
that might also be um um beneficial to
to the risos spere and and again I might
be over anthropomorphizing here but in
my notes I put like shelter reproduction
space you know you know um uh noncarbon
nutrition like like the idea of shelter
may not actually exist exists in soil in
the rizosphere but but it seems like it
should exist there because you have got
more more Predator residence in the
biosphere and more passive residents in
the biosphere and and you know normally
life forms need to take shelter when
they reproduce and so you know I I'm
very willing to be very wrong on this
right but but is it tell us a little bit
about how the community interacts
and if there are attributes of our soil
and amendments that that potentially
provide more of this shelter and
reproduction space and non-carbon
nutrition absolutely yeah I mean I think
uh the best place for plants to
overwinter um in terms of seasonal
changes would be in the roots and in the
in the kind of sketi plant bodies that
are no longer actively growing um that's
a great place for microbes to overwinter
and be ready to uh be introduced to your
plants when you're planting them in the
springtime and then I just do want to
Circle back a little bit on the ma stuff
and say one more thing um I want to go
back to I want to quote Dr elain Ingam
from the soil food web and say you know
what do microbes love uh sugars right
and that's why the cakes and cookies
that are the root exodites are really
kind of you know being deposited by the
plants in theory to to colonize or
recruit microbes to the to the root Zone
um the other thing that I wanted to
mention was going back to that that big
Open Table analogy with empty seats um
another kind of enhancement of this
theory is is like uh if that table is
being catered and and there is only you
know slabs of meat being put on that
table only only uh you know carnivore
type people are going to be sitting down
there to consume that stuff right so we
also want to provide a lot of diverse
inputs of of Max whether that is uh
different types of compost tea or sugar
sugars like molasses or you know just
comp uh broken down leaves and pine
straw and stuff like that um but the
important thing is by providing a lot of
different forms of microbial accessible
carbon we're feeding uh lots of
different functional microbes in the
soil right so if if there's um if that
table's being catered with vegetables
meat and a little bit of both we're
going to have omnivores vegetarians
vegans and and carnivores all sitting at
that table uh the same applies in my in
my head at least to the plant roots
right so if the the Tomato root is only
exuding the the same compounds tomato
plants exude then only a few types of
microbes or functional microbes are
going to be able to use those food
sources um so the grower can kind of
apply different forms of Max molasses
compost stuff like that or even
companion planting um to provide a lot
of different food sources because uh the
general thinking in microbiome science
is uh health is very closely associated
with high diversity in a
microbiome all right so with my next
question I'm going to set up a little um
a little example first about EM1 and you
know uh a lot of folks like to use EM1
and um the idea is like okay you can by
EM1 which is a a blend of microbes and
you can add it to your plants and your
plants will love it and if you want to
expand the bottle so your your your
bottle lasts longer there's uh usually
instructions on the back of how you can
do a um a a simple air rated tea so that
you can expand what's in your bottle but
but eventually if you just keep on
Brewing it and Brewing it um the the
microbes that are differently aggressive
and competitive the balance that is in
the actual EM1 balance that they
recommend it'll eventually get out of
balance and so you have to go and you
know get a new bottle of EM1 and start
over with the the actual balanced
product um so so using that as the
example um if we are grabbing uh lots of
different plants that are local to our
area that are thriving and we are um
either degrading them or extracting them
into some sort of extract or irated
compost tea is there any um awareness we
should have about the balance of those
microbes and nutrition that we're
actually putting into the pot if if if
if we do want to have our um rizosphere
life to be in balance and we influence
that balance by what we're adding from
our compost pile as a t do we need to be
worried about throwing off the balance
of the residence of the of the
rizosphere
because we are feeding out of balanced
uh
teas uh yeah actually that is that is a
major concern and um it's cool that that
a product like that has those types of
instructions for kind of increase you
know bang for your buck um but yes I
think uh my best advice and this is
maybe my opinion but based on some
science um would be when you're making
those types of products try to use them
up um you know do do your research and
say you you've found a lot of sources to
say 48 hours is the ideal incubation or
irration time for a compost tea try to
use that up uh pretty pretty quickly uh
after it's ready to go um and I think
that is based on the thinking that um
all types of microbes whether there's
one thing in a bottle or a thousand
things from a sample of compost have
different uh growth and Metabolism rates
so um when things are grown together the
term is like co-cultured um the faster
Growers are always going to be able to
have that Advantage towards the other
members of that you know biome um
because they are just uh genetically
advantaged to eat faster and divide
faster and break down faster right so
you can see things like um if you let a
compost te sit for two weeks uh maybe if
it's aerated um as opposed to one week I
bet that that microbiome completely
shifts just based on the ability for
those faster Growers to become dominant
and I think you know the diversity with
probably the highest within the first 72
hours of brewing a compost tea and that
starts to probably taper off just based
on the way microbial microb ecology kind
of works in that system um there's only
so much food around right and uh if the
fastest eaters are you know kind of
throwing their elbows at the other ones
and and eating it faster they're going
to become dominant and maybe those
aren't the plant growth promoting
microbes that you're in search for maybe
they're just really good at eating those
Max M I like that idea that that as
you're as you're Brewing it for 36 to 48
hours and you're and you're pulling it
out of the bucket right then you have
got so many aerated microbes and they've
all just been getting all the Iration
and nutrition that they could possibly
want which just means like everybody is
fed and thriving and at the starting
line and that's when we want to give it
to our plants but the longer we get away
from that starting line and let that
compost tea sit for one day two day
they're all they're all already racing
in competing and beating each other up
and eating each other and so by day you
know three or four you you're fully at
survival of the fittest at that point
and you're not providing a nice even
balanced array of nutrition and
microbiology you're actually providing
them something imbalan that's going to
have some sort of effect on your um on
your soil environment does that sound
about right absolutely yeah I mean and
the way to say that is in microbiome
science we use a term called Alpha
diversity um so if I have a basket of
fruit and there's 10 pieces of fruit in
there and nine of them are apples and
one of them is an orange I have really
low Alpha diversity but if I have 10
pieces of fruit in a basket and one's an
apple one's a grape one's a banana
blueberry everything is a different
thing um the parts of a hole are all
different that is really high alpha
diversity so the longer something like a
compost tea might sit um it's likely
that you'd be lowering your Alpha
diversity where those fast Growers or
good eaters are going to become dominant
um right on that's that is super
interesting and because I want to look
this up after the show are you saying
Alpha a p ha that is correct yes all
right cool that's very interesting idea
that is new to me on compost te's as
well um I I collaborated on something
when I was in school uh where a
colleague was making Verma compost tea
from worm castings and finished compost
um and this person was able to uh grow
it up I think they did a 48 hour Iration
um and then they boiled half of it and
then they applied the other half
untreated and they actually found that I
think it was a basil host or a tomato
host um those plants benefited more from
The Boiled compost tea um so this is not
me suggesting that everybody should be
boiling their compost tea but maybe on
their Iration time they were able to you
know increase the populations of things
that might not directly benefit plants
and actually compete for plants for
those beneficial parts that get released
when we make a compost tea um so it was
kind of interesting to think about you
know boiling or trying to get the
microbes out of a compost tea the ones
that can't survive boiling uh actually
made the plants do better um presumably
from A reduced uh amount of microb
competition for the same things the
plant Woods that kind of get released
from the irration process in compost tea
wow man boiling compost you just kind of
blew my mind there um I'm going to have
to think a lot about that but but what I
think about it immediately is that if if
if we've talked constantly throughout
this episode so far about um the
biodiversity of the teas and you know of
the carbons and of the plant sources
that we continually pour into our plants
that if I'm going to make air rated
compost teas and I'm also going to do
cold
extracted uh teas like I don't see any
reason why uh having a big pot of boiled
plants that I then let cool and then
apply to the plants CU I'm going to get
a whole a whole different um cast of
characters in that and all I'm doing is
increasing my diversity by using all
three different types of teas I would
agree with that yeah definitely you know
the the the non-boiled compost tea and
the study I'm referring to is is kind of
a balance of both probiotic or just
bacterial members and prebiotics whereas
likely after it was boiled you know it
wasn't measured chemically but that was
probably just more uh I'm going to use
the term Prebiotic but just uh kind of
the the metabolites that are released
from the compost T Brewing process um
ready for the the plant to slurp right
up rather than kind of have to share
with the microb
right on all right so um before we move
on to our next topic I want to hit
something one more time because um you
know um I've heard you kind of allude to
the fact that one of the good things
that biochar does in the soil structure
is to you know not only provide um you
know the carbon for food but also um
it's like a unique housing structure if
you will cuz it's got all these nooks
and crevices um is is there anything and
the answer may be no but I'm going to
try to squeeze you on this anyway is is
there anything else that we should
consider adding as an amendment to our
soil that is less about nutrition and
having it break down to provide you know
foods which is what most of the stuff we
do um is for but instead is something
that we are going to amend the soil
because it actually provides um a
physical mechanism that is good for the
micro life
yeah uh I for that I think you know the
the biochars are a really good approach
to that and I think I'll always
recommend if people aren't already doing
this to get a starting soil test before
you start applying your inoculant or or
inputs to that as well um but I think in
terms of kind of like housing the
microbes are giving them like a nice
place to live um you
know again I'm biased towards the soil
systems as opposed to like a hydroponic
system but when we think about no till
um not only is that really kind of
maintaining uh soil you know Carbon
that's stored from those plants um but
that's also keeping those those houses
for the microbes dormant in the plant
roots ready to be uh you know introduced
to the fresh roots that would be kind of
germinating in the same soils so like my
me personally um I have one of my
experimental you know garden beds in my
backyard that I I've never ched for and
I'll plant seeds or directly transplant
things there and it seems to be um you
know speculative that those plants get a
little bit of a boost uh because the you
know I I do apply heavy compost and
things like that there's a lot of
factors we're not considering but I
think a big thing is you know those
microbes have overwintering structures
and they were evolved with the plant to
survive through these these uh you know
cold temperatures and hot
temperatures um so yeah I think uh
people should maybe experiment more with
notil or you know companion planting and
things along those lines yeah that
certainly makes sense uh regarding our
experience with noil every year the soil
just gets more mature and it lasts
better through the winter and the the
the the following Year's plants are
thriving it's always hardest that first
year when people are using like you know
immature bagged soil without a lot of
mycelium and you know they get kind of
mediocre plants um and then and then the
longer they go no till the more you know
beefy the plants get yeah yeah it's like
a a a bettering you know I think there's
probably a limit to it year three year
four or something like that everybody's
system is different but yeah the more
the more organic material and different
types of plant materials and you know
their root exits stuff like that you can
get in that system you're adding that
diversity which is you know really
correlated with plant and microb health
rotating and amending you know no till
soil every you know let's say four years
um you know it that is such a massive
Improvement then the idea of you know
kind of old school where every year you
start with new fresh clean soil that
doesn't have any pathogens in it and
while yeah we want to avoid the
pathogens um but the the best way to
actually keep pathogens at Bay is to
have a vigorous soil that's already aged
and I always I always feel bad for
people who are very much set on the new
season new soil tip because it it just
it just makes things hard every year
instead of year three and four being
like easy yeah to me the the that kind
of feels like a scorched earth type of
approach um and and I like that you
mentioned you know the diversity uh in
what you just said um you know we've
seen uh things like fusarium uh species
highly present you know 10 the 6 10 the
eth cells per gram of soil um in a in a
plant Rises spere sample um but it's you
know very far along into flower
maturation and there's no signs or
symptoms of the fusarium attacking the
plant um so it's like this the fusarium
is taking one seat at the seat the table
with 100 seats and the other 99 seats
are plant benefiting things or soil
benefiting things so you know pathogens
can be present without becoming fent and
it all comes back to soil microbial
diversity you know out competing
fusarium is the only potential solution
that I see that there is other than just
dumping the soil um you know we we've
talked about fusarium I've had fusarium
Specialists on this on the on the um
program and and usually their answer is
like throw the soil away and I get that
um but um but it's interesting to
realize that as a preventative since
fusarium is everywhere it's not like
it's not going to be in your soil um
just make sure you keep on you know
adding microbes incubating microbes
adding indigenous microbes and fusarium
will never get a good
foothold yeah I mean you know never is a
strong word but I
think differently from you know adding
all the microbes and really
intentionally applying you know diverse
forms of microbes whether they're from
you know your wildcrafting or input
somebody could buy I think the other
thing is you know soil Health practices
really is where a lot of this soil
microbial diversity preservation can
start um so those things like the
prebiotics and the organic inputs and
companion planting uh crop rotation no
till uh soil health I think maybe even I
would put higher on the list than uh
microbial accessible carbon from the the
previous question but they're related
right yeah yeah yeah all right cool so
the last topic I want to hit uh during
here during the set two here is um you
know so so far this uh this set we've
been talking about the things that we
can do to make the living environment
for the microb life and in the
rizosphere as diverse and beneficial as
possible and and why that's kind of
everything right it it we keep on coming
back to the same answer and it's because
the answer is is kind of the only thing
that we need to be doing as regenerative
Farmers is is adding um adding diversity
into the soil and then and let nature do
the rest so so that's great um I also am
very attracted to the idea that the pl
is also um trying to help itself as well
by by putting out you know exudates that
that encourage particular microbes or or
um or different residents in the
rizosphere where they're kind of
curating uh who they are attracting to
them and I've heard you talk before
about um recruitment that that cannabis
plants will recruit bacteria that that
they find beneficial and and I'm
unfamiliar with this idea but it but
just the idea of it is fascinating so so
I I don't know the right question to ask
you on it so I'm just going to kind of
hand you the mic and say will you tell
us about how cannabis plants recruit
beneficial bacteria itself kind of like
intentionally yeah absolutely thank you
um I think you know there's a lot of uh
literature from the past five or six
years that show photosensitive photo
period sensitive plants or plants that
you know have major changes in
development um also changed their root
exited profiles so I think it was first
you know learned about in a rabids wild
wild mustard model um a plant that has a
rosette stage and then it bolts and then
it makes flowers and those flowers make
seeds um at each one of those stages uh
it was seen that the the root exited
profiles change um you know the early
growth and development there was just a
ton of sugar and later in the uh the
flowering and maturation there was a lot
of you know organic acids and things
that are uh can be harsh to certain
microbes whereas sugar is like a really
broad food source so the kind of
thinking from the authors of that paper
were um and I'll get to cannabis too I
promise were about um you know the
developmental needs of the plant are
changing you know more nitrogen in the
beginning more phosphorus and potassium
later and you know those micronutrients
trickled throughout um and we know that
the microbes help plants uptake these
things so you know let's wonder if the
plant is actually I'm going to use the
term uh intentionally uh signaling for
different things as it goes on through
growth and development so I mean being a
cannabis Enthusiast seeing that study I
was like wow you know what's the most
popular photosensitive photop period
sensitive plant that we use you know
hampen cannabis right um uh so it
was I'm not sure if root exit at work
has been done um but we've done some
work on the um the vegetative versus the
transition so you know maybe a couple
weeks after flower on set after the
solstice and the days get short in an
outdoor system um as well as the hard
Harvest uh you know functional
microbiome of cannabis and we see that
um regardless
of the you know specific species of
cannabis uh or strain uh whether it's
hamper cannabis 3% THC producers are
higher
um the same functions or at least the
same bacterial Genera are occurring in
in a many different uh types of soil
environments um we're using like the
USDA climatic zones for that but
basically um cannabis being as as
nutritionally
uh needy compared to some other plants
um you know we we see uh really strong
associations with the bacteria um based
on development so when we use the term
like recruit it's it's kind of like the
um the cannabis plant is sending these
signals into the risos phere to likely
get some type of risos feric function by
the bacterial or fungal or just anybody
in the soil microbiome um and these
needs are pretty standard from you know
the genus or the the the Cannabis sativa
plants uh whether you they are
classified as hamper marijuana uh you
know depending on the the amount of
metabol it produces right um all that to
say is plants really want microbes um
and if we can kind of provide microbes
uh that the plant can't search for in
indoor systems um or in really you know
low Alpha diversity 10year monocultured
cornfield soils where there's lots
there's like five different types of
microbes I'm exaggerating um then we can
kind of benefit the plant uh in a way
that it would in its natural environment
and the wild type relatives and the
progenitors might have you know kind of
evolved to
do so it sounds like um if I'm
understanding you correctly the main
point is that over the life cycle of the
plant the plants uh the the the dominant
bacterias in the rizosphere changes and
we know the mechanism or or at least
we're pretty sure that the mechanism of
why it changes is because the plant
wants different types of bacteria and so
it's putting the plant is putting out
different types of exudates to encourage
different types of bacteria and so um
the best thing that we can do is to um
you know a let the plant do its job and
then B do our part by um offering
um varieties of other um nutritions and
and probiotic bacterias and such that
that the plant can't produce and it
needs to get its environment so that
between the partnership between us and
the plant The Roots have just got
everything it could possibly desire to
express itself most fully yes that a
perfect distillation thank you and I
think um you know most importantly the
uh I'm going to sound like a broken
record but soil Health right the soil
health is is maintained then we are
going to assume and you know we've
proven like the science has proven
there's lots of alpha diversity
microbial diversity in a very healthy
soil um so whether or not the microbe
that's present during the vegetative
growth period uh of your Canabis plants
life cycle is recruited by the plant um
during that time if you maintain that
soil Health it's likely there will still
be those microbes in low enough cell
numbers and then when the plant changes
its root exitation compounds presumably
to attract microbes to uh help it meet
its nutritional needs based on
development um then you know soil Health
maintains microbial diversity those bugs
are hanging around when your plant is
flowering and and in need of those types
of uh functions hell yeah that's
actually really exciting I like that
summary a lot it's like uh it's it's
very rare in uh discussing uh
soil health and and you know soil
maximalism if you will to actually have
uh that clear of a recipe for what we
need to do this season thank God so yeah
right right on well good well well thank
you for that Michael let's go ahead and
take our second uh commercial uh and be
right back uh you're listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is
microbiologist Michael Deli and remember
you know without these advertisers shape
and fire wouldn't happen so please
support them and let them know that you
heard of them on shaping
[Music]
fire you've heard me talk about the
award-winning cannabis seeds that come
from the analytical breeding program of
Seth and Eric Crawford who founded
Oregon CBD seeds in fact Seth was a
guest on shaping fire in 2020 to talk
about triploid genetics Seth and Eric
are now releasing high THC seeds for
homeg Growers and Farms as grow the
revolution seeds at GTR seeds.com their
high THC seeds are extraordinary and
that they will start to flower at 16 1/2
hours hours of daylight instead of the
typical 14 1/2 hours of daylight that
means in most regions your plants will
start to flower outdoors in the middle
of July instead of the middle of August
which means these photo period plants
finish in September and not October
totally upending the photo period Seed
Market Seth and Eric took their prized
early flowering CBG line and bred it to
some of the most desired verified
genetics out there including Sour Diesel
triangle Kush wedding cake chem dog
Skittles and others these crosses all
Express powerful photo period tarpine
profiles and THC giving you a great High
GTR seeds has a new thcv line with
plants like double Durban and Gigantor
that boasts one:1 THC to thcv and people
want that
thcv gtcs are very consistent true
growing inbred f1s from stabilized
inbred parent lines these seeds are
nearly homogeneous and the plants should
all grow the same there is only one
phenotype in every pack available as
diploids and triploids sethan Eric's
company is still family-owned patient
employee Centric and partially powered
by their 2 Acres of solar panels
everyone can purchase these seeds in the
entire catalog of Oregon CBD seeds at
GTR seeds.com go to GTR seeds.com today
and choose something revolutionary for
your next indoor or outdoor
[Music]
run fish poop brand fertilizer is an
allnatural fish poop concentrate with
nothing added real fish poop is
extraordinarily complex not only are you
adding the nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium your plants need to build mass
transport nutrients and enhance flavor
but fish waste is also packed with
biological activity and
micronutrients when you add fish poop to
your irrigation water you are adding
life life force probiotics and active
microbes these microorganisms include a
wealth of various bacteria and protozoa
which further enhance nutrient
availability for the plants because
plants are limited by the absence of any
essential micronutrient these Trace
nutrients are the difference between
having a decent garden and having a
garden that makes you feel really proud
of your efforts fish poop is a naturally
complete solution that fills in the
cracks in your fertilizer program to
ensure you offer your garden a broad
basee of nutrients not all fish poop is
created equally most products with added
fish waste don't reveal their sources or
lab results fish poop brand fish poop
however generates their own fish waste
as a byproduct of their organic
aquaponics cannabis farm where they
raise ornamental koi and tilapia you are
even invited to tour their Farm in
person or on their YouTube channel to
look for yourself this sort of
transparency is wildly rare in the
fertilizer Market
the folks behind fish poop are also
lifelong medical cannabis producers who
have deep Connections in the community
donate more product than they sell and
support cannabis prisoner veteran and
patient collectives and Charities to get
your bottle of pure fish poop go to fish
poop.com and to see their entire line of
cannabis products go to ounce ofh
hope.com that's fish poop brand fish
[Music]
poop one of the reasons why no till
cannabis growing is so valued by Farmers
is because the melium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year and we know these fungal networks
are essential because they are the
nutrient super highways that extend far
and wide in the substrate to feed your
plants the trouble with growing in New
Living soils or Blended cocoa substrates
is that it takes most of the plants life
just to create these melium highways
dinico endom micro risal fungi in ulent
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the other popular brand in the US at
900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation damico is the
result of 30 years of research and
trials at the volcani agriculture
Research Institute in Israel it has also
been vigorously Tried by cannabis and
food Growers across the US damico is now
a aable at Grow shops and on Amazon in
the United States I love using dynamite
code to both speed up the growth of the
melium networks in the soil but also as
a bio stimulant to make clone cuting
more veal you can see side byid showing
the comparative growth on their
Instagram at
dinico if you demand reliable growing
results and appreciate the importance of
an active root Zone in creating a
thriving plant I encourage you to check
out dino.com and use the store locator
to find out where you can get yours
that's d y
n.com shaping fire listeners can get 10%
off any size of dynamico on dynamic.com
by using the discount code shaping fire
onew no caps whether you are starting
with new beds or pots or if you want to
add some Zing to tired soil choose
damico to maximize your plants potential
dynamico endom micro risal
inoculant welcome back you are listening
to shaping fire I am your host Shango
Los and my guest today is microbiologist
Michael Deli so here we are at the big
finish you know during the first set we
talked all about bio stimulants and
plant growth regulators and what we
wanted to do as regenerative cultivators
to make sure that we have the healthiest
most biodiverse soil so the plant can do
its job of growing in a healthy way that
resists pests and gives us awesome
yields and tpes during the second set we
talked a bit more more about the care
intending of micro life specifically and
and and not only how we can add U
microbes and biodiversity like we were
talking in the first set but also how we
can help them Thrive and keep them
wellfed with carbon and here on the
third set um we're just going to hit on
um two more kind of miscellaneous uh
biodiversity topics um that didn't fit
in the other two sections but I think
are really important and things that we
have talked about uh prior on the conver
on the on the program so the first of
the two is uh choosing companion plants
to encourage biodiversity so Michael
we've talked quite a bit today about uh
plant exudates and how plants push out
the exudates from the root structure um
uh and and and attract different um um
microbial life and life forms in the
rizosphere um that that it wants to use
as as different you know flavors of
tools and and and I understand that like
the plants that are planted near our
cannabis plants can influence the risos
spere of our cannabis plant because it
is also calling forth different types of
nutrition and melium um to its uh root
systems as well and um I understand um
you know partly what you study is is um
how these systems May interact and and
how to choose companion plants that will
be a good neighbor for whatever the
target plant that that we're looking to
grow in in our case we're talking about
cannabis and so will you kind of um Talk
us through how to think about choosing
our companion plants and in in order to
encourage the the most biodiversity in
our
soil yeah absolutely and I think the
reason that this isn't more you know
widespread or adapted or adopted rather
is is because of the um the scalability
of this but I I would love to see it you
know on hundreds of Acres I think um two
really cool examples that are new to me
for kind of companion planting for
cannabis would be um I had some friends
do the three sisters but replace the
corn with the um the cannabis plant as
opposed to Corn um and for those who
don't know the three sisters is corn
beans and squash the corn serves as a
trellis for the beans to grow up um the
beans have a nitrogen fixing symbiotic
bacterium called rium that live in their
roots and that nitrogen can get leeched
out of their roots and be available for
both the corn and the Squash and then
the squash with their large leaves at
the base of the plant they provide shade
so soil States kind of cooler
temperatures and doesn't get baked from
the Sun um so in this case uh they
replace the corn with the the hemp
plants and the cannabis plants to serve
as that trellis for the the beans to
climb up um and both you know the squash
and the excuse me the hemp was able to
benefit from the beans being present due
to that rium bacterium being there um
and also you know certain soil
temperatures if they get too hot that
can actually be detrimental to microbial
um populations so having that cooling
effect from the squash leaves uh
depending on your grow environment
Colorado we have 320 days of direct
Sunshine that can help cool it down um
to keep those soil temperatures uh happy
for lots of different things to to keep
growing rather than just uh you know the
ones that are tolerant to warm soil
before you move past hold on before you
move past the three sisters I have got
to ask are you serious we want to have
beans climbing up our cannabis plants
like that sounds awful like does that
work do they I mean I'm imagine that the
bean plants get all into the flowers and
then and how does that work I think it
might require a little bit more um uh
maintenance from the cultivator than
than than most people can do in a
production system um but yeah so they
would kind of climb up and and on the
fan leaves and things along those lines
um do the be beans are also the beans
stay closer to the stock cuz like
normally the flowers are are you know
kind of far away from the stock so so
are the are the beans perhap perhaps
going to just like grow up the center of
the plant and not grow out to the
flowers or will the will the beans
eventually grow out the branch to the
flowers
the ones I the ones I saw in the system
were were more so like the the tips of
The Bean vines or you know yeah were
kind of hanging out in the empty space
between fan leaves in the middle parts
of the plant they didn't might quite
make it up to that top Cola um and you
know this is a one one example right so
um another approach to this though cuz I
do hear what you're saying with you know
beans could effectively act like a a
bind weed um and pull plants down like
that so I think um a bush bean or a
different type of legume like a cow pea
might be a better type of nitrogen fixer
to get that you know diverse root exit
profile diverse microbiome from the root
exodites and the nitrogen component to
from the legume plants and so those
different those bush beans and and the
reason why those are better is because
you would plant those at the foot of the
cannabis plant and so their risos speres
could talk to each other but the plant
is not a climbing bean and so you'll
just have like Bean Shrubbery at the
bottom of your cannabis plant which is
fine um it just won't climb the plant is
that where where that goes yes
absolutely and so like that rizosphere
becomes representative of at least you
know two to three different types of
plant species with your your Vining
squash you know your fruits should be
okay because they'll be far away from
the rest of the beans that are kind of
bushing at the base um but if you have
all those roots kind of in the same root
ball as long as there's adequate
nutrition and organic material um that
will be like a very healthy diverse
microbiome uh as a factor of just having
three different hosts yeah I like that a
lot and um we've talked on the show
before too that people who uh who grow
in berms that are heavy built up with uh
compost and you know grass clippings and
and other agricultural clippings um it's
very popular to grow potatoes in that
too so you know you've got your potatoes
and your beans and your squash kind of
trailing off down the down the line of
plants um i' I've always loved the idea
of of growing food crops with the
Cannabis so that you can feed yourself
as well as you know smoke and save your
soul if you will absolutely Ely yeah
okay so now that I've pushed you on that
what other what other strategies or
plans do you have in mind for um
creating a um diverse rizosphere well
this was something that was kind of um
new to me that I read about I didn't get
to see this one in in in action but it
was a farm that had been co-planting um
um a plant with a mushroom so they were
kind of using myceliated uh beds of a
winec cap mushroom to get um both
Harvest of winec cap fungi edible
mushrooms at the base of the soil and
the uh the hemp was able to grow um and
flow at the top so it was kind of
getting um both you know that fungal
microbiome benefit uh as well as the the
plant roots there too so not directly
you know plant-to-plant signaling like
we're seeing with like the three sisters
we just discussed um but something along
the lines of you know trying to have uh
more bang for your book in terms of
square footage for harvesting and things
like that and wine mushroom is one of my
favorite eating mushrooms they're
absolutely delicious I I tried to do
that in my indoor and it didn't work out
because the the humidity for mushrooms
seems to be a little higher um than we
want it to be in an indoor setting it
seems to work well
Outdoors um so long as you've got good
plant coverage because uh normally we
want our plants in direct sunlight right
but the mushrooms don't want to be in
the direct sunlight so you got to make
sure that you're growing plants that are
going to be big enough to um create that
shadow underneath that allows the the
wine caps to exist yeah maintain that
humid microclimate underneath the plant
canopy that is super ideal for mushrooms
oh and the Squash will help with that
too that you're talking
about those big leaves yeah all right um
do you have any more on that before uh
before I move on uh I think just
companion planting is really really
excellent and I think there is a um you
know go back to the literature and and
look out you know if you deer eating
your your hemp merry Golds can be
deterrence for deer right I think
there's a different different plant for
a different need um and just always
going back to the more diverse roots and
host in the in the soil would you know
increase your soil health and microbial
diversity there so so I actually was
planning on doing um big pots of
marigolds uh next to the plants for the
first time this year um because we do
have a lot of deer pressure and luckily
I got some um some deer fencing this
year so hopefully that'll help too but
um is it is it as effective that if the
um the marigolds are are not in the pot
with the canos or in the ground next to
it but like are beside it that the smell
of the maragold is enough to keep the
deer off or will the deer just come over
and browse the weed and and just ignore
the marrow gold I'll be ful honest with
you uh when I when I tried to use Mar
Golds as a a deterrent crop in in
Maryland I I watched a deer chew one
down before so you know that's like your
mileage may vary right yeah you know
like uh kind of like different different
strains of cannabis might have different
turpenoid or cannabinoid profiles
different species of marigolds you know
they have the multicolored ones have
different uh type of phytochemical
profiles or you know those volatile
organic compounds that smell icky a deer
um um so I I don't know a variety off
the top of my head but I imagine that um
you know it's very species specific r on
well thank you I app I appreciate your
uh your honesty in that and you know if
we're really going to go for it um you
know these bioions have got different
deer right so different deer could be um
accustomed to browsing different types
of plants whereas whereas Mar Maryland
deer don't like marigolds but or or no
do like they do like Mar Golds and and
maybe you know my West Coast deer um are
more um snoody and they don't want marro
Golds you know right or something like
that so all right um but before we leave
the companion planning topic I just want
to ask are there any um plants that are
um obviously um U poor neighbors um the
the the name for it is is escaping me at
the moment but but there's there are
often plants that you don't want to
plant near other plants because they
they they will they might poison each
other or or or be toxic to the other
person's or the other plants rizosphere
are you aware of any of those yeah there
is one that's jumping off the top of my
head although I know there's you know a
lot of examples um black walnut uh trees
for example you know not specifically
related or cultivated for a regular
Harvest like we're talking about with
cannabis or vegetables um but those
those guys uh have a a root exit it um
that is under the nature of aathy uh so
they are actually able to shoot a
compound into the soil that makes it
pretty inhospitable for anything but its
Offspring to grow um and to counter that
there's also plants I think certain
trees as well that you know don't want
its own offspring to to compete with the
you know the mom plant uh for the
resources there so they'll they'll send
signals into the soil that make it
inhospitable for the plants of the same
species to grow um to try to uh you know
preserve its own nutrients that might be
in the soil right on that's that's
that's good to say and I'm going to
throw in my two even though some people
like these um you know I always make
sure that any any plants that I consider
for a companion plant um does not give
off floating seeds like dandelions I
personally really love uh Pink
dandelions and I and I and I encourage
them in my yard actually CU they look
really trippy um and so but but before
they go to seed um you know I've got a
different seed crop at a different
property but but like I have to make
sure you know I grab those because I
don't want all those like little fuzzy
puff balls in my resinous flowers right
that is definitely a party fowl and so
any plant that gives off um you know uh
fluffy seed that are going to be wind uh
distributed you want to be careful of
those and then even though a lot of
people like uh red clover I personally
caution people from the red clover
because the red flower shoots up and if
you don't grow monster plants if you're
growing plants that are only you know 3
feet and not 10 ft uh 3 feet the Clover
could totally grow up into and start
interacting with your resin and and we
don't want that either so the last
question here is is is one that uh I
talk about sometimes on um on shaping
fire but but mostly it the the
discussion has has happened on the
shaping fire YouTube channel where um I
posted a a video with a microbiologist
that had was a specialist in in plant
microbe interaction talking about how um
the 24hour light strategy is is bad for
cannabis and and I fully believe this to
be the case because um you know uh photo
synthetic plants have a have uh evolved
processes that happen during the dark
cycle so so if the plant is naturally
growing Outdoors it gets a day cycle
gets a night cycle during the night
cycle the
photosynthesizing um stops and other
processes happen and that's how you keep
a strong rambunctious plant but we know
from experiments indoor plants when
you're supplementing with light that if
you grow the plant at 24 hours um it's
it's like giving the plant cocaine or
something like where the plants just go
go go go and constantly photosynthesize
constantly process these sugars go ra
and and like and so it will it will make
your your your your seed germinate
faster it will make the young plant move
faster it will bring it into be becoming
you know a ready to flower teenage plant
faster and then in the flowering some
people find that they reach maturity of
the flower faster to such a degree that
they can you know knock a week off of
flowering sometimes and they're all like
listen if if if if if I do that with
every cycle my whole year I can actually
squeeze in another cycle a year and
that's real money and so because of that
the case for a 24-hour light cycle is
made and I take every opportunity I can
to try to teach that the the dark cycle
is necessary for plant health and um you
Michael you know you're you're the front
line of this debate as a microbiologist
you know these Cycles
intimately and and you know what happens
in the you know what happens in the dark
and so so I'm going to kind of throw
myself up um hopefully um hopefully I'm
not wrong in your eyes but um I'd like
to hear you speak to this idea of the
24-hour light strategy and um and how
that that might impact uh the
plant yeah absolutely I think um you
know that's got to be one of the most uh
nutritionally expensive types of
cultivation practices I would think um
that could be done uh I I wonder what
types of um you know nutrient usage uh
rates people are going through if
they're uh doing this practice with
24-hour light cycles um because I would
imagine that with 24 hours of daylight
without any types of resting period um
that the plant is going to be constantly
uh requiring extremely high
concentrations of nitrogen phosphorus
and potassium um essential processes
like the kreb cycle happen uh at
nighttime um plants also do these um
things called like gation where there
might be air bubbles in the plant
vascular tissue which can be detrimental
um but at night time they can push those
out um you know they also close their
stamata and uh don't evaporate the water
out of their bodies as as quickly so I
think primarily the
um the benefit to get another cycle
might be missed by the amount of
nutrients somebody might need from
trying to maintain the nutritional needs
of the cannabis plant uh by blasting
them with 24 hours of light right if
you're going to be um you know basically
giving your plants cocaine and keeping
them at high energy high growth optimal
fast growth rates and developments
there's going to be a lot of energy
spent for that um and in order to them
for them to kind of account for that
deficit there needs to be tons and tons
of available nutrient inputs there um
and I I don't know that one other cycle
might be uh beneficial enough to to to
have to add that much more fertigation
in in my experience the people who are
defending the 24-hour light cycle are
are usually people that are using you
know two-part bottled salt fertilizers
and so they're kind of like force
feeding the plants uh nutrition anyway
and uh you know it's it's pretty rare to
find a you know a bottled nutrients
grower who isn't overfeeding anyway
because if some is good more is better
right and so and so that that's actually
the answer that I get online when
discussing this with with these these
cultivators are at that'll well if it
just makes the plant more hungry for
more nutrition I'll just pour more in
and I'm like Ah that's not really how it
works um but um for folks who aren't
familiar with it you mentioned that the
KB cycle happens in the dark period we
we will you explain what that
is well the um the plant starts to
respire so it stops using the light um
or the photons from the sunlight or your
LEDs or any types of lighting you have
as um kind of like the building blocks
to metabolism um and it starts to
respire basically it's getting its
energy from off gassing um things that
might be in the there as opposed to
using the light energy to um kind of
make more chloroplast and and things
along those lines so when I'm when I'm
talking about uh this with folks who who
are very very
um into the 24-hour light strategy um
they come back to me and they're like
they're like well you're telling me I
can't do this but I do this all the time
and I get plants and I smoke them and I
get high and it's great and and and to
the best of my scientific knowledge I
say to them I say yeah but you're you're
getting a plant that isn't the best
plant you could have
grown um if you if you need
fast cheap styrofoam tasting flour
quickly okay that that might be an
appropriate strategy to consider but
since most of us are looking for a
thriving plant which um you know also
provides high quality Tarpin that just
like engage us and give us a better high
and also creates pest resistance it
seems to me that the 24-hour lightle
will slowly but surely degrade a
cannabis plant throughout its entire
life cycle what what are your thoughts
about that like is the is is the is the
life of the cannabis plant so short
where over where over that life cycle it
doesn't matter if we starve the
soil I I kind of am thinking that I it
does matter you know the canopus plant
life cycle is a lot longer to to
maturation and harvest than a lot of
other different crops that are kind of
following the school of thought and I
think that um you know speculatively
there's a lot of uh things that happen
that are beneficial to the pl vascular
system during the rest period um pushing
those air bubbles out closing those
stamata uh and things along those lines
that I would imagine play a role in the
the synthesis of cannaboids and
terpenoids and other secondary
metabolites um so I think yeah it would
be interesting to do a side by side with
the same kind of cultivar or strain of
of cannabis uh you know in a 24-hour
cycle versus an 186 followed by a 1212
um and then the other thing that I
wanted to mention uh you were talking
about kind of the indoor Growers and
having those you know two to one salts
readily available and probably slightly
over applied um it it would be cool to
to get to a point to where we can kind
of start to supplement uh those
conventional salt-based fertilizers with
more organic things um and maybe even
get to the point uh and this is from Dr
James White the rise ofy scientist um
using those salts that are easily
slipped up and and you know immediately
used in in building blocks of the plant
body um kind of has like corrective uh
treatments and you notice the deficiency
you apply a salt and then you start to
kind of balance both your your salt and
your organic based of nutrition inputs
not only will that benefit the plant um
but also same thing with the microbes um
there's been studies showing the same
exact you know strain of of cannabis
growing in living soil versus growing in
uh Hydroponics with Biologicals and the
tarpine and cannaboid profiles are you
know statistically different from one
another and I think a lot of that has to
do with the the Tera or the terar of the
cannabis plant yeah yeah the idea of
supplementing with uh with um salt on
its face I'm prejudiced against but as a
citizen scientist I want to learn more
you know what I mean so yeah I
understand yeah yeah yeah yeah so anyway
well well thank you for for uh diving
into that topic for me um it's clearly
something that I am passionate about and
I get argued with sometimes and so
anytime I you know when I get a
microbiologist like you willing to talk
to me about it I always bang that drum
so thank
you yeah absolutely I mean like just
more on the microb side I think just
like the the soil temperatures do cool
or the root temp the root Zone risos
spere temperatures will also cool in the
dark so kind of factoring in the
microbiome um that's just allowing more
environmental changes to maintain
different diversity and things like that
um with the the darkness period because
you know a grow room will cool off 10°
when the lights are off and things like
that yeah right on yeah and I'm sure
there's different cycles that need a
cooler temperature to happen yeah but
I'm interested in in kind of learning
more about the effects in the microbiome
you know with this 24-hour versus
getting that rest period that plants you
know were evolve to have yeah so awesome
well Michael we are here at the end um
thank you so much for sharing your
expertise and experience and and time
and good cheer with us um I've really
enjoyed our discussion and um you know
it it I I I didn't expect uh uh so much
so many times for us to come back to the
answer being diverse micro teas but but
really you know the the more I get into
regenerative growing and really uh
growing in a way that's uh response to
Nature the more I realize that um The
Farmer's Only job is to create um Rich
Nutri nutritive biologically diverse
soil and and so you're always going to
come back to tea so so thank you very
much for being here and for for you know
sharing what you know absolutely thank
you so much for having me Shango uh it
was a great conversation and I'm really
grateful to be able to kind of just you
know talk about this stuff with somebody
else excellent yeah me too it's it's
nice to find another nerded for this
stuff so thank you totally yeah right on
so um if you want to reach out to uh
Michael or no more what's he more of
what he's up to there are two placs to
do that um you can follow Michael Deli
that's d i l gge on LinkedIn where he
posts what he's up to in his latest
research and also um uh the company
where he is uh director of microbiology
is impello biosciences and you can find
out what they're up to at
impello
P bio.com you can find more episodes of
the shaping fire podcast And subscribe
to the show at shaping fire.com and
wherever you get your podcast
if you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you would leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too on the shaping fire website you
can also subscribe to the newsletter for
insights into the latest Cannabis News
exclusive videos and giveaways on the
shaping fire website you'll also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
be sure to follow on Instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast that's @ shaping fire and @
Shango on Instagram be sure to check out
shaping fire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot
shaping fire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire I've been
your host Shango
[Music]
Los