[Music]
pain and chronic illness are so dynamic
that they injure us on multiple levels
certainly there is the obvious pain and
suffering that comes with chronic
illness for those we use cannabis and
other herbs and medicines but then there
are the other injuries from not being
able to work or perhaps play with our
kids or be intimate with our lover
those are injurious to our soul our zest
for life that last one
feeling so broken that we cannot manage
to rise up and Express sexually with our
partners can be incredibly soul-crushing
sometimes it leaves us feeling very
lonely and ashamed and I know cuz I've
been there after both my accidents I was
so broken that while cannabis helped the
pain my inability to move properly made
me feel like a broken man that's why
we're doing this show today because I
work with cannabis patients every day
and I know of the internalized emotional
pain that comes from being vibrant and
energetic inside with an inability to
actually perform on the outside it
totally sucks
but maybe this episode can help there
are solutions for these challenges
you'll need an open mind but there are
indeed best practices to be learned so
that you can have fulfilling intimacy
and sex even if your human body is
suffering if you want to learn about
cannabis health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode you
are listening to shaping fire and I'm
your host
Shango lows today my guest is world
renowned sex educator Chris Maxwell rose
chris has been practicing as an
independent sex educator since 2003 and
holds certifications in both
professional massage and somatic
sexology as well as a degree in
sociology from Vassar Chris's co-host of
the wildly popular speaking of sex
podcast perhaps better known as pleasure
mechanics
at pleasure mechanics calm today's show
is going to be something special
during the first set we will discuss the
mental and emotional challenges of
having sex while experiencing chronic
pain or chronic disease the second set
is all about interacting with your
partner and how to communicate
effectively when either you or your
partner or perhaps both of you are
suffering from a debilitating ailment
and in the third set we will talk very
specifically about sexual positions toys
and some creative strategies for
sexualizing your everyday life even in
pain as you can imagine today's episode
is probably not one to listen to with
your kids in the car while most podcast
distributors give our show and explicit
rating due to cannabis we are really
going to earn that explicit rating today
welcome to the show Chris it's such a
pleasure thank you for having me
I'm really grateful for you sharing your
valuable time with us and your life loss
lifelong experience on this really
important topic so so let's get right
into it
so many pain patients feel alone in
their suffering because you know most
folks just don't usually talk about
sexual difficulty at all let's start out
by getting everybody in the same boat
and feeling less isolated you know it's
it's pretty do you find it that it's
pretty common that painful injury or
disease inhibits a person expressing
their sexuality mm-hmm I mean yes yes
and yes all right I'm finding the human
condition in this human culture inhibits
us from expressing our human sexuality
and that's kind of the thing is we're in
a sex negative pleasure phobic culture
to begin with and a culture that has a
very narrow window of what it tells us
is sexually permissible and for who and
so when something like illness or injury
whether it's temporary or chronic
strikes us when our lives change
dramatically and things we have their
light on our whole lives our identities
change sometimes non-consensual II
sometimes very dramatically our
sexuality is one of those things that
gets thrown in
to such dramatic upheaval and yet we
don't have a lot of support for it we
don't have an occupational therapist to
help us get back on track very many of
us don't even have friends we can talk
to you honestly about it and so when
change strikes our lives in any way and
we have to allow change in our sexual
lives this can be a moment of such huge
disruption shame guilt fear shutdown
because our options that we wants relied
on or no longer available to us yes this
is huge it's huge for all of us kind of
no matter and that's why you know I've
been doing this work my whole life and I
will be doing it till I die because
sexuality isn't easy for any of us for
any of us even you know some of my
coaching clients are quite literally
supermodels it's not easy for them and
so if complications are thrown at us or
changes are thrown at us it's especially
not easy but but change is also a moment
of possible transformation of growth of
curiosity and so it can also I think as
a lot of us discover when illness or
pain comes into our lives it can have
strange blessings to it as well it can
have strange silver linings and this is
especially I think true and sexuality
because it's an opportunity to get to
know ourselves again to get to discover
something about ourselves and our
partner to meet one another anew so
that's how I approach it is with both
holding the full complexity of this
conversation and also honoring all the
potential that is here with us the
pleasure and the joy and the love and
connection that sexuality is designed to
give us so the question becomes how to
access that one of the things I've
learned from working with pain patients
is that so often the life decisions they
have to make because now they are
injured or they've been given a
diagnosis means that that not only do
they have the pain and the diagnosis but
they also have to do other things maybe
have to move into a less expensive
apartment or maybe they have to move
back with her family for goodness sakes
and and it's so challenging I would
imagine
because not only do you have this trauma
that has happened and now you have this
this pain experience but also at the
same time you're trying to do these
important interactions with with your
partner and and it's like it's like it's
like so it's not super easy for most
people to talk about their sexuality
even at the best of times and and and to
be in a place where you're experiencing
so much pain and need to go through this
this significant vulnerable and growing
time with your partner it's like oh man
this is the worst time for me to even
try to be open with my partner and try
to you know grow emotionally to where I
need to be to do that mmm well that's
one perspective on it I want to offer a
few others and I also want to say going
into this conversation
I want all bodies to feel included in
this and we need to honor that illness
and injury is such a huge spectrum of
how it impacts our bodies what it gives
us to work with what it takes away from
us some things are temporary but what
all of us have in common just from being
humans is change so that's what I really
want to come back to over and over again
because also even if you have a terminal
diagnosis there's gonna be a thousand
changes along the way and so so much of
this becomes dancing with change and
allowing change and changing our
attitudes and that's the other theme I
want to weave in here is allowing our
attitudes about sex to change and one of
the attitudes I want to just bring up
right away as you keep mentioning
partners our first and foremost
relationship and our sexualities with
ourselves and whether or not you have
one partner many partners no partners
for the foreseeable future you have a
sexuality and so as we talk about
sexuality I want to talk about our
relationships with ourselves how we feel
about our bodies what we desire what we
allow for ourselves and how we meet
another person naked in bed right his
sexuality lives in all of those spaces
so let's talk about that relationship
with our own body because you know
having been a pain patient myself I know
that after my car accident my body fell
foreign to me and it was acting in ways
that I had not experienced before and
and you know there luckily I have two
pretty good headspace about my
relationship with my body but there were
certainly times that I was angry and I
felt like my body was letting me down
even though it was doing everything a
good to heal
since our primary relationship with
sexuality is with ourselves what kind of
advice do you have to offer people who
feel that you know maybe their their
body has become diseased and is selling
them out and so it becomes an
adversarial relationship totally there
can be a sense of betrayal there can be
a sense of grief for what was lost there
can be in a sense of anger like why me
and this is especially true if you've
been able bodied um athletes or soldiers
I've talked to who have been able-bodied
and used their body as a tool that could
be relied upon right and even dialed in
their body for optimal fitness right
like the we all carry different
relationships going into our illness so
when you wake up many of us we wake up
in a hospital bed we emerge into this
new condition we're diagnosed first you
have to really go through all of that
[ __ ] you have to be real with the anger
you have to be honest with the grief and
then try to find the mental space of
asking okay what now what next what's
possible and also remembering that will
change so my own kind of health crisis
when I woke up in so much pain there can
be such a sense of will it be this way
forever and that breeds despair right
like why why would I even try my
sexuality has been taken
from me I'll never love again like we
can have these sense of just complete
betrayal and despair from our bodies
it's usually not true and sometimes we
need friendly faces or voices telling us
that's not true things will change
you're still worthy and lovable people
will still find you desirable that can
be more or less hard to believe
depending on your circumstances but even
again with yourself a sexuality as
possible pleasure as possible joining
connection as possible kind of no matter
what and you and I know this but from
working with people in terminal
conditions at end of life after
disfiguring accidents pleasure joy love
all of these things that we want out of
sex are still available to us so maybe
it's my voice reminding of you of this
for the first time or a friend sitting
with you at the bedside or your partner
still looking at you with love desire
wanting even if that wanting has changed
right so Charlotte and I were together
for a decade before I got sick our one
ting used to be feisty and playful and
full of passion and lust and like I want
to tear your clothes off and do nasty
things to you right now that wanting
changed who I want you to be alive with
me I want you to take your next breath
but that wanting was deeply romantic too
because we let ourselves feel it so so
much of this is going to go back to
feeling letting yourself feeling letting
yourself feel what you feel in the
moment being real with it and then
trying to have a sense of agency of what
you want to feel next what do you want
to experience next what is possible for
you given your condition you might have
pain for the rest of your life great how
are you gonna have a sexuality with pain
in the back seat that's now your
question and a lot of this is about
context we forget sometimes how
context-dependent our sexualities are
and if your context is now the
ground-level bedroom at your parents
house that's a very different erotic
context than your own apartment in the
city yeah how are you gonna make it work
that's gonna take curiosity
creativity courage commitment practice
iteration mistakes but it's possible and
if you know it's possible and you start
asking that question it can be array of
warmth and pleasure admits all of the
rest of the horror your life has become
for the moment it can become a thread
you follow back towards a new life and
that also reminds me half we can't ask
the question when will normal come back
when will I get my old body back after
change you never go back
you always go forward these these ideas
that these ideas that you're talking
about being open to change and to be
willing to change the context of your
sexuality that seems like that would be
the same path out of you know the the
feelings of depression that normally
come with pain as well you know we we
there's there's this initial shock when
suddenly the pain arrives or or if it
pains the pain comes slowly sometimes it
hits you when you get like a fin
official diagnosis but not only does the
pain itself like that I don't want to
perform in this way because it hurts but
then there's also this this depression
that comes along with it where it's like
like damn I'm broken and I'm never going
to be happy and love again and that can
be so heavy independently that you know
some people are so depressed that they
lose a will to express their sexuality
just because they're depressed and they
don't even have the pain and my heart
goes out to those folks too but it
sounds like they they both share this
this pathway out that you're describing
of essentially releasing the definitions
of what our society tells us is that is
this the pretty strict bandwidth of
where sexuality lives and and it doesn't
have to be that that's small of an area
mmm totally and you know we
people using the word pain it can be
also nausea it can be mental fog there's
a lot of things that can come with
illness or injury lifestyle changes
health changes that impact our sexuality
pain is kind of a short word for all of
them because they're all a pain in the
ass embracing this change totally so
much of it is about scripts and
recognizing that our sexuality is for a
lot of us for a lot of our lives have
been very dependent on identity based
scripts that tell us what we should do
usually as men and as women what people
want of us what successful sex looks
like what sex even means what it is what
activities it involves and it's kind of
shocking especially if you're not queer
if you haven't already spent a lot of
time opening up your sexuality and your
sexual attitudes when you start looking
at it you realize what a narrow script
most of us are operating in and what it
should zhan us like the shooting on us
is and I use that kind of intentionally
as almost like a nasty verb because
that's how it feels what does a man
should like what should a man do in bed
what should a woman do in bed how should
a man feel and for a lot of us these
gendered scripts tell us a man should be
the active initiator the one that gets
on top and thrusts the one that
initiates with you know a rock-hard
penis at any moment a woman should be
desirable she should be able to receive
penetration she should be wet and it
turns out none of these actually align
with our lived experience of sexuality
none of them align with the human
physiology and mechanics of sex and
there's so much more available to us
beyond the script and so this is the
liberation that's possible when all of
us that in our script is burned in the
bonfire of life and we're like holy [ __ ]
what am I left with my dick doesn't work
or it doesn't
stay hard long enough my [ __ ] doesn't
want to be penetrated anymore do you
want softer words realizing no I think I
mean we're already okay the show and
we're we're we're Network we count as
explicit so I guess we're just kind of
earning it today my body doesn't want to
be penetrated anymore or as often
I am tired all the time right like these
changes that come that throw our scripts
in the fire what are you left with and
this is the kind of deep inner work that
we get to do not that we have to do that
we get to do when we have big changes in
life that reveal so much about ourselves
that we reveal what is left of our
desire when the scripts get tossed out
the window what actually is possible
from these two bodies right now as is I
was on another podcast disability after
dark which is another great resource to
check out especially for folks who get
thrown into kind of major life
disabilities and Andrew and I boiled it
down to like we end up being just two
bodies in a room together asking you
know what do you want how can I please
you how can I serve you and that is such
a beautiful place to be with another
human being when all the [ __ ] is
stripped away when there's just this
urgency of life and of time which is
also another gift of disease gives us is
we have an urgency of life again and
from the hot place the homeless pleasure
is possible human bodies and I know this
is you know a polymorphous queer person
who is [ __ ] and been [ __ ] by all
sorts of bodies human bodies can fit
together in all sorts of ways and
pleasure one another in all sorts of
ways and we don't need anyone specific
you know capability or ability to engage
with that some of the most beautiful
lovers and kinkiest people I've known
have had the most limitations and the
most creativity and willingness to play
with one another
so I don't know I just really want to
like have the attitude of because I
can't perform
sorry bumped my mic I think what is
essential here is confronting the
attitude that tells us all is lost
you'll never love again it'll never be
the same therefore there's nothing to
look forward to you know that despair
does not help us heal it doesn't help us
manage our pain it doesn't help us
connect with our current lover or
partners we want to be engaged with
right like a despair is not useful for
very long it can be a very temporary
state to kind of languish in for a while
and feel it fully grieve what has been
lost and then if you're gonna choose to
continue living the question has to be
what next what now what do I want to
experience
well then let's let's talk about that
that place at the beginning because you
know when well I after my accident you
know after I got over the initial
awareness that I had been in an accident
and I had a brain injury and I was in a
lot of pain and experienced a lot of
exhaustion and you know there was the
firt I don't even really remember the
first three weeks after it I just kind
of I disappeared and from from everybody
and I mostly just slept and and when I
really came to grips with the reality of
my life I felt scared and alone and so I
called up my partner at the time and and
and I said hey you know I know I've been
missing but I told her I wanted I'd love
to get together with her and we got
together and and you know it touching
led to lovemaking and suddenly the
vertigo was there and and the like you
were talking about the male role earlier
as I was going through traditional male
roles leave it bet that I got really
dizzy
and I and I and and I was above her and
and this combination of feeling dizzy
and swooning and kind of falling to the
side at the same time I realized what
was happening and what this meant for my
life and I started crying and then I'm
realizing that oh my gosh I'm injured
and I'm crying what a disappointing guy
right it all builds up yeah fast right
in the moment and you know luckily I am
a you know I'm a I'm a pretty vulnerable
speaker anyway and so so I was able to
speak with her about what was going on
for me and I'm grateful for that but but
for people who are at that place and
their self-worth is so diminished
because of whatever this health
challenges that they're dealing with you
know it takes a certain amount of
self-worth or Moxie to start down this
path you're talking about right you know
being vulnerable and recontextualizing
sexuality for oneself that's not really
easy work so so what would you say the
baby steps are in in concrete terms for
somebody who realizes that they're here
but they are emotionally ready to change
it yes well thank you for sharing that
story because it encapsulates so much so
much of our moments when I say you know
our scripts have gone in the fire
fuck'em I say that with a certain amount
of queer irreverence but I also say that
knowing that our scripts are deeply
comforting they are what have told us
that we have value that we belong that
we are wanted and when we think about
that moment of you know seeing your
lover again and conversation leading to
kissing leading to lovemaking the heart
of what's going connect and you're
trying to establish like we can still do
this right and the question that has to
be asked is like what is the this we are
still trying to do and what is the new
way we are going to do it and this
starts with
this starts with communicating about sex
and I want to say again like this step
of changing our erotic lives can happen
with or without illness with or without
disease but the more loaded your life is
the harder this is the more pieces that
you can control right you're not doing
this erotic transformation under the
best of circumstances you're a little
bit transforming under duress so there's
a lot of self compassion that has to
come into play here and patience and
just baby stepping into it so some of
this is like taking stock of what this
situation is right what is your body
capable of right now how has your body
changed and that process can take months
and again like changes can happen so
quickly in illness that this has to be
an ongoing process in mindfulness we
have one of our courses is mindful sex
which I actually developed while I was
sick and healing because the way I
managed my pain and my rapidly changing
body was so much with my mindfulness
training I had from ten years earlier
and so much of that is about paying
attention moment to moment without
judgment right really easy to say hard
to do but it's an essential practice
when we're sick because we have to pay
attention to our bodies a lot of us have
to track our symptoms that becomes kind
of a superpower over time where we get
to know our bodies really well we can
talk about that later but the first step
and of taking stock where's my body at
what can I feel what capabilities do I
have do I not have and how different
does my sex life need to look because
for some of us the changes will be
subtle but really profound for others of
us it's completely different the
activities and positions and
interactions we are used to are no
longer available and that might take
some really serious creativity bringing
in toys you've never even heard of to
assist you in having the experiences you
want but all of this starts with
sation either with yourself first right
you're lying in bed you're trying to
heal and you're like all right body what
do we have what do we have to work with
what desires are there because your
desires might have also changed the sex
like you used to have might be even like
not even thinkable to you going out to
the club dancing picking up girls if
that was your sex like before it might
not even be possible anymore if you used
to make love to your wife four times a
week that might not even be on your mind
right and I'm curious with you and your
process like as sexuality got on your
mind was it about will I belong will I
be lovable will I be dateable will I be
alone or was it about like when's the
next time I'm gonna be able to have sex
like we need to stop thinking about sex
as this package deal and start realizing
how much we get out of sex physical
touch
perfection for me it was about about not
mattering anymore because you know how
our sexuality and how we present
ourselves about about sex like gives
people an impression about what our
thoughts are about sex and and and for
me it was like have I made myself no
longer relevant to the saucy you know
sexy people who I identified with when I
was that age and granted I was going out
to clubs and things more at that time
and you know since my brain injury
III stopped going out to clubs and
entirely and I it was is my feelings of
being irrelevant and and that's scary
right when when somebody perceives
themselves as being you know going to
art openings and going to restaurant
openings and you know getting to all go
all the cool stuff and then realizing
that you know I'm in a lot of pain and I
can barely walk and I get overstimulated
and am I really just gonna be at home
sitting here alone forever and a lot of
this is about the modeling we have for
sick and disabled people which frankly
sucks and so I also encourage people to
start following and fee
like their social media feeds with the
disability justice community who talk
and speak about their bodies with
respect and reverence and honor no
matter what it's a beautiful community
to learn a lot from but that thing of
belonging right and I was with Charlotte
for ten years we had been sex educators
we were like committed to eros as a
spiritual path I got sick and I was like
go on without me leave me find a better
lover you know and that self deprecating
I am worthless now that is our
internalized ableism speaking that is
our culture telling us you are no longer
valuable you are no longer worthy you
are no longer lovable and it's just not
true and hopefully the people in your
life will start showing you that showing
you how deeply lovable you are no matter
what if not start surrounding yourself
hopefully with people who can reflect
that back to you my ice just linked
hopefully we're surround yourself with
people who can reflect that to you but
ultimately this is a gift we give
ourselves we find our worthiness again
and again this is about identity the
things that we identified with our
communities that we felt a part of that
we found joy and belonging with may not
be accessible to us part of that is on
that community to be more accessible and
inclusive but it's also part of is like
our desires might shift as you said your
love of music might transform from going
to festivals to listening deeply at home
with headphones on to totally blissed
out your desire for nature might change
from surfing to sitting on the shore
meditating right like how does your body
now fit with your pleasures and your
desires this is going to be the
adventure of a lifetime to figure out as
your body continues to change but I
think what we know from people who are
ill even with terminal cancers even with
persistent pain that would you know the
pain patients here all the times like I
just can't imagine living that way it's
like well if the option is death you get
used to a lot and our bodies are so
resilient and adaptive that eroticism
and sexuality can be a part of that how
will your sexuality adapt how do your
attitudes need to change and that's
where it starts for so many of us I get
emails every day about the struggles and
people want the solution but what
happens if we swim upstream to the
attitude that is generating that
experience of the struggle that is
telling you that because your penis is
in hard sex is impossible
well let's swim upstream change that
attitude show you what sex is possible
and then you can choose from the menu of
delights right changing our attitudes
because frankly our sexual attitudes are
just really really toxic in this culture
so we all need to do this work but when
we do it through this lens of change and
transformation in order to give
ourselves the joy of sex back in our
lives it's really a gift to ourselves
and I really want to remind people this
doesn't have to look even like partnered
sexuality like if you are facing a
terminal illness you're errata sysm
might look like a lot of solo time in
nature taking deep joy and pleasure out
of that time that might be your erotic
expression it's really variable but
what's important is that it's yours and
on your terms so I've got one more path
I want to take on this idea of our
relationship with our self first before
we go to our first commercial and during
the second set we'll talk a lot more
about vulnerability and communication
with other people but I think it's I
think it's really important that we get
that relationship with ourselves good
and grounded first and that's this you
know if you go to the extreme if you go
beyond just the pain and then just the
depression and then just the diminished
self-worth if you continue that
there are people who have gotten to a
point that performing sexually under
duress of pain in the bed in the bedroom
can be is so bad that people begin to
form negative associations around sex
generally so far what you and I've been
talking about there seems to assume some
some seed of wanting to be sexual again
right and we know that sexuality is is
part of an overall healthy human you
know makeup and life experience what
kind of insight would you have to offer
with people who have felt like this for
so long that that sexuality or the
expression of it has become like a
contrast for them a conflict it's the
enemy and and and though they know that
it might be good for them mm-hmm the
word that really stuck out in your
question was performance to perform
under duress that sounds miserable for
anyone in any arena and so much of sex
again when we're talking about scripts
you perform a script and we have been
taught that sex is a performance and you
do it well or you fail you are a sex God
or you're a total loser right like we
are taught that sex is a performance
that you get a grade on sex is something
we experience through our bodies through
our beings right we can stop performing
sex and start being sexual beings and
again this isn't just like you know cute
language for Instagram this is really an
important attitude shift where if the
question is not can I perform sex
tonight according to a script and I have
to hit these certain marks in order to
be successful if the question is what do
I want to experience what is my body
capable of what's available to me how
can I serve you how can I pleasure you
if you have a partner then you have an
open-ended path to take together
and it's so important to remind people
of this because so much of that not
tonight honey or dodging sex or avoiding
the rejection cycle comes out of this if
I initiate sex we have to do X Y &amp; Z and
it's a package deal and if your body
isn't feeling like being kind of traded
and your husband initiates sex it's so
much easier to be like nope not
available then to communicate well I'm
not really available for penetration but
X Y &amp; Z sounds good and let's see after
the foot massage right let's start with
the 10-minute foot massage see how that
makes me feel and know that there's no
pressure to continue either way and if
you want to get off after my foot
massage I will watch you as you stroke
yourself right but this level of sexual
communication is almost unthinkable to
most people this level of sexual knowing
of having that ease and fluency of
talking about sex is unthinkable so
where do we need to start by talking
about sex by thinking about sex by
getting new ideas so we have a
vocabulary of what might be possible if
that intercourse you know a few minutes
of oral leading to intercourse script is
no longer available to you what then
there is so much available to you and
people like me are here to tell you and
root you on
and remind you that you are not alone
and in the end that's that's pretty much
what the goal I had with this show is
because I know that a lot of folks who
are not in the best relationships with
their body and who use cannabis for pain
or other relief they could probably use
hearing this message too so thank you
Chris
we're gonna take a short break and be
right back you are listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is sex educator
Chris Maxwell Rose if you listen to
shaping fire and you grow your own
cannabis chances are high that you are
very particular about the inputs you use
for growing people like us painstakingly
self-educate on cannabis nutrients and
techniques so we can cultivate the best
and cleanest flowers possible and when
we go to purchase those nutrients we
want to be sure that our supplier shares
our values and is providing exceptional
quality this is why I recommend build a
soil calm to my friends who care about
quality build a soil empowers organic
growers to do their best work by
sourcing and shipping only the finest
cannabis growing supplies from organic
inputs soils soil testing and pots to
Lights growing tents sprayers and cover
crops build a soil founder Jeremy Silva
doesn't just stock his store with what's
available he goes deep to personally vet
each product for quality and determine
that there isn't a better version of the
product that he could be selling because
of this arduous process you know that
your options on build a soil calm have
been carefully curated to create the
results you are looking for not only
that but the build a soil way is a
philosophy that will permeate your
interaction with the company from
website design to pricing and shipping
to after purchase support Jeremy and his
team always strive to do their best and
give you the best customer service in
the business
checkout build a soil dot-com today for
top tier quality cultivation supplies
and a friends and family buying
experience and check out their
educational videos and extraordinary
social media while you're there to
quality organic growing supplies at
build a soil calm in times like these
when so many cannabis companies are
growing their flower in gigantic
warehouses and fields using synthetic
nutrients it is good to know that there
are authentic California heritage
growers using natural farming techniques
and sunshine to cultivate cannabis
flowers for you California has produced
the best cannabis in the world for
generations and the idea that massively
scaled industrial cannabis production
could produce the same quality as small
batch lovingly cultivated flowers is
just silly moon time medicinals is
located in humble
County on the lush South Fork of the eel
River watershed in the epicenter of the
American cannabis heartland moon time
medicinals grows under bright California
Sun in greenhouses using only natural
farming techniques like google culture
compost teas whole food fertilisers and
fermented plant juices every part of
their growing process plays its own part
in nature and nothing synthetic is
injected into the process the result is
big beautiful cannabis flowers with
wide-ranging terpene profiles that taste
like great cannabis should if you live
in California ask your bud tender for
moon time medicinals and visit moon time
medicinals on the web and instagram moon
time medicinals is also available as
part of the Redwood roots family moon
times whole flowers appear in Redwood
roots curated joint packs alongside
other heritage cannabis cultivators like
lady sativa farm Ridgeline farms humble
redwood healing and others moon time
medicinals top-shelf cannabis grown in
harmony with nature did you know that
shaping fire has a fabulous YouTube
channel with content not found on the
podcast when I attend conventions or
speak or moderate panels I always record
them and bring the content home for you
to watch the Shango Losey youtube
channel it has world-class speakers
including kevin Jodrey of wonderland
nursery talking about breeding cannabis
for the best terpene profile nicholas
mahmud on regenerative and poly culture
cannabis growing dr. Sunil a girl on the
history of cannabis medicine around the
world Ben Cassidy of true terpenes on
using terpenes for health in your
everyday life Reggie Godinho of steep
hill on the cannabis genome and Jeff
Lowen Fell's on the soil food web
there are several presentations from dr.
Ethan Russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system and even my own
presentation on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose cannabis business even though the
risks are so high as of today there are
over 100 videos that you can check out
for absolutely free go to youtube.com
forward slash Shango 'lose or click on
the link in this week's newsletter
welcome back you are listening to
shaping
fire I'm your host Shang golos and our
guest this week is sex educator Chris
Maxwell Rose so as we saw in the first
set common challenges to fulfilling sex
for pain patients or really anybody who
is looking for body relief is often a
blend of emotional and interpersonal
communication and physical issues
there's like this is working on a lot of
different levels so let's talk next
about the communication aspects because
you know these insights likely work for
anyone who hesitates from talking about
sex at all you don't necessarily have to
be injured but since today we're really
focusing on cannabis patients with
chronic pain or other chronic issues
Chris what sort of advice do you give to
folks who want to initiate conversation
with their partner or potential partner
to get them talking about their desires
and physical limitations because so
often it's just
oh the getting started part that's so
hard you open your mouth and you want
sound to come out and and it's hard so
where can people start with that mmm
it's such a great question and we need
to remember when we're talking about all
communication one of the things we're
doing is we're making the invisible
visible we are bringing our interior
life outward to be shared and that's can
be vulnerable it can be scary but it's
also what makes things possible so I
just want to give you a little bit of
cheerleading that while opening up your
mouth and speaking about sex might be
one of the scariest things you do in
this process it will also be deeply
rewarding if you stick with it because
part of communicating about sex is
getting specific we've been talking
about the script we all get kind of this
cultural download about what sex means
what it means to be a man or a woman
what it means to be sexy what it means
to be desired a lot of that information
is frankly just wrong or it comes from a
deeply sex-negative place that's trying
to very limit your sexual experience so
what we want to do is open up our minds
open up our vocabularies
and start getting ideas insights and
operate like options ideas are pathways
to possibility we need to have that in
order to envision what is possible for
us because if you're a man who's just
gotten a prospect to me and you've lost
your penis function or you're in so much
lower back pain the idea of thrusting is
just nowhere on the table the question
has become like well then what is
possible communication can start with
listening reading or watching right that
is a form of communication where you are
starting kind of in the receptive role
there are great podcasts ours is just
one of them there are books you can read
we'll try to put some resources together
for you but that can be a really gentle
way to start as you're lying in bed as
you're going for your healing walks
whatever it is listen to a podcast and
when there's an episode that resonates
for you share it share it either with
your intimate partner or even with a
friend and talking about sex with
friends can be less scary maybe than
talking about it with your partner you
want to find a zone of safety and when
I'm talking about safety I'm not talking
about just physical safety from violence
I'm talking about the social safety and
there's a lot of brain science we can go
in here but I'll keep it simple the
social safety where you feel connected
and like you belong and you're accepted
where you can feel calm and interested
in conversation that's the zone you want
to try to talk about sex out of if
you're feeling scared and activated and
ashamed and fearful your brain can't
really work you can't really communicate
well and so that's maybe a signal to you
if you feel that in your body like oh
this is feeling too scary that you want
to take a baby step back and listen to
some more podcasts or try something
different one of the resources I'll give
to you is episode we did about nonverbal
communication you can write your lover a
letter you can start
choose your own adventure book with your
lover where you say would you rather
this or that you can listen to a podcast
together walking on the street with
headphones on and then stop at a bench
and discuss it and you already have this
whole banquet of language to talk about
you can print out an article and
highlight a few sentences and just say
to your lover you know I saw this
article about this thing what do you
think right you're not saying I want
this will you do it to me
that's a really charged question it's
just saying what do you think about this
idea but for many of us talking about
sex is scary because of all the shame
all of the guilt all of the stigma
associated with sex in general and we're
on different places with this right like
there's generational issues here there's
cultural differences but you also want
to get to a place where you can think
and talk about sex on your own even in
your own mind in your own authentic
voice in a way that doesn't start with
shame that doesn't start with fear and
that can take some excavation if you've
learned you know different people have
different cultural backgrounds that tell
them that sex itself is dirty or that
pleasure during sex is not the goal or
the body should not be seen all sorts of
messages we internalize and sometimes
it's shocking you know what we realize
what we have to kick out of bed like we
think were really sexy free beings and
then we realized just how constrained we
are by shame or traumas from the past so
a lot of this is again that self inward
stuff of like alright this is going to
be scary to talk about but the truth is
after an illness and injury a disease
there's so much you need to talk about
your mobility might have changed your
diet but probably has to change your
cannabis use might change so you need
conversations with your lover or your
partner or the people you're living with
and yourself about all of these things
and sex is just going to be one of them
and what I find is that a lot of
partners are really relieved when the
subject
comes up because I think when you know
your partners in a hospital bed or has
this new injury sex can feel unimportant
to name very few of the doctors will
bring it up especially if they don't
perceive that children are an issue and
there's so much there you know like the
medical industry needs so much training
about sexuality but they might not even
mention it or they might say something
flip slip in like wait six weeks and
then you should be able to resume normal
activities like really and I always wish
like I could pop into people's bedrooms
as the sex fairy and just be like it's
okay there are options but we don't have
that magical sex fairy and so we need to
be bold and courageous to just like look
our partner in the eye and be like how
are we going to connect what are the
stages here what are the seasons ahead
of us right like are we heading towards
a terminal illness and we're facing a
very specific season ahead of us is or
is this the acute phase and things are
gonna get better
most of the time you don't actually know
and so it's just about being and this is
a language that really came out of my
illness was being in the current sexual
season that you are in looking at your
partner being like this is where we are
right now what do you need what do I
need how can we meet each other where do
our Venn diagrams overlap they might not
be touching at all and some of this and
I think well maybe touch on this later
but is what is your partner like what is
the non ill person need assuming just
one of you is more deeply impacted
although that's not always true
what is the healthier partner need the
more able-bodied partner need because
sometimes their needs get totally
overlooked it becomes all about the sick
person and resentment starts to build
and they start you know that can lead to
other things and so it's a conversation
about both of you and about recognizing
the season you're in deeply with honesty
with humility with all the fields and
then starting the conversation about
okay
like what do we need what do we need to
talk about to move forward and sometimes
talking itself is the erotic
relationship for a while
you know if you can't physically move
maybe you're gonna be in a conversation
for a few months and that's an
opportunity to read erotica together to
listen to podcasts to get more honest
about what you're both wanting but it
doesn't always go this smoothly right
like I'm painting a picture of what is
possible you know people are gonna find
themselves in all sorts of different
contexts and all sorts of different
conversations I think what we want to
try to Center is the dignity the idea
that sexuality can be a pleasurable part
of your life no matter what
it just might look different and embrace
this idea of change this is where we are
right now we don't know where we'll be
in three or six months so what fun what
pleasure what connection can we share
right now some people will be in the
mood to like have an orgasm
the second they wake up in a hospital
bed that impulse is there and they are
ready to like reclaim their sexuality
for other people it is dormant asleep it
gets buried under a ton of other
survival needs and it wakes up slowly
so it's so much about seeing where
you're at honoring it fully and then
going from there with support yeah you
have set up a couple different scenarios
so that people can you know create this
vulnerable environment right where
whatever whatever that looks like for
them with whoever they're choosing to
speak to and that and that's good I like
you though have this idealized picture
that that once once folks start talking
and they and they get the ball rolling
that the world the words will come
freely and and the conversation will be
animated and they'll just be all this
wonderful healing but you know I know
that for a lot of people that is not
going to be the case
there there their partner might be in a
place where they are traumatized from
the other person's injury or whatever's
going on for them the they may not they
may be they may have their own sexual
hang-ups where they're like I don't want
to talk about this so so why don't you
share some insights on that if if you're
the patient and you are trying to create
this vulnerable and sharing dynamic so
that you can kind of get off script and
create this new context as you're
describing but the partner is a little
resistant because they're just not there
with you in their head yet yeah and
again this is a disparity that can come
up with or without illness the idea that
one person wants to talk about it and
explore and the other is unwilling and
so much of this again is excavating and
meeting the other person where they're
at and recognizing you know I know you
come from a long line of stubborn women
who aren't willing to talk about my
things it's really important you know
it's like maybe that's not the best
lead-up what are the best questions I
really like is how can I love you right
now what is one way I can take care of
you
especially when I was sick and my role
is like the giver and the lover and the
one with the magic hands like all of
that was gone and part of my
worthlessness that feeling of despair is
I have nothing left to give I'm taking
so much as a patient
I'm not producing right I'm not working
giving your partner giving the sick
partner opportunities to show up and
love and do something is a gift to both
of you so if the healthy partner can say
what I love is to sit and you know [ __ ]
at you all about my day and have you
just listen great or you know are you
available to give me a foot massage you
might be really sick but still available
to touch your lover are you willing to
sit with me and watch porn and just be
with me while I watch a little porn and
masturbate like
is that in your vocabulary looking at
what options are there but okay this
cooks about like you're asking about the
people who are I'm talking about
watching porn together and you're asking
about talking about sex there's this
huge gap and you know I work with this
gap every day like our audience
represents this huge range of human
sexual experience from the frozen and
mired in shame and trauma to the point
that you barely want to look at your own
eroticism to like I am ready to explore
the mountaintops of what's possible
we're all somewhere in that process and
we swing wildly within it we've been in
our lives I've been at all stages
multiple times when you're sick the
vulnerability and just like that holding
on to life is so precious and can be so
erotic that your pleasures will make
themselves known to you because when I
say erotic I don't mean like this is
deeply sexual and sexy I mean erotic as
in you are feeling big feelings you are
feeling alive you're feeling that pulse
of vitality at my sickest is when I felt
that thrumming through me of like what
am i alive for what pleasures are still
available to me you might be someone who
loves flowers go deep into flowers like
put flowers by your bedside every day
and marvel at them and let that fuel you
your relationship with sexuality doesn't
have to be like the far-out sexy sex we
think about it's this whole range of
pleasure joy connection so if you're
starting this conversation with your
partner and things have changed so much
of the question is like how what are you
scared of might be a really good place
to start what are you worried about
because that will allow the quite the
vulnerability from both of you I'm
worried I'll never be able to make love
to you the same way I'm worried we won't
be able to have children I'm worried if
we do have children we won't be able to
parent the way we thought we'd write
like your worries will come bubbling up
that is going to be scary but you're
both holding them anyway that's the
thing and I like that too because you're
not you're not initiating the
conversation with let's do new sexual
things you're starting with tell me your
story that you're saying inside to
yourself and I think that that if the
other partner is you know potentially
going to feel awkward with this
conversation
starting with them saying their truth
telling their story I would say that
that would be one of the easier places
to start when somebody's feeling super
hesitant because maybe they have been
traumatized by their partner being
traumatized and maybe they're not too
comfortable talking about sex at all I
mean my gosh I have you know I have
dated women who you know the main thing
they wanted was to just be treated not
meanly right and and and to put someone
in a position where where they're being
asked to share what matters to them even
just emotionally I would say that that
that may be a really softball entree to
get words and emotions flowing yes yeah
and you know that soft flummery place
where you're both kind of like torn open
a little bit is a good place to be if
you can get there safely and again I
want to come back to that how do you
create a context for these conversations
to happen where you both feel regulated
you feel connected you feel like you can
say things and mess up and be forgiven
this is what we call the culture of your
relationship and so depending on what
the culture of your relationship was
kind of you know before and after
whatever this big change was you'll have
your own strategies one of the best
strategies is getting in the car and
driving together for that harder
conversation because you're not forced
to look at each other you're not forced
into that eye contact that can become
confrontational
some people and there is some kind of
magic about road trip talks isn't it I
don't know what that's about really and
maybe it is because you're not looking
at each other or that so often part of
the road trip is at night right and so
somehow we seem maybe we feel a little
safer by the dashboard lights alone but
there really is some magic about the
kind of depth that comes when you're in
the car for hours together yeah and
solutions then can start coming up once
you know what the fears are once you
know what the vulnerabilities are
sometimes you'll say the thing allow
that you're so afraid of and your
partner will be like Oh baby you don't
need to worry about that that's not even
on my mind and that relief is just
palpable or they'll say I've been
thinking about that I've been waking up
at night with these thoughts so what do
we do and you can look at each other
knowing okay now we're both in this
together
or they'll say you know I never even
thought about that this is what I'm
worried about this is what's right in
front of me preventing me from
connecting with you and then you can
address that together right you need to
get on a same page so you can start
writing what is next what is coming for
you the vast number of changes
adaptations pivots you're gonna have to
make in your life and this is just try
again you know we're recording this in
2020 in the middle of a global pandemic
and so we're getting a master lesson in
change and resilience this is what the
human condition is about and we're
actually really good at it and we're
better at it when we do it together with
people we have established love and
connection and affection with and so you
can leverage this right like
relationships will change sometimes
illness injury comes relationships will
end right one partner is just not in for
the ride and that has to be valid you
know there can be huge amounts of
abandonment betrayal and all sorts of
things there but if you are in for the
ride together if you are saying all
right we're gonna embrace this change
and keep on loving each other this is a
moment where everything gets to change
and both of your needs get to be more
fully met and you get to be in that
crazy wild adventure of living together
right illness can wake you up and create
this urgency if we allow it
it can also be terrifying and put us in
states of freeze but if we are awake to
our condition if we don't feel alone
with it if we feel resourced which is
very hard in this particular country
with our healthcare system and again
like what is your stress right because
we talked about all these things if
you're ill probably the top stressors on
your list have nothing to do with your
sex life it's health insurance it's
medications it's your job but all of
those things create a context where you
no longer feel the place to play you no
longer feel the desire or the permission
to let go and enjoy yourself and so we
need to look at the whole life context
what the stressors are how you're gonna
relieve your stress cycles together your
partner might need permission like you
go to your yoga class three times a week
I'll call in my other friend for the
assistance I need for bath time right
like you need care networks also to get
through this the idea that your partner
is gonna be your caretaker help you with
all the health insurance paperwork maybe
be a co-parent and be your lover that's
a lot to ask yeah who else in your
community can help who else in your
community can even provide you with
companionship or conversation to lighten
the load between you so there's more
space for this connection this play but
it's a lot right like we're this is a
lot and I want to say you and I have
both been in it I'm now about four years
out of my health crisis and now living
with chronic illness and pain and it has
completely transformed how I approach my
work as a sex educator I've always been
aware of the complexity of sex we've
always approached it that way this has
been such a humbling lesson in how
complicated how nuanced it can be but
also how powerful it can be to give
yourself even when you're sick even if
you're dying even if you're riddled with
pain permission to ask the question what
would make me
feel good right now what would give me a
little bit of pleasure in my day maybe
how can I give someone else pleasure
because a lot of us giving someone else
pleasure is a joy for us too that makes
us feel worthy of being alive again so
even having a shred of that that is like
bring me flowers from my bedside that is
an act of erotic agency on that day and
it counts
I like this term that you used the
culture of a relationship and I think
that it's something that is probably not
uncommon that someone gets injured or
gets a bad diagnosis in a relationship
and they're already in a really crappy
cultural relationship and you know the
the the the vulnerability and the
strategies that that we're talking about
today they kind of assume a modicum of
healthy culture in the relationship and
I think that it's probably worth
addressing the idea that that maybe you
have got this you know new pain or
disease or whatever in your life and you
actually don't want that other person
around
they are the trauma has made you realize
that they are they're not going to be
helpful during this time and I was
thinking about the first set when you
talked about how the primary sexual
relationship is with ourselves
certainly self gratification but even
getting yourself flowers right and I
think that people should remain free to
know that they can make a decision to no
longer be with the partner that they
were before the accident or whatever and
it doesn't mean that they are they're
choosing to fire sex right they are
probably choosing to express it
themselves for a while and they're going
to have to you know develop some skills
to
you know attract find another partner
that they could build a healthier
context of relationship with but there
is certainly enough stress that comes
from a from a trauma like that that will
just go ahead and take a bad
relationship and just crush it well I
think many of us will be nodding along
when we talk about this moment of you
know you see who your friends are
after you get sick you see kind of what
people can hold and I don't want to
judge people who cannot hold the
intensity or some people will just slip
away but some people in your life will
show up for you in ways you never
expected
the sad thing here is we don't have a
culture that teaches us how to love one
another this is something I've been
raging against recently we don't have a
culture that shows us how to show up for
our friends in the hospital how to love
people who are dying most of us get
totally freaked out and ghosts so a lot
will change your Friendship Circle will
change your family network will change
let the people in who are offering help
and as you said show people the door who
are making you feel lesser than who are
making you feel like a burden you will
think all about of yourself you do not
need people in your life telling you
that that is their ableism at work that
is their fear of mortality it's it's an
uncanny thing how little healthy people
like to be reminded of their mortality
and so especially again if you come out
of a community of athletes like some of
your friends are gonna be really shitty
to you some people and often it's the
people who have had a sick mother or a
sick friend who have gone through an
illness themselves will show compassion
for you let it in and allow your life to
change in that way too but yes
absolutely if your relationship is not
one that can change with this change in
your life it takes an act of courage to
be even more you know I don't use the
word alone
without partnership without that support
but bad support is actually a burden so
yeah yeah bad support just makes
everything worse right sometimes like oh
my gosh I wish my helper would go away
I'd rather be trying this on my own and
there might be a step there what is your
helper need like you know again we're
not trained to be caretakers and I've
been in both the role of caretaking
someone with a huge major illness and
being taken care of to the point where
you know I couldn't lift my limbs and
they were being arranged for me the hat
role is like a sacred beautiful role and
if you're not getting professional
support you might as a family in it as
an individual need to ask for more help
about how to make these changes our
medical system again you get sent home
from the hospital with a brochure and
it's like good luck figuring it out so
for me it's you know online communities
of people with my condition podcast like
this are where you will get the support
to figure out the changes ahead of you
ask other people with your condition
about their sex life
right get on the Facebook group and be
the bold one to be like so what have you
guys figured out about your sex life
after this any tips you'll get responses
you have to be willing to talk about
this and know that you're not alone
whatever you're facing right whether
that's sex through pain sex through
disease sex at the end of life there are
people who have done this before and
have your back and can be in loving
conversation with you to figure this
[ __ ] out you do not have to go it alone
another thing that our American culture
is not super great at at the moment is
self-care and in the first set we hit on
depression as an obstacle to sexuality
you know any suggestions on getting
yourself in the mood like I it sounds
like it can be obvi you know it should
be an obvious thing but I think that
with the with the general lack of
self-care that we have in our country
and then if you add pain or a diagnosis
or something that pushes up us off our
game
that it may not be immediately obvious
to people to kind of get themselves back
in their own mindset to even want to be
sexual yeah so this is another one of
those moments for a swimming upstream
and getting a new framework that will
help here and that is one of the two
forms of desire the two forms of sexual
interest we talked about spontaneous
desire a lot right I'm just in the mood
I get horny it was like a thunderbolt
comes out of this guy and bam that is
not often how people get aroused
there's also responsive desire where
something feels good your brain tracks
it it says mmm that feels good more of
that please and it builds on itself so
when we kind of know that both
spontaneous desire and responsive desire
possible responsive desire is the one we
have a lot more agency over we can start
cultivating an attitude of curiosity
about pleasure
right so so much of this is a curiosity
towards pleasure what is bringing me
pleasure today I'm going to follow that
thread and in the mood for what again if
it's a package deal of kissing oral sex
intercourse and I'm not in the mood for
intercourse I'm just gonna throw out the
whole package maybe I'm in the mood to
cuddle and I can express that like it
would feel really good just to lie in
bed turn all the lights off get under
three duvets and have you lie behind me
naked can you give yourself permission
to ask for what you want that is a huge
skill set and the first part of that
skill set is like tuning into your own
body
this is interception of feeling your
feelings feeling how your body is
feeling noticing little sparks of desire
like oh it would feel so good to be held
right now and then giving yourself
permission to move towards that to ask
for it you know the word depression can
mean a lot of things it can mean
clinical depression that needs to be
like
read it as its own thing but for a lot
of us it can also mean context and the
context is so important for arousal and
this brings up another framework and
again we'll link to deeper podcast so
you can geek out on what interests you
but arousal works kind of like a gas and
brakes model and we are often thinking
about what would put more gas on it what
would give me more interest but it's
really useful to think about what is
putting the brakes on my desire what is
putting the brakes on my interest or my
willingness and those are some of the
things we can start actively managing
maybe my bedroom has become like filled
with medical equipment and it just
doesn't feel sexy is there anything you
can do to make your bedroom have more
context and the medical equipment live
in another room or can you do a hotel
room once a month what about your
context can you change are there
medications that are deeply impacting
things can you tweak that are there ways
of like parts of the day like you have a
lot of energy in the morning at night
your pain is spiking can you have a
conversation about like can we have a
little bit of time in the morning to
just roll around in bed because that's
when my body feels best
we each develop our strategies here
based on our conditions but so much of
this comes back to permission are you
giving yourself permission for pleasure
and I dare you to even start
prioritizing your pleasure when we're
sick when we're like you know there's
always insurance calls to make there's
always work to catch up on we always
feel like we're not contributing enough
to the household do you have the mental
space to say it's okay to take 20
minutes and just do something because it
feels good for a lot of us like that's
the first like is there permission for
pleasure in your life anymore
if not how do you give that to yourself
and then what's important is noticing
the impact of it because pleasure is
some of the best medicine we have
pleasure is what allows us to connect
with others and share deep feelings that
makes us feel like part of the human
family pleasure is what motivates us
into the next day and pleasure can be an
amazing painkiller orgasms can be an
incredible painkiller pleasure can get
your mind off of your disease for like
15 precious minutes where you are not
your illness and that freedom can
transform your experience of being ill
this is about agency like I am ill but I
am still also a mother a lover a friend
I am ill but I'm also still loving
massage and a little kinky I am ill but
I also still want orgasms and oral sex
right like you're ill but what else is
true about you let yourself have
permission to be an erotic being on your
own terms right now and see what that
looks like for you knowing it doesn't
have to be the pornstar model at all to
be deeply satisfying and nourishing and
that's another thing I get after a
decade in this field plus what is
satisfying and fulfilling to us as
erotic beings it's so vast and variable
and changeable but that feeling of like
yes I am here in my sexuality I am a
whole person pleasure is available and
accessible to me that is available to
all of us in one form or another that
sense of freedom and erotic wholeness is
what we all long for like how do we get
there now and that's the
choose-your-own-adventure that's the
dance all in so you know in an ideal
world we would end that line of
questioning there because because oh you
know we're essentially giving the
message you know that there are
solutions for you you know you guys do
you think out of the box and and you can
get there
but I think that I want to ask a
question
to give voice to a certain group of
people who have already tried this and
they have been unsuccessful in getting
themselves in the mood and their pain is
overarching or their disease is
overarching and they have not been able
to reignite their sexual vibes because
of it and you know maybe they're there
for their partner for their for their
pleasure or not but for themselves
they've decided they're done with sex
right they've given up on having sex
they've just decided that I'm not even
going to try anymore because I have done
all the trying I can do we have anything
heartening for those folks who are
afraid that their their relationship
with their sexuality and maybe their
relationship is doomed hmm well there's
two pieces here you can give up and have
that be okay you can have very little
interest in sexuality in general or
sexual connection with another person
and some people are asexual their whole
life and that is not a struggle for them
so it's not a problem if it's not a
problem for you there's no magic number
of kinds of sex or frequency of sex that
makes a sex life healthy it's healthy if
it feels good and right and fulfilling
to you so what are the areas that don't
feel right what are the areas that still
feel like a struggle you may say like I
am never have I just talked to a woman
who is like I am never having sex again
and she was like I've given up on
sexuality turn it on she went all into
it but she delights in all of these
other things with human beings and has
all this whole other set of pleasures
that she fills her life with and has
like a really fulfilling life so giving
up on what are you giving up on pleasure
because that sounds um that's to be me
yeah that's different and I don't even
want to problematize that because I'd
like their depths of human experience
that I cannot understand when I was at
my most ill you know I had lost a
hundred pounds I had lost all of my
muscle mass
and I was like my life was reduced I was
in bed feeling the sheets against my
very frail body and all my body was was
pain right at that moment I also had a
one and a half year old daughter I had
this beautiful wife I had this purpose
filled work I loved and so my pleasure
just became about stayin alive
my pleasure became about hoping for
healing became about doing research into
my own healing so I could try at least
to you know keep my feet pleasure had
totally changed for me and then it
changed again and then it changed again
and then it changed again and that trust
in change is what I think I really want
to bring to this because you might have
just given up on sex like you might
never imagine you're gonna be erotic
with anyone that is fine if that is what
is healthy and feels real and right to
you good you might have other priorities
in front of you you might have you know
a diagnosis and be like I don't want to
spend any time chasing tail I'm gonna
write make that writing as pleasurable
as you can buy the best pen you know
like
luxuriate and whatever we are doing with
these lives of ours I think you know
that's the urgency I talk about when we
realize you know my disease is one I
have to manage every day and kind of
keep myself alive by pushing buttons and
double-a batteries that action every day
just reminds me of this preciousness and
whatever spiritual overlay you have you
know and I light up a bowl of cannabis
and exhale and look out the window and
feel alive in my human body even if it's
pain I'm feeling I'm kind of like
there's a gratitude of just being here
for it
so I think like give up on what you like
give it up we have we all have to give
up a lot there's a surrender like give
it up and then be like what's left what
do I want to do as I'm drawing this
breath as I'm exhaling this smoke as I
love the name of your podcast so much
because for me like Hannah
is a sacrament and I really do think
about what am i shaping with every
breath what am i shaping in the world
what am i creating conspiring means like
breathing together who are you
conspiring with towards what what is
bringing you delight
that is your pleasure follow that don't
worry about what sex means to anyone
else that's your errata sysm that is
your thread of life right now awesome
thank you Chris for going there with me
let's let's go ahead and take our last
short break and be right back well and
if and if you've been it and if you're
here to learn more about sexual
positions don't worry don't go away
after after the break we're gonna be
talking more about broadening the
possibilities of sexual expression in
itself but physicians toys and mom yeah
exactly stay tuned so you are listening
to shaping fire my guest today is sex
educator Chris Maxwell rose there are
lots of good seed makers out there every
once in awhile someone becomes legendary
the Mendocino California cannabis
breeder called mandelbrot is one of
these people Mandelbrot was also known
as roz truth and his cultivars are known
as the foundation for the Emerald
triangles world-famous gasoline scented
terpene profile back in the day when it
was really hard to find quality genetics
and education
Mandelbrot was advocating for organic
growing techniques and providing
exceptional seeds that would sell out as
soon as they hit the shelves
Mandelbrot lived too short of life dying
in 2015 but while he was with us he
created several connoisseur level canvas
masterpieces like oil spill the truth
and royal cush no matter if you approach
growing cannabis more as a toker or a
breeder you will find something that
delights you in Mandelbrot selections
because while some strains are better to
grow or to smoke Mandelbrot's creations
excel in every category and that's why
people keep talking about them even
today emerald mountain legacy continues
the rasa truth tradition by preserving
these coveted genetics for future
generations unchanged as they were
originally created in the mid 2000s
emerald mountain legacy also creates
tasteful modern crosses to Mandelbrot's
classics these lines worked by
Mandelbrot's brother ben furthers their
families genetics and a spirit that
mammal brought himself would approve of
check out the emerald mountain legacy
instagram and website to see photos of
these plants and learn more about
Mandelbrot and his infamous strains
emerald mountain legacy seeds are
available online from seed banks and
distributors including labyrinth seed
company the regenerative seed company
and pure sativa emerald mountain legacy
keeping Mandelbrot's legacy alive as a
business owner you are incredibly busy
in reality you are responsible for
everything your company does you've got
so many responsibilities every single
day that often you just don't have the
time to really dig into your marketing
as deeply as you'd like you know there's
more that you could do to reach out to
new customers and encourage loyalty and
the customers you already have but you
certainly don't have the time for it and
you're not ready to hire somebody
full-time for that role either for you I
recommend blunt branding at blunt
branding Kirsten Nelson and her team are
focused on improving your bottom line
you know most marketing firms are
excited to make your logo packaging and
website very pretty but they leave
responsibility for improving your bottom
line up to you they don't want that kind
of responsibility but that's pretty much
the most important part of marketing
right Kirsten and her team will help you
engage new customers funnel them to your
point of sale whether it be online or a
storefront and keep them coming back to
you and telling their friends now if you
happen to be a new cannabis company or
an established company moving from
medical to adult use in your state
Kirsten especially can help you not only
is she well versed in marketing and
finance but she totally gets cannabis
whole plant medicine terpenes heritage
farmers and the particular needs of
startups check out what she did recently
for moon time medicinals and humbled at
moon time medicinals calm Kirsten and
her team put together a whole brand
package for them built their website and
wrote their sales materials no doubt
this is a paid commercial spot but that
does not mean they bought my opinion
I've worked with blunt branding on five
projects now for various of their
clients and ever
single time they have done more than
they have promised and over delivered on
results I love how they generate new
revenue and focus on that as the goal
instead of just making a pretty logo
similarly every single friend I have
referred them to has come back to thank
me and that just does not happen every
day grab a pen and paper because the
website address is coming up if you want
someone to implement marketing programs
that feed your bottom line give blunt
branding a call they will share proven
techniques to increase your audience and
generate sales while using cutting-edge
technology solutions in the background
that make all of this easy automatic and
trackable go to shaping feiyr.com
forward slash blunt branding to find out
more you can also click the link in our
newsletter Blount branding marketing
that makes you money pre-rolls have come
a long way since the early days of
normalization
when you choose Saints joints you are
smoking all flour top-shelf pre-rolls
with terpenes that will sculpt your high
in a way that dry old pre-rolls just
can't whereas most brands release
pre-rolls as an afterthought for the
last five years
Saints joints has focused on their line
of exotic curated joints and while some
companies just chase the hype strains
Saints joints goes deeper searching out
hard-to-find strains unexpected crosses
and nearly forgotten land races and
classics and some hype ones too not only
does a joint from Saints Smoke
incredibly well they have fine-tuned
every step of the process so you don't
get runs in the paper the joint is just
the right density to have a nice pull
and the joint stays lit even if you get
a bit chatty Saints joints boxes are
works of art and will spark conversation
when you pull them out at a party Saints
award winning boxes change with every
release feature edgy outsider art and
often raise awareness of important
issues like equal rights Saints boxes
are so desired then many collect them
and display them in their homes ask your
bud tender for Saints joints and have a
premium joint experience now if you are
licensed cannabis cultivator I have an
extra message for you Saints is looking
for partners in legal cannabis States to
expand the availability of the Saints
joints brand do you grow exceptional
canvas flower but are less excited about
all the effort cost and risk of
launching your own brand Saints joints
may be just a partner you are looking
for already established in California
Washington and Oklahoma and recognized
by Entrepreneur Magazine and green
entrepreneur as a cannabis industry
leader the Saints joints brand will set
you apart in your home market the best
thing I can recommend is for you to
visit their Instagram at Saints joints
and look at their patented drawer design
boxes become that brand everyone is
talking about without having to build it
from scratch
check out the Instagram at Saints joints
and then visit Saints joints calm to
find out more welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I'm your host
Shango losan our guest this week is sex
educator Chris Maxwell rose so Chris
we've gotten to the meat of the
situation that's probably what a lot of
people came for it's like how do I still
have sex when I feel like this so let's
start off with limited mobility so what
do you recommend to people with limited
mobility to figure out the new positions
that will work for them uniquely totally
it is so much about finding what works
not only for your body but how your body
fits with the other body for the thing
your bodies want to be doing together
right and so when we think about
positions it's easy to think about
positions for intercourse but there are
also positions for cuddling for spanking
for cunnilingus and fellatio for all
sorts of pleasures right and so so much
of it is finding that geometry the way
your bodies fit together now because how
you fit together in the past is not
probably how you fit together now how
you can move to do those things right so
again our mind might go to thrusting
what position will be most comfortable
for my hips to move in a thrusting
motion to have that kind of intercourse
I used to have if that's the question
that's like a very specific set of
parameters
if the question is what are the
positions where my partner and I can
have PVI penis vagina intercourse right
if that's the goal that kind of
connection there's a lot of positions
you can be in if you're willing to give
up the thrusting so how important is the
thrusting to you and so a lot of this is
kind of breaking it down to the
essentials like what does my body want
to be doing how do I make that happen
a lot of this is getting out of
missionary style which I learned by
being you know a woman wearing a
strap-on how much work it is to be in
missionary style penetrating someone
it's like an athletic feat especially if
you want to make it big right and so if
that athletic feat is not available to
you right now or ever again we're gonna
look at all sorts of other ways of
creating penetration and movement so
some of this might be standing up is
standing up available for you where you
can position your bed height you know
their risers for your bed come in all
sorts of different heights if you can
position your bed so your partner can
either be lying face-up bent over the
bed all sorts of positions and that's a
good height for your hips to move for
some people standing and moving is much
easier than being up on elbows or their
hands holding their weight and then
moving so that might be an option
there's all sorts of props and pillows
and tools that you can bring into your
bedroom again if you get over the
attitude that these things are kinky or
weird or you know just for women or toys
or for all of us tools are for all of us
and there's so many different kinds of
toys and tools that can assist you in
creating the kinds of experiences you
want to be creating so I'm thinking
about something like a sex sling for
some people they might think whoa that's
like a sex swing that's so kinky they
think of all the sitcoms where you know
the closet door has swung open to reveal
the little like dungeon inside with a
swing
yes they are found in sex clubs they are
also an assisted mobility device if you
think of it that way and having a
portable swing you can take out that you
can put your partner in and that allows
you to connect it doesn't have to be
kinky at all right wrap some silks
around it and make it like you're a
little love sure I and like put your own
aesthetics on these things and they can
become yours if you claim them right
like what is stopping you from getting a
sex pillow is it the idea of having sex
furniture well now they come in all
sorts of aesthetics so your sex pillow
can also be your reading pillow and if
your cousin comes over it's like you
know that's my wedge I use for reading
it's really great you should check it
out right like we don't have to and then
they're all like let me show you how to
use that wedge you use for reading it's
like the shame of bringing these things
in can prevent them from being really
powerful tools and devices for us and so
I want to give you permission to explore
toys and tools assistive devices of all
kinds right so you asked about assisted
mobility that can mean a lot of things
all the way up to being paraplegic or
hemiplegic or semi plee Jake in a
wheelchair where you're sex like it
might have to be totally reinvent so
again it's assessing what's true for you
now asking for help there are some great
resources there's a sex educator named L
chase and she wrote a book about sex
positions specifically for fat people
and people of size but what that enabled
her to really look at is how do sex
positions get adopted how do we move out
of bed onto different pieces of
furniture to allow all of our different
bodies of all different sizes and
abilities to fit together so bed is not
necessarily the best place for sex for a
lot of us if you can sit in a chair or
on a stool and your partner is able to
straddle you and ride you
that might be your new favorite position
because your body gets to relax your
lower lumbar that needs support has your
extra pillow you feel supported and now
you get you know your queen on top of
you riding you but again that requires
her to feel comfortable doing that you
know and we can take and there's all
sorts of assistive devices like if your
penis isn't getting as hard as you want
it to be there are toys for that if
penetration is harder than it used to be
there are loops for that there are some
great cannabis loops that are incredible
tools for pelvic pain and endometriosis
or recovering pain after pelvic surgery
cannabis is a really great sexual tool
to manage pelvic pain that would be a
great whole episode yeah so I think it's
so much again about what is possible for
you so if the rusting in bed is not is
sitting if that's not is standing if
that's not like what is is lying flat on
your back and right so what positions
are you able to do and then how do you
adapt that and a book like el Chase's
will give you all of these pictures so
you have possibilities you and they're
more useful than like those Kama Sutra
charts that any college dorm rooms yeah
those are all like a hundred one
positions for the athletes and the
Cirque de Soleil people what are the
positions for real bodies with real
limitations I think it's important to
point out too that you know certainly
it's it's actually kind of difficult to
de rata size like toys and dildos and
things like that but a lot of the the
supports and pillows and wedges and some
of the other things that we've talked
about they don't have to seem medicinal
in in and I want to go two ways with
that number one I liked what you said
earlier about claiming a device and you
know there's a lot of similarities
between a sex swing and some of those
types of traction I've seen for injured
people to get in and out of bed like you
know I can see some dual use there
and if you recontextualize it mmm
suddenly like the there are there are
new options but also there are a lot of
reasons why some of these you know
wedges and pillows were developed to
begin with it doesn't have to be a oh we
can't have sex the scripted way so we
have to have this second slightly lesser
than sex using these pillows so that we
can manage
in my experience experimenting with some
of that stuff I'm like oh this is
everything I liked about the scripted
kinds of sex but now everything is all
way more convenient and nicer this can
actually be an upgrade versus a oh I'm
I'm sent back to the Junior League
totally totally and you know a goal here
can be making your sex life even better
than before because you are more awake
to it you're choosing it more actively
and the pleasure that is available to
you is not in any proportion to how
young or able your body is I really want
people to hear that like what is
accessible to you is so much about your
attitudes what you bring to it and your
internal sense of freedom you know the
degree to which we are all mired under
the shame of our sex culture really
cannot be emphasized enough and it takes
a certain momentum to break through that
and then see the it's like the storm
clouds open and there's this whole
possibility on the other side and
there's this whole community where
errata sysm is celebrated and safe and
revered and just more as possible for
you and yeah you might actually find new
things that you like along the way
because if you're if you're being pushed
off script that means that you are now
exploring and when you explore you often
find unexpected things and you know
listening to you know the show that we
are we have produced
you know my kinks are you know emotional
vulnerability telling each other your
secrets and win-win right for me that is
super sexualized and this whole entire
show these these instructions for for
two people coming together and sharing
their hopes and their fears and there
are things they haven't told anybody
else that's hot for me right and so I
want to suggest to other people that
that even though that sharing may seem
like some emotional work and might seem
a little awkward or might seem scary to
you before you do it
you may actually feel like it's so
liberating that you can actually have a
more fulfilling sex than you've ever had
in your life just don't think of it you
don't have to think of all this as
medical no yeah I mean your medical
stuff will have to be managed and then
the rest of it is play toys curious
exploration the word curiosity comes up
a lot with us because some of us can
feel really charged and the spirit of
curiosity allows us to just take baby
steps in and ask what if well what
happen is what would happen if I you
know tuck my colostomy bag to the side
put a nice pillow over it and then let
myself experience oral sex right you
might find that like that experience of
oral sex is totally available to you
your partner's completely used to your
class me bag by now
doesn't even notice it and it's a game
changer and we can weep with that relief
sometimes sometimes we have a
breakthrough moment or a moment where we
do something we're ashamed of and we do
it anyway and we realize what we've been
holding back and you can weep with
relief and gratitude at what we have
given ourselves permission to explore
and the baby steps are so important here
right especially if you've already been
you know tenderized by illness and all
the other kind of survival issues that
come with us again that zone of safety
where can you establish that zone of
connection where you feel like relaxed
ready to explore
with curiosity and just ease into it
maybe that is just reading erotica in
the bathtub or listening to audio
erotica like while you're getting your
chemo or listening to audio erotica as
you're doing your deep breast every
afternoon that you need to get through
the day something as simple as that is
just like listening to a naughty story
on your headphones and allowing yourself
to be lulled into sleep by it you might
have sweeter dreams and you wake up the
next day like feeling a little nourished
by it we do these things because they're
good for us right we don't seek out
sexual pleasures and buy all these toys
and trick out our bedrooms because we're
trying to recreate Vegas or something
you know this is not like this is
because it is good and nourishing and
feed some part of our humanity that
wants to be fed we do these things
because they're healthy right relaxation
is healthy for us orgasms are healthy
they are good for our bodies
so how do you make space for them how do
you give it permission and how do you
give it permission to look totally new
and different and changed and be kind of
excited I mean novelty is something we
all seek right all of the relationship
therapists will say oh you're in a
long-term relationship seek novelty
create change do something different
life sometimes gives us more novelty
than we ever wanted to handle and all of
that change comes as at once but we can
face it and just be like all right
what's next
buying your first vibrator is a huge
experience for people but once you have
one you tend to have four or five and
then you realize like these are just
tools that allow you to stimulate your
body like and maybe some of your sex
stories are like massage boys things
that help you manage your pain and you
like we have so many body toys around
this house it's hilarious like we have
all sorts of massage balls and back
things and things that help us with our
bodies manage our symptoms our allies
and even the word medicinal right like
my marijuana is medicinal but it's also
deeply pleasurable it's a sacrament
it's a way I socialize with friends and
it's good medicine just like a really
rich conversation is good medicine right
I think it's also worthwhile since we're
all stoners here that you know to time
your cannabis consumption right so so I
think that you know if you're gonna you
you know have cannabis be part of your
of your sex play you know think about it
ahead of time so that you're you're not
overly checked out or or that you're
you've had enough so that your pain is
treated properly at the right time and I
also think that it's important to
remember that you know we become less
inhibited when we use cannabis and that
and that is good and can be good but
also if that inhibition goes a little
further than maybe we want we can
actually reenter ourselves right we've
all I think gotten into the swing of
things and and and found ourselves
holding up our bodies in ways that are
not not good for the injury or just for
the body in general and but we're like
we're in the zone you know and and we're
not gonna we're not going to change it
in that moment and you know using enough
cannabis where we move through the where
we go too far we're going the wrong
direction right so so just be mindful of
your cannabis use so that you're using
the right amount in the right modality
whether it's you know smoking your
tinctures or whatever and and get
yourself timed right and you know
especially if you're feeling awkward
about this don't take more of it so you
feel better but you take more of it and
then you start having a good time and
then you go too far mmm wise words yeah
and dial it in with your strains with
your terpenes again it's just another
tool that you can use to be with your
body then I want to say two things
really quick one is adjusting for
comfort when we get in the zone when we
feel like Oh
is going good finally at last right
we've made something happen you don't
want to override discomfort or emotional
or physical discomfort in order to keep
that going there are no martyrs in
pleasure so keep it pleasurable and if
you need to make adjustments make
adjustments and know that what you're
building is doesn't have to be fragile
and again that's the culture of pleasure
you create in your relationship where
you both have permission to change and
adjust and make requests and say oh my
feet are cold grab a blanket or oh my
god I have to get off my ankles over my
hip just gave out and that's not like oh
you poor weak pathetic thing it's oh my
gosh but let's find a position that
works now we want to keep this
pleasurable thing going so let's make it
more pleasurable what could make this
even better is one of my favorite
questions to ask all the time is what
could make this even better because it
acknowledges we have a good beautiful
mutual pleasurable thing going what's
next what could make this even better
let's optimize our time together right
like sex and play and touch these are
all beautiful times we get to share how
do we take the performance out of it how
do we take the pressure out of it and
restore it to play and connection and
that can be hard with medical devices
flying around you know I wear an insulin
pump so I have this like device dangling
from my body 24/7 an alarm will go off
in the middle of sex it's gotten ripped
out and blood started spurting on the
sheets right yeah how do we just move
with these moments or manage them as
best as we can and also just have like
the flexibility right it's like most
diseases are not static your symptoms
change day to day so you have to be able
to have that conversation like what are
you up for now and again knowing a
five-minute foot massage can lead to a
blissful hour of sex if things get
flowing and you're both feeling good and
you lead like one pleasure to the next
or if it's just five minutes of foot
massage and after that five minutes you
tell
off your hands and you smile at each
other and you just feel a little bit
more connected and relaxed that is a win
that is a like a good thing that just
happened
and you can build on that right I talked
a lot about micro pleasures so for
yourself and then how do you share micro
pleasures and build on them throughout
the day on a recent episode also about
pain and moving from opioids to cannabis
we we talked about not comparing your
experience to others because you know in
cannabis your dosage may be that you
need only 2 point 5 milligrams of whole
plant THC whereas somebody else may be
looking at 25 or 50 milligrams and you
know in the cannabis scene there's a
there's a little bit of ego coolness
factor about all that's all you take and
like I think that's so absurd you know
you know individualized medicine is a
modern thing and calls for everybody to
take the amount of cannabis that gets
them the relief that they're looking for
and it doesn't matter what your neighbor
is taking so similarly what I would love
you to speak to is the idea that you
know the various sex toys you've been
talking about and that are available are
somehow gender related right like these
are boys toys these are girls toys and
I've heard you talk about this before
but I'd like to you to talk you know
address that idea of the universality of
these and use what the hell you want
totally more and more of the industry is
just releasing incredible toys that are
high tech vibrators and high-quality
materials that can be used to stimulate
all sorts of body parts we need to
really get over this idea that vibrators
are for the girls vibrators can be
incredible tools for higher stimulation
right if your erectile function has
changed a lot goes into an erection that
could be blood flow that could be nerve
endings that could be mental stuff
sometimes it's just you want more
stimulation and there's also this whole
category of toys that are just sensation
toys and we tend to think of them
as kinky toys or leather toys or BDSM
toys oh those aren't for me because I'm
not kinky there's a huge range of toys
and props in that world that can be used
for just a lightful stimulation and
sensation and I also just want to
mention a lot of people who experience
chronic pain find a lot of relief in
BDSM in heavier sensations and there's a
lot of really good studies going on
right now about how that works like how
can we use intentional stimulation to
override pain signals and so again give
yourself permission right like if some
part of you is intrigued by a spanking
read a story about it see how your body
responds spank yourself a little bit
during masturbation see how that impact
play affects your arousal see if it
helps your pain see where it takes your
mind right a lot of this is
experimentation and willingness without
the judgment right so going back to
mindfulness which is paying attention
without judgment we have so much
judgment about shame that limits we have
so much judgment about sexuality that
limits our experience and some of that
can be like oh that's not for me because
I'm a man that's not for me because I'm
not kinky that's not for me because I'm
not queer if I did that what would it
mean about my identity and I just want a
presence very briefly here prostate play
and anal play for men a lot of men
explore it under duress when their penis
is no longer working and then discover
orgasms that are more powerful than
they've ever had in their life discover
this whole new way of being sexual and
wonder what what the hell is I ever
waiting for our bodies are capable of so
much more than we can imagine if we
explore them with curiosity and joy and
without the shame and misinformation
that limits our experience of it do you
even know your own genitals right like
we've had this whole conversation about
sex most of us aren't even in a aware
relationship with
our erotic Anatomy with our parts how
they function how they fit together we
haven't looked at them very well so some
of this is just like know thyself and
know where sexuality can fit in the rest
of your life and then give yourself
permission to explore it little bits at
a time with curiosity and get support
right don't do this alone listen to
podcasts read books talk to your friends
people are starving for this
conversation so you'll find that as you
have the courage to speak up about sex
there's a lot of people really ready to
talk about it I think it's also worth
pointing out that both shopping alone
online for all sorts of sex fun toys and
with a partner itself is a really fun
foreplay there's there's like what the
hell does this do there's giggling about
it and and it creates the opportunity to
talk about these things kind of like
like not a kind of third person right
there's there's there's two people
talking about sex toys but if it's two
people looking at a website now you're
not necessarily talking about what you
want actually youyou were talking about
this this method earlier where you're
you're actually talking about the sex
toys as eight as a third party thing not
necessarily what you want but what do
you think about this object and I think
that it allows a lot more vulnerability
to come out naturally and you can learn
a lot about yourself and your partner
totally totally and you know the
shopping experience can be a game you
can fill the shopping cart and then send
a link and ask your partner to choose
one you can send your partner a gift
card to a you know and a lot there's sex
toys on Amazon I would really recommend
going to a dedicated store because
there's a lot of rip offs and like
falsely advertised toys on Amazon so
avoid shopping there go to a sex toy
store that can
give you education a lot of them have
buying guides they'll walk you through
they've got videos there's tons of sex
toy reviewers so yeah you can make that
part of your exploration but also don't
get overwhelmed by all the options and
go back to the question what do I want
to experience how do we want to connect
what kind of pleasures are we looking to
explore because sex toys can also be a
really generous declaration right like
if you can't touch your partner in the
way you used to if your female partner
loves having sex loves being penetrated
loves being filled up you're having
erection issues like it is so sexy and
confident to buy a toy and then use it
with her you know go down on her hold
the dildo and [ __ ] her silly that is no
less sex than you having penis vaginal
intercourse right you're there you're
right face-first in her pleasure and
that is like so liberating because all
of a sudden her getting well [ __ ] if
you excuse my language her but her
pleasure being centered isn't contingent
on whether or not your penis is getting
hard in that very moment and your
medications are on point and your pain
is manageable like we can't wait for
conditions to be perfect so we need to
be flexible and have options and when we
get beyond the script options are
limitless lying with your partner as
they're touching themselves and having
an orgasm is one of the most intimate
vulnerable beautiful erotic acts and all
it requires of you is your presence I
remember cracking up when I realized the
similarities there were between buying
sex toys and buying like bongs and pipes
because you know you men should go to a
you know go to a quality store right and
it's the same thing right like you know
there are lots of online head shops that
have got like poorly produced pipes and
bowls that are crappy and thin glass and
then
and there are like really nice custom
glass and they're made with care and
there's stainless steel involved in this
so you know if you if you like good you
know bongs and pipes that are made with
quality and consider your usage of it
use that same headspace when you're
going to buy your toys because you know
this is certainly a market where buying
quality is rewarded totally and you can
have your own aesthetic with it right
and your own point of pride right we're
all excited to show off our favorite
toys in the cannabis realm and share
them with friends and there's no shame
in it right there's no like oh you have
to use that device for pleasure oh I
love my volcano and I love my Hitachi
Magic Wand and they both are both top of
the game device as I plug into the wall
I use with intention and they create an
experience for me we're taught a lot of
shame around sex and a lot of this thing
of like which orgasms matter more and
what sex counts and if you're ill you
know I was out of the game for a while
right like if you're ill and you still
want to connect you have to get creative
you have to be flexible and savor the
moments that are shared right like that
lying with your partner just naked under
three duvets if you're fully present to
that it can be enough and it can be
enough to sustain you through that
sexual season that might be incredibly
fallow that might be very scary where
you might not even have hope that you'll
be you know at the top of your game ever
again but you can still sustain yourself
and then start building pleasure
incrementally and maybe discover whole
new arenas that you never even would
have considered if your script hadn't
been you know torched for you and I
don't want to silver align this too much
being ill sucks being in pain sucks
there are days where I just want to
throw my pain out the window like you're
not allowed to be a passenger in my life
anymore
for me if I engage with that with a
really deep intention and presence and I
learned to work with my pain I call it
doing BDSM with God right I'm like in it
I'm awake to it I'm not in the struggle
of denial options start becoming
available to me what would help me or
just how can I ride this how can I just
be with what is even if it sucks it's
still better for me as a strategy than
struggling against what's true and
wishing it where another way and you
know yeah then that's not gonna take us
anywhere yeah yeah you know in this kind
this kind of exploration together or by
oneself to be really renewing renewing
of the relationship or even if there's
not another person just renewing of
one's own life and so for for you know
pain patients all patients and those who
love have them who you know have had
we're gonna have a little success with
this and they want to explore more
together I enthusiastically recommend
Chris's podcast called speaking of sex
which is how I first learned of her
listening to her show and learning a lot
and learning a lot about poop you know
techniques sure but like perspective how
to think about this stuff so Chris um
you know me describing your show will
pale in comparison to you describing
your show so would you just take a
moment and tell folks about the show so
they have an idea of what they would be
you know checking out if they if they
bother to go over there mmm I love how
you describe it you know a lot of what
we've been doing here it's explicit
conversation about the heart of
sexuality unashamed uncensored
but with soul and reverence and
heartfulness My partner and I have been
together for 13 years and we co-host the
show and also bring on guests and
sometimes we do deep dives into topics
like libido and we do a ton of research
and try to understand like what is
libido and how does it work and other
times we'll do single episodes about a
new kind of sex toy or you know so it's
we have 370 episodes we've been going
for years so there's something for
everyone the episodes are sorted in a
sex index on our website pleasure
mechanics comm so you can kind of find
quickly topics you're looking for and
I'll also curate a little section
that'll be on the show notes page here
because it can be overwhelming to get
started but yeah it's explicit yet
soulful is what kind of what we've come
down to some people call us the cooking
show of sex it's like a wholesome but
queer and irreverent you know like we
have been sex workers and sex coaches
and sex educators for a combined total
of like 25 years between the two of us
we've worked with bodies of all kinds
couples of all kinds and a lot of what
we do is we collect the wisdom of our
audience we're in deep dialogue with our
audience with men and women and couples
and trans folks of all nationalities all
over the world and we are gathering
communal wisdom about sex how it lives
in our lives and then talking back to or
and then speaking this wisdom back to
our audience week after week so
definitely please visit us at pleasure
mechanics check out the show it's
speaking of sex and we are here for you
I have an open email policy so if
anything you've heard on this show
resonates for you please feel free to be
in touch with us and we do our best to
get back to you what's the difference
between the speaking of sex podcast and
the online class series that's on the
website mmm
the speaking of sex podcast is free
there's 370 episodes to explore and
those are deep dives you can learn a ton
I have people who write to me all the
time who say their lives have been
totally changed their marriages have
been saved and all they've done is
listen to the podcast and I'm delighted
by that the online courses are there for
you when you are ready for a deeper dive
especially in learning new erotic skills
so we're both trained in massage and
then became somatic sex educators so
there's a lot on this site about erotic
touch from couples massage you know
full-body massages like when I was sick
but Charlotte's giving me just back and
butt massage just like stroking my body
was how we sustained our love couples
massage is amazing or you might want to
learn foreplay techniques and arousal
techniques or erotic spanking and kink
and so we teach that all we also have a
class on mindful sex so those are guided
deep dives in erotic exploration and
techniques they're all available online
accessible in your own home and then we
are there for you when you have
questions and need a little personal
coaching on how we do our thing and
we've been doing it for 10 years and go
in and we love this work because it just
allows us to you know zip into your life
as that little sex fairy that you know
at the right time can be there for you
with a conversation that you need to
hear and just connect with you and let
you know you're not alone so much of
this is relieving that feeling of you
know you being alone in this and that
there's no hope and there's no options
there's so much possible for you no
matter what's going on with your body I
love you I am here with you in this
human condition that can be so painful
but also so pleasurable and so beautiful
well hopefully we have been able to
serve that vision in some small way here
today Chris thank you so much for
joining us I know that this is you know
a little atypical to come on a cannabis
show and and and to share this
experience but you know I've just I I've
talked to enough patients where I knew
that I wanted to be able to bring this
kind of perspective to them and and then
if they want to explore more it was an
option so I really appreciate you
sharing your time your expertise or good
cheer your smiles with all of us so that
you know we can we can all heal to be
more fully human thank you so much for
all you're doing
I love you so much and I look forward to
being in community with you for years to
come right on thank you Chris so to
reiterate some of the links that Chris
gave us if you want to check out
the speaking of sex podcast and just
like all the delightful writing that
they have on the website that's pleasure
mechanics.com and the podcast again is
called speaking of sex and you find that
on pleasure mechanics.com you'll also
find the online class series there if
you want to check out some of the links
that chris mentioned about like some of
the resources like some of the books she
mentioned and and that interesting
resource that suggests all of the the
sexual positions right because like
sometimes just inventing them in your
head is challenging and you actually
kind of want to go through like a menu
and go like yeah let's do that
there are those links on the shaping
feiyr.com page for this episode also so
we so you can get all that stuff on
shaping fire calm but also we've created
the link shaping fire calm ford slash
pleasure if you want to go there and you
forget pleasure mechanics but but you
can remember pleasure and chafing fire
well that that's there for you as well
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shaping fire calm and on
Apple iTunes stitcher and Google Play if
you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you'd leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download your review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango
lowes.com
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaving
feiyr.com to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire i've been your
host Shango lowe's
you