hey there so we're gonna try to do
something different
normally when we record an episode of
shaping fire we just do it audio only
but our friend Lee Morrison is here
today and we just recorded an episode
with him and it's very true that there
is one aspect of how the layers of soil
the horizons of the earth really could
use a visual graphic and so Layton had
the great idea why don't we show you the
graphic now and he will walk us through
it a little bit and then and then we
encourage you if you have not listened
to the podcast episode go why or go
listen to the podcast episode and if you
are here because you already listened to
the podcast episode hopefully this will
give you a better understanding of the
information that we covered so lately
thank you so much for joining me both on
the episode today but then also now here
in my living room good so wonderfully so
so I'm gonna go ahead and insert the
graphic here okay and why don't you go
ahead and explain the and the important
intricacies that maybe we're more
difficult without looking at the graphic
itself perfect you know it's interesting
you know the cannabis industry as a
whole has has looked at soul we do
Verizon at the top the ori so verizon it
so stands for organic and you know
everything has been focused on getting a
matrix or a system that will allow fast
routing and for nutrients to be absorbed
and obviously pulled up by the plant and
so in that regard it makes sense that
you use a pure organic matter like a
peat moss or coke or any of these other
growing mediums but the interesting
thing is is that that works great with
nutrients but as soon as you go into a
living soil system or an organic
regenerative type of farming
it does not work because the organic
matter has a couple issues number one it
goes hydrophobic which means that it
will not absorb water and it goes
anaerobic on the inside so it's a double
negative so this is why I tried to
explain to people that if you're going
to go regenerative organic you need to
consider all the horizons just like the
soil just like the mother nature dieted
in creating these different layers that
provide different things we're gonna
start with the over eysan generally
speaking in these diagrams you'll see
it's very small it's a very tiny layer
can only be an inch you know half an
inch deep in a lot of cases in the most
productive and fertile soils on the
planet which is a good love this
question what do you think the most
fertile soil is on this planet I hope I
see the Amazon ready the rainforest
ready right wrong that's the top soil do
Verizon is very small there it is
just maybe nature too actually it's the
prairies in West because you'll have the
O horizon as deep as 2030 feet we'll get
into soil trance
construction in the podcast but for
right now I want you to think about okay
well the over aizen's very deep how do i
drain that how do I prevent that from
going hydrophobic that's where those
other layers what's called the a horizon
and the B horizon come in and then you
also have sometimes the e horizon which
is the alluvial layer
that'll generally happen in old drainage
areas well riverbeds
that's where you're gonna get a
concentration of an e there so typically
it's just the over aizen to a rise in
the B horizon the B horizon is gonna
tend to the more mineral-rich which
makes sense because the plants you know
they send their top roots down and
they're gonna be able to absorb those
clay particles and
minimal concentrations that exist inside
the clay to their atmosphere through the
network of organisms now the day horizon
in my mind is the most important for
cannabis growers because that's going to
pull excess moisture out of the horizon
so that's going to prevent them from
going anaerobic so a literally acts like
a wicking system so think of it as
pulling the moisture away excess
moisture away from the plant away
pulling it out of that over eyes which
is holding it like a sponge so it's
actually going to help in transpiration
which means providing oxygen down into
the soil roots for the organisms and
also pushing the co2 out for the plant
so so and you're using vocabulary that
we use to describe the horizons of the
earth you know how top soil thank you
they could call it the skin of the earth
but your butt your butt now you're
making I think that you're making this
transition to talking about how we're
layering our pots mm-hmm so are you
suggesting that instead of us taking our
soil and just mixing it all together you
actually are gonna lay one layer down
and lay another layer down and then lay
another dilator down is that the idea so
it's called biomimicry that copying
nature it's very easy to do when I work
with clients generally speaking is I
will have a few different horizons
planted for usually I'll used to be
horizon or lluvia layers for drainage
underneath and I using a horizon and
then and then organic matter or a deep
organic matter and authorize it okay so
basically it's just three Verizon's the
bottom horizon generally speaking I'll
just take rocks three-quarter-inch rocks
one-inch rocks whatever and I'll blend
it some coarse sand so I'll pack the
rocks down and I'll put a layer of sand
over the top of it the reason I use the
sand is it's EMSA more as a sand filter
system we use it and aquatics equal
aquatic ecosystems to actually filter
out the fine particulate so in this case
it's reverse were protecting the soils
from migrating to finds our because we
don't want those lines to come out of
the soil every time we water so we
trapped
santé botnets on the same layer so the
roots could still go down migrate or
pull out the minerals and nutrients from
those finds and we're never gonna get an
anaerobic layer which is huge because if
you have an anaerobic layer the roots go
down to that go down the die and they
die and then now they did the alcohol
actually melts the tip of the root and
that plant cannot healed every that's
done so you're never gonna hit plant
potential if your roots are hitting
analytic zones so that's why it's so
critical this drainage so then we have
the a horizon which is again gonna have
a higher contest and so it's protecting
the over Eisen from losing its nutrients
and it's fines from migrating down and
plugging up the whole system so that's
why each one of these layers is so
critical and should be taken into
consideration especially for doing pots
alright so um what else is in this
graphic that you want to point out
before we just wrap this up and send
people off to the podcast what should
they be what's what should they be seen
when they're looking at the graphic I
think the most important thing is is for
them to wrap their mind around the fact
that this is layered and it's layered
for a reason and it works and functions
correctly and effectively because it's
layered so when you dig a hole next in
your backyard for those layers and and
you know get into it and notice the
color change pick up those soils and rub
them in your fingers and feel them and
you'll see the difference in texture
gentleman that I'm working with spent
sales which is a big issue with cannabis
growers and he's you know I love it he's
like I'm trying to be good about this I
have mountains of this fence so what can
I do with it
I'm like alright let's start with basics
let's add a little bit of sand to it and
I want you to put it in a cup drill some
holes in the bottom and watched a lot of
move through it and do the same without
us and so he started playing around with
that he was like oh my god this is
totally different it feels gritty its
draining better I don't have it doesn't
get smelly and I'm like to see this you
know just by adding that little bit of
stain to that over aizen or that spent
soil you
you're getting it to function better so
when you're considering building soils
you've got to think about the function
of it how do I get water to move through
it without turning anaerobic how do I
prevent an aerobic layers and all of
that happens naturally in nature through
these layers rather through using de
layers to separate and to hold and
protect from from too many my vines
migrating into the deeper lower levels
right on good point so so the graphic
that you've been seeing this is
essentially what started this episode
that late and I are recording because I
saw this at the regenerative agriculture
conference that he and Joshua Rutherford
put together and and when I saw it and
and he's suggesting that this is how we
should be building our pots like my mind
was blown right because I'm all like you
know all we take our soil we saw it we
makes mix the soil when we put it in and
then when we do some sort of green mulch
right so that's like pretty basic stuff
but the idea that I actually should be
making you know three or five mixes and
then pouring them in order I think
that's a new way for us all to grow as
farmers so that we can be growing the
most thriving quality plans so so if
this is new for you like it is for me I
encourage you to go and check out the
the new podcast episode out today the
same day I'm publishing this video with
Wayne Morrison and listen to that it's
gonna be a long long form explanation of
this but then also this video is here so
that everybody can check out this
graphic that we'll be referring to a lot
in the podcast so can I just add one
more yeah um you know I think it's
important for you to understand it this
technique is for using it forever in
other words you're not replacing this if
you're just cutting the plant and you're
leaving the soil long this is a
long-term functioning pot and part of
this is because we're trying to
establish that micro
the network which takes 90 days to get
going so that's about the time you're
harvesting your plan so this way you can
harvest your plan you can save your plot
you can save the mycorrhizae that's been
the entire sphere is intact ready to go
for your next plan and you're not
dumping it this is this is a permanent
constructed soil that can be reused over
and over and over again for your entire
life
yeah this is best practices for no-till
yeah yeah awesome thanks for him right
you