[Music]
in the early days cannabis primarily
tasted and smelled like it did due to
the soil climate and genetics of the
region of the world that it came from in
the United States we primarily received
flour from Mexico but flowers from other
Latin American countries certainly
showed up as well
rarely but sometimes we were able to
delight over something especially exotic
from Afghanistan or Thailand - over time
though enough bagsied found its way into
the hands of cannabis lovers who also
had the mind and resources to grow them
locally breeders all over the world
began to cross and hybridize these
cannabis keema vars to create unique
plants that had their own taste growing
patterns colours and medicinal value
this breeding happened both indoors and
outdoors but due to prohibition breeding
was mostly done indoors in the United
States breeders hybridized plans to
tease out the most wonderful attributes
sweet sour earthy skunky and fuel tastes
all became more pronounced once breeders
got involved breeders also selected for
mold resistance size overall health and
and so many other attributes that a
particular grower thought might be
valuable this dedication to craft is why
cannabis breeders are revered and why
modern cannabis is so badass compared to
the stuff we grew up on if you enjoy
hearing frank discussions that dive deep
in a cannabis health business and
technique i encourage you to subscribe
to our newsletter every week you'll
receive a new podcast episode delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos - don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode you
are listening to shaping fire and I am
your host
Shango Lowe's my guest today is Mean
Gene Mean Gene is a legendary cannabis
breeder from Mendocino in the Emerald
triangle region of Northern California
he is owner of cannabis genetics company
freeborn's selections but is most known
for his epic collaborations with
aficionados
like the black lime reserve strain today
we're going to talk about mean jeans
breeding practices naming conventions
and that epic black line strain hey
welcome to the show Mean Gene okay how's
it going good good I'm glad that you
could make some time to be here you know
when I was getting set for this show the
first thing I noticed is that you know I
actually thought that your primary
association was with aficionado seeds
because everywhere I've gone it's always
like you know mean gene from aficionado
but after I got the opportunity to start
following your Instagram feed for a
while I realized that that you know the
the imprint that you are primarily
responsible for is actually your own
freeborn selections so would you kind of
like break it down for us like like how
you work between aficionado versus
freeborn uh yeah I mean um basically uh
you know Leo from aficionado was
somebody who actually was living right
on the same Road as me and he won the
Emerald cup and I see you know I said
well these guys look like they have some
good seeds and so you know I messaged
them I think on Facebook to to say hey
you know can I pick up some of your
seeds and I wound up meeting them and
you know they those guys saw what I had
and they were like do you want to do
some some kind of a release through
aficionado your stuff is really good and
so you know we started collaborating on
a little bit of stuff here and there and
we put out a black lime reserve and the
in the pines and the Versailles and I
gave them the the red Hindu Kush f3 that
I had I think that's about the only ones
that we really put out and and that's
you know those are the ones that people
you know like black lime reserve was a
was a big huge hit I knew it was going
to be good because I really like black
lime myself and so when we put that one
out that one got a lot of really good
press and then I did I think it was
there was like 650 entries or something
in the Emerald Cup in 2000
was it 2014 I think and I took second
place with that and so people really
know me from from my work with efficient
auto more than anything else because
those are the those are really the only
feeds that I've publicly released other
than me and Braveheart from Oregon we
did a little giveaway that was a nubia
which is a CBD plant crossed with a with
the Harless ooh from ringo at Soham
seeds and so really freeborn selections
a lot of people are growing out the
seeds and have grown out the seeds that
I make for years but if for anybody to
really know me for having ever got any
of my seeds at a club or anywhere else
those would have been efficient Otto so
that's really why people you know if you
ask Oh me and gene they're going to go
yeah fishing Auto black lime Reserve in
the pines and those ones that I did work
on it's a lucky thing that you chose
somebody good to work with when you one
right because you know if you're going
to be associated with somebody you know
we owe an aficionado is like you know
that's that's that's something great to
be associated with even if it was you
know just for for a couple of runs yeah
for sure and you know it was funny
because they won in 2012 and then I came
in in 2013 and I took third and then
2014 I took second and then mm uh 2015 I
guess I took first place in the Emerald
cup and it was funny because after a
while people started to say you know
it's fixed these guys win every time
there there's no way that you can just
win every time and you know it was
actually one of those things where I was
I was actually uh it was actually a
great feeling to have people say oh the
contest is fixed you win too much look
so about those mountain seven or eight
episodes ago we had your neighbor Alan
Adkison on the show and you know he was
telling us that you live on the same
mountain
and and he said he says yeah man he's
like you know you know I can throw a
rock and like you know uh you know hit
all of these cannabis cup winners that
live all around me now you know it's
like there's some kind of magic on that
mountain you know what do you look for
when you're looking for a location for
breeding well you know there's a really
interesting thing that happens and you
know there's the whole people have
finally started to kind of open their
eyes lately to the whole question of
Tour wah and and you know basically
location and some people will say oh it
doesn't matter because if you're growing
in potting soils and that doesn't even
it doesn't even plication doesn't even
play but what's interesting about this
part of California is that if you go all
the way over to them to the extreme
coastal zone your flowers will basically
produce mostly leaf and they'll produce
a lot of resin and they'll produce a lot
of terpenes but they'll have very little
density and they'll be very lightweight
and your plants will grow really slow
and it's not good for production but the
for smoke ability stuff is really nice
so then when you come a couple miles
back and then you start to get into
areas like calm qi Brandt's come a
little bit further inland and that would
be maybe like lake it uh you know the
west side of Garberville and Redway and
areas like that even a little further
west and close to the coast would be
like honeydew there's all these little
these little areas and every area has
something different and and from looking
at it over the years and being in
different places I've been able to find
a correlation where you look at what is
when you get farther away from the
coastal influence what happens is your
flowers they have smaller features every
part of the flower is smaller the stems
or Center
the leaves are smaller every everything
is basically smaller even the trichomes
even become shorter and more closely
clustered and so there's an interesting
thing that happens where when you go to
the coast it gets larvae when you go
inland it gets so hard that when you go
to break it up too
like say roll a joint it actually breaks
down in almost a undesirable way where
those flowers themselves are so dense
that when it breaks up it almost turns
into powder and if you go over to the
coast then it breaks up into these big
chunks where every every piece is this
big big piece you know and so I'm right
at a place where I get the benefit of
the coastal influence that causes it to
grow really big well-defined features
and I get the really big tall thick
trichomes but I still have the advantage
of being far enough inland that my
flowers still are dense and they look
nice to people who are into that look of
something that's actually got a nice
dense round look to it yeah that bag
appeal yeah and so it's really
interesting because people will say okay
well you know it's just either it's a
coincidence or it's a fix
you know either as nothing to do with
anything scientific because it just is
random and there happens to be a lot of
people in this area who have
award-winning cannabis or they say oh
well they just give it to somebody who
they know from that area but what people
don't understand in a lot of cases is
that the way that people like Tim from
the Emerald cup or the judges from the
Emerald cup I met those guys because I
you know I mean I knew Tim from years
and years back but we weren't in the
same circle we didn't hang out together
he might have known who I was a little
bit but the reality was that those
people got to know me because they went
wow you had some really good really good
weed and that's how I started to know
those people it wasn't the other way
around and not that's how it happens
when you run an event like that and then
you meet people who have really
outstanding stuff you're going to go oh
well you're the one with the they
obviously have an interest in really
good weed they're having a contest right
right so that's how it happens that
their winds up being in this little area
in my opinion
uh people here have really been holding
a lot of the best genetics for a long
time this particular town in this county
is a place where a lot of really really
good stuff has has come out of and and
so you have the genetic advantage you
have the advantage of a lot of people
who have experience and then what I was
saying about the climate is you have
this one little area where you get the
best of both worlds where you have the
coastal influence but not enough to to
take away from the quality as far as you
know like okay well it's got the look
and it's got the smell and you know if
you go ahead and you go over one
Mountain over to the east you'll have a
lot heavier flowers and you'll get a lot
bigger yields but when you go to break
it down to roll up a joint when they go
to smoke it in a cup it doesn't break
down the way that like nice indoor break
down it's almost like it's compressed
because it grows so dense it's
ridiculous and so um you know for me if
I'm looking for the ideal climate I
really like places like you know just to
the east of Santa Cruz Santa Rosa the
east side of Garberville the east side
or red way right here where it's in
Mendocino along these ridges here
there's these certain areas that really
will produce um produce the type of
flower that makes it the most smokeable
and that wouldn't matter say for
something like concentrates but for the
actual in a flower contest there's a
certain texture that just breaks up and
it rolls up better and and so certain
strains if you have a left strain that
has less dense floral clusters and you
grow that to the east of me then it'll
get dense enough to where okay well
maybe someone Sour Diesel might be
coming from the east and that might do
better than something that I have here
because when I grow it here it's not
really dense enough to get the to win
the points on the look in the contest
you know yeah so there's there's
different things and there's certain
strains that do
in certain climates just like with great
so if you grow one type of grape you're
going to want one type of you want a
certain temperature on the nights and if
the year is not as good then it's not as
good of a it's not as good of a year for
a certain certain type of wine you know
and certain areas and and then of course
you know then the soil goes into play
but most people use potting soil and
that's the big that's the big point
everybody has well it doesn't matter
where you do it if you're using potting
soil and I'm like no climates big if you
run it indoor room and you keep it
slightly more humid then you're going to
have flowers that are going to be not so
ridiculously dense and if you run it a
very very arid environment you're going
to have stuff like if you grow purple
Urkel you look at it and you can't even
tell where the features are it's just
this thing you're like I can't tell
where anything is at all it looks like
somebody put it to smashed it all to get
grounded up and smashed it back together
because every little feature has grown
to be so petite you know yeah so um so
let me I'll take that one that's a big
thing yeah let's take that one more step
further right so so you're talking about
breeding the the superior flower for for
a cub and for you know you and your
friends to toke so how does that play
into the breeding right because you know
you're choosing you know your Yorkie
males and females in this you know kind
of Olympic training environment that
you're growing these flowers in and and
but then you know you're passing on this
gear to people who are going to be
growing it all over the country and
indoor and so you know do you what do
you keep what do you consider when
you're growing it on your property which
is pretty much a perfect place to grow
when you're considering the gear that
you're going to pass around to others so
that so that maybe it doesn't need to
have such a perfect environment oh well
that's that's another interesting thing
too is that as much as it's a great
environment for something that will do
well in a contest it's also an area
where things have to be really really
Hardy and they have to be really weather
and you know like if a strain is is
prone to powdery mildew it's going to
show in this area because we do start to
get the fog at the end of September so
where other places won't have it in and
we do get you know this is this is like
considered like a temperate rainforest
here especially when there used to be
more redwoods in the area this area you
know this year I think I mean I this is
just a rough estimate but I think we got
maybe a hundred or 110 inches of rain
here this year and that started in the
end of September last year so anything
that does well here it's going to have a
pretty good shot at doing well for
people in most climates like if I have
something and it really does great for
me here somebody in Oregon or Washington
where the weather is even worse there
it's still going to do better than a lot
of stuff they might get because because
of how the weather is as opposed to if
say I was an outdoor guy and I was in I
was in Southern California or I was in
Nevada or you know if you were at a low
you know it just it's it's um we're at a
fairly high elevation here we're fairly
coastal and so everything as I go
through I really try to look at okay
well how would this do for somebody in a
more extreme climate and I try to really
go for things that are Hardy in all ways
and that's one of the things that's made
me wind up with strains that are so high
in terpenes because terpenes are oily
and strains that produce a lot of oil
tend to do a little bit better in say
the rain or the fog because they're it's
almost like it's like water off a duck's
back you know
the rain falls on them and it just it
just comes off you know so um so yeah
it's interesting because it's such a
great climate for the finished product
and yet it is kind of a challenging
climate as a farmer it kind of like a
survival of the fittest
is like well if it does well on your
property it's going to be thriving and
that the Terps are high because it's got
a really strong immune system and so
then it's attractive attractive to our
human nose too so you're you know big
the combination of of the difficulty and
also the you know your terroir means
that that the the strains that you're
breeding are probably going to be pretty
good you know pretty bulletproof just
about anywhere unless you you know
change temperature humidity in a big way
yeah it's it's really neat it's almost
kind of like like a magical thing you
know to look at it and go okay well
there's all these things that have come
together to make you know to delete lead
things down the past that they've gone
down because you know it's everything
has been underground for a long time so
people don't necessarily know uh like
Mendocino County it's not people at this
point maybe people still are you know
saying Oh Amsterdam or uh you know these
different places where people know about
a lot of weed or even like humble
humbled has been known for a long time
and Mendocino and Humboldt Trinity
Sonoma Monterey County there's really
been a lot of really great strains that
have come out over the years again and
again there's just all this stuff and I
feel like part of it comes from the
people who live here of course not more
experienced and do more stuff but I
think also the climate of this area like
I said you know if you have this stuff
if your weed is greasy it does better in
the weather and the fact that we have a
little bit of a more extreme climate I
think that you know that in all of these
areas that might be that might be
pushing that a little bit you know
yeah right on that makes sense hey let's
go ahead and take our first short break
and be right back you're listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is Mean
Gene master cannabis breeder at Freeborn
selections we'll be right back
as cannabis normalization sweeps the
country knowledge of how to grow
cannabis naturally and without synthetic
inputs has become more and more
available in fact probiotic growers are
experiencing large yields and
exceptional terpene profiles without
using chemicals banned in their state
move away from the risks inherent to
chemical nutrients and instead invest in
your soil use your soil again and again
reducing costs and improving the
vitality of your soil with each cycle
keep it simple organic has been a leader
in aerated compost teas for years and
now provide premium soils and nutrients
to the cannabis industry they offer a
full line of all-natural inputs for
building your soil feeding microbe
communities and brewing nutrient and
compost teas they can even help you test
your soil to spot deficiencies that may
be holding you back check out their
website at K is organics calm enter the
word Shango into the form at checkout to
receive 10% off your first order stop
pouring bottled nutrients on your soil
only to throw it out each cycle start
building living soil that will serve you
for years to come visit K is organics
calm and grow healthy thriving cannabis
we humans are attracted to plants
because they offer us relief and are a
whole lot of fun sometimes though the
best parts are buried inside the plant
and we need to use specialty extraction
technology when it comes to cannabis it
is extraordinarily important to extract
its precious oils without changing them
in the process we want to preserve the
properties of the cannabinoids terpenes
and other constituents that all work
together since 1994 Eden labs has been
developing extraction technology and
processes to do just that
Eden labs was founded by a cannabis
loving engineer during the early days of
medical marijuana in California and the
expanded Eden team has been designing
and building industry-leading solutions
for cannabis extraction ever since
Eden labs flagship product is the newly
improved high flow co2 extractor as
other extraction companies enter the
market it is
hi flow from Eden labs that everyone
chases and tries to compare themselves
with not only that but the improved
automation software allows data to be
collected stored and studied Eden labs
can outfit your whole lab Eden's
coldfinger ethanol extractor creates
astonishing whole plant extracts working
alone or in tandem with an initial
stream distilling steps to isolate
monoterpenes before extracting the rest
of the botanical constituents Eden
offers you many options including vacuum
distillation column distilling stirred
reactor units and accelerated solvent
recovery when you partner with Eden labs
your lab team is enrolled into the Eden
labs training program to boost their
understanding of Eden's best practices
to ensure that your outputs are exactly
what you require for your application
whether it be DAB oil oil for pen
cartridges or edibles when you work with
Eden you're not just buying the tech you
are buying dedicated customer support to
help you attain your business goals -
you can hear Eden's CEO AC Braddock talk
about the company's values during
shaping fire episode 19 that was all
about co2 extraction so many of the new
companies in the market just smell
opportunity slap an ex tractor together
and hire a marketing company Eden labs
has been listening to feedback from
extractors and consumers for about 25
years now they care about both you and
your consumer partner with Eden labs to
extract astonishing cannabis oils and
terpenes that you will be proud of go to
shaping feiyr.com
Ford / Eaton to find out more welcome
back you are listening to shaping fire
I'm your host Shango Lowe's and our
guest this week is Mean Gene Master
Canada's breeder at Freeborn selections
so Jean before the break we were talking
about the importance of weather and
terroir there on your very specific
mountain where you grow and you know a
lot of people take your seeds and they
bring them indoors so you know it begs
the question you know do you have a part
of your breeding process that that comes
indoors I mean do you do any sifting
indoors are you doing all your sifting
outdoors well I mean you know in certain
cases it's
nice to do certain work with clones that
have been proven again and again indoors
to be really stable because then that
way you know that you're at least
getting part of your gene pool is coming
from something that's tried-and-true
indoors I do a little bit of breeding
indoors or in a like indoor outdoor kind
of environment meaning that it's like a
you know like a green a winter green
house with supplemental lighting which I
honestly think is better for stress
testing for indoors than actual indoor
scene because it's a lot harder to keep
the environment really dialed in yeah
because it really swings exactly and you
get you know you will get those lower
temperatures and you will get some of
the higher temperatures and you know
it's a little bit harder to keep it like
you know if I if I was running an indoor
it's really easy to go okay I'm 76
degrees all the time night and day
that's all it is and and that's cool for
me because um indoor where I live has
kind of gone it's kind of gone out years
and years ago there's people who do it
but as soon as people were able to grow
out in the open and the Sun and the
prices started coming down for people
what started to happen is it became a
lot more efficient for people to start
running light depths and running
greenhouses and running outdoor and so
what I do basically is I try to breed
stuff outdoor because in my experience
if it does if it if it does good indoor
it's going to do great outdoor so like I
said if I'm starting with some of those
some of those genetics you know
different you know oh geez or mass
Turkish Hindukush
different things that that they you know
they do perform well indoor and then I
incorporate those into stuff that I have
coming from outdoor but a lot of the
genetics that I had that we're coming
from outdoor were a ski a knee based and
so when you take them and you put them
into
they do great you know so stuff that I
the stuff that has more of a problem
going indoor is ironically the stuff
that's coming from indoor like the chem
dog the Sour Diesel some of the og Girl
Scout cookies cherry pie those are the
things that you know even when you bring
them into an outdoor breeding program
you go through Mandy go oh some of these
here they you stress them a little bit
and they say go intersex on you so you
know what I do is I is I mainly breed
outdoor because if it looks really good
outdoor and it smokes really good
outdoor when somebody takes it indoor if
they do it the right way
indoor has potential to have a little
bit more of what like what I always call
like the perfume on it like if you grow
outdoor OG it's very earthy and robust
and it's nice that's a great smell but
good indoor OG has this little added
little spectrum of terpenes that seem to
show up that are detectable it looks a
little prettier it's a little shinier
it's a little the resin tends to look a
little bit more light-colored and so I
try to find the stuff that when I when I
breed an outdoor it looks almost like
it's indoor you know and I want to say
like oh this will pass for indoor but
it's in that ballpark you know so then
what I do is I'll have people go ahead
and grow them out indoor and as far as
I've seen so far a population that you
can grow really stressed outdoor or in a
greenhouse and it stays stable and
doesn't show any signs of intersex when
you take that and a good grower grows at
indoor it's going to do just as good as
far as sexual stability indoor as it
does outdoor everything that I have that
is problematic indoor it's problematic
outdoor if it's stressed you know if
it's over watered if it's too hot in a
greenhouse or whatever it
is so for me for breeding I do pretty
well being able to do it all outside and
then do a lot of testing inside you know
yeah right on that makes a lot of sense
one of the things that I enjoy doing is
over the winter I'll I'll play with some
some new seeds and strains that I've
never you know used before and you know
see what they do indoors but in the at
the end of the day for my own head
I really like the terpene profiles that
come from full on sunshine you know I
mean my LEDs are great and and you're
right there are all sorts of really nice
attributes of growing indoors and you
know it's kind of like training an
Olympian right your training and
training for a very specific thing and I
can control everything and I end up
getting this good product but but I also
like that little bit of a you know that
that wild outdoor taste with from the
broader spectrum of the sunshine so you
know whatever whatever I find over the
winter that I love the best I'll take it
outside and see it express itself that
way and you know I think that's just a
fun thing of being able to go indoor and
outdoor that you can see both
expressions yeah I think so too and I
and I know what you mean about the
outdoor I mean like personally for me um
I only know a few people I know a lot of
growers and there's only a few people
who's indoor is something that I would
want to smoke above outdoor you know I
mean if it's it's a lot of people say
okay indoor is always better and for me
I'm like if I'm going to see a hundred
samples of indoor and a hundred samples
of outdoor I'm probably going to like
five of the outdoor and two of the
indoor you know because outdoor
everything just kind of thrives and it
works and indoor a lot of times stuff is
just really washed out and you can tell
that there's too much heat and it just
doesn't look it doesn't look like it's
healthy and that that happens a lot you
know and then I notice outdoor although
indoor the resin might be more visible a
lot of times the outdoor it's actually
more of these thick almost like
sheets of resin where the trichomes are
almost sticking together and like globs
and I you know for me like if I if I
smoke in door I'm going to be I'm going
to be high for you know maybe an hour
and if I smoke if I smoke outdoor and of
course it's genetics or it's hugely
dependent on genetics you know some
stuff no matter what it's going to get
you high for like four hours if it's got
some crazy haze or something but I
really like the high from the outdoor to
me it really just hits me and it stays
and I can really feel it and it's not
just like this little rush of stuff you
know so yes I also find that you know at
you know I still consider myself a
novice grower and growing outdoors is
just so much more forgiving you can make
simple mistakes endure and end up with
big problems but but outdoor you know
you've got you've got you know pests
predators naturally outdoors you've got
the sunshine to help you with some of
the molds so long as I don't have you
know extensive fog I'm you know I know
I'm going to be in pretty good shape
outdoors whereas indoor something can go
bad fast yeah it seems like outdoor the
environment is forgiving enough that as
long as you as long as you handle it and
dry it correctly you know as long as
it's properly dried and handled you're
going to have something that's really
nice but when you're indoor it's almost
like the whole process of flowering is
like a curing process if your room you
know outside your stuff can be budding
and it gets up to 90 degrees and you're
fine but if you're growing in door and
your room is sitting 90 degrees all the
time it's like when your weed is finally
done it's just going to be um you know
it's just so tired it's just a yeah it's
just there's nothing substantial anymore
about about the residents profile you
know it's like when when I stay in the
Sun too long you know like oh that I
need to go take a cold shower somewhere
yeah yeah so so you know every breeder
has got those specific Canada
plant attributes that turn them on the
most and and you know if it's a regional
thing and it's also a breeder thing what
you look for when choosing plants that
excite you that you want to work with
further well you know for me it's like
um experience leads me a lot like I can
look at a plant in the loo that's one of
those plants that gets the big buds all
the way inside of the plant or whew
that's one of those plants that doesn't
need a lot of support or that's one of
the ones that's shaped that certain way
where I know it's just going to get tons
of tons of buds all over it or you know
the main thing for me as far as like
what what defines the quality of a
strain is really what do you wind up
with in your bag when it's all said and
done so for me what I want is the ones
that have that crazy I'm really you know
I mean for a lot of people it's all
about well is it it is it's Tony what's
it do to you what are the effects and I
can appreciate that and I respect that
mindset a lot but like honestly for us
growing up here like when we were
smoking a lot um we would smoke so much
that it wasn't a matter of okay well we
only have this four grams weed how high
is it going to get us so we really got
into flavors and smells a lot and I
really like I really like the flower um
just for aesthetics aside from actually
consuming it or doing anything with it I
like to sit and I like to hold it I like
to smell it I mean the same way people
like like cut flowers like if you like
um you know whatever tuberose or
gardenias or you know whatever kind of
flowers that are nice just because you
can sit and smell them I think of I
think a weed like that so I want to I
want usually to have it be something
where when I have it I really enjoy how
it looks and then I really enjoy how it
smells and I like the ones that
are really special in that if you smell
them and you didn't know it was weed you
might not know that that was a weed
smell you know yeah uh so that that's
what that leads me a lot but then it
comes down to on top of okay what is it
in the bag it's also what is it in the
garden
so is it fun to grow or is it a
nightmare to grow you know and so
anything that's where I say that's why I
say experiences led me it's like I look
at a plant and I go oh this one's going
to be a pain in the butt you know or
move this one's going to be a dream and
I'm going to be happy just to go work
with these plants every day so if I have
something and I say oh I like this one
you can bet that the plant is going to
be fun to grow it's going to be fun to
look at it's probably going to be fun to
harvest and it's also going to be fun to
have it dried in your bag
yeah yeah right on your your black line
Reserve was a you know a homerun by
anybody's standards and I'm grateful to
have been able to sample it a few times
you know it's like it's got that bright
lime and coconut and fruit over over
like a bed of like soothing herbs and
moss you know its plays both ends of the
spectrum yeah and it's not like you know
like when you when somebody says can you
taste the fruit continue and you're like
oh maybe I can wear it where's the lime
it's like boom you know it's like it's
like a you know a green pop stick a lot
of the out of the fridge that that
you're that out of the freezer that that
point you know what what did what went
into that you know since it's probably
the strain that you know I would say
nationally you're probably most
associated with you just just gives us a
little bit of background of the black
line okay so the deal with that was that
that release was a clone that I keep
that I call lime number one and what it
is is uh it's a PK two og type because
there's a couple different kinds of PK
but the one I used was a oh g type and I
I crossed it with what I called black
lime
and what black lime was was I I had
these plant
I had these seeds and I got on my sink
96 or 97 I got the I got the two
different kinds of seeds and one of them
I was working with my buddy and he
actually got one side of it which was an
old strain that was a lot of a lot of
chemical smells really deep really heavy
a lot of skunk enos really toxically
stony to the point where like if
somebody's drinking alcohol like smoking
that is a no-no like four beers and two
hits of that and you're probably going
to be laying in the bushes throwing up
you know it was really really strong and
we called it pong for purple orange and
green I didn't come up with it my buddy
did and it was it was old genetics that
were that work that came from my family
in the 80s and got recycled through a
couple people and then came back to us
and um you know it was kind of like just
the regular stuff to me and I didn't
really you know I didn't really hold it
at a high value because none of it was
pure anymore it had become this old oil
cans strains crossed with which was a
which was a walk and Afghani crossed
with the Northern Lights that was a
clone we gave them for years and and
this guy did this breeding and then me
and my buddy worked for me got some
seeds so there's that side of it which
is this really deep heavy nasty gross
thing but it was it was amazing but it
was just crazy you know and and then I
had I worked for for another friend of
mine and I I was silk-screening
people's trim back then to make him hash
you know and I was pressing the hash and
people were like whoa this is like old
school hash from back in the day you
know and this is like I started doing
this in like 94 95 this guy from Lebanon
showed us how to do it how to press it
you know and we're like oh that's really
neat you can press it because of course
if you have
good hash you compress anything but he
showed us how to press anything
basically that could be pressed to make
dark sticky nice hash um using heat and
everything and so I was doing that and
so I went through the guy's stuff and as
I'm going through I go hey there's some
seeds in these are these good you know
and he goes yeah I'll give you some
other seeds though but if you want them
you know I mean you can try and he goes
but there nothing I did on purpose so
who knows what they really are they're
just seeds and like a rounding error for
him yeah so uh so I take the I take the
one I take the one and I take the other
and now the Paul guy knows good so I
grow it out the other one which at the
time I didn't know what it was I just
knew it was like Afghani and uh and
later on I found out there was Northern
Lights in it and then even more recently
only like last year I was talking to the
guy goes and I was talking to a friend
who had been talking to the guy I got it
from and he goes hey did you know he had
used the the old Burmese in there from
so-and-so and I go no I never he never
told me that he goes yeah I was he goes
we went further down the rabbit hole you
know we got down the worm hole or
something like that and he goes then all
of a sudden you know this is more info
pops out and he's got the Burmese in
there the old branch camber beef and I
was like oh okay and so that made a
little bit of sense too for there to be
some else in it because it was so exotic
this other thing was always like
grapefruit or cranberry or lime or
something just always really nice you
know and so so of course the ones I knew
were pretty good because the POG my
buddy had bred a couple times and he
said oh these are all really good now
and so I did a seed patch garden and
what I did was I went okay well here's
the here's the one that I know is great
I'm gonna keep the males from these and
here's the one that came out of that
shake I'm gonna go ahead and get rid of
those males because I don't know yeah I
don't know what's gonna come out of this
stuff cuz the guy who gave it to me he
said he didn't know you know yeah so he
only grew one thing but he just wasn't
he is like
probably not my keeper plants those are
probably the more wimpy ones because
it's the prey you have to focus
somewhere yeah yeah so so I get those
and I grow them and out of the ones that
were the citrusy ones I got a couple
really nice big beautiful plants that
were just what I would have wanted but
interestingly enough the worst plant in
the whole thing that was all one of
those ones that if you looked at all the
plants and you go okay well there's a
dozen of them let's get rid of the
weakest one that was the one that wound
up smelling like it smelled like tie
line you know and so I er like you're
like buck up campers you got some work
to do you need to bounce back oh yeah no
I mean it was it was basically like okay
well and and typically in breeding the
way I do things is this if I get boys
that are really really really weak or
there's something that I really don't
like about them I'll go ahead and kill
males but and this is for open
pollination of course I do selective
line breeding too or you only use one
male but in this case it was just we
were just trying to make a whole bunch
of seed with this stuff and just kind of
see what we get so I wound up killing I
want I wound up killing all the males
from the citrusy stuff and from the
fuelie stuff I wound up keeping maybe
three or four males I don't remember
there was a bunch of them there and I
killed most of them and so so when I
have females even if the females look
bad I keep them just in case they have
something really cool because it's not
going to water down the gene pool
because it's easy to keep the seeds from
a female separate but when you have a
lot of males together you can't keep
them separate their pollens all going to
mix right right so whereas I call a lot
of the male population I don't pull out
much of the females unless there's
something really bad about them like
maybe if they get like a stem rot or
something that I just I just don't want
to have nothing to do with even growing
at one time but if I'm willing to grow
the plant one time and it's a female
it's going to stay and so it was just
this wimpy little plant its buds when
they were finished were only about as
bigger
my son none of them were long and they
had these tiny little leaves and these
thin little stems and it gets all the
way I think it was a boy was a Burmese
throw back judging by what was in
everything and it gets all the way to
the end and it gets this incredible
smell to this day it's still my favorite
smell and it does it comes out of the
line but there's not a ton of them in
there because the lime was the cross of
this weird plant that was there and it
was already kind of a sport and then I
had crossed it was something that was in
a totally different world of flavor so
um anyway uh what ended up happening was
I labeled it I labeled all the plants so
I had like tall purple um tall purple
cranberry um tall green fat Northern
Lights you know and then this one plant
it smelled like lime and it turned black
in the fall so on the package of seeds
which was a bag of seeds that you know
Jesus was a lot you know it's a lot of
seeds I made it was a whole imagine you
know it's a whole garden full of
six-foot plants and they're all fully
seated you know yeah that's a lot a
release right there yeah it was a lot of
seeds and so so that that's what it
wound up getting labeled as as the blast
so that I would know which planet was oh
this was the plan that smelled like lime
and it was and it turned black so that's
where the name black lime came from it
wasn't like let's get a wonderful dinner
really think is cool or whatever it's
like no it's just it's just off of my
label which is how most of my names come
about I just I write him down for
reference for myself and then people ask
what it is and that's the only name for
it and then the name sticks you know
yeah so that was really where that came
from and then I wound up taking a male
out of that population when I planted
some of them because the females came
out really good and I didn't really
expect him to be that crazy but they
were they were amazing they were like
the best stuff I've ever seen and then
it started there started to be the og
craze and so I went well let me take
some of my different males and throw
them
oh geez and see if I get anything to
come out oh gee which I didn't because
all my stuff was so dominant over the og
so I wound up with this basically with a
plant that had does that did really good
but it it it wasn't OG it still had all
of the all of the terpene profile from
from the middle ground of the of the
black line so it has this really heavy
chemical funk earth moss thing like you
said and then it has all this really
beautiful floral limey citrus zest stuff
going on you know and that's that's
that's why it wound up being such a um
such an odd thing because I really I
took two things that were really
different you know what I mean it was
like peanut butter and bacon or you know
it was it was a weird thing to put
together so right on cool well thank you
for sharing that story and that makes a
lot of sense too because the the flour
that I have you know it's it's this kind
of you know blackish bluish almost
iridescent and it's nice to hear the
background behind it and we're going to
go ahead and take a our second short
break and be right back you're listening
to shaping fire and my guest today is
Mean Gene master cannabis breeder at
Freeborn selections if you grow cannabis
with sunshine you can often feel limited
by the seasonal cycle you want to grow
sustainably and save money so you use as
little electricity as possible but if
you haven't studied or implemented light
deprivation techniques into your
greenhouse you're leaving a lot of money
on the table by incorporating light
deprivation solutions into your
greenhouse you can often add two or
three additional growing cycles to your
year when you pencil out the financial
benefit of those additional cycles
you'll realize why commercial scale
light deprivation technology is remaking
the cannabis industry what used to be
done by pulling tarps over hoop houses
has been scaled up over the last few
years in such a way that it's become
mechanized easy and affordable to even
small-scale commercial cannabis
operations forever flowering greenhouses
is the industry leader in light
deprivation greenhouse designed in
operation for the commercial cannabis
industry their team of greenhouse
experts have been in the fields of
Northern California for decades and
they're now building greenhouses for
commercial cannabis companies across the
country
if you are new to light dep and growing
in greenhouses I encourage you to go
back to shaping fire episode 13 with
guest Eric Branstad of forever flowering
I talked with Eric about the importance
of intelligent greenhouse management as
well as the huge financial benefit of
incorporating light depth techniques
there are so many aspects of utilizing a
greenhouse that can go wrong from
temperature and airflow to light depth
and workflow forever flowering will help
you produce crop after crop of
well-cared-for flowers they can help you
retrofit your existing greenhouse with
light depth and other modern systems at
a level that fits your budget if you're
just starting out forever flowering can
help you plan and build your new
greenhouse so that you get started on
the right foot the candidates business
has enough risks without trying to go it
alone with your greenhouse contact
forever flowering greenhouses to partner
with folks who have an indisputable
reputation as knowledgeable and easy to
work with go to shaping fire calm board
/ FFG to find out more now that the
health benefits of terpenes have become
well known in the cannabis industry
people everywhere are looking for the
purest terpenes without adulterants the
problem with most terpene providers is
that they're not sourced naturally and
instead are made as a byproduct of
refining petroleum and that's so sketchy
the terpenes sold by true terpenes are
entirely different they are certified
organic non-gmo and food grade that
means that they are extracted from real
plant sources there are no solvents of
any kind they are distilled only with
steam that's right only steam in fact
terpenes from true turbines are so pure
that you can eat them not only that but
you can stack them with better results -
what I mean is other companies terpenes
have got a few percent of impurities and
when you stack those terpenes to make
your blend you're adding a variety of
impurities that degrade your final
product true terpenes also have
strain-specific terpenes for a wide
range of cannabis strains like Durbin
poison sunset sherbet and granddaddy
purple true terpenes has robust in
support of customer service so your
questions will get answered fast and
efficiently if you shop for Turk's
before you know how rare that is
so whether you want to cup your hands
just smell some betta carry off lean to
calm down
after getting too high or if you want to
dab some pining so your lungs feel
fabulous and your mind feels liberated
true terpenes will provide you with a
truly natural experience if you are a
cannabis product developer these are the
Terps you want to add to your oil or
edible or capsule or whatever true
terpenes are simply the best your money
can buy don't try and make a premium
product with substandard terms choose
true terpenes for a top-shelf experience
go to shaping fire calm board flash true
terpenes to find out more or click on
the link in this lisa newsletter welcome
back you are listening to shaping fire
and I'm your host Shango Louis and our
guest this week is Mean Gene master
cannabis breeder at Freeborn selections
so Jean you know I know that you've done
some runs with aficionado and the
aficionado stuff is all you know ultra
premium elite and also in limited
edition and you know that is an
interesting aspect of it because it
makes the seeds themselves more valuable
but it also keeps it out of the hands of
a lot of people so I'm just curious what
your thoughts are on the limited nature
of seeds like like do you are you
attracted to the idea of a limited run
so it's a little more rare or was that
mostly just because that's the
aficionado like premium model to release
you know that's actually a concept it's
kind of a double-edged sword with with
doing stuff limited but it's a concept
that I was supportive of because I've
noticed over the years that if things
are a little bit harder to get people
tend to value value a more highly and
take them more seriously which from a
preservation point of view because
that's really you know I'm really
concerned with things staying around
because I've seen so much stuff just be
gone and you never see it again
so to me I feel like if somebody gets a
pack of seeds and they know that there
was only ever a couple hundred of these
packs released or there was only 50 of
them released once they get it they're
more likely to breed it and keep those
seeds around and people are more likely
to say oh I really
to get that whereas if everybody's
already seen it at everybody else's
house they're more likely to go yeah I
could get that anytime I'll grow that
later you know yeah I mean I mean
certainly when I see people at your at
the aficionado booth at Emerald cup I
mean people are treating these things
like they are you know gifts from the
gods because I mean not only are they
paying you know serious money for them
but you know really if you know that's
all you're going to get and so you know
it you're you're popping each one with
intention and you're taking care of it
and you just you know I know when I have
got rare seeds i I just shower them with
more love and care than I do if somebody
gives me oh here this is my latest run
here's fifty seeds of it you know yeah
and I you know I use the analogy of dogs
you know because I see a lot of you I
see a lot of things a lot of parallels
because you know breeding breeding dogs
breeding seeds um like you know I I have
a I always I always say hey you know
like and it's the same with seeds with
dogs I say hey go adopt a dog go get a
dog at a shelter they're all good it's
the same as seeds it's like hey go buy
that $18 PACA seeds go tribe yeah
plant those seeds that you found in the
bud go plant those seeds that can't even
it you know what I mean like just try
them all and there's going to be there's
going to be some stuff but I know for a
fact that if if somebody goes and they
and they go get a dog out of a cardboard
box in front of a store you know they're
going to be less likely to focus on that
dog as much as if somebody says hey
here's a $12,000 puppy somebody who buys
a $12,000 puppy you think they're going
to miss their shots and let them get
parvo or they're not going to cut their
toenails or they're not going to check
their dog's ears and teeth and you know
what I mean like I have you know I have
dogs I have one dog that's inexpensive
you know highly bred like show dog tight
pit bull and I have a mutt that's a
Saint Bernard and blue pit bull mix and
I treat them the same but I also treat
crappy bag seeds
that I find out of a bud that I think is
a good bud to me
finding that bag seed that's just like
somebody saying hey here is a pack of
seeds these are really expensive they
didn't make very many you know so for me
I have like that understanding that it
could be anywhere but I know that
there's a lot of people who don't think
that way so I do understand the the
value of telling somebody look these are
very rare there's not a lot so that's
like when the black Lyme reserve was the
first thing that I put out publicly with
aficionado I was like well you know I
had a lot of them I could have put out a
couple thousand packs but I knew that if
I put out three hundred packs that
people would take them more seriously
and they would be more likely to clone
once and when they get a keeper they'd
be more likely to make more seeds and
they'd be more likely to make crosses
with the seeds because I like it when
people do that stuff with my seeds I
don't want to just put out across and
have people go oh yeah that's cool
what's the next one you know it's like
the like you said people people act like
they're gifts from the gods and like you
know depending on whether people believe
in God or a God or just the universal
force or the spirit or whatever people
believe we're we're getting our getting
our life from you know those seeds are a
gift from that force you know like that
that's a major thing that like every
type of every type of life form that
there is is special but these ones the
outlets as much as cannabis I mean you
know there's nothing that's really as
helpful potentially to us as as cannabis
can be I mean you got something here
that can potentially if you find the
right plant it could cure any disease it
might just be a matter of finding oh
okay well look this one produces this
chemical and you know once you get it
down to everybody only going oh yeah we
just all grow oh gee or oh we just only
grow sour we just only grow cookies
that's fine but it gets to a point where
you go well but what about all of this
you know these plants they don't all
grow by themselves we've we've adopted
them into our cultures
then we keep them and then that means
that if all of a sudden we lose them
it's like we've adopted them and then
we've abandoned them you know so we
become responsible for the gene pool
because we've done these things to it
and we've created all this really crazy
diversity and then after a while then we
go oh no no no and it just all gets it
all gets left by the wayside and so you
know there's there's there's like
there's an aspect of things being
thought after and so at this point now
when I feel like okay people understand
that if I have a breed and I say that
it's really valuable and it's really
special and it's worth growing people
now more so than when I first release
stuff people will believe me so I feel
like now I can put out a lot of feeds
and I can put out a lot of different
strains and people will understand where
I'm coming from in breeding that that
these things are special so I don't
necessarily have to say okay well this
is so special like this and so so
special because of that I can just say
look this is really good this is worth
having please if you buy them make more
give them to your friends take clones
keep it around because it's part of of
what's going on you know so that's why I
say it's like a double-edged sword where
you go okay well it's good to have it be
limited but at the same time you're
going to miss some of these people who
are out there who are preservationist
who were hoping that they could get a
pack and those guys didn't get a pack
and some guys who just grew them out
real quick and sold the weed without
ever even smelling it because they heard
it was a hot item those guys got some of
the packs too so I want to be able to
put them out so that both those I want
to be the guys who want to get the seeds
and they just want to hey I just want to
grow a bunch of weed and I'm gonna make
money and I'm going to look cool and
this and that great get these cool
strains but I want them to be able to
also reach as many of the
preservationist as as they can so that
people get their hands on them and in
you know 50 years or a hundred years or
a thousand years from now there's
somebody who's got these things and they
go hey I don't know where these came
from but they're really cool
and uh they're valuable let's keep
making more and you know that that's
like a service to the to the plant
because the plant is um you know they're
like for me personally there's nothing
in life that's ever done as much for me
as a cannabis plant as you know yeah
well amen to that and you know you're
you know I I'm glad to hear that you
like the idea that people are you know
making crosses with your gear in order
to you know preserve it in their region
the the seed pack that I know that came
up here near near me you know my buddy
planned the four crosses well in advance
so we had it all lined up and you know
and so we got to try you know the
original black line as you intended but
then also you know four crosses and you
know the black line is still in there
you can still taste it but you know you
could also get the variations and so so
there's a lot of joy in that and and so
you know let's let's uh let's wrap up
with this you know there's a lot of
folks who are listening today who aspire
to be an elite breeder like you are and
a lot of folks you know they're getting
their start by you know just they've got
two you know two strains that they like
and then they cross them and they've got
F ones and they share them with their
friends and they feel good about that
and so they you know they they pick up a
breeding book and they get a little more
serious but but you know you you've done
you've done it all now at this point so
what advice do you have for folks
willing to put in the work who want to
follow on this path behind you what
advice would you give them that can kind
of help them along their way um my
biggest advice would be you know like uh
do you know go with what really what you
really really like a lot of people you
know as like a commercial breeder I was
talking to somebody and they were saying
oh I just you know I just take I just
take males and put them on these clones
and like kinda you know like oh yeah
like that's not that and I was like well
you know if you're going to make stuff
repeat for other people I what I said I
think uh if you want to please the crowd
you got you got
play the hits right yeah so that's a
cool thing to do but if you're even if
you are doing that you really want to go
with what you really like so the things
that really uh that you really vibe with
like alright this is something that I
really like like you know I have a buddy
who he's like I've seen all the weed
I've seen all the Kush I've seen
everything he goes I like granddaddy
pert or herbal those are still the thing
that I like I like perps I'm not into
this Kush I'm not into this Diesel he's
just like purple like if you're the guy
who likes the purp then that's your
thing if that's your very favorite thing
then be the guy who makes the purp
crosses who makes the the strains that
are based on purp and that have those
things that you really like and then
really really tune into that really tune
into what you're vibing with because
those good feelings that you're getting
about something those are what are
really telling you that that's what
you're supposed to be doing that's how
our intuition works and that's how
that's how our our brain and our our you
know everything is really is our whole
energy is really wired to that like okay
if you want to breed breed the things
that you really like now you might if
you want to do it like commercially you
might have to think about okay well what
where where is the place that there's
the overlap between these two these two
groups of traits here okay everybody
else wants it to be
stony they want to get good concentrate
production they want a plant that's easy
to grow they want to plant this
high-yielding they want disease
resistance okay now so you know
everybody wants those things so then now
with the things that you really love
which might be like in my case I love
stuff that's floral I love stuff that's
spicy I love stuff that's earthy I love
the smells that to me are like classy
like to me like loud is cool but it
doesn't have to be loud for me it needs
to be special so that's like my little
thing that I got going so it's got to be
whatever you are really really into
you've got to tune into that and make
that be
what what you're working towards you
know because that's the only way you can
really do something well is to go is to
be able to really be turned on by it
like alright this is the thing that I
like so this is what I know about you
know like if you're going to be if you
like heavy metal don't play jazz you
know what I mean if you like if you like
tacos
don't make pizza you know do whatever it
is that thing that you really really
like tune into that and do that to the
max and then that's when you're going to
wind up having these things that are
that are really cool you know
yeah totally following your passion and
you'll you'll you'll never be bored in
the in the cannabis field that's for
sure so genius thank you so much for
spending some time with us I know your
time is valuable especially this time of
year when you're especially busy but
thank you for being here and sharing
what you got yeah thank you for having
me on dude and um you know I'm glad to
be able to get a little bit hopefully
you know somebody can get a little
tidbit of info here there a little bit
of inspiration or direction or whatever
and um you know make some make some some
good seeds or just you know find some
good seeds and grow some good weed or
you know whatever whatever people are
doing with it I think that there's some
amazing insights in your story and a lot
of inspiration too so I'm sure people
are going to dig it you can find out
more about Mean Gene and free board
selections by following his Instagram at
Mean Gene from Mendocino I also highly
recommend that you check out the
interview that Kevin Jodrey from
Wonderland nursery did with Mean Gene as
part of the wonderland nursery seed
series shaping fire was actually a
sponsor of that down in Humboldt a
couple months ago you can check that out
on the Wunderland nursery comm site of
course you can find out more about
aficionado seeds at aficionado comm and
you can buy aficionado and freeborn
selections when they're available at
seeds here now.com or you know come on
down
- the Emerald Cup in December and buy
direct at their booth you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shaping fire
calm and on Apple iTunes stitcher and
Google Play if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you'd leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where i will be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm as your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host
Shango lows
[Music]