[Music]
it's true that cannabis is a harder Road
for entrepreneurs than most all
entrepreneurs need vision to raise money
find help and deliver their product or
service while turning a profit if only
cannabis was that easy cannabis
entrepreneurs also must find a bank that
accepts cannabis clients a location that
will rent to them and find suppliers who
may themselves be unsure about working
with cannabis companies and sometimes an
entrepreneur needs to create a law that
will even allow their business to exist
my guest today I'll Warner is this sort
of entrepreneur if you enjoy sharing
frank discussions that dive deep into
cannabis health business and technique i
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter every week you'll receive a
new podcast episode delivered right to
your inbox along with commentary on a
couple of the most important news items
from the week social media sites are
becoming very unreliable and showing
folks every post they want to see so
sign up for the newsletter to make sure
you don't miss an episode you are
listening to shaping fire and i am your
host Shango lowes all Warner's
extraordinary efforts is a citizen
lobbyist created the country's first
cannabis health and beauty aids law the
acronym for that law you'll hear a lot
today is Chava that Washington law
removed cannabis health and beauty aids
from the state's Controlled Substances
Act those products can now be sold in
any store like food co-ops massage
suppliers and even big chains like
Walgreens all the way back in nineteen
ninety-five I'll Warner founded cannabis
basics in Washington where she's still
presently CEO cannabis basics has two
lines of products the first line is
based on the healing properties of hemp
seed oil and are available throughout
the United States the second available
only in Washington are based on whole
plant cannabis with THC the astonishing
thing though is that they have THC and
yet can be sold anywhere i received the
1999 hemp times by a near award for
outstanding achievement in body care and
the MJB a women's alliance special award
for her focus and dedication to the
women in washington's cannabis industry
I was also founder an executive director
of the international cannabis health and
beauty aids producers Alliance which
spells out the wonderful name of each
otha pas I has been a cannabis activist
for decades and now finds herself at the
helm of one of the most important and
visionary cannabis companies in the
country while inspiring people in other
states to figure out how they can create
chavos where they live like Oh has done
in Washington and that's what we're
going to talk about today welcome to the
show ah hey thank you so much I'm so
happy to be here I'm very glad you are
so let's get right into it so you know
during the 2016 washington state
legislative session you successfully
lobbied for a new state law that would
allow full plant cannabis extract health
and beauty products with a THC content
of less than point three percent to be
sold in regular unlicensed stores and
you know this was a big deal because
this kind of law exists nowhere else in
the United States so tell us a little
bit about this law and what it took to
get past it was actually so that's all
true except that it was 2015 oh gosh so
yeah so we introduced the language Jean
eco well senator Jay Nicole wells was my
champion in the Senate and we introduced
that language in January 22nd of 2015
and it was passed signed by Endsley on
june thirtieth and enacted on july first
of 2015 so it's been over a year and a
half now it feels like it's amazing it's
amazing how time flies but you are
absolutely correct this is some
legislation this is law that doesn't
exist in any other state in the Union um
and so we're leading the way for
cannabis health and beauty aids so
products less than point three percent
PA SI non intoxicating and topical
applications only are available to be
sold on the mainstream market place here
in washington state only yeah it's
profound and so i want to drill into
this just a little bit more because I a
lot of people are like well we've got
cannabis laws in our state why aren't
they the same what is what makes this
particular law unique well it basically
it defines so that I see three divisions
of cannabis topicals one is hemp body
care one is cannabis health and beauty
aids in the middle and that's what we're
specifically talking about and then the
third one would be recreational /
medical topicals that are sold in a
regular in a highly regulated market
like our 50 to market and so we are
csaba is the only place that Java
actually exists is here in Washington
State and so what we did was we defined
it for the first time we defined it as
not marijuana and we were able to get it
removed out of the washington state
controlled substances act which was a
big deal and it means a lot for other
states because it was with we were the
first day to remove anything cannabis
out of any state's Controlled Substances
Act and I believe it to be true that now
industrial hemp hasn't even been removed
out of any state's Controlled Substances
Act so this is the first chipping way of
the block of a state csa so pretty proud
of it yeah that's a lot to be a proud of
and you know since so much of us are
throwing around this this sub point
three percent as it as it applies to the
cvd from hemp world I think it's
important that we take a moment and
clarify for folks that that this is not
what we're talking about it's that same
point three percent number but we're
talking about authentic cannabis plants
not industrial hemp and the key point is
the percentage of THC in the final
product that goes on the shelf which
must stay below 0 point three percent
right absolutely yeah and so I used that
hemp level because I knew that that was
the one that was everyone was
comfortable with in the United States at
less than point three percent THC I used
that when we were writing the language
but but just because it's less than
point three percent THC as a finished
product it doesn't make it hemp it's
chava hemp is a plant a cannabis plant
that's less than point three percent THC
so there are very different definitions
but we absolutely use the same number
and I just want to make sure that people
understand you know when you say less
than point three percent THC in a
finished product so I'm talking about a
cream or ointment or lotion you're
actually talking about 85 less than
eighty five milligrams of THC in a
finished one ounce product so people
think I'll less than point 3 % HC it's
nothing will actually a
is quite a bit 8080 less than eighty
five milligrams is quite a bit in a one
ounce container yeah absolutely and so
you're right when saying point three
percent it sounds like in an
insignificant number but when you when
you switch over to milligrams they're
like uh you know in and out that makes a
lot of sense as far as yeah you know
relief goes when you look at active
ingredients in like an arnica cream
you're talking the active ingredients
like five milligrams seven you know what
I mean they're really low when you talk
an active ingredients in in healthy Oh
in you know topical therapeutics did you
find that you you really had a lot of
challenge with legislators who just
didn't want to touch the cannabis topic
at all you know was it was it difficult
for you to kind of have them understand
to tease out the difference between you
know other cannabis policy and cannabis
policy as it applies to health and
beauty aids well I have to say you know
I was very very you know this is 2015 so
medical was being shut down I mean we've
had this tumultuous transition it's been
very painful but I have I really was
conscious of the fact that I needed to
keep shabbos separate from medical
marijuana and chavez separate from
recreational or adult adult use
marijuana and so I was conscious of that
fact and the legislators in Olympia
they're pretty savvy they do I didn't
have a whole lot of opposition and
actually you know there was only one
when my son and I lobbied Olympian took
our two of our products to every office
in Olympia there was only one office
that refused to take it and so everybody
was pretty happy and you can you can be
guaranteed that Olympia was talking
about cannabis topicals in cannabis
basics for like you know three weeks
after that okay so no they were very
receptive is the short answer to that
right on and you know while we're on
that you know I i have heard you talk to
a lot of different folks about you know
how to approach policy makers and so so
as of this as an aside why don't you
just take a moment and give folks your
general primer because as so many people
get are so emotional about wanting to
liberate cannabis for for patients and
for
that sometimes they they go and they
interact with their politicians as if
they're the enemy and I think that
everybody can learn something from you
about how you approach them well it's
about perspective and so in the cannabis
culture in the kanima community cannabis
community we have a different
perspective but you have to understand
it in order to make anything happen to
change you know to liberate cannabis we
have to work from their perspective so
when you go first of all reach out to
your legislators legislators but always
be professional always you know please
and thank you and always look
professional when you're down there
because remember they're not walking
into your community you're walking into
theirs so it's really important that you
be yourself because that's what speaks
to them but you but you must present
yourself like you you are down there
lobbying every time you walk into a
legislators office you're actually
lobbying for a cause so present yourself
be serious and you know and if they're
trying to make jokes you know because it
is weed you know just keep you know be
light-hearted about it but remember say
this is really isn't a laughing matter
anymore we really need to work on this
and get through you know the fear and
the you know the laughable part of this
but for me specifically what it was was
I just happen to have the champion
washington state champion jeannie
Caldwell's who's now in king county
council woman call wells she happened to
be the senator for my legislative
district 236 district in in washington
state and so she was the perfect person
I I got an introduction to her I had a
meeting with her and from get she was
just like oh these are amazing this
doesn't make any sense why they would be
regulated so heavily blah blah blah you
know what I mean she she was all in from
the beginning within six months we had
legislation we introduced it and six
months later it was passed so what you
think is going to be a super super
daunting thing can sometimes be fairly
easy it's all about putting one foot
front of the other and being clear about
what you're asking for so after you got
this new never been seen before chavo
law passed I'm assuming that you had to
go on a serious education campaign with
retailers
like you had to do with legislators
because they must have been a little
astonished that they could actually even
carry your product yeah and just like I
had to do to retailers back in the 90s
for him and just like I had to do in the
mid to that 2012-2013 for the medical
world for topicals I mean it's been one
education after another but retailers
now you know the irony and I definitely
want to make this point is that
marijuana being legalized has brought
attention to my whole company my hemp
line and my chava line and retailers are
much more savvy now than they were even
two years ago you know it's hip cannabis
is now acceptable so when they didn't
wouldn't even talk to you before at
least they're having a conversation now
that being said I have had some bigger
buyers in Washington State say we're
just not ready for this we're just not
willing to take the risk even though I
can refer them to the RCW that shows
them that it's absolutely legal for them
to tell to sell these products in their
store some of them are still
apprehensive that being said we are
making progress you know I lost 125
medical marijuana stores on July
fifteenth of this year I'm sorry of 2016
so I lost my entire medical marketplace
and now i'm up to about 55 mainstream
stores so we're talking grocery stores
and spas and coffee shops and
chiropractic doctors naturopathic
doctors this is the type of buyer that i
have now and they're far more savvy than
I you know I would even say some of the
medical buyers that I was dealing with
two years ago and now i actually have
because i'm in the mainstream i have the
opportunity to have distribution and so
now I now have the first distribution
deal for champa product I believe in
Washington State and so now I have
someone else reaching out to the bigger
buyers on my behalf and so it's kind of
streamline this and make this happen
much more quickly but buyers are much
more savvy these days I can imagine the
on your behalf part can be challenging
because as you are selling to the retail
level buyers they
inter need to explain what's going on to
the end user and our consumers buying
the products do they get it the
consumers get it and I have to tell you
in most cases you know every time I
speak and I do a fair amount of speaking
the last thing that I say is the best
thing that you could do for for java and
for liberating all of cannabis is to
talk to your local retailer your corner
store where you go in to get your milk
ask them do they carry any java and of
course this is only Washington stay for
now but ask them do you have any Java do
you have any cannabis health and beauty
aids and if they don't say well I would
encourage you to look into it it's now
legal for you to sell it and so it's
it's consumers and it's patients also
going to their doctors and asking their
chiropractors it's safe for me to use
this it's really working for me so it is
kind of a groundswell of consumers
asking the retailers and asking their
care providers to carry these products I
mean I was like I'm excited to talk to
you about how this is a model for other
states but first we're going to take a
short break and be right back you're
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is all Warner founder of cannabis
basics if you like podcasts like shaping
fire chances are that you'll like audio
books too just like with podcasts
audiobooks speak to you tell you stories
and teaches stuff here's the thing
audible.com has an offer that I want to
tell you about right now they are
offering a trial of their audiobook
service for absolutely free you can go
to shaping fire calm poured flash
audible and you'll get a free audiobook
straight up you can listen to it on your
mobile device computer or download it
and listen to it you know like anywhere
it's really simple of course they want
you to subscribe to their service after
the free trial and enjoy audiobooks
forever but you don't have to all you
have to do to get the free audiobook of
your choice is to just check out the
service for free and the service is
pretty great there are whole sections on
permaculture sci-fi history biography
hell you can even listen to a book about
card counting in blackjack whatever it's
all pretty rad so that's the deal your
first book is free it's easy to sign up
it's easy to quit and their online
library of free
is pretty incredible so just check it
out go to shaping fire calm /a dab'll to
find out more or just click on the link
in this week's newsletter welcome back
this is shaping fire and i am your host
Shango Lohse today's guest is aa Warner
founder of cannabis basics so in the
first set we were talking about how I
got the first in the nation chava law
passed and now we understand that that
she's also working on a new law that
will give chava companies the privilege
to buy raw inputs cannabis inputs from
state license recreational cannabis
producers that follow-up will pretty
much remake the health and beauty aids
market how is that new log in to work ah
well let me just set the premise of why
it's necessary on of course on July
fifteenth of two of 2016 not only did I
lose my medical retail marketplace my
buyers but I also lost the collective
garden model system which is what
medical worked under here as far as
growers were concerned so I lost my
sourcing as well so I lost my way to
acquire cannabinoids because I don't
grow I'm not a I'm not a marijuana
grower and so what we really need is a
way we need it we needed an
accessibility vent to be able to work
with 50 to producers and so that's what
we're working on now we have a piece of
legislation in both the House and the
Senate right now that is on pause until
next year for four reasons that we just
thought the climate wasn't quite ready
for considering the new president and
and the federal climate that's all I'll
say about that so but when it goes next
session in January we'll be moving
forward with a piece of legislation that
will allow me to source that allow chava
permitted manufacturers and they will be
permitted through the liquor current and
cannabis board they'll have a permit
that will allow them to take
cannabinoids out of the 502 system and
make their products as long as the
products finish is less than point three
percent THC so it'll allow for the
handling of cannabinoids so the
the kind of impact of all the fantastic
work that you've been doing and kind of
where I want to go with the show today
is that you are doing this you know
nationally breakthrough work here in
Washington but as far as you know the US
as a whole this can become a model and
so you know how are these two laws a
model for similar work that could be
done by other entrepreneur activists in
other states yeah I love that so so my
number one goal is to get the hands that
get these types of products in the hand
back in the hands of all health
conscious consumers remember the
products that I make were they were
fairly commonplace 150 years ago so
let's we didn't read we didn't invent
anything we just defined it here with
our law and so but as far as other
states using what we've done here in
Washington State I think that it would
be fairly easy for them to do they could
just look at their Controlled Substances
Act and figure out a way to define these
types of products and remove it out of
their own States Controlled Substances
Act but they also have to figure out a
way for them to work with their own
medical or adult use regulated system I
mean you gotta remember in some states
don't have either yeah so it's going to
really depend on what is exactly
happening in that state I've had people
from Colorado in California both reach
out to me and asked me to do what we did
you know in their states what we did
here in Washington and it's not it's
easier said than done because you have
to look at the laws that are in place in
in those states and then tweak it from
there so but I encourage anybody that
wants to try to look at that to make
that happen because it will be state by
state by state unless of course they
just federally do scheduled marijuana
altogether but yeah it's exciting but as
you know that being said I am proud of
the fact that Washington State will be
known as the birthplace and epicenter of
cannabis modern-day cannabis health and
beauty aids so one of the things that I
know just from being friends with you is
that you are a
you're constantly working you are you
love doing strategic alliances with
other good people and and you've got
you've got this work ethic which is just
you know intense it's very intense and
and so you know I know that there are
other folks that are listening and our
understanding what you're putting down
about cannabis health and beauty aids
and you're like you know I might be able
to do in in my state what I did in
Washington what piece of advice or what
would you say to them if they came up to
you at a convention and said you know I
want to do this in you know in another
state what kind of advice do you give to
those folks so are you asking whether
they for them to change the law for them
to start making products like these
let's say let's say well probably the
changing the law I'm thinking of the
entrepreneur activist that's in a state
that at the very least has medical and
maybe they've got wreck but but they're
seeing this new opportunity and they
just want any words of advice sure well
it's not for the faint of heart however
it could be easier than it seems I you
know first of all you want to make a
relationship with your legislator so you
need to know who your senator is and who
you're too house of representatives are
those people are your champions and once
they're just people it seems a little
intimidating but once you have those
people's ear there it's their job I mean
it is really their job to listen to you
and their job to try to help you to
manifest especially new industry
remember this disc is new industry and
this will it won't generate an adult
marijuana tax it only generates a
regular sales tax but it's still
business for the state so anytime it has
a monetary value to it that you've got
their ear just a little bit more but it
really is just about having you know it
exactly what you want to do and aligning
yourself with somebody that you know if
it's not you that writes the legislation
then you know get a untouched with a
legislator tell them what you need and
then sometimes they have will write the
legislation for you you don't always
have to write it like they have Senate
lawyer
you know writers that tweak all this
legislation and get it into the actual
language you know the law language
should get it through but they will help
you along the way it's about literally
making those phone calls and setting up
those appointments and getting the air
of your legislators so yeah it's not
necessarily glamorous all the time
there's a lot of detail work and tasks
know and what I did you know I have to
say that I think one of the things that
we did that was really smart I took my
son I took my 15 year olds out of school
and I'm proud to talk about this because
it gave him such a civic lesson to be
down there with me we went down and we
dropped off to the paint two of the
products in every single office that's a
hundred and forty eight offices in
Olympia we made sure that when they had
to choose you know when they were making
the decisions on this cha the law that
was in front of him they knew what it
looked like they knew what it smelled
like they knew what it felt like and so
it was an education campaign down there
but that was just time and a little bit
of money you know it really wasn't that
costly it took us two days although the
the Capitol security stopped us in the
middle of our effort because they
thought that it was illegal for us to be
giving our products away and yeah and so
we had to reach out and get
clarification and they said come on back
down I mean they literally said shut us
down for a day and then went to their
lawyers and got back to us and said okay
it's okay for you to come back so yeah
so it's easy right on so so along those
similar lines you know I know that the
FDA watches the health and beauty aids
market really closely and I imagine that
must be sticky for you are you allowed
to claim any health benefits from
Canada's on the packaging no absolutely
not so so I am so I'm not a supplement
and I'm not an herbal remedy so I mean
that's a kind of a different category
than a topical application so there's a
little less scrutiny on topical
applications but you can't as far as the
FDA concern you can't make any claims
that aren't substantiated by science
that aren't readily sanchi aided by
science and the fact of the matter is
there you know worse because of the fear
that's been around
this for all these years we're not quite
there as far as yes there's more and
more research all the time I don't want
to say that there's no research out
there but as far as for claims on my
actual labels I don't make any claims my
labels have to be FDA compliant because
I am what I am you know I would have to
be super super careful I don't even make
any claims about the arnica in my
products which I could I'm just being
ultra safe and so it basically says the
FDA doesn't support any claims but we
encourage you right on the label it says
we encourage you to do your own research
on our ingredient list so I've got I've
got a similar question but I want to I
want to change it up a little bit
because for folks who haven't let's
figure this out yet the the chava the
cannabis health and beauty aids are sold
epithet that part of your line are sold
in Washington because Washington has the
chava law that you got past but then you
also have a second half of your product
line which is all made with hemp seed
oil and you know hemp seed oil has been
around for decades are you allowed to
speak about the health benefits of that
even sure oh yes I am yeah I can
anything that's substantiated hemp oil
is you know if the rich in essential
fatty acids is rich in vitamin E vitamin
C vitamin B got key amino acids I mean
it's amazing for our skin and we've
we've been able to input we can't grow
in many states still and you know that's
a whole nother hour show um but I've
been importing him seed oil since 1994
and I've been buying it organic hemp
seed oil from Canada since 1999 and you
know it's widely widely used in the
United States now and just for for good
reason I mean it's you know it's the
closest to our own natural semen it is
sebum it is the best oil for skin care
for for humans so for other folks like I
who don't know what sebum is what is
sebum it's just our own natural oil
production oh so like the oil that I
feel on my skin that's that's called
sebum yes folk and so if see it's also
got waxes
there's you know it's it's a little more
than just what you think of as oil it's
got the natural lipids very good very
good so we're going to take another
short break and be right back you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is all warner founder of cannabis
basics as a business owner you are
incredibly busy in reality you are
responsible for everything your company
does you have so many responsibilities
every single day that often you just
don't have the time to really dig into
something as deeply as you'd like you
know there is more that you could do to
reach out to new customers and to
encourage loyalty and the customers you
already have but you certainly don't
have the time and you're not ready to
hire someone full time for that role
either for you i recommend blunt
branding blunt branding principles
Kirsten Nelson and Anthony Garcia are
focused on improving your bottom line
you know most marketing firms are
excited to make your logo packaging and
website very pretty but they leave
responsibility for improving your bottom
line up to you they don't want that kind
of responsibility but that is pretty
much the most important part of
marketing right Kirsten and Anthony will
help you engage new customers funnel
them to your point of sale and keep them
coming back to you and telling their
friends no doubt this is a paid
commercial spots but that does not mean
they bought my opinion I've worked with
blood branding on three projects now for
various clients and every single time
they have done more than they have
promised and over delivered on results I
love how they generate new revenue and
focus on that as the goal instead of
just making me a pretty logo similarly
every friend I've referred them to has
come back to thank me and that just does
not happen every day so grab a pen and
paper because the website address is
coming if you want someone to implement
marketing programs that feed your bottom
line give blunt branding a call they
will share proven techniques to increase
your audience and generate sales while
using cutting-edge technology in the
background that make all of this easy
automatic and trackable go to shaping
fire calm forward slash blunt branding
to find out more you can also click the
link in our weekly newsletter blunt
Brandon
marketing that makes you money welcome
back this is shaping fire and i am your
host Shango lowes today's guest is AA
warner founder of cannabis basics so the
first two sets we've been talking a
whole lot about the different kinds of
topicals and the changing of the law in
Washington and how that could be applied
across the country but I got to say that
every time I talk to a consumer or a
patient about cannabis topicals they all
want to know if it will cause them to
fail a drug test and since you do so
much rd and are so deep in the science I
think you are probably the best person
to ask so I will using a THC cannabis
topical cause someone to fail a drug
test well I think that there are
definitely people smarter than I as far
as this particular topic is concerned
but the fact of the matter is we
actually don't know yet I can tell you
this this is this is what I know
personally my next-door neighbor she
never has never smoked pot in her life I
gave her my strongest products it's
about 10 milligrams per 1 ounce serving
so it's not a it's well under the point
three percent THC we tested her 15 mils
for 30 days and gave her you a and it
came up negative so we doubled the dose
30 with 15 mils the first 30 days and
then 30 mils the second 30 days tested
her again and again it came up negative
and so so I would say that probably not
but if before 44 chava highly
concentrated topicals I think that it is
a possibility that it might but I don't
know that for sure but I think that if
you are somebody who has a job with NASA
or you know you're going to lose you
know your your job over a tripped up QA
that I would just not quite use them yet
just not until we get a little bit more
science about how it would actually
affect a UA and what that level is for
topical applications so when being used
topical topically how important is the
carrier of choice by the Prophet product
designer because you know I hear people
debate oh we should use emu oil or oh no
you only need to use methanol or
eucalyptus or alcohol and and so so you
know if someone is true
using a topical only to treat on the top
of the dermo like for psoriasis or
eczema well that's fine but but if
you're using it for you know muscle
relief or anti-inflammation i would
think that you've got to break the derma
so what does it take to carry the
cannabinoids through the skin barrier
well there's people use differing things
and I think some more natural than other
you know DM DMSO is used for penetration
emu oil is used for penetration in my
products I like to go like supernatural
way hemp is a great carrier oil as well
as some of the terpenoids not only in
cannabis but Detroit's in other
essential oils like linen loool is a
great carrier for the absorption of the
rest of the formula so that's how I get
it to be absorbed but my products aren't
necessarily they're not they're not
designed to be transdermal but they do
have a fairly deep level of penetration
I do want to make one point though as
far as for if it will cross the
blood-brain barrier pretty much
everything crosses the blood-brain
barrier and this is why it doesn't cause
intoxication you know when we smell
lavender that'll in elul gets into the
oxygen across the blood-brain barrier
and so it travels that way but as far as
our products the reason why it doesn't
cause intoxication is because there's
not enough of a level of that activated
THC to cross the blood-brain barrier in
a high enough concentration to cause
intoxication so it's not true that
things don't cross the blood-brain
barrier it is it's important that we
know that everything does it just
doesn't cross in a level that would
cause intoxication it sounds to me like
there's actually a whole bunch of
misinformation out there on just this
little sub part because you know I've
certainly been in the in the presence of
someone who was selling a topical and
and you know a truck driver would say
you know can I use this for pain relief
in my on my you know arm muffled and
and be sure i'm going to pass my my
urine analysis analysis at work and it
would seem that 22 real get your muscle
relaxation you're gonna have to break
through the derma and if that's the case
we actually don't know if they could
fail a drug test because the the science
hasn't been done the testing I actually
I don't think we know yet Shango I mean
there may be somebody that knows but I
had that information hasn't gotten to me
and I would certainly love to hear about
it if anybody has scientific evidence to
show one way or the other yeah people
people certainly have a lot of strong
opinions but I haven't oh yes yes well
the thing to think about it we barely
have any research at all on cannabis so
the topical application of cannabis is
going to be one of the last things that
really people put money behind to
research and I'm doing hoping to be
doing some you know some research on my
own but there's just so much to study so
so hopefully yeah well we got we got
money and slacks we got to start
somewhere yeah so so so uh you know I
can't help but imagine that women led
companies are just going to crush this
new Java market niche that you've
created you know women already lead much
of both the Hava industry as it is now
and also the newly forming cannabis
industry and now and now when you when
you put those together into cannabis
topical companies it just seems like
it's there's a lot of opportunity for
women in both sides of industry to work
together yeah I think so I mean I'm not
opposed to working with anybody and you
know I dude I just want to throw out
some props you know a couple of the
stronger brands here in Washington are
actually run by men and there's a great
company in Colorado that's uh that's run
by an amazing guy who used to work for
aveda but the women seemed to baton and
I'll tell you my the female perspective
is that great manufacturers here Megan
Co screens love her that's my sister
doing a great job with Java but the
great thing is also the buyers most of
those buyers tend to be female in these
grocery stores and
you know and there tend to be the people
that actually buy the products and give
them to their partners or you know what
i mean so it's not just about the
manufacturers it's about who is actually
buying these and who is you-know-who
who's going to really push the market
forward and in depth those buyers and
then down to the consumers the consumers
they're the ones spending the money the
women are what the I forget what the
statistic is but they spend sixty five
percent or something of the household
money so it will be female driven it you
know it's a lot roundabout way of
confirming that question I love it I
love the women in our community you know
it's an amazing camaraderie so you know
I know that a lot of what we've talked
about today has been about this
revolutionary law and how it could be a
model for other states but I also know
that you are an expert product developer
and you know and you're a mover and
shaker when it comes to your product
lines so so what's coming up for
cannabis basics what are you seeing the
future for your company well we're super
excited now that we we just got all our
new display boxes so we literally we
look seriously legit on a grocery store
shelf now so that's pretty exciting and
that you know the distribution company
is just getting ready to go full force
on that right now in the next six months
we're all about community outreach so
we're doing a lot of fairs and festivals
we're doing pride we're doing you know
of course we respond sir hempfest every
year we're doing uncorked in kirkland
you know we're really just trying to get
out there and let the brand be seen by
people that aren't in the cannabis
community it's about the mainstreaming
of kent chava right now for us and then
as far as you know there's a fascinating
new you know four years ago when i was
thinking about these products i was
thinking about the whole avon and mary
kay kind of situation and you know I'm
not really crazy about the pyramid
markings marketing scheme but i have
found in the last couple weeks that
there's been a really huge influx of
retired aged women that still have a
business license and they're finding us
and
they want to be reps for my company and
I just had this vision of this army of
retired women having parties and selling
chava to you know and word of mouth we
all know that that's the best
advertising ever you know so that's a
brand new kind of marketplace that I
really wasn't focused on until just this
last couple months you know so as far as
selling the product it's you know
there's so many different avenues one of
the things about cannabis is that is
that it is so effective that mostly you
just have to tell focus folks is
available and they're suddenly
interested oh oh and it's cool that's
the other thing it's got a cool factor
not only is it helping people with their
aches and pains and skin issues and all
that good stuff but but these people
want to be connected to this hip thing
right now like we're all of a sudden
kind of trending you know so that's
amazing the last one thing I want to say
about the future of cannabis basics is
that we're actually looking for property
right now I think I mentioned this to
you we're building a whole complex with
a manufacturing facility and going to be
doing hemp research you know growing
hemp and processing hemp seed because
we're now it's legal to grow in
Washington state as of this year this is
they're rolling out the industrial hemp
research program so we're looking for
property right now to kind of build that
dream it'll have a museum aspect to it
they'll be classes there'll be a little
Event Center some overnight stay
hempcrete cabins so the vision is very
big but it's very bright as well that
sounds fantastic thank you so much for
taking some time for being to be on the
show with me today ah oh thanks for
having me it's always a pleasure Shango
if you would like to find out more about
all warner and cannabis basics please
visit their website at cannabis basics
com you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shaping fire calm and on
Apple iTunes stitcher and Google Play if
you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you'd leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download your review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where i'll be
speaking you can check out Shango
lowes.com does your company want to
reach our national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hot spot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host Shango lowes
[Music]