[Music]
for decades it's been the habit of most
cannabis growers to dedicate themselves
to using several bottles of various
synthetic nutrients to grow their plants
what we've seen in the last few years
though is a revival of natural growing
techniques that focus on building
healthy soil which in turn grows
thriving plants instead of dumping raw
chemicals into the soil and demanding it
grow true gardeners are learning to work
in cooperation with the soil and its
inhabitants to create the healthiest
environment possible for their plans to
live these natural cannabis growers work
with the soils microbe communities fungi
and organic food web to strike a balance
where they no longer need to add raw
nutrients at all because the soil itself
contains everything the plant needs to
thrive naturally if you enjoy hearing
frank discussions that dive deep into
cannabis health business and technique I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter every week you'll receive a
new podcast episode delivered right to
your inbox along with commentary on a
couple of the most important news items
from the week and videos - don't rely on
social media to let you know when a new
episode is published sign up for the
updates - make sure you don't miss an
episode you are listening to shaping
fire and I am your host Shango lows my
guest today is Jeff lowenfeld Jeff is
author of the award-winning trilogy of
books titled teaming with microbes the
organic gardeners guide to the soil food
web teeming with nutrients the organic
gardeners guide to optimizing plant
nutrition and teaming with fungi the
organic growers guide to my coryza
Jeff writes the longest-running
gardening column in the u.s. running 41
years now for the Alaska dispatch he's
also a lawyer and former TV and radio
show host I was fortunate to have the
opportunity here Jeff speak at the 2016
Emerald cup in Sonoma California he is
an incredibly lively speaker and he kept
the room laughing with fallacious jokes
about fungi in the food web I knew I had
to ask him to come on this show and he
was kind enough to accept the invitation
welcome to the show Jeff host my
pleasure to be here so Jeff when I was a
kid the folks on my block would would
actually cook their soil in old coffee
containers on the grill to make
it was good and dead before adding their
store-bought inputs and potting up their
plants but now though the idea of
creating a living soil community to
nourish the plants instead of just
adding nitrogen phosphorus and potassium
is really taking over and for many
growers the idea of creating a
self-sustaining soil system instead of
just pouring in more fertilizers is a
huge jump in their thinking how do you
like to describe living soil in a way
that makes sense to folks who are new to
thinking about it this way great
question
and it takes me back to my father's
sterilizer he has the biggest compost
pile literally in the town I mean this
was almost half an acre of compost and
and he would then take that compost and
put it into a sterilizer Wow I remember
how bad it smelled so let's start right
there I think he could you could sort of
say that you know living living soil is
all that smell that occurs when you
sterilize soil and and so I would start
right there obviously soil is is not
what it used to be we used to think it
was just this inert substance that was
there to hold plants and on which you
could put fertilizer and you know which
allowed water to drain through we now
know that that's absolutely not true
it's organic matter its minerals from
rocks that have broken down over the
eons and it is a tremendous amount of
living organisms which require oxygen
and water in order to be able to live so
it's it's completely different than what
it was when you and I were were younger
yeah absolutely my actually my dad did
that same thing with with taking his
soil and sterilizing it and and nowadays
when we think about living soil it's
much more of a instead of considering it
in an inert thing it's it's more about a
neighborhood we're trying to create a
neighborhood of good neighbors that'll
that'll you know be a nice buffet for
the plant instead of essentially being
dead and therefore needing to rely on us
for everything well I think what we're
really trying to set
yeah you're right we're trying to set up
a neighborhood and so if you've got a
good a good soil situation what you got
is a condominium that's operating
properly so it's a it's a perfectly
constructed condominium never needs any
repairs it's got all of the inhabitants
that you'd want to have in a condominium
so that everybody has fun and they can
you know help each other out and they
don't irritate each other too much and
they take care of the bad guys when they
appear and and it's fully stocked with
great food so everybody has a great time
in that condominium you're absolutely
right it's you know it's a neighborhood
it's a condominium of you know that just
hums and it really is the soil food web
concept that's taking over I think you
know how we're looking at not just how
we grow cannabis but it's how we grow
food it's how we what we eat it's how we
eat it's why we eat the comparison
between the stomach and how it operates
I should say the stomach with the
intestines and how it operates you know
versus you know the the soil food web
mean at all is everything ties together
it's a beautiful beautiful system so
because there are so many ways to coax a
biologically active community along in
the soil what do you see is a good place
for a beginner to start well I think
compost is always the best place to
start yeah you know compost contains in
it all of the organisms that you'd
really want to have just to hold the the
foods that the plants eat and or that
yeah well I guess that's the proper term
and in all of the organisms that eat
those organisms and poop out that food
so that it's available in plant usable
form so it's got all of the fungi and
the bacteria which are at the bottom of
the soil food web and then it's got the
nematodes and protozoa in phenomenal
numbers and that that cycle the
nutrients so that so that compost
becomes usable for the plants and and
you know compost is just the easiest
thing to get your hands on it's easy to
make it's it's easy to buy course
by lousy compost but it's also easy to
buy good compost and it's easy to make
so I would start right there that's
that's that's the be all beginning so so
when people have you know found their
way to either a good source to buy their
compost or they've done a little
homework and they've figured out how to
make compost at home most folks tend to
move on from that to nutrient teas and
and we're huge fans of nutrient teas
you're exchanging fire one of your what
are some of your favorite wild crafted
nutrient teas for encouraging probiotic
growth in the soil well again I mean
let's think you're thinking in terms of
the beginner I mean you take that
compost your rises once you have that
compost then you learn that you can do
designer things with it you can make
more fungally dominated compost or more
bacterial dominated compost for cannabis
you want that clearly dominated compost
and and for all sorts of reasons you
could make teas out of that compost and
you can make fungally dominated teas or
more fungally dominated teas and and
that clearly dominated teas which you
can use as soil drenches and which you
can then spray also on the leaves where
the microbes that are in that compost
tea out-compete the bacteria that well
actually yeah the bacteria in the fungi
and the bit and the nemetes the bad guys
that might be on those leaves or might
get on those leaves so if you spray good
stuff on them there's no room for the
bad guys there's no food left of the bad
guys there's no entry ways for the bad
guys so compost he definitely something
that people want to get into the
intermediate step would be a compost
extracts you don't need a brewer you
don't need a tremendous amount of time
in 15 minutes you can you can take
compost wrap wrap it up and in
cheesecloth and this just need it in a
in a you know a couple of gallons of
water then you've got you've got an
extract of a lot of those microbes they
haven't multiplied themselves but you
pull them out of the compost and then
the next step of course is the compost
teas which require a brewer it's often
called fermentation because you're
brewing the tea you're taking energy and
you're pulling out the bacteria and the
fungi and the nematode
the protozoa and you're then feeding
them and causing them to either grow or
to multiply or to change their ratios
during a 24 to 48 hour period and that
that to many people is sort of the
ultimate way of adding biology I would
have said so when I wrote teaming with
microbes
the first edition back in 2006 I'm
beginning to think that it is certainly
important but that there are other
things that you can do namely
mycorrhizal fungi which which can be
added of course we already know about
adding nitrogen fixing bacteria to the
proper plants so so I think I think
compost tea is a large part of a bigger
picture so when you were talking about
the nutrient teas you were talking about
a fungally dominant one and and then or
bacteria lead um or or bacteria lead um
and and um you know a lot of people who
have not gotten to the point yet where
they're prepared for a Brewer either
they don't quite have the budget yet or
they're just you know on their learning
path and they're just not there yet um
they'll be probably be using more the
the second version that you suggested
which is simply take your compost and
put it in some in some cheesecloth and
squeeze it in grab you a five-gallon
bucket of water that has had the you
know chlorine vaped off of it or
whatever and then there's and use that
to to water your plants and that's great
but some folks still would like to be
able to get that fungal e dominant tea
effect can you suggest a way that we can
perhaps inoculate our compost pile so
there's going to be more mycelium there
for when we do this this squeeze the
cheesecloth approach sure well well what
happens of course is that if you add
more Brown material to your compost pile
particularly once you've got that
compost cooking and really going you're
breaking down more more materials which
which are likely to feed the fungi so
you can start there you can take the the
material that you can be using either
for your tea or for your compost extra
which is that second method and you can
inoculate it with foods that will grow
the fungi and then you take that
material and you use it to make your tea
or your extract and in that particular
instance you can use a baby oatmeal you
know ground-up barley but baby oatmeal
is probably the easiest thing to get
your hands on and you just simply you
mix it in so that you can see the flakes
and then you keep it in a dark warm area
for 24 48 hours and the fungal hyphae
will grow and multiply and form mycelium
and then you can use that block because
it will become a block for your compost
here your compost extract that will be
more fungally dominated or you can and I
should say you can use fungal foods in
your compost tea not in the abstract
because they're not there long enough to
be able to grow in a compost tea the
bacteria will start to multiply in the
first 15 20 minutes fungus will grow but
they really will multiply for 24 48
hours probably more like 48 hours and
really what they're doing is growing
them in a compost tea so you want to use
foods that will feed them
turns out molasses will actually feed
compost tea a fungus as well as bacteria
just don't use too much you'll get a lot
of bacteria if you use too much the fish
hydrolysates will will also feed the
fungi and some people use green sand in
their compost tea as a substrate to try
to feed fungi so yeah what you really
want to make however for cannabis is a
bacterial dominated tea so you really
don't even have to worry too much about
this stuff well then let's add just that
begs the question right so if that was a
how to make a fungally dominant how
would we flip to the other side and make
it more bacteria lead um well remember I
said they multiply within 20 you know
within 15 minutes if you do nothing to
the tea but just you know aerator for 24
hours days it's going to be multiplying
because they'll be living off the
organic material but if you add molasses
they will go nuts and
you know of course it's got to be non
sulfur and mil they'll multiply like
crazy a lot of people will throw a
little bit of alfalfa in their compost
teas the last the last couple hours
because there's they're covered with
protozoa and they'll multiply and so
you'll get a nice little mix that
recycles itself or cycles the nutrients
throughout so you know it's a pretty
interesting system and above and beyond
everything else whatever kind of tea you
make it's ultimately up to the plant to
adjust its extracts to be able to
attract what it needs so the plant will
adjust things to make it work right on
so to kind of to summarize that for
folks who are new to this idea and it
isn't just fitting in immediately you
start by taking some of your finished
compost wrapping it in a cheesecloth
squeezing it into a five-gallon bucket
of water just sort of want to do this
kind of kneading it for 15 minutes you
know you rack it up and you just need
that cheesecloth for 15 minutes just I
can make some sound effects you know and
you squeeze these things up because let
me let me just back up for a second just
to make sure for people who really don't
know what we're talking about that and
it's all outlined in the first book
teeming with microbes which by by the
way everybody should get and if you get
it and don't like it I'll buy it back at
three times the price I guarantee you're
going to you're going to get a lot of
use out of it but the bottom line is
what's happening is the plants are
putting out chemicals through their root
system that attract the bacteria and the
fungi and they eat the stuff that the
plants putting out because it's got a
lot of carbons in it they in turn
attract nematodes and protozoa who eat
them they poop the excess it's got a lot
of nutrients in it particularly nitrogen
which feeds the plant that's all
happening right there in the root zone
the plant can change those extra dates
to attract what it needs so you know if
it's if you put down something and it's
something in there the plant wants it'll
change the extra date to attract what it
needs the plant is in control not you
but again so so you you you you need the
stuff for 15 minutes you if you pull out
the nematodes on the protozoa in the
bacteria and and and the bacteria and
the
in the fungi makes soil structure and so
that's why you've got to use the energy
of your hands to make the compost
extract or the energy from a pump to
make compost tea because these things
are sticky and they they bind together
it's like the bacteria on your teeth you
don't just swish your teeth out in the
morning with water you brush them with a
lot of energy to get rid of that
bacterial slime and that's what you have
to do to the particle of soil to break
off that bacteria and and and and to
strip out that fungi so you use energy
and you make this super these T's and
then you and then you use them on your
your system and so the you know I tend
to use a what you call an aquarium pump
of that act both aerates the tea but
then also provides the energy to break
it up
do you find that that that works good
for you as well no because I think
unless it's a gigantic aquarium like the
size of the you know the monterey
aquarium I think the pumps probably too
small you know in the beginning we used
to use those aquarium pump a lot of
research was done by dr. Laningham who
was certainly the goddess of all of this
stuff and anytime you get a chance to go
hear dr. Elaine or read anything she's
written she's you know well what can I
say I mean we bow at her feet but yeah
those pumps don't don't provide the six
or seven parts per million air that you
really need and so you really got it you
really got to step up the air if you
want to make it really work so write out
great I'm glad I have that glycogen you
shouldn't use those aquarium stones
either because those stones when you
turn the pump off fill up with water and
it's got the bacterial slime in it it
forms and grows in those little little
holes and they're impossible to clean
and then you get bad situations so you
just you know just bubble sure sure yeah
so after after folks have gotten into
you know nutrient and compost teas a lot
of folks really enjoy moving on to
fermentations and labs and such what are
your favorite fermentations for thriving
soil well you know I don't
I'm not really into them in a big way
you're talking about eeehm and yeah
exactly yeah you know to me if you're
using compost tea you're getting what
you need
eeehm is it certainly works that means
people tell me it works I don't use it
other than making Bo Kashi in the
wintertime because it's a great way to
so that make compost in a cold climate
in the winter without getting smells
when your piles not working obviously
but but it's got you know six six 15 16
different microbes in it compost tea is
35 thousand different microbes and you
know there's a world of difference and I
think the diversity makes sense when you
when you believe that the it's the plant
that's choosing what it needs going to
give it as much opportunity to choose
what it what it really needs so I like
the diversity of compost tea over these
ferments but but I'm certainly not
discouraging of them I think all of them
do one thing that that's important and
that was sort of outlined in the second
book teeming with nutrients which don't
guarantee cuz I think it's a much more
difficult book to get to but I think
it's an important book and that is the
law of return and we we violate the law
of return when we deal with soils
because we harvest things from that soil
that stuff's supposed to fall down and
be decade and go back in and feed the
plant again and feed the soil again and
feed the microbes again we harvest it so
you know we're taking stuff away and
when you put these ferments in you're
adding a lot of some of the stuff that
you've taken away you're you're you're
helping to rebalance the Law of Return
right that makes it yeah yeah I follow
you right so we're going to take our
first short break and be right back you
are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is organic gardener and
author Jeff Lowen tells if you grow
cannabis with sunshine you can often
feel limited by the seasonal cycle you
want to grow sustainably and save money
so you use as little electricity as
possible but if you haven't studied or
implemented light deprivation techniques
into your greenhouse you're leaving a
lot of money on the table by
incorporating light deprivation
solutions into your greenhouse you can
often add two or three additional
growing cycles to your year when you
pencil out the financial benefit of
those additional size
you'll realize why commercial-scale
light deprivation technology is remaking
the cannabis industry what used to be
done by pulling tarps over hoop houses
has been scaled up over the last few
years in such a way that has become
mechanized easy and affordable to even
small-scale commercial cannabis
operations forever flowering greenhouses
is the industry leader in light
deprivation greenhouse design and
operation for the commercial cannabis
industry their team of greenhouse
experts have been in the fields of
Northern California for decades and
they're now building greenhouses for
commercial cannabis companies across the
country if you are new to light deep and
growing in greenhouses I encourage you
to go back to shaping fire episode 13
with guest Eric Branstad of Forever
flowering I talked with Eric about the
importance of intelligent greenhouse
management as well as the huge financial
benefit of incorporating light depth
techniques there are so many aspects of
utilizing a greenhouse that can go wrong
from temperature and airflow to light
depth and workflow forever flowering
will help you produce crop after crop of
well-cared-for flowers they can help you
retrofit your existing greenhouse with
light depth and other modern systems at
a level that fits your budget if you're
just starting out forever flowering can
help you plan and build your new
greenhouse so that you get started on
the right foot the candidates business
has enough risks without trying to go it
alone with your greenhouse contact
forever flowering greenhouses to partner
with folks who have an indisputable
reputation as knowledgeable and easy to
work with go to shaping feiyr.com
forward slash FFG to find out more now
that the health benefits of terpenes
have become well known in the cannabis
industry people everywhere are looking
for the purest terpenes without
adulterants the problem with most
chirping providers is that they're not
sourced naturally and instead are made
as a byproduct of refining petroleum and
that's so sketchy the terpenes sold by
true terpenes are entirely different
they are certified organic non-gmo and
food grade that means that they are
extracted from real plant sources there
are no solvents of any kind they are
distilled only with steam that's right
only steam in fact terpenes from true
turbines are so pure that you can eat
them not only that but you can stack
them with better results - what I mean
is other company's turbines have
a few percent of impurities and when you
stack those terpenes to make your blend
you're adding a variety of impurities
that degrade your final product true
terpenes also have strain-specific
terpenes for a wide range of canada
strains like Durbin poison sunset
sherbet and granddaddy purple true
terpenes has robust and supportive
customer service so your questions will
get answered fast and efficiently if you
shop for tips before you know how rare
that is so whether you want to cup your
hands to smell some betta carry off lean
to calm down after getting too high or
if you want to dab some pining so your
lungs feel fabulous and your mind feels
liberated true terpenes will provide you
with a truly natural experience if you
are a cannabis product developer these
are the Terps you want to add to your
oil or edible or capsule or whatever
true terpenes are simply the best your
money can buy don't try and make a
premium product with substandard terms
choose true terpenes for a top-shelf
experience go to shaping fire calm board
flash true turbines to find out more or
click on the link in this leaf
newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I'm your host
Shengo Lowe's and I guess this week is
organic gardener and author Jeff
lowenfeld so Jeff you know often with
crossover gardeners coming from foods
and ornamentals over to cannabis they
don't know too much about cannabis
sativa but you know from hearing you
today and more especially listening to
your 2017 emerald-cut presentation you
definitely seem familiar with growing it
where did you learn about growing
cannabis Qi where did I learn about
growing cannabis um I'm trying to think
I was I guess I was in college so back
in the oh my god it was a long time ago
um maybe I was in law school when I grew
my first plant but I've always grown
things and cannabis is you know and I
tell people aside for those who don't
don't know on this broadcast I write a
garden column I've been writing one for
oh my god forty some odd years for the
Anchorage newspaper in Alaska and and uh
you know I write about cannabis now
because is legal here and I tell people
it's just a plain
so it doesn't take any real special
skills to grow I think the biggest
problem that I am beginning to notice
with growing cannabis is that there are
too many myths that people follow
without thinking about what they're
doing and why those myths may might have
developed and why they might might be
myths and and therefore not fact but I
started way back when back in the I
guess back in the late 60s growing
cannabis first in my apartment in Boston
then I moved to Alaska I remember having
a couple of cannabis plants here it was
legal because our Supreme Court back in
1975 came out with a conclusion that our
Constitution allows you to grow cannabis
privacy of your home and so I had some
cannabis plants growing on my property
and I remember my father coming up to
visit and wandering around saying gee
what is that plant and he was he was the
guy that taught me all the stuff I knew
about growing plants although he had
never seen a cannabis plant so I've been
growing it for a long time it's been
legal here in Alaska as I said since
1975 and therefore I've had a lot of you
know opportunity to practice without
having to worry about the law coming
down on my head yeah that makes a lot of
sense it must be really exciting for you
you know with your relationship with the
plant going so far back and now suddenly
people asking you more questions about
cannabis instead of you know the more
traditional gardening topics that you
might get through your column it must be
interesting and exciting for you to be
able to you know talk more about this
plant that you love now that it's it you
know it's being normalized across the
rest of the country yeah I mean for the
most interesting thing is first of all
that my both of my publishers timber
press which has published all three of
my books you know said this books got to
have cannabis in it Wow have they said
that to me in 2006 teeming with microbes
would have been all about cannabis but
my publisher in my newspaper also has
said gee we in your column we'd like you
to address cannabis what
a lock you know I don't have to disguise
it as a tomato planned anymore it's
really quite a change so that's that's
that's interesting
the excitement is that cannabis growers
as you know are some of the finest
growers in the world I mean they
I shouldn't say growers finest gardeners
in the world and and so the opportunity
to be able to kick around questions and
and things about cannabis and to learn
things from from them is exciting and
finally you know speaking of tomatoes in
Landers if she was a garden columnist
would have said how many times can you
repeat a tomato column to get something
new to be able to write about and
something with so much to write about
Wow it's fabulous and I am convinced on
a gardening side that cannabis is the
next tomato plant you know the tomato
has always been the holy grail of the
home gardener to grow a beautiful tomato
you know and I and I think now we're
going to see cannabis replacing the
tomato as the holy grail plant oh that
sounds like such a beautiful vision
right there well in fact it's not even a
vision I can tell you that three of us
are going to be speaking at the Garden
Writers Association's conference the
National Conference on cannabis i'm
going to be speaking about how you write
about it
you know for a generalized public we've
got a gentleman is going to be speaking
about the breeding efforts that are
going on so that it's available as a as
a you know outdoor six pack plant a
gentleman who is very very heavily
involved in in micro propagation and
then the third part of the speaker is
going to be somebody who's going to be
pointing out you know some of the
stupidity that people have bought into
that has resulted in the stigma that
makes it difficult to write about this
stuff so it's going to be very
interesting the first time ever this
national organizations had a
conversation about a plant that I'm
virtually certain three-quarters of them
use you know on a weekly basis it's so
nice to see
you know we're essentially priming the
pump of the next generation of educators
to reach out to even more people you
know I spend a lot of time speaking with
with doctors and naturopaths and other
caregivers about how to work with
patients and their endocannabinoid
system and so I'm creating new educators
similarly with the event that you've
just described you are educating
gardening writers how to then reach out
to their following and teach them how to
grow cannabis and this is how you know
these are force multipliers of education
call absolutely I mean in once trust P
once the garden writers start writing
about it we reach and we say garden
writers but these are the folks that do
television shows and you know podcasts
and radio shows newspaper columns and
magazine columns and books once they
start writing about cannabis on a
regular basis the same way they write
about Tomatoes it's over folks I don't
care whether it's Jeff Sessions uh you
know his mother or his grandmother it's
over because it's just a plant folks
it's just a plant well that could be a
good book title I really enjoy seeing
all the people who have not ever really
kept a garden before suddenly decide
they want to start growing food because
they've had such a good experience
growing their first couple cannabis
plants and then realizing that that more
than anything cannabis is actually a
gateway to gardening absolutely yeah I
mean you know it's an easy plant to grow
yeah I mean I'll admit to grow to grow
really great cannabis takes a little bit
of skill but but once once you grow a
nice cannabis plant you say whoa wait a
second you know I could I can grow
anything and you can cannabis is a fun
plant to grow they're a couple little
tricks but once you once you nail those
down man what a fun plant to grow right
so let's get back into the garden so you
know gardeners use a lot of nutrients as
we were talking about in the first set
what do you see is a good model of
recycling these nutrients back into the
ecosystem in a sustainable way after you
harvest hmm a good model
cycling well I think what you're really
describing is sort of regenerative
gardening and if I understand your
question properly there are a number of
things that I do to try to again it all
goes back to this law of return that I
that I try to do in order to balance the
fact that I've broken the law of return
so I guess do my time this property so
first of all I reuse my soils I know a
lot of people fill their soils out at a
minimum put the soils in the compost
pile let them compost for a season or
two and then reuse them after that but I
reuse my soil right away I don't disturb
the roots that are in the soil I let
that organic matter become available to
the microbes and therefore the soil
system itself during during the growth
of the next plant I let that root system
act as a guide way for the new roots of
the plants that I plant in there and I
let the mycorrhizal network which I know
has developed in that pot or in that
garden bed remain undisturbed so that it
going out to get goodies which which
which I'm adding into the garden or into
the pot by a using soluble organics and
be putting compost in organics on the
surface any leaves that come off the
plant on the surface any sticks and
stems either go into the compost pile
that then goes on the plant or go right
on the surface of the plant and I always
always have mulch
whenever I'm growing cannabis so it
actually sounds like you're sounds like
you're that's a no-till technique really
I like but in a container and you know
my next question was actually going to
wrap into this I was going to ask you if
you think's it may think it makes more
sense to no-till and simply replant in
the same pot using fresh top amendments
that will get watered in or you more a
fan of emptying the pots in the pile and
and amending the whole pile but it
sounds like you're of the mind that no
just just pop out the the top of the
root system of the prior plant and then
just put your new start right on in that
same hole yeah I don't think you can do
it forever while you probably can't do
it forever you got to keep an eye on
what's going on but it's true
worth people experimenting and trying
you know the other system works as well
don't get me wrong but butchy you've
done a lot of work for that book let's
take a male plant for example people
just throw them out wait a second that
male plant has been throwing out the
extra dates that a cannabis plant throws
out into the soil wait why would you get
rid of that you know it's full of these
wonderful delicious extra dates as
Elaine says cook cooking candies and
stuff that these microbes love you never
throw it out just because it's a male
plant no no no no you cut off the
flowers you know you compost the rest do
you keep that soil and you plant right
in there's good bingo you got all the
extra days you need right away to start
with Wow
no it's it's just to me it just makes
logical sense but I've written three
books on the subject so earlier you were
talking about Bokashi and Bokashi really
seems to be taking over and for those
who don't know it's a fermented
inoculated fermented bran I guess and
and do you have any tips or insight that
you'd like to offer on making or using
it because you know you've probably come
across them over the days well you know
it's supposed to be a proprietary makes
you supposed to buy it only from people
who've got licenses to Center etc but if
you go on the internet and I won't do it
for you but you can certainly use Google
which is the cannabis growers finest
tool you can you can find all sorts of
recipes to make your own it's not hard
it's very very easy to do so and you can
use some of your old Bokashi to sort of
you know inoculate the stuff that you've
used but again to me compost is much
better than just the newsing and I can't
figure out why it's taking over right on
you know sometimes you can we came on
coming back to compost tea and it makes
me think that sometimes you know people
like to get more complex just for the
complexity sake because they're active
learners and they're curious and they
want to do more and more stuff but since
we keep on circling back would you say
that you know the using a quality
compost tea is you know I mean the air
quotes this but all you need that like
really keep it simple and if you use the
compost tea you're going to
get where you want to go and if you want
to learn this extra stuff by all means
do it for your own enjoyment
but really it's it's you're adding icing
on an already done cake well it depends
on what you're growing in I mean if
you've got phenomenal soil like we have
here in Alaska you know yeah a compost
tea is all you need our soil is full of
volcanic ash it's got all the minerals
you'd ever want cetera et cetera et
cetera I you know I understand and I
believe that it is possible to grow
plants without ever adding anything
other than the microbes no question in
my mind but that takes longer than you
want to wait perhaps you know you've got
a season you don't want to wait three
seasons you've got a business it cetera
et cetera and so adding stuff is not bad
and using just compost tea can certainly
work if you've got the right soils but
it each to his own so you've got to do
some testing now I am I am a big
believer in banding organics underneath
plants when I put them in that doesn't
mean I rototill when you put in a seed
or you put in a transplant you make up
whole for it well you can put a little
fertilizer in down at the bottom and a
whole you can make the whole little
deeper you know I'm saying you don't
have to further you don't have to
rototill the whole area to destroy it
and still be able to apply fertilizers
or what I call microbe food so and
certainly by all means you can use
solubles and and and certainly by all
means you would want to use mulches and
compost site includes one of those
mulches what is that term you use this
new to me
banding organic well if you if you take
a look at my second book which is called
what is my second book called oh yeah
it's kind of nutrient oh my god so yeah
your eye if I may just digress for a
second I wonder right this second book
why cuz I had nothing else to do I guess
no I because I was curious about how
plants ate and so I thought it was going
to be teeming with nutrients how plants
eat of an organic gardeners guide you
know thinking you know how teeming with
nutrients organic gardeners guide to
optimizing plant nutrition what the hell
is that anyway
you know you learn how plants eat what
they take in and one of the methods of
course well there's three ways plants
get their food you want is by flow in
other words there it's in water its
soluble and then it goes into the root
system by mass flow the other is by you
know osmosis diffusion which you know
you struggle through in tenth grade and
then you've got mycorrhizal mycorrhizal
fungi the osmanthus diffuses you know
that's really sort of when you've got
direct contact and then you've got
mycorrhizal fungi that go out into
little pores and bring food back and I
forgot exactly what you were asking me
about but I was just asking you to
define the banding organic yeah yeah
yeah so when you band below where you're
planting and and by bending you just put
a little flat area in there and you just
put your fertilizer right down there or
you might call it microbe food maybe a
little soil on top of it then you put
your transplant or your seed so that the
roots grow out into that band I see okay
now I understand so essentially you're
creating a preset buffet of nutrients
and and then the the roots are growing
you know aspiring for nutrients and then
they grow down and then they hit that
band and then they're there waiting for
them well the band is there they've
already diploma SHhhh but you know
what's what's what's in that little zone
as they're growing the mycorrhizal fungi
which you've also inoculated your season
your roots with are growing and are
going out into that band and bringing
that food back quicker you know it's all
part but it but there's that little bit
of food in there that you could add so
you know when you break that law of
return by removing the cannabis plant
then if you're going to use the same
soil you've got to return the nutrients
that would have decayed had you not
remove that plant as I say in my talks
whoever fertilizes the Redwoods how do
they get that dig nobody ever puts
fertilizer down there nobody puts
Miracle go down there nobody use general
hydroponic crap no
uh had that happened if it's this thing
it's the law of return wasn't ignored
wasn't broken all that stuff fell down
and decayed fascinating innit
so anyway so yeah so the fact but the
but do go back so the second book
teeming with nutrients which people
should read and struggle because it's
important to know no it's got some
chemistry in it and I apologize but it's
got the least amount of chemistry I
could put in it I promised myself I
would never ever talk about the krebs
cycle and so it's no krebs cycle in it
whatsoever I don't even think I have the
formula for photosynthesis and it's
people know not to panic it's got sort
of a a picture of how you would band as
well as the description to some of the
things you might use in order in order
to to make that band when I saw you in
December it the Emerald cup I'm going to
paraphrase this poorly but you'll know
where I'm going and you can take it from
there
you were you were you were talking about
some of the topics from your teaming
with fungi book and and you were talking
about that you recommend it for cannabis
folks to to roll their seeds in a
particular fungus add to to support them
as soon as they pop and and I was I was
taking as many notes as I can but I
missed which which which my coryza it
was and what your actual strategy was
and it was fascinating so so with that
set up will you just kind of deliver
that that little nugget to everybody
well you put me in a real but you put me
in a very difficult position so you so
let me back up for a second all right
all right so I've got these three I got
a trilogy of books right which I'm
supposed to sell let's say I make my
living right and the last book is
teeming with so I call myself Lord of
the routes incidentally because I have
this trilogy bump-bump
so my last book is teeming with with fun
funky people should I buy it and find
where that one is in the book rather but
myself I always go so fast when I talk
so that people can't write it down so
they will go out and buy the book but I
know everybody's going to go out and buy
the book anyway so I'm going to I'll
talk about it but
quickly go back a little bit and talk
about these micro raschel fungi 90 to 6%
of the plants on the planet Earth have
them this is the reason why plants were
able to colonize terra firma 400 million
years ago and 200 million years ago a
second type developed and this second
type of mycorrhizal fungi does exactly
what the first one does only in a
slightly different fashion and that is
in return for these extra dates which we
talked about at the beginning in the
program these guys take the extra dates
from the plant by literally taking you
from the plant they're inside the plant
living inside the plant and the other
end of them are outside the plant and in
return for those extra dates they go out
and get all sorts of nutrients which
they then transfer to the plant and if
they don't transfer them to the plant
then the plant doesn't give them the
extra dates so this is a very symbiotic
relationship and they get nitrogen
phosphorus those two in particular but
copper and zinc and a couple of the m's
which always I always forget this group
right out of mine manganese and anyway
they go out and get all these terrific
things that the plant can't get itself
and so they feed the plant so they're
very very important and we know of about
360 different kinds we know that we can
only grow about 15 of them and if you
buy a package of what's called Mike
arisal fungi even though it may say
mycorrhizae it's really called
mycorrhizal fungi mycorrhizae is the
symbiotic relationship that forms and it
always includes a root so that's not the
right term for what's in the package you
get mycorrhizal fungi you'll see that
there are about eight or nine of them
listed on that package only one of them
happens to associate and form that
relationship with cannabis
and this particular one forms that
association with cannabis sativa indica
Rudy Alice it doesn't matter whether
it's Durban poison Jack Herrera you know
whether it's teeming with microbes no
there is no one call teeming with
microbes ignorant it doesn't matter what
it is there's only one that feeds these
guys and it is called so get the pens
and paper out oh wait a minute here's a
problem when I first started writing the
book it was called Glomus mossy mo sSAE
a or AIDS in the U on the Latin mossy
dry ropes GL o ma Glomus unfortunately
or fortunately I guess over the two or
three years three years it took me to
write the book the genetics of these
individual mycorrhizal fungi became
important enough to know that they began
to study them and they have now
reassigned the names of all of them my
poor editor had to go back through the
book and rewrite all of these Latin e
that's why we've got second editions
easy to write a second edition people
don't understand just as an aside a
second edition they say okay if you can
take out six words you can put in six
words they're not that easy right they
don't just say is for you get you know
put in a new chapter no you got any way
I could go back the one that you want is
now called a rise of rise o faggus RHI
zo p h AG us rise o faggus inter intra
int RNA intra rossi DS RACI des razzle
faggus the capital r inter recede ease
with a small I but many
in the package you'll see it as Glomus
Massey or as Glomus interest CDs or Rago
faggus Massey so it's very confusing but
but you get the idea that's the one you
want
yeah you guys we've got our key search
terms now and you know that that should
get us there and and you know hopefully
everybody who's listening is is super
geeked about this now and you can find
links to the teaming with fungi book on
the shaping fire podcast on the episode
page for this interview and also you
know it's an easy thing to find on
Amazon if you haven't go there on your
own
so so so let's go ahead and take our
second break when we get back we're
going to take some questions from the
show audience how exciting you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is organic gardener and author
Jeff Lowenthal's we'll be right back
using pesticides when growing cannabis
has been common for a long time nowadays
though we know better we know that most
pesticides formulated for food crops
have never been tested for use with
cannabis they've been tested to be eaten
in tiny doses they have not been tested
to be inhaled and especially not
concentrated into a cannabis oil
chemical residues from pesticides are
not healthy for anyone but they are
especially dangerous for patients for
commercial cannabis growers this has
become very impactful cannabis
enthusiasts and patients have gotten
educated enough that they avoid growers
who used pesticides not only that but
states across the country have begun
making pesticide testing mandatory on
all licensed cannabis crops the time has
come to find a better way to fight
garden pests than covering your cannabis
and chemicals and there is a better way
let some good bugs fight your bad bugs
beneficial insects and predatory mites
have come a long way since we were
buying ladybugs online and putting them
in the grow room and just hoping for the
best natural enemies biocontrol
can help you solve pest issues without
using chemicals natural enemies founder
Shane Young learned best practices from
working in the ornamental plant industry
and has fine-tuned those strategies
civically for large cannabis crops shane
works with commercial cannabis clients
across the country to ensure that they
keep their crops safe and pest free
without the use of chemicals natural
enemies has proven solutions for spider
mites a feeds thrips Russert mites broad
mites shore flies white fly and others -
you can rely on natural enemies for
expertise and excellent service for more
information go to shaping feiyr.com
forward slash natural enemies or simply
click on their banner in this week's
newsletter if you like podcasts like
shaping fire chances are that you'll
like audiobooks too just like with
podcasts audiobooks speak to you tell
you stories and teaches stuff here's the
thing audible.com has an offer that I
want to tell you about right now they
are offering a trial of their audiobook
service for absolutely free you can go
to shaping fire com poured flash audible
and you'll get a free audiobook straight
up you can listen to it on your mobile
device computer or download it and
listen to it you know like anywhere it's
really simple of course they want you to
subscribe to their service after the
free trial and enjoy audiobooks forever
but you don't have to all you have to do
to get the free audiobook of your choice
is to just check out the service for
free and the service is pretty great
there are whole sections on permaculture
sci-fi history biography hell you can
even listen to a book about card
counting in blackjack whatever it's all
pretty rad so that's the deal your first
book is free it's easy to sign up it's
easy to quit and their online library of
free ebooks is pretty incredible
so just check it out go to shaping fire
com forward slash audible to find out
more or just click on the link in this
week's newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I am your host
Shengo Louis and our guest this week is
organic gardener and author Jeff Lowen
sells so during this last set we're
going to take some questions from the
the shaping fire audience that I asked
for a couple weeks ago since I knew that
you're going to be on the show and the
first question is from Mike West and and
Mike asks since most of the plants
cannabinoids are created by NZ
maduk bio pathways but the precursors
are provided by symbiotic relationships
would Jeff please describe the
microbiology biosynthesis of terpenes
and cannabinoids in the roots as well as
foliar biomass so so what do you have
for that there Jeff oh yeah well you
know now she just felt might should read
my second book teeming with nutrients
because it really sort of discusses that
in a in a much simpler way what I think
he's saying is listen all of these
things are built inside the plant but
they're there they're created using the
enzymes inside the plant the enzyme
factories make all of the things that
are inside a plant I'll go back and
discuss that in a quick second but but
all of the enzymes are taking goods that
come from the soil through a biological
pathway ie and the microbes mineralize
it and didn't make it available to the
plant and the mycorrhizae fungi go out
and get it bring it to the plant and you
know it's kind of an interesting it can
get converted inside the plant from one
sort of energy outside the plant to
another kind of inside the plant so let
me just back up for a second and say
that the second book and one of the
reasons why people find it a little bit
complicated talks about how plants eat
and you can't talk about how plants eat
unless you talk about cellular biology
the first book is microbiology
microbiology is a lot of fun because we
studied in high school and you know we
know paramecium's and amoebas and all
that kind of stuff is kind of fun cuz
you know we you know we're bacteria
folks is a group and you know fungal
folds and so to study them and read
about them in the microbiology is fun on
the other hand cellular biology was
always a pain in the butt nobody really
liked it you couldn't see this stuff you
had these microscope microscopes even in
microscopes you couldn't see things you
had to use pictures in books everything
was two dimensions it wasn't fun today
on the other hand it is not only sort of
fun because we have electron microscopes
of now we know a lot more about what
happens inside the cell but as gardeners
and growers of cannabis there's a need
to know what goes on
in cellular biology so so what happens
in the soil is described in the first
book teeming with microbes and I you
know those three methods that I
described before are used to bring in
individual nutrients into the plant and
the nutrients enter the plant and there
are only 18 of them and they enter the
plant each through their own gateway and
their own gateway through each
individual cell in the plant and each
cannabis plant might have twenty
trillion individual cells each one of
them has a plasma membrane just inside
the cell wall and that plasma membrane
has these little tunnels and gateways
and each individual tunnel takes in only
one kind of nutrient molecule and each
one of those gateways is constructed by
the enzymes as is the plasma Dermott
which is that plasma membrane as is the
cell wall and as is every single thing
made inside the cell by using enzymes
and each individual cell has ten
thousand or more different kinds of
enzymes and at least a thousand of each
one of them in an individual cell in
which a cannabis plant or of which a
cannabis plant might have a twenty to
thirty trillion and these enzymes take
these individual 18 elements you can't
play cards with 18 cards but they're
able to convert these 18 elements into
every single thing you see in a plant
and therefore every single thing
basically you see in an animal because
that animal you may not be a vegetarian
but that animal you eat is and they're
eating plants which are made up of these
cells which have all these enzymes which
have made up every little piece it's
mind-boggling and so Mike should read
the second book
and and we're that question in mind
right I mean that's a great answer and
you know it's a really on point answer
too because you know you mentioned about
you know you know at the cellular level
we can't see them and when I when I
actually you know asked for four
questions for you Trent Rinka wrote in
he says Oh tell Jeff that his three
books caused me to buy my first
high-powered microscope that's what I
mean you know you think about it let's
take a you know the idea that you flush
your plants or hydroponics you can't
understand how you can't understand
either of these things I like to say you
can't understand why you shouldn't flush
and you can't understand you know even
the use of hydroponics if you don't
understand the cellular biology involved
and this it is fascinating and it's very
very important for the grower that's
trying to grow good organic weed and and
it's also important from a philosophical
perspective because you can't help
reading the second book walking away
with the idea that wait a second
you know we maybe you know maybe you and
I are just part of a big cell you know
we're two enzymes and these ideas that
we're kicking back and forth or like
that enzyme making we're making ideas
here and these ideas build up and all of
a sudden somebody comes a grower boom
wow this is the same thing that happens
inside an individual cell maybe we're
just one of 37 trillion cells in a
gigantic cannabis plant okay I'm done
it's different just a difference of
magnitude you know is you can't just
read these books you've got to sit back
after you read them you know and ingest
a little bit of this wonderful chemical
and let the cannabinoids you know help
you think about what you're doing you
know for me 360 degree way up in the air
view and we have the science from these
books you can do that did you did you
say in that last bit that um that you
don't recommend flushing I don't I don't
recommend flushing and I don't recommend
you know I don't recommend using kelp
for the reason that people use kelp I
mean though you know
plant has these 18 nutrients you put
kelp down
it's got 5662 nutrients they don't need
the rest of those nutrients you put the
kelp down to feed the soil food web yes
you know but not to feed the plant
really and then flushing me why do
people flush hmm if you're feeding your
plant properly and is growing properly
its balanced properly what are you
trying what are you flushing out what do
you flush out you flush out
carbohydrates I mean I can't think of
anything else you can flush out well it
seems to be a holdover from people still
using bottled salt nutrients right and
you know most of the most of the hard
core probiotic growers are like it
what's the point once once you're all
green yeah yeah so that was a seaman
with the salsa man I got a question I
mean you can all you you go
hydroponically basically as far as I'm
concerned you can almost always taste
the chemical um you know you can flush
all you want I think what do you think
you're doing you're growing in water
that's flushing I don't get it I just
don't get it but right on so so another
question comes in from sea bass wolf he
asked what mycelium from my home garden
or a nearby forest could I dig up and
use on my cannabis plants what plants or
trees and nature would provide good
mycelium starts for me to mix into my
soil okay a great question you know
first of all not from your trees because
your trees use the other kind which is
the exfil mycorrhizal the cannabis
plants and notice I say cannabis I think
using the word marijuana is is still
racist it was racist when it started
back in the 1930s so I don't use it I
use I use the word cannabis like it's
kerbals me that Alaska for example has
the marijuana act or agon is the Oregon
marijuana program no it should be called
cannabis but anyway um uh where was that
question again let's this was my silly
yeah from the olden garden Kenny 3 oh
yeah two trees no good
cannabis requires that one that I
mentioned the Rezo feigus riser faggus
Erie you've got the yellow root of town
right
and and you can get it from carrots
I think peonies
I believe potatoes so there are some
things that you grow in your garden that
also use the same the same fungi but but
why not you know why not use your
previous plants Yeah right not because
we know it's there because it's about
Rijo thoris yeah we certainly hope it's
there and it's certainly there if you
put it there so it makes a great deal of
sense the other thing that I think
people are beginning to notice at least
least I've been told this number of
people who do know and that is that when
you grow in a container you get some
pretty quick multiplication of the
spores when you grow in a field
situation or a big bed situation you get
you get the mycelium and it turns out
that when that mycelium is broken up it
will produce propagules that will grow
into the the ore will actually act as
spores and grow new fungi so you know
it's pretty cheap to buy particularly
when you know that you only need the one
it gets more expensive when you're
buying seven and eight and nine
different kinds so now that you know
what to look for on the package you just
buy the one you know you might want to
be thinking that way right on so here's
kind of a fun one listener Tony Leyva of
boneyard seeds in the Emerald triangle
down there
rights to ask if you have any particular
cannabis cultivars that you personally
like for ease of growth yield and the
terpene profile well hi you know my
all-time favorite is Durbin poison yeah
I mean who doesn't like Durbin poison
quick quick grower a beautiful plant
best terpene taste I can think of god I
love it here in Alaska you know we've
had a funny funny situation it's been
legal here in Alaska in the in the
privacy of your home tent hotel room etc
and so we've been growing in here
forever but for years and years and
years we grew two things though the
first was what people you know
euphemistically call mts
and and I don't know whether we are but
it was always the same stuff and so for
I'm swear I got four five or ten years
we were all smoking the same stuff you
know it got pretty boring huh
then Northern Lights appeared and so
they're not okay and now of course we've
got legalization but we we've got a very
interesting problem here and that is our
day length situation does not coincide
properly with the temperature and so
when you live in Alaska you have this
wonderful burst of daylight and if you
use light deprivation you could have a
phenomenal crop but if you just got a
regular backyard greenhouse it gets cold
before the plant sits the flowers fully
didn't last year was the first year ever
and people were just rejoicing beyond
belief and so we're limited to what we
can grow and a lot of people grow OTO
flowers and you know when you grow
flowers you don't end up with clones you
don't end up with giving seeds to other
people and so there really isn't sort of
that you know what do you like to grow I
like to grow OTO flowers because they're
easy but see they're all different yeah
you know you never know what you're
getting so but to go back again if I had
my way oh god the whole world would be
growing durbin poison right on so the
last question for you Mike Flanagan
writes in to ask about your thoughts on
Korean national career natural farming
yeah well you know and interestingly
enough teeming with microbes which has
been translated and I think nine
languages now uh was early on translated
into Korean like I couldn't figure out
why it's called Combe Sumida amoeba
which I love and every now and then I go
into a Korean restaurant here in
Anchorage and I like to bring the book
with me and they are very impressed that
and and $16.50 gets me a pretty good
Korean meal here but anyway uh you know
it is a it is a form of soil food web
gardening I guess if that's what you
want to call using benefit
organisms there's all there's you know
and it's it's very similar to e/m lactic
acid bacteria it's got about six or
seven or eight really key bacterias and
is you know it cycles the nutrients uses
mycorrhizal zits it's not different from
a soil food web system it's just that
there's a bunch of different ways that
to add amendments so that there's
fermented fruit juices and fermented
plant juices and amino acid juices and
also all sorts of nutrient mixes that
you can make and yeah I think you know I
mean I think it certainly works it's it
is a variation of adding either foods or
minerals I mean or minerals on some of
the foods foods or microbes so that the
soil food web will give the plant the
the microbes it needs to work with right
on yes
you know it's a lot of work but I you
know and it's very interesting I can't
see how you can't go through the Korean
system without learning a tremendous
amount of stuff it's almost like
biodynamic farming yeah I think that
it's for somebody who's moved beyond
their compost teas in the basics Korean
natural farming and even very
specifically the fermented the juice
ferments are really exciting and nerdy
well yeah I mean I've been I think
there's also animal involvement and all
sorts of stuff so so yeah I mean you
know and let's face it there's
spectacular spectacular farms and
Gardens in Korea it must work Jeff
thanks so much for being on the show
today this has been really exhilarating
and has opened so many new doors for
folks I really appreciate you sharing
your time with us well I hope we get to
meet again and any time you want to have
guests to you can hardly shut up you
give me ring
Jeff Lowen fells is the author of the
books teeming with microbes teeming with
nutrients and teeming with fungi you can
find links to those books on the shaping
our page for this episode or by going
directly to Jeff's website at WWF low
nfl.com that's Lowi n fel s comm you can
find more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast and subscribe to the show at
shaping fire calm and on Apple iTunes
stitcher and Google Play if you enjoyed
the show we'd really appreciate it if
you leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I will be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm as your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host Shango lows
[Music]