[Music]
so here we are at episode 50 in some
ways it feels like episode 104 because
before I started shaping fire I recorded
54 weekly episodes for my friends over
at ganja preneur calm but this episode
is number 50 of shaping fire the shaping
fire show is in its third year and some
folks ask me why there are only 50
episodes which works out to about two or
so a month belonging the short of it is
that to make a quality show
I can't just spit them out for most of
my guests I need to read their research
or their book or bone up on some aspect
of cannabis just so I can ask the
questions that you most want to hear
answered if I just asked generic
questions the show wouldn't be
particularly interesting and the number
one piece of feedback that I get from
folks is that they love my lines of
questioning so I make sure I take my
time when preparing a show also as an
interesting side note I went to college
on a full debate scholarship so that's
probably where the question-and-answer
skills come from also not only do I like
to take some time building a show but
I'm out in the field constantly learning
more and meeting new experts to bring
them to you on the show I'm down in
California a few times a year hearing
what farmers are saying and trying to
get introductions to hard people to
reach like Caleb Inspectah who was
recently on the show that interview took
almost a year to bring together but it
was hella worth it I also run my own
test garden and spend the bulk of my
time working with cannabis patients and
caregivers teaching them how to use
cannabis medicine and set up patient
grows it doesn't pay anything but it's
the most important part of all this to
me and while the podcast can now support
my basic needs through advertising I am
still doing some brand strategy and
business consulting for select clients
so I could afford the occasional
vacation you know I think because I am
involved in so many aspects of cannabis
and I'm not cloistered at home in the
studio that it offers you a perspective
that you won't find anywhere else but
that also means this will probably never
be a weekly show but we'll see and while
I can finally live off the commercials
on the show you'll notice that I still
don't have any bottled salt nutrient
companies as advertisers while most of
the industry
propped up by helping sell salts there's
no way I would take that kind of money
while being such a proponent of
regenerative agriculture poly culture
and organic cannabis farming techniques
I'm doing my best to walk my talk
similarly you may have realized that I'm
doing fewer shows on canvas business now
and more about cannabis health and
technique sure there are still shows
about the industry because I'm still
interested in that and I'm still very
much a part of that but you aren't gonna
find me doing a show about like track
and trace software the content I am
producing now is much more for hardcore
cannabis enthusiasts than it is
necessarily for business owners though I
love business owners too it's just that
I'm more interested in the plant and the
medicine than I am about spreadsheets
and regulatory changes so as you'd
expect shaping fire evolves like it
would over three years of the show
thanks for listening the show and
watching the videos on the YouTube
channel thanks for sending your kind
messages and following on Instagram and
thanks for recommending me to your
friends and to good-hearted cannabis
businesses that you think might be good
advertisers like our tagline says we try
and produce meaningful cannabis content
worth your valuable time to check out so
thank you for being an important part of
the shaping fire family if you want to
learn about cannabis health business and
technique efficiently and with good
cheer I encourage you to subscribe to
our newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks for a signed up to receive the
newsletter this month we're giving away
prize packs of the endow mycorrhizal
inoculant from dynamite there's nothing
else you need to do to win except
receive that newsletter so go to shaping
fire time to sign up for the newsletter
and be entered into this month's and all
future newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shaping fire and I'm your
host
Shango lows today my guest is
veterinarian dr. Garry Richter I had the
pleasure of hearing dr. Richter speak at
Emerald cup a while back and have been
excited to have him on the show ever
since gary is a holistic veteran
and scientist with a practice in Oakland
California while Gary cannot legally use
cannabis in his practice being in
California means that he had to research
can have an apotheca s'en anyway just to
answer the questions of pet owners he
has become a national expert and is a
sought-after speaker and he's also a
really nice guy today we're gonna talk
about in detail the use of cannabis with
pets and livestock
welcome to the show Gary thank you great
to be here so glad you could join us so
let's start at the very basic because
you know we talk about cannabis medicine
on the show all the time and one of the
key aspects of cannabis medicine of
course is that it interacts with the
human endocannabinoid system and often
when we talk about cannabis and pets
people are often surprised that Oh an
animal has an endocannabinoid system too
and I generally explain to them that
that you know all mammals do to varying
degrees and and people are surprised
about that when you talk to people about
the endocannabinoid system and their pet
kind of explaining to them how it works
for the pet instead of the human how do
you go ahead and explain that to folks
yeah that's a really good question I
mean you know explaining the
endocannabinoid system can get can get
tricky even when you're when you're
trying to explain it to medical
professionals because you know remember
very very few medical professionals be
they physicians or veterinarians learned
anything about the endocannabinoid
system in medical school either but but
you know the way I approach it is is is
you know the endocannabinoid system it
is a system of neurotransmitters that
are present throughout the body both in
the central nervous system as well as in
the rest of the body and and and while
we could talk for days about all of the
various all of the various actions and
and physiologic responses that are
caused by the endocannabinoid system the
overarching message is that the
endocannabinoid system is designed to
promote what is called homeostasis which
means balance within the body so whether
you know whether there
some sort of physiologic stress and
illness and injury emotional stress the
endocannabinoid system can help balance
all of that out and keep the body on an
even keel that's fantastic and and I
think it's interesting to the idea that
that that the endocannabinoid system is
constantly bringing any system that is
running hot or running cold back to the
center and I think that's interesting
because people say how can cannabis
potentially help so many different
things and I tell folks it only really
helps one thing it helps your
endocannabinoid system it's just that
hat that happens to have its fingers and
everything sure yeah I mean it's it's
almost like it's almost like when people
talk about stem cell therapy and-and-and
stem cell therapy being able to treat
this incredibly wide range of medical
conditions is because it's because stem
cells are really at the root of of what
cells can be in the body and therefore
they can address so many different body
systems and and while endocannabinoids
are clearly not stem cells it is similar
in the sense that the endocannabinoid
system touches almost every system
within the body and therefore there is
the potential to utilize the
endocannabinoid system and and phyto
cannabinoids to to positively affect
those systems I think that in many cases
pet owners are pretty darn sophisticated
and with access to the Internet a lot of
folks are doing their research before
they even go to the doctor's office I
was curious you know when people come to
your office and I know that you don't
recommend cannabis in your practice
because of the laws in California
but people constantly come to you asking
about it which kind of forces the
question you know to be answered and do
you find that people generally already
know that their their pet has got an
endocannabinoid system or is is that
very advanced for just about everybody
you talk to coming in you know what I
think a lot of people that come in while
they may have seen the term
endocannabinoid system somewhere either
on the internet or wherever they don't
really have a firm ground
but exactly what that means or how it
applies but what they do know is that
there is the potential for cannabis as
medicine to help their pet and while
many of them may not be concerned with
the with the specifics and the science
of the Y they certainly are concerned
with what can I do to help my animal
yeah you know sometimes people will come
to me and we'll be talking about pets
and they'll say you know I understand
there's this thing called
endocannabinoid deficiency and you know
they've often read dr. Ethan Russo's
papers about endocannabinoid deficiency
in humans and they're all like you know
how do I tell if my my animal has got
endocannabinoid deficiency and I usually
tell them you know what there's not even
tests for that in humans what do you
tell them well I that's that's pretty
much the long and short of it I mean
even even for people I mean you know
even Russo's paper on endocannabinoid
system deficiencies which is a fantastic
paper you know a lot of it is
speculative you know because we're
really we're really at the very very
early stages of understanding the the
more subtle nuances of how the
endocannabinoids system works and
there's certainly no diagnostic testing
on the veterinary side to be able to
measure endocannabinoid tone if you will
and that actually kind of feeds into the
kind of a general theme today that we're
probably gonna run into a bunch of times
which is these studies haven't been done
yet and so a lot of the insight that
you're going to be offering is is based
on kind of a combination of anecdotal
evidence your intuition you know stories
that you've heard come back to you and
and you know you're you're very
experienced hunches and and I know that
you know you you you've said that you'll
point those out when they're more
hunches than anything but I think it's
important for people to realize real
clearly upfront that these studies
generally have not been done but people
are asking so many of these questions
that we decided to go ahead and do an
episode about it kind of like the this
this the state of the art like you know
the the best we know so far
yeah you
and that's true and and but one other
thing to mention is there's certainly a
lot more clinical data out there
regarding cannabis as it as it affects
humans from a medical perspective and
while clearly a person is not a dog nor
nor a cat you know they are all complex
mammals and they all have an
endocannabinoid system so while we may
not be able to necessarily you know draw
direct correlations from one to the next
there's enough similarities here to
where if we have reasonable scientific
data on the human side there is an
expectation that we would see similar
effects on the veterinary side awesome
yeah that's a really good clarification
there are there are a lot of very
reasonable similarities and jumps that
we can make and we'll probably be doing
some of that today so all right so now
that people generally have an idea of
what we're trying to interact with in
the animals that were talking about
today I have have taken the kinds of
animals and topics that that people ask
me about most often and let's go through
them over the next you know hour or so
and talk about each so that whoever's
listening they're their particular
animal with that particular issue will
hopefully come up and by far most
everybody is talking to me about their
cats and dogs and I'm figuring that's
probably the same for you and the number
one question I get is my domestic pet is
getting old and their joints or
arthritis or they're just not they don't
have the the same get-up-and-go because
it hurts for them to get up and go and
people are asking me all right so they
often come to me for the CBD and and
then we often talk about the TIA we talk
about THC instead for the
anti-inflammatory so when people are
talking to you about simple joint pain
for a house pet what kind of guidance do
you give them or what kind of
perspective do you set them up with well
you know as it pertains to cannabis that
that happens to be one of the areas
where we do
have a little bit of scientific data on
the on the veterinary side there was a
study that was published last year out
of Cornell that looked at using CBD to
treat arthritis pain and dogs and what
they found was is that is that CBD was
in fact effective at controlling
arthritis pain and dog so that is as I
say it's one of the few areas where we
actually have some real data
you know perhaps the the bigger question
or at least the other question is is
okay well if CBDs effective what about
THC what about other cannabinoids and
that is something that we really don't
know definitively yet although again
going back to the human literature we do
know that THC or a combination of THC
and CBD can be very very beneficial to
treat people with pain and and as such
it's it's probably reasonable to assume
that similar things could be could be
experienced by dogs and cats now the so
the the trick to all of this of course
is is is what product and what dose and
that's you know that's where that that's
where the you know the rubber hits the
road so to speak as it pertains to it's
a sort of veterinary medicine or human
medicine and and the use of cannabis so
that's something that you know as I'm
sure you and your and your listeners
know really plays a huge bearing on the
effect of any any kind of cannabis
preparation you know the varying either
amounts or ratios of cannabinoids
terpenes what-have-you and that's that's
that's really where we need to be
looking and where we need to be focusing
yeah you know I often which wish that I
could speak to these dogs and cats that
people come to me and then they say oh
we've got our dog and we we gave it just
a little bit of THC based tincture
because it had joint pain and we were
hoping for the inflammation to go down
enough that the dog can you know yeah
heck sometimes just go outside to to
defecate you know and and so people will
give their animal just
little bit of THC you know maybe maybe a
milligram maybe a milligram and a half a
very very small amount and then and then
the dog will you know you know you know
get up and kind of lumber around and
seem like it's in good spirits and step
out and I'm always curious to know
whether or not is this the dog
experiencing muscle relaxation and less
tension of the muscles and less
inflammation somehow in the moment or is
it just that the dog somehow is
experiencing a pleasant cannabis
experience like so many of us have which
kind of changed their mood and caused
them to get up because we try to
anthropomorphize their actions and and
it's so important what the motivation of
the actions are when we're talking about
dosing humans and the doses are so much
more sensitive and and and lower for an
animal it it it makes it very
challenging to come up since there's no
studies yet yeah I mean it is very
challenging but you know one thing that
we do know with dogs in particular is
that dogs actually have a greater number
and a greater concentration of cb1
receptors in their brainstem then do
people and as such they are much more
sensitive to the potential toxic effects
of THC then would be a human on a sort
of on a per weight basis so what that
means is is that is that we do have to
be very very cautious with the amount of
THC a dog gets now you mentioned like a
half a milligram or one milligram of THC
now it kind of depends on the size of
the dog you know for fur so for example
for a medium to a large sized dog
probably a milligram of THC is not going
to have any any outward effects in a
negative sense like the dogs not going
to be high the dogs not going to be
experiencing THC toxicity but that said
it's possible that even at that low dose
the you know that amount of THC could be
providing some pain relief could be
providing some real
sation as you say I mean it's very
difficult to get any kind of direct
feedback from a veterinary patient so
all we really have to go on is is how
they're acting how you know how they're
moving around because you know from the
dogs perspective there is no placebo
effect here now certainly as a human
perceptual issue we we may read things
into it that aren't there and that you
know that as a placebo effect in and of
itself but you know if the dog is
unquestionably doing things that
otherwise wasn't doing the only
explanation for that is because they
feel better yeah yeah that makes sense
and also you know kind of to relate that
to the humans and and we talk about this
often on the show where people are
experiencing or they're looking for
relief from something but they really
don't want to experience any level of
you know THC euphoria or intoxication
and so we always tell people that you
know take two point five milligrams four
times a day and you may never feel it
but it's still epi those those clinical
doses still causing muscle relaxation
and causing anti-inflammation it's just
not a high enough dose that you're there
getting anything in your head and and
and I think that's that's exactly what
you're describing for the veterinary
patients as well yeah you know that's
that's very true as a you know when I
speak to groups of pet owners or groups
of veterinarians I mean I very
frequently tell them that that it is
just like with a person it is absolutely
possible to put an animal on tac and
have them not be high it's just a
function of understanding how many
milligrams you're giving relative to the
body weight and or species of the of the
particular animal that you're treating
and and to go along with that
you know therapeutic dosing so so you
know doses of say THC that have a
positive effect medically speaking do
not have to be psychoactive doses
there's plenty of space in the in the in
the therapeutic dosing window that are
well below whatever would cause psycho
activity and a human or an animal
and you can still get benefit from it I
mean look at all these people that are
out there that are that are functioning
members of society that rely on cannabis
you know to get through their day
because they have pain or anxiety or
whatever it is that they may have you
know those people are not walking around
high you know it's just that you know
like with any medication you have to
understand what you're giving and what
dosage you're giving I think it's
important to to point out that while
let's see how do I want to go into this
so I'm gonna start with the anecdote so
over the course of my life of using
cannabis I have been in the presence of
other people who have had pets and at
some point they got the the the pet hype
you know by blowing smoke in their ear
or whatever that you know have seen
happen and and at some point the pet
decided that it liked it so that so that
when I'm over at their house and and
they light up the the the would say a
dog the dog here's the lighter and so
the dog comes in the room and it's kind
of begging for it I always found that to
be really extraordinary both because I
did not think it was fun or funny to
dose an unsuspecting animal but since it
had already been done and I was there
and the animal seemed to want more I
found that to be a rather interesting
data point do you have any you know
feedback from your your patients and
their owners about pets that have
acquired a desire for more of it you
know that's honestly that's not
something that I've really come across I
mean I you know I feel pretty strongly
that that you know that kind of that
kind of activity like intentionally
blowing smoke in your dog's face or
something that I mean that's that's not
okay and in fact that that borders on
animal abuse
you know partially because you know
these animals are not equipped nor aware
of what's coming from a psycho activity
standpoint and also because you know
what I mean inhaling smoke is not
necessarily good for anybody and I
certainly
not good for dogs and cats and if you
know and if if cannabis as medicine is
something that they benefit from and and
one could speculate you know what if
that individual dog seems to seek it out
maybe there's something that dog is
getting from it medically speaking you
know maybe something hurts less or maybe
they just generally feel better and if
that's the case then then you know
that's when it's time to investigate a
more responsible use of medical cannabis
rather than what I went to what I would
describe as irresponsible use of
recreational cannabis yeah right on that
makes sense to me so so we talked a
little bit about the potentiality for
the use of both CBD and THC to decrease
you know pain and joint pain just
general body aches of a older domestic
pet people have started writing online
that they're using CBD to rebalance the
endocannabinoid system so their pets
don't have allergies and and I've never
run into this aunt with an animal before
so I don't know how I would know that my
pet has an allergy and what it's to and
then to choose to treat it with CBD but
what do you what do you have in that
category you know of all of the things
that I've seen animals benefit from
cannabis for I mean allergies is not
it's not at the top of the list you know
I you know as as we have mentioned I
mean cannabis and it's in its many forms
it does have anti-inflammatory
properties it does have sort of overall
immune system and body balancing
properties by virtue of promoting
homeostasis as we discussed before I
have in fact on a couple of occasions
seen topical cannabis products used on
animals that seemed to have helped a
little bit with itching and allergy so I
think you know there may be something
there although like I say I mean you
know you look at all of the various
things that cannabis is used for you
know in people as well
and you know I mean treating our Jesus
you know it's not super high on that
list of things I think there are there
are there are other options out there
both natural medicine why
and if necessary pharmaceutically
speaking that probably would work a
little better
one thing I've seen for sure is when
folks will administer small amounts of
THC to there you know domestic animal
that for for pain or something often
they will get the munchies and you can
just see them go to town on on their
food and and people are often overjoyed
because like oh my gosh the the animal
had had so much it was in pain and they
weren't getting a lot of movement and
they didn't even want to go over to
their food bowl and now suddenly there's
movement and they just totally cleaned
out the bowl and so they they kind of
help bring the pet back to health by by
leaning on what I'm assuming is going to
be the MIR scene in the in the THC
preparation have you seen that taken
place in your practice you know I'm not
honestly convinced that cannabis is is
directly an appetite stimulant and
animals like you know from from like the
munchies standpoint but what I think we
do see is because a lot of the animals
that are receiving these medications
they're you know they're not eating or
they're not eating well because they
don't feel good you know they feel sick
whether they have an upset stomach or
they're in pain or there's something
else going on I mean you know I think we
all know from our own health that when
you you know when you feel crappy you
know going out and eating a bunch it's
not necessarily always you know your
first priority and I think what happens
with these guys is oftentimes we see
them eat better because they feel better
so they're not they're not in pain
anymore maybe their stomach upset is is
relieved and therefore they're gonna eat
more but you know like I say I'm not I'm
not a hundred percent convinced it's
directly appetite stimulating in the
sense that like people get the munchies
see this is another great quest that
we'd love to ask them you know you'd
really love to yeah totally so I ran
into something new recently someone
using a mere seem dominant THC tincture
with their pet after surgery so they
they had
pet that had normally has a lot of
energy and was gonna be jumping around
and they did not wanted to give it
traditional
I don't know pharmaceuticals to dope out
the animal after the surgery but they
were still concerned about the sutures
getting ripped open or just a little
give letting them have the time to get
over the trauma of the surgery and so
what they did is they they use this
tincture and they intentionally got
their dog a little high but the dog
seemed fine and relaxed and just kind of
chilled out around them for the next few
days and then they you know then they
stopped the the dosing and that the dog
kind of perked back up and went on its
merry way and you know outside of the
the discussion that we've already had
that you've got to be really darn and
careful with dosing and we're gonna talk
more about dosing after the break what
do you think about you know the use of a
THC tincture to kind of slow down or I
don't know incapacitate an animal so
that they can get through they're more
important healing you know it's it's a
really interesting question because
because well like in my mind my
immediate sort of knee-jerk response was
gonna be you know what that's a bad idea
but you know when I when I look at the
when I look at the kinds of
pharmaceuticals that we typically use in
veterinary medicine for just that
purpose so so post surgical animals to
keep them calm to keep them from being
too active after a surgery I mean
effectively that's kind of what we're
doing is we're intentionally sedating
the dog or the cat or whatever so
they're not excessively active so you
know is giving is giving say like a
pharmaceutical like trazadone is that is
that demonstrably better than somebody
giving an appropriate dose of a you know
a cannabis preparation with THC and
mersin I mean honestly I don't actually
know the answer to that question that's
one of those
things that down the road I think
research would be really fascinating to
start to look at like at like
physiologic parameters like you know
heart rate and respiration rate and and
pain you know pain response it'd be
really fascinating to see if cannabis
you know can be appropriately used in
that sense you know clearly it is going
to be extremely difficult if not
impossible for a pet owner to get any
kind of guidance in that regards from a
veterinarian so you know that as you say
that just it rolls us back around to
that discussion of dosing and I think
that that's that's particularly
important with this particular scenario
biggest now now we're talking about
really getting up close to the line
between a therapeutic dose and what and
what would be considered a toxic dose
yeah so so let's pick up this dosing
conversation after the first break you
are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is veterinarian dr. Gary
Richter now that the health benefits of
terpenes have become well-known in the
cannabis industry people everywhere are
looking for the purest terpenes and
custom terpene blends true terpenes
isolated terpenes and terpenoids
are tested to the most demanding
worldwide safety and stability standards
terpenes from true terpenes our
third-party tested non-gmo and food
grade their triple distilled making them
the purest terpenes available in the
world with over a thousand terpene
isolates strain profiles and Terp
flavors you can be sure that true
terpenes will have the perfect aromatics
for your manufacturing goals true
terpenes also offers custom blending so
that you can match your company's
marquee strains across all your product
categories while you can certainly
simply just order terpenes and go right
to manufacturing true terpenes also
offers a wealth of manufacturing insight
best practices and a willingness to help
you break new ground with your product
formulations true terpenes has robust
and supportive customer service too so
your questions will get answered fast
and efficiently if you shop for turps
before you know how rare that is if you
are a cannabis product developer these
are the Terps that you want to add to
your oil or edible or capsule or
Everage true terpenes are simply the
best your money can buy don't try and
make a premium product with substandard
terms choose true terpenes for a
top-shelf experience go to shaping
feiyr.com ford slash true terpenes to
find out more or click on the link in
this week's newsletter cannabis is fun
medicine and we love to celebrate it
cannabis connects people and creates
opportunities for new friendships at the
joke shop we create custom cannabis
themed jewelry money clips rolling trays
and home furnishings that I love and
they also make great gifts too i'm
ashley Villafranca owner of the toke
shop I came to cannabis as a patient
seeking an alternative to the
pharmaceuticals being pushed at me for
chronic pain and fibromyalgia I realized
that not only was cannabis a huge help
in controlling my symptoms but I found
cannabis to be wonderfully social too
cannabis makes friends so I took my love
of jewelry design and blended it with my
newfound passion for cannabis and began
hand crafting bracelets earrings and
friendship necklaces and then expanded
to many clips rolling chaise and other
home furnishings all made in sterling
silver 14 karat gold and aluminum so
there's something for everyone's budget
I consider it all to be new-age cannabis
fashion and cannabis couture I invite
you to stop by my website at the top
shop CEO at the top shop CEO you'll find
a wide array of attractive and fun
cannabis items starting at only 10 bucks
and if you're fancy there are very fine
luxury pieces as well and I'm always
happy to do custom orders with your name
or a particular theme come check out my
array of items hand stamped with
terpenes cannabinoids and other cannabis
themes that's the toke shop see oh
thanks welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango Lowe's
and our guest this week is veterinarian
dr. Garry Richter so before the break we
were talking about the importance of
making sure you get the dosing right and
you know this is true of humans as well
because you can very easily move
somebody from a dose that's going to
help them to an over medicated dose
that's going to have them you know
potentially upset for an hour or so and
we never want to do that with animals
because they don't know what's going on
to them and they trust us to take care
of them the best way that we can but
it's hard because most people don't know
how to even dose humans properly and so
when they're trying to apply the same
you know lack of experience to their pet
things can get into trouble real fast
so Gary during the first set you were
talking about how dogs have gotten more
cb1 receptors and so they they have a
faster uptake of cannabinoids and I
often explain that to people it's like
the difference between taking an edible
versus hitting a joint when you inhale a
joint that goes to your lungs and it
goes or immediately in your bloodstream
and it hits you all at once and that's
why you feel stoned faster whereas when
you take an edible or a capsule it takes
a longer time to be processed through
your bag and it comes on a little more
slowly well with what you us about
earlier about the cb1 receptors and dogs
that tells me that we've got to be even
more careful than I thought we needed to
be so when you're talking to people
about figuring out dosing what do you
tell them when they when they're trying
to weigh like how do I know how many CB
receptors my pet has got versus dog
weight you know these are these are
unknowns at this point so how do you how
do you help bring somebody through it
yeah you know I mean the I think the
there there's a couple of a couple of
hard and fast rules in this regards and
and you know if I were say speaking with
a group of pet owners or educating
veterinarians on on you know ways that
they can think about using cannabis and
their practice you know the two things
that I think are important to remember
as it pertains to dosing is number one
you know it's you know it's all about
body weight it's all about the body
weight of the animal so you know it's
interesting when you look at when you
look at dosing for humans very commonly
in the literature you'll see you know
this drug X number of milligrams per
adult human male or human female but
there's so much variability in sizes of
adult dogs I mean you can have a one
pound
or a 200-pound Great Dane
so so knowing how much the patient
weighs has got to be step one and step
two as as we often say even when it
comes to human medicine it is very much
a start low and go slow kind of approach
yeah so you know we start them at we
start them at a dose that that we know
is going to be safe and is very unlikely
to cause any sorts of side-effects and
then slowly over time we increase that
dose until we get to until we either get
to a therapeutic effect that we're
looking for or we've gone so high that
we're now seeing side effects that we
don't like in which case we may need to
think about a different medication and
that's why it's important to go slow
because that you know if you're gonna go
step step step and like let's say that
it's the fourth step where you're
starting to see adverse reaction you
don't want to be taking big steps so
that there's a big adverse reaction you
want it to be very very subtle so that
you can read your animals body language
and then realize okay this is this is
our threshold point here and so again
it's it's important what would you call
a a a small step are you talking about
increases of like a half a milligram
well again I mean you know it's it's
it's hard to say on a per milligram
basis because it depends on the size of
the animal so you know I might look a
little bit more from a percentage
increase rather than per milligram you
know so probably you know a safe thing
to start with
would may be like like a 20% increase on
a weekly basis and you know what people
need to kind of look out for is is if if
as they're ramping that dose of if they
give if they give an increased dose and
and the pet looks you know they look a
little glassy I they look a little out
of it they're sort of staring off into
space then probably that means we need
to back off the dose somewhat so Gary
one of the things that you know that
that everybody wants to know is the
exact dosage that they need to start
with and this is difficult right because
nobody wants to
about it and and when I when I when I
read places they don't want to go to
that level of detail so you've already
spoken real clearly that there are
variations between a smaller pet and a
larger pet but but there's got to be
some algorithm where we can get people
to start because they're gonna do it
anyway so so what do you recommend yeah
you know I mean that if that is true and
that is that is invariably one of the
questions that almost all people who are
looking at cannabis for animals have and
quite rightly so so you know to start
with as it pertains to dosing to start
with CBD and and I'll start with that
because we actually do have some some
research information here the study that
I was mentioning a little bit earlier
that came out of Cornell looking at dogs
with arthritis as well as another study
that came out of Colorado State
University looking at dogs with epilepsy
so treating seizures with CBD both of
those studies looked at dosages
approximately of two milligrams of CBD
per kilogram of body weight twice daily
so you know as a doctor all of our we
sort of think in in terms of milligrams
per kilogram when it comes to dosing but
what that really translates to in in
plain English is about a milligram of
CBD per pound of body weight so for
example if you have a ten pound dog
you're talking about give or take about
ten milligrams of CBD twice a day now
mind you if you're if you're familiar at
all with with with with CBD dosing that
dose may strike you as high and and and
in truth when I saw these studies
initially I kind of find that found that
dose so seemingly a little on the high
side as well I have seen a lot of
animals do very well on much lower
dosages of CBD so it may be that that
that even significantly lower dosages
can be beneficial but but as you know
you know the the margin of safety for
CBD is like a mile wide so so you don't
you you don't have a lot of concern
there from the standpoint of overdose
toxicity that sort of thing now clearly
that's
not the case when it comes to THC so let
me preface this by saying that the
dosing that I'm about to discuss is is
unfortunately not based on any
scientific research at this point it's
really a combination of extrapolation
from human research what I have seen
work well in pets reports that I've
gotten from from other veterinarians
from other medical professionals etc but
I think it's I think it's a reasonably
good guideline and the guideline from
the standpoint of starting a THC dose
for a dog or a cat is going to be
approximately point zero five milligrams
per kilogram twice a day so that's 0.05
milligrams per kilogram of body weight
twice a day so again in plain English
what that what that's going to translate
to is about a quarter of a milligram per
10 pounds of body weight so if you have
for example a 40 pound dog you might
think about starting with a milligram of
THC twice a day and and as we discussed
you know you can sort of slowly ramp up
from there but that should be a
reasonably safe place to start so Gary
of course that brings us to how do we
actually get the dose into the animal
you know often I will recommend to pet
owners to use an alcohol-based tincture
because that goes through the skin so
easily and following the the analytics
on the label to dose them the proper
amount on the skin under the fur on the
back of the neck and and I've heard some
people do that same technique but
they'll do it with the ear because it's
got you know very soft membranes as well
but in your role you are constantly
teaching people how to give their pets
you know you know capsules or liquids or
whatever they normally need to take so
how do you how do you advise people to
actually get the get the cannabinoids
into the animal which which won't
necessarily recognize it as food sure so
you know I am
I'm a big proponent of of cannabis
infused oils and I like them for a
couple of reasons
the first reason is is whenever you're
administering a liquid you have a lot of
leeway as far as as far as dosing goes
so you know as we were discussing
earlier you know if we're gonna go with
the sort of start low and go slow theory
and we're gonna say okay well you know
increase by say 20% each week if you're
gonna do that with a liquid it's quite
easy if you're gonna do it with some
something that looks like a food item
like a dog biscuit or something you know
20 percent can be tricky you know it's
hard to break those things up into you
know into sort of even portions and I
also do like to give the oils directly
orally with the intent that hopefully
we're going to get a certain amount of
trans mucosal absorption so absorption
into the bloodstream directly through
the mouth
even prior to that medication being
swallowed and ultimately digested and
absorbed through the gastrointestinal
tract so you know I think I think oral
administration is is is certainly my
preferred method just to address what
you were speaking about before what I
would call transdermal so putting it on
the skin with intent being systemically
absorbed they don't have an enormous
amount of information about the efficacy
of that but I can tell you that the the
aforementioned study from Colorado State
University looking at epileptic dogs
also looked at rates of absorption of
various methods of administration of CBD
and they found that the transdermal
absorption was the most poorly absorbed
preparation so so at least preliminarily
it may be that that you know that
cannabis is not is not super well
absorbed in that way but if nothing else
you know one thing that I can say really
just from my experience with other
transdermal medications that are used in
veterinary medicine is at best
absorption is is unpredictable from one
individual to the next so it's a little
bit
to tell how much is actually getting in
the patient yeah fair enough
so if you are recommending oral and and
if I understand your vocabulary
correctly you don't really want it you
know clearly we don't want to do like a
preset dosed biscuit dog biscuit or
something or animal whatever but but we
do want to use an oil but you're also
saying don't take a pre-measured amount
of that oil and apply it to the dog
biscuit you regularly give them I think
you're saying just put the oil in their
mouth is that what you're saying I mean
I think in a perfect world yes that's
what I'm saying now you know I mean
that's all well and good but I mean if
an animal is just bottom line not
amenable to being medicated that way
then by all means feed it to them put it
on food put it on a treat it's not you
know it's it you know these things are
not it's not black or white you know I
think if we're looking for the most
efficient means of absorption directly
or Alize probably a good way to go and
you know and I think that that you know
I think that that speaks a little bit to
the conversation of if you get the right
preparation for the individual dosing
becomes really easy because let's say
that if I'm going to dose some given dog
and based on the concentration of the
medicine that I have the doses two or
three drops of oil I can put those drops
of oil on my finger and just lift up a
lip rub it on his gums and I'm done I
see so you know but you know if you can
I shouldn't you have to give like three
teaspoons of oil then yeah that's gonna
be a problem
right on and it's always important I
think when when just like interacting
with human patients when you have an
animal patient they have got a life
experience too and and we want to make
sure that we create a healthy experience
for them so they don't want to resist
being handled and medicated and and who
knows you might have an experience like
we talked about earlier where the animal
realizes that
after I get rubbed with this oil on my
gums my pain decreases they may end up
being like all in like I'm in favor of
this you know that that may in fact be
true though the one part we're worried
it may not work out as well as we wanted
to is is is while dogs and cats are
certainly very attuned to a
cause-and-effect relationship it may be
that the effect is far enough down the
road from the cause that they don't
connect the two you know if they don't
feel better for like a half hour they
may not connect that to when we put it
in their mouth yeah fair enough fair
enough so let's let's take this to the
far end of the scale right because they
at the far end of the scale we've got
animals with cancer and fourth up for
folks who do not understand what a
typical human cancer protocol is it's
taking sixty grams or technically
milliliters of of this cannabis oil
commonly known as Rick Simpson oil or
ethanol hash oil but essentially it's a
it's an ethanol extraction of the oil
from the plant very concentrated and and
a human will take 60 milliliters of this
over 90 days and that is an
extraordinary amount of cannabinoids and
just about all the patients find that
they sleep through the majority of the
time because it's so I could makes you
so lethargic you know there are
certainly people who will be taking
these high dosage and and it actually is
a buoy to them they're actually feeling
better and more lighthearted and they
don't sleep but that's that's really
uncommon normally people are lethargic
and and they sleep most of the time but
the problem is that when people are
getting up they would when they're
titrating up and going to a higher
higher dose every third or fourth day
sometimes you get nausea from the higher
dose or or like any kind of dysphoria
that people will sometimes have when
they take too much THC and so people
will say okay I know
oh that I that that humans are taking a
THC preparation for cancer and my dog
has got a tumor or some other form of
cancer and so I want to do that for my
dog too because they have an
endocannabinoid system and so the
problem of though is that when you're
working with a patient the patient is
giving you very clear feedback about how
they're feeling and we are dealing with
high dosage so that feedback is
incredibly important when we're doing
this with our you know house pet we are
way closer to cannabinoid toxicity
levels by trying to do in high enough
dose that is actually acting as a as
they cancer cure because this is way
more of a dose than just helping them
with joint pain but the but the animal
can't give us really quality feedback to
know if they are getting paranoid or
getting upset or getting nauseous or any
of these things and it makes for a very
difficult situation and yet I'm
regularly hearing from people who are
buying syringes of ethanol hash oil
putting it in capsules and giving it to
their animal to try to help with their
tumors I think that there are so many
ways for this to go wrong what has been
your experience well that is that is an
accurate statement there are so many
ways for this to go badly you know first
of all if anybody you know if anybody
has ever had the experience of eating
too many edibles you know you can start
to get an idea of of what kind of
effects that we're talking about I mean
you know overindulging on edibles is not
a good time for anybody and if you've
ever seen a person on one of these
cannabis protocols for cancer I will
tell you that it is brutal yeah it is
not fun for these people but you know
what I mean if it's something that as a
human if that's what you've signed up
for then you've made that decision and
you understand why you feel the way that
you do and
that's all great that said we cannot do
that we can't do that with animals and
you know I mean you know there's a
couple of things to say I guess in that
regards first of all you know justjust
from an from an oncology perspective so
from a cancer treatment perspective you
know there's a little bit of a different
philosophy when it comes to when it
comes to animals versus people so for
example if a person has cancer and and
they go to their oncologist essentially
their oncologists mission is to keep
their patient alive no matter what and
sometimes that means damn near poisoning
them to death in the process when it
comes to veterinary patients when it
comes to animals nobody wants to put an
animal through that kind of chemotherapy
and as such the goals of of oncology
when it comes to animals is not to
preserve life at all costs it is to
preserve quality of life so I think
that's the first thing that we have to
we have to really sort of pay very close
attention to is is you know what I mean
it's cancer and and just like with
people you know a lot of pets
unfortunately are going to ultimately
succumbed to cancer and the best thing
that we can do for these animals is to
give them good quality of life for as
long as we possibly can so having them
uncomfortably stoned out of their minds
for the last weeks or months of their
life is is really is really not a good
way to go to speak to the specific
preparations I know there's a lot of
people out there that are buying Rick
Simpson oil and other sorts of super
concentrated cannabis oils I would
HIGHLY highly advise against giving any
of those products to animals and the
reason why I say that is because those
products are so concentrated that it is
functionally impossible to accurately
dose so we talked a little bit earlier
about dosing
you know on a on a milligram per
kilogram of body weight basis or a
milligram per pound of body weight basis
you know when you're talking about
something like Rick Simpson oil that is
so concentrated that a grain of right MA
10 20 50 milligrams of of THC and let's
say your dog's dose is one milligram of
THC there's no way you're gonna be able
to sort of accurately dose that and and
you know again from from a doctor's
perspective a grain of rice is not a
dose you know yeah you know I mean you
know my you know my immediate thought is
always like what kind of rice is it long
grain is it short grain is it basmati
rice I mean you can't you can't you
can't dose medicine in this way I mean
if you're gonna call if you're gonna
call cannabis powerful medicine which it
is then we need to treat it in the in
the same way that we would any other you
know any other powerful and effective
medicine so to kind of just sort of
bring this in for a landing I guess as
it pertains to dosing cannabis for
cancer oftentimes the goal with these
animals is to ramp them up to the
highest dose that we can get them on and
have them still feel okay and feel
functional you know remember that just
like with people dogs will develop a
tolerance to the psychoactivity of THC
over time so over time you can get them
on much much higher doses of THC than
you will be getting able to give them on
day one and I will tell you that I have
seen dogs with dogs with cancer on doses
of THC then if I were to take it I would
be under the covers for three days so
you know they can develop a tolerance
just like people can but you got to do
it slowly and you really just don't want
to push it any further than they can
handle right on thank you Gary this is
this has been a great set I'm really
glad to be able to get this level of
specificity on dosing all together and
in one place so it's time for us to take
our second short break and
be right back you're listening to
shaping fired my guest today is
veterinarian dr. Gary Richter did you
know that shaping fire has a fabulous
YouTube channel with content not found
on the podcast when I attend conventions
or speak or moderate panels I always
record them and bring the content home
for you to watch the Shengo Lowe's
YouTube channel it has world-class
speakers including Kevin Jodrey of
Wonderland nursery talking about
breeding cannabis for the best terpene
profile nicholas Mahmood on regenerative
and poly culture cannabis growing dr.
Sunil Agarwal on the history of cannabis
medicine around the world Ben Cassidy of
true terpenes on using terpenes for
health in your everyday life Reggie
Godinho of steep hill on the cannabis
genome and Jeff Lowen Fell's on the soil
food web
there are several presentations from dr.
Ethan Russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system and even my own
presentation on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose cannabis business even though the
risks are so high as of today there are
over 100 videos that you can check out
for absolutely free go to youtube.com
forward slash Shango 'lose or click on
the link in this week's newsletter as a
listener of shaping fire you already
understand the importance of living soil
when growing cannabis when you have
active microbe communities in your
substrate you go way beyond simply
fertilizing with nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium having active microorganisms
in your substrate supports vigorous
plant growth throughout the plants root
zone making for higher yields and
thriving flowers mammoth pee is the
first organically derived microbial
inoculant that focuses on your plants
nutrient cycling processes to release
soil phosphorus and other micronutrients
from there bound forms making them more
available to the plant increased levels
of phosphorus will also keep inner nodes
shorter and focus your plants energy on
bud production not only that but the
microbes act as a defense shield for the
plants rhizosphere
by out competing potentially harmful
pathogenic microbes pretty cool right
mammoth pee not only unlocks the
nutrients in your soil but it also helps
protect your plant from disease mammoth
peas beneficial bacteria act like
microbial reactors continually producing
enzymes
release nutrients mammoth pee was
developed at a u.s. university has been
extensively tested by Colorado growers
and independent laboratories mammoth pee
is proven to increase growth and enhance
blooming one of the great things about
supplementing with microorganisms is
that they won't compete with whatever
fertilizer program you're already
running simply dose on top of your
fertilizer schedule for increased
benefits to learn more and to find out
where you can buy mammoth pee near you
check out their website at
www.opm.gov/tribalprograms as far as we
know oh I don't know and in fact you
know the endocannabinoid system is
fascinating in a sense that that you
know if you look at the the types of
animals that have an endocannabinoid
system evolutionarily speaking you're
going back millions and millions of
years I mean there are there are
marine invertebrates that have an
endocannabinoid system Wow so so so I
mean most complex animals that you can
think of have some form of an
endocannabinoid system of course you
know that doesn't mean that it works
exactly the same way as it would in a
mammal but but you know from an
evolutionary standpoint it is it is it
is pretty well ingrained in the animal
kingdom
now to get to your question about about
small furry things like bunnies and
whatnot the reality is is we don't
really know pretty much anything as it
pertains to as it pertains to dosing on
these sorts of things you know I can
tell you that that you know sort of the
digestive tract and the metabolism you
know of a rabbit or some others you know
sort of small furry animal like that is
pretty drastically different from that
of our dog or a cat so it it's probably
not applicable to just sort of downsize
the dosing accordingly per body weight
you know as a rule you know a lot of
these animals are significantly more
sensitive to pharmaceuticals
then-then-then say would be a dog or a
cat on a per pound basis so odds are the
dosing is actually going to be lower
than people might think you know I think
from a safety perspective you know if
somebody had like an arthritic bunny or
a bunny that had like back issues or
something they could try a little CBD I
think quite safely and see if that helps
I'm not aware of any medical issues that
that have come up as far as that goes
with regards to something like THC like
I say I mean there's just there's just
no information out there to even have a
even have a clue about where to start
from a dosing perspective so let's go
the other direction so I live on an
island
that is very equestrian heavy and there
are there are horses everywhere and
people see THC and CBD being used in
other animals and so they're there
looking to deploy THC for you know for
injury or everything we've pretty much
discussed talking about using it for
dogs and cats really oh they're starting
to cross apply to horses and people are
starting to experiment with high doses
of CBD to to keep horses calm but these
are huge animals with a pretty
significant different kind of system
right down to how they how they process
their nutrition what our thoughts on on
using THC and CBD Nia and the other
novel cannabinoids on these these larger
livestock animals yeah that's it that's
a really great question and again I mean
there's there there are people that are
starting to look at those issues I mean
I can tell you just you know from from a
pharmacology standpoint horses on a per
pound basis usually take far far less
medication to be effective than say what
a dog or a cat
so the dosing is is is very likely a lot
lower than people would think that it
would be you know I do know that there's
some people out there that are starting
to look at the use of CBD and horses
again we don't really have any any
published or even very much anecdotal
data out there as far as you know
specific doses go you know certainly one
thing that I would urge extreme caution
with as it pertains to THC and an animal
like a horse is is you know potentially
causing even mild THC toxicity and a
horse I could I could foresee as being a
very very concerning thing you know from
the standpoint of you know horses as you
probably aware are fairly fragile
creatures and you know if a horse would
you know got a little too much THC and
lost their footing and fell I mean that
literally could be a life-ending event
for a horse so you know that's something
I would certainly urge extreme caution
and if people you know if there's horse
people out there you know they may
actually have a little bit more
information than I do because because
that's not really so much the world that
I live in but but you know i would i
would definitely urge urge extreme
caution and taking things very very
slowly and not only could it potentially
put the the horse or other livestock at
at risk but also i mean we all know how
dangerous a horse can be when it is
spooked or honor and if it's having
this experience that it's never had
before and it's feeling unsafe Wow it
could it could hurt the people around it
and it can hurt itself against against
things that are nearby yeah I agree I
mean it's a you know I'm not I'm not I'm
not gonna say that it's it's something
that should never be done because again
it's a little out of my area of
expertise but I mean it's something that
that should be done under veterinary
guidance and very very carefully right
on I think that's a good point for us to
say you know we're pulling so much of
our experience from from anecdotes and
from personal experience of people doing
this on the animals that tend to be most
commonly in our lives right dogs and
cats and and as we as we work our way
out to smaller animals like rabbits and
larger animals like like horses and
cattle the the number of data points
that we have even anecdotally get less
and less and less and so if you're
working with animals at either end of
the scale don't think that you can just
take the the dog or cat dosing algorithm
and just apply it to these other animals
right yeah you're absolutely right yeah
so let's have let's have a little
discussion about topicals for these
animals because topicals are nice
because they generally keep the dosing
pretty low and a certainly CBD
topicals for for you know psoriasis and
dermatitis and these these other types
of skin issues certainly are great for
animals my question which is pretty
basic is how do you do use a topical
with an animal with fur well it's tricky
you know it's tricky for two reasons the
fur is certainly one of them and you
know if there was an area of skin that
that you know seemed like it really
warrants a topical then it may be that
that area needs to be shaved because
otherwise I mean I think you know I
think a topical would be we'd be
difficult I have seen some products out
there that are essentially just alcohol
extracts that are that are packaged as a
spray so it may be that you know you
might be able to you know get good skin
contact with a spray even without
shaving you know and there are certainly
endocannabinoid receptors in the skin
and the hair follicles so I mean I think
there's absolutely medical application
there the flip side of it the other
thing that we have to be concerned about
is that you know what anything that you
put on an animal skin is likely to get
licked off and that's a real issue
particularly if you're talking about a
topical product that has THC in it
because again now we have to think about
well how many milligrams of THC is this
dog ingesting because they're licking
this stuff off and is that a concern
from from a toxicity standpoint so it
may be that if people are using topicals
particularly ones that have THC and
they're gonna have to put like you know
like what we call an e-collar like the
lampshade if you will something on them
to prevent them from turning around and
looking that stuff off so Gary before we
move on to talking a little bit about
pet nutrition I do want to point out
that that there's not any quality
standards that are enforced for for pet
medications and there are a lot of folks
that are in the you know in the green
rush that are bringing cannabinoid
isolate products to the market and as
we've learned with humans it's very
important to use a whole plant
preparation because these individual
molecules say for example CVD which is
short for cannabidiol a lot of people
put out products that are just that
individual molecule in some kind of
vehicle and there then they suggest that
it might work just like all the studies
say and yet the vast majority of the
studies are all focused on whole plant
preparations meaning you do a whole
plant extraction and you not only have
the cannabidiol there but you also have
the other novel cannabinoids that the
the can of flavin that and all the other
parts of the cannabis plant that that
are found in the in the trichome oil
they're also and they work together to
do what's called beyond taraj effect
they work together as a as a complex
lock that unlocks the endocannabinoids
system well unfortunately there's a lot
of people who are bringing products in
the market that are just these
individual molecule isolates and so my
question for you is do you find that
whole plant preparations are preferred
for animals just like they are for
humans you know that's a it's a really
good question and and you know that is
certainly that is certainly something
that certainly something that comes up a
lot because as you say i mean there's a
lot of people out there that are looking
to make money in the cannabis industry
and and you know certainly CBD isolates
are certainly one of the things that are
out there you know i in my office I
practice what I would describe as
integrative medicine meaning that I I
offer both conventional Western care but
also holistic and natural medicine and
and we use a lot of herbal preparations
in this office both Western herbs
Chinese herbs what have you and and as
such I am a very big fan of the
entourage effect and of whole plant
extracts in my experience I find that
those products tend to work better
usually then then isolated compounds and
I think that this kind of plays out a
little bit if you look at for example if
you look at reports from people who are
who are taking medications like Marinol
which is synthetic THC so that's
basically just pure THC isolate that was
uh that was manufactured synthetically
molecularly speaking it's the same THC
that you would find in cannabis it's
just that there's nothing else there and
very frequently those people will report
that whole plant cannabis tends to work
better for them than just the THC
isolate so I mean I think that I think
that it bears out that these isolate
products you know speaking in
generalities do not work as well as a
really good quality full-spectrum
extract very good so one thing that's
interesting about folks everybody and
how they acquire endocannabinoid
deficiency we generally suggest that
unless you're predisposed to it people
generally get endocannabinoid deficient
from from stress and anxiety and poor
sleep and poor nutrition and
environmental toxins and things that
generally run the body down to a point
that it's not making its own endogenous
cannabinoids effectively anymore and
then we go and supplement it with phyto
cannabinoids from the plant but I know
that you are an expert also on on pet
nutrition and I know we're talking about
a lot of different animals today right
but but I think that one of the key
things is that if people put the care
into the proper nutrition of their
animals that even if something goes
wrong there their body's more likely to
bring their endocannabinoid system back
into balance and and and thus the other
systems back into homeostasis all on its
own so outside of the use of of you know
supplementing with cannabinoids what's a
perspective that you would offer to
people who care for their animals just
so their nutrition is high enough that
endocannabinoid deficiency is less
likely sure
so just to speak to endocannabinoid
deficiency specifically i mean that is a
that is a very very difficult if not
impossible thing to really prove in
give an individual so it's a it's a very
difficult thing to it's very difficult
thing to quantify that said you know you
can't have good health without nutrition
you know without without appropriate
nutrition and you know I mean no matter
no matter what kind of supplements no
matter what form of cannabis a patient
may be taking if they're not eating
right then they're probably not going to
be healthy in that you know I mean
that's that's always the first
conversation I have with anybody that
brings their pet into my office is is is
what what ideal nutrition looks like for
their pet because that's got to be the
foundation to everything and so so what
do you is there a general guidance like
what I'm kind of like poking at is do
you recommend that that people give
their animals like whole foods that they
that they you know go to the extents to
to make them meals are is is is an
animal chow if sufficient I don't
actually have an opinion on this I'm
just curious along with probably a lot
of the listeners gotcha so so I am very
much a proponent of fresh whole food
diets so you know the bottom line is is
that no animal or no person evolved
eating highly processed foods you know
so you know our bodies are not
particularly
ideally equipped to to eat things out of
a can or out of a bag so so you know my
preference is always to have my patients
eating eating fresh whole food diets now
whether those diets are raw food versus
cooked food that they've purchased from
a company that makes it or if they're
making food at home using an
appropriately balanced recipe you know
any of those things any of those things
are fine but but you know as is the case
with all of us the fresher and the more
Whole Foods they're eating the better
off they're going to be right on so you
know mostly we've been talking about
using cannabinoids today as
as a solution something's wrong but what
do you think about using cannabinoids as
a preventative like your your animal
already is healthy and yet we know that
THC prevents cancer or long-term and we
know that supplementing the
endocannabinoid system with cannabidiol
is generally good for health what do you
think about giving supplementation with
cannabinoids even if the patient is not
presenting a problem you know what I
mean I think what we're really talking
about here is micro dosing and and the
truth of the matter is is I don't know I
don't know that anybody really knows in
the sense of you know as we've discussed
I mean we have so little research as far
as as far as use of cannabis to treat
known disease you know using cannabis as
a preventative is you know I mean I
think it's I think it's an intriguing
question but I have I just have nothing
to offer by way of is that a good thing
or a bad thing
well that fair enough fair enough on
that well dr. Gary Richter thank you so
much for sharing some of your valuable
time with us you know this was this is a
different kind of show for me because I
with a lot of these shows since I and
teach much of this medicine for humans I
kind of know the answers in advance but
I was surprised time and time again
chatting with you so thank you for
sharing your very unique and hard-earned
knowledge and and and good luck on your
pursuits with with the laws changing so
that you can actually start discussing
this with other veterinarians thank you
so much it's been my pleasure to be here
if you'd like to follow up with dr. Gary
Richter or if you'd like to bring your
pet to his office I've got two websites
to share with you if you live in the San
Francisco Oakland area and you actually
want to visit his office you can find
out more about the office at holistic
vet care com now if you want to access
dr. Gary Richter's brain but you don't
necessarily live in the California you
can also go to his website where he
provides general pet information on a
range of issues where you can read that
and then and then apply it wherever you
and that's at dr. Gary rector calm and
Richter's spelled RI CH ter so it's dr.
Gary Richter calm and that's you can
find general information about your pet
that is not going to involve you having
to go into the office you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shaping fire
calm and on Apple iTunes stitcher and
Google Play if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you'd leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire i've been your
host
Shango lows
[Music]