[Music]
the radically dysfunctional American
Health Care System programs us to get
sick get on long-term prescriptions and
get some expensive body scans until
we're out of money and benefits our
Health Care system is in shambles after
the insurance company capture of
independent hospitals and the
mismanagement of the coveted pandemic
more and more people are realizing that
there is no one coming to save us after
a life of processed food alcohol stress
and poor sleep there is no greater
wealth than keeping your health or
improving your health if you are already
at a deficit
the vast majority of people find their
way to cannabis medicine after Western
medicine has failed them
for the 10 years I've been helping
patients nearly everyone who has
approached me for direction and cannabis
use has already been spent dry by the
Health Care system and given little to
show for it
cannabis medicine is still considered a
last resort for most folks I propose
that we start looking more at cannabis
as a preventative a potent source of
stability both physically and
emotionally
for True longevity cannabis can take
some time to Bear fruits but the results
from early and daily use of cannabis
offers rewards that are often described
as miraculous by traditional doctors
pairing daily cannabinoids with Whole
Foods and less alcohol could possibly be
today's Fountain of Youth
if you want to learn about cannabis
Health cultivation and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we're giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter there's nothing else you need
to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shapingfire.com to
sign up for the newsletter this week and
be entered into this month's and all
future newsletter prize drawings
you are listening to shapingfire and I
am your host shangolos
my guest today is neuroscientist and
cannabinoid researcher Hunter land PhD
Hunter land is the vice president of
research and development at
biopharmaceutical research company one
of the few DEA schedule 1 FDA compliant
cannabinoid research and development
companies
he has 20 years of r d expertise across
25 different indications as well as 12
years of cannabinoid focused research
as an expert in the field of cannabinoid
science he has developed a pipeline of
Discovery work on over 20 novel
cannabinoids and terpenes
previously Dr land acted as the senior
scientific director director of
cannabinoid research and scientific
spokesperson at canopy growth most
notably though he was GW pharma's first
full-time r d employee in the United
States where he played a critical role
in the development of epidiolex and
sadavex and co-authored multiple
protocols for the treatment of
refractory epilepsy multiple sclerosis
and pain
Dr Lan has presented over 50 scientific
conferences is a named inventor on nine
patent applications and has over 20
Publications
Hunter serves as guest lecturer at the
University of Wisconsin and the
University of Colorado Skaggs School of
Pharmacy and holds other important
positions including Chief scientific
officer for the National Hockey League
alumni scientific board member of the
veterinary cannabis society and member
of The Advisory board for the Council of
federal cannabis regulation
special thanks to the folks at medicinal
genomics who shared Hunter's
presentation on longevity at can Med
2023 this year on YouTube can Med
deserves a lot of credit for making
these presentations public and not
gatekeeping them you can find links to
Hunters and all the other can Med
presentations on the shapingfire website
page for this episode during the first
set today we will discuss what longevity
is in practice the mechanics of Aging at
the metabolic level how increasing
cellular energetics improves your health
span and how the endocannabinoid system
plays a significant role in all of this
the chunky second set is devoted to
discussing individual cannabinoids their
longevity benefits on particular Health
Systems functional cannabinoid ratios
and how to go about determining an
individualized dosing strategy to meet
your goals including a vibrant
discussion of using whole plant resin
versus cannabinoid isolate and during
the third short set we will focus
specifically on a few cautions to
consider when taking cannabinoids to
extend your functional life
welcome to shaping fire hunter
uh thanks so much for having me so you
know getting right into it
um one of the things I like about your
presentations is you make this very
delicate delineation about lifespan and
health span because so often people just
think about how long will I live
um but but as I get older I realize that
there's a lot of difference in quality
of life
um if I get older and sicker so will you
tease those apart for us so that um you
kind of set us up for the direction
we're headed in today
of course um I think it's a critical
distinction living a really long life
but not a robust Life field of activity
is certainly a shortcoming right so we
don't want uh to have the situation
where we can live you know well over 100
years but our last 30 years we're unable
to do the things you know the normal
activities of daily living that we enjoy
that goes to quality of life so a lot of
us researchers we don't just look at how
long something could keep you alive we
look at the quality of life there in the
middle and interesting enough that kind
of middle set of Health span measures
mainly around activity level seems to
feed quite well into lifespan generally
so those who are maintain health and
health span measures in the middle of
Life often as an extension of that
extend lifespan quite significantly and
and those who extend lifespan often
don't have this prolonged
unfortunate lack of activity at the the
terminal terminal years of their life
so that definitely gives us the idea
that you know uh in one case in one way
it might be better to live a higher
quality shorter life than a longer life
that's lower quality because if you're
if you're really getting sicker the last
20 years uh it's like increasingly being
in a prison and yet you're still alive
exactly you know I think the the goal
ultimately would be both and I think we
can achieve both with some level of
intervention and we've seen you know an
extensive change in lifespan if you go
back maybe 100 to 150 years
you know average life expectancy was
about 35 years uh you know it was
riddled with problems around giving
birth uh infections you know lack of
surgery and now we have those things and
we've been able to extend life but
unfortunately the health span remains to
be problematic and that kind of those
middle years of life and ultimately
impact age-related disease
so I don't think that we need to
convince very many people that living a
long and healthy life is the goal so
that's probably going to be our easiest
thing to you know try to convince people
of today so so let's move right on to
the the the the the part of that the
endocannabinoid
um system can play in this you know
um I'm gonna I'm gonna start with how I
normally explain the endocannabinoid
system just because a patient's dig it
um uh but but then I'm going to ask you
to give us like a you know a more
elaborate scientific explanation but
um to people who have never come across
the endocannabinoid system before I
always say that it's it's very similar
to being a second grade teacher in the
room you know you've got you've got the
teacher in the room and you've got all
these students and when the teachers in
the room all the kids are pretty much
doing what they're supposed to be doing
but then if the teacher gets called out
of the room the kids might be good for a
few minutes but eventually one kid
cracks up and then another kid cracks up
and then like all the kids are cracking
up and then and then eventually the
teacher comes back in the room and has
to settle everybody back down and our
endocannabinoid system is in the same
way like even you know if if the
endocannabinoid system gets weakened
eventually one of the systems that it
moderates will go bad and then another
one will and another one and it may be
different systems
um that are falling out of balance for
different people first but um you know
the chaos increases as they run into
each other so you know you know at that
that explanation would certainly never
fly at one of your scientific
conferences
um so I I would appreciate it if you
would explain in a more scientific way
um how the endocannabinoid system acts
as the body's Master regulator for all
of these Mission critical systems
oh well I think the analogy is is really
interesting and and suitable I I like to
think of it generally the
endocannabinoid system as the rest
relaxed restore system of the body I
think that was something that uh Ethan
Russo uh one of my mentors refers to it
as and I think it's a good
representation of of how that system
works if you look at the brain uh the
cannabinoid one receptors these are
receptors that a THC is an Agonist or
activates these receptors as well as
your own body's cannabinoids or
endogenous cannabinoids and that's
essentially how the system functions is
by either local activation your own
bodies endocannabinoid system or by
external cannabinoids and and THC I
think is is one of the the best examples
of of what we would call a partial
Agonist at CB1 and the way an easy way
to think of this again not trying to go
in too much detail but your brain it has
neurotransmitters that that signal for
effects and these things can be certain
neurotransmitters may act like
stimulants so think caffeine and other
benzodiazepines so things Xanax and
these are signaling Pathways but if you
get too much release of the stimulant
component so that's glutamate or the
benzodiazepine the the Xanax like
component which would be Gaba things can
go awry because we we don't want these
systems to be out of control just like
your your second graders in the
classroom and and the the second grade
teacher so to speak would be your your
endocannabinoid system which actually
tells these neurotransmitters to stop to
settle down to calm down to not release
as much of this neurotransmitter
essentially like a reset switch for
those systems the interesting component
is this happens on a very localized
level so you're not reprimanding the
whole classroom room your body doesn't
you know punish all the kids if only two
of them were bad it only focuses on
those two bad children or the two uh the
small section of neurotransmission
that's gone awry the important
difference here is when you take a
exogenous cannabinoids so like THC it
can down regulate
all of that system so the stimulation
and the inhibitory or the the xanax-like
effect which can be problematic if you
if you use too much uh then that's where
you get massive anxiety and paranoia so
it's a very
um particular system
that can be regulated well on its own
and in many cases may need to be
regulated or can people can benefit from
regulation uh using something like THC
so we're not going to dwell too much on
the mechanics but I do have a couple of
a couple other questions to go down this
path before before we switch
um you know often we will talk about uh
certain cannabinoids uh being in an
Agonist or an antagonist and my
understanding is an Agonist essentially
is turning on something or an antagonist
is turning off something and often you
know lay people will talk about
um you know this or that cannabinoid
turning on or off a receptor
um causing a particular effect or
another
um is it is it really like that black
and white zero and one do do do do these
end agonists and antagonists really just
flip a switch and it's either a or b or
is it more analog where there's a range
of of how much it is being at agonized
or antagonized yeah absolutely there's a
tremendous range and and you know we
could probably do a show on just that
component or just that question which uh
I think we'll we'll skip some of those
details but the the degree to which you
stimulate or agonize a receptor or block
it uh can be very powerful or it can be
more gentle right so THC is not a very
potent Agonist it doesn't it's not like
a sledgehammer for your your CB1
receptor there's some synthetic
cannabinoids like spice and K2 that are
extremely inebriating and very potent
and very dangerous and can cause a lot
of side effects there's also antagonists
so at lower doses thcv so similar to THC
but with two less carbons on the tail it
can be an antagonist so it can actually
block your endocannabinoids and May lead
to a very different effect there was a
drug called Ramada band that was
designed to be an antagonist and
unfortunately it's something we call
inverse agonists so it's not like THC I
think is the the important point and and
what happened with that particular drug
is it caused increase
suicidal ideation so people were
depressed some people were depressed and
some people had Suicidal Thoughts they
also lost weight and seemed to help
regulate blood sugar and a couple other
aspects so your point of how strong
something is at either blocking a
receptor or stimulating receptor
especially as it relates to medicine and
and health outcomes is of critical
importance
so circling this mechanics conversation
back to this idea of longevity and um
you know that that bigger holistic
picture
um
you know when we think about the
endocannabinoid system and its ability
to to you know uh uh turn on and off
different systems to bring them into
balance things that are running hot it
can have it settle down or if something
is too sluggish it can suddenly be
stimulated by the endocannabinoid system
most of us
um you know folks who are cannabis
enthusiasts but are not researchers
um you know we we throw around the ideas
of the CB1 and CB2 receptor you know
pretty pretty liberally even if if not
necessarily scientifically accurate just
so that we can un you know generally
understand
um how to dose ourselves one way or
another and um and and I know that um
you know CBD doesn't really act upon
those receptors and yet we still
consider it part of the endocannabinoid
system which which clearly suggests that
the endocannabinoid system is made up of
more than just these uh
neurotransmitters and and these two
receptors now now I know again it would
be an entire show to ask you to review
all of the parts the endocannabinoid
system but what I'm what I'm looking for
is is
um for you to just give us a a quick uh
survey of of who makes up the
endocannabinoid system like what parts
because in in you know in in a little
bit in the show we're going to be
talking about how we're working with the
endocannabinoid system and I want to
make sure that people understand the
reach
sure well the endocannabinoid system is
is heavily uh integrated with so many
other systems in your body it can couple
or affect Upstream Downstream things
like serotonin which is associated with
depression dopamine which I think we're
all well versed and and what dopamine uh
actions of dopamine are but also
critical roles and inflammation and mood
sleep so you know it's it's heavily
integrated so I I've personally like to
think of the endocannabinoid system in a
classical case so just CB1 and CV2 in
the endogenous ligands so the
cannabinoids that your body makes and
then the Transporters whether that's
because you have to get these from point
A to point B and they're all Targets for
potential making of medicines and and
maybe plant molecules modulating these
systems
once you go outside of that then you
start calling a lot of different things
the endocannabinoid system so for
instance trip receptors trp receptors
especially trip V1 we know is activated
by cannabinoids and sometimes
desensitized that's the same receptor
for the spicy taste right and that's
actually an ion channel so that's just
an example of another system altogether
that cannabinoids can function at but
isn't necessarily A what I would
consider the classical
endocannabinoid system
but to your point there are tons of
targets especially for CBD we know there
are about 68 different targets meaning
places where CBD may work or function in
the body and almost all of those are
outside of the endocannabinoid system
and the same can be said for probably at
least a hundred of the other
phytocannabinoids found in cannabis that
their principal role is probably not CB1
or CB2
so so in a way of summary will you make
the case rule for me real quick uh make
the case that for for somebody wanting
um to you know increase their health
span why working with the
endocannabinoid system is a great place
for you to be working
well I think you know the
endocannabinoid system is as I mentioned
the rest relax restore system of the
body it's the importance around
inflammation and the immune system is
critical and when we think about
age-related diseases a lot of these are
mediated by our body's inflammatory
response autoimmune response and and
things that have gone awry so if your
body's able to keep these components in
check then maybe you do have better
health span and and lifespan measures by
just keeping everything in this nice
balance of where it should be in
homeostasis and not outside of that I
think that's a certainly a a has strong
potential for extending life and and
activity and secondly I think there's a
big role for cannabinoids and
endocannabinoids around mitochondrial
health and mitochondria if you remember
back to grade school or the PowerHouse
of the cells so as these things go into
decline
um you know you have problems with
cellular energetics which if you don't
have energy for your engine of your cell
then kind of everything starts to go
awry
when when people talk about
um you know cannabis medicine and all
the things that it can help
um people new to cannabis medicine will
also have often have this reaction that
um oh you think cannabis is a Panacea
you know it's it can just cure
everything that's ridiculous nothing can
cure that much and and what I tell them
is it really only helps one thing it it
helps balance the endocannabinoid system
and and and the issue is that all of
your body's systems play into the
endocannabinoid system so really the
canvas plant really has one job which is
to keep the endocannabinoid system in
balance and and in my head I always
think of it as you know the Endo the
only thing that you can do other than
the endocannabinoid system that can have
such far-reaching effects to heal and
restore the human body is eating a Whole
Foods diet because that too reaches
every part of your body
um how does that set for you
well I I think it's an interesting point
um I first thing I would like to say is
cannabis is not cannabis is not cannabis
right because we know that there are I
think last time I checked about 545
potentially active compounds that can be
found in cannabis and we estimate right
now there may be up to 150 different
phytocannabinoids and they're all very
unique right so when we use cannabis as
just a plant it is a very unique plant
because of the compounds it produces
these are things like terpenes and
terpenoids and flavonoids and obviously
cannabinoids as well as a lot of
components that were not even really uh
well versed in as of yet the science
hasn't really directed us to examine all
these components and and with that being
said the complexity is which of these
components worked well well where and
how does that affect disease
so to your point if we're talking THC
and some of the other cannabinoids then
then you know endocannabinoid system may
be critical but if you look at something
like CBD I would I would make an
argument for uh the principal areas of
action are not
um directly related maybe upstream or
Downstream but not directly related to
the endocannabinoid system so again
another level of complexity
um to a very very complex situation I
agree with your statement about food I
have a deep interest in nutrition I
would also add
exercise and potentially fasting to that
as having a systemic a beneficial effect
to treat multiple diseases
um I've heard you talk before about
um you know that the aging process as
part of this overall topic of living a
longer healthier life and um and people
often think talk about like the body's
clock and and how you can turn back the
clock or stop the clock or you know
different ways that that people use that
turn of phrase and
um I'm curious at a I guess a
biomechanical level what does the the
the the body's clock
um what what is that mechanism you know
in passing I've heard people say oh
folate is the body's clock but like I
don't actually know what that means
oh man this is uh I think there's a lot
of components to dive into here
um when you talk about body's clock a
lot of this has to do with um their
compounds within cells called sirtuins
and they regulate something called
epigenetics and you can think of this uh
the genetics is kind of the recipe and
the epigenetics
um it could can either cover portions of
the recipe or uncover them for
production of critical components
for health span and lifespan so your
body basically looks at the recipe and
makes what it needs over time those
recipes get damaged and
um to the degree that cannabinoids play
a role interacting with these sirtuins
and helping regulate these genes isn't
incredibly clear but I think when people
largely when people talk about their
bodies clock uh they're they're thinking
about how this information gets damaged
over time and then measuring lengths of
things
called telomeres where you can get a
kind of a biological age and they seem
to map some of these compounds seem to
map with biological age which is very
different than chronological age
so um so if I were to summarize that
like you know if I was talking to a
friend or somebody I I would say that
you know our when we're young or when
we're born our body is born with a um a
set of recipes to to make various
um you know chemicals and parts that
make us human and and as we get older
um that the recipe book
um starts to get uh corrupted over time
and so the recipes don't get made right
anymore and and therefore the
functioning uh continues to degrade
until you know the souffle flattens and
we die
um is is that is that one way to say
what you're saying sure I think that's
one way you start out making chocolate
chip cookies and and you know at the end
they don't look anything like chocolate
chip cookies because you've got this
disrupted recipe and I think that's
that's one component and the other
component
um you know has to do with cellular
energetics and and also the cleaning of
of the cell so getting rid of the bad
and coming in with the new and and that
also gets damaged over time the your
body's ability to heal which I think
everybody can can agree that you know an
80 year old individual does not have the
same ability to to heal their injured
knee as you know a 10 year old and that
ability declines over time for for
multiple reasons and some of that is
your own body's adaptation to to
Cleansing the bad and bringing in the
new
if as we age
um our the recipes are getting corrupted
and and and and what we want is thriving
cellular energy energetics
um so that we have a longer Health span
what what is it that is degrading these
recipes that potent cellular
energetics is able to undo or defend
against
I think it's a great point A lot of
people are investigating this I mean
there are some people that just have
great genetics from the start these
centenarians you know that live over a
hundred a lot of them have smoked
cigarettes their whole life and maybe
drink too much Etc but they were just
you know blessed with uh you know this
genetic predisposition of just having
this really robust uh genetic system
that takes care of their their uh the
health of their DNA and their cells but
for most of us we don't have that and
the things that we can control are
largely environmental so that's what we
put in our body the amount of rest and
sleep that we get
the toxins that that may be around us
and activity level and I think those are
that pretty much sums up
um you know
the
outcomes of how well we can maintain
these recipes and the cellular Health as
we age
you know it's kind of ironic that that
even though you know the the underlying
kind of point of the discussion today is
is you know growing and using uh
cannabis medicine as a a supplement can
increase your health and your your
health span at the same time
um it's not lost on me that we keep on
coming back to the best thing that you
can do for your health span is to uh eat
well sleep well and exercise and and
except for maybe you know Whole Foods
more or less like those are all those
are free things right those are things
that don't cost money and yet they're
the hard thing to do and so people are
all like you know I still want to stay
up too late I would still like to eat
like crap I don't really want to
exercise but I would really like to buy
this bottle of vitamins and just eat
these and get away with living my crappy
life
right right it's much easier yeah and
and we see that you know with with
modern medicine uh you know for instance
some patients that are diabetic may be
able to manage it
um with diet and exercise
um and I'm not a physician so you know
consult your physician before you do any
of that but it could in the early stages
is
potentially be managed with diet and
exercise but it's much easier to take a
pill or a shot or take a medication than
to put all that effort into controlling
something uh more naturally right on so
um with that said we certainly recommend
a Whole Foods diet exercise and uh and
good sleep but we also want to be able
to um you know do the best we can and so
we're going to continue the conversation
now and talk about
um you know some cannabinoids and and
what their mechanics look like in the
body
um to support this uh this increasing
Health span that we want to get now
um you know yeah there's there's you
know 545 compounds and and 150
phytocannabinoids and clearly we're not
going to go through them all today and
and you know I don't really think we
need to either because for for most
listeners we're really only going to
have access to
um you know CBD THC CBG and then whole
plant resins that will have a smattering
of these other phytocannabinoids in it
which we may not even know about because
they might not be testing form in the
COA so
um so we'll just 100 yeah well so let's
just focus on these because this is what
people really have access to and so we
might and I don't want to I want to keep
this relevant to real people you know so
so so since you've already started
talking about CBD and the plethora of
targets I think you like said 68 or
something something like way bigger than
um most people take for granted
um um and I'm I'm we're going to start
with CBD and then I'm gonna hit like all
you know all of the next three but but
let's start with CBD
um what is it that we are hoping that
CBD does you know when people ask me I
just generally say we want the CBD
supplement as an um to re that we get
from the plant to replace an endogenous
cannabinoid That We're Not Making or
that we're depleted in or we don't have
enough of so so our our body doesn't
have enough and so we take CBD to
replace it and and then it helps keep
things in Balance how would you discuss
it as a as a cannabinoid researcher
I would um
I would discuss it a little bit
different because most of my work around
CBD has been in treating disease and
primarily you know the the at least the
initial work I've done with CBD was an
epilepsy specifically a lot of
refractory childhood epilepsies like
Gervais and Lennox Gusto where these
children had failed you know 14
different modern medications and were on
three or four and still having hundreds
seizures a month and we do see CBDs
quite effective generally reducing about
50 percent of seizures with some
patients being seizure free and it
doesn't work like these other anti
-epileptic drugs or these anti-seizure
drugs
that's I think the the
really clear component is that we know
that it is safe and effective for
seizures but these doses are much higher
than what you would take CBD as a
supplement so in the clinical trials you
know patients were taking you know
between 500 and 1500 sometimes more
milligrams of CBD a day
now would that be lower if it was a
whole plant extract I think it would
have to be lower because the whole plant
extracts contain THC would that be
better it's certainly possible that it
would be better but but again we would
really need to do that research THC is
also an anti-convulsant so as you and
your listeners probably know if you're
getting a whole plant extract the
overwhelming majority of them still have
some THC present which which may be a
benefit to some patients with epilepsy
it could also be Pro convulsant to some
patients and it may be of critical
importance to areas like pain and and
maybe areas like anxiety now as you go
down in doses there's been some evidence
that CBD is a is a pretty powerful
anxiolytic we've seen that for things
like public speaking they haven't done
any work with podcasting yet but maybe
that's a that's an option we do see that
the anxiety tends to go down in several
studies and that seems to be at lower
doses if you bring that dose down
further to let's say 25 milligrams
they're really hasn't been a lot of
research to say you know what do these
low doses do and um and that's because
you know it may not be doing much at low
doses or it may be that it takes a long
time to see those effects for example if
you eat a healthy diet or you take a
certain uh nutritional supplements you
may not see that immediately it may be
down the road where you see benefit and
those are things that are very difficult
to to look at and very expensive to look
at in a scientific setting we often talk
about psilocybin on this show and that's
the kind of the idea whole idea behind
micro dosing right is that is that you
just take a little bit every day and so
the materials are there and it's the
it's the constancy over time that uh
allows the for the neurogenesis and
Improvement in in the in the brain
um one of the things that always gets me
about CBD though you know where where
I'm asking you about
you know the function of CBD so as as
somebody who's looking for longevity
knows
um you know what the CBD is like doing
for them it's it it doesn't really
discriminate right it kind of gets into
everything and so it's almost like all
right
I can't tell you specifically what CBD
is going to do for you and how soon but
I can tell you that CBD does so much
good for so many different systems that
you should just take it and and just let
it decide where it's going to work
well when you have multiple
mechanisms multiple ways of of having
some sort of benefit
you know if there's one area that's not
problematic it may not modulate that
particular system which potentially
could give benefit if there's another
area where that needs modulation or
activity and to your point earlier that
I kind of glossed over CBDs relevant to
the endocannabinoid system there's been
a lot of study about it being a negative
alloster modulator meaning like it it
can reduce
the ability for things like THC to
attach to that receptor there's been
some other things like a boost or
endocannabinoids your body's own
cannabinoids I think those are kind of
difficult to really understand if that's
really a mechanism but one of the really
interesting uh studies that that I think
has just been published was in fragile X
which is a type of seizure disorder and
these patients have disruptive
endocannabinoid systems specifically
endocannabinoid
and it appears that CBD was able to
restore that and it may be because
you're not a CBD May prevent the
internalization so uh the basically The
Disappearance of of these CB1 receptors
so think of a uh you know a a tree that
gets sucked back down into the dirt
right so when the tree is gone then it
doesn't matter you know what type of
molecule you have to stick to that
particular receptor there's nothing
there to activate so it is possible that
that CBD May prevent some of this
internalization which would be good for
uh
an amyloid system as a whole
so I'm sure that we can describe
um several different cannabinoids in
that similar way where where they can
participate uh in in several different
ways in several different systems
um but but we do know that CBG can have
a gerol actually does different things
than CBD does so I so next like would
you make a delineation
um and explain to us what is different
about CBG than CBD and and how you have
found it acting or you know what what
the state of the science is for CBG
because even though you know most
cannabis enthusiasts are relatively new
to CBG
um you know researchers have been
jumping on it as you know the exciting
new novel cannabinoid for a few years
now
mm-hmm yeah I love CBG I think it's a
really interesting molecule to study it
is available which some of these other
minor cannabinoids are not available and
it is quite distinct from both THC and
CBD and mechanism
um for your listeners they probably know
that you know cbga the acid form is
considered the the mother of all
cannabinoids it it is after CBG your the
plant that can
the cam produces thca or cbda which
which we know very well but it is a
principal component and a lot of
available cultivars of cannabis now
which makes it easy for us to or at
least easier for us to study and it's
also not a schedule one compound so Labs
don't have to have all these
certifications to examine it so that's
that's step one it's not been available
that long so we don't know nearly as
much about CBG as we do THC and CBD
primarily we know that they're different
and then we do know that there's some
unique properties for for CBG around
immune system regulation and around
there's something called nucleotide
receptors and those are things that are
activated on the nucleus of cells so it
may be very important for coding
things that your body produces that are
of benefit or preventing things from
being that are problematic since the
theme for the day is um is Health span
and Longevity will you speak a little
bit to cbg's activity on the immune
system
sure well we do see down regulation in
in a lot of things that are potentially
problematic like uh tumor necrosis
factor and interleukins which can be
kind of broadly destructive and are are
common in a lot of disease States
autoimmune related disease states that
result in pain and neurodegeneration
Etc so so we do know that it has
activity there the interesting thing
will be be to learn does that in
combination with other cannabinoids does
that have a additive or super additive
effect that can really help treat some
of these diseases and conditions
um for folks who haven't come across
that vocabulary before I'd like you to
briefly explain
um uh additive and more specifically
super additive because
um we continually make the case for
people to consider finding
um either you know whole plant or built
cannabis medicines that that have
several of these cannabinoids and this
idea of of of of of the the sum being
better being
um more effective than the parts I think
people I want people to be able to wrap
their heads around that
sure I and I love the subject
um I think a lot of people talk about
the Entourage effect
um it's a very interesting topic and we
do see
um I like to think of the Entourage
effect is is super additive right and
what that would mean so let's take a
step back so additive I think of
additive as very simply as one plus one
equals two right so if you're taking
let's say two medications
um and one of them reduces your pain by
half or let's say 20 and the other one
by itself would reduce pain by 20 if you
take them together and you get a 40
reduction in pain then that would be
additive one plus one equals two which
is benefit right because you may not be
able to to take medication one at a
higher dose because it may be toxic or
maybe it just doesn't work Beyond
reducing 20 percent same thing with
medication too so you have this additive
effect but sometimes we see these
synergies where we have two different
medications and you they both reduce
something by 20 but you put them
together and it's it's forty percent
reduction you get a eighty percent
reduction and that's what I would call
Super additive effect and the idea that
um with cannabinoids you may be able to
combine these or they may exist already
in the plant to where by themselves they
would do nothing or they would help
somewhat but when combined they do a lot
more and I think that's what the
Entourage effect is defining and it
could be cannabinoids with other things
that aren't cannabinoids as well like
terpenes or flavonoids like cam flavins
we're not really sure but I do think
it's important to outline that
cannabinoids
specifically sometimes they seem to work
well together and you get this additive
or super additive effect and sometimes
they don't and we've seen that in with
CBD and THC and glaucoma we're using
them to other actually prevents the
benefits or the decrease in the the
pressure in the eye of THC which is
relevant for glaucoma so sometimes it's
great to combine these things but we
need to know what we're combining why
we're combining it and who's it for and
what's the purpose of them taking it and
then we can probably better understand
the the potential for having these
additive or super additive effects great
so I've got one more CBG question before
we go to our first commercial break and
and that is you know
um we have been aware of CBD cannabidiol
for a long time there's now um a a
substantial and growing body of research
on it where you know uh you know except
for in extreme circumstances we're
pretty confident that CBD is is pretty
much good for everybody we don't really
have to be concerned about
um taking it
um and it'll it'll it'll help us or not
but it's it's unlikely to hurt us and
and we were talking about CBG like uh
we're just learning the benefits and and
uh certainly anecdotally we know about
how great it is for things like you know
um anxiety and neuropathy and things
like that but because we know so much
less about it
um do we know yet that uh CBG is you
know can be generally regarded as safe
for everybody uh where where even though
it hasn't been researched fully yet
where we're to the point like listen you
know uh we know CBD is going to be safe
cbg's A lot like it we know enough about
it don't worry about taking it and and
I'll be clear I'll say it for you this
is not medical advice to anybody out
there who is a who's thinking of it that
way but please Hunter
yeah thanks thanks for that
um I don't think we can say it yet you
know I would like to say it
um I will say that in the work I've done
both in C elegans and rodents side by
side with CBD
um I found CBG to be better tolerated at
very high doses than than I have CBD so
um and again these are animal models
talks work usually translates fairly
well to humans but not always I mean
they're I don't know if you remember
years ago there was this uh this drug
this company called bile and they were
making a drug for modulating the
endocannabinoid system it was a thaw
inhibitor and it looked great in rodents
and then they put it in humans and three
patients had like brain death wow now I
don't expect that that is going to
happen with CVG but you don't you don't
always know there's and we certainly
don't know the test you know like the
the level we haven't tested the level uh
to to where we can go with CBG whereas
like you know there's not really an ld50
a lethal dose that kills 50 percent of
the population with THC no known
reported deaths other than I think a guy
got smashed by cannabis in his car in a
car accident
um so I guess that might be related but
in C D also seems very safe acutely
we've given patients like 6 000
milligrams there are concerns with high
doses and and the impact on liver uh
especially with other drugs like
valproic acid we haven't done any of
that work with CBG and it's not as well
known in humans like what doses we could
go to so we're not there yet it looks
promising right now though I think it
looks like a very promising molecule in
terms of both safety and efficacy yeah I
agree CBG just has such amazing effects
specifically for anxiety in the patients
that I've turned on to it and um it's
great where especially when CBD doesn't
work for them I say have you tried CBG
and then they're like oh wow that
actually worked a lot better for me and
it's and it's interesting you know
everybody's you know different and
that's one of the things I like about
cannabis is individualized medicine
because everybody is a bit different so
um our next our next cannabinoid we're
going to talk about is THC but let's do
that after the commercial break so we're
going to take a short break and be right
back you are listening to shaping fire
and my guest today is neuroscientist
Hunter land and you know without these
advertisers shaping fire would not
happen so please support them and let
them know you heard them on shaping fire
foreign
cannabis seed Distributors often seem to
be all the same but Multiverse beans
constantly Works to provide you with
cannabis seeds and a buying experience
that you won't find elsewhere
Multiverse beans Works directly with the
Breeders to secure as many packs of your
favorites as possible so that they have
your favorite beans long after others
have sold out some shops simply buy
breeder minimums but I get messages all
the time from breeders saying some
version of Multiverse asked to buy my
entire run
at multiversebeans.com you can find rare
cannabis seeds from Night Owl seeds
including the dark owl sub label
Mephisto genetics Square One genetics
Robin Hood seeds and Ethos and so many
others
Multiverse also initiates projects with
breeders to secure exclusive packs that
you simply won't find elsewhere
Multiverse founder Paul lall sees
himself not only as a curator of the
best cannabis seeds available but also
as a collaborator with breeders trying
to bring novel crosses to the market
that his customers are asking for
Multiverse beans also creates exclusive
stickers for their popular seed
varieties that are available free only
when you order those seeds from
Multiverse
check out their stickers like the badass
recent slap for Mothman by gnome
automatics on Instagram at Multiverse
beans and finally the freebies as you'd
expect Paul sends quality freebies with
every order and when you spend at least
150 dollars Multiverse allows you to
choose your freebies from their special
selections
you can get a 10 discount off regularly
priced items when you use the discount
code shaping fire all one word at
checkout
sign up for their mailing list to be
eligible for their monthly seed giveaway
worth 250 dollars
so go to
multiversebeans.com now for a buying
experience you won't get anywhere else
businesses everywhere are striving to
reach people through advertising we all
know though that trying to reach a
cannabis audience with a quality message
is pretty difficult that's why many
people choose to advertise on the
shapingfire podcast
advertising on this show allows us time
to talk about your product service or
brand in a way that really lets people
know what sets your company apart from
others bold people who own companies
know that getting into relationship with
their customers is essential and that is
what we offer we will explain your
service or product what sets it apart as
desirable and help our audience get in
contact with you it's pretty simple
really advertising does not have to be
all whiz-bang smoke and mirrors nowadays
I find that people prefer just to be
spoken to calmly accurately and with
good intentions
if you want to make your own commercial
spot well you can do that too
during these pandemic days conventions
and cannabis events are pretty poorly
attended but podcast listening is
skyrocketing
with a commercial and shaping fire
you'll reach your customers in the
privacy of their headphones right now
and will continue to reach new listeners
as they explore the shaping fire back
catalog of episodes again and again for
years
a spot on shaping fire costs less than a
printed postcard per person and the
shaping fire audience is full of smart
cannabis enthusiasts cultivators and
entrepreneurs who are always curious to
learn
do yourself a solid and contact us today
for rates on podcast and Instagram
advertising email hotspot
shapingfire.com to find out more
[Music]
one of the challenges with buying
Autoflower seeds is that often you'll
have as many different phenos as you
will have seeds in a pack that can be
fun sure but so many varieties in one
pack is a sign of an immature seed line
that hasn't been worked enough
I prefer my autoflowers to be worked
enough that each Fino in the pack really
captures the aspects that the breeder
was intending
this is why I recommend gnome automatics
to my friends and listeners who grow
automatic flowering cannabis seeds
gnome automatic seeds are not just
crossed and released they are
painstakingly sifted again and again
tested in a wide range of conditions and
taken to a level of maturity that each
plant will be recognizable by its trades
traits that were hard earned so that you
can have your best growth cycle ever
the last 10 years gnome automatics
founder Dan Jimmy has become a trusted
breeder and he continues to pour His
passion of breeding cannabis into every
variety he releases for you to grow
check out the gnome automatics Instagram
at gnome underscore automatics to see
the impressive plants folks are growing
you can score gnome automatic seeds in
feminized or regular at your favorite
seed provider listed in the vendors
section of their website
commercial cannabis Farms across the
country love growing gnome automatics
because of their consistency from seed
to seed short grow times THC percentages
and colorful bag appeal Farms interested
in bulk seeds of more than a thousand
should reach out through
gnomeautomatics.com
while on the website be sure to check
out the gnome automatic shirts and other
merch section too
if you want reliable seeds hand built
from effort expert selection and
experience choose gnome automatics
welcome back you are listening to
shapingfire I am your host shangelos and
my guest today is neuroscientist
hunterland
so let's pick back up right where we
were with uh THC targets or or thc's
functionality because you know we we
talked a lot about our familiarity and
the substantial body of research we have
in CBD cannabidiol and then how we have
less research in CBG but we're already
seeing all of these fantastic results
anecdotally and we're starting to see
them in the lab as well well THC which
is the cannabinoid that most people love
first in cannabis when they get turned
onto it
um you know it it acts in very uh
different ways than the other
cannabinoids most of them that we really
like so so so why don't you start with
that what are we when we're when we're
taking THC
um with it with longevity and wellness
in mind
um what are the functions of THC that
were that we're looking to include in in
the mix
oh that's a tough one I mean in terms of
longevity there's been we haven't seen
anything that would say that THC is
overtly poor for longevity and we
haven't seen any major problems with
acute toxicity or neurotoxicity at
relevant Doses and there could certainly
be some some protection I would say it's
just not incredibly clear
on how specifically that may help with
longevity other than maybe some
neuroprotection and autoimmune type
components
um
that's that's essentially where we where
we stand right now so so
um let's let's hit on that autoimmune
component real quickly because
um you know there are you know
autoimmune diseases is is at least is
probably becoming way more common but it
is at least becoming uh more commonly
diagnosed and and so what what action
does THC uh take in that Realm
well again
um there's been there have been some
studies especially around like
rheumatoid arthritis and things of that
nature where we've seen clinical benefit
um and there have been some studies
pre-clinically that have outlined uh
some benefit around these cytokines so
these compounds that kind of
indiscriminately kill cells but but
again it's it's difficult to make that
broad leap to say that you know THC is
is certainly going to extend uh lifespan
I think if you have a condition like
let's say and we don't know this
scientifically so just to be clear the
FDA hasn't approved THC or THC
components for anxiety conditions but
let's say
that as many people do often share that
it helps with anxiety or sleep then then
by helping those components by helping
with sleep or or pain sensation or
anxiety you may
indirectly or Downstream effects may may
be that you have improved quality of
life that you have better activities of
daily living that you feel better as a
person and that all feeds into this kind
of Health span category which ultimately
could feed into lifespan
you know I often can uh suggest to
patients who are having inflammatory
issues that doing doing a uh a a CBD
dominant blend with THC so you get the
anti-inflammation properties of both is
a good combination and and for me that
would be the the primary
uh longevity Advantage uh to THC
um are we still seeing that in the in
the research that THC is still you know
considered a beast when it comes to
decreasing inflammation
some models we do see that that THC is
an effective anti-inflammatory we also
see similar effects with CBD and some
really interesting effects for with cbda
and I don't want to go down a rabbit
hole here but
um cbda is the acid version that
happened that that occurs naturally in
the plant before we heat it and I think
both thca again the acid version in the
plant before it's heated or what we call
decarboxylated seem to be really
important for those inflammatory
responses
I think with uh the conversation that
that we're having about THC and how
um you know the the different things
that it can do at different levels this
would be a really good time for us to
address uh the biphasic nature of
cannabinoids because I I think that it
is most obvious to most early users when
it comes to THC so will you review that
for us
oh yes I I think I'm so glad you brought
it up because I think this is probably
one of the more critical uh components
of being able to use especially use THC
for its position potential to treat
disease so you know I think if you look
at the literature and you look at
self-reports a lot of patients will say
THC at lower doses help my anxiety we
know it's approved for increasing
appetite and multiple indications we
know that it helps with nausea I think
those are clear but what's also clear is
this biphasic effect where as you go up
then you lose those properties and in
fact you induce the opposite so low
levels anti-anxiety high levels massive
paranoia low levels increase appetite
reduce nausea high levels vomiting and
nausea the spins Etc so there is this
therapeutic window that I think is an is
incredibly important and this isn't you
know just unique to cannabis and THC
it's also common and like Robitussin for
example
um it could be effective for for as an
expectorant to help you breathe while
you're if you have a cold uh maybe with
cough and congestion but if you drink
the bottle you're probably going to
hallucinate right so there's this
therapeutic window and I think that's
where THC sits the difficult thing
around THC is we mentioned it earlier is
this endocannabinoid tone so you've got
two things in in patients that are are a
little bit confounding when you're doing
cannabis research one of those is how
many CB1 receptors do they have and
where are they because that's why
certain people can take high doses of
cannabis and they're fine and then other
people will take it and they'll have a
lot of problems right
be very prone to anxiety and that's
probably based on the dose and then
secondly is if you're consuming it
orally metabolism and I'm not speaking
like metabolism like how fit are you I'm
talking about these compounds that are
in your liver as well as elsewhere but
primarily in your liver they're called
cytochrome p450s or or sip enzymes for
short and they break down uh a lot of
plant derived molecules and um and these
and what the result is is
the components the outcome so to speak
of of how much exposure it gets to your
brain so certain people just can't break
down THC very well and they get very
very high levels and other people are
rapid metabolizers and they break it
down really quickly so we have to juggle
these two things in research and there's
no way of looking at somebody and saying
oh you're going to break this down
really quickly so I need to give you a
higher dose or you have more CB1
receptors on your Pathways that result
in anxiety so we need to be more careful
wow there's so much in what you just
said let's see all right so going back a
little ways
um uh uh I I I will say this and you do
not have to comment on it but it has
been a long time since I've thought
about Robo tripping uh you know you
talked about drinking the whole bottle
of Robitussin and back when I was a a
you know young freelance
um
pharmacist if you will in college
um you know you know it was something
that we heard you could do and so and so
you know you got to get the right kind
and all this kind of stuff and so we
tried it and it's it's it's it's really
unpleasant for for your gut and
everything
um but oh gosh
um yeah so I I haven't thought about
that in 25 years so so that's
interesting
um uh the the second thing is is um you
know
when we're talking about each person is
going to have their own I don't know
what you'd call it but a biphasic
threshold for THC I think that's another
good reason why when people start to use
um cannabis medicine for the first time
that includes THC that you always start
low and slow because you may be
particularly sensitive you may not be
but but it's better to start slow and
and work your way up based on an actual
plan of the results you want instead of
just assuming you're going to be fine
and starting high and then having to pay
the piper because
um you know when when THC goes from you
know jolly good and relaxing to oh my
God I'm I'm freaking out and do I need
to call paramedics which you don't but
you might you definitely think you might
like that that is a really bad day at
the office
it is bad it is you know THC induced
psychosis is pretty scary I've I've
witnessed some high-dose THC studies the
FDA in in some cases
um wants you to do high-dose studies to
figure out where this threshold is and
it can be quite scary and when we did
some of that work with satavex patients
had to be sedated so remember earlier
when we were talking about Gaba uh the
the benzo like effect being cut off by
CB1 receptors
that's one of the reasons that you get
this anxiety so one of the treatments to
prevent that is to give benzos and
that's often what can happen in hospital
settings when patients get this massive
paranoia so it is it is scary
um with for those of you who don't know
what side of X is it's a it's a
basically a 50 50 blend of a two
different plants high THC and CBD plant
that was used in clinical trials and a
lot of the research that we have around
cannabinoids is based on that particular
medicine that's approved you know in
about 28 countries but not in the U.S
and when that they did those trials as
they continue to learn about it they had
a self-titration built in to the
clinical trials and this is something I
worked on uh in a good bit of depth and
you know we would see patients kind of
all over the map some would have six
administrations a day and some would
have 12. and you can never look at them
and tell and we asked them to balance
the safety and efficacy so to go up to
the point where they felt like it was
helping and they weren't getting bad
side effects and and I think that's a
good rule of thumb if you're using THC
actually going to the point where you're
intoxicated may be negative there's some
evidence that when you get really high
you increase sensation to pain and
increased sensation to to feeling in
general I mean you know if you go back
to the 60s when a lot of cannabis was
being used at you know music festivals I
I don't know that they were doing it to
decrease sensation and and it may be
that that lower doses are better for
treating pain than intoxicating doses
so I want to take a sidebar because you
mentioned a topic that I'm very
interested in and that it's very hard to
find information on and that is a rapid
metabolizers so so I only learned about
rapid metabolizers you know about about
four years ago or so and um and it
explains a lot and and so I I want to
set it up in a certain way and then I'd
just like you to speak to it because you
know in cannabis it is it is very common
for people to have
um dumb internet arguments about dosage
right and and you know you know Dr Russo
is is talking about you know Optimum
doses for THC you know you know well
under well under 20 for nearly everybody
and whereas other times you're you're
you're you're you're you know I'll watch
somebody eat a 200 milligram edible of
THC and I'm like how in the hell is that
even possible and okay if somebody is a
long-term chronic pain patient certainly
tolerance can be made up over time but
sometimes these people are like newbies
and and they're just eating that and and
it doesn't seem to phase them and and I
didn't really understand that there were
these rapid metabolizer people until I
met a whole family of them and
um it was interesting I was
um you know aware of their cannabis
usage and and the doses that they were
telling me that they were taking for
their various issues
um were like as far as I was concerned
they were off the charts like they were
they were really high they were you know
to you know to to to to relax after work
you know somebody who was relatively new
was was taking you know 80 milligrams of
of THC and RSO and I'm like you've got
to be kidding me I'd be I'd be crying at
80 milligrams let alone without my
tolerance that I've got from years of
use right
um and then uh I was at a a music event
on the island with one of the people in
this family and I watched them eat five
grams of mushrooms for their first time
and um and and it and it didn't affect
them and and they're like oh I'm a rapid
metabolizer you know it it just my body
just like metabolizes everything like I
can't have any fun and I'm like man hey
you're lucky because taking a heroic
dose like that without knowing it your
first time could be also be a really bad
day so so it's weird because rapid
metabolizers
um they explain a lot of these kind of
Black Swan events that that as somebody
who is trying to support people to learn
about you know cannabis medicine
specifically but you know the wider
field of entheogens as well these people
like they they their biology Breaks the
Rules so would you just speak to the I
don't know the metabolics of of of rapid
metabolizers
sure you know it's it's fairly common
that a proportion in these trials will
have rapid
metabolizers and there's actually a test
that we can do so it's about 450 dollars
and you can be tested to find out which
enzyme so the enzymes are the components
that break down these plant compounds as
well as other compounds like drugs in
the liver and you can look and you can
say oh wow I have a really elevated or
I'm most likely to metabolize drugs that
are through the 3a4 pathways so sip 3a4
or 2c19 there are a bunch of these
different enzymes and they could say
pretty definitively say you know if you
take these drugs you're going to have to
take higher levels or they're not going
to work because as soon as they get to
your liver they're going to be broken
down immediately so that that does
happen and you can also have the the
opposite effect where a lot of patients
will will break them down very slowly
and they have to go with ultra low doses
to avoid you know toxicity and side
effects the other interesting component
here too is that that kind of levels
goes on with this is the is the food
effects so you know Administration in
let's say a gummy could be very
different than Administration with fat
we know that with THC if it's taken with
with a high fat meal you increase
exposure three to five fold so that
brings on another level you know you've
got this endocannabinoid tone then
you've got you know how quickly or
slowly are they metabolizing THC or
other cannabinoids and then did they
take it with food because then we've
increased the levels
um that wouldn't normally be there if
you took it on an empty stomach so it
gets pretty complicated yeah it really
does and and again this is Another good
argument for one size fits all just
because your friend is taking this other
particular blend of cannabinoids and
it's working for them doesn't mean that
specific blend is going to work for you
and we really need to you know start
with the basics and build up your
endocannabinoid you know medicine
exposure over time and also why I you
know recommend that patients always keep
a uh a a dosing journal for any any
entheogens
um just so you remember what worked for
you and and what didn't especially what
didn't
right and I would just I would say in
that journal they should also take note
of if it's something that they're
consuming rather than smoking they
should probably take note of what they
had to eat and
what the format was because you know if
you take it it could be so minor as in
if you take it with MCT oil medium chain
triglycerides which is what a lot of
these products come in versus something
like Sesame or corn oil or hemp seed oil
the exposure is way different the the
MCT oil kind of carries it great
directly to the liver and some of these
other fats can can push some of it into
the lymphatic system so it gets into the
bloodstream but without going to the
liver first to get broken down so again
it's I wish it was simple but it's it's
not that's really interesting I hadn't
heard that about
um Sesame oils being able to push it
into the system bypassing the liver I'm
gonna have to look into that yes some a
proportion of it and and this is kind of
the same technology if you hear like
seds like self-emulsifying drug Delivery
Systems or like some of these that are
that are used in beverages or fast
acting uh most of it's not proven but
there are some data available that that
show that some of this technology can
push it quickly into the lymphatic
system and you don't have to wait for it
to get broken down by the liver and um
and there's higher levels in your blood
earlier great so all right so uh let's
move on to the next cannabinoid uh and
and since we already did CBD CBG and THC
which are our most readily available for
you know regular folks I'm going to
create a basket of the rest of of the
cannabinoids you know one that I know
you've done a lot of research in is uh
canned Flavin but also there's there's
all these other
phytocannabinoids that that
um either we won't have the time to talk
about today or there isn't even any
research on them so I would like you to
generally speak to them as this for
people people who prefer whole plant
resin preparations like you know what we
call many people call RSO Rick Simpson
Oil but like a whole a whole um a whole
resin extract like that
um how should we wrap our heads around
these these um these trace and novel
cannabinoids that will like all also be
in there right they're not going to be
mentioned on the label they're probably
not going to be tested for but uh but
most many of us who are fans of whole
plant medicine we like them in there
because of a of a belief that they hold
a synergistic quality maybe some kind of
protectant nature from having a bad
experience and an assumption that
they're probably good for us in ways
that we don't know but like there's a
lot of assumptions in what I just said
and so and so you know
with the goal of trying to
um
speak to how these extra components play
a role in longevity for people who are
going to be designing their own
supplementation system what do you have
to say about these these kind of like
variables that we can't control but
we're just assuming they're gonna be
okay
yeah I think it's I think it's difficult
um because it's to some degree it's a
little bit of a mystery soup and I would
say that mystery soup could be very
important we know that some of the
cannabinoids um there there's one called
thcp uh that's in in very small amounts
in certain plants but it's a very potent
CB1 Agonist at low levels
um so that may be of critical compo
importance uh to some of the these
Botanical extracts
um but but having it there are not
having it there could ultimately make a
tremendous difference I would say if you
found something that's a chemical
extract that you like and that worked
for you then I wouldn't you know trying
to to get something different you may
have a very different effect this could
be down to the terpenes it could be down
to these minor cannabinoids
um canned flavins could be of critical
importance around inflammatory processes
so without knowing what that is it's
difficult to say Hey you know this group
of other things this other mystery soup
is going to help where it's going to
hurt and and you could as I mentioned
earlier that that that those mystery
molecules could be the Holy Grail to
treating a disease or they could be
counteracting one another and we see
this with terpenes and cannabinoids so
without having it better characterized
it's it's really tough it's really tough
to say because they're also unique you
know yes it's a tough one so to wrap up
this particular topic before we move on
I want to talk uh briefly about
um uh endocannabinoid deficiency
syndrome um our mutual friend Dr Ethan
Russo has been on shaping fire several
times
um uh talking about endocannabinoid
deficiency syndrome as it relates to
different research that he has done and
um it's it's interesting that you know
one of the reasons we want to supplement
our body with these phytocannabinoids
that we are sourcing from the cannabis
plant is because our own body is not
producing the endocannabinoids the
endogenous cannabinoids that are made
inside of the body properly and so you
know the the causes for endocannabinoid
deficiency include you know poor
nutrition poor sleep anxiety and immune
suppressing Pharmaceuticals and uh you
know environmental toxins you know a
whole bunch of things that are just
generally not good for our human and we
get that right
um but I'm of the opinion that the vast
majority of Americans are are probably
suffering from endocannabinoid
deficiency syndrome from the beginning
um and so you know I personally think
everybody should be taking some kind of
of supplementation to strengthen it
um would you speak to
um I I don't know if you can speak to
the commonness of endocannabinoid
deficiency but would you speak to um the
idea of endocannabinoid deficiency as it
relates to you know longevity and and
how you know being deficient in
endocannabinoids will degrade probably
both your length of life and your your
health span of life
oh that's a that's a good one
um I think it's again it's difficult to
say uh definitively I think we can both
agree and and just about everybody will
agree that the endocannabinoid system is
critical to health and uh can play a
major component in a variety of
different diseases the the interesting
thing about
endocannabinoids is they they're they're
made on demand and they're metabolized
very quickly especially most of them
inside the brain right and we can't it'd
be great if we could just test you like
a regular blood test and draw some blood
and say oh you're anandamide
right make everything so much easier it
would make it so easy but unfortunately
the levels in your blood and how quickly
they change based on stress and
environment
um it they don't match what happens in
the brain so if you have endocannabinoid
deficiency room so to speak that affects
that's important because remember these
cannabinoid receptors are also in the
periphery so it's not just anxiety and
mood it could be joint pain it could be
um inflammatory bowel disease something
completely unrelated to what's going on
the CNS then then maybe you could
examine this and get some idea of of you
know a dosing regiment that would help
that but for CNS Related Disorders you
can't really look at it so I would agree
with you that it's the endocannabinoid
system or dysregulation may be a
critical component to a lot of diseases
is it the cause or is it a symptom I
think is still very difficult to
determine but we do know that it does
happen and is associated with many
different diseases
all right so the next thing I want to
talk about is um how functional ratios
between the different cannabinoids how
that plays a role in your overall health
span because you know you know the
underlying idea that that I'm suggesting
that that that folks find a blend of
cannabinoids that work for them and then
take it you know as a daily supplement
to keep their endocannabinoid
um strong or their endocannabinoid
system strong
um how much of each really does uh play
a role and and you know I've gone in and
out of
being behind functional ratios when I
was when I was all new to this you know
I was I was very into the okay do we
want a 20 to 1 ratio or is that a two to
one ratio of CBD to THC and and you know
you know this ratio is for Parkinson's
and this ratios and and I realized over
time that those might be good places to
start but really
every person has got their own
functional ratio I think and so
um would you explain how you approach uh
thinking about ratios uh from a you know
a longevity and wellness
um perspective as a research scientist
well in terms of longevity and wellness
we don't know a lot I mean the the best
the most recent work is one of the kind
of first examinations around c elegans
um looking at isolated compounds versus
like this Botanical drug substance that
contained CBD and CBG and THC together
in combination but um you know is that
the ideal ratio what happens when you
change that how does that translate to
humans I think it's still in the early
stages in terms of functional race
ratios and how they potentially could
treat disease I think that's a little
bit more clear-cut
especially in when not to use certain
things or when to keep certain things
low like THC in way where it may be
better to have higher amounts of THC or
or a smaller ratio with THC and CBD I
think that's that's a little bit more
clear again to do this research with so
many different humans who are all
different with so many different
diseases and so many different variables
is tough and it's it's almost
like you know it's a case-by-case basis
as you mentioned you you said you kind
of have like certain ratios that you
think are ideal for certain diseases but
that may only be the the starting point
they may be able to be further optimized
or on the contrary there might be
certain conditions where you don't need
to optimize them very much at all it may
just be that it works at that level
of that disease state
you know uh this this next thought is
for folks who are you know so far down
the path with this that they are they're
producing their own medicine because you
know as as we see when when the rubber
hits the road when somebody is sick
enough and Western medicine has not been
the solution for them and they find
their way to cannabis and they find
something that works it's a very short
path from oh my gosh this works a little
bit to suddenly they're you know growing
their own plants that are the types of
plants that they want and then they're
processing it using you know ethanol and
they are making their own Custom Blends
that work for their particular body
right and um it's it's been great you
know over the last say five years with
um the Advent of some of these uh
spectacular hemp varieties that you know
will isolate one uh cannabinoid like you
know the the all CBD hemp plant that you
know comes from Oregon CBDs or the or
the all CBG version you know so so you
can you can grow these plants and and
and make one uh make a CBG oil and make
a CBD oil and then make your type one
plant your THC oil you know make three
different oils and then and then blend
them like a Vintner would like you know
blending a red table wine or something
and and you know that's what I had to do
after my brain injury to find something
that was going to be a low enough amount
of THC that I could
um you know take it during the day and
still be functioning at my best level
but then also high levels of CBD I
wanted for for the neurogenesis and the
Brain support and then and then then
when when it became available the CBG
plants because they keep my central
nervous system from running too hot
which which happens to me because of
other diagnoses so so this idea of hand
blending them
um I I think is a real is a real winner
um so so I guess my my my I guess I just
would like to hear your thoughts on the
gap between
um What patients need how patients
become citizen scientists and how so
many patients go to the the licensed
market for their first medicine and and
it doesn't work for them like it has
worked for other people
I I'm on board with the idea of blending
to a certain specification from multiple
different plants so you know there is a
limit to what can be produced in an
idyllic ratio from Plants I mean it's
nice to think I mean a lot of people
think oh you know this plant that's here
it's on Earth it's for us it's the cures
it's to heal us
um and that's that's fine but
um plants aren't actually here so we can
eat them predominantly because of you
know a lot of these are defense
mechanisms
they're not they're not bred in a such a
way that that if we that they were so
magic that they would just be gone at
least historically now obviously we grow
them and breed them for recreational use
or medicinal use and that's that's
helped but I I don't think that we'll be
able to just say oh this is the perfect
plant and the perfect ratio and it will
stay at that perfect ratio I think to
your point of saying hey let's have
multiple different extracts in blend
them to a ratio of Active Components
that we know help at this ratio is
probably a much better approach than
just saying you know some arbitrary
named cannabis cultivar is the best for
treating this disease and and
unfortunately I think we've seen this in
dispensaries in many cases where you
know Grandma goes in and she said oh you
know I've got pain what should I use and
somebody gives her you know AK-47 or you
know whatever and uh that's not they
didn't tell her about dosing they didn't
tell her about Ratio or or anything like
that she has a bad experience and her
thought is I've tried medicinal cannabis
it didn't work it doesn't work and it
made me sick you know or you know they
take somebody says oh you know CBD is
good for it may help my epilepsy and
they take 25 milligram gummy and it
doesn't do anything and they're like oh
I've tried CBD for seizures and it and
work so I think you're kind of on the
right track and more on the scientific
track and the others are kind of more on
The Branding and
kind of
optimistic idea that something magical
is going to happen
so I want to finish off this set with a
conversation that um you know I know
you're really well versed in and I spend
a lot of time thinking about and and
because I keep an open mind about it my
opinion has definitely uh changed over
the last you know decade
um of of working with cannabis medicine
and it is the idea of a whole plant
medicine versus using isolate and and
this is this is how I want I'm gonna set
you up is that you know uh because
because you know Dr Ethan Russo has been
my mentor from the very beginning and um
he has historically
um you know
I dare say ferociously whole plant and
um and you know I learned that from him
and then
um and for those who aren't familiar
whole plant means that um you're you're
you're you're using a method to extract
all of the resin from the plant and then
you are uh you know taking that resin
orally
um and then you know nowadays when there
are so many more labs and people are are
uh you know separating uh the resin from
the plant and then continuing to extract
the single molecules of say CBD or CBG
from the resin and then and then either
you know selling that as a as a as a
powder or taking you know that powder
and putting into a gummy or or or
whatever it is
um and then and then at the at the
extreme what is going to become much
more common is pharmaceutical products
where uh different components of the
resin are isolated and then combined and
you know I've I've gone so far when I've
when I've been talking at conventions to
call this like you know
Frankenstein built like preparations and
and you know I'm not quite that hot
about you know it as much as I used to
be but there but we do know that isolate
acts different than whole plant medicine
it is it you know there's a um there's a
plateau point where where Moore doesn't
uh help anymore
um and and many believe that it acts
differently because it's not necessarily
working in a synergistic uh way with the
rest of the novel and minor cannabinoids
that are in the resin and yet there is
absolutely good use for it the first one
for me that I had to come around to and
embrace isolate was when CBD became
popular but before the CBD plants were
everywhere and so and so people were
like we want to take CBD in our you know
cannabis oil but there's no CBD in the
plants that we have near us and so you
know we decided to start
um you know spiking a type one plant
like a THC plant we we started you know
like like talking about spiking those
preparations with a CBD isolate because
CBD isolate was available before
um CBD plants were in a lot of places
let alone CBD plants that don't have THC
that are going to mess with your ratio
right and so you know I I first went to
Ethan about it and he's all like yeah
until you can get the plant you know you
can Spike with
um
with the powder and you know we talked
to Dr Sunil Agarwal and he's all like
yeah you know until you well well damn
because that suddenly I was I was
interested in isolate and recommending
it that that patients use it for this
particular purpose now with that big
setup I know that uh you know you and I
have discussed the challenge between
balancing the kind of you know ideal
nature won't hurt me any nature can heal
me kind of like Beauty you know ideal
plant medicine headspace that I really
grasp onto with with the more more
realistic idea or or differently
realistic idea that good cannabis
medicine is the same every time gives
repeatable results and hits the goals of
the patient and you know I gotta say
that there's so many variables in in
making your own cannabis medicine that
that very often we won't hit those goals
and so in so you know breaking it apart
and putting it back together by hand
like a pharmaceutical company would or
like you have to do in the lab for your
studies that makes a lot of sense as far
as control goes but then it also makes
me cringe because I really do think
there is some kind of like known X
variable of healing that comes with
whole plant so so I know that's this is
also probably another topic that you
could do a whole show on on her but um
but but I know there's a lot of people
out there who are making their own
medicine who really chew on this and and
I'd like to hear your thoughts
sure I think it's an interesting topic
and and like you said it could be a long
topic
there are a couple components first I
would say that if you're looking at
isolated compounds quite frankly you
should be careful about what the
excipients are and those those compounds
and I think this kind of goes without
saying for most of your audience but
when you when you're making an isolate
and this isn't the case with every
isolate maker there's a lot are you
gonna are you gonna just are you gonna
Define what an excipient is are you
going to get there oh yes I'm going to
get there all right but uh yes so in
excipient I'll just go
go for it now right and the excipient is
um the a component that is not
um what is in that particular ingredient
so an excipient like adulterers in the
isolate
yeah you could call them adulterants but
they're used specifically for the
extraction and crystallization process
for so one Method Of crystallization to
make it into a white powder out of a
resin is to add things like heptane or
pentane and you can and you can clean
those up right but depending on who's
making it you could have some of these
nasty solvents in there so it's not it's
not the isolate that would necessarily
be the problem but it could be the
provider so I would say if people are
using those it would be important to get
a COA that shows things like metals and
everything else but also what solvents
are present in that isolate and that's
where you know if there aren't
regulations in place to make sure the
stuff's clean that taking solvents over
and over again like naphthala or paint
thinner or butane residual butane could
be problematic so just something to keep
in mind when you're using those
compounds to fortify existing uh
formulations the other thing just to
point out on the isolates versus the
non-isolates is I think there are
certain conditions where
you know to get the Entourage or this
rational polypharmacy uh kind of effect
may not be needed in in an example uh
would be in some cases of pediatric
epilepsy
um I don't think the jury's out on how
much THC is is good or bad for children
um and and on of the uh the group that
would say until we know if we can avoid
it and get the result we want that may
be beneficial I think there's a lot more
safety data on CBD for kids so if um if
I can give a child CBD in an isolated
form and then be seizure free and not
have side effects then I don't I don't
see a good reason to say let's add a
bunch of other stuff in there if they're
already basically if the treatment is
successful unfortunately that doesn't
happen all the time it actually is quite
infrequent that that happens and that's
where you'll need to to
you know this whole plant extract can
these other cannabinoids play a critical
role to reducing seizures or help treat
disease and and what are those
components um so uh it may be that that
fortifying existing whole plant extracts
with other isolated compounds is the
best way to get what you call
Frankenstein medicine but I would say
maybe optimized medication that may be
the only way to get there
it's probably a very similar to the
argument you just made but for for those
of us who really idealize whole plant
medicine would you make the case
to me as a whole plant medicine
Aficionado on
why I should be open to the kinds of
formulations that are presently
happening at pharmaceutical companies
do you mean isolated compounds or yeah
like like you know you know we can take
you know epidiolex or side effects or
any of these where where
um you know they have taken multiple
components of cannabis resin and then
they have put together those exclusively
so so it's it's not the entire melange
of resin but they have taken the parts
that they think are most essential
to getting the desired results for the
patient and but it's not whole plant but
there are reasons for it so I you know
as somebody who like you have a foot in
both camps right you believe in both and
so so for me who is still resistant to
uh you know the pharmaceutical
preparations
um I I would like to hear what you what
what you what you would say to somebody
like me because so that all of us who
think like me can learn
so you know I would say well satavex is
a whole plant medicine it's it's
literally an extract of two different
cultivars of cannabis and Blended
together so you have a idyllic ratio or
at least what they thought was an
idealistic ratio when they invented it
now the the other components the the
excipient so what that cannabis is in
um isn't necessarily the same as what is
commonly available
um in in dispensaries right so they use
other kind of pharmaceutical components
that that may or may not be important so
to speak for for delivery now epidiolex
is is CBD isolate and sesame oil with
strawberry flavoring and a little bit of
ethanol to dissolve that strawberry
flavoring and that's that's primarily
done so you know these kids that are
um you know very sick and off often they
have like autistic like features or not
all of them obviously but oftentimes
that's what happens in these cognitively
delayed children and if it doesn't taste
good then they're not going to take it
right so you know I think in these
instances
having you know a pharmaceutical that is
prescribed by a physician that's covered
by insurance that works is is a great
step in the right direction
we know that the doses that you need for
CBD to control seizures are usually
quite high so from the hundreds to even
thousands of milligrams needed to
control seizures if you were a patient
it's almost like
um it's almost like dangling a carrot
you know it's like hey we have this
treatment it may help you or it may help
your child but you're going to have to
spend a hundred dollars a day or fifty
dollars a day to buy it off the shelf
then it becomes unattainable so how
having a system whether it's a whole
plan you know a whole plant extract that
goes and meets FDA requirements for
being the same thing standardized that's
proven to work in a disease accepted by
physicians and scientists and you know
whether you're from the deep south and
think cannabis is evil or whether you're
a cannabis connoisseur where you're like
hey we've got data that works and it's
safe and it's covered by payers and
insurance is a really good situation for
patients until we fix all the other
stuff and that could be for an isolate
or it could be for a whole plant extract
that we just know is the same and
because we've proven it worked it gets
reimbursed from from insurance
I think that's a really good uh way to
ground that argument hunter that that in
the end
what is our end goal our end goal is not
whole plant medicine our end goal is to
reduce the suffering of our fellow
humans and if and if we can get there in
a way that is safe for their physical
body and also relieves their symptoms
um whether or not it's whole plant or
it's whole plant spiked with isolate or
it is a you know pharmaceutical blend
that was put in a lab like they're all
hopefully getting us to the goal which
is to reduce suffering and that's the
point
yeah I couldn't agree more and and
you're just
your audience most of your audience I
would expect that that most of you guys
out there listening
um are not anti-cannabis but there are
people
um that are completely anti-cannabis and
there are people that are maybe on the
fence but they're just not going to a
dispensary they're not you know and a
lot of doctors are not going to
prescribe grandma or Grandpa you know
um purple kush or you know name any of
one of these these different uh
cultivars of cannabis they're just not
going to do it so if you we want to help
that subset of people whether they're
right or wrong in their opinions having
a cannabis extract a whole plant
medicine or an isolate that can help
reduce their suffering that would be
prescribed by a physician
has a much higher chance of success than
trying to convince them to talk to their
budtender or grow their own cannabis and
make their own medicine it's just it's
not going to happen
yeah right on well said all right well
this this set has gone a little long
this is a great conversation um but
let's go ahead and take a break and then
when we come back we're going to have a
a nice short set where we're talking
about a couple of the things to be
careful for
um when taking
um cannabis uh to increase your
longevity and health span
um you are listening to shaping fire and
my guest today is neuroscientist Hunter
land
you've heard me talk about the
award-winning cannabis seeds that come
from the analytical breeding program of
Seth and Eric Crawford who founded
Oregon's CBD seeds in fact Seth was a
guest on shaping fire in 2020 to talk
about triploid genetics Seth and Eric
are now releasing high THC seeds for
home Growers and Farms as grow the
revolution seeds at GTR seeds.com
their high THC seeds are extraordinary
in that they will start to flower at 16
and a half hours of daylight instead of
the typical 14 and a half hours of
daylight that means in most regions your
plants will start to flower outdoors in
the middle of July instead of the middle
of August which means these photo period
plants finish in September and not
October totally upending the photo
period Seed Market
Seth and Eric took their prized early
flowering CBG line and bred it to some
of the most desired verified genetics
out there including Sour Diesel triangle
Kush wedding cake chem dogs Skittles and
others these crosses all Express
powerful photo period terpene profiles
and THC giving you a great High GTR
seeds has a new thcv line with plants
like double Durbin and Gigantor that
boast one-to-one THC to thcv and people
want that thcv
GTR seeds are very consistent true
growing inbred f1s from stabilized
inbred parent lines these seeds are
nearly homogeneous and the plants should
all grow the same there is only one
phenotype in every pack available as
diploids and triploids Seth and Eric's
company is still family owned patient
and employee Centric and partially
powered by their two acres of solar
panels everyone can purchase these seeds
and the entire catalog of Oregon CBD
seeds at GTR seeds.com go to GTR
seeds.com today and choose something
revolutionary for your next indoor or
outdoor run
[Music]
sometimes the topics I want to share
with you are far too brief for an entire
shaping Fire episode in those instances
I post them to Instagram I invite you to
follow my two Instagram profiles and
participate online the shaping fire
Instagram has follow-up posts to shaping
fire episodes growing and processing
best practices product trials and of
course gorgeous flower photos the
shangolos Instagram follows my travels
on cannabis garden tours my successes
and failures in my own garden insights
and best practices from personal grows
everywhere and always gorgeous flower
photos on both profiles the emphasis is
on sharing what I've learned in a way
that you can replicate it in your own
garden your own hash lab or for your own
canabatopathic health so I encourage you
to follow at shapingfire and at
shangolos and join our online community
on Instagram
foreign
[Music]
episodes do you sometimes wish there was
more cannabis education available to
learn well we got you shapingfire has a
fabulous YouTube channel with content
not found on the podcast when I attend
conventions to speak or moderate panels
I always record them and bring the
content home for you to watch the
shangolos YouTube channel has
world-class speakers including Zoe
sigmund's lecture understanding your
endocannabinoid system Kevin Jody of
Wonderland Nursery talking about
breeding cannabis for the best terpene
profile Frenchie cannolis Lost Art of
the hashishan presentation Nicholas
Mahmoud on regenerative and polyculture
cannabis growing Dr Sunil Agarwal in the
history of cannabis medicine Around the
World Eric vlosky and Josh Rutherford on
solventless extraction and Jeff lone
Fells on the soil food web there are
several presentations from Dr Ethan
Russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system too while there
be sure to check out the three 10-part
shaping fire session series one with
Kevin jodhri one with Dr Ethan Russo and
one with Jeff lowenfels and even my own
presentations on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose cannabis business even though the
risks are so high as of today there's
over 200 videos that you can check out
for free so go to youtube.com forward
slash shangolos or click on the link in
the newsletter
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I am your host shangolos
and my guest today is neuroscientist
Hunter land so here we are with the big
finish you know Hunter I wanted to talk
about a couple of things that folks
should be careful of
um when designing their uh
supplementation regime to increase their
their lifelong wellness and health span
because
um because you know people do put other
things in their body as well and and
nothing in the body uh you know exists
in a vacuum and so you know we recently
did a a full-length show with uh uh uh
Jahan Marcou about interaction between
cannabis and other Pharmaceuticals but I
I think it deserves to be brought up
here as well since we're talking about
you know wellness and people you know
developing a supplemental routine that
they use every day
um because there is a very you know
there it's very possible maybe even
likely that there will be interactions
between the Cannabis regimen that that
they come up with for themselves and
other things that they are taking and um
so I would like you to speak to the idea
of of cannabis you know drug drug
interaction
um so people can understand the lay of
the land as they are thinking this
through on how they're going to proceed
please
sure yeah I think it's a very important
point I'd like listeners to keep in mind
that you know the reason that we have a
lot of these enzymes in our liver and we
have our liver to process uh compounds
that we're exposed to and many of those
are plant compounds and the way that
these enzymes work is when they're
exposed to the compound it breaks it
down to something
not active or usually inactive that's
easily excreted by the body
there's a lot of overlap on what each
enzyme breaks down whether it's a
medicine or a drug a plant a nutritional
matter the body doesn't know whether
it's artificial or if it's real it just
it sees something that it needs to get
out of the body or at least it thinks
and I'm
personalizing the liver now which is a
little bit odd for a scientist but um so
it doesn't really you don't really see
this distinction between natural and
synthetic as far as the liver is
concerned it just knows it needs to
excrete these compounds the problem
comes when you only have X amount of
enzyme to break down one drug and an or
one compound and you also need that
enzyme to to break down another compound
and that's one example of where you can
get elevations and we see this a lot
with CBD especially at higher doses so
for example there's a drug called
clopazam that's commonly prescribed in
LGS and Dravet to Pediatric
really sad forms of epilepsy
and what happens is if you take CBD in
conjunction with clopazam both the drug
clopazam goes up as well as the active
metabolite seven hydroxycvd which also
works both of those go up
um when when clopazam goes up it causes
sedation
and we saw this in clinical trials and
the patients needed to reduce oftentimes
reduced either CBD or clopazam after the
trial and clinical practice to limit
this this potential drug drug
interaction there's also interactions
around potential interactions around
bleeds for things like Warfarin which is
a commonly prescribed drug for for
people with clotting that need to reduce
clotting factors and probably the most
concerning thing that we saw in all the
CBD Research is risk for liver toxicity
so we didn't really see any per se liver
toxicity but we did see indicators in
blood work that said hey this might not
be good for the liver at this dose and
that was commonly in really high doses
and it was also common when they were
taking another drug called Depakote
which is a known liver Toxin and these
are the ones we know about they're
probably you know five to ten other
drugs that may have this interaction
with CBD where it may not be a good
thing and that the same thing can be
said for some of these supplements
um you know there's a lot of supplements
that combine a lot of different plant
components and some of these can be
enzyme Inhibitors so exhibit inhibiting
the the components that break down the
drugs or they can also induce them
basically tell your body oh we don't
have enough of this so we're going to
increase these levels and then then
you're not going to get the the the
quality or the amount of exposure needed
to treat your disease so these can be a
tough little Balancing Act if you're
doing it on your own so it's always good
to consult with a pharmacist or a
physician about these potential drug
drug interactions
and for considering the state of the
technology and everything right now you
know for for the common person probably
the place to start would be to Google
your
um your pharmaceutical that you're
taking and the word cannabis and start
there right because like that's that's
pretty much gonna be your entry to any
of this kind of data and then and then
follow up with whatever studies you come
across if there are any
sure yeah that would be one way you
could definitely do that again cannabis
you know if you look up if you've got uh
just a little bit of CBD in your
cannabis that's probably not going to be
the same as if you're taking like you
mentioned a high CBD chemovor of hemp
right so so dose is definitely a
critical component to these I think it's
a reasonable place to start
um the other thing would be
um you know to the pharmacists actually
are pretty pretty knowledgeable in this
area and the other type of drug drug
interaction that we see is
pharmacodynamic interactions and what
that means is like how does it it might
not be the molecules themselves
interacting but it may be that kind of
like you're having the Entourage effect
to treat disease you might have uh
Entourage effect for inebriation or
sleep or something like that whereas
like if you take if you drink alcohol
with cannabis you know they're not
necessarily inner acting directly but
they may have a pharmacodynamic
interaction like then if you didn't want
to drive the car with your you know x
amount of drinks you might definitely
not want to drive the car with that plus
cannabis so those are things and that
happens with other medications too like
commonly deprived prescribed
antidepressants or or a lot of these
drugs that are mood stabilizers and
things that are for sleep so you might
get these other interactions especially
with THC the pharmacodynamic ones I've
got one more safety question and then
we'll wrap up
um you know we've been talking about a
lot of different
um dosages and some of them are quite
high
for people who are developing their own
regimen
um is there a too high a dose then that
can actually hurt like you know as as
many of people have said it's like oh
even water can kill you if you take
enough of it so we do know that there's
like a maximum for pretty much
everything but
um you know how can how can somebody
who's formulating for the first time
think about the how much is too much
question
yeah well I think you know we've seen I
mean cannabis generally is pretty safe
but you also see cannabis hyperemesis
syndrome some so some individuals
um just end up for whatever reason over
time not being able to tolerate THC very
well so there is that component that it
could change what is safe at the
beginning may not be safe months or
years later
and secondly you know I I think it would
be a reasonable idea if you're taking
um CBD you know in in hundreds of
milligrams types doses
looking at your kind of standard liver
panel your standard liver enzymes as
part of your physical exam I think could
be important because you can always see
these elevations or maybe you already
have these elevations and then piling
CBD on top of that may be maybe a risk
so I think it's it's um it would be in
everyone's best interest to kind of
monitor these things just for peace of
mind right on right on and and if and if
folks are new to this idea of cannabis
hyperemonis I'm
cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome
um uh we did an episode uh 80 on it with
Dr Ethan Russo whose name has come up a
lot today and uh and and it's a great
guy yeah he is and he's you know he's
researched so much so it's you can't
really talk about you know
cannabinopathic medicine without
tripping over a bunch of his research
right so uh so yeah so episode 80 if
you're new to that so all right so 100
to to bring us to the close here you
know we've we've we have talked about
kinematopathic medicine today in terms
of of longevity and and not only the
length of life but also the quality of
life and and instead of like you know
often we think about connect you know
cannabinoid medicine as oh this is broke
how do I fix the broke thing in me right
um whereas when we're talking about life
lifelong wellness it's it's more about
like keeping the system going and
rebalancing itself rejuvenating itself
keeping those systems functioning
um to bring us home what do you see as
the um you know the novel cannabinoids
or the research that you are seeing
evolve right now that hold a lot of
promise for longevity with uh cannabis
medicine
oh well I think it's a really
interesting topic I have an acute
interest in both Botanical drug
substances that combine or or include
multiple different cannabinoids to to
whether we want to say Entourage or uh
additive super additive effects or
rational polypharmacy there's a bunch of
ways to to term it but go to to treat
disease
in combination by multiple different
methods or mechanisms so I have a really
big interest in that and I think that
relates directly with age-related
disease so maybe in preventative
medicine and maybe once you've passed
preventative medicine maybe we can we
can stabilize those conditions and the
other thing is these what I would
consider more novel cannabinoids things
that are understudied like the the acids
the the cannabinoid acids so before
they're heated and um some of these
other cannabinoids like CBC and CBE and
a lot of these really understudied uh
cannabinoids that we just don't really
know we know they're active we just
don't know where to use them and how to
use them and how much we should use so I
I think I've got a lot more work ahead
of me as well as as many other
cannabiners so to speak in the space
right on well uh Hunter thank you so
much for spending your time with us and
and bringing your unique experience that
has you know um you know your ability to
do complex research in the lab but then
the other ability to be able to speak
about it to lay folks like us so that we
can better understand you know the
Cannabis medicine that you know so many
of us rely on so so thank you so much
for sharing your very valuable time
oh well thanks so much for having me if
you want to learn more about Hunter land
and keep up with his research uh there's
two great places to do that the first
place to do that is his LinkedIn profile
at Hunter land and also uh where he does
his primary research which is at
biopharmaceutical research company and
their website is bio Pharma
researchco.com
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast And subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts if you enjoyed the
show we'd really appreciate it if you
would leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too on the shapingfire
website you can also subscribe to the
newsletter for insights into the latest
Cannabis News exclusive videos and
giveaways on the shipping fire website
you also find transcripts of today's
podcast as well
be sure to follow on Instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast that's at shapingfire and at
changolos on Instagram be sure to check
out shapingfire YouTube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shapingfire I've been
your host shangolos
[Music]
thank you