[Music]
farming has always been a risky business
interacting with nature is fraught with
potential dangers leading to crop
failure some of them like deer or even
spider mites you can see and do your
best to prevent
some threats though are nearly
undetectable and will decimate your
plant before you even know it is there
today we're going to talk about some of
those unseen threats
if you want to learn about cannabis
health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer i
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too
don't rely on social media to let you
know when a new episode is published
sign up for the updates to make sure you
don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter this month we will
randomly choose four newsletter
subscribers to receive three packs of
seeds from pride of the lion seeds in
mendocino county
check out their instagram profile at
pride of the lion seeds and request
their new catalog of over 150 photo
period and autoflower seed varieties
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive the newsletter so go
to shapingfire.com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month's and all future newsletter prize
drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and
i'm your host shango los
today my guest is cora mcgee cora mcgee
is a phd candidate in plant science at
the university of connecticut her
research focuses on the association
between microbial communities and
pathogens causing root rot she holds a
degree in horticulture and a master's in
plant science
during the first set we will talk about
fusarium wilt its causes and prevention
during the second set we'll do the same
thing with pythium and in set three
we'll cover proper tool cleaning a bit
on root rock in rockwool systems and the
importance of microscopes
welcome to the show cora
happy to be here fantastic so let's jump
right into it you know one of the things
that caught me off guard right away
when doing my advanced research on this
show about fusarium and pythium molds is
that pythium actually isn't a mold which
caught me off guard because we certainly
talk about it as one
um but i understand there's some
taxonomic discussion about whether it
really is a mold and it seems that
they've even created an entirely new
kingdom for it which for me seems to be
like a pretty big deal um so would you
hit on that a bit before we go into
pythium's characteristics um that matter
to us as cultivators
yes of course it's a really good
question so you know it's brought up a
lot because we tend to group pythium
with all the rest of the fungal diseases
because
it's very similar in the way that it
grows and
and by and other types of um infection
but the biggest difference is that you
know true fungi have chitin and their
cell wall and in pythium a different oh
my seeds is what we categorize pythium
in uh they don't so they lack chitin in
their cell wall and that's that's a big
difference when we're talking about
characteristics of fungi
uh and it's funny because yeah pythium's
not a mold but we tend to categorize it
as a water mold because it thrives in
water it loves water
so it's kind of an informal way that
even plant pathologists talk about
pythium but when you talk about
classification no it's it's not a true
fungi it's an oh my seed and you could
even think of it as a um it's a protist
but you know if you grow it in culture
it it's still got hyphy and it grows
very similar if you see it uh
the mold anywhere on a plant you know it
really does look like a fungus but you
know being
being technical when we talk about it
it's not so they're in their own little
world and category of the oh my seats uh
and not the true fungi so
yeah do do we find that that happens
like to have them re-categorized
taxonomically is kind of common my only
experience with it is um you know i i
kept aquariums for years and
occasionally we'd get one of these uh
you know small schooling fish or
something where they would change the
name of it from what we knew to a new
one because they're like oh yeah we we
moved we moved where it was on the
species chart and i always thought that
was such a i don't know kind of cool and
odd thing to have happen um i know that
you study a lot of these
i don't know i guess i'll call
microorganisms um are you finding that
that these things like jump around on
the chart regularly
yes yeah and it's funny like most plant
pathologists you know it's kind of
annoying because
we'll call something
uh their scientific name or latin name
for years and years and you know someone
who studies even a pathogen uh you know
it's got the same genus and species and
when it changes on you then you know the
the correct way is to call it by its
proper name even though like you know
you know it is the name that you've been
calling it for years and i have a really
good example of epithelium that i worked
a lot with and then all of a sudden 2014
the
uh the genus of the pythium change so
it's not even pythium anymore we call it
globus burangium
which is like a much longer name uh for
pithium irregular is the is the species
that i'm talking about so instead of
being pithium irregular it's
globosporangium irregular so that's a
really good example and i attribute it
um
more commonly the more we learn about
these organisms uh i think sequencing
and molecular technologies have really
helped uh correctly classify them and
keep classifying them and it's not just
microorganisms
uh
tree species and um and you know even
woody ornamentals go through this as
well uh and there's a whole board it's
it's actually a whole
formal process of people getting
together and trying to figure out uh how
to reclassify and
and it can turn into a headache but you
know you just go with the flow yeah
right and then you accept its new name
and and and keep going with it uh but
i can imagine that it um it does
separate the old-school scientists from
the new folks coming up because some
people know the old name and some people
knew the new name but let's let's let's
uh cycle around and focus on cannabis
now so um is there just one
species of pithium that is of concern to
cannabis cultivators or or are there a
variety of them because i mean i know
there's a lot of different pythium
varieties but i don't know if all of
them are concerned to we cannabis lovers
yeah that's a good question so
of course you know as cannabis is
becoming a way more popular crop and
we're still learning a lot about what
types of pythiums that we're finding
within infected plants and infected
substrates
or soil that people are growing the
cannabis in and my personal experience
i'll start
with i've personally isolated pithium
myriatylum
from
infected cannabis plants and uh have
also
extracted well i was just talking about
pythium uh a regular but it's really
globus ferangium irregular but you know
you they look very similar and you can
still think of it as a pythium even
though the genus name has changed so
i've identified um
both of those at a commercial marijuana
facility uh within infected infected
plants however uh going into the
literature there's a lot of reports not
just from one state
but multiple states in which they're
finding pithium affinitum
within cannabis production whether it's
marijuana or hemp we're seeing that you
know it doesn't really matter the
difference
uh you know cannabis is cannabis uh so
so yeah those are the three main
pythiums that i have
that i've been seeing not just in
literature but in my own experience and
out of all three of them pithy amerio
tylem seems to be the most virulent um
which means basically causing the most
damage and the most symptoms within the
plants uh
and and and it's not just mature plants
that you can see these pythiums and uh
pythium you have to actually look for
throughout the whole production stage
because uh pythium is also known for
attacking really young seedlings as well
they're very susceptible uh that classic
kind of wilt damping off symptom is is
pretty classic of pythium so something
to look out for not just within mature
plants and in the soil of those plants
but also um within the seedling
production as well
so does um
does pithium live in all soil or let me
here let me ask this question
differently you know very often cannabis
um
cultivators are are thinking about
keeping their
plants sterile from these pathogens
which you know
since since we mostly talk about living
soil on this show of course keeping a
living soil pot somehow sterile is kind
of an oxymoron but but people kind of
think of like i don't want any pithium
in my garden so i'm going to guard
against having any pythium and i suspect
that pythium is probably in every single
pot but the question is is we want to
keep our pot in balance so that it
doesn't fall out of balance and and
create a living environment that lets
the
pythium out compete
like i don't know whoever it competes
against and so so what what is that what
is that like is it is it pretty sure
that pythium's already present
everywhere and it's just about keeping
it in check
right so so that's a question that i've
actually asked a lot like where is it
coming from it seems to be everywhere
and and so now um you know myself and
other uh extension agents and i'm sure
pathologists have kind of gotten to the
point where now we tell growers just
imagine that pythium's always there it's
pretty ubiquitous it can be found
in lots of different uh growing
operations lots of different hosts and
that doesn't exclude cannabis so i would
say yeah just um just keep in mind that
it may always be there no matter you
know you should keep you know doing your
practices keeping everything clean and
and and trying to keep
um
everything sanitized however
i always say it really comes down to not
creating conducive conditions for the
pythium to be very happy and like you
said really out compete all those other
microorganisms that may be antagonistic
to the pythium that's in that living
soil um which brings us to the crux of
all this right let's go right let's go
right to it what are
the living conditions that create this
opportunity of imbalance and and gives
pythium a chance to take over our pot
so the biggest one that i really want to
bring up and we kind of hinted on it
earlier
is uh pythium loves water
it it can infect really easily in water
and so waterlogged soil conditions
really creates this awesome environment
for pythium to take off uh so
so any time that you're not um managing
your soil moisture properly and and your
soil moisture is is too saturated and
you're really waterlogging your soils
because that not only creates you know
less oxygen getting to the roots and a
really you know kind of stressed out
unhappy root zone within the plant it's
also making this pythium very happy
because it's got infecting tropicals
called zoospores
that are very efficient in swimming in
solution and they'll swim right into
your roots
and another thing that makes pythium
really happy is high nitrogen levels and
excess fertilizer uh because that can
really break your um
root cells open and then the pythium is
very efficient it's swimming and going
towards your roots and affecting them
that way see so you really want to
create a healthy and happy root zone to
stop that pythium from coming in in the
first place so again it's like always
act like the pythium is going to be
there in the pot with you but don't
don't allow those conditions that make
pythium thrive within that pot let's
let's talk about the mechanics of that
really specifically because cannabis
cultivators are an ingenious lot and
they are always looking for their own
solutions so let's talk about this
mechanic so the way that you said it was
that you don't want to have too much
moisture in the pot because the pythium
will swim towards the roots and infect
that way like there's got to be more to
it right because like the the i imagine
the root actually has got a membrane of
some sort on the outside how does the
water
create an opportunity for the pythium to
air quote swim into the roots
well it's not just the water it's the
water um
that too much water is having an effect
on the roots so roots also need oxygen
to survive just as we do so if you're
not allowing adequate oxygen to get to
the roots and always having too much
water bound around those roots then
you're already kind of creating an
effect where you're rotting out your
roots and then that that's where pythium
can really take the opportunity uh to
come into the roots
so you're saying like the the the root
is wet and so the root starts to
like literally rot and so there are like
fissures in the roots
well yeah if that if that root cell
burst open it'll it'll start leaking out
we call it leaky roots they'll start
leaking out root exudates and that
and um zoospores can can sense that and
swim via in the root chemiotaxis via
chemotaxis can get into the root um so
so that's why i also mentioned not just
water log conditions that are not
allowing adequate oxygen within the root
zone but also excess fertilizer can also
like high salt concentration within your
growing operation can also really affect
those roots stress them out break them
open kind of like cause some root
necrosis root damage especially at the
tip level and then again you're just
allowing this entry point uh for the
pythium to get through really easily
that's right i've never heard an
explanation for what what i'm thinking
we all refer to is root burn then people
say oh you don't use
don't want to use too many fruits
because you'll burn your roots i bet you
this is what we're all referring to when
we use that common parlance
yeah yeah i guess we call it leaky roots
because like they're leaking out those
root exudates that's making you know all
these plant pathogens are waking up and
being like oh yeah we have an entryway
now and and and then once they get into
that tissue then you know they they
really have something to feed on and
they start multiplying your populations
just get get higher you know they have
now they have a host so so they can
survive efficiently uh
dormant and not need a host uh within
soils and things like that but they can
really take off and increase the
population when they have that host and
those those tasty roots to feed on i
guess if you want to think about it like
that so really it's not that pythium
it's not that pythium has come in
and
um attacked your plant as much it is it
is
that the cultivator has over watered its
plant or doesn't have enough drainage
for long enough that the roots are
rotting
and that the smell of the exudates if
you will like wakes up the pythium and
it it goes into the root via those those
cracks in the root structure and so
the the pythium is just gonna sit there
and be
um dormant thank you dorman i was gonna
say hibernation i'm like that's not
right pretty much it's a good way to put
it yes like hanging out yeah it's just
hanging out right so that's interesting
so we really can't like blame pythium
really like it's like we're creating
this attractive nuisance essentially
yeah yeah what over watering and over
fertilizing like though
they really really do not help and they
really help and they don't help the
grower but they help invite the pythium
uh to infect so those are the two huge
things with the root rots um that
you know pathologists really can't
stress enough uh because you can stay as
clean as you want but you know those
root zone conditions you want white
plump roots uh so so anytime those are
compromised you you are kind of you know
alluring all these
uh especially pithium uh diseases to
to come into the roots yeah so um you
know
for both pythium and fusarium the main
way that most cultivators recognize that
there's a problem is because they get
what you know people call either
fusarium wilt or pythium wilt where the
plant droops in a very severe way that
looks unlike a regular wilt when they
get thirsty right um this somehow looks
more dramatic
um
and you know once you've seen it a
couple times it's really you don't
really confuse them anymore
but um but is there are there other ways
that um
we can find signs to determine if we
have pithium like before it takes the
plant are there are there other signs
that we can look for
yes and and that's a that's a good way
to we always say you know scout early so
so i'll go back to my previous statement
um
you want to really start with inspecting
all the healthy material coming and all
the material and making sure it's
healthy when it comes into the facility
or coming into your yard what have you
like wherever you're growing your plants
make sure those are healthy and that
you're not starting off with
like any rotted plants things like that
and if we're talking about like a you
know more mature potted plant and what
are signs that you can look for
it'll it starts in the roots so
so once you get that wilt and that
dramatic droop like that there really
isn't going back or saving that plant
which which i hate to say but it's all
about prevention so once you get to that
level of you're getting the will then
then then it's a goner but
since it starts in the roots and it
you'll you'll start getting kind of
brown uh necrotic roots that's the first
step and something that's telltale about
pythium that's not so much for fusarium
is that with pythium it's called a rat
tail so you can like if you see that
your roots are looking kind of necrotic
or browning is it going to put just kind
of like dead not healthy white roots you
can take some of that root tissue pull
it apart and if the outer cortex or just
like
um the outer membrane however you want
to say it of that root comes off so
easily and exposes that internal
um
that intervascular
tissue within the root uh the inner
cortex uh we call that rat tail that's
pretty telltale pythium if it just
easily sloughs off right when you like
break that root apart
uh that's a that's a good tell that you
have pythium brew right and hopefully
you can catch that before you start
getting the wilt symptoms uh and then
another
characteristic sign is reduced growth so
this is a big one because uh you know
say you've got six plants on a table and
you're seeing you know they you want to
look for uniformity and uh and if
there's some plants that are just
looking like really smaller you're like
i bought these like around the same time
things are looking you know more reduced
growth they should be probably bigger
with how much you've been fertilized and
you're watering you're like man that's
weird i just feel like they're growing
really slow uh that's another telltale
sign that you've got a root rot issue
because it's just that plant its roots
are compromised so it's just not growing
as vigorously as it should be if it had
white healthy roots uh and then another
symptom that you can see within both you
know fusarium and pythium is yellowing
of leaves so you can see we like to call
it chlorosis chlorotic leaves
yellowing's the same
uh and and that's a big symptom as well
so so before you even get to the wilt
stage because the will it's like the
final you know the the the roots have
been totally compromised and that that
pathogen just totally took over and and
it's done
those are three big ones to really look
for and it starts with the roots so
so you really just want to be checking
making sure like you have white healthy
roots it's very exciting when you can
like you know kind of pull the pot back
and see like yeah i have white roots
like and it's it's kind of root bound
too like they're you know they're grow
there's a lot of them but when you're
not seeing many roots within your root
ball and when you're seeing that the
roots are turning brown that's a good
sign that you should maybe bring that
plant out of production
so that your other plants don't get
infected as well and that you're not
spreading
um that infection you know that's a you
know i have heard
that people pull small plants i mean i
even pull small plants just because
they don't look they are like they're
going to yield enough to justify their
space in the greenhouse
but i had never really thought about it
as the runts might just not be um you
know seeds with finos that are not as
rambunctious but they actually could be
sick i mean that
you know making a decision to get rid of
a runt based on yield is um you know is
a lot more of a passive decision than
potentially getting rid of a runt
because it's a very good sign of you
know root rot um that kind that seems
like it's way more pressing than you
know than just yield
yeah yeah
and and and you know if you really don't
want to get rid of that brunt like say
like oh well i could get something out
of it again just check those roots
because like that that'll tell you
really quick is my plant happy and
healthy and are the roots thriving
because if they're not then it's a
really good sign you know yeah i have
root rot like that's why this plant's
not doing well it's because not enough
water and nutrients are getting uptaken
through these necrotic you know these
browning roots it's calm you know it's
compromising it's it's the plants really
struggling
to to to get to high yield so right on
let's talk a little bit about the best
practices of that so as i'm picturing
you know looking at my roots first thing
you know a lot of a lot of folks grow in
um you know huge cloth pots you know of
hundreds of gallons and clearly you're
not gonna like flip that over in your
palm and and knock out the plant into
your hands so you can look at the roots
so if you're if you're growing in in
huge pots that probably
um isn't for this solution and also if
you're growing in um you know generally
fabric pots they don't really slide out
as elegantly as they do when you're
using a black plastic landscape pot so
it's probably not for for for
you know fabric pot people either but if
you're growing in
a plastic pot that is of a size that you
can
realistically turn the plant over and
you know give it one shake so it
dislodges from the pots and you look at
it
that would seem to be your
best case if maybe the only case where
checking for that works so let's say
that i am using you know a 5 or 10
gallon and it's dried enough that it's
not gonna fall apart and i turn it over
and i've i've got it cradled in my hand
so i don't break the the um
the stem and i give it a one quick shake
and it slides out and now i'm looking at
the roots
what are we looking for
so what you want to see is really white
uh full plump roots so you don't really
want to see much brown uh kind of dead
looking roots and you want to see a lot
of them too so so depending on how old
the plant you know what we what we
consider a healthy plug or
you know a healthy potted plant
is you want to see um
you know it root bound almost like not
not too much where it's unhealthy but
you really want to see those white roots
like all the way around and what i've
seen uh too many times with pythium root
rot is you'll look at that root ball
and you barely see any roots around that
uh soil media or you know whatever media
you're growing on it just looks like you
know and the roots you do see are brown
you'll see like maybe some white roots
but they're attached um
you know a part of them as brown
so
so it
you should be looking for
white healthy roots and then you can
feel better about like oh yeah like i
don't think there's much of a problem
and and um you know i i'm always for
for testing so that's also like a good
time you know it's it's
especially depending on how many plants
you have and you don't want to
compromise your operation or all your
grow you know it doesn't hurt to also
get a soil test
and
since you're not sending tissue to these
labs and it's pretty inexpensive you can
tell really quick like yeah but i'm
getting yellowing of my leaves like
isn't that a symptom of pythium uh or my
plants aren't growing that much you can
at least um
kind of on your checklist or what have
you get away with oh i have a nutrient
deficiency because at least if you send
the soil you can see oh i have adequate
nutrients like my ph is in a good range
so so
um
so say you know you're getting the
yellowing and it's it's deficiency of
nutrients uh
you know at least you'll know that uh
because i'm sure it can be confusing if
you have yellowing plants and your roots
are looking really healthy and you're
like oh but what's going on like so so i
feel like that's one good that's that's
one tool that you can put in your
toolbox for sure
just to eliminate it because i don't
expect all your growers to just become
plant pathologist overnight and i think
that's a little bit of the stressful
part
into where i think research and
extension
and services need to really match the
industry and the home growers and the
popularity of cannabis
because we really want to help and
and a lot of these things um you know i
can name out symptoms but a lot of them
can span across you know pythium
fusarium symptoms look very similar and
i wouldn't you know i wouldn't expect
growers to know the difference between
them uh just just looking at you know
even cuttings or mature plants like you
can definitely get a idea of like oh is
this is this unhealthy but i wonder if
it's disease or i wonder if it's
environmental or nutrient and i feel
like that's the first question you
should be asking yourself truly not what
disease is it but is it a disease and
then the second question once you've
figured out oh it must like i think or
you know this is from a pathogen these
symptoms then okay what pathogen now so
i think there is uh i do want to stress
like the steps of diagnosis in general
um when working with any crop because
even if you presented me with two plants
one had fusarium wilt one had pythium
wilt uh i wouldn't feel confident within
my diagnosis or assessment unless you
know i was putting those roots under a
microscope slide like looking at the
structures like you know you can even go
as far as molecularly identifying it
which you know usually isn't isn't
needed for certain cases
uh and things like that but again like i
don't think growers should have to bear
that responsibility i think there should
be um resources that can help with that
yeah well as as we get into better
relationship with the federal government
and are able to take advantage of
you know more um
you know resources within the
agricultural industry like extension
agents and stuff we'll we'll have a lot
more help i mean for years cannabis
cultivators have been been pretty much
on our own
um so let's say that we we do have a
plant and it's already pithium wilting
and you've already clearly established
that once once the plant has gone full
wilt
that uh that it's done and so um
so
what do we do to dispose of this plant
because i'm not thinking i want to take
that plant
and and just throw throw the substrate
back into my compost pile uh and and
take the risk of increasing the overall
amount of pithium in my soil supply so
like
i probably want to take it away from my
whole property right
yes yeah bag it tag it double bag it get
it out of there don't compost it make
sure you get all the debris i think
that's why it's really important like
not just you know
take it out but really like bag it
contain it like you know you don't want
that soil particle going anywhere you
don't you don't want any of those
infected leaves falling anywhere you
just just to be safe just bag the whole
plant and uh and yeah get it get it out
of your growing operation and do not
compost it is is the best the best
situation uh if you get a pythium
outbreak or you know a plant that's
fully wilted you don't want it uh to be
around the rest of your plants man the
thing that irks me and you'd be
surprised that you see it is you know
someone will have a wilted plant it
doesn't even matter if it was from
pythium but if you have like an infected
plant or a plant that's wilted or just
any debris that you're not
growing with or just like some plant
that's sitting in the corner that you're
gonna deal with later like deal with it
as soon as you can because the more that
you know
dead tissue just sitting or dead debris
sitting near your healthy plants uh
there's lots of plant pathogens that
like to feed on uh dead tissue decaying
organic tissue and you know we're going
to talk about fusarium in a little bit
fusarium's you know
a very efficient saprophyte and it would
love to stick around and hang out on all
those wilted leaves kind of sitting in
the corner and botrytis is another one
you know we start getting to more foliar
pathogens that you could really avoid
just by bagging that plan up getting it
out like deal with it right when it
happens uh and
you know your past self will thank uh
future self so yeah my uh my growing
mentor hector um he would love hearing
you say this and he'd feel so justified
because uh you know i was brought into
this scene and he was meticulous with
any time we were removing
um leaves from the plant
to put them in a bag that was then
removed from the property and you know i
always found that a little tedious and
time consuming and then when i got into
the regenerative growing
scene i felt like a bit vindicated
because so many um regenerative growers
will remove leaves off the plant and
then
put them on top of the container down on
the soil near the base of the stem
so that
that leaf can degrade and you know the
idea is that the nutrition goes back
into the soil as well as making home for
you know little
you know small organisms that live on
the top of the soil and things like that
but what but what you're explaining to
me is that
this is absolutely increasing risk of
pathogens without a question
yes and and you know i i've got to
applaud like the person who wants to
take you know
be sustainable and not want to waste
like tissue but there is a place for
that tissue and it's in a compost
it's in a compost that's going to be
like treated and away from your healthy
plants because yeah right when you take
any type of debris and put it especially
like in a nice moist place like on top
of the uh soil where your healthy plants
growing you know i i can imagine i could
honestly already see the botrytis or
like diseases like coming for that
tissue like within you know a couple
days like it it really doesn't take long
for another issue to occur uh
for for when you have any plant debris
yeah any type of organic matter even
soil that's hit your floor like you know
that's where cleaning really comes in as
a good proper preventative so not just
getting rid of the plant debris getting
rid of soil debris and anything that can
just kind of hang out around your
healthy plants uh because um you know
not only like insects but lots of uh
lots of pathogens will hang out there
stay dormant until you know
until they're given an opportunity yeah
totally until they you know that little
piece ends up on your shoe and then that
shoe goes trudging in your side garden
and you know like so it's it's just
better to sweep get all that stuff out
of there and uh it's just yeah
it's the best best uh procedure right on
so we're gonna take a short break and be
right back when we come back we're gonna
do this same thing again but with
fusarium you are listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is plant
pathologist cora mcgee
[Music]
for 20 years humboldt seed company has
been family owned and providing reliable
high yielding seeds originating in
northern california while the current
trend is to slap one super male into a
line of hype strains humboldt seed
company continues to breed with
precision and care by doing large sifts
and back crosses to emphasize the
absolute best traits that a line has to
offer this kind of breeding takes time
talent and space to work
no matter what kind of aroma you are
particularly into humboldt seed will
likely have something you'll love if you
love fruit you can choose from banana
mango apricot papaya blueberry blood
orange melon and lemons across their
various strains they have all gas glue
and classic sour diesel lines as well of
course there are the heritage california
strains like og kush jack hair and
headband and their award-winning
blueberry muffin is one that delights
just about everybody's palate especially
when concentrated
humboldt seed company is proud to bring
to market the infamous freak show
cultivar 2 which has a great thc high
but looks so much like a fern that some
folks can't even identify it as cannabis
it's a plant that really needs to be
seen to be believed
if you're looking for well-balanced cbd
seeds humboldt seed company can turn you
on to cbd strains that actually have
flavor like the dill and pepper terpenes
of willie g's lebanese land race
whether you are looking for regular
feminized or autoflowers humboldt seed
company has the gear to make this your
best growing cycle ever
visit
humboldtseedcompany.com today to check
out their line of vigorous genetics
download their catalog and find out
where you can pick them up you can also
check out their instagram at the
humboldt seed company to check out their
gorgeous flowers and the extraordinary
freak show plant
humboldt seed company let them know
shango sent ya
[Music]
for years organic cultivators have been
looking for a replacement for using peat
moss peat moss has long been the go-to
soil amendment for water retention and
container growing but organic growers
know that peat moss is an unsustainable
resource and the mining of peat bogs
destroys habitat and releases
sequestered carbon but peat moss works
so well that many have continued to use
it but now there's finally a
revolutionary replacement for peat moss
that shares the same benefits while also
being sustainable
pit moss sounds and axe like peat moss
but instead of being mined from fragile
ecosystems it actually is made from
upcycled organic paper and tree bark pit
moss is excellent at retaining water in
your substrate and creating air pockets
and tiny living environments for
microbes pit moss instantly increases
aeration nutrient absorption and water
conservation too
carefully and locally sourced pit moss
is the result of decades-long research
into the use of recycled paper fibers
pit moss has the fluffy nature of peat
moss and handles exactly the same and
like peat moss pit moss is inert so it
won't change your ph
available in a range of preparations
including a nutrient enhanced blend a
coco coir blend and also as an organic
soil conditioner with no added nutrients
pit moss is also available as an animal
bedding
so go to pittmoss.com now to learn more
that's p i t t
m o s s dot com
growing healthier more sustainable
plants pittmoss
[Music]
businesses everywhere are striving to
reach people through advertising we all
know though that trying to reach a
cannabis audience with a quality message
is pretty difficult
that's why many people choose to
advertise on the shaping fire podcast
advertising on this show allows us time
to talk about your product service or
brand in a way that really lets people
know what sets your company apart from
others
bold people who own companies know that
getting into relationship with their
customers is essential and that is what
we offer we will explain your service or
product what sets it apart as desirable
and help our audience get in contact
with you
it's pretty simple really advertising
does not have to be all whiz-bang smoke
and mirrors nowadays i find that people
prefer just to be spoken to calmly
accurately and with good intentions
if you want to make your own commercial
spot well you can do that too
during these pandemic days conventions
and cannabis events are pretty poorly
attended but podcast listening is
skyrocketing
with a commercial on shaping fire you'll
reach your customers in the privacy of
their headphones right now
and will continue to reach new listeners
as they explore the shaping fire back
catalog of episodes again and again for
years
a spot on shaping fire costs less than a
printed postcard per person and the
shaping fire audience is full of smart
cannabis enthusiasts cultivators and
entrepreneurs who are always curious to
learn
do yourself a solid and contact us today
for rates on podcast and instagram
advertising
email hotspot at shapingfire.com
to find out more
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host shango los
and my guest today is plant pathologist
cora mcgee
so we are essentially going to do second
set like we did with first set where
first set we were focusing on
uh pythium the non-mold root mold
but now we're going to talk about an
actual mold which is called fusarium and
honestly i would say that fusarium is
probably more commonly known in cannabis
because you know pretty much anything
that wilts we say oh it's got fusarium
wilt and i bet you that a good share of
the plants that actually die from
pythium
when the story gets retold later that
night over beers that pythium is
actually being sold as fusarium because
you know
fusarium wilt looks an awful lot if not
exactly like pythium wilt so
um
you know what like let's start the same
way is are there multiple fusarium
species that cannabis cultivators run
into problems with or is it really only
just one
there's some main ones uh that
researchers and pathologists have been
identifying down at the species level
within um more commercial greenhouses
but you know it stays true to gardeners
as well
so fusarium oxysporum
that is a really common fusarium that a
lot of people
have started seeing in cannabis
including myself uh sophia max oxosporum
is a fusarium wilt
it causes fusarium wilt and
it's it's pretty common it's a pretty
common fusarium across all host species
uh so i guess we weren't too surprised
when you know started realizing cannabis
was susceptible to this this pathogen
and um another fusarium that causes more
of a root rot is uh fusarium solani
and i haven't personally seen this in
cannabis but dr punja
he's a pathologist in canada who's been
surveying i feel like he hits a he comes
out with a new paper every like six
months
uh with all different pathogens that he
finds in commercial marijuana facilities
as well from you know soil to
hydroponics you name it and and it seems
that that fusarium oxusporum and
fusarium solania are the two biggest
that he finds in abundance uh within
within these facilities and that's
mostly the roots the root rots the crown
rots and the wilts
um and and it's funny i you know if you
zero mocks the sperm can found can be
found in mature plants uh causing the
will but i've also encountered it within
uh cutting production so at the younger
tissue stage
and
and i just wanted to say real quick uh
fusarium doesn't just affect
roots or cause wilt uh fusarium can also
uh be
a fungus that attacks the buds of the
cannabis plants as well so just like you
were saying you know it sounds like
fusarium is getting a lot of the credit
uh where pythium may be involved
uh but i think the same goes for
the fuserium that that a few researchers
not just myself but i saw cornell has
seen this as well within cannabis buds
his fusarium is detected on that as well
so i'm sure when growers see
mold growing on the bud they they
immediately are like oh botrytis
because that's a common one and i've
seen botrytis on the buds as well
but i just i just want to let your
listeners know you know
again just going back to where testing
is really important that could also be
caused by fusarium
and there are some
some differences between them but again
you know you'd uh it would really help
if you had diagnostic tools or if you
had a pathologist that that could help
identify it i'm not expecting um you
know home growers or even some
commercial growers to really tell the
difference uh with that mold because it
looks it looks similar it looks very
similar does fusarium on the buds look
like botrytis or will it present
differently
so
it's hard to say because it depends
who's looking at it right uh so if i
were to look at it um from afar i
probably couldn't tell but once you
start getting more up close like
botrytis is you know it's called gray
mold because
the canadia uh and the spores the actual
what you see
the mold fuzzy part on your plants it
has kind of like a grayish color to it
for botrytis and then also the way
botrytis grows it grows in like uh
chains so so that's something that i
would know and that i would try to look
for when looking at it but when i've
seen fusarium grow on bud it has more of
a white color it has more of like a
white thread like growth
uh versus like um spores and chains
which botrytis uh which botrytis kind of
that that is characteristic to botrytis
uh so so i would say yes to me i saw a
difference but to tell you the truth
when i first saw a fusarium on the bud
i'm not gonna lie i was like oh well
maybe it's botrytis because i really
haven't seen any reports a you serious
on fusarium on on the bud and you know
that'd be kind of crazy because um you
do want to really look out for that
because
fusarium head blight on corn
uh is you know some species are known
for producing mycotoxins and those can
be you know harmful toxins if humans
ingest them and and so and so it's it
again it's not something you should just
kind of uh
forget about you you really want to get
a good diagnosis
diagnostic
take on on what you're looking at uh
within that bud but anyway going back to
the story when i was looking at that bud
uh right when i put it under the
microscope though i mean it it you know
the structures are very different
between botrytis and fusarium so i
immediately was like whoa i have a
fusarium and then i went further and i
not only
uh looked at the museum under the
microscope that i saw on the cannabis
but i put it in culture so when i say i
put it in culture there's um
a nutrient media that you can put in
petri dishes and you know that's how we
can grow out different pathogens to
really see um
morphological characteristics and
culture and that can help identify so
fusariums and culture are well known for
creating vibrant colorful pigments right
so when you put botrytis in culture
you're going to see those kind of like
gray
uh
gray spores in the petri dish and then
they'll also go on if it sits longer in
the culture it'll create a sclerotinia
which are their resting structures that
can survive and you know substrates and
things like that they almost look like
tiny mustard seeds almost like black uh
little
uh rocks
that's what their structures look like
but fusarium can create these gorgeous
well i say gorgeous but very like
vibrant colors um and pigments and
culture so fusarium oxisporum as we were
saying which is common in cannabis that
create that can create and culture a
very uh pretty kind of purple lavender
color and culture and the fusarium that
i picked up on the bud had this uh very
striking kind of orangish red color and
culture uh and then i actually had that
fusarium sequence you could tell i was
like very curious
so i was like okay i'm also gonna um i'm
gonna sequence it so i can you know not
just morphologically identify it
but i also want to molecularly identify
it again like you know fusarium
structures can look very similar
depending on species so it's like oh i
wonder like what species this is and it
was more of a curiosity thing and when
we had it sequenced it turned out the
fusarium sporotrichoides
and uh and that's also been known as a
fusarium head blight on like wheat and
and uh more cereal crops so
so it's a long story to say
uh yeah fusarium is not just seen within
the roots it can be within the bud and
that's just one example of a personal
story of how i've diagnosed uh to
species level one on the bud and i think
just as more pathologists get their
hands uh
on these different pathogens different
production sites like maybe more reports
will come out to see how common that is
because that's something i can't really
speak to is was that a rare occurrence
it was in our research facility at uconn
uh or you know is that is that a common
uh common pathogen we see i i read
something cornell has seen similar
things on outdoor hemp production it's
it and it actually they went as far as
they saw that some fusariums they saw on
cannabis uh buds did produce mycotoxins
and i thought that was very interesting
um and and something that the cannabis
industry should uh should keep it its
eyes and ears out for for sure i'm
feeling so schooled and humbled at the
moment because um i here on vashon
island where i live
you know i help a lot of patients with
their grows
because i'm kind of the local expert
and
we have been experiencing what i now
think is fusarium
all over the island the last two years
and for me as i saw it i'm like wow this
botrytis is really presenting
differently this year right which now in
retrospect that sounds so
so novice but you know your your
explanation of it was so good normally
we would see botrytis which is you know
the the gray spores and they kind of
look like you know little gray clouds
inside of the
the flower but then about two years ago
we started getting these what you know
these white strands that you um describe
that to me kind of look like like white
cotton strands
and and in my head i'm like oh it's like
a um
a a spider mite got in here and did all
of these white you know webbing instead
of the kind of webbing they do on the
crown right and i'm like they're all
these like straight webbings of white
and cottonyness inside the flower which
is clearly a mold and clearly not
something i want to smoke but also
wasn't something that i had seen
a lot of before
last year which is interesting because
the weather here for the last two years
has been significantly wetter and colder
earlier
and um
it's interesting that you would say that
all of these what are essentially
beautiful colors come out when you put
it in the petri dish because the main
way that we are identifying
what i now will call fusarium in the
buds because you know they're on the
inside of the flower so the flower will
look great
normally until you crack it open and
you're like oh god what's all this
cottony stuff that's all white but the
telltale sign which you know if you know
your garden well you can see from across
the greenhouse is that
there will often be a part of the bud
that has gone incredibly colorfully
necrotic
there will be like one leaf that will go
like bright maroon or purple or pink or
orange or something and you're like oh
look at this fantastic gorgeous bud but
there's that one
there's that one sugar leaf on there
that has gone
you know royal purple or something
and and then when you crack that bud
open suddenly you see all of these
cottony white strands
a have you had that experience with the
sugar leaf turning colors on the bud and
second
what causes the change in the color um
what we say you know in the garden is
like oh you know all the anthocyanins
are showing right which would suggest
that the chlorophyll has left the leaf
and like i don't know that could all be
bro science but i'm hoping you
understand my example enough that you
can just kind of generally speak to it
yes so in my experience i did not see
any um
different coloration around where i had
saw the fusarium bud rot on the on the
bud and i think i caught it pretty early
too because i didn't see a lot of dead
tissue around
uh the signs of the pathogen
on the bud um so there's one
and then two uh so i haven't had a lot
of experience with the bud rot uh
and
and i'm not sure
i'm not sure what produces the increase
in pigments within the tissue and it's
interesting because at uconn um since
about 2018 2019 we have multiple
researchers like looking at these types
of interactions and seeing like how do
different pathogens that are infecting
these plants like affecting pigmentation
how is it affecting genes uh how is it
infecting trichomes so those are all
um
questions that i can't answer but
hopefully are starting to get answered
as research has been opened up for this
crop because that's the thing it was
kind of this crop we couldn't touch for
years so that answer may
the answer to that question may be
answered within other crops but
but i'm not sure if it's been answered
within cannabis and it would be a very
interesting research question uh because
that could really be applicable to
growers you know that could be maybe an
early sign i've been seeing like a
different pigmentation uh is that
something that pissarium is causing
unfortunately it seems to be a late sign
because at any time about after the
necrosis okay
yeah
we see that by the by the time we see
that color it is time to
uh either remove the whole plant or or
adjust the crown and actually you use
this term crown rot earlier in the show
which i had not heard before and that
sounds like the perfect phrase for what
we've experienced these last two years
where we've got this beautiful plant
with this killer cola and the cola
gets fusarium and then it shows one
sugar leaf that changes color and we
crack it open and it's it's got advanced
uh cottoning you know these cotton white
cotton strands on the inside and um and
you know calling it crown rot it's you
know that's a pretty cool name for it
you know
well i would call that bud rot so when i
mentioned crown rot earlier crown has to
do with the crown by the root zone oh i
thought you meant the top of the plant
yes
no so so i was so i think um and it's
totally easily uh
misunderstood because when you talk
about crown rot uh it's more at the base
of the plant uh so that the crown of the
root which fusariums can cause so that
there are fusion crown rods out there uh
such as like um fusarium solani i think
i'm pretty sure has been reported as one
however uh when we're talking about the
bud rot
um
we wouldn't pathologists wouldn't call
it a crown we'd call it bud like a bud
rot because it's on the butt of that um
you know part of the plant yes so just
to clarify that for for that's good
that's good clarification i appreciate
that
so um all right so circling back around
to like the main thrust questions uh
fusarium does is it in the soil all the
time just like pythium is and it is also
just looking for an opportunity to take
over
yes well unfortunately yeah it's a
soil-borne pathogen so
so you want to imagine uh it can be
around especially you know you're
growing and these living soils and
there's lots of nice microbes in there
and
and you you don't want to create
conditions that are conducive for the
fusarium to to increase in population
and then cause
infection and get into your roots and
then get into your stems because you
know fusariums can also cause uh
vascular issues vascular um
stem rots and wilts within your plants
as well so yes you know everything i
said earlier
about uh
not to do within
your pots to avoid pythium is very
similar
uh with fusarium such as you don't want
to over water you don't want to damage
those roots you don't want to have you
want to have optimum nitrogen for your
plants because you know cannabis or
heavy
heavy um feeders yes they're heavy
feeders thank you
but you don't want to have uh too much
nitrogen you don't want to have too much
compost on your plants uh because it can
really uh again like we talked about
create those those leaky roots and and
create a really opportunistic
uh time for that fusarium to infect uh
and
and the symptoms are really similar as
well
however fusarium since i said it can
cause vascular wilts and basically like
within the stem is what i mean when i
say that you can sometimes see
discoloration in the vascular tissue and
even sometimes on the bottom of that
stem you can sometimes see like a
discoloration of a brownish or sometimes
like a reddish brownish color at that
bottom
and you know if you wanted to
sacrifice the plan if you're really
having a feeling like oh this plant is
looking sick its roots look compromised
what have you if you cut open that stem
and you kind of see this hollow
or a discoloration within your stem
tissue then that's a that's a good
telltale sign yeah i may i may have
fusarium uh within my plant
i'm assuming that you know if if if the
fusarium is in my soil on a day-to-day
basis and um
would it be fair to say that it is
dormant like we talked about the pythium
yes yes yeah it has
so it'll be dormant and then we make it
wet which which you know causes it to
get active and then we keep it wet which
means that it's starting to thrive
in a um
anaerobic environment and then the roots
are
rotting and creating opportunity for it
to get inside of the plant um
like like like anywhere along this line
this plant isn't coming back
and so by the time we see the wilt uh
i'm guessing we're in the same situation
we were with the pythium where what did
you say bag it and tag it and get it off
the property yeah yep correct
oh that's so sad sometimes i mean it's
like one thing if you're if you're
scaled right and you've got 500 plants
but first you know since i don't do a
lot with scaled growers and i'm more
focused on on smaller patient gardens
like sometimes that can be you know one
plant can be
you know 20 percent of somebody's entire
grow
during the summer and
there's so much resistance to just
throwing away the plant instead of
trying to revive it but so the longer
that plant stays in your garden the
higher
the the pathogen pathogenetic load to
your garden the more likely that those
pathogens will hop over to another plant
right and i mean there is if you have
less plants hopefully you can try to
optimize their root zone and their
health like as closely as you can to
avoid uh this this occurring in the
first place and you know i know your
listeners are really into
uh the microorganisms the beneficials
within the living soil like you know if
if you have a really good uh
microorganism buffer i should say within
your soil like hopefully that's another
preventative defense uh that's you know
can can be good to have into place and
then you're right it's it really is like
do not over please try not to over
fertilize and over water because yeah
that can you know eventually be a death
sentence to a plant and and it and it is
very sad because there's no corrective
uh control measures you know it's all
organic and and so it's all a
preventative game and and i know we've
been talking about that but that that
really is you know cleaning and just
making sure those conditions are really
good for the plant to avoid it from
coming in in the first place and taking
over it's interesting to think about the
mechanics of that that death spiral in
specifics right because if your
microorganisms and the other
you know living
folks in the rhizosphere are actually
one of your defenses against pythium and
fusarium
and first thing you do is you pour all
this water in there and or maybe maybe
it's the right amount of water but you
have terrible drainage whatever reason
you've got really damp soil so the first
thing that's going to do is create an
overly water environment that is going
to wipe out a whole bunch of your
microorganisms that are supposed to be
part of your defenses and then
you know you're creating this low oxygen
and environment that's going to rot your
roots and then like essentially it just
leaves the field of play open for a big
old pythium party
right right yeah all right so um
so we understand the living conditions
and that this is all a preventative game
and that you know once we've gotten to
the point that we actually see the wilt
like don't even try just like get you
know bag it tag it and get it off the
property so so
i want to take all this and put it on
its head before we before we leave this
uh second set and that is um you know
sometimes you gotta try to save it and
and this is the example that i want to
give you it's kind of an impossibility
but but i want us to like kind of work
it out anyway because i know that
there's people including me who grow
this way and let's imagine you've got a
four foot by eight foot
raised bed that you know let's just say
it's like 18 or 22 inches deep and
you're going to put multiple plants in
there and the whole point is that you're
gonna be you know growing you know
you're gonna have living soil and
companion plants and you're gonna have
multiple cannabis plants in one bed so
that you know all of their roots can
talk to each other and they can share
nutrition and information and it's just
this big sexy regenerative success until
one of the root zones gets fusarium or
pythium and suddenly you see like let's
say one of your six plants in this bed
you come in in the morning and it is
wilted and you know it's not water
everybody else looks good
but this one plant is totally screwed
and
um you know the idea to
bag it and pitch it is great in theory
except for the fact that
um it's in this shared bed
um so let's say that
you know as the cultivator you really
don't want to cull the entire bed
because you know if you've done it right
you've got you know tons of rocks in the
bottom and then silt and and sand and
you're like building your layers of
substrate up and it's just this
beautiful thing that took all this
effort but now you've got this you know
essentially this like like out of
control pathogen that's in the root zone
of one plant
if we needed to try to at least try to
save the bed
what would your radical prescription be
for trying to
extricate that one plant
and revive
the
the bed so that perhaps it doesn't
spread to the rest of the bed
so this might be really unpopular what
i'm about to say so i apologize in
advance to all the growers you don't
want to gut the rest of the plants that
were sharing the soil
so it's really important first off to
make sure that that diagnosis is a
fusarium right you you want to make sure
that
that you have fusarium in the bed in the
first place before you make these really
dramatic calls but say it's like oh like
i think it is i don't want to risk it
what i would do
is at first of course take the plant
that was showing symptoms uh wilt or
what have you get it out of the bed bag
it get it out of your operation
i would also
i would get rid of the rest of the
plants in that bed too because really
you're just creating a happy habitat for
that peasarium to now go to those those
roots and and feed on those and you know
if you've had a plant already wilt in
that same bed you probably have pretty
high populations of that fusarium
already in that bed now so you don't
want to increase that population even
more and make it even harder down the
road to be growing and that
high raised bed or what have you
so i would get rid of all the plants say
you've got six plants in the bay one
went down get rid of all of them and
then at least
um
you may have like moderate populations
of the fusarium because it hasn't had
time to really you know feed on all six
and and now you just have like a crazy
amount of uh fusarium uh structures and
infecting agents within that that soil
uh so there's two things that come to
mind once you've gotten rid of all the
plants and now you're just left with
this bed with again like you said all
these layers i've i've really been um
you know adding to my soil and making it
healthy
uh
there's two things i'm going to say i'm
not going to guarantee it'll work but
you could at least try
uh and see if it could eliminate um if
you want to keep growing in this bed so
one i would say is that you could try to
cook the soil so so when i say try to
like cook the soil i'm saying try to
create an environment where you're gonna
you're gonna try to
get a lot of temperature get the
temperatures really high within that bed
so it can hopefully uh kill those
infecting tropicals and those structures
so a way to do this is you can get um
some plastic some some clear plastic so
the sun can penetrate through and you
want to really seal it around in that
bed like make sure there's no air
pockets you really want to get that
clear plastic on top of that soil layer
put a bunch of bricks around it what
have you and and it really helps when
it's a hot summer day as well because
you know if you do it right you can get
temperatures up to like 120 degrees
fahrenheit
that can really help penetrate and kill
some of those
infecting propagules within that bed so
that's one and again just depending on
how bad the populations are it may be
effective
so it's something to try
and then another option
uh which i i've heard other extension
agents talk about this within uh
cannabis
is you know crop rotation
so i i know you really want to put
cannabis back in that bay really badly
you know that's where you grow your
cannabis plants but but since you know
that there's fusarium right now in it
and it's compromised but you don't want
to gut the bed out you don't want to
waste all that good substrate uh you
could try to
plant another crop that season in that
bed uh so i've heard hairy vetch
um
some people like see it as kind of like
a weed but it has a really pretty purple
flower kind of pee like leaves so it's
called hairy vetch and it it's actually
shown that if you use it as a
crop
within fields where watermelon get
fusarium it's shown to show suppression
of fusarium within uh within that that
field so so you could try something like
that putting another crop
that is either can help suppress the
fusarium over time or that just isn't
cannabis so you can really you're really
just trying to decrease those
populations now in that soil so that you
can eventually put cannabis back in it
and feel more confident that you're not
going to have another
outbreak
wow
that's actually a pretty
like novel idea using a plan for kind of
using it as a beneficial i really was
expecting you to talk more like when you
when you did that apology at the
beginning i really thought you were
gonna go into
um
uh like anti-fungal drench or something
like that um which isn't what isn't
which isn't really how you went with it
um so i guess i will are there any
um
you know organic or omri omni summary
certified
um
fungicides that you think might solve
this issue now granted this is this is
like a nuclear option right because it's
also probably going to take down your
mycelium networks and everything else so
like this is not what we want to do but
people who do all sorts of radical
things uh when they've got an infest or
you know an infected bed so so i figure
it's worth asking
yeah so there's there's a few um there's
there's actually quite a bit of
biological fungicides that are out there
that you can i'm pretty sure you can now
use within cannabis uh but there's
there's three that come to my mind that
are more efficient towards fusarium
uh and and they're all biological
fungicides so a good way to think of it
as good microbes versus your bad
microbes such as your fusariums the bad
microbe and the good microbes that i
have in mind are pseudomonas uh species
and biological uh fungicides so you can
just look it'll say active ingredient
when you read the label and if it if
it's a pseudomonas strand and if it's
labeled for fusarium
um
diseases then that's that's a good
contender that you could use another one
that's really popular that i've used
because it's it's really efficient
within uh suppressing pythium is root
shield so that's a trichoderma
which is a beneficial fungi that can
mycoparasitize
other bad fungi or oomy seeds so it's
really efficient in in that and bacillus
so bacillus is a bacteria psoas
pseudomonas the one that i said earlier
those are both beneficial bacterias uh
and and there's a lot of products such
as triathlon ba is a biofungicide that
comes to mind with bacillus in it and uh
and companion now i think they just came
out with a new formula like companion
max so these would all be uh good
formulations that you could use that are
organic they're omni-certified like you
said um and you could you could like try
to try to put those in the bed but it
just depends how high those fusarium
populations are
uh to see how effective those biological
fungicides will be on helping colonize
that fusarium that's in the bed and prey
upon it but yeah like that's another
another good solution that you could you
could try out and those are the three
that come to my mind that are that have
been
pretty efficient towards fusarium right
on and then and then after you use them
as a nuclear option you're gonna be left
with a bed that's like out of balance
and you're gonna have to spend some time
you know like rebuilding the biology
which is why you know it is considered a
nuclear option where you're just trying
to
you know save
maybe not save the living part of the
soil but just not have to replace the
soil and the silt and this you know sand
and the rocks and and like start over
with a clean slate like you're like
maybe you can
maybe you can save your inputs but
you're gonna have to rebuild the biology
after you use something like that
right and i don't think it's a bad thing
so i think we see it as oh if we add
these products they'll be so dominant
like we'll just have like bacillus in
the bed or we'll just have pseudomonas
but i think we need as researchers
um to really look into what will happen
uh when we just add these products to
because i mean we're talking about like
outdoor
uh beds even if they're indoors like you
know you got silly you got rocks you
have you have soil that you had there
previously i'm i'm not so sure if adding
these biological products would totally
dominate you know this microorganism
community in there if if anything you
know i would hypothesize that adding
them may recruit other different
organisms to make up in the bed and
things like that like i think we
underestimate how complex these
microorganism communities are
uh within all these different
living situations so i i think that
would be like a really interesting uh
thing to study like you know if i have a
bed uh that had high populations in
fusarium if i added a biofungicide how
does that reduce the populations and how
does that change the microbial makeup of
that bed i think all these are very like
unanswered questions that hopefully in
the next you know five ten years with
all these researchers now getting grants
to study cannabis like something that
we'll have more answers for because
that's that's something i just i just
don't know hear hear i love that answer
i love that i was doomed i was dooming
about the whole thing and you're like oh
you know let's trust the microbes which
is usually my answer for things so i
love that so all right cool well we're
going to take another short break and be
right back you are listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is plant
pathologist cora mcgee
[Music]
there are so many seed banks nowadays
that you really have options in who to
choose not only that if you pick the
wrong seed bank you could be in for a
really sketchy ride and that's only one
of the reasons i recommend hembra
genetics collection to my friends and
listeners who are looking for a seed
bank that's hembra spelled h-e-m-b-r-a
hembra is not just another seed bank
hembra is a woman operated boutique
cannabis genetics provider that only
sells thoughtfully curated seeds from
the top names in cannabis breeding with
over 50 breeders and over 500 strains to
choose from you will certainly find
something you'll love
hembra genetics has something for
everyone with over 350 feminized strains
200 regular varieties and over 100 auto
flowers to choose from
names you know you can trust like
humboldt seed company night owl
cannerado in-house genetics fast buds
and gnome automatics
we both know that there are other seed
banks who will take your money but have
no customer service
i invited hembra to advertise on shaping
fire after hearing so many good stories
about them from my friends
they have a plus customer service with
lightning fast response times
in most cases helene and caitlin will
get your order out the same day you
place it and you'll usually receive your
seeds in just a few days
most seed banks are simply not this
organized or interested in getting your
seeds to you this fast but hembra cares
you even get free seeds with every order
helene and caitlin get it they have been
in the cannabis growing scene for over a
decade
so save a few bucks by using this
discount code too use the code shaping
fire all one word at checkout to save 10
off your order
buy seeds from good folks who will get
you great seeds reliably every time
visit
hembragenetics.com today that's hembra
genetics
[Music]
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by farmers is
because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year
and we know these fungal networks are
essential because they are the nutrient
super highways that extend far and wide
in the substrate to feed your plants the
trouble with growing in new living soils
or blended cocoa substrates is that it
takes most of the plant's life just to
create these mycelium highways
dinomyco endomycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the other popular brand in the u.s at
900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation
dynomica is the result of 30 years of
research and trials at the volcani
agriculture research institute in israel
it has also been vigorously trialed by
cannabis and food growers across the us
dynamico is now available at grow shops
and on amazon in the united states i
love using dynamico to both speed up the
growth of the mycelium networks in the
soil but also as a biostimulant to make
clone cuttings more virile you can see
side by side showing the comparative
growth on their instagram at dinomyco
if you demand reliable growing results
and appreciate the importance of an
active root zone in creating a thriving
plant i encourage you to check out
dinomyco.com and use the store locator
to find out where you can get yours
that's d-y-n-o-m-y-c-o
dot com
shaping fire listeners can get ten
percent off any size of dynamico on
amazon or dynamico.com by using the
discount code shaping fire one word no
cabs
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some zing
to tired soil choose dinomyco to
maximize your plant's potential
dinomyco endomycorrhizal inoculant
[Music]
cannabis folks are innovators and
problem solvers and we like to make
money have you developed a tool
technique or plant that you want to
protect and monetize
you'll likely want legal representation
that is experienced accessible and
shares your values
plant and planet law represents a wide
variety of clients who choose to respect
the environment while pursuing their
business goals
have you invented a machine or gizmo
that you're bringing to market did you
discover a breakthrough environmentally
friendly pesticide or fertilizer
formulation that you're about to start
selling
have you bred a canvas plant with
attributes not found anywhere else
attorney dale hunt and his plant and
planet team have established genetic
patents in over 30 countries
working to help entrepreneurs scientists
throughout the life sciences plant and
planet represents environmentally
positive clients in cannabis and other
botanicals fungi water purification
clean energy emulsions and medical
applications
plant and planet helps people protect
what they've created if you are an early
stage company with an established idea
and are in the process of fundraising
often the investors require intellectual
property protections happen at the same
time
plant and planet can be your sole
representation or they can integrate
with your existing legal team and plug
in their specialties
plant and planet is made of scientists
lawyers with a real passion for cannabis
inventions and the environment they have
the scientific and legal depth to help
you establish patent protections for
your great idea
you don't have to go it alone
friendly qualified and honorable legal
representation is available to you
contact plant and planet law today to
start the conversation
email info at
plant and planet.com
that's plant and planet law our clients
make the planet better
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host shango los
and my guest today is plant pathologist
cora mcgee all right so cora we have
already talked a lot about prevention uh
which is essentially don't let your soil
be too wet because all hell breaks loose
when uh the soil is too wet um but a
couple times you have mentioned um not
not causing the
pythium and fusarium to spread by you
know keeping things clean right
and um
while
how do i want to say this while lip
service is given to oh you know wiping
down your
scissors or whatever in you know the
cannabis cultivation scene um
i gotta admit to myself i don't even
know if i'm cleaning my tools right i
mean i just cleaned my tools the way
that my mentor taught me to clean my
tools but i didn't learn that anywhere
so let's start with that um what what
tools should we be keeping clean and how
do we clean those tools properly
right so
so pruners and shears and things like
that uh things that you use to prune or
take cuttings those definitely need to
be sanitized and you can sanitize those
by
if you have isopropyl alcohol
some people spray down their tools and
wipe them uh i'm saying i'm not saying
anything's wrong with that but
personally i would fully submerge
the tools in the isopropyl alcohol just
to make sure you're getting um you know
it's covering all the surface area and
whatnot you're not missing anything when
you just spray
i think that would be one thing i would
say and then
you can also use a solution of 10
percent bleach to also clean your tools
which is pretty effective however i
would give a contact time
to sit in that ten percent bleach before
you use them for all your plants for you
know about five to ten minutes uh to
really make sure that
it's getting uh any
any infecting uh tropicals that may be
on those tools uh really you know give
you
security that that they should be
cleaning when you say the contact time
do you mean that the bleach solution
should be like it should be soaking in
the bleach solution for 10 minutes or
are you saying that don't put it on your
plants for 10 minutes after you do it
that's a good that's a good question to
clear it up so i'm saying you want to
you want to let your tool sit in the 10
bleach solution for about 5 to ten
minutes and then you can just wipe them
off and use them but you just you do
wanna make sure that within the the ten
percent bleach solution that uh the
contact time is is enough to where the
cleaning solution is actually doing its
job for the tools
does that does that 10 minutes also work
for
using the isopropyl or ethanol solution
so it's interesting so uh speaking from
i know not a growing side but in the
laboratory when i'm doing anything like
very sterile or if i'm putting isolates
into long-term storage you know i do let
my scalpels and my my metal tool sit in
uh alcohol
for for at least 10 minutes just to be
safe and then i'll flame them however i
understand that uh i haven't seen this a
lot within growing operations i know
definitely the contact time for the 10
bleach is very important but it's really
up to you
um
again my preference i would say i'd want
to fully at least submerge them
but i don't
i don't think that it's necessary for
that that 10 minute contact time with
the isopropyl uh
alcohol so let's get really specific
because you know i am usually using
either
isopropyl alcohol or ethanol because as
a cannabis enthusiast these are things i
have a lot of in my life around
and normally i would have a washcloth
that has got some isopropyl or ethanol
on it and i will simply
wipe
the scissors on the four blade sides
and just call it good i am thinking at
this point that that's not enough
contact time
well it's not just that but you're not
truly like so if you're just kind of
wiping the blades of the scissors like
that the scissors may have other parts
of it that haven't gotten
exposed to the alcohol that now you're
clipping and you know it could be a
source of contamination
so just to totally eliminate that uh
you know in my opinion i i think
spraying can be effective but you know
also submerging the tools and the
alcohol can also be effective just to
make sure that you're covering all parts
of the tools
so so
i'm trying to think of the best practice
for this because
um you know putting all of my tools into
a bath at the end of the day and walking
away and even leaving them overnight
like that sounds like easy squeezy but
i'm also using those scissors on
multiple plants during the day and i'm
pretty sure you're gonna tell me that
there should be some amount of cleaning
before i go plant to plant because
that's how i spread infection right
you should yeah i mean
if you especially if you've been having
issues with disease in the past and you
just like want to be very sure i know
within uh the apple and pear industry
they i mean that they
plant a plant i mean five minutes
soaking between plant to plant like it
it's pretty serious within that industry
so yeah you could also uh take a page
out of
what other crop producers um or other
yeah pretty much other crop producers do
and other growers do uh by you know you
could have multiple shears in a jar of
ethanol and you know kind of rotate them
out as you go plant a plant so you're
not waiting forever
or you know i like that that's that's a
pretty good best practice because like
one thing that we cannabis growers have
are lots of freaking scissors right like
because we go through them and and you
know we're all trimming at the end of
the season and so i probably got 17 pair
you know the hardest part would just be
finding them all at the same time but
but i like the idea of if i'm if i'm
going down the row and trimming all of
the plants of everything that's necrotic
or unnecessary or big leafing or
whatever to to have like you know six or
seven pairs in a bath and just work my
way down the line and use a pair of
scissors and put them in the back and
then grab the next pair for the next
plant and by the time i get to the first
pair again
they will well have been have the
contact time that they need
yeah yeah
and uh and you know better to be safe
than sorry too so it might seem like
overkill but you know
if you're not getting disease then at
least you know
it's a good pat on the back where it's
like oh well
this might seem really excessive but i
really don't want to get diseased
because then once i have it there's no
way to control it yeah i would say that
that's a no-brainer yes to anybody who
is scaled for sure because you've got a
lot of room for loss but then also
anybody who's not scaled because
like in the example earlier if you've
only got five plants one of the benefits
is that you can go slow and you can
scout every day and you know you can
you know do do
soaks like this because every plant is
precious so whether every plant is
precious or you've got a lot to lose
from sheer numbers it really does sound
like a best practice for anybody who's
actually just a conscientious grower
right and i would also say you know it
doesn't just stop with uh pruners and
shears you could also if you're reusing
a bunch of pots like even spraying down
those pots and getting all the loose
soil out and just really starting clean
with um with with everything that you're
using within the production
is also a pretty good idea as well so do
you mean like spray down the pots with
like isopropyl
yeah you could do that 10 bleach uh yeah
let them but make sure you let them dry
before you know you put soil in sure
sure uh but yeah like just another way
uh you know i'm sure you you reuse like
seedling trays or i'm sure that's true
y'all don't do stuff from seedling but
you know where you put your cuttings or
just any type of plastics is a good way
to put it uh pots and things like that
that you keep reusing yeah that also it
does not hurt to uh
to get
you know empty them out kind of kind of
brush them out get all that uh like any
like you know roots that may have been
in there get them out of there any like
old soil
you could even do a dip within the 10
bleach let them dry somewhere and then
once they're dry they're ready to go and
you've got clean pots that you can reuse
uh it's a good
a good um
sanitation procedure right on so um
so
i'd like you to speak briefly to
the other cross-contamination that
you've just kind of alluded to a couple
times and so i'm gonna give you just a
couple data points and then just kind of
let you run with it one
is that um
you know you mentioned how
the
you can get an infection from pot to pot
and so i would like to know what the
mechanism for that is and then you
mentioned you know stuff getting on your
shoes and the floor and so it sounds
like
we need to be careful with pot to pot
prevention and then also
you know literally maybe maybe we're
even using a 10 bleach solution on the
floor so so kind of speak to that if you
would
yes so
so it's it it's easier so say you're
growing kind of worn an indoor silly it
can be a little easier to sanitize uh
surfaces as you will with um you know
ten percent bleach or you know i don't
know how big the operation a lot of
commercial growers will use xeritol or
sanidate some of these oxidizers that
can really cyst open and kill infecting
tropicals um really efficient on
surfaces
uh so so that's one
and you don't want like excessive
splashing going on everywhere uh and
yeah if you have debris on your floor
again like you really want to get rid of
all that plant debris that soil debris
root debris that may fall out from
plants that you've harvested and you're
trying to get rid of
because yeah those you know we talked
about earlier how these
pathogens can survive and you know
decaying tissue and soil uh and just
kind of stay dormant so so it
it's easy to spread that around when
it's just kind of sitting on the floor
sitting on your bench and it's not and
it's just sitting there and not getting
swept up taken care of putting in the
trash and uh even after you sweep up
it's a good practice to you know even
sanitize those floors sanitize those
benches uh if you have a canopy you know
like cleaning that canopy um off every
now and then uh can can really help
again like your your whole goal is to
lower the contamination is to lower
these pathogen populations within your
growing
operation
what do you specifically mean by
splashing that's kind of that word seems
kind of out of context
so splashing
there's multiple ways you can splash so
a lot of people uh within cannabis
industry that i've personally seen i
don't know if it's for everyone uh does
a lot of hand irrigation
and so within other crop um production
at a higher scale a lot of drip
irrigation to avoid the splashing that
i'm talking about
because say
say i have
a bunch of debris or i've got debris
somewhere and now you know i'm i'm
splashing everywhere and the water is
getting on the floor and it's you know
you don't want anything to splash into
your uh your healthy like you know
uncontaminated soil um from a potential
contamination source so that's one and
also you know with boots like you can
get things on your boots and then you're
walking around in the water and then you
know say you've got multiple stages one
thing that i really want to stress is
you don't want to go trudging around and
uh say you've got a section where you
have more mature plants older plants uh
and there's a lot of soil and you know
you're working within that um
you know you're irrigating your boots
are all muddy what have you and then you
go into your cutting or you know younger
tissue seedling bay you really want to
make sure that that stays really clean
because those young
uh cannabis plants are a lot more
susceptible to these diseases so like
even at you know a lower population they
could they could be compromised and get
an infection so you you want to be
careful of how you're even contaminating
um
you know bay to bay or or you know
garden to garden you know bringing any
soil and and really bringing
contaminants with you in different
sections uh wherever you're growing as
well uh so it's something to really keep
in mind
uh and even like cleaning your boots off
you know that's a yeah you get into the
habit of it spraying them down after
each day and
and uh yeah i am so guilty of that
splashing from hand watering i had not
even ever considered that because i am
one of those people
that hand waters from a hose with a
water wand on the end
and i just go plant to plant and
you know so long as the soil isn't
hydrophobic it will
almost immediately soak into the soil
but there is a moment there that it does
kind of collect on the top and and i'm
doing you know using the rain setting
and so there's all these micro splashes
and it's probably aerosolizing all sorts
of stuff from the top of the pot
that is
you know very likely going to be spread
to the nearby plants
yeah that's me so all right um all right
so uh sorry so so before we move on from
like cleaning stuff is there is there
anything that i have missed that that uh
i should ask
um i think we've covered a lot of it uh
you always want to inspect your new
plant material like i said you know the
youngest plant materials super
susceptible to these diseases um and i
know you t you know if you take cuttings
from mother plants you always want to
inspect that mother plant i know within
commercial
facilities they don't they don't want to
keep a mother plant for more than two
months uh they always want to be
starting with uh really clean plants
because you know it really starts in the
beginning you want to start with healthy
plants and end with healthy plants and
um
and yeah just make sure you get all that
debris off the ground you're not
you know bringing contaminants from one
field to another field
and you're properly sanitizing your
tools and all the equipment that you're
using to grow again just as another
safety net as that prevention umbrella
we've been talking about
so
sort of really help your your grow right
be the most successful you can
the same team we all just want the
plants to be uh as happy and as as uh
healthy as they can be so just putting
these things into place it it seems like
a pain but it always pays off when you
don't have disease issues uh so it's all
good practices to keep in mind right on
now see that is such a great summary
right now would be a great time for me
to like wrap up the show and thank you
and everything but there's one more
question that i want to ask you
um
when you and i were first on the phone
and talking about whether or not we
thought this was going to be
an episode we wanted to do together
you said something in passing that
totally
you know got my attention and and i
wanted to ask you about it and
and
you were talking about your research
there at university of connecticut
and you were all excited because you
said that you had just killed a whole
greenhouse of cannabis for research and
you were all excited about it and so
like would you tell us the story like
why why did you kill an entire
greenhouse of cannabis and why were you
thrilled about it
that's a total like if there's like any
plant pathologist listening they're like
uh yeah it's like we only feel that way
it's like when we see sick plants we
like get really excited
so i want to give a little context so at
uconn i i predominantly study
uh root pathogens within leafy greens or
vegetable crops that's that's what i
focus on however
since the doors have really opened for
cannabis and not a lot of people have
been working on it we had gone to a
commercial facility in 2019 and they had
symptomatic plants with the same
symptoms that we've just covered in this
show reduced growth yellow tissue they
even had one plant that fully wilted
that they bagged and was like trying to
get it out of there
um and at uconn at any research facility
we can't take the tissue so i wasn't
allowed to actually take the roots and
take uh any in the infecting tissue so i
took because these are cannabis plants
to be clear these are not leafy greens
you got to go to a commercial cannabis
facility
yes yes so
right thank you for clearing that up so
so we had gone to a cannabis facility
because they're you know having some
issues we're just checking it out
and we ended up taking the
they were growing mature cannabis plants
in coconut core
uh so we had taken the coconut core
surrounding the roots of all the
symptomatic plants brought them back to
the lab well um we had actually ended up
getting 26 uh organisms
uh wow that sounds like a lot it was
yeah it was a lot we did serial dilution
plating some people can get like more
but we had collected from a good bit of
plants so within that uh fast forward so
we had identified them morphologically
and molecularly we got 21 of those
isolates where pithier mario tilum the
one that i spoke about earlier that's
very sev causes very severe uh symptoms
within cannabis and we've seen that
and then three were this globosporangium
irregular that was formally the pythium
irregular
and then one was a fusarium oxisporum
that we actually got from a cutting uh
in rockwool
so
so fast forward we've got these isolates
and as a plant pathologist in order to
actually publish and be confident about
our findings that these organisms were
the ones that were causing the symptoms
within these plants it we have to do
what's called coke's postulates
so we have to
isolate those organisms and then we have
to reinfect the same crop
with those isolates
separately so we can see the effect of
each one of these isolates
on the cannabis plants to see
if they cause disease and they caused a
lot of disease and i mean i've been
working with root pathogens for about
six years now and i i really haven't
seen this type of virulence or severity
within um
within seedlings uh as much as i have
with cannabis uh when i had
introduced these pythiums that i had
gotten from the facility so uh just to
kind of wrap it up
we had a whole greenhouse with a
thousand cannabis plants and they were
uh
i inoculated them
at two weeks old after i'd grown them
from seed so so they're pretty young and
and they were growing pretty well and
then we'd inoculate them
uh
how tall were they i want to say
i want to say they grew to about a foot
so these are about foot uh kind of young
cannabis plants and we got about a
thousand of them and all of the 21
pythium meriotilum isolates that we had
gotten from that facility that we
introduced back on to healthy uh we
couldn't do marijuana plants those hemp
plants
all of them went down i mean chlorosis
they all wilted uh only you know
some as soon as a couple days after that
pythium was introduced to them uh so it
really showed
wow yes these
these pythiums that we got from the
facility um are very pathogenic
pathogenic uh
to cannabis and and cause high virulence
or high severity when we put them back
on the plants so then as you know as
scientists it's like okay so now
now we're going to report it so you
can't just take a disease from a plant
and be like okay it causes disease you
know you have to like i said uh make it
happen yes you have to prove you have to
like i didn't just randomly get this
organism
you have to prove that can actually
cause uh symptoms and infection on the
plant that you got it from so yeah
i guess it was very
exciting because like i said i i
cannabis is very susceptible to pythium
and that just kind of opened our eyes to
like wow like research really you know
it's exciting because i'm sure there's
going to be a lot more research projects
and opportunities coming up to help
these growers and help everyone
really not only identify but help
control and the things you're talking
about and understanding more about it
because it seems
uh you know i always i work with
poinsettias a lot too within our lab we
do some with ornamental growers and
poinsettia is like really susceptible to
pithium as well it's you know if you
talk to any growers who grow poinsettias
as it is a big pathogen they look out
for and i'm like like cannabis is the
next poinsettia when it comes to pythium
because uh because pythium's pretty
severe on it so um
right on well i appreciate you sharing
that story and you know uh you know
props to university of connecticut for
doing whatever
legal like hoops they had to jump
through in order to be able to do
you know uh cannabis research whether
it's hemp or type one is is you know
doesn't matter because it's the same
plant it's just nice to know that we've
got university ag departments working on
our side now and that and that people
like you are doing that kind of work and
killing thousands of plants
so that we can all the rest of us
learn best practice
so so shout out to university of
connecticut for that and and i so i
guess in in wrapping up thank you also
to you cora for for joining me here on
shaping fire and sharing your experience
you know you've um since you work with
us on a daily basis in a university
setting and you know you're getting
ready to defend your own phd
it's really nice to have somebody who
has got such specific examples and
easily accessed metaphors and knowledge
where you can go right to the point
instead of dancing around it so thank
you so much for coming on the show and
uh and sharing your expertise
thank you for having me it's been very
fun and you've been all so awesome
shango and just it's been a pleasure
excellent so if you want to learn more
about uh different molds and how they
involve with the cannabis plant i
recommend that you go back and check out
episode 28 of shaping fire which is all
about botrytis and powdery mildew in
scientific detail
with kevin mckiernan and that is a bit
more of a genetic approach than this
show was which was more about usability
and best practices but uh oh my goodness
you will know a lot more about botrytis
and powdery mildew after that show
from a genetic level and best practices
to uh to try to control it and um and if
you have enjoyed uh cora and you wanna
keep up with her and her exploits in the
lab um you can follow cora on her
instagram and that is cora mcgee with an
unusual spelling so i'm going to give it
to you that's
cora mcgee c-o-r-a-m-c-g
so that's cory mcgee on instagram
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts if you enjoyed the
show we'd really appreciate it if you
would leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for insights
into the latest cannabis news exclusive
videos and giveaways
on the shaping fire website you'll also
find transcripts of today's podcast as
well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast that's at shaping fire and at
shango lose on instagram be sure to
check out shaping fire youtube channel
for exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire i've been
your host shango lose
[Music]
you