[Music]
humans have been using various plant
medicines together as
blends for as long as there has been
medicine a root of this
a twig of that a mushroom maybe add some
heat and we found that we started to
heal
over millennia we refined our process
and got more adept at interacting with
the natural world
in the modern day even people who don't
consider themselves herbalists are
becoming quite adept at blending plant
and other medicines together to feel
better
so many of my friends are using smoked
cannabis
oral cbd oil micro dosing mushrooms and
have an essential oil diffuser in their
house
gang gang we often heal in similar ways
if you want to learn about cannabis
health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer
i encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week
and videos too don't rely on social
media to let you know when a new episode
is published
sign up for the updates to make sure you
don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive that newsletter so go
to shapingfire.com
to sign up for the newsletter this week
and be entered into this month's and all
future newsletter prize drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and
i'm your host shango los
today's episode is different from
anything i've offered before i was
recently invited to san francisco to
moderate a private panel recording on
synergistic medicine
the panel was entitled cannabis
mushrooms and terpenes for optimum
health
and was produced by cookies i did not
choose the panelists or the topic
but cookies reached out because they
loved shaping fire and i was happy to go
to the bay area to participate
when we were done recording i ended up
driving the pacific coast highway down
to southern california alone for a few
days too
it was a pretty nice break from
quarantine here on vashon island and
allowed me to travel while interacting
with less than 15 people the entire week
that drive along the pch never fails to
be spectacular so
the episode today is the audio from that
panel recording
i asked cookies if i could publish it as
a shaping fire episode because the
insights expressed by these speakers
is exceptional and there's a lot to
learn in it because there were multiple
mics used at various locations
and online and some of us were even
outside to be covered safe
some of the sound quality is variable
all in all it sounds good though so
don't let the audio of my speaker
introductions get you down
it gets better really fast so i hope you
enjoy this departure from the regular
show format and the great info
on blending synergistic natural
medicines
hi everybody and welcome today's round
table discussion brought to you by
cookies
um our topic for today is cannabis
mushrooms and terpenes for optimum
health i am your moderator for today's
discussion shango los
if you enjoy meaningful interviews with
the top minds in cannabis cultivation
solventless extraction and cannabis
medicine i invite you to check out my
podcast
at shaping fire at shapingfire.com or
wherever you get your podcast
we have an impressive and eclectic panel
today
to talk about synergistic medicine in
the modern era
people are encouraged to take medical
advice only from doctors
and the advice patients are usually
given by most doctors
is to take pharmaceutical company blends
of single components
rendered from the plants and other
naturally occurring life
these are often what's called for but
not always
today's discussion will focus on
cannabis
mushrooms and terpenes and how modern
formulators
healers and citizen scientists navigate
the interplay between them
so let's get to know our speakers so
because of the present pandemic
two of our speakers will be joining us
by video feed which you've probably
already figured out
so we'll start there via video link from
vashon island washington
dr ethan russo is a world-renowned
neurologist and cannabis researcher
he is author of several books of
cannabis medicine and has published over
30 articles in neurology pain management
cannabis and ethnobotany he is presently
founder of credo science
also via video link from vancouver
island british columbia canada
is jeff chilton jeff has pioneered the
development and manufacture of
organic mushroom extracts since 1973.
he received a fellowship to the dutch
school for mushroom growers
jeff co-authored and published the
classic best-selling book on small-scale
mushroom cultivation
the mushroom cultivator he is currently
founder of namex organic mushroom
extracts
so here on the set with me we've got
tony berzera
tony founded blue river terpenes and
extracts and is a visionary on the
extraction and use of terpenes
most recently tony has founded advasa a
licensed cannabis processor in
california
developing groundbreaking solvent-less
extraction technology
tony developed these companies as a
mechanism to reach his extraordinary
goals as a formulator of
modern cannabinoid blends and across
from me
is burner burner is a rapper songwriter
and entrepreneur
he is founder and ceo of cookies one of
the most influential lifestyle brands in
cannabis
burner uses his success and influence to
work with others to bring reliable
access
to emerging medicines for minority
neighborhoods that are often left out of
breakthroughs in health care
so welcome to all of you thank you so
much for being here
and so let's get right into it so uh
since we're gonna be focusing on blended
medicines with synergistic components
today
let's start by establishing their
efficacy in history
so dr russo we're gonna start with you i
know you have studied indigenous and
tribal medicines your whole life
and have spent a good amount of time in
peru working with indigenous people
there
is there a good basis to believe that
humans have combining
different plant medicines for thousands
of years absolutely
uh certainly among the matcha genga and
all the tribes
in amazonia it's common to mix things
particularly the ayahuasca admixtures
uh you necessarily have to have at least
two components
uh you have to get the harmaline
alkaloids
from the banisteriopsis vine
and the dimethyltryptamine from
psychotrial leaves or or
other donors there are hundreds of
plants in the amazon
that have dimethyltryptamine and there
are many other complex mixtures that
they employ
the prototypes that are probably most
familiar to people though are
traditional chinese medicine where you
might have
several components that attack the
problem itself
but there are a multitude of other
components that might deal with the side
effects from the main components
so mixtures of the norm as opposed to
simples meaning
one ingredient additionally on
western tradition among the greeks there
were
theriakos which were often again complex
mixtures and you see this
again through uh arabic medicine
uh some of those included cannabis for
example
and then coming up to modern times let's
take a complex
problem like cancer it usually is not
sufficient
to attack one aspect of the cancer
rather you have to attack multiple areas
of weakness
so that you get a good tumor kill at the
beginning
so for particularly for something like
leukemia people get a cocktail of
medicines
and then we have the example of cannabis
which is a cocktail of medicines in one
plant
between the cannabinoids and terpenoids
and potentially other components like
the flavonoids
but it absolutely makes sense to combine
cannabis with other herbal agents um
and the beauty of it is that our bodies
are really
uh equal to the task they're used to
dealing with these complex mixtures
because a lot of these things
would be components of our foods um
so it it's very much the norm as opposed
to
western medicine where they might
identify a target
in a receptor and computer design a
molecule to
fit there with the highest affinity
and highest potency but that doesn't
mean it won't be toxic
with these natural products although
there can be things that are toxic and
too high a dose or even low doses
for the most part our bodies are capable
of metabolizing them and
there's usually very little harm
attached that's great so
so jeff so i know that you have
researched both the the history of
chinese medicines
as well as interacted with the
indigenous folk
in china to learn them firsthand so
you've probably seen these ancient
mushroom blends that come out of china
too
why does chinese medicine blend
mushrooms well you know
i think dr russo was correct i mean
there's there's so many different
aspects to putting these different
formulas together
and and traditional chinese medicine i
mean it's the perfect example for that i
mean that's what it's kind of based on
they will
the traditional chinese doctor will will
prescribe
he'll diagnose he will prescribe
different herbs
that he believes will will address the
particular illness that
is present regarding mushrooms you know
they've been used for thousands of years
there
the there's one mushroom in particular
porya cocos which is a
a diuretic and one of the other things
that that we've found
too and what researchers have found is
that different
mushrooms will have effects on different
tumor systems
so so let's just say you you wanted to
either
prescribe one for as an adjunct to a
certain
tumor you could do that or in fact you
could put
them together into one particular
formula
and that would work in in different ways
on
on that particular uh illness that
somebody has in terms of cancer so
they're definitely reasons that you can
blend these together
and and certainly when it comes to
triterpenoids which is something that
we're really looking at
there are over 130 tri-terpenoids in
reishi mushroom and they found that
specific
ones will have specific activities so
that's something too that that is pretty
interesting in what you're talking about
i totally agree that that is an
interesting aspect in fact
when we talked um last time i was
actually surprised to find out that
mushrooms had terpenes
as a primarily uh you know cannabis
enthusiast
of course i've talked about and and done
my research in terpenes by the time the
mushrooms get to me
or at least the mushrooms that i usually
participate in they kind of they just
kind of don't seem to have all that much
smell but then when you smell one that
is fresh
you're like oh this is an entirely
different experience
[Music]
indeed and just to be clear not every
every uh
single species will have triterpenoids
there's a couple of species
in particular that are famous for that
one would be ganoderma
the reishi mushroom and the other would
be
chaga and and reishi's really packed
with these triterpenoids and that's what
gives it its bitter flavor
but a lot of the mushrooms do not have
those compounds so now that we've kind
of talked about um
how blends have been made throughout
human history
and we realized that actually blending
medicinal properties together
is is more the expectation rather than
separating them out and isolating them
let's talk a little bit about
um what people do when they blend them
so tony i'm coming over to you
as a professional formulator and healer
what attributes do you look for when
designing a healing blend or
formulation from different components i
subscribe to
both what they're talking about when it
when you look at eastern versus western
and i think really i think the
difference becomes
in the pharmac pharmaceutical world
they're really keying on
like on a compound an active ingredient
and
many often times they're creating a
synthetic
version of that so if we look at like
what the fda and what the world is
approving in actual medicine
we look at that they're looking at an
active compound or one singular type of
molecule that they're isolating
and they're utilizing that you know to
go through their research
and like you guys were talking about
they're you're
kind of addressing one issue but then
you might actually have a side effect to
another issue
and so when you're looking at um
synergistic
properties of all herbal medicine and
you look at what's called grass approved
that's what ethan khan was talking about
and these things are
made in earth they're made naturally and
so when you put them into your body
we're also from the earth
and so if we put things into our body
that is uh you know synthetically made
it doesn't it leaves a footprint right
and even it's like plaque
so if we were to you know start printing
3d
cannabis you know it's like oh well we
know what's in cannabis we got the
cannabinoids the terpenes the flavonoids
um we put a computer together and we
start printing
that herb you're never going to ever
ever capture
all of those compounds that are
naturally produced on earth and as we
put
those things into our body then it
leaves footprints and then we don't have
a sustainable
and a very synergistic type of approach
to what we're doing as a medicine
and so i think when you look at the
world of healers in the world of
pharmaceutical compoundist they have a
completely different approach
and so there's a chemist and there's an
alchemist and so i don't really
subscribe
to um and i think there is a place for
chemistry and i think it has a wonderful
place in the science world
but for me personally i'm trying to like
figure out a way to
naturally capture what's available in
the plant
and remove impurities that we
that are maybe in the plant that we
don't want to particularly have
and so that way we can actually do what
the western world is trying to
accomplish
but in a plant-based effectiveness and
so if i look at the plant of cannabis
and
burner gives me a particular type of
strain i'm going to look at the
statistics of it right i'm looking at
the compounds and say okay this has
thca cbga cbca
you know different kinds of actual
available phytocannabinoids
and then look at the terpene profiles
and we're looking at you know
upwards to 300 compounds and in between
that there's also those
other oils like we were talking about
the flavonoids
that also play into these oils and so
the terpenoids or terpenes of
mainstream cannabis viewers see it or
even terps
that's where you know when i first
started calling that everyone was upset
because it's terpenoids or terpenes i'm
like well
it's easy for the most people to
understand them as terps but
those are really not just the aroma uh
not just the flavor but they're really
the catalyst and the effect
behind all of that and our friend on the
panel here inspired me by the way
in taming thc i think it was 2007
when he wrote that um you know
everything i've done
has come from those that came before me
that laid the ideology down in front of
us that said hey
here's a concept the human body can have
an endocannabinoid deficiency
and that means that we're working off
receptor base in our body
our mind our body and our soul has a
synergistic
spirit if you will we're here and so how
do we interact with those
and so we want to be able to target that
receptor system as a formulator
and try to pull out all the really good
parts in uh
everything we're talking about to then
overlay that
similar to probably like how he makes
music right everyone thinks that you
probably have four tracks
probably hundreds hundreds of tracks to
make sounds
and have this whole thing come together
in the same way a beat or song's laid
down
i look at it the same way as how how am
i going to take
the worlds of what's available in this
cannabis plant
what's available in the mushrooms that
he's talking about and how do we create
this overlay to create that synergistic
natural compound
and reaction that we think
is going to do x y and z and it probably
will do x y and z but there's probably
other beneficial things
that's tapping into a different
consciousness there wow there's a lot of
good stuff there
um the first thing for anybody who has
not read it
i do recommend that you check out dr
russo's
taming thc paper that tony just referred
to
for many of us it was the thing that
opened our doors
to terpenes and understanding how they
interact with our endocannabinoid system
and um it's old enough now that it's
free online so uh you just want to
search
tamingthc and dr ethan russo and you'll
find it
and it's it's actually very readable
paper even though it's
also very legit science the other thing
that you said tony that i want to follow
up on is
i like this elegant uh delineation that
you make
between um chemistry and alchemy
whereas one um you're you're trying to
reduce
things and spread them apart and break
them apart
whereas with alchemy you're trying to
bring
essential essences together and um
they sound like they could be very
similar but they're certainly different
in intention
and and then as we look at different
extraction technologies
and separation technologies like
solventless
we also learned that um the the effect
of the the final medicine is drastically
different right
um uh is there i can't i can't really
imagine what would be
a rule of thumb but i figured i'll ask
you for it is there any
any like uh borderline or delineation
that you come up against where you're
like oh
i'm i'm drifting from alchemy into
chemistry
and that's not the direction i want to
go how do you know if you're if you're
thinking too chemistry-minded
well i don't have a chemistry degree so
i don't i don't i don't know how to use
chemicals
so i guess that's uh everyone you know
gets to that roadblock it's like i have
no choice you know
um so i just don't you know i feel like
i have
counter partners in the industry
that there's a few individuals out there
that seem to be following in the same
path that i and where i'm at where it's
like how do we
how do we break this thing down uh but
retain what's there
and so i do feel there are people out
there that use chemistry
and from a molecular standpoint um
we get into these debates all the time
so it's like hey if i've got this
solventless thca
that tests 99 and someone says well i
have this
chemical thc that tests 99 there's no
residuals left there's no
footprint left is this the same thing
the answer is in short it is you know it
is the same thing
um but how we get there uh is
is important i think and what's and and
ultimately how
we're utilizing that and what we're
doing to get to that so does it have an
environmental impact
right and so that's something that i
look at and a lot of people don't
really understand so if i'm using a
chemical to extract something from a
plant
what happens to that plant what's the
what's left in that plant for that
particular chemical is it reintroduced
into earth
or are we being able to capture
everything from that actual plant
and use everything in every part of it
and i think that maybe is where you're
going with this because alchemy is
how do i use i think we kind of had a
conversation once about this how do we
how do we use everything from that
flower without
creating pollution or an environmental
effect
we want to break this apart but every
part has a use
right we don't want to just focus on hey
i want this thc from this cannabis plant
let's throw the rest away and if i used
ethanol or i used butane or something
like that
now we've kind of created the next
problem which comes back to like this
medicine so
what is it what does it take to make
that synthetic opioid
in the process of making that just to
make that particular pill or that
fentanyl
right so they've done a great job making
the synthetic but then what did they do
in the process
of making that and what kind of
environmental impact so i think
it doesn't just come down to a chemical
versus mechanical
it comes down to a consciousness of what
you're what you're making
and then how do we make both the impact
on the human and on us
on this planet i don't know cool thanks
for breaking that out
so berner um you've spent a lot of time
with what i'll call citizen scientists
right
people who may or may not have the
degrees but they
are experimenting with good intention
to make either medicinal or recreational
and
you know that's a pretty blurry line too
but but you work a lot with citizen
scientists
cannabis breeders and psychonauts too
who experiment with the body
by ingesting you know all sorts of
things and substances right
what do you and other citizen
researchers look for
when combining healing or recreational
drugs
i mean i think it's important for people
to understand that even if they're going
into a recreational store to buy
cannabis and smoking is still a medicine
i think that's the biggest message we
try to get across is that
this is something that helps in so many
different ways so as you may be smoking
weed and a lot of people a lot of
friends i've met a lot of people that
that i've hung out with along the way
they don't really realize that they're
using it as a medicine
to them they're just getting high
they're kind of healing their pain
they're enjoying the taste but
so much of that that that plant medicine
is important for a lot of us
it unifies people it brings people
together and furthermore it helps a lot
more than
some of the pharmaceutical uh medicines
out there so
you know i think i think it's pretty
interesting because we have a voice and
a platform to educate
um that this is a medicine and that's
why
you know i was in the proposition 215
days and
you know i've been doing this legally
since i was 18 i personally saw
firsthand
off-duty cops coming in and buying
cannabis and
lawyers and teachers and it made me
really realize that
you know when it went wreck that we
shouldn't lose that we shouldn't lose
that message that this is a medicine
and you know where i where i grew up
working that there was a
lounge there so essentially people would
be able to come in and buy the herb and
they'd build a blaze and
just that that releasing of the mental
anguish so if someone was coming from
the va
and they've had a really bad time and
they just wanted to come in there not
just in medicine but
the way that people bond around the herb
is super
super healthy is good for the mind it's
good for people in general so
you know i feel like the people i'm
around and the people i'm trying to
educate is that
no matter if it's recreational or not no
matter if you enjoy smoking butter not
it still is a medicine
whether it's helping you with anxiety uh
depression you're celebrating you're
mourning
you're helping with your appetite um i
think that it's important to kind of get
that message across that this is still a
medicine
whether it be recreational or not yeah i
think that's a good point a lot of us
don't even realize sometimes that we're
we are taking it for medicinal reasons
even though in our head
we're doing it for recreational right
well yeah you may you may think that
you're smoking herb because you like the
way it tastes and
you know it puts a smile on your face
but there you go it puts a smile on your
face and
you know happiness is everything
especially during kobe and what's going
on in the world right now we need more
smiles we need more good vibes and good
energy
more unity people need to love people
more and that's just kind of what we do
why we do what we do i mean heck if at
this very basis being in a good mood and
being
joyful boosts our immune system and so
if if um you know using cannabis can
help get us there well
let's go for it right absolutely the
price of peace of mind right
that's medicine um and a quick story
i was in colorado once and i was in the
medical
world and it turned into the wreck and
you said it was kind of a gray line
and i was i was really down because i
spent a lot of time there i spent a lot
of time with patients and trying to help
people and i too was behind
the bar every single day if you will and
getting to know people and i saw people
coming in and we
helped a lot of people when it went to
recreational kind of got down
and i actually came out to the bay area
and
i always looked up to you and what you
guys were doing and
he started with you know one one spot
and i came out i was like oh man cookies
is still keeping it real they're still
with the people and the patients
and so i left that that whole entire
industry
for nothing behind me because of an
adult use and i was thinking i had that
chip on my shoulders recreational you
know
and then it just had that awakening i'm
in the bay and the community here
and the people uh that were behind it
it has something you know it's not just
the plant
it's how it brings people together and
then how we take care of each other
and there's a certain uh community that
comes behind it
and so i started to have a much
different approach to it
and realized exactly what what berner is
saying is that
i don't even like the word any more
recreational it's just responsible adult
use and now it's full
access for anyone that's 21 and up now
we don't have to have an excuse to say
you need to go see a doctor before we
can come
talk to you about getting whatever herb
makes you feel good because it is a
nerve and it is
medicine so well if you look at the
diversity of this conversation right
here we all have
different we all come from different
walks of life but we're united on this
conversation
i probably wouldn't be speaking to you
if it wasn't for cannabis vice versa
these gentlemen are super educated and
been doing this for a long time but
we're all coming together in this
conversation because of cannabis and
that's why i still do it
if there is this this sometimes not so
subtle mindset
uh from the from the medical days where
a lot of people honestly were kind of
sketched about going into some of those
stores
but once you were inside it was a very
loving
homey huggy good environment right
and then nowadays um the adult youth
stores are
very you know they've got a lot more
money behind them right so they're
they're very they're very shiny
and people are being programmed more for
the recreational mindset
by um by you know media
and yet they can still get a huge
variety
of quality flowers often and so it's got
a good
existence as well what do you see that
may have
been lost in the transition from
medical dispensaries kind of more grungy
lovey days
to this cleaner but maybe more
commoditized environment
that that we might want to encourage to
bring back yeah so
when when you used to come into a
medical dispensary it was like cheers
it was like taxi cab confessions people
would come in you'd be able to show them
the herb out the jar
if they they could smell it they could
pick it up it was way more personable
you can get to know what they like you
can recommend things
i might even give someone a bong here
let them taste it for their purchase
so if you look at the way that we're
doing cookies right now i encourage
people to do this
if you step into my store i still agree
to right away
and i have an ipad and they walk with
you to the flower menu and they're kind
of going through and talking to you
about
each and everything that you want to
know about they're educating you they're
giving their personal opinions and from
there when that customer is done with
that blood tender
then they go to get checked out so point
being is the personal experience
hands-on you come to some of these
flashy dispensaries
it's just a menu on the wall and you
kind of get in line and you kind of just
put your order and you bounce it's not
as personable
you know what we're doing with the
cookie store is we kind of created a
huddle
i believe a lot of good things happen in
the huddle so you got the flower table
is round and people are sitting around
that flower table and just like this i'm
smelling something you're seeing my
reaction
i'm seeing your reaction we may have a
conversation the personable
experience with people working with
people still there and that's what we're
doing with our dispensaries
and so i encourage people when you open
a dispensary
keep the customer in mind you know like
i said you know someone may be coming
from the va they may be coming from the
hospital they might have a terrible day
you want to give them your full
attention and kind of make it more
personable not so in and out you know
and so
that's why we chose the dispensary set
up the way we do we kind of keep that
good personable
interaction in place i think it's very
important yeah i would say that
because i've gone through that
experience right and now that you say
that
i do see that being the difference in
what's going on in those stores and now
i see
how you took that from the medical side
because you're right
there are a lot of stores out there they
just got their counters
and and before when it was medical um
it was that cheers kind of thing but i
can tell you that
being behind the bar at times where it
was just a couple registers
and you wanted to rap with someone and
talk to him everyone else had to wait
and that actually wasn't the most
efficient way to help someone
but now looking at thinking about what
you just said and you're right because i
came into the store and i'm like oh this
is kind of neat because this person did
come with me and i'm like i don't know
what flowers i need to come i came in
with my wife right
and she loves all the cookies flowers
she's like oh she's very particular she
wants to smell everything she wants to
know about everything she wants to know
everything there is
and i realized that that first
experience was like oh this is very
personal in the sense that
we had someone that catered to us and we
were looking at everything
and they didn't they weren't
transactional they weren't there for the
transaction
they were there for the education and
then it was like okay then you get in
line
so i do think he's got the right vibe
there and the right mentality in the
sense that that's how
the store looks amazing and you're right
it is it's got a lot more
bells and whistles behind it and there's
a lot more uh products there
but you know there's there's that touch
and for for us
i have a duality right so a lot of
people know me as
as blue river and i look at that as my
you know
top shelf uh extracts that it's like how
far can i push the world in the
boundaries of solventless
to me that was always like my the
products that we'd inhale
it was my my push for what can i do in
the adult
use world and then everyone that says to
me oh well the product's so expensive on
the patient blah blah blah
that's where the this other product line
that i created with invasive wellness
was capsules sublinguals topicals
you know creating cbn and these
different things because i'm like well
if you're really hurting
and you want something affordable let's
switch you over to a different delivery
method with a different price point
and they do carry both wide ranges of
these products so
i think that you know if you're opening
a dispensary it's not just about the
flowers or the extracts
but make sure you also still carry the
medicinal products too because there are
people that are looking for them
amen um you know i hadn't thought about
that about how the cookie stores are
designed
i experienced that at your at the
cookies uh geodesic dome at emerald cup
last year
i just generally liked how you go in one
side and out the other side but inside
there's all these like little kiosks
where people can mill around and learn
and ask questions and
that was pretty cool they create a
conversation yeah when you know people
that like herbs or
like to smoke they want to they want to
understand other people's experiences
and
that conversation is priceless that's in
2 15 days that's what we know
that's what i loved about my job is
talking to people even the jar
if you see the jars that we design it's
so you can pick it up you can look at it
you can twist it you can smell it
even though you can't do a deli style at
a big jar anymore we created a jar
custom for our store so people actually
see what they're they can actually see
it
clearly they can smell it they can still
be hands on a little bit you know
clutch yeah totally when i saw that i i
really missed the days of the mason jars
and sticking your nose in it and we're
probably away from those days forever
but um
we got to be creative about new ways for
people to be able to shop with their
nose again
well you and real quick you remember
that like i used to open those big jars
we'd shake them up and kind of like
so if you think about what that just did
was that
i don't want to sell the product from
that jar that i've opened all day long
with all the broken trunks
especially what's going on right now
it's like you want to get your like look
at the sample
but let me buy something brand new and
sealed and so that's also another really
good touch
that you guys do that i think is
different thank you we're going to take
a short break and be right back
you are listening to shaping fire
sometimes the topics i want to share
with you are far too brief for an entire
shaping fire episode
in those instances i post them to
instagram i invite you to follow my two
instagram profiles and participate
online
the shaping fire instagram has follow-up
posts to shaping fire episodes
growing and processing best practices
product trials and
of course gorgeous flower photos the
shango los instagram follows my travels
on cannabis garden tours
my successes and failures in my own
garden insights and best practices from
personal grows everywhere
and always gorgeous flower photos on
both profiles the emphasis is on sharing
what i've learned in a way that you can
replicate it in your own garden
your own hash lab or for your own
cannabinopathic health
so i encourage you to follow at shaping
fire and
at shango lose and join our online
community on instagram
if you listen to shaping fire and you
grow your own cannabis
chances are high that you are very
particular about the inputs you use for
growing
people like us painstakingly
self-educate on cannabis nutrients and
techniques
so we can cultivate the best tasting and
cleanest flowers possible
and when we go to purchase those
nutrients we want to be sure that our
supplier shares our values
and is providing exceptional quality
this is why i recommend
buildasoil.com to my friends who care
about quality
build a soil empowers organic growers to
do their best work
by sourcing and shipping only the finest
cannabis growing supplies
from organic inputs soils soil testing
and pots
to lights growing tents sprayers and
cover crops
build a soil founder jeremy silva
doesn't just stock his store with what's
available
he goes deep to personally vet each
product for quality
and determine that there isn't a better
version of the product that he could be
selling
because of this arduous process you know
that your options on buildasoil.com
have been carefully curated to create
the results you are looking for
not only that but the build a soil way
is a philosophy that will permeate your
interaction with the company
from website design to pricing and
shipping to after purchase support
jeremy and his team always strive to do
their best
and give you the best customer service
in the business
check out buildasoil.com today
for top tier quality cultivation
supplies and a friends and family buying
experience
and check out their educational videos
and extraordinary social
media while you're there too quality
organic growing supplies
at buildasoil.com
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by farmers
is because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year
and we know these fungal networks are
essential because they are the nutrient
super highways that extend far and wide
in the substrate to feed your plants
the trouble with growing in new soils or
blended cocoa substrates
is that it takes most of the plant's
life just to create these mycelium
highways
dinomyco endomycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of
nutrients faster and it's three times
the concentration of the current leading
brand in the u.s
at 900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation
this new product called dynomico is the
result of 30 years of research and
trials at the volcani agriculture
research institute in israel
it has also been vigorously trialled by
cannabis and food growers
across the u.s since the product first
arrived here last year you may have
already even heard about dynamico by its
original name
dynamic now dynomico is available at
grow shops and online in the united
states for the first time
i love using dynomyco to both speed up
the growth of mycelium networks in the
soil
but also as a biostimulant to make clone
cuttings more
virile you can see side by sides showing
the comparative growth on their
instagram
at dinomyco if you demand reliable
growing results and appreciate the
importance of an active root zone in
creating a thriving plant
i encourage you to check out dynamico at
dynomico.com
and find out where you can get yours
that's
m y d-y-n-o-m-y-c o dot com whether you
are starting with new beds or pots or if
you want to add some zing to tired soil
choose dynamico to maximize your plant's
potential
dynamico endomycorrhizal inoculant
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire and i'm your host shango
los and our guests this week are dr
ethan russo
tony verzura jeff chilton and burner
let's return to the panel discussion now
so jeff the medicinal and psychedelic
mushrooms are becoming increasingly
popular in the u.s and throughout the
world right
um and you can buy tincture in
concoctions like nearly
everywhere including like some gas
stations even right it's so strange to
see
medicinal non-psychedelic mushrooms at a
gas station
because of that there's a wide variety
of qualities and price points of
medicinal mushrooms now even though we
know that they've got varying amounts of
medicinal qualities to them what
attributes do we want our
medicinal non-psychedelic mushrooms to
exhibit
so we know they will be potent and have
a positive effect on our lives
well you know one of the biggest issues
in the in this category
right now is the fact that a lot of the
products out there are not actually
even mushroom and you know this speaks
to to you know you know like with
with cannabis for example there are
multiple
parts of this plant so you've got the
roots you've got the leaves you've got
the flowers
and each one of those is going to have a
certain chemical profile
now it's no different with mushrooms and
and
what we call a mushroom is actually a
fungal organism that's got
what i call three plant parts mushrooms
don't have seeds
so how do you grow a mushroom well
mushrooms have spores
the spores will germinate into a fine
filament called a haifa those haifa come
together and produce what's called
a mycelium this is the actual body of
this organism
when conditions are right it will
produce a mushroom
and then that mushroom will will uh grow
up mature it'll produce spores we've got
a completion of the life cycle so we've
got three plant parts we've got spore
we've got mycelium and we've got
mushroom now the mushroom is what's
traditionally been used
as medicine and the mushrooms very
complex on what it can
actually produce but they're actually
products out there where they grow the
mycelium but they grow it on a
sterilized grain
in a laboratory and at the end of the
process
once the grain has been covered with the
mycelium
they will actually uh
dry it grind it to a powder grain and
all
and sell it as mushroom so this is one
of the key issues out there again it
gets back to
would somebody want to be selling a
cannabis product and they're just
grinding up leaves and saying hey here
i've got these great joints of a
pot and it's like well no no of course
not
i mean that's something maybe in the in
the 60s we might come across right
somebody would say hey i got this great
pot it's like
oh yeah huh tastes pretty bad what is
this really right
well that's what's going on right now in
the medicinal mushroom
uh category there are products out there
that are not mushroom yet they're being
sold as mushroom they are mostly
starch so and you know one of the things
i'd like to stress here too
is that what i love and i'm sure you
guys do too
and that is analysis i mean that's one
of the things that cannabis is really
built on is analyzing and and
this was something in the mushroom
category that was non-existent
uh five years ago where maybe they would
be measuring what are called
polysaccharides
um when in fact polysaccharides can also
be the starches and these
products that are that are manufactured
on this grain
well grain is a polysaccharide we have
tests for beta glucans that can
demonstrate
that we've got the compounds in there
that are actually important
those are the compounds that provide the
medicinal benefits the immunological
benefits
these myceliated grain products are
mostly starch with very low amounts of
beta glucans if you know what tempeh is
that's actually what's being ground up
to a powder
and sold as mushroom and if you hear
people out there touting
mycelium um basically
they're not mycelium is good on its own
not quite as good as the mushroom but
it's
it's um it's sometimes spoken about
or or being sold but it's on this grain
as a carrier
so for us that's the key thing that you
have to look for when you're out there
looking for a
mushroom product and and primarily look
and see whether they're analyzing for
the beta glucans because that's
the important compound you you want to
see
if they say polysaccharides well forget
it it's probably
one of these other products and maybe
you'll have a really high number of
of polysaccharides but that's because
the product is mostly starch
so so again we love to analyze we have
about four
different compounds that we analyze for
every single lot that we produce it'll
be beta glucans alpha glucans
ergosterol ergothionine
we've got a profile it's got to meet
that profile then when you're talking
about let's first let's for example try
terpenoids
we've reached a point now where we can
actually
analyze for up to 20 of these
triterpenoids and get a much more robust
profile and this is kind of like the
future of analysis for us when it comes
to
the reishi mushroom or or chaga to where
now we've got this amazing profile much
like you guys have this these profiles
of the cannabinoids
i mean it's just a whole new universe
for us
in terms of as we move forward and being
able to
to actually uh have this type of profile
for
our reishi for example it seems to make
it really clear that
it doesn't matter really whether we're
talking about cannabis
or mushrooms or terpenes
there's there's so many people trying to
do it different ways and so many of them
are
being motivated by the dollar
that it's important to always do your
homework to make sure that the products
that you're
blending together our good products to
begin with
and we are still at a point in this
market where
no matter what you're buying um you will
be rewarded by doing your homework
well you know what the fact that
the operation has been us
been with us since the beginning of
commerce i mean it's just a fact of life
out there so it doesn't really matter
what herbal product it is for example uh
adulteration is out there and always
will be
i was gonna say something it sounds like
uh in the world of
cannabis versus uh mushrooms it's
interesting as he was describing that
we and like from our side you know we we
see this as the trichomes develop
as first little stalks and then they get
that little mushroom head
you know from an extractor side it's
like i'm i can't even
i'm like i can't extract if i don't have
the mushroom head right
and i was like so what he's what he's
basically saying in our
in my kind of world is that he's saying
that there's people out there that
aren't even getting to the resin gland
they're just growing the little stock
they're not even doing it on the plant
they're doing it on some other they're
like on a yeast like when you hear like
oh
someone's growing like thc on yeast
there's
it's like apples and oranges here you
know it's like two different things but
it's interesting because he's got a big
macro mushroom head
and we're looking for those little micro
mushroom heads because that's where all
the the nutrient dense base is
um and i also looked at your uh
testing when he was talking about the
testing thing which we're also big into
testing and providing a certificate of
analysis
you guys have been like fda approved
since like
90 something like 96 or something
well well you know what nobody actually
gets fda approved
in that sense you know certainly not in
in our industry i mean there's
there's fda laboratories that you could
have things
analyzed by um and we
no i'm not uh not fda i'm sorry you're
um
certified organic since 19. oh yes i
mean my company's been certified organic
since
1993. i mean i totally believe in that i
mean you were talking
before about how something is produced
our mushrooms are produced as
naturally as possible and one of the key
things about is we produce
them on natural substrates and most
medicinal mushrooms for example
grow on wood that's what we use to grow
our mushrooms it's like the wood is
important it's got the precursors
necessary to produce those medicinal
compounds so
so again you know it is something where
and the whole the whole process i mean
when we're finished
that wood that the mushroom has been
growing on now that gets to be recycled
onto the fields as an adjuvant to the
soil
in some cases they dry out that uh wood
block that the
mushrooms come off of and they use it as
fuel there's just uh you know there's
very little
waste in that and not only that
mushrooms generally are
growing on agricultural waste products
they're an amazing
organism i mean can you imagine
straw and sawdust and everything else
that's out there
after growing all of the foods that we
eat
or the the timber that we're using
i mean what do you do with all that
material well
you know feed it to the mushroom it will
love you for it
it will produce you a good food or a
good medicine
so so for us and you know this is it the
mushroom is an organism this fungal
organism
it repurposes organic matter
so that's part of what it's doing out
there in the environment all of that
the leaves the perennial uh
annual plants that grow up and die every
year the wood that falls down
repurposing it into humus
so let's move on a little bit uh so
ethan terpenes
like mushrooms are also vastly
increasing in popularity
and of course a great deal of the credit
for uh people's interest in
terpenes goes to your milestone paper
that we've already talked about
um humans have been using terpenes for
healing and romance for ages um
what what are the different ways that we
can consume
terpenes and what is the mode they use
to
influence our human functioning sure
well let's start at the beginning
uh so uh terpenoids come in different
flavors
uh that relate to the number of carbon
atoms
uh in cannabis we're usually talking
about monoterpenoids with 10 carbons
cesco terpenoids with 15 there's a
single
uh diterpenoid which is phytol it's only
present after drying
and then there are tri-terpenoids but
only in the roots so that's something
that cannabis roots
and the medicinal mushrooms have in
common
the monoterpenoids and sesquiterpenoids
are what give
cannabis its its specific aroma
people may be surprised to learn that
the cannabinoids themselves are odorless
you could have a a bucket full of
pure thc and there'd be no aroma to it
but what they are really doing is
synergizing
with the cannabinoids
and modulating their effects on this can
come
in different flavors but mainly we think
in terms of
modulating the psychoactivity
tc when there's too much of it
produces anxiety rather than alleviating
it but
that can be modified by other components
um historically both
pinene from pine nuts and limonene
from lemons or other citrus were noticed
to be
good for people who had overindulged
with hashish or whatever it was
and then there are agents like linalool
which we don't see
as much of uh as we should have
in most uh chemovars chemical varieties
of cannabis and
it's a very powerful um
anti-anxiety agent without being overtly
sedating
so these are just a few examples but uh
additionally synergy includes the
ability to contribute to
the therapeutic effect an example there
is caryophyllene
which works on what's called the cb2
receptor that's the non-psychoactive
receptor
that also is a pain reliever an
analgesic receptor an anti-inflammatory
so having a lot of caryophyllene will
contribute to its ability to treat pain
or inflammation
without adding to the high which often
isn't necessary because there's plenty
of thc around
so ethan while we have you and while we
have the audience's attention
i would like to uh give you the platform
to speak on one of my favorite topics
that you
speak on which is you know so much of
the consumer market
is trying to get the most bang for their
buck and so
they go and they are shopping for the
highest percentage of terpene
that a laboratory will will say they
have
right and what thc
yeah so right would you explain how um
as far as the experience goes
um the the higher the thc
it's it means a lower terpene profile
and how we want to get that more into
balance
yeah well it may uh particularly with
concentrates when we're talking about
vape pens you'll often see that there
could be as much as
90 thc or mixed cannabinoids and
leaves very little room for the
turbinoids
one of the problems that we're seeing is
a lot of the co2 extraction which is
very clean
is done in a way that it really
squanders the terpenoid content
and so it resembles nothing like the
fresh flower from which it was derived
and this is really a shame i would
advocate to people that
the number on the thc is not really that
important
you can always get more by an additional
inhalation or a little bit more orally
but what you really are looking for is
the effect
and i think what bud tenders should be
asking
consumers is what are you trying to do
with this
not how high do you want to be uh you
know are they doing this
to treat anxiety are they doing this
because they need to clean the garage
and cut the boredom
whatever it is there is a terpenoid
profile that's going to enhance the
experience and i really would underline
that word enhance three times because
that is really what it's about
i think this message that just smoking
as much thc as we can
without understanding that terpenes
sculpt the high
is one of the most important consumer
messages that
we as a group of folks trying to produce
medicine and educate people can say
so thanks for weighing in on that i
would love to jump in if that's cool
yeah so you know when when nevada first
opened up
and washington first opened up people
are coming in
and buying strictly on the thc and some
of the best herb i've ever smoked
might be 16 17 thc but the terpenes and
the cannabinoids and everything else in
it
make it so much better and so i you know
urging everyone else that's watching
this just like you said there's so much
more that goes into some good herb
that will do a lot more for your body
than the thc
you know me and my friends joke about
it's the guy that wants to go get the
thickest burger it may not be the best
it's kind of dry
it's big you know what are you looking
to get do you want a tasty burger do you
want to enjoy your
so thc uh you know people shopping for
just a tac number it's just not the best
idea
there's so much more that goes in the
plant that makes it special and that
helps your body and
makes you enjoy that smoke than just a
thc i've never been a
let me get a 30 thc guy you know i'm let
me get the best smelling the most
euphoric the best
you know what the best looking for for
myself you know there's so much more
that goes into it so
i'm glad you touched on that because big
yeah
i like jumping on that too because
there's a big misconception with that
and i i subscribe to exactly what both
these guys are saying
in the sense that somewhere along the
line the consumer has got it in their
mind
that the highest thc is the best bang
for the buck
and this is this is the latest thing in
the last definitely a couple years
it's the worst thing because i just
don't understand where it came from
because ultimately our
our bio essay like what we go to smell
that we want
the consumer like you know at least for
me for 20 years
smoking cannabis is what does it smell
like what does it taste like and most
importantly what's the effect
on your body what is the effect that i'm
looking for and so
i can tell you from the extract side and
i
am a i'm a terpene hunter right i'm not
so much about the terps and that's why
i'm sitting here and that's why
we do projects together because they're
creating
terpene flavors that are mimic things in
life that we're used to that we're like
familiar with and i think when you take
the
the brain and somebody's a consumer and
like i smell something like this gelato
or this cookie or this type of
lemon cello you know it's like it's like
a familiarity
that like i have i smell this somewhere
else
i recognize this but it also has that
cannabis you know smell too
and then what's the effect and he nailed
it about the different types of terpenes
and ultimately um this is where i kind
of geek out with extracts
when someone says oh the flan or the
turoni like i come up with
uh names that um are are these like
familiar to desserts based on their
textures but it's
actually what i'm doing with my
signature extracts
is i'm modulating him it's because of
him once i take a solvents extract i'm
like
am i once i'm able to get thc a thc the
full spectrum
all of the terpenes and remove all the
lipids and waxes and cellulose
and i can say to myself well now i'm
gonna i'm gonna build
a designer dab here for an effect
and so when i deal with rosin that's to
me a full spectrum effect
right and then i do a tarone and that's
like cleaning it up a little bit like
he's talking about the burger
but i'm actually overlaying certain
things to create a modulation effect
and the flan is the most most modulation
effect so i'm actually able to like
look at something and target something
and most of our extracts
you know what we're known for is
everyone's averaging extract is like
three to five percent
but we've had this conversation before i
don't have to reintroduce
anything if it's already in the plant so
there's a lot of times where we would do
like
uh cookies extractions someone's like oh
that's 15 or 20 percent
terpenes it's like they didn't need a
reintroduction if the terps are there
so and that's your that's what i always
call the volume knob
you know and so like we all watched i'm
sure these guys were familiar with
spinal tap right
i remember as a kid i was like those
dudes got amps that go to 11
right and so that's what we're trying to
do we're like well can i get it to 15
can i that's what i'm doing as a kid i'm
like can i get this thing any louder
and it has nothing to do with the thc we
don't go to the bar and order everclear
you get you get a chopin or a hennessy
or
you know a nice um bourbon or something
you're not saying give me ever clear i
want to get i want to get as drunk as
possible
you get the drink you enjoy that tastes
best and you know
that's that's part of that's my opinion
i think he also has a uh another paper
out there
maybe that you did once upon a time with
another company i'm not really sure i
thought it was you
that um they had a study about just pure
thc
without terpenes and what that effect
was and then we looked at
i think then you know there's other
papers about synthetic thc
and how it relates to pain and just pure
thc like he was saying
doesn't have a smell it doesn't have a
flavor doesn't have a lot of medicinal
effect it's only when you start adding
these like
nuances of terpenoids and you start
building those profiles
that we start to see a real medicinal
effect from anything
another great thing too is uh when
people start
purchasing based on terpenes it's going
to change
the dynamic of the market because right
now it's strange to think that consumers
are buying cannabis
based on what company could influence
their local analytical lab
to give them a higher percentage and
oh gosh you know we all know that that's
a problem in the industry right now
whereas i would much rather people are
buying based on
what companies are able to treat their
flower
well not not cause the terpenes to
volatilize off and who's using good
genetics to begin with
and i think that's where our emphasis
should be instead of what lab we happen
to use and what influence we have over
them
so so moving on we're going to come back
to you tony
so so you were just talking about the
the really
high quality terpenes at good numbers
that give a really great experience
we're going to talk about the other side
now right
because since we're talking about
quality we should talk about um
what happens to lower quality terpenes
so
when we're considering synergistic
medicinal compounds we have to be aware
of how quickly terpenes degrade right
and what are some of the causes to
terpene degradation
and what is left when a terpene degrades
great question so we touched the uh
russo touched upon this a little earlier
monoterpenes and sesquiterpenes
and ultimately in the world of cannabis
this is live fresh frozen
right when the plant is alive it's got
a real high abundancy of monoterpenes i
would say
it's probably got about 80 percent of
the full profiles of mono chirping when
it's alive and on the plant
and if you disagree i have no problems
you correcting me
um right um so from from my experience
when the plant's alive and it's cut down
if it's quickly frozen
we're going to have a lot of mono
terpenes if we were to cut that plant
down and naturally dry it traditionally
dry it for smoking
we start to see the go from lots of mono
terpenes and they're volatile
at room temperature so people that are
carrying their cannabis they try to keep
it around 60
65 if they know what they're doing they
keep it at certain humidity
because they're like trying to preserve
the flavor in it as they're trying to
cure it
but let's say if you kind of got a
little warmer or you let it dry some
people were sun drying it back in the
day
you would start to see this monoterpene
from it being alive to when it's
completely dried and cured
it starts it you start to see less of
that and more sesquiterpenes
so i actually started uh in 2015
extracting fresh frozen live
monoterpenes from flowers
and i would extract terpenes of
sesquiterpenes
and i saw a clearly different uh two
different pathways
and for me i and we kind of educate
people as well we have different uh vape
carts
that are dried and cured and more
sesquiterpene based and the ones that
are live
are going to be more monoterpene and one
tastes very fresh like the plant
and those trichome heads are not
oxidized and they're
retained you know at low temperatures
the whole time
and so what ends up happening is that i
think
those that are traditional smokers
tend to actually like the dried
sesquiterpenes
right because if i've given i've given
10 people out the live cart and i give
people
a cure card if they didn't look at it
because it obviously looks different
they just did a blind test they'd be
like if they're a smoker they're gonna
they're gonna hit that cart
and like wow that tastes just like just
like the herb
the people that are desiring those uh
fresher mono terpenes are going to be
looking for like this
totally different real plant live taste
and feeling
however they evaporate very quickly so
um those that are making uh live
extracts
have a shelf life problem right so when
the product goes
onto the uh shelf and they have a live
rosin and they say hey here's what i
look like and i look cool in the picture
it can quickly dry up and so what you
end up happening this could actually use
to your advantage
and back in the day i would i would be
able to utilize
monoterpenes for a recrystallization or
precipitation of cbd or thca
or different things to precipitate out
from a base of all these other
cannabinoids
hope allowing the terpenes to evaporate
this was like kind of what i was doing
a long time ago and i don't do that
anymore but
i learned that how do like you said how
do we capture
these beneficials and monoterpenes
without letting them just fly off into
the air
and so that is like where i started
doing these like different extracts and
flans and jellies and things where
how do i how do i break this apart and
then utilize
active thc and raw thca
and those terpenes and create almost a
natural preservative
within those actual extracts to hold and
trap those together
and then obviously the next transition
was well i need to be able to powderize
this
or put this into a suspension of a
liquid and then be able to retain it as
real medicine which then gets into a
capsule
and so i think that that is the biggest
challenge
is being able to capture those from the
cannabis side and what i really liked
about what
with jeff and what he was talking about
and as i researched his company
was the other group of terpenes right
and so and i learned something today
which another chapter will open in my
mind because of you
about the roots of cannabis and these
mushrooms having the same terpenes
thank you for that one because i'm going
to start making terpenes from roots
because what i realized is that he's
making a pure product
we're doing the same thing on our side
he's a 10 to 1 ratio
and he's being able to get these very
heavy concentrations of that terpene
concentration we don't even know what
that synergistic
effect is yet we start laying these
cannabinoids on
we start laying these terpenoids on from
cannabis and i'm able to preserve those
right and i'm able to uh overlay them
like we were talking about earlier with
the terpenes that's coming from his
mushrooms
because he's using the purest form of it
he's getting the highest concentration
this is an unknown synergistic effect
that excites me
all right so bernard you've worked
extensively in the cannabis community to
curate flowers
that have an attractive aroma and
desiring healing effects
what have you learned from consumers
about what they actually look for in a
terpene experience
they love the like the fruity foodie
type smells
we we came out with cherry pie sunset
sherbet gelato
biscotti um you know the the food kind
of flavor profile the sweet
to kind of sweet and gassy people love
that um
i i curate our menus and and encourage
our breeders to go strictly for a flavor
we're not really hunting for the biggest
yielding plant we're not really hunting
for
the most thc we're going for the most
enjoyable
smoke possible you know cannabis is now
recreational and it's 2020 2020 20
you want to be able to enjoy your smoke
as much as possible so
what we look for and what i've seen
people react to more more than anything
is
the good smelling the good tasting
flavors we kind of we kind of
got a hype around flavors exotics is
what they call them
people are really into og kush they're
really into the hazes they're into the
train wrecks and stuff like that but
once we introduce
this certain flavor profile that was
sweet and
very aromatic and would leave like a
soap pissy smell in the air
it became you know a huge huge hype and
so
i think that our customer base is
looking for flavor
over everything so i've got two
follow-ups on that the first one
is um in your experience um are
do people are they aware that there is
terpenes
that the terpenes are playing a role in
what they like
and so they are buying with their nose
and they're familiar with the vocabulary
of terpenes
or are most people all like oh this is
the gelato
i smell the gelato i like the gelato
without ever actually thinking about
terpenes
yeah i think there's a not a lot of
education around terpings
you know like they mentioned earlier
people are shopping for thc but
there's no denying that no as you pop
open that jar and that's why we created
the jar we we
the way we did once you smell it i mean
it's like when you smell some good home
cooking you know you smell a restaurant
walking down the street he knows doesn't
lie and i think that people are just
shopping on based on what they're
smelling what they're seeing
and i think that you know hopefully
after people watch this they're educated
on actually how big of a role terpenes
play on cannabis
the second follow-up is uh you know
you've got a long breath of experience
with uh curating for the public right
and
and as you're saying the things that uh
people are most attracted to
at this point in the market are um of
sweet smelling
uh food reminiscent things that have got
some gas to them right and
and i agree i like those as well but i
also like
a lot of the cultivars that we used to
get that were rank right
they smelled like baby diapers or
rotting flesh
or some of this really gross stuff that
but that when you
taste it you're all like that gross
thing is so delightful and the buzz is
so wonderful
do you think that with a consumer-driven
market we're going to lose those old
nasty beautiful things
no absolutely not especially because i
got a breeding project going in at my
house right now
and i'm bringing all those old school
gases back and that's why i named
cheetah piss cheetah piss
to kind of get the consumer away from
looking for the you know um
you know ice cream cake or the you know
the fruit roll up like that's cool
that's cute we've done that for a while
i'm bringing back the gas
so when i'm breeding myself personally
and this is the first time i've actually
done my own breeding project
instead of you know art directing a
breeding project i'm bringing
straight gas back and there's going to
be a lot of baby diaper and
you know a lot of a lot of burnt rubber
kind of vibes and
you know as a pie head you want to have
a variety you want to have a lot of
different tastes so
my goal is to keep that alive and to
educate you know our customers while i
still got a good voice and platform that
there's so much more out there than the
fruity stuff some of these old school
gasses
and the super skunks and the kind of
musty dirty stock smell
it's still good it's a very different
height and it may smell crazy but when
you smoke it it's just
you're like wow that's that's gym socks
it tastes nuts like you know
so i'm into bringing that back to life
for sure
so ethan i'd love to get your thoughts
on this too you know
um as as thinking about the medicinal
nature of
uh terpenes um and people are often very
attracted to these
these sweet terpenes is there anything
that you might have to add about the
medicinal benefits of these these smells
that we would normally consider gross
but as you develop a connoisseurs
palette for cannabis
you actually find yourself very
attracted to ah
sure i don't deny that that's the case
um
you know it really depends on the blend
the proportions of these different
components and
the funny thing about turbinoids is a
trace component
really totally alter the smell and with
these complex
mixtures once there's more than three
terpenoids it's really
hard for anyone even experienced people
to really
have an idea of what's in it um
you know i use the comparison
if we blindfold somebody
and put before their nose a lemon a lime
and a grapefruit
everybody is going to be able to tell
them apart they all have
limonene at their base but it's the
trace components that really make the
difference in the
both aromas and the flavors and the same
would be true about the effects
um you know the psychopharmacological
effects
so you know it's uh an art and a science
um i spend a lot of time looking at
certificates of analysis and
you know i also want to know how how are
people affected by this
and they're generally if you know what
you're doing they're good correlations
so i think this really highlights that
one of the advantages of cannabis as a
medicinal
is that it really brings about the
possibility of individualized medicine
you know we really can tailor uh the
contents of the cannabis to what the
person really needs
uh you know what ails them on how do we
help them with that through the right
profile
in in cannabis we're going to take a
short break and be right back
you are listening to shaping fire
with the national hemp program influx
due to stringent thc testing
requirements
brother seth and eric crawford continue
to release seeds to hemp farmers that
will be legal
no matter how you grow them or when you
test them these new varieties from
oregon cbd seeds have substantial
amounts of cbdv
cbgv cbcv and thcv
while always staying below the point
three percent thc limit
and guaranteeing compliant crops for
farmers every time
also these new varieties cannot be
pollinated by your neighbor's
uncontrolled pollen
or a rogue male in your own crop either
oregon cbd seeds are non-gmo certified
too
oregon cbd seeds was founded and funded
in 2015 by seth and eric
maxing out their personal credit cards
without outside investment
they continue to refuse outside
investment that would change their
company culture
oregon cbd grows tons of fresh food on
their research farms for local food
banks
literally tons of food they also give
away tens of thousands of pounds of r d
flour to patients
as their company began to succeed seth
and eric started donating money to the
cannabis medicine and hemp fiber cause 2
by giving millions of dollars to oregon
state university in order to establish
the world's leading cannabis genomics
research program
and they treat their employees right
oregon cbd pays for full health and
dental coverage for their employees
a 401k program and their minimum
starting wage is 20 bucks an hour
plus everyone shares food from the farms
seth has been on shaping fire a few
times to talk about novel cannabinoids
you can check out episodes 25 and 37 on
cbd cultivars in the hemp market
episode 66 on triploid cannabis genetics
and the very first shaping fire live
episode 47
with seth and soil expert jeff lowenfels
talking about autoflowers
if you are a hemp farmer and you want to
grow reliable seeds that are sure to
thrive in past testing
check out oregoncbdseeds.com to learn
more about buying seeds for the 2021
season
that's oregoncbdseeds.com
after you've caught up on the latest
shaping fire episodes do you sometimes
wish there was more cannabis education
available to learn
well we got you shaping fire has a
fabulous youtube channel with content
not found on the podcast
when i attend conventions to speak or
moderate panels i always record them and
bring the content home for you to watch
the shango los youtube channel has
world-class speakers including
zoe sigmund's lecture understanding your
endocannabinoid system
kevin jodrey of wonderland nursery
talking about breeding cannabis
for the best terpene profile frenchie
cannolis lost art of the hashishin
presentation
nicholas mahmoud on regenerative and
polyculture cannabis growing
dr sunil agarwal on the history of
cannabis medicine around the world
eric vlofsky and josh rutherford on
solvent-less extraction
and jeff lonefels on the soil food web
there are several presentations from dr
ethan russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system too
while there be sure to check out the
three 10-part shaping fire sessions
series
one with kevin jodrey one with dr ethan
russo and one with jeff lowenfels
and even my own presentations on how to
approach finding your dream job in
cannabis
and why we choose cannabis business even
though the risks are so high
as of today there's over 200 videos that
you can check out for free
so go to youtube.com forward slash
shango los or click on the link in the
newsletter
as a business owner you are incredibly
busy in reality you are responsible for
everything your company does
you've got so many responsibilities
every single day that often you just
don't have the time to really
dig into your marketing as deeply as
you'd like
you know there's more that you could do
to reach out to new customers and
encourage loyalty and the customers you
already have
but you certainly don't have the time
for it and you're not ready to hire
somebody full time for that role either
for you i recommend blunt branding at
blunt branding kirsten nelson and her
team are focused on improving your
bottom line
you know most marketing firms are
excited to make your logo
packaging and website very pretty but
they leave responsibility for improving
your bottom line
up to you they don't want that kind of
responsibility
but that's pretty much the most
important part of marketing right
kirsten and her team will help you
engage new customers funnel them to your
point of sale whether it be online or a
storefront
and keep them coming back to you and
telling their friends
now if you happen to be a new cannabis
company or an established company moving
from medical to adult use in your state
kirsten especially can help you not only
is she well reversed
in marketing and finance but she totally
gets cannabis whole plant medicine
terpenes heritage farmers and the
particular needs of startups
check out what she did recently for moon
time medicinals and humboldt at moon
time medicinals.com
kirsten and her team put together a
whole brand package for them
built their website and wrote their
sales materials no doubt this is a paid
commercial spot but that does not mean
they bought my opinion
i've worked with blunt branding on five
projects now for various of their
clients and
every single time they have done more
than they have promised and over
delivered on results
i love how they generate new revenue and
focus on that as the goal instead of
just making a pretty logo
similarly every single friend i've
referred them to has come back to thank
me
and that just does not happen every day
grab a pen and paper because the website
address is coming up
if you want someone to implement
marketing programs that feed your bottom
line
give blunt branding a call they will
share proven techniques to increase your
audience and generate sales
while using cutting edge technology
solutions in the background that make
all of this
easy automatic and trackable go to
shapingfire.com forward slash blunt
branding to find out more
you can also click the link in our
newsletter blunt branding
marketing that makes you money welcome
back you are listening to shaping fire
and i'm your host
shango los and our guests this week are
dr ethan russo
tony verzura jeff chilton and berner
let's return to the panel discussion now
so one of the first alternative
medicines people often turn to
in their life is cannabis but few folks
understand the general action that
cannabinoids the active ingredient in
cannabis take
and i know that an explanation of the
endocannabinoid system could take hours
because we've done that on
the shaping fire podcast right but for
today
can you distill it down and give us a
summary of what cannabinoids
are in the cannabis plant and how they
generally interact with the human body
sure well it is a very complex issue but
we have this thing
called an endocannabinoid system within
us the endocannabinoid system is the
master regulator of homeostasis
homeostasis is a balance in
function let's look at the brain
we have neurotransmitters chemical
messengers between
nerve cells the endocannabinoid system
regulates their release it actually
inhibits the release
so if it inhibits a stimulatory
neurotransmitter it damps down that
signal
if it inhibits an inhibitory signal
it's magnifying the effect but the more
endocannabinoid cb1 receptor
a receptor in the brain that
have a greater density than that for all
of the neurotransmitters put together
and so that's any aspect of brain
function as influenced by the
system but the same thing applies to
digestion
or any other functions of our body
so this really gives the foundation for
why
cannabis as a medicine is so versatile
for so many different conditions it's
not a panacea
but it is amazingly versatile
in what it can do for many conditions
where conventional medicine just
doesn't quite do the job properly
right on thank you so back to you tony
so tony
everyone um on this round table
uh is a proponent of whole plant and
fungi
medicine meaning that the medicine
should respect the structure
that nature provides in it some folks
get confused about what
is and isn't a whole plant and
unfortunately with
um the arrival of extracts and and some
of these
um these these newer products people are
been playing with the vocabulary to
include their products when they often
might not
some folks get confused about this so
how should we think about the oils of a
cannabis plant as
whole even though it's no longer a part
of the entire plant
another good question um
okay so the way i look at this is
it's very interesting because when we
talk about
a full spectrum oil as an example
we have to think about how did we get to
that right
so we were talking he was talking about
co2 earlier
and co2 itself is under a lot of
pressure
and it takes the buds themselves and it
passes at very high psi
from gas to liquid and it goes through
the plant and it generally
pulls a lot out of the plant it's a
clean process
i personally don't like this process
because of a couple of things
it's not the process of the co2 it's the
post-processing
because if we're able to pull all of
this raw extract out and if you were to
stay with
raw co2 and did nothing else
that's a different conversation but
you're going to be pulling a lot of
these
lipids and plant fats and waxes and
honestly a lot of heavy metals
because of the way that extraction
method works and so everyone tends to
winterize or
de-wax their full-spectrum oil
right and in the process of using
ethanol
is what they do it's an eight-to-one and
so they just take that muck
they pour alcohol over it and then they
like turn it into a solution and they
freeze it and then they
bind that alcohol to the fats and then
they pour everything out which as
russo knows destroys all the terpenes
because we're also talking about polar
polar semi-polar nonpolar and polar
properties of the plant
and so if we're really talking about a
true full spectrum
oil that's been unadulterated it
wouldn't be co2 through winterization
it wouldn't be ethanol through
distillation it wouldn't be
a hydrocarbon and then distillation
but if we talk about hydrocarbon and
there and
there are good extraction methods with
hydrocarbon that's using
uh and those monoterpenes and terpenes
that we were talking about they're also
a group of hydrocarbons so terpenes
themselves are hydrocarbons
um and the hydrocarbon used in the bho
extraction actually kind of binds to it
and so it's a low psi pass so it's going
to pass right through and if they know
what they're doing and they have a full
recovery system
they're making live resin and making all
these particular uh
oils that's really a full spectrum oil
if there's none of the butane left in it
but again we have to look at ourselves
and say well did that
chemical or that solvent that passes
through the plant
alter the full spectrum oil and to me
the answer is also yes
and so that then takes us to the next
category of
of say particular flower rosin so we
moved to flower
rosin right and so when we get to a
flower rosin
similar to co2 much less waxes we would
have eight to twelve percent but we're
actually going to get a full spectrum
oil
out of flower rosin if we just press the
flowers put them under pressure we are
basically
using high pressure and steam to secrete
all of expel
all of those oils that's a true
solventless
full spectrum oil will have some of the
lipids and waxes in there
but if we were talking about that before
and we said what's the cleanest and
the most accurate representation is
flower rosin however
in the dabbing world if we were using
that for capsules and other things it
would be very good
in the in the world of where we're at
the scalability
of creating that being able to say hey
do you have 100 pounds can you press a
hundred pounds of flowers this week to
keep up
that's also very difficult and
to be able to take that flower rosin it
used to be a popular thing like four
years ago but then dabbers
they start using quartz and they start
using puffco peaks and different things
and like man
leaving a bunch of stuff behind so
that's the waxes so then
we then there's only a couple other
methods right and then we move to hash
rosin or live rosin which then we're
just
separating out all the resin glands
to get a full spectrum profile of the
actual
uh plant so we have to say to ourselves
there's
you know there's a lot of terpenes
there's about 50
of the plants terpenes are inherently in
the leaf and in the surface of
of the leaf but then the ones that we're
actually desiring that we want to smoke
and has the most abundant
is in the heads so just like what jeff
was talking about these mushroom heads
i'm looking for the trichome heads and
so when we separate
we're going to get heads and we're going
to get a little bit of the stalks in
there and so
when we talk about a full spectrum from
a hash rosin
we're trying to isolate the best of the
fruit right and so i'm going to try to
pick
these grades of fruit from it and if we
were talking about a lemon tree
and and the tree was ripe you know if
you hit the tree the right time
you're able to shoulder it boom all the
lemons that come off as your first
the best the best lemons and you kind of
pick through the tree as it gets ripe
and you pull those off
and so for me personally i'm going to
try to get
all of the best fruit to make my juice
from it
to make that full spectrum oil now when
i do that
that's where i then take it to the next
level where people like you said there's
misunderstandings where they think oh
you're reintroducing you're altering it
when i could get to this particular
before it gets to that oil
let's say we were able to get um expel
all of those heads so if we're looking
at the surface of the trichome head as a
grape
like like as the grape is i want to
remove these skins
and that is when we make hash rosin or
live rocks and we're pressing it
and we're keeping the skins in there but
a little bit of those skins
melt in the process and it gets into
live rosin or gets into hashrats
not a lot much less than flower rosin
and so we're going to
and somewhere around three percent what
all i'm doing
is being able to remove those impurities
and it's
naturally allowing the terpenes and
naturally allowing all these other
cannabinoids to boost themselves
so the world of what i'm saying
deconstructing and rebuilding
it's kind of just like an easier way to
educate people because it's already
difficult for you guys to
for everyone to like follow that and
that's why i went from terpenoids to
terpenes and just terps
like it's the terps right and then it's
like people were like what's your wax
now we're like no wax right so
deconstruction people get that in their
head and it's just an
artistic way of saying hey i'm just
breaking these things out
but i'm really maintaining and
preserving the things so for me
personally
full spectrum uh is is getting to the
purest portion
and trying to do a ten to one as what
jeff's doing and some of the extracts
that i'm doing i'm even getting to a 15
to watch
i like that explanation too because it
again focuses on the fact of how much
consumer education that we all have to
do as an industry
because i mean how many of these threads
have we seen online where people are
arguing about this
when nobody involved in the discussion
actually understands the science right
so hey so hey jeff um you know earlier
you were talking about how
um the different varieties of mushrooms
uh play well together
and and how uh the the you know ancient
chinese folks
recognized this and they they made these
um these these blends
when i go to uh my acupuncturist
um she is going to do some physical
acupuncture on me
she's probably going to recommend a
mushroom blend for me
for whatever i'm looking for relief from
but then she also gives me
you know a particular diet and foods and
i actually she actually told me she
wanted to learn more about terpenes too
recently and it was funny i gave her a
uh
a true terpene sampler i'm like here
start smelling these and learn right
but where i'm going with this is that
she says that
mushrooms are a a type of medicine
that plays well with other medicines
and um you know because i pay her based
on time i couldn't get a full
explanation from her
but i'm really curious to hear your
insight on
on mushrooms ability to play well
with these other uh synergistic inputs
we've been talking about
like uh like cannabis and terpenes
well well you know you know what chango
there there's
actually not that much research out
there on that subject
specifically you know the way the way i
look about
at mushrooms is that they are um in a
sense
food is medicine so you can start out by
by just putting them in your diet
mushrooms are kind of a forgotten food
in asia
everybody eats mushrooms there's like 12
15 different species in the marketplace
that
that people are eating and this kind of
too gets back to what ethan was
referring to
earlier about products that
actually will help with homeostasis for
example
mushrooms are the perfect food and
medicine in that in that sense they're
they're what are considered an adaptogen
and adaptogens that's kind of their role
homeostasis harmony i mean when you talk
to
anybody in china chinese medicine
traditional chinese medicine
practitioners for example too
that's really what they're trying to do
i mean disease they just look at that as
you
you're out of balance some way so
they're really trying to bring you
back into balance and so for me that's a
big part of what mushrooms do
they're they're one of the great
balancers they're one of the
the great harmony herbs out there and
and so
since you know you can combine them
together but the one thing you have to
to understand too is it is that
sometimes
when you put too many different
uh for example in this case mushroom
species together
you end up diluting the primary species
that are giving you the the major
benefits there
so so you can only go so far i mean you
know how sometimes there's a race to
um like what i call the kitchen sink
products out there too
you know everything in one jar you never
have to eat anything else or supplement
with anything else because it's got
everything you need
and it's like well no thank you right
um there's a there's a certain level
where you do have a synergy
or where where putting things together
makes sense
but for example for me there are maybe
five mushrooms that i would say okay you
get to get up to five
don't go any further because now you're
just going to to
actually lessen the benefits that you're
looking for
and so so really and again
the um in terms of synergies it's kind
of interesting because there is actually
a study that was just done
in australia where they were utilizing
our mushroom extracts and they
they um it was testing them against
a whole panel of cytokines
and so they were okay what is uh what
kind of cytokine
stimulation do we have there and we've
got each single one
how they did and then when they put them
together actually they got
a higher level of cytokines production
through the putting the three together
than each one individually
so there's definitely those types of
benefits
from putting them together but we're
still kind of
uh new in that sense there i mean we're
not
anywhere close to being what uh tony's
doing right now for example with the
triterpenes i mean uh and the other
thing too is
getting back to just full spectrum what
what i'm really trying
to do is i'm trying to bring everything
out of the the dried mushroom
all of the constituents of it i don't
want to leave anything behind in my
extracts
i mean we're not we're at the point
where we're trying to build up this or
build
up that what we can do there is
basically through the cultivar itself
because different cultivars for example
reishi cultivars
are going to have different levels of
tri-terpenoids
a researcher that i saw his presentation
back in their
2002 tested 12 different cultivars of
reishi
the level of triterpenes was from 2 to
12 it was
just amazing so the key thing for us is
making sure that we have
a cultivar that's going to give us a a
good
measure of try terpenoids which i think
are really important and what sets
ganoderma or the reishi apart
so i think that's very important
constituent of that
we really to the the cultivar itself
and testing it to make sure our starting
material
when we are creating that extract is
high in what we want
right on thanks jeff so ethan you know
um
because because this panel is
uh involves cannabis chances are that a
lot of the folks who end up watching it
are going to be tokers you know people
who have smoked cannabis for some
or all of their life and you know as the
only medical doctor on the panel today
i would like to hear your thoughts on um
alternative forms of ingesting
um these synergistic
medicinals that we're talking about most
of us are used to
smoking our cannabis medicine in um
in flower form and and and you know more
people are getting interested in edibles
but honestly
a lot of folks are are selling you know
a cookie or a gummy or something
that um is is more like candy and maybe
some companies use isolate and all this
whereas
if people are really thinking about the
medicinal
nature of delivery um capsules are a
really good way to go
um but the thing is i've never explained
to people why that's true
i just know it's true from working with
patients so would you talk to the idea
of of taking um you know these
synergistic medicines in a capsule
form to kind of educate people on why
putting the stuff in their belly works
for them sure
well let's preface this by saying that
uh you know i i really don't recommend
uh smoking because of lung irritation
vaporization is better
and in terms of getting the most bang
for the buck
from turbinoids vaporization
or topical application that does get
through the skin
those are both going to be really
efficient when
terpenoids are taken orally they're not
going to be quite as
prominent they certainly will have
effects you don't lose that entirely the
effect orally
is going to be better when there is a
lipid carrier in other words
with a fat um and certainly with a gel
cap that is an
oil base you're going to get
a good absorption of the turbinoids
and with a proper edible
with a proper edible there will
definitely be a difference
that people will appreciate as compared
to an isolate with
just a cannabinoid
right on and so um while we're used to
you know smoking our cannabinoids and
having it
um you know hit our bloodstream through
our lungs
um you're saying that when we take it as
a capsule
and and it finds its way to our stomach
that our stomach is very effective in
pulling all these
apart and while they may have a
different experience we're still getting
the
medicinal qualities from it is that a is
that a
right of summation that's true when
terpenoids are taken orally they're
going to
hit the liver and be metabolized
somewhat faster when they're inhaled
they're
going to have the ability to go straight
to the brain without passing the liver
first
so again the effect is going to be more
pronounced
but with a good formulation orally
it will get absorbed and it will
modulate thc
and the other cannabinoids so certainly
you know in a gummy it's most likely
going to be an isolate
just thc you're not likely going to see
a full
a lot of full spectrum gummies that are
going to give a quality experience
and i wouldn't think of those as
medicines for the most part
cool thank you ethan so so we're to our
last question of the panel
and it's going to be the same question
for everybody so but i want to hear all
of your thoughts
as we look into the future and kind of
put our visionary hats on
and um as far as answering it in the
order
i'm gonna ask it first to burner and
then jeff
if you would jump in and answer the
question and then ethan
will come to you third and then we'll
finish off with
uh with tony here so this last question
is the same for all of you
and it's about your motivations and
hopes for the future
uh of synergistic medical blends all
right so where where we want to see
our community go while pharmaceuticals
can do much
good and we've all seen the substantial
amount of
bad that they can do too that has led to
this
our movement towards alternatives we are
seeing now we've been talking about
today
and we all participate in what is your
vision of the future for the creation of
new
medicinal blends and an increase in
their accessibility
to patients directly so let's go ahead
and start with burner
yeah i feel like um it's our job to
educate we all had different platforms
these guys know the science of it a lot
more i've been
experimenting with some stuff that tony
created and it's kind of a blend on some
of the stuff
we talked about today but i've noticed a
major change in my body
when it comes to anxiety i've had
anxiety for a very long time i have to
take xanax to kind of calm my body down
and
wasn't really having the best sleep uh
because of
metformin which i take because of my
diabetes and whatnot and
recently just mixing um the cbd the cbn
and some of the mushroom blend that tony
has put together has really changed my
life
for the better a lot and i feel like
it's my job
to have you know i have a nice platform
and a voice to the black and brown
community into the urban community
to educate them on on this a lot of
people think mushroom they think um
we're getting high or they think gas
station mushrooms uh not really
real mushrooms you know so my i feel
like my role right now
my kind of mission and the future of
plant medicine is to educate put in
hands and
kind of help everyone's bodies i feel
like the cbn i never really was up on
cbn i didn't really understand
how how important cbn is or stevie g
i've just been a pothead for a long time
and i've been smoking her but
by taking daily blends i've noticed a
big change in my body and my sleep
patterns and my anxiety
and so a lot of people that i speak to
my audiences
deal with a lot of post-traumatic stress
anxiety
pain depression sleep problems
especially the diabetics so you know i
think the future of
plant medicine is educating putting in
the hands and providing real access
we don't want people to buy gas station
mushrooms and have a bad experience
cbd for their grandma that really needs
it
we want to provide safe real credible
access to medicine that's helped change
my life
and so i just look forward to being able
to to kind of
you know roll this out properly and kind
of just educate my people
the younger people the people that don't
really think that that this is a
medicine or any of these things mushroom
or cannabis is a medicine so we talked
about that earlier but
that's kind of my agenda and my
objective moving forward is just
putting in the hands of people and
letting them understand it's really good
for your body it's beneficial and
a lot of stuff that we're prescribed
like metformin uh or
xanax is not the best for us long term
we our bodies don't want that
you know so there's there's ways that
that we can educate put in a
put in the hands and just kind of like
you know his education will be a lot
different than mine which would be a lot
different than yours which would be a
lot different than his but combined
is very powerful i think we all need to
play our role for sure
thanks so uh so jeff uh let's get you on
this so so where do you see the
you know where would you like to see
these synergistic
medicinals come together going forward
well let me first say
um it looks like we've got a new term
that's come out of this gas station
mushrooms
that's that's really a good one
you know you know it's really what's
really interesting having been
in in like the supplement industry for
quite a while i mean i started growing
mushrooms in 1973 commercially so i've
been doing that for a long time but in
terms of
the supplement industry i've been there
since 1989 when when mushrooms were
still
not even in the industry at all no
company had a mushroom product and i had
to really do a lot of education
but back then the the industry was full
of
actual herbalists and people who were
you know some of them actually coming
out of being cannabis growers for
example i mean people who were
really deep into it in a totally
different way let's say
today and one thing that's happened is
is our industry has gone
from what i would call products that are
a little more natural a little more
earthy to
a pharmaceutical model and and a lot of
that has come just from the regulations
that have been put in place
we we are saddled with regulations that
make us adhere to a pharmaceutical model
the way everything is produced in terms
not necessarily the way we grow our
mushrooms
that's still quite quite natural but in
terms of
uh processing and in terms of the the
different standards that we have to meet
before we can sell the product
and that's something that i'm really
kind of concerned about and so are a lot
of people in
in the industry because i i'm totally
believing in organic production and
certified organic
products and keeping with that whole
whether it be regenerative agriculture
or or basically staying closer to
the earth and and not so much into
the pharmacy so to speak those those
kind of sterilized
you know it's like it's like getting a
certificate of analysis and you look at
the heavy metals in there pharmaceutical
model would be
um or the micro for example the micro
biological panel
zeros you know if i see zeros i think
okay now
somebody along the line has irradiated
this or done something to it to
kill off all the microbes and that's not
a place where we really want to go
so so for me um going forward
what i think is really important is just
maintaining that
natural component of this and not
getting
too far away from what it's really about
it's just it's like me being in mexico
back in the
70s and and you know smoking the
different
uh weed from different states and and
living in oaxaca and the the plants that
were being grown there which were just
amazing uh and and those are kind of of
uh
pot that i really love and and makes me
fee
feel really good so again for me i think
moving into the future there's a lot of
things that we can do
a lot of synergies that we will find
especially like right now i
i just love the fact that cookies is
putting mushrooms
in with their cannabis products i just
think that's
you know we'll see where that goes it's
really interesting to me but
again the key for me is is keeping it
natural
keeping it close to the earth and not
getting too far
into that whole pharmaceutical model
right
yeah nice so ethan i know that you think
about these
you know synergistic products a lot with
credo science that you founded
um what's your vision of the future sure
well in addition to internal projects uh
we're really moving now
into formulation our our whole ethos is
to make cannabis safer and better
uh but also to extend it out uh
into combinations with these other
plant-based medicines and fungal-based
medicines um and i very much uh
in tune with what jeff said uh we want
this to be done in a holistic
clean manner organic preferably
through regenerative agriculture so
we're
absolutely in support of those endeavors
right on so bring us home tony i know
you are a big thinker
and kind of an alchemist philosopher i
hope i didn't put too much
on you right there but like what what do
you see as a formulator for the
direction that we should be going
so i kind of subscribe to um what the
panel's saying i really think what
burner said is well said as well as jeff
and and and ethan i i subscribed to that
my mission since 96 when i got on this i
was started
at 16 and 18 i had my own personal
experiences with uh different types of
things that were prescribed to me
that once i found cannabis in the herb
i got upset and i realized that we don't
you know not every condition in the
world with the things that you touched
on
in the general basis you know people
need their sleep
people have anxiety people have pain
people have digestion
there's amazing breakthroughs with other
types of conditions but
those are the four main major things
that's going on my mission since 1996
was to get people off of synthetic
opiate-based
products and synthetic drugs that
we can bring plant-based medicine into
a pharmacopia level of
of of grade so i always think of
plant-based
but how do we do this at a
pharmaceutical level to where people
will take it serious enough
and understand and like just hearing
what he said about
the capsule is why i do what i do you
know it affects me
as a person and it's like why i do what
i do because i just want to be able to
positively influence as many people
i think this panel in this type of
synergy
is going to do tremendous education but
ultimately that's that's the next move
for the next generations like we start
getting caught up in synthetics
we start getting caught up in
artificially trying to create
experiences and things in life we're
going to lose ourselves
and so that's for me the mission is
plant-based
cool thank you i like i like how tony
finished with uh
suggesting that this synergy that we
have created here
um all experts from different fields and
i think i think that's a beautiful thing
so
in wrapping up so let's first we'll uh
we'll thank all the speakers
via video thank you jeff chilton thank
you
ethan russo here in california thank you
to tony versura and the burner
i've been your moderator shango los of
shaping fire and thank you to all of you
for tuning in and learning a little bit
about synergistic medicines thank you
for being
here you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts
if you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you would leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download
your review will help others find the
show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for insights
into the latest cannabis news
exclusive videos and giveaways on the
shaping fire website you also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast
that's at shaping fire and at shangolos
on instagram
be sure to check out shaping fire
youtube channel for exclusive interviews
farm tours and cannabis lectures
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts
email hotspot shippingfire.com to find
out how
thanks for listening to shaping fire
i've been your host shango los
[Music]