[Music]
you are listening to shaping fire and
I'm your host Shango Lowe's before we
get in today's episode I want to explain
why it's been a month since the last
episode see it's summer growing season
right now and even though I'm not a
professional grower nor do I grow in
volume here locally on Vashon Island
where I live I help out in a lot of
different cannabis patient gardens
because I do so much patient education
here I tend to make friends with folks
who use cannabis medicine and they often
ask for a little help with you know this
or that during the summer well there was
a whole lot and more of that this year
than ever before more and more people
are wanting to grow a few plants to make
their own tincture or RSO or whatever
you know it's great to see but that's a
lot more people to you know help get set
up and help identify deficiencies and
then stop by to help them determine if a
plant is male and when to harvest by
looking at the trichomes because I got
into this work with patients I chose to
work in their gardens rather than be in
my office in front of the computer
pretty easily also though this is
research and development season for me
summertime is when probiotic growers and
cannabis breeders are practicing their
craft and I got to go out into the field
to learn earlier this month I
disappeared into humbled and Mendocino
for a couple weeks to record content for
the YouTube channel and also find out
what's you know new and interesting and
you know that is time that I'm not in
the studio making shows that said these
road trips without an agenda where I
just explore and meet people
keeps the podcast and the YouTube
channel content interesting
it's from going on those kind of feral
trips that the energy and the ideas for
shaping fire come from so yeah next
thing I knew it was August and it's been
five weeks and here we are in my own
defense I also did have two guests
postponed recording their episodes last
minute because they too were also busy
getting their own full term crops in the
ground we'll talk to them in November if
you want to learn about cannabis health
business and technique efficiently and
with good
here I encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items for the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter there's nothing else you
need to do to win except receive the
newsletter this month we are giving away
several packages of happy endings
compost tea mix and the ocean bounty
flowering soil amendment from green
bicycles I use this stuff in my own
garden and love it in fact I talked with
green bicycles founder Patrick Smith
about his tea on the You Tube channel
recently go to shaping feiyr.com to sign
up for the newsletter and be entered
into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings my guest today
is colum Riley co-founder of Malibu
compost an ultra premium living food web
compost when I first heard colum speak
about the bio regionalism of microbes I
just about jumped out of my seat with
curiosity the idea that all of this
living soil microbe community stuff
we're all into actually differs by
location and climate really opened up a
huge new set of variables and
understanding and I really had to ask
him a bunch of questions about it that's
what we're gonna talk about today today
we're gonna go deep deep into compost
welcome to the show : fantastic to be
here Shango excellent so nice to hear
your voice again so so let's get started
with some quick basics because there's
some people who are still pretty new to
compost and so for people who don't know
please give us a brief understanding of
what compost is and how basically it's
made at home excellent question and
there is a lot of confusion around
compost so not to sound like the
stereotypical professor but sometimes it
helps to start with the definition and
in this case I'd like to give a
definition that actually just got
reworded in the last year by the u.s.
composting council but it's important to
kind of break down and what they say is
compost is the product manufactured
through the controlled
aerobic biological decomposition of
biodegradable materials so it's
undergone mesophilic and thermophilic
temperatures you're reducing the weed
seeds and the pathogens you're
stabilizing the carbon to make it
beneficial to plant growth and then
there's a whole host of uses for it but
it's important to understand in that
definition that it's a controlled
process and it's aerobic and biological
decomposition of materials so so before
we go to the biologic decomposition with
aerobic which means oxygen what are the
two thermic that you I don't know those
two words ah mesophilic and thermophilic
refer to different temperature ranges so
we'll take this down to the home
composter so when you pile a bunch of
stuff in a corner of your yard and come
back a year later that's not really
controlled and it's not really aerobic
and there's definitely some biological
decomposition but you're missing two of
those other factors and as far as
temperature when you turn a pile or cut
into it sometimes you can see steam
sometimes you can put your hand in and
feel the heat um but the temperature is
one of those four variables of the earth
water air and fire that's the fire
aspect and so a thermophilic process is
when you get temperatures that exceed
133 degrees and that's sort of
considered the proper threshold it kills
off weed seeds it'll kill off pathogens
like fecal coliform or ecoli or
salmonella but you don't really want
that thermophilic range to go much
higher than a hundred and sixty degrees
where you start killing off a lot of the
beneficial microbiology and we can come
back to that so a typical compost cycle
you want to build the materials such
that they can have air flow and the
carbon and nitrogen materials are mixed
with moisture being another variable in
such a way that the temperatures can
exceed 133 degrees so that hot phase is
considered the thermal
feliks breakdown of the compost pile and
mesophilic is more sort of that
simmering down range as the temperatures
drop under 130 but they're still well
above an ambient temperature as far as
getting to that temperature some people
you know bake their soil and that's not
what you're talking about right you're
talking about letting the compost itself
generate heat from degradation and
bringing its own temperature up right
absolutely I mean one of the ways I like
to break it down when I talk to kids is
think about microbes sweating and if you
got a whole bunch of microbes with a
gigantic pile of food to consume their
job is to shred that food literally some
of we have soil food webs called
shredders so they are shredding and they
are sweating and they are working up
steam literally and figuratively
and so that break down is what's
producing that heat as you have this
bacteria breaking down attacking the
surface area of the materials again they
need oxygen a lot of people don't
understand the importance of airflow but
it's like any living organism you need
water and air and food to survive so
during this process with all that new
material that hasn't yet been broken
down that's largely when you see the
temperatures is in the first phase of
the composting process where you have
this rapid breakdown and decomposition
that's all run by these digesters just
the think of it the compost pile is like
the digestive tract pre-application of
the soil right on that makes a lot of
sense and you know you know that might
be a definition you develop for kids but
that is really gets right to the point I
think I would be using that myself with
adults so so thanks for sharing that so
so the other part of your definition
that is really important is the aerobic
breakdown because this is very
specifically oxygen centric so you will
you break out that part of the
definition yeah and there's
two things I guess in the broad sense of
things it's important for your listeners
understand there is what I would term
intentional composting and what I would
term organics recycling and both of them
have a very important place and I would
say organics recycling is trying to take
organic matter and recycle it in such a
way that you can derive benefits and get
the nutrients back out of it and reapply
it to the land and even a lot of quote
unquote composting facilities or
operations or people calling themselves
composters or even material in the
marketplace labeled as compost is really
recycled organic matter it's been piled
up it's been degraded it's kind of
broken down and it's sort of turned into
this broken down black or brown material
that's not as distinguishable from how
it started but that's not necessarily a
controlled process you know with the
biological the chemical or the physical
properties in place so intentional
composting is really looking at what do
you want out of this what we're looking
for all the attributes of compost
everything that compost is and we're
building the pile and controlling the
process to derive that out of the
finished product so we need air we need
the pile to breathe and a pile typically
breeze from the bottom and breathe out
and that's what's allowing the microbes
to break everything down turning the
pile is critical because as things
compact the oxygen the space for free
air space disappears and the more things
become come back compacted and the more
oxygen that's eaten up by the microbes
in the pile there's no more oxygen and
so what this leads to is anaerobic
conditions and all you need to do is
take some material put it in a glass jar
and put a lid on it a biological
material and it comes back funky and
putrid that's what happens in anaerobic
conditions it can't really breathe and
anaerobic conditions can cause a lot of
harmful microbes and other harm to your
plants if that's not prop
we composted broken down allowed to have
the oxygenation process the second part
is when the oxygen when the compost gets
more towards a finished phase it still
needs to be able to breathe there's a
finished process that is typically
called the curing process and if you
think about a wine being allowed to to
ripen to have this expression there's a
maturity and a balancing during this
curing phase it also allows things like
ammonia to convert to plant available
nitrogen so many are people now that you
kind of hear the definitions you can
understand you can cut into a bag or
sometimes open a bag of commercial
compost and you get this strong ammonia
smell that means the compost wasn't
finished it wasn't the microbes weren't
finished doing their jobs or it was
exposed to anaerobic conditions and the
same thing happens with severely
compacted compost even on our farms are
in your piles you'll find that
oftentimes at the bottom of the pile and
you can certainly turn that around
riah mend it keep working it recom post
it for all intents and purposes as a way
to do it but the ideas that's ultimately
take it through a process have the
materials in the proper ratios to begin
with with the moisture and the oxygen
turn the piles so you avoid the
anaerobic phase you create hot
temperatures to be able to kill off the
pathogens and the weed seeds and break
it down and then let it cool down and
simmer and finish during that mesophilic
phase 2 where the compost is going to
mature and stabilize and be ready to do
its job in the soil you know that idea
about opening a bag of compost and
smelling the ammonia I actually was
really startled the first time I you
know that's the stuff that I normally
get right that's the stuff that I had
historically purchased his stuff you
open it up it's a little damp
it smells like ammonia it's like okay
this is what I use but then I did score
a bag of your Malibu compost and and
when I opened it you know it wasn't wet
it didn't smell like ammonia and
visually it looked like really really
high-quality soil it was it was more it
was more granular with occasional chunks
and it and it smelled good it had that
that that you know who miss smell like
you get when you go out into the forest
and you smell like the forest Duff as
you as you walk along and I'm like oh my
gosh this is this must be what it's
supposed to be like because like I got
you know I picked up a bag after I heard
you speak for the first time right so
I'm really alright this this stuff
sounds crazy I need to check this out
for myself and so boom so and then I'm
like wow this this really is incredible
so so since since our conversation is
moving slowly but surely towards talking
about micro bioregion and and you and
your company ship all over let's take
that basic idea of how we make compost
at home and scale it up because I've
seen photos of your compost piles on
your Instagram and they are you know
I've got a compost pile right but you've
got like like these long compost lines
that's like a huge pile that just goes
on and on and on that looks like it goes
on four acres you know in the
photographs so so will you give me a
give us a little idea of how you take
that basic idea of compost and then you
scale it up so that you can make a
premium commercial product and you know
and when once we have those those
technicalities of the scale up will will
have a good basis for our next wave of
the conversation absolutely I mean it
that the principles are all still
fundamentally the same and so in your
home compost pile if you're looking to
get thermophilic hot temperatures you're
gonna need at least one cubic yard of
mass of material that means at least
three feet tall three feet wide three
feet deep minimum and typically your
compost will shrink 50 percent so you
want to build your piles much bigger and
they're gonna shrink down but you need
to have enough mass to have those
microbes be able to generate that heat
and break it down so understand that as
a general rule of thumb when I you know
tell people home composting systems
the simplest things you'll find is
either a pallet system with four pallets
one underneath and three on the sides or
a large kind of circular chicken-wire
type of structure where you can make
your compost in but you need to have
enough mass and so we're doing the same
thing on the farm in terms of mass but
we're using a windrow system and so a
windrow is just essentially a large long
row I typically build the piles no
higher than 5 or 6 feet tall knowing
that they're gonna shrink and no wider
than 12 feet tall we do use a compost
Turner to turn the piles and kind of
goes through it turns the outside in and
the inside out you can also roll your
piles with a front-end loader a skid
steers one of my favorites but
essentially you're just building it in a
long structure it's the same concept
that you have enough material in one
place together another consideration is
obviously having that proper carbon and
nitrogen ratio and we can certainly you
know talk more about that but that's
where you hear people talk about your
greens and your Browns and layering it
but it's important no matter what you do
is understand the exact characteristics
of whatever you're using in that pile
and as the piles shrink you want to have
more material but you sometimes want to
start a new pile so in home compost or
people with tumblers they say the
compost is never ready well it's hard to
have it ready when you're always adding
brand-new materials so sometimes a two
bin system is great where the one gets
really tall and full and then you start
a new pile you're able to kind of rework
your old pile so in a commercial setting
I'll have the same thing I'll build a
windrow five or six feet tall it gets a
hundred and forty hundred and forty-five
degrees inside everybody's steaming away
and chowing down and that pile suddenly
shrunk for five and a half feet to three
feet tall and so for that secondary
phase of the compost oftentimes I'll
push to Windrose together and combine
them so there's still enough mass to
hold the heat and finish the process but
the other variable you know
you're dealing with California and
Oregon and winters and summers is you
want to be able to hold in moisture you
don't want too much surface area in the
winter months and sometimes you have to
employ covers fabric covers that allow
them to breathe and you should do that
for a home compost pile as well but
sometimes in the summer I want to trap
the moisture inside so I don't have to
artificially add moisture coming in with
a some type of a water wagon or
something else but creating those ratios
in the beginning and getting that down
is critical
so in terms of scaling it up the
principles are still the same when I
inoculate the piles using the biodynamic
method I might have a windrow that's a
hundred yards long
but I'm dividing that wind row into
eight or ten different or twelve or
thirteen different sections so each
section is approximately for biodynamic
purposes I look at each section of the
wind row every seven to ten tons of wind
row is like its own unit and I want to
knock you late that small part of the
pile so it's it's a long system but I
think of it as all these little batches
combined much like somebody who's
planting cannabis you might have one
plant that you're treating as one plant
but you might have a whole row that's
planted in the ground
and one of the things you want to
realize is in between those plants is a
vast array of for all intents and
purpose biological intelligence so
oftentimes people think that you know
they're little drip watering systems
just at the base of the plant is the
most efficient way to do it and maybe
it's efficient in terms of overall water
but when you look at the grand scheme of
it all and really harnessing all the
life and all the power beneath the soil
that's available to you you're missing
out on a vast amount of biological
intelligence of biological resources and
nutrient resources that lie within the
soil in between those plants because
they do communicate with each other
whether you're paying attention to
or not so dividing it into sections but
really keeping an eye at the really big
picture is one of the important things
of scaling it up and the third variable
goes back to that idea of intentional
composting is selecting your materials
with meticulous care and for Malibu
compost and for biodynamics as a whole
it all starts with the cow and we can go
into a hundred of different reasons with
that and that kind of goes into that
microbe and the bio regions but we're
looking at a clean grass-fed organic
dairy cow manure and having that rich
manure blended with the proper carbon
materials to be able to have a good
carbon nitrogen ratio to start the
composting process and blend it in such
a way that we can pile it up where it's
homogenous enough to be able to have an
even controlled biological breakdown and
not end up if it starts with chunks of
hay and chunks of manure and chunks of
this often times you're gonna end up
with a wide variation in the biological
decomposition of the pile and you'll
find really hot pockets and really cold
pockets when it comes down to
temperature so you're not having a
homogeneous even microbial controlled
breakdown which is what we're altima
trying to do even if we are scaling it
up right on that makes a lot of sense so
so feeding the cows grass and and
leaving the cows organic and not pumping
them full of chemicals that's fairly
obvious but but what is your reasoning
for specifically using dairy cows and um
I should preface this by saying is one
of the most important aspects of making
compost is use what's available to you
for all your local composters find
what's most readily available and then
work your way out and around your local
region in that regard
um for us at Malibu compost because
we're doing a back
agda product we really started with
working backwards from what is the most
valuable most superior what could we
think of as the best compost on earth
and then work backwards from that and
that's what's brought us to biodynamic
agriculture and there's a number of
different reasons for that but there's
something incredibly special about the
cow is the cow is a giant digestive
fermentation machine the cow it's not
meant to run and jump the cow stands and
eats and digests and has four stomachs
and there's a 12 days of that digestive
process from the time that that grass
enters the cows cud and starts chewing -
whether it comes out the other end so
there's all this fermentation in these
enzyme in these bacteria but the cow
itself and you see this now as research
is coming out grass-fed dairy cow also
produced specific compounds one of them
clas are conjugated linoleic acids and
you'd have to ask somebody who's much
more of a chemist than I to really break
that into it but there's a link and
really what it comes down to is you need
high quality soil to create plants and
if you have high quality healthy plants
that are deriving their mineral
nutrition from the soil in the air this
builds a high functional immunity in the
plants and plants that are strong and
have strong immunity and strong immune
systems that then gets transferred to us
as humans in the form of food so it
sounds pretty simple but eating healthy
food from healthy plants creates healthy
people and that all starts with the
health of the soil so dad kind of backs
up to what goes in the soil and what
we've seen is that the cow it's not just
the digestive process but the cow is
eating grass
it's eating local grasses that are grown
specific to this area and we can get
into Allan savory and rangeland
management and grass management and
that's probably a whole nother show for
you if you haven't had one already and I
direct people to acres USA and a lot of
other resources that look at no-till and
grazing and pasture management but they
all have something in common which is
all these perennial grasses all these
local grasses that are indigenous to
different climates you can find a
hundred different grass types in the
field and you might find some weeds that
are in there often considered weeds but
they might be performing a specific
function to create balance in that soil
and so a cow all out on grass is is
processing biological material that's
specific to that locale it's those local
indigenous grasses and pasture grasses
that are passing through the cow coming
out the other end and fertilizing that
pasture and nature knows what it needs
and Nature has this incredible symbiotic
way of balancing itself out if and when
given the chance and so while it might
sound like a stretch of the imagination
I would say I would go so far as to say
that the cows digestive system has
almost a perception if you will of what
that grass and that pasture needs for
fertility and between the grasses that
it's grazing on and the manure that's
coming out the other end and up to 25%
of that manure could be considered
microbes it's passing on the same
fertility that's needed to keep in
balance and continually improve those
pastures so that's what we're after in
that dairy cow manure is all of those
microbes is all of that balance is all
that processing of those living native
annuals and perennials and those grasses
that are just growing in harmony with
the soil underneath and because of the
nature the dairy cow industry not all
dairies are because of land are able to
grow all the forage that they need and
so they end up often having much more
pasture land than they can for food and
so if they're not growing all their own
food on-site oftentimes they have land
close by you know both of our farms that
we work with in California and Oregon
have off-site hay pastures so they grow
their own hay still vertically
integrated they just do it a couple
hours away because the value of real
estate obviously but what we find there
is still by controlling those variables
they're not getting hay that's imported
from hundreds of miles away or from
different states that who knows what it
has in it but you're really controlling
this microbial population in different
regions that are gonna have their own
positive affect not only on the soil but
it goes then also into the plant and
plants that have a stronger native soil
have stronger indigenous microorganisms
they're able to build a stronger immune
system and it's you know much like
humans that are able to do well in an
area where you grew up or we see this
with different cultures different
cultural phenomenon it's the same kind
of function of building that immunity
and building that plant health through
building the soil health so in our in
our second set we're gonna talk a lot
more about local microbes but but but as
we wrap up this first set I was curious
you know I'm it - not knowing a lot
about cows actually at all but but you
always when you talk about you talk
about dairy cows thus excluding meat
cows and I always wondered was there
something about the biology of a dairy
cow and that the cow is you know at a
part of her life that she's giving off
milk does that add some kind of
fertility to her output in and of itself
just because she's at that stage in her
life
exactly
once a cow has given birth and is
producing milk through that lactation
cycle there's a whole different set of
enzymes that become presence in the
cow's rumen and in the cow's die jet in
the cow's cut really it starts in the
cow's mouth as they're chewing those
grasses and so that's passed on and we
see you know the the fatty acids and the
milk content and we're able to analyze
all these different compounds in milk
now and we can see through the growth of
probiotics and utilizing raw grass-fed
dairy cow milk for making cultures and
making labs and all sorts of I mean you
can just do an experiment with
store-bought milk and with organic milk
and with raw milk and you know you can
see the difference in its ability to go
through you know that process and that's
really a reflection of what's in there
so that mother dairy cow has these
different enzymes that are produced and
we're looking for the same kind of
probiotic elements if you will coming
out one end of the cow that's coming out
in the form of the milk of the cow now
that's not to say that there's a lot of
benefits to the male cow's butt and you
see that because an organic male cow
would be considered out on grass would
be grass-fed beef and grass-fed beef
still contains a lot of those same
conjugated linoleic acids that you find
in dairy products and these are
compounds the body just doesn't produce
them they we need them but the body just
doesn't produce them and so this is one
of the ways that you're able to get it
and that same kind of fertility it's not
necessarily in the composting process
but I would encourage your listeners to
take a look at the Marin carbon project
and the work of John wick down in Marin
with restoring the rangelands but we've
seen that the fertility of these animals
grazing after years and years of not
grazing on rangeland that has been dead
you know has degradation year after year
one summer of these cows grazing
reverses the degradation of the land and
it starts a carbon sequestration cycle
through one application of compost
furthermore native perennials start
coming back and the cows pick up weight
and over the summer months they become
much more lush they gain weight you can
physically see the difference in the in
the coats of the cows but really the
most fascinating thing is what's
happening under the soil as this process
of grazing and these nutrients getting
restored to the soil are able to
literally reverse this problem of soil
degradation and sequester carbon and
that is one of the greatest
opportunities that we have available as
we look you know towards our future and
we look at these issues of global
warming and the amount of carbon and the
challenge of growing healthy food and
the challenge of soil degradation and
land that has been abused and soil that
has just died off after years and years
and years of chemical synthetic
conventional agriculture right on thank
you : so we're gonna take our first
short break and be right back you're
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is Colm Riley co-founder of Malibu
compost now that the health benefits of
terpenes have become well known in the
cannabis industry people everywhere are
looking for the purest terpenes without
adulterants the problem with most
terpene providers is that they're not
sourced naturally and instead are made
as a byproduct of refining petroleum and
that's so sketchy the terpenes sold by
true terpenes are entirely different
they are certified organic non-gmo and
food grade that means that they are
extracted from real plant sources there
are no solvents of any kind they are
distilled only with steam that's right
only steam in fact terpenes from true
turbines are so pure that you can eat
them not only that but you can stack
them with better results - what I mean
is
other companies turbine
have got a few percent of impurities and
when you stack those terpenes to make
your blend you're adding a variety of
impurities that degrade your final
product true terpenes also have strange
specific terpenes for a wide range of
cannabis strains like Durbin poison
sunset sherbet and granddaddy purple
true terpenes has robust in support of
customer service so your questions will
get answered fast and efficiently if you
shop for Terps before you know how rare
that is so whether you want to cup your
hands just smell some betta carry
awfully to calm them down after getting
too high or if you want to dab some
pining so your lungs feel fabulous and
your mind feels liberated true terpenes
will provide you with a truly natural
experience if you are a cannabis product
developer these are the Terps you want
to add to your oil or edible or capsule
or whatever true terpenes are simply the
best your money can buy don't try and
make a premium product with substandard
terms choose true terpenes for a
top-shelf experience go to shaping fire
calm board / true terpenes to find out
more or click on the link in this week's
newsletter using pesticides when growing
cannabis has been common for a long time
nowadays though we know better we know
that most pesticides formulated for food
crops have never been tested for use
with cannabis they've been tested to be
eaten in tiny doses they have not been
tested to be inhaled and especially not
concentrated into a cannabis oil
chemical residues from pesticides are
not healthy for anyone but they are
especially dangerous for patients for
commercial cannabis growers this has
become very impactful cannabis
enthusiasts and patients have gotten
educated enough that they avoid growers
who used pesticides not only that but
states across the country have begun
making pesticide testing mandatory on
all licensed cannabis crops the time has
come to find a better way to fight
garden pests than covering your cannabis
and chemicals and there is a better way
let some good bugs fight your bad bugs
beneficial insects and predatory mites
have come a long way since we were
buying ladybugs online and putting them
in the grow room and just hoping for the
best natural enemies bio control
can help you solve pest issues without
using chemicals natural enemies founder
Shane young learned best practices from
working in the ornamental plant industry
and has fine-tuned those strategies
specifically for large cannabis crops
Shane works with commercial cannabis
clients across the country to ensure
that they keep their crop safe and pest
free without the use of chemicals
natural enemies has proven solutions for
spider mites Athens thrips Russert mites
broad mites shore flies white fly and
others - you can rely on natural enemies
for expertise and excellent service for
more information go to shaping feiyr.com
forward slash natural enemies or simply
click on their banner in this week's
newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I'm your host
Shango Louis and our guest this week is
Colm Riley co-founder of Malibu compost
so before the break we learned
soup-to-nuts about how compost is made
why it's regenerative and how to scale
it up but one of the important things
that you continually point out column is
the use of local microbes and this you
know is in contrast to the idea that
that compost can be made somewhere on
the other side of the country and then
it gets shipped to you on pallets and
then you use it locally expecting it to
keep your cannabis plants alive when the
food is actually from somewhere else so
you know it really kind of blew my mind
when you were talking in San Francisco
and Indo Expo about these micro bio
regions and the importance of
incorporating local microbes in cannabis
horticulture will you go through that
line of thought for us a little bit
right now in the in the difference I
guess I mean the diversity of local
microbes and why we want to make sure
that we capture and use those local
microbes in our soil for growing
cannabis sure and I guess there's to say
I suddenly got hit over the head with
the bat of eco guilt because our compost
does ship to other places and people do
use it but that's why
flying out at about midnight tonight
back to Pennsylvania to get to work
again on our first wind rows that we're
making in Pennsylvania congratulations
on that exciting as it is to ship
compost to Pennsylvania I think it's
much more important to make the compost
in Pennsylvania and then have it
available there so certainly sometimes
you know something can still work and
the things work on a nutritional and a
biological level but yeah there's this
question of local and uh I guess one way
to explain it would be if you think of
microbes as almost livestock of the soil
think of all the same kind of
biodiversity that we have above-ground
in our forests and our plains and our
wooded areas think of the same just
massive biodiversity of microbes
underneath the soil so you're gonna have
different types and different herds of
microbes in different areas of the
country because it's just different soil
types and different characteristics and
those have an important role to play in
those regions and have a historical role
so with the dairy cow it's we're we're
kind of cherry picking because the dairy
cow is foraging on pasture so those
pastures have different characteristics
in different parts of the country and I
would certainly say we've seen
significant differences between the
compost that we make in California and
the compost that we make in Oregon and
not to put myself down but I feel that
there is sort of an inherent I don't
necessarily want to use the word
superiority but there seems to be a much
higher level of energy and diversity in
the oregon compost and i believe that
has a lot to do with the fact that
because of rainfall and weather and some
other meteorological phenomenon the cows
are able to be outside and have many
many more days on pasture than their
california counterparts that's certainly
one of the things that you see
and the pasture management is really
good because of the water and the
different cycles that you're able to
have there but it's still important to
have locally produced composts so when
you start looking at some of the micro
bio regions just think that there's many
many different curds of microbes in
different areas and here on the west
coast from the Pacific Northwest to
Humboldt and Mendocino County right down
the California coast line to the redwood
forests of Santa Cruz we have an
ecosystem that's largely derived from
the Pacific and I always talk about this
when I'm talking about indigenous
microorganisms I always throw out the
question does a bear [__] in the woods
and yes it does but one thing to
remember is there used to be a whole lot
more bears in these woods and what did
the Bears use to eat salmon and then
what would the Bears do [__] in the
woods
so you have this fertility that's almost
sort of ocean derived spreading itself
out in that nutrient footprint whether
it's from the birds or the bears or all
these other animals and filling all of
our mountain ranges along the coastal
lines and the rains come and this is one
of sort of the local nutritional
footprints if you will of this type of
soil so when we're talking to growers
and it doesn't matter what you're
growing there's a significant
consideration in my mind when you start
thinking about how am I going to add
additional fertility to your plants and
contrary to what the chemical companies
will have you believe not all NPK is
created equal it's not so when you're
putting blood meal on your plants or
bone meal on your plants you might be
getting bone mil from a hog processing
facility in Arkansas run by Johnsonville
that you would never want to take
anything
um and you're putting on that plants
when you have available to you shrimp
meal and kelp meal and crab meal and
kelp meal and uh fish meal and all sorts
of crustacean derived that have a much
more sort of localized footprint for
what you're doing but you find it all
around it has to do with the weeds and
the plant matter that's growing in that
soil it has to do with the forest Duff
as you said and so this is a fascinating
area where science is struggling and
trying to catch up and almost literally
invent and define this field of soil
microbiology as fast as they can and
it's one of those exciting things where
you know the science of the soil is
probably just as misunderstood or has
yet to be understood as from a geography
standpoint the depths of our oceans it's
just that area that we've never really
hit but everything else you know we've
been able to define so there's this kind
of vast unknown but we know that there's
just these different aspects of
different areas and one thing you find
which is interesting where science is
still kind of trying to explain it is
where indigenous wisdom comes into play
and you know biodynamic sometimes some
of the purists like to think okay
biodynamics was coined by Rudolf Steiner
in 1924 and it's the end-all be-all and
it's not quite that way but it's not it
was much more also a cultural scientist
and he looked at what different cultures
did and when you start looking at some
of the agricultural practices of the
Mayans or the Aztecs or different Native
American tribes you see that there's
relationships in their agricultural
practices that have to do with the
cycles of the Moon that have to do with
the cycles of the year that have to do
with the cycles of plants and animals
and how they plant and there are
different practices that they did
sometimes they might not even really be
able to tell you everything behind it
other than it was just passed down and
more recently I saw you at a phenomenal
podcast talking about Korean natural
farming techniques yeah now with Kris
Trump yeah and so I'm sure I wasn't able
to catch every segment of that but one
of the things that Korean natural
farming looks at is harnessing the power
of these indigenous microorganisms so
something as simple as taking a plate of
steamed rice that are in a box and
taking it and putting it underneath a
tree on your property and like you
mentioned that houmous that forest Duff
when we say compost happens all you need
to do is go stand underneath the tree
and microscopically every hour every
second compost is happening
microorganisms that you can't even see
are slowly falling to the ground and
getting broken up and compost is
happening on that forest floor every
second of every day and so putting
steamed rice out in the forest
underneath the tree is all those
millions of local microorganisms are
landing on that rice and sticking to
that rice and that rice is then used as
a catalyst combined with plant matter
harvested from that property filled with
water and you doing utilizing a catalyst
such as a lactobacillus and what that
does it starts that fermentation and
reproduction process and those
indigenous microorganisms now are
reproducing over and over and over again
and replicating themselves and you're
now building populations of
microorganisms that are uniquely
specific to your property and it's not
that you're going after those indigenous
microorganisms for NPK nutrients but
you're really going after that health
that vitality and that immune system in
the plant and the stronger the plant is
as far as its ability to not have to
worry and have a care in the world for
pest and disease and other aspects it
can just do what it does is have this
symbiotic relationship with all the life
in the soil and having that healthy soil
and having this healthy approach to the
plant is what's gonna create this
nutrient density you know and you can
look at a soil test and you can look at
a multivitamin look at the label on your
kid's multivitamins and look at all the
compounds that you find in your soil
test and you're gonna see the same
compounds there you're gonna see zinc
you're gonna see manganese you're gonna
see iron you're gonna see all these
different minerals that we look at in
terms of human health and you're gonna
understand that that's what's
transmuting into the food and all the
secondary metabolites is really what
we're looking at that can build not only
just the human health and the plant
health but its health just beyond the
nutrients that our bodies crave it's
this added health and vitality it's the
the ability to resist pests and disease
it's we see it in children that played
in the mud or grew up on a farm they
just naturally are healthier and more
resistant we don't have to look far
outside away from our journals of
science and our journals of nature and
our journals of everything else but the
problem is we basically have a medical
field in this country that knows nothing
about nutrition and health so there's a
whole disconnect here you know the
diabetes rate in this country used to be
one for every 50,000 people now it's one
out of every 20 so something severely
wrong with our soil with our plants and
with our food and as we take this back
to cannabis it's understanding the
cannabis does have incredible medicinal
properties but to me sometimes it's
almost blows your mind for people that
can swear up and down the cannabis has
medicinal properties yet are completely
ignorant of the fact that the medicinal
properties and value of cannabis has
everything to do with how it's grown
you're not gonna stick a cannabis plant
in a bunch of rockwool and dump a bottle
just bottle after bottle of bottle after
nutrients synthetic nutrients and then
say oh but the cannabis is is its
medicinal you know it's it it's
medicinal it's it's you know I mean
that's like saying a steering wheel has
the ability to drive you down the
freeway from Seattle to Portland it
doesn't you need the car that's attached
to it so it's it's it's one aspect of it
but to ignore that aspect of it is kind
of doing the same disservice that all of
us are trying to overcome and really be
a part of the solution of what's wrong
with our food system and our
agricultural system and not be part of
the problem that really takes the whole
idea of whole plant medical cannabis to
a to a whole nother level not only are
you talking about all the cannabinoid
constituents but also the the entire
life and micronutrients of the plants
and you know you know one of the things
that always Curie not always I believe I
don't when really didn't think about
this for about a year but one of the
things I've been curious about for the
last year is that um with these local
microbes does it make sense to only use
your local microbes I would think that
since everywhere in the United States
pretty much plants are growing that you
should have a complete set of the
necessary microbes where you live and
not necessarily have to bring them from
somewhere else I mean perhaps you want
to ship yourself a higher quality
compost that's one thing but but when I
first started thinking about microbes I
was thinking oh well if I were to order
a compost say from Oklahoma where it's
certainly more dry and the soil has a
different composition than where I live
in the Pacific Northwest so I order a
bag there and I bring it here and the
microbes that would come with it you
know there used to a dryer and
they're not used to these tepid winters
they're there they're built for a
different environment and I'm thinking
you know they very well might not do
well in my soil here but then what if
there's something that's missing I mean
probably where I live in the Pacific
Northwest I probably have got a full set
of microbes but I can imagine that there
might be parts of the country that are
so where the soil is so stripped that
they really need to need to import
microbes from somewhere else because
their own soil is lacking is there is
there any truth or possibility to that
yes I think so and this might be an area
where people that are far more
knowledgeable on specific microbial
inoculations than I could speak better
to that but I'll throw out a couple
examples I have a very close family
friend and agricultural friend that we
work together as a biodynamic vineyard
consultants and he's worked all over he
honed his craft in France and he's been
all over top vineyards on the west coast
he's utilized some microbial inoculants
on some vineyards down in the Central
Coast of California sort of down Sandeen
as type area and one of the things that
he told me was adding a microbial
inoculant what he noticed and you know
it's not as scientifically rigorous so
please don't question my numbers but he
said something like it looked like
something like after taking samples
something like 60% of the microbes that
had been added died off that they just
they weren't they couldn't thrive in
that environment but what they also
noticed was it had a detrimental effect
on a lot of the indigenous
microorganisms so when something gets
introduced it can out-compete your
you're creating something completely out
of balance so I just saw the headline
yesterday that what they said like
30,000
factory farmed salmon escaped from their
free pens up in Newfoundland and now are
like swimming around the ocean and they
didn't notice this they didn't tell
anybody that there was a hole in the net
and only happened when local fishermen
started catching these salmon the timber
like these aren't our normal salmon and
so they create these factory farms
salmon and they stick these pens out in
the ocean
but they're highly you know all the fish
are combined in one small area so
they're much more prone to picking up
certain diseases and then they escape
through the net and now all of a sudden
they're out roaming about and they can
out-compete they can create they can
just create all these different
imbalances so going back to the soil you
can have different microbial
inoculations but there's the question of
are they gonna survive and thrive in a
new climate and what's the effect and
impact that they're gonna have on the
local indigenous microorganism
populations so one of the things you're
after is a lot of diversity and there's
no there's no one silver bullet and I
wouldn't tell somebody in Pennsylvania
or Maine or Oklahoma or anywhere else to
just buy a bag of Malibu and that's it
even in Oregon and in California we're
telling our much larger customers people
that want several truckloads of compost
for their for their vineyard or for
their orchard or for their cannabis grow
is if you're getting a larger amount of
compost and we can work with you bring
me some of your own on-site compost
bring me some of your topsoil let's bury
that in the compost pile while it's
cooking while it's simmering while it's
going through this heated process and so
we can introduce those microbes right
from your property into the larger thing
and have them sort of work out their
issues and figure out a way to get along
and reproduce before they even you know
so that way they can kind of hit the
ground running for for a lack of a
better way to put it that's so long
necks that's so next level compost
column I mean I mean the idea that you
would have this thought out to such
degree that that you're going to
actually inoculate your I'll
you know custom off-the-shelf compost
with their inoculant from the locality
you know if it's actually exciting to
know that somebody's even bothering to
do that because I think so many of the
growers who are listening you know
that's what that's that's what's in
their heart you know what I mean and the
fact that you are able to do it at a
commercial level it's invigorating you
know it's exciting it's super exciting
and where I really would say you know
the proof is in the poop is this is
where compost teas become so exciting
and so this is a way that somebody can
capture some of that diversity and some
of all these amazing benefits that we're
talking about between the cow and the
digestive system and the microbial
diversity and then still get it out onto
their property and um there was a minute
gentlemen
Alex pote Alinsky who's in Australia and
you can now read about the pote alinsky
method but Alec Spode Alinsky followed
by a dynamics and Australia was just
getting devastated by this growth of
commercial synthetic agriculture and
fields were getting more and more
degraded and he followed by a dynamics
and he saw this and the cow and
everything but he realized we don't have
cows we got some kangaroo poop running
around here but like there's not the
same massive amount of herds of cows in
Australia that there are in in you know
the United States and Europe and so what
he did then was realize is we needed to
make sort of a compost catalyst from the
cow and so that's the preparation that
you see that there's stuffed and the cow
horns that's buried underground and
that's allowed to turn into this rich
sort of houmous material but that is
literally taking a teaspoon of that and
stirring it into water and diluting it
to the point where it's treating one
acre of land so you know you can have a
pound of compost that's being treating
that's treating 50 acres so we're
talking about something on the most
minut and homeopathic level and as crazy
as it sounds and
nobody believed this guy until
Australian public television aired a
special with him and then a bunch of
people thought he was into witchcraft
and thousands of farmers started driving
overnight to his farm to come visit and
figure out how could we do this as well
so there the proof you can see and
somebody will do a compost tea
application that's only the most minut
introduction in small doses but we're
looking at creating that impulse and
just that small little impulse that then
it's gonna replicate it itself and then
replicate itself another time and
replicated another time and so you're
building up this health and vitality and
it's not a one size fits all massive
approach but you're going over it so no
matter where you are in bio dynamics I
always say you always want to add your
own topsoil or clay or something into
your compost during that process so
while it's undergoing this
transformation you have that spectral
profile if you will of your soil and
your indigenous microorganisms add it
into the soil if you're purchasing
Malibu compost or any other soil for
that matter you should be looking to
maybe you don't have much of your own
compost but anything that you can have
on-site maybe even you make a tea out of
what you have and you're spraying that
onto the compost that you can use but
regardless one to join forces with the
other and the earlier in that sort of
process that that can take place the
better if you can add something into
your compost pile or into my compost
file of yours while it's simmering and
cooking you're you're allowing a lot of
those issues that suddenly can result
from a shock type thing just think about
you know transplant shock for example
and you're mitigating that by creating
something that can kind of work out
their issues and then get to this point
of harmony and synergy before you're
introducing you know plants as living
organisms into a chaotic environment
rather it's an
that's just thriving and you know ready
to do its job damn straight
wow that's awesome well let's go ahead
and take our second short break you're
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is colum Riley co-founder of
Malibu compost join me at the upcoming
kin met event in Los Angeles for a
gathering of the top minds in cannabis
medicine field experts will present
their latest findings and best practices
in treating a variety of conditions with
cannabis including epilepsy pain
traumatic brain injury cancer autism and
more laboratory professionals will share
their revolutionary technologies in
cannabinoid and terpenoid extraction
delivery methods and quality and safety
testing can med 2018 is October 22nd
through 24th at the Luskin Conference
Center at UCLA and while the final
speakers list is still coming together
the speakers who are already announced
give you plenty of reasons to get your
ticket today prepare yourself to learn
from 54 thought-leader presentations
focused on furthering the convergence of
medical cannabis research treatment and
product development speakers include the
father of cannabis research Raphael Mis
ulam Michael door chief medical
consultant for the Israeli Ministry of
Health will be there to the list of
esteemed speakers participating is long
and includes shaping fire guests
cannabis neuroscientist dr. Ethan
Rousseau and Kevin mckernon of medicinal
genomics you can view all the speakers
at kin med events calm this year's kin
med features a special education track
on the application of blockchain
technology in the cannabis market
including cannabis banking seed the sail
tracking sequencing the cannabis genome
ico financing and more if you are a
medical care provider be sure to arrive
a date early to participate in the
pre-conference CME course find out more
about that at kin med events comm that's
c-a-n-n-a me d events calm 95% of
attendees said kin med 2017 met or
exceeded their expectations that's a
serious vote of confidence that can med
2018 will be well worth your time and
resources so don't delay visit
can med events calm today to reserve
your seat and find out more
skinny-dipping
humpback whales beatnik poetry the
Ottoman Empire soil remediation
interdimensional beings and tree frogs
these are just a few of the interesting
topics you can find in the audio books
library at audible.com if you like
podcasts like shaping fire chances are
that you'll dig audiobooks too just like
with podcasts audiobooks speak to you
telling you stories and teaching you
stuff here's the thing audible.com has
an offer I want to tell you about right
now they're offering a trial of their
audiobook service for absolutely free
you can go to shaping feiyr.com forward
slash audible and you will get a free
audiobook straight up you can listen to
it on your mobile device computer or you
can download it and listen to it like
anywhere it's really simple of course
they want you to subscribe to their
service after the free trial and enjoy
their audiobooks forever but you don't
have to all you have to do to get the
free audiobook of your choice is to
check out the service for free so that's
the deal your first book is free it's
easy to sign up it's easy to quit and
their online library of free ebooks is
pretty incredible just check it out go
to shaping feiyr.com forward slash
audible to find out more or click on the
link in this week's newsletter welcome
back you are listening to shaping fire
I'm your host Shango louse and our guest
this week is colum Riley he's co-founder
of Malibu compost so now that we've got
everybody all excited about compost
wanting to make their own wanting to you
know have wild harvest local microbes
let's talk a bit about the applications
for compost both you know some typical
stuff that we're gonna see in
horticulture but also some of the new
kind of groundbreaking applications that
we're seeing so so why don't we start at
the top colum and hit each of these for
a little bit so so tell us a little bit
about compost tea
well compost tea is incredibly exciting
and I'm sure you've had plenty of
podcasts and guests who are experts in
that area I certainly wouldn't claim to
be one but there's you know I would
guess I would point out there's a
distinction between a compost tea which
is considered something the
actively aerated versus a compost
compost extract and there's you know a
lot of debate on different sides there's
you know a lot of people that are
fiercely into the actively aerated
compost teas on the Elaine Ingham side
um I've you know heard then read some
stuff that Scott is working on at where
he's looking a lot more towards extracts
and what that does but um the
fundamental ideas well back it up even
more when I talk about compost tea we
put together a very very rudimentary
sort of I call it the gateway drug to
compost tea is our little Malibu compost
tea bags they're available on Amazon and
most of your local stores but it's a you
know quarter pound of compost and a
little cotton baggie it's all dried out
and you soak it in five gallons of water
and you put it on your plants the next
day so I did not use the word aerate
there and I didn't use it because
technically if you soak it and squeeze
it out and put it on your plants the
next day it's considered a Coldwater
compost tea extract by the compost tea
definitions but you could put an
airstone in it and you can put your
bubbler in it and you can brew a compost
tea where all these microorganisms are
reproducing you know millions and
millions of times over so there's
different aspects of compost teas
there's different recipes for compost
teas and the things that you can use but
I also find really exciting how you can
use compost teas so whether it's an
extract or actively aerated compost teas
most people look at brewing a compost
tea but then watering it into the soil
and that's great because you're getting
the nutrients the minerals the trace
minerals but really what we're looking
at is all that beneficial bacteria and
fungi and we want the beneficial guys to
out-compete the harmful guys that's
really what we're looking at um one of
the most common applications of compost
teas that you'll read and hear about is
adding it as a foliar spray so if you're
spraying it on the underside of the
leaves where the plants stomata is it's
able to take it up through the stomata
right into the plant the way that I
think that
it's like a quick fix it's sort of like
a quick has to go right into the plants
immune system so all those beneficials
are able to go right through the stomata
into the plants immune system as opposed
to having to go through the soil compete
in the soil make their way up through
the root system and out to the leaves
and and things like that
so you're spraying it right on to the
leaves you want to be careful that it
has smaller particles because the
smaller the particles the greater the
surface area the easier the plant can
absorb it but you don't want to use some
of these battery-powered super you know
atomizers because sometimes the force
with which you spray it can kill the
very microbes that you've spent all this
time to breed and to diversify I think
it's really exciting when you see tree
surgeons and tree care people that will
have these like ten foot long syringes
if you will and they're injecting
compost tea down into the root system of
trees as a way to balance out and add
more benefits to the overall it's sort
of just like a quick fix of being able
to treat the teas but one of the things
I always tell people is I'm typically
not a huge fan and again I'm not an
expert so somebody can correct me but
I'm not a huge fan of brewing further
than 24 hours because I just feel
inherently like once you get to the
point where you have to start
introducing bacterial foods and fungal
foods and microbial foods once you get
to that point you're almost introducing
a level of competition and different
microbes may or may not have preference
for different types of food sources so
once you've blended all your ingredients
and you've created all this diversity by
simply adding molasses for example you
seem to almost now be source selecting
which microbes are gonna do better and
which microbes are gonna do worse and
are gonna thrive in different
competitive environments so you know
I'll leave that to other people in terms
of overall teas and approaches um but
just
sheer results that people see with T's
are I mean that's the proof and you know
when we sell an expensive compost that
people can add to build your soil
biology and people use it and they
carefully pay attention and then they
tell us how great it is but it takes a
little while but the beauty of compost
tea is people will put it on their
plants and they'll call you immediately
and they see the color green change and
they see the leaves turn towards the sky
and start praying upwards and they they
see and they feel these physical
tangible results and that's what gets
them excited and so there's so much more
you can do in terms of building your
recipes with teas and how you use the
teas and how you're just adding this
thing where something's you're using a
principle of frequency as opposed to
quantity and it's creating these small
little impulses but just giving nature
the tools that it needs to nudge it in
that right direction and just keep that
health and vitality in your soil and in
your plants I like that frequency versus
quantity so you know let's also talk
briefly about soil amendments because
you know pretty much all of the the
healthy probiotic stuff that you just
said about compost tea will also cross
apply to just simply taking some compost
and mixing it in with your soil but
often I you know hear from people you
don't want to just use compost because
it may even somehow be too potent so
when you're recommending compost as a
soil amendment
how much do you recommend people go with
um if you're using a well balanced
compost um you know typically you could
go anywhere up to 25 percent of your
soil may be as high as 30 percent of
your soil mix but you're gonna need
aeration you're gonna want some local
you know like a more of a top soil type
of blend for people who are in
containers you know I mean we see people
use like 1/3 perlite 1/3 peat 1/3 Malibu
and call it a day yeah we
with that but you compost also has a
higher bulk density means it has less
free airspace so you don't want
something and as you add more water it's
gonna gradually get eaten up taken down
by the plants and create more compaction
so you don't want to have too much
compost in your mix without having the
proper aeration but really it kind of
depends on what type of cut you know if
you're getting something that's and
sometimes often it's things that aren't
even compost because they've changed the
definition now so things that used to be
called composted steer manure or
composted chicken manure they used the
word composted as a substitute for aged
yeah means it was just a put in a pile
and just kind of got old and now they're
calling it compost did so it's it's
different so with things like that you
can get a lot of different pockets a lot
of different hot areas can burn plants
it can lock out nutrients you can have
some different negative effects by using
compote you know using too much compost
sure but typically I'd say anywhere from
that 10 to 25% range with what you're
doing and keep in mind that everything's
all about balance and whether you're
looking at the work of dr. Elaine Ingham
and she's talking about balance between
bacterial and fungal or you're looking
at the work of Albrecht where you're
looking at these different ratios of
minerals you want to have that balanced
you know I many many people could look
at me with an absolute blank stare in
the eye if I've ever asked them if
they've used a Brix meter on their
cannabis no concept of it no concept of
the overall compounds you know it's all
about the Terps dude so it it's
understanding that you want to build
this diversity and you want to build
this balance and these ratios so it's
just it's I guess it's imperative to
really understand what you're working
with so the quick answer would be well
it depends on what kind of compost but
general parameter 10 to 30 percent of
your soil mix right on well said and I
think that you gave enough extra
information that people can kind of you
know think through the challenge on
their own based on the on the variables
you gave them one of the ways that I use
compost is as a as a top dress and that
kind of hits on your frequency over a
quantity because I'll put the compost on
top and then every time I water it you
know some of the goods go down into the
soil and I think that's a pretty common
way to use it especially when people are
having a not good experience with either
growing their cannabis or their
vegetables they're going in for the save
and you know and they're adding some
compost on the top and watering it in my
question for you is when using it as a
top dress do I need to put down the
compost and then put some more soil on
top because I'm I suspect that if we use
compost and it's going you know and it
is interacting with the air that it's
gonna dry out and all my beneficials are
gonna get choked out just from the
dryness no that's a great question um
one is typically I tell people when
they're applying it as a top dress you
just want to kind of lightly scratch it
into the surface um that also helps
sometimes composts have this sort of
initial hydrophobic aspect and you want
things to just absorb evenly and get
that flow down um but that's also where
it's important to not have bare soil on
the top and utilizing just something as
a mulch cover at the top whether you're
using grasses or planting cover crops is
planting cover crops whether you're in
the ground or even indoors in a
container you can plant cover crops
around the base of your cannabis and
that that adds shade it protects the
soil from being bare which allows all
these microbiology in the soil to come
and literally feed off the top layer
there and so these are one of the things
you see exciting and probiotic gardening
such as working with the earth box where
you're growing in a small limited area
and your roots can't go down further
they just can't go into the ground ad
infinitum and just keep going and going
in search of good food and if you're
growing outdoors you need to have a soil
bank approach a three to five year
strategic approach for building your
soil
because if you're not you're an idiot in
my opinion but you're just otherwise
you're just gonna outsource money that
you could be building each year but if
you're in containers you got to realize
things just don't drop out of the sky
and your root system can't go anywhere
else so you have an opportunity to
create that top dress as a nutritional
layer and that's where you're really
you're feeding the soil not the plant
and you're adding the compost you're
protecting the top so people can come up
and eat off the top surface that's where
adding amendments like like a Bokashi or
just other other forms of nutrients and
foods that can be applied at the top
surface as a top dress but then just be
gently covered up so then they can be
taken not just through watering but you
know the the microbiology in the soil
will come to the surface and literally
eat it
and you know and excrete it and move it
out I mean we see you know indoor
warehouse is now where everything's
grown under lights but they're growing
in soil and these guys have cover crops
growing around the base of their
cannabis plant and they'll pull back you
know the the hay or straw that they're
using as a mulch layer and you'll see
worms crawling around and you know a
55-gallon pot and just creating this
whole sort of symbiotic food web right
there even if they're limited to an
indoor environment that's that's so
awesome and especially when you know it
no it replaces the dead zone at the top
of a pot yeah and you if you just simply
even cover it with with some sort of
organic straw or something and it
increases the size of the or rather the
percentage of the amount of soil that
your plant can actually readily use I
would think that a pot you're gonna lose
a certain amount of the usable soil if
the soil at top is just facing the air
so you might as well put in a cover crop
not only does it look very visually
satisfying but it's super great for the
plant as well so we're almost out of
time but there there are two more things
I want to hit with you call them and one
is its it's not mess
growing based but you've talked about
these these compost socks that they're
using at construction sites and I think
that's an interesting idea so would you
just hit on that briefly just because so
people can go oh that's cool yeah I mean
it's I was fascinated to learn several
years ago that the largest purchaser of
compost in the state of California you
know was not almonds or not hazelnuts or
not grapes or anything else or cannabis
its Caltrans and it's the State
Department of Transportation using it
for erosion control on highway projects
and what they've realized is it's just
it's that ability to create to build the
soil back up as a sponge to add life to
the soil to help prevent water from
running off that's the problem with
California we never have enough water
until it rains and then we have too much
water and it all runs out to the ocean
we're not capturing it we're not
creating that filtration we're not
building the subsoil and so the erosion
controls fad you know just works great
and then they spray indigenous or native
wildflowers on it and boom they they
grab the ground immediately and it takes
the place of a lot of these other things
but you'll see it on construction sites
anywhere where there's runoff creeks
streams berms and Bank mints your
backyard might have a steep slope coming
from a neighbor and the compost socks
are similar to those socks that you see
the straw wattles in but think about
almost sort of a fabric pot material and
a large sock and the fill the entire
thing with compost and you lay it down
and now it acts like a bio filtration so
as the water from the erosion is running
down the hill it's having to pass
through this compost berm and that
compost is pulling out a lot of the
heavy metals and a lot of the pollutants
and a lot of the harmful excess
nutrients that are running into the
creeks and creating these algebra and
everything else and it's capturing that
in the compost and it's also flushed to
the ground much different than those
concrete k-rails that you see that it
looks like all the silt just goes right
around you can use compost berms in
conjunction with specific types of
it's for bioremediation which you see
them using insights where
petroleum-based runoff or other harmful
things that you'll see which caused you
know just severe degradation and this is
something that should be looked at even
more in areas of heavy intense
conventional farming and if you look
what's happening to the Gulf of Mexico
and everything else that's going
downstream from that you know I went to
register our product in Michigan and the
biggest there issue there is phosphates
and now people have been ignoring it and
you'd had farmers for years that have
been calculating how much fertilizer to
add to their land based on how much
nitrogen they need to grow per acre of
corn but they're only looking at the
nitrogen they're not looking at the P or
the K or the access load and I don't
even know what the the statistics would
be for a state or for this country or
for the world but when you look at like
just the fact that we're in a shortage
of nutrients how many excess nutrients
just get flushed into our river and
waterways and just are choking our
aquatic life which we depend on which
once again you know contributes to
global warming you know if there is such
a thing well this actually bleeds
perfectly into the last question I had
for you so like you know we've got we've
got a you know with the last three or
four minutes I heard your presentation
last weekend and enjoyed it on on the
organic revolution and and you know you
in your role at Malibu compost I see you
both as as a researcher and product
developer you're trying to figure out
these these techniques for creating this
most biodynamic compost that you can but
then also you're also an advanced list
right because you're one part sales
person you know encouraging vineyards
and cannabis people to use your compost
um but also you're doing things like
like right here on my show just pretty
much talking about compost for the
people and for nature anyway so
regardless of your own brand you know
just use compost people make it buy it
whatever you got to do use it
and so you have got a unique seat for
this this this revival of probiotic
growing kind of post synthetic inputs
and so my question to you is is what are
you seeing you know are you are you
seeing that people are hearing the
message and are making in the transition
or are you seeing that it's falling on
deaf ears I am seeing just an absolute
I'm seeing a world in flux and I'm
seeing problems become greater and
greater and more dire and human beings
having less and less compassion and
communication and on the same side I'm
seeing community come back together that
we haven't seen in years and the
regenerative agriculture movement is so
exciting and inspiring because a lot of
people just want a better way but there
must be a better way
just please show me and what's happening
in this movement and thank you for what
you do because your help spreading the
word of saying these are tangible steps
that you can take and they work there's
a better way and sometimes it might even
seem a little more expensive up front
but you have to just look at where it is
six months down the road one year down
the road two years down the road you
know I've talked to people who've bought
truckloads of my compost and put it in
their pots and they haven't bought any
the next year because they've talked
about the residual impacts on their soil
of what's happened after one application
of really boosting that soil and
creating you know if they're growing in
ground or in trenches of what they see
happen the secondary year and developing
a system so they don't have to use as
much um and everywhere you look more and
more research is coming out that's
showing people a better way to do it
we're realizing and it's one of those
things you know the difference between
organic and biodynamic versus
conventional and a lot of things like
this it's not the differences aren't as
you know hyper defined until things have
problems and then it becomes more and
more and more clear I you know if I want
to do a side-by-side trial on a lawn
with and without compost I'm gonna find
a really crappy lawn no pun intended to
put my compost on because the
you know it's just gonna be that much
more dramatic but we live in dramatic
times you know we live in dramatic times
where people have more and more cancers
and more and more mental illnesses and
Rudolf Steiner talked about this back in
1924 he said if people continue to eat
food that's devoid of life in the soil
the greatest problems plaguing mankind
are being to be cancers and mental
illnesses because you have to think
about our body and our brain as a highly
developed digestive tract and we're a
reflection of the nutrition that we
receive you know no matter what form it
comes to us and so people are coming
into this with challenges people are
getting into growing cannabis because
somebody got cancer you know people are
getting into this for all sorts of
different reasons but they're coming
together and realizing this and with
these new platforms of communication
whether it's your podcast whether it's
Instagram people doing things in the
right way in the ethical way around the
world are now sharing information and
saying look at what I've done look at
what I've done look what I did taking
what this person has done and built off
of it and creating this synergy of
knowledge and of information and of
tangible practices that we can do in our
own gardens in our own communities you
know and in our own countries is having
a massive residual effect and people
that are doing it are seeing the results
their healing their cancers their
healing their diabetes their you know
their their living you know they're told
they got six months to live in twelve
years later they're giving classes on
nutrition and soil health you know this
is the world that we live in so the
inspirations all around us you know
again thank you for what you do because
the the knowledge is there and it is a
battle it's a battle a lot of this work
has just been snuffed out by the power
of these big chemical companies by the
power of these big agricultural
universities land-grant universities
because anytime there's something for
someone to gain somebody else has
something to lose and when you follow
the money and you see what other people
have to lose and you say oh that doesn't
sound
possible what's not possible because
somebody spent millions and millions and
millions of dollars to convince farmers
you're right it isn't possible because
they stand to lose everything they have
absolutely well hot damn call like that
was that's fantastic I feel very
enthusiastic and and actually really
really pleased with how this show turned
out this information came together on a
really nice package and and most
importantly to me not only does it give
the compost basics but we really went
deep into it into like third and fourth
levels of analysis so thank you so much
for for not only sharing your time
because I know your time is very
valuable but thank you for sharing your
experience both with the compost but
with your ability to explain it in a way
that we can all grok it without science
degrees so thank you so much brother oh
absolutely such a pleasure to talk with
you and thank you again for you know
spreading the word on so many important
topics to so many people awesome man
thank you if you'd like to be in contact
with Colm Reilly you can reach him
through Malibu Malibu compost at Malibu
compost com you can also follow his
Instagram which is a lot of fun and
colum Riley and that's C o L um are i l
ey on instagram and then also be sure to
check out his great presentation at Indo
Expo in San Francisco in his entirety
for free on our youtube channel at
youtube ford slash Shango lowe's you can
find more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast and subscribe to the show at
shaping fire calm and on Apple iTunes
stitcher and Google Play if you enjoyed
the show we'd really appreciate it if
you'd leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too on the shaping
fire website you can also subscribe to
the weekly newsletter for insights into
the latest cannabis news and product
reviews on the shaping fire website you
will also find transcripts of today's
podcast as well for information on me
and where i'll be speaking you can check
out Shango lowes.com
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
feiyr.com to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host
Shango Lowe's
[Music]