[Music]
there are two aspects of teaching
cannabis medicine that stand out as
most challenging to me the first one is
that cannabis
educators and caregivers must do a lot
of personal work to be good at the job
a caregiver cannot be overreacting to
the challenges the patient is going
through
while also not making light of them a
good
caregiver is a difficult blend of stoic
educator and friend of last resort to
the patient
several times in the last decade i have
sat down with a terminally ill person
who has asked me how to use cannabis in
their last
days so they can be lucid saying goodbye
to their family
this is heavy duty humanity this is a
very serious conversation
that patient doesn't want my tears or
concerns for them most often
they want me to stick to business and
give them the information they require
give them good product recommendation
and be gone
it is a role of service and to do it
right it takes a lot of
self and situational awareness by the
caregiver
the second especially challenging aspect
is that cannabinopathic medicine keeps
changing
as the paucity of cannabis knowledge
we've had is replaced by
modern studies with more participants
and better analytics
we have to constantly update ourselves
on the latest understanding because that
understanding is constantly evolving
these days
if you are a doctor or caregiver who
found part one
of endocannabinoid mechanics and has now
returned for part two
thanks for your dedication to the
caregiver service role
the humans under your care will be all
the better for it
and if you are here for yourself as a
cannabis patient
like me know that this material is
presented to you so we can all learn and
grow and heal together
it is as simple as that if you want to
learn about cannabis health business and
technique efficiently and with good
cheer
i encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week
and videos too don't rely on social
media to let you know when a new episode
is published
sign up for the updates to make sure you
don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive that newsletter so
go to shapingfire.com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month's and all future newsletter prize
drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and
i'm your host shango los
today my guest is miyabi shields phd
dr shields is co-founder of real
isolates which
ironically focuses on the importance of
secondary plant components and
synergistic plans
so essentially whole plant medicine
miyabi received their phd in
pharmaceutical sciences focusing on the
biochemistry of the endocannabinoid
system
from northeastern university in 2018.
miyabi has authored or co-authored six
peer-reviewed publications and presently
has a patent under review
for a novel fungus and plant extraction
method
miyabi also has a substantial list of
honors and awards
including a 2016 international
cannabinoid research society
pre-doctoral research award their tick
tock channel
at miyabi phd has 130
000 followers and is where i first met
miyabi
today is part two of endocannabinoid
mechanics
and during the first set we'll talk
about how certain cannabinoids function
the second set is all about comparing
the various ways
we get cannabinoids into our bodies and
the third set
is about dosing thresholds for cannabis
efficacy for chronic and other serious
patients
welcome back to shaping fire miyabi hey
happy
to be here excellent me too i had really
enjoyed our first conversation and it
got a
really popular response people people
dug the quality and kind of information
that you share
so let's go ahead and and do some more
so
let's jump right into it people say
offhand
that taking thc a is a lot like taking
cbd and that makes sense to me in use
but like what does that really
mean at a chemistry level that statement
is too vague to really be useful to most
caregivers and patients
is it just that thc a
heals without the euphoria
of thc like cbd does or does it work on
similar receptors or perhaps still
something else
well you pretty much answered the
question yourself there with that one
yes so it's interesting i actually this
is so weird without my model
yeah in your hands yeah um but so thca
is the acid right it's the acid version
of
um thc which means that it has a extra
carboxylic acid group
um and carboxylic acid is a carbon
that's bonded to two oxygens and it's
really negatively charged and it's
pretty big
um so that changes the shape of the
molecule
and that change in shape affects like a
couple of things
the first thing it affects is the
ability for the molecule to get into the
brain
generally speaking the more charged
something is like
this in this case having a negative
charge um will decrease
its brain penetration so that's one way
in which they're different
the next way is how it binds to the
actual receptors
um there has been uh evidence that thca
does bind to like the cb1 and cb2
receptors but it's
far less than thc and really interesting
about people saying
qualitatively that it's similar to cbd
for me what's interesting about that is
that
both thca and cbd
activate or turn on the serotonin 5ht1a
receptor and that's actually the
receptor that's been linked
to the beneficial mental health effects
of cbd
in mouse model research so i think
you're right on the money there when you
say that thca
and cbd interact similarly
to serotonin receptors and that's why
people think that they
feel the same way that actually makes a
lot of sense in practice the fact that
the thc
a molecule hits the same receptors
though let more light more lightly than
cbd
because a lot of folks who well you know
at this point ever most people have got
access to cbd one way or another but
but you know a couple years ago pre cbd
being everywhere um people who only had
access to thc
through the um the heritage market
would just be able to go and and enjoy
uh und carbed flower
and it would give them the same kind of
you know anti-anxiety
and anti-depression benefits similar-ish
to cbd
and and people use it that way the other
thing that's interesting about thca is
it seems to be kind of universally give
people
serious munchies you know so it's very
very useful
for folks who have lost appetite let's
take this let's go one step deeper down
to this so let's talk about these other
novel cannabinoids the the acid forms
and and probably
the varan forms as more novel
minor cannabinoids are studied and bred
for
we're all going to get the opportunity
to learn and smoke the acid forms the
the unheated unaged forms of these
cannabinoids
and also their varying forms of thc and
cbd and the others
to most folks thc is the queen of course
and cbd is seriously helpful
but few folks understand the nature of
the acid and variant forms other than
knowing that thcv
tends to inhibit appetite and stops the
munchies
so i'm going to kind of hand this to you
in a basket
will you explain what the acid forms of
cannabinoids are
in relation to their non-acid versions
and then either during or after do that
same thing for the varins
so however you think it's going to be
explained more carefully the gist of the
question is
give us a better understanding what the
acid and variant forms of these
cannabinoids are
right so i mean the acid forms are it's
it's very
simple you just add a carboxylic acid to
the same position
um it's on the phenol or benzene
ring portion of the of the molecule
and it is like i said earlier it changes
the structure and the shape
and also you know the charge it's it's
called electronegativity but there's a
negative charge
on the acid versions of these and so
they display
very unique pharmacological profiles
meaning that
if you change the structure it will
change the receptors that it interacts
with it also
changes like i mentioned earlier about
like brain permeation like permeability
or the ability
uh for these molecules to get into the
brain um so it changes like the
distribution
of where these molecules end up
interacting in your body
um like it's there's been some pretty
interesting research done
i believe it's in australia on the acid
versions
of both thc cbd cbg
so you know thca cbda cbga and i think
cbd va
also um to mix up both the acid and the
variant form there
um there's been a lot of really
interesting research that's being done
on like anti-epileptic properties
specifically
um being linked to the these forms and
epilepsy shares
uh pathophysiology with a lot of other
um
a lot of other disorders that people use
cannabis for like migraines
cluster headaches um and so i think it's
gonna be really really interesting to
see
more research come out and also to see
more qualitative information come out
as people are able to you know
experiment
and see see what it what are the
therapeutic applications of it because i
definitely believe that there are unique
therapeutic applications for these rare
variations it's really interesting that
we're at this time where
patients are able to literally do
citizen science because
a prohibition for so long has has
stunted
scientific research and people who are
desperate for
relief you know take cannabinoids just
to say well all right they're safe
enough
let's just see what happens to them and
so we patients
stumble upon things and then we tell
people and we tell other they tell
people
next thing you know there's something
coming up from the underground that the
more formal scientific you know
community needs to
to you know jump on and get get evidence
to
um to back it up you know how you
describe the differences between the
acid forms and the regular forms
you know they're so different you know
how they access the brain or don't
access the brain is different
the receptors that they attach to are
different and it sounds like in
different amounts
it kind of gives me the idea that
we should not consider the acid forms to
even necessarily
be related in quality to
their their non-acid forms like cbda
doesn't necessarily act or do what cbd
does
thc a does not really act or
necessarily do what thc does and
it re it sounds like their their names
you know cannabidirol
for example that has more to do with
the the structure of the molecule
chemically and the the addition or
removal of this
acid component really makes it an
entirely different
cannabinoid than
you know it's more common non-acid
namesake
yeah i mean that structurally they're
very similar right
because the only difference is one
carbon two oxygens and then depending on
the ph there's a hydrogen there or not
um so like this like in structure
they're super similar
um and that's why they sit you know thc
and thca
cbg and cbga you know et cetera um so
they are very similar but in terms of
like small
yeah small changes in a molecule will
have
really really large changes in in
therapeutic effects profiles
so in terms of like considering them
different things like i would just like
say as an example
um you know in in the pharmaceutical
world as an example there are different
benzodiazepines they are
very similar um classes right but they
are all
slightly different structurally and
that's something that's kind of like the
same here where like
we have the cannabinoids but all the
rare cannabinoids are
similar but they do have slight
differences in structure
that can have really large overall
effects on like the therapeutic profile
right on so let's talk a little bit
about the varanz so
the varan's are of course you know
so hot right now because they're so hot
so hot because you know for for most of
us we all started with thc and then cbd
came out and kind of like rocked the
whole cannabis world
and then as people realized oh my gosh
if cbd
you know is such a big deal all these
other novel cannabinoids
uh we're all hungry for those now and to
learn about them and so we're diving
you know very you know diving deep into
them
and then you know the the varans
seem to be the ones that are going to be
hitting the scene next as these
as these seeds uh become available this
this coming summer
and really all i all i really know about
the varanz
is that um they are there there's not a
lot of them there have been
uh very few of them because they've been
bred out of cannabis more or less as
people
focused on breeding for thc and i am
told that thcv
is an appetite suppressant though i
haven't really had that experience
uh myself because i haven't had a varan
dominant thc varan dominant plant yet so
with all of that said what are you
unique to the varanz
so as they start coming on in the market
in the next year people have a little
bit of frame of mind
of what the hell people are even talking
about so the
the difference between the varians and
the parent molecule so like we're
talking about the parent
um molecule being thc or cbd for that
matter
those molecules have like if anyone
who's seen my videos i call them a fatty
tail i call it a fatty tail
those molecules have on the end of it a
five carbon
it's called a pentyl chain because
pencil for
five it has a 5-carbon chain at the end
of it
and that's just a really it's a fatty
tail it's just
a piece of the molecule that is very
sticky
sticky like butter greasy um and that
has a very unique like chemical property
that interacts with receptors um
the varins only have three carbons
instead of five
so they're shorter and there's a smaller
fatty tail so that changes the way that
it interacts with receptors
one of the things i think is really
interesting about
thcv specifically is its interaction
with
a receptor called trpv1 adolfo
are familiar it um stands for transient
receptor potential
vanilloid one it's not a very sexy name
for a receptor
um but it's it's a receptor that's an
ion channel that also interacts with the
endocannabinoid system
um and it's been shown to be important
for like pain management
anti-anti-inflammatory things and i
i'm wondering if it somehow is related
to its interaction with
trpv1 um that it causes this you know
this effect but i i haven't seen too
much
research on thcv yet i'm really excited
to see more of it
i think part of the reason why it's
difficult to study thcv is because it
falls underneath the
class of molecules that are regulated
since it's an analog
of thc um that is
at least why i think there's less on
thcv than say
cbd but i'm really excited to
to learn more about it i actually tried
um years ago i tried
like a i think it was a one to one to
one
micro doser like uh tab i think it was
called a tab lingual
was what it was called um and it was cbd
cbg and thcv if i remember correctly
um and it was very interesting but i
mean it you know that
it's there's a number of variables there
that i'm changing
um but it was a very interesting
experience i really enjoyed it
and i mean just the the pro the
therapeutic profile of it was completely
different
from thc when you're looking at the
molecular level for the varanz um
while we don't have a lot of research on
them yet for a host of reasons
do you as a chemist have you know
educated guesses on what you think the
veran's will do
or is it or are the are these
cannabinoids so different from each
other where you're all like
only god knows what's good the barons
are going to do after we test them
yeah i mean i guess i don't i guess i
don't know
necessarily like off the top of my head
what i would predict although i think
it's
interesting that so the shortening like
the shortening of that fatty tail
basically makes it structurally more
similar to
less fatty molecules of which there are
many in the body
um so i definitely think like without
without saying anything like for sure
that i definitely think that it has
unique pro like it has a unique profile
it probably has unique transport
around the body as well um and
i i know i would be really excited to
see it i mean i also think it's you know
this is just something that
um is difficult to think about when
we're talking about receptor receptor
pharmacology which is
you know how molecules interact with
receptors
um when we look at these things and we
test them we're testing one thing at a
time
and we're often looking at something for
a very specific reason
you know many of the rare cannabinoids
have not been tested against some of the
more classic
system um targets right like dopamine or
opioid or serotonin some of them have
and there's definitely some information
out there
um but usually when we discover a rare
cannabinoid or we find something that's
structurally related to the cannabinoids
obviously the first thing you think is
to test them on the endocannabinoid
system
uh but it's just you know anyways just
research tends to get
categorized if i'm i'm trying to phrase
this correctly
um like the based on the grant funding
structure of of research
and how research is is funded um you end
up like having categories of research
where labs will
hyper-specialize in something because
you need to that's what you have to do
to get the funding to
do your research and do the papers so i
think that i mean i think as
as we expand beyond that and start
looking at crosstalk between systems
and and interactions like on on larger
scales which is starting to happen
already we're going to find some really
interesting
interactions between all of these alone
and then there's a whole nother level
when we start talking about putting them
together
yeah the the the crosstalk between the
systems is something that is huge and uh
honestly i have to give you credit
you're the one who taught me or or
turned me up
turned me on to start thinking about it
and also that is
potentially an entirely uh additional
show so
yeah don't don't get me started on the
crosstalk of endocannabinoid system with
others
right on well let's hold that aside and
we'll approach that another day
so so um let's talk about the feeling
that cannabinoids uh give us um we've we
talked a lot and
in part one about the the mechanics and
how the receptors work
and how um you know the cannabinoids can
block block each other from the
receptors
and we talked a lot about that mechanics
but but
you know that you know that sigh of
relief that folks get from a cocktail
at the end of a work day like when the
alcohol hits the bloodstream you can
feel your body
shift down a few gears and you go like
and then like everything feels a little
bit easier right
that also happens similarly
but but kind of different with cannabis
as well right we
you know for those of us who prefer
cannabis we'll we'll have a bit
and then it hits our bloodstream and it
comes on and we have like that similar
sigh
and we're kind of like you know
depending on the kind of canvas it is
where you're floating or in the zone
but whatever it is we can feel that
downshift from the intensity
of production mode right whether that's
like being at work or
or you know watching the kids or you
know whatever we happen to be doing
it shifts us down into some sort of
ease mindset what is
happening then right and and if it helps
to say what's happening with
with alcohol and then compare that to
to cannabis i'm all for that but but
there's something very specific
mechanically that happens in that moment
when when the first of the cannabinoids
hit the hit the bloodstream after work
and we shift down into not work
and i'm i think we're all curious what
what that is
so i'm gonna answer this ques we're
gonna get really abstract here i'm gonna
i'm gonna answer this question with
something
um an answer that is pretty much
something that can't be proven
but that is also absolutely true okay um
which is that everything in the brain is
subjective to contrast
um and in my opinion what we're
describing here is the shift
in your perception right it's this
contrast and that and how that initial
shift
like the first like the first hit right
versus like the second third fourth or
like what you were describing the first
drink at the end of the day right
um is that that initial change that
very first alteration in your perception
will always feel different than the
continuation of an altered state
um and that's just because everything
that we interpret in our brains
is is relative to what has happened
before i mean this that's also just true
like
in life and everything in general right
like every single thing that our
brain has is built upon a contrast of
the things that it's already experienced
and our brains are very used to um what
is the
way i want to describe this our our
brains are very used to getting into
like a status quo
um you know keeping everything the same
and then when you cause like a dramatic
shift in that
that initial shift it's like you know
when you're on a hot it's like it's a
hot day like
it's been really hot here recently and
you're in the air conditioning and then
you take your first step outside and
you're like whoa it is hot and humid
out here like and it's almost like when
you step outside for the first time or
vice versa in the winter you're in the
heat and you go out and it's cold
and you almost like can't breathe for a
second because you're like wow that
change in temperature was
dramatic like that was a dramatic change
um and then
you're you're out there for less than 30
seconds or a minute and you're more used
to it
it's something more similar to that
except in
your processing of your brain and in
that status right
um because absolutely like the
cannabinoids have
anxiolytic effects right like they in
general they can they're relaxing
um and that's true all the time but in
that initial
that first initial phase of changing
your
like altering your pharmacology and your
brain um
that initial change will feel different
and i think that that has to do with the
fact that it's in contrast
to what you were like before yeah that
that makes a lot of sense and you know
that that plays out with how
we experience it as a human too because
on on our harder days sigh of relief
seems to be more intense right if you've
had absolutely
yeah if you if you have a light day and
you come home and you puff you're like
ah today was a pretty good day oh my my
my cannabis is pretty good too i'm gonna
have a good evening right it's kind of
like
like a uniform but if you've had you
know a really
challenging day that has pushed and
pulled you emotionally
and you get to the end of the day and it
hits your bloodstream you're like oh my
god
my favorite thing thank god you know and
that makes sense the contrast aspect to
it
you also mentioned the anti-anxiety
um aspects of it um would you hit that
on a molecular level like what what is
actually happening
to kick off that uh did you call it an
anxiolytic yeah anxiolytic
so this is a kind of a honestly this is
kind of a complicated one to explain
because
the cb1 receptor so thc activates the
cb1 receptor
that receptor has been associated with
decreasing anxiety or having an
anxiolytic effect at like lower
concentrations
it's also possible that it causes
anxiety so there's this whole like
very delicate balance going on um with
why this happens but in in general
um at least at low concentrations
activating the cb1 receptor is
responsible
for reducing some types of anxiety
um it's not really i'm trying to think
of like in terms of like
research that's been done um most of the
most of their research has been an
animal models although some of it
has been like repeated in humans and it
seems like
um it's called a biphasic effect it
seems like at a high
concentration there's a second threshold
that you'll reach
where all of a sudden it reverses and it
causes anxiety or it causes paranoia
right
and one thing i've been really
passionate about educating people about
is that
our our thresholds are different every
one of us will have a different
you know threshold for that second level
of that effect
so for some people they might never get
anxiety right
and others it might be a side effect
that it's you know it's very easy for
them to to come across
i would be in that second category and i
got to tell you it's made me very aware
of you know in in the scene people talk
about puff and tough right
you know it's like like you know how
have more
finish the joint have another hit you
know we we
part of cannabis is definitely
you know there's pressure to always use
more right and um
and i find that i think that that really
stems from a lack of understanding by
most folks that
of this biphasic effect where you know
if you have a bit
you have the decrease of anxiety and the
increase of euphoria
and and your joy increases that's that's
wonderful
but where that that tapers off and and
becomes
anxiety causing is different for every
person and i for myself i know that
you know i can smoke a certain amount
and it'll put me right where i want to
be
but if i go beyond that i can feel
i actually don't know what i feel i feel
i mean i think about it as
my my adrenaline turns on that's that's
how i
explain it i'm like oh you're your
flight your fight or flight okay so good
right well i'm not that far off so so
i'll have that little bit more and i'll
just like feel it turn on
like like you would feel an air
conditioner in your hvac come on i was
like oh air conditioner camera or oh
first time the heater came on for the
fall you know you can feel the house
rumbling well the same thing
i will smoke a bit and i'll have a great
time and then i'll and then i'll smoke a
bunch
and i'll feel the adrenaline kick on and
you know i've been smoking for so long
now that i'm like oh okay
time to go outside for a walk time to
step out outside of the party
time to you know like whatever to do a
little bit of self-care
and check in on my set and setting so
that i don't get
upset however we do have to be aware
that we all have got a different
threshold for that and
some people may never hit the anxiety
causing part
and then there are other people like me
who it my body tends to kick it in
pretty low
so you know i know that i need to check
myself earlier i run into this actually
at conventions a lot right where people
are outside and everybody's puffing and
trying each other's stuff and everybody
wants me to try their stuff because
they're proud of it and i want to
celebrate how great their their grow is
but at the same time i'm like if i do
that
a few times in a row suddenly i'm so
anxious i can't go back into the
convention right
so so we will use you know will you
speak to that aspect of it about
um you know like what happens
mechanically if you will
when we when we hit our biphasic
threshold
well absolutely so i'm also i am right
there with you i'm a total lightweight
um specifically when it comes to anxiety
and
paranoia um and i mean i'm at the point
now where like i actually don't usually
smoke anything
from anyone else because i mix things
very specifically for me and other
people are welcome to smoke with me like
i
would love to smoke i'd love to smoke
you out at some point like we got to do
that
but but uh you know i'm
very sensitive um and it's been one of
my passions to understand
this biphasic effect and it has to do
with what's called endocannabinoid tone
and i know we discussed this a little
bit on the previous
um the previous talk and we were talking
about dr russo's
clinical endocannabinoid deficiency but
it
in general endocannabinoid tone
describes the levels of circulating
endocannabinoids in your body and then
also the levels of the receptors the cb1
cb2 receptors probably also trpv1 and
some of the gprs
these things are all different for each
of us this is also a way of just
it's one way of describing
neurodiversity for those of you who are
familiar with neurodiversity
neurodiversity is describes just
differences
in the way that our brains can all
process and have information
um and we are all like we are all very
similar
in the way that our brains process
information and then we are all very
very different and one of those ways
has to do with endocannabinoid signaling
and the actual levels of
endocannabinoids
um so in terms of being really really
sensitive
it means that for for both you and i
when it comes to like anxiety or
or paranoia there is probably that we
have
an increased level of cb1 receptors in a
very specific part of our brain
that maybe people who do not have a high
threshold of that
have lower levels of cb1 receptors and
are not as sensitive to that
it's also why to a certain extent if you
develop levels of tolerance
sometimes certain side effects will go
away because
tolerance is usually it's associated
with a decrease in the number of cb1
receptors
so some people when they develop
tolerance will realize that like certain
effects go away i mean generally when
you develop tolerance
you know all of the effects go away
without using more but
for it's usually like certain effects
one at a time right like some of them go
away first
um and that has to do with changing the
levels of cb1 receptors in very specific
areas
right on so before we move on i think i
want to just make a very intentional
plug i mean we made the case very
obvious for folks but
if you are a listener and you have
um you know a low biphasic threshold for
anxiety so you you puff a little
and you get your no your anxiety
decreased
and then you puff more and your anxiety
increases my friend do not let people
bully you
into taking more thc really not
and if you are one of these people who
have got a very high threshold for this
and
let's say that you're you know you're
dabbing and you can puff with everybody
and you can puff all night
please do not bully those of us who uh
have got a lower biphasic threshold
into smoking with you for sure offer it
to us but please don't bully people into
it
because it really is different for folks
and if you are
if you care for that person enough that
you want to get them high
also be you know have enough care for
them to
let them tell you that you know they've
had enough because we don't want to
you know you don't want to make your
friend anxious so so anyway
uh i'll get off my soapbox on that one
but i absolutely agree with that because
all of us are trying to just have a good
time right like everyone
we're all trying to increase quality of
life essentially
and i think that's going to be that's
going to be different for all of us and
i think it's important to know and also
as another psi i would love
for people to start regularly saying
like oh yeah my biphasic threshold for
thc
i would love to make that a regular
thing it's actually thc is biphasic for
a number
of effects it's not just anxiety um so
it's true that each of us has very
specific side effects that we're you
know prone to i'm also prone to getting
very cold
are you prone to that django um i'm not
actually um i'm familiar i'm familiar
with it i actually get cold
from um allergy medications how
interesting my extremities specifically
i get like cold
fingers and stuff huh histamine
receptors
yeah interesting um all right so so
let's hit one more question on this on
this tolerance and cannabinoids thing
before we go to the break so
so you know we talked about like the the
having that end of
day toke and how it shifts us down
and decreases our anxiety and
um you know anybody who's told and who
really appreciates that aspect has
probably also come home
and have a toke and nothing happens
and and you talk and you're like you
know something's not
working and you know depending on the
person they might blame the flower
or they might say that oh it's my
tolerance
but but you know as somebody who studies
this in the lab
what are your thoughts on what are the
most common i mean
do you think it's more often than not
like a tolerance response or
are there also just some days that we're
not gonna get high
because of the chemical blend in our
brain that day
so so i think that there's a number i
mean tolerance definitely
may play a part in it but i've always i
mean set in setting which is usually
talked about in psychedelics right
usually that's a more common
um it's a more common thing that people
talk about in psychedelics i
really feel like the endocannabinoid
system and serotonin system
share an extremely strong synergy i
consider cannabis a soft psychedelic
um there are certainly near psychedelic
experiences or
i would even i would classify them as
psychedelic experiences that i've had on
cannabis
um i think that set and setting are
really important
and i think that we don't often you know
we don't often think about
so set being like the mindset that
you're going into and then setting being
the environment sometimes your
environment can be like
you're like the stress levels of the day
and what you're planning
what you are planning or anticipating on
doing um all of these things play a role
in your neurochemistry and i definitely
feel like alterations in your
neurochemistry
will affect the way that you know
molecules feel when you take them
and it's not always going to be the same
and i
i know that like what we're looking for
is for something to always be
exactly the same effect but even with i
mean everyone if we're going to make the
the same um metaphor with alcohol
it's the same way you know sometimes
it's
it's a generally generally speaking you
have a effect right
but sometimes you have a really great
night and then other times like you're
sad and you cry
you're angry yeah that's a really good
example you're right about that i hadn't
made that connection before
yeah but it's pretty similar right
because your brain so
the way that our our brains sort of like
function and perceive the the world is
always in response our brain is always
changing like we are always
in flux we're always going our brains
always responding to something and it's
always
changing so like right now you and i
having this conversation
our brain is in a transition from what
it was
two minutes ago to what it's going to be
two minutes from now what it was
yesterday to what it's going to be
tomorrow
what it was last month to what it's
going to be next month
etc there are changes that are going on
on every scale of time
in the brain all the time and so that
will
be different depending on a number of
factors and like you brought up
having stress having a really bad day be
you know feeling really negative
um that will alter your neurochemistry
it's been shown and proven that when
you're happy
right like you actually see more your
your vision is clearer
and you notice more things um i won't
get too deep into positive psychology
because that's like a whole nother
that's a whole nother rabbit hole that
along with crosstalk that we could go on
to for forever but
i am a very big believer in positive
psychology
i think that there are subconscious
things that we cannot change and that we
can't alter
but i also believe that there are
conscious things that we can change
in our minds and that we can really
focus on and behaviorally modify in
ourselves
that has an impact on our neurochemistry
um whether or not these things can be
measured at this exact moment like
i i couldn't tell you but i
know for a fact that set and setting in
the way that we
approach like an experience really
changes
the outcome of the experience i mean
that that's part of why cannabis has
such a high placebo effect right
um is the expectation and what we are
like wanting to receive from the
experience having a having a big impact
i love the idea that some positive
soft talk some some you know thoughts in
your brain or some mumbling to yourself
about you know self-care and self-love
and you know being worthy could actually
make our high better i think i think
that's a beautiful thing and i think
that we should make that
the uh the custom oh i
i i absolutely feel like that's you know
that's true that's why meditation goes
so hand in hand
right now cannabis and other and other
psychedelics right like
awareness fantastic all right viaby
we're gonna go ahead and take our short
break and be right back
you are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is cannabinoid
pharmacologist miyabi shields phd
[Music]
for years organic cultivators have been
looking for a replacement for using peat
moss
peat moss has long been the go-to soil
amendment for water retention and
container growing
but organic growers know that peat moss
is an unsustainable resource
and the mining of peat bogs destroys
habitat and releases sequestered carbon
but peat moss works so well that many
have continued to use it
but now there's finally a revolutionary
replacement for peat moss that shares
the same benefits
while also being sustainable pit moss
sounds and axe like peat moss but
instead of being mined from fragile
ecosystems
it actually is made from upcycled
organic paper and tree bark
pit moss is excellent at retaining water
in your substrate and creating air
pockets and
tiny living environments for microbes
pit moss
instantly increases aeration nutrient
absorption
and water conservation too carefully and
locally sourced
pit moss is the result of decades-long
research into the use of recycled paper
fibers
pit moss has the fluffy nature of peat
moss and handles exactly the same
and like peat moss pit moss is inert so
it won't change your ph
available in a range of preparations
including a nutrient enhanced blend
a coco coir blend and also as an organic
soil conditioner with no added nutrients
pitt moss is also available as an animal
bedding
so go to pittmoss.com now to learn more
that's p i t t m o
s s dot com growing healthier
more sustainable plants pittmoss
while i love growing under the sun
there's a lot of good reasons to grow
indoors
and if you're like most folks you want a
lighting source that grows high yielding
healthy plants without using excessive
amounts of electricity
bios lighting creates biological
lighting solutions
that brings the natural brilliance of
the outdoors into your grow room
bios lighting has the attributes that i
look for in a horticultural lighting
solution
i've bought those cheap lights online
and they're difficult to work with and
fail in no time in contrast my bios led
light is industrial grade to last a long
time
it is ip66 wet rated so little foliar
overspray won't harm it
it is easy to clean without taking it
down and of course the most important
aspect
is built for the exact light spectrum i
want for great yielding healthy cannabis
plants
and it doesn't hurt that their lighting
rigs look badass too
many horticultural led lighting systems
are based on irrelevant performance
metrics and people love to argue online
about these numbers
i prefer to judge on par photon
efficiency and how happy my plants are
and the bios lights exceed my
expectations in these categories
bios lights have an optimized broad
spectrum that
maximizes photosynthesis and plant
growth while also providing the ideal
conditions
for superior par efficacy and a
comfortable visual experience
i also love their attentive and
over-educated customer service folks
bios starts with a team of biologists
before getting the electrical engineers
involved
they have studied how light impacts
cannabis plants and devised an overall
strategy that works
i encourage you to check out their
website at bioslighting.com
to learn more about how this strategy
can work for you
and shaping fire listeners can get a
special deal use the discount code
shaping fire all one word no caps for 10
off your entire purchase that's
biosliding.com
[Music]
for 20 years humboldt seed company has
been family owned and providing reliable
high yielding seeds originating in
northern california
while the current trend is to slap one
super male into a line of hyped
strains humboldt seed company continues
to breed with precision and care
by doing large sifts and back crosses to
emphasize the absolute best traits that
a line has to offer
this kind of breeding takes time talent
and space to work
no matter what kind of aroma you are
particularly into
humboldt seed will likely have something
you'll love if you love fruit
you can choose from banana mango apricot
papaya blueberry blood orange melon and
lemons across their various strains
they have all gas glue and classic sour
diesel lines as well
of course there are the heritage
california strains like og
kush jack hair and headband and their
award-winning blueberry muffin is one
that delights just about everybody's
palate
especially when concentrated humboldt
seed company is proud to bring to market
the infamous freak show cultivar 2
which has a great thc high but looks so
much like a fern that some folks can't
even identify it as cannabis
it's a plant that really needs to be
seen to be believed
if you're looking for well-balanced cbd
seeds humboldt seed company can turn you
to cbd strains that actually have flavor
like the dill and pepper terpenes of
willy g's lebanese land race
whether you are looking for regular
feminized or autoflowers
humboldt seed company has the gear to
make this your best
growing cycle ever visit
humboldtseedcompany.com today
to check out their line of vigorous
genetics download their catalog
and find out where you can pick them up
you can also check out their instagram
at the humboldt seed company to check
out their gorgeous flowers
and the extraordinary freak show plant
humboldt seed company
let them know shango sent you welcome
back you are listening to shaping fire i
am your
host shango los and our guest this week
is cannabinoid pharmacologist
miyabi shields phd so miyabi we've
talked about
these different um methods of
bringing the cabin cannabinoids into our
body but anybody
who has spent a lot of time with
cannabis and has
you know smoked and had edibles and
maybe try to sublingual
they know that they all hit different
and and when i say
hit different i mean that they come on
at a different rate
and they feel different in the body
and often they will have different
medicinal effects depending on
how we ingest them
so would you please explain the
differences in how our body
absorbs the cannabinoids that method of
action
and then the differences chemically so
we as
patients can use the best mode
for our desired relief yeah
absolutely so i'm gonna hit the first
two
the two largest and most significant
routes of administration
which is edibles which is an oral
administration or smoking
um so with edibles there's well there's
three differences in the two routes the
first one is
like the actual absorption right um so
that means when when and where do the
molecules
enter your body and how are those
molecules entering your
entering your body when you smoke all of
the cannabinoids are absorbed in the
lungs
they get from the lungs into the blood
and go to the brain
directly and it happens all at once i
mean it happens in like
less than a second that isn't there also
just for every also a psa like don't
hold in your hits like it happens really
really quickly you don't have to like
don't hold your breath like that's no
don't do that and let's
since we're going to hit that and let's
also reference
uh from the robert littman episode all
on cannabis and breathing
that not only is it not necessary to get
your cannabinoids out as miyabi is
saying
but the longer you hit your hit the more
damage you are causing your lungs and
your cilia
from having the hot heat in your lungs
and like smoke particulates and other
things that will come over
the longer you're holding your breath so
definitely yeah no holding of breath
it happened anyways it happens really
quickly so all of the cannabinoids get
absorbed like let's say within one
second of each other
all of them go to the brain and then
have their effect that's why
um usually it's like 10 minutes right
there's like a 10 minute onset between
the blood
going from your lungs your heart pumps
it up to your brain really really quick
um with edibles you eat them they go
through your stomach
and then they're absorbed in the small
intestine they actually have to pass
through the liver
first before then your your body pumps
them all the way through and then it
gets to your brain
um so in terms of absorption it takes a
really long time i mean it could take
anywhere between like 30 minutes to
sometimes like three hours i've heard
people say that like
an edible has hit them like four to six
hours later
it also depends a lot on like what
you've eaten that day what does your
diet look like
do you have any gi issues or gi motility
issues that you struggle with right um
so these things can all alter like the
length of time and that's has to do with
absorption um that's the first thing is
absorption the second difference is
metabolism
so in the smoking example when you're
smoking it in the lungs it goes straight
to the brain
there is no metabolism between that
between that stage between it going from
your lungs to your brain
there's no metabolism so it's thc
and they in terms of like getting
metabolized or deactivated it also
happens all at once which is kind of why
smoking hap like has a very short
duration of action
um that's because as um
as the smoke is like after it goes to
your brain then it goes to your liver
and it all gets metabolized
um as opposed to edibles they get
metabolized first
so when you eat an edible gets absorbed
in the small intestine goes through the
liver and gets metabolized
most of us make 11 hydroxy as the
primary
metabolite which is more potent and has
stronger effects um i think there's so
there's another metabolite it's a
carboxy version of it
that is inactive i do think that a
significant portion of people who cannot
feel edibles
create that metabolite i would love for
someone to study that
um because there is a significant
portion of the population that can't
feel edibles that's like a whole
other topic um but for those of us who
can feel edibles your
your body metabolizes thc into 11
hydroxy
that is actually the molecule that will
go into your brain
and cause effects which is part of the
reason why edibles feel different
and then like i said earlier about the
absorption happening more slowly over
time
that means that 11 hydroxy is present
more slowly over time it'll last much
longer that's another reason why the
duration of action
is longer before it gets deactivated
and then the third difference which
people don't usually talk about
is um transformation at high
temperatures
so cannabinoids are pretty sensitive
molecules
and when you heat them to temperatures
that are above say like 300 degrees
fahrenheit you know
you're causing a significant change in
in molecular structure for a significant
portion
of of the cannabinoids that are present
uh for example like i think at 300
degrees fahrenheit
uh studies done on thc it was about 30
of the thc converts
into cbn or cannabinol uh that's a
dehydration reaction
so basically um two hydrogens are
removed
from um is it two
there's there's two extra double bonds
in the in the top ring
um and it changes the actual formulation
and actually this is like my main this
is my main research focus so i
maybe maybe stop because i'll go on
forever and ever about this one
but um basically if you're smoking and
you're using a lighter
a lighter can reach temperatures well
above a thousand degrees
fahrenheit right if even if you're
smoking a j right or like spliff or
something
you have an ember the actual that's a
whole different
chemistry because the actual area of the
ember is a different temperature than
the area right above it
and so there's this i mean joints are
very complicated which i i also love
um but you get this this very high
temperature
transformation and a significant amount
of the cannabinoids are transformed so
you get a different formulation and
that's the third
the third difference because most
edibles are made to preserve
thc or more recently also now cbd
and that is part of the reason why
smoking feels so different is because it
is actually a completely different
formulation of cannabinoids all right
that idea that um
the the lighter can change the
cannabinoids that in
itself is like a huge thing that i put
into my notes
that we should talk about later because
we could we could do the rest of the
show on that but let's
let's hold that aside for a moment and
focus on
on first the um the
the two different forms of
thc or or cannabinoids that can come
out of the liver um you said we could
you know that's a whole new path but
let's
let's hit that path so so there are you
know
there are patients that talk to me
regularly who
who are concerned slash annoyed
that they eat edibles and nothing
happens to them
or they can you know they can eat a
hundred milligram
uh thc rich
edible and like get a little high and
and they're both frustrated because it's
much more expensive for them and if and
if they are a patient who needs edibles
then they're in a very difficult
position and and and you said that
when the cannabinoid goes through the
liver it
it'll break into 11 hydroxy or or a
second one that i that i actually miss
the name of
so are you suggesting that that
each human has got their own ratio of
thc into the liver and then coming
out is this different percentage between
these
the 11 hydroxy and the secondary one
and and if it's less 11 hydroxy
you may have to eat a whole lot more
edible in order to get the results and
the relief that you're looking for
yeah this is actually a problem that
this is a problem that i brought up
um to other scientists a couple weeks
ago at an international conference for
like cannabis science and like
no one had had heard of this phenomenon
i would not be aware of this phenomenon
if it wasn't for
tick-tock actually i'd never heard of it
before
i think that there are three possible
there are like there are some
possibilities for why this happens to
people
um and i and none of these have been
proven yet um but they are just all
theory right the first one is like a
problem with absorption
there's some sort of problem where the
thc doesn't really get absorbed at all
um i do not think this is a this is a
likely problem because of
like how thc is it's such a fat soluble
molecule
it comes over membranes really really
easily so i don't think that that's a
possible like i don't think that's
like the possibility for most people but
it's it's an option right some people
might have
an altered microbiome for example or
differences in absorption and then they
just are are not actually absorbing
the the thc in the small intestine um
the next two pro the next two
possibilities have to do with metabolism
so
there are two phases of metabolism uh
phase one
was the one i was talking about with
hydrox the
the the formation of 11 hydroxy phase
one is normally just oxidation
so you add an oxygen and the other
option was a carboxy i don't want to
name the whole name because it's just
like numbers and
not fun but the second version of it is
a carboxy which is just a carboxylic
acid
instead of a hydroxyl group which is
just another it's basically one extra
oxygen
um similar to what i was talking to
about uh thca right a carboxylic acid
versus thc in this case though um
the our bodies add the carboxylic acid
to the 11 position which is right at the
top
of the molecule um that one is it so
that carboxy metabolite is inactive
and the determining factor of which one
of those molecules our body makes has to
do with our our metabolic
enzymes in our bodies like so our body
is absorbing
uh the thc goes to the liver in the
liver
there are enzymes present and those
enzymes determine
what happens to that molecule um maybe
it's a mutation in the enzyme maybe
it's a variation in the the levels
of these different enzymes that are that
are present right
but it's possible that for the people
who can't feel edibles their body is not
making 11 hydroxy it's only making this
inactive version
so they're taking they're eating the
edible the thc goes in and then your
body turns it into something inactive
that's not to say that that metabolite
doesn't have any effects i
i haven't seen a lot of research on it
honestly so it could be doing something
but it's not having the psychoactive
intoxicating effects
um because it's it's not active right
and then the the other option has to do
with phase two metabolism
which is the second phase uh what our
body does is it takes
the molecule and it adds a a sugar acid
like a glucose
molecule it's called glucuronidation
and that inactivates the molecule as
well if you think about it it just takes
a sugar molecule you snap the sugar
molecule on it boom the thing is turned
off
it's inactive so there's an another
option which is that people might have a
very very fast phase two metabolism
so perhaps someone that's taking an
edible
for specifically for thc they can't feel
it because
they take the edible their body does
phase one metabolism but then it
immediately does phase two and then
everything is inactive
wow um i would love to
see research on this um and also
there is the option that there's
tolerance right like there's there's
some option there that
you know some people who are really
heavy cannabis users develop a tolerance
and then
you know you don't you don't see these
marked effects with edibles although i
have seen people say they've taken
hundreds and hundreds of milligrams and
so
that just doesn't add up when you take
into account that these people also
probably
smoke flour and can feel a hundred
milligrams of thc
right yeah totally if they smoked it
they would they would get hit upside
yeah
exactly so i mean it just it just
doesn't that doesn't match up to me that
it means to me that there's a problem
with like absorption or metabolism and
actually
this is something i'm collaborating with
another pharmaceutical scientist on
to like establish like how how
prevalent it is um in the population and
her name is riley she's also a
pharmaceutical scientist and riley and i
used tik-tok actually to pull how many
people could feel that it's a
significant population
of people who can't feel them um and i
think it's something
worth worth looking into to figure out
at least at least why
all right so then let's thread the
needle so if we've talked about
um smoking on one side being
fast and heavy hitting and then we've
hit on
edibles which are significantly slower
but can be stronger and more
i don't know time released longer acting
what about sublinguals because you're
not smoking it it goes in the mouth
but it also doesn't go through the gut
it goes through your
your you know your mucosal membranes
excuse me um so so what what is that
intake like chemically
okay so when we're talking about
sublinguals like are we talking about
like tinctures that you put under your
tinctures that you or or a sublingual
spray or
normally it is a cannabis oil that has
got a little bit of residual
um ethanol in it so that when it hits
your
your mucosal membranes or just like the
the the tissue in your mouth
the um the the residual ethanol takes
the uh the whole plant medicine over or
through the tissue
yeah so like i don't know if something
is wrong with my mouth
but i have never been able to feel
sublinguals successfully so i'll just
talk about it in theory
um in theory when you absorb something
either sublingual or subbuckle which is
like a cheek
there are some cheek swabby products
that i've seen
before on the on the market so both of
those methods of action
should bypass first pass metabolism they
should be really quick
similar to smoking in the lungs um
and be i guess have comparable
advantages
uh as smoking um no transformation
obviously because there's no heat
um but you know just like personally
anecdotally i haven't like had tons of
success with that and then also
if we are talking about a tincture and
you put it under your tongue and then
eventually you do swallow it
that then becomes inedible like whatever
is left
that that didn't yeah that that that's
true you know they're they're the the
the street wisdom on this at any way
is that there's there's a small amount
of fluid in a tick in a tincture
normally
and you put it underneath your tongue
and you know you might hold it you might
not depending on
on what the tincture is made out of it
may burn
too much to hold it there but whatever
you you put it in your mouth
you swish it around a little bit and you
swallow it and
when i talk to folks anecdotally folks
believe
that the thc is absorbed in their mouth
and then
if they swallow it you know they're it's
it's a long road
from the mouth to the gut and it's going
you know through the throat and the
esophagus and all this kind of stuff
on their way down and that the rest of
it is actually
soaked in on the way down in in before
it gets to
the intestines and therefore it
never becomes an edible how does that
hit for you
um i don't agree with that right on it's
fine it's fine
for people to think that though i don't
i don't have any proof that that doesn't
happen
but i i think it becomes inedible that's
my my personal opinion is whatever
doesn't get absorbed
in the mouth then when you swallow it
maybe there is like trace absorption in
like the esophagus or the
uh the stomach but in like in general
the small intestine is what's built to
absorb
like exogenous like in general the small
intestine is where our body like absorbs
all like when you eat food there is it's
like very dissimilar there is some
sublingual absorption then when you eat
it like
very i would say like i don't know the
statistics on this i'm not a gi person
but i think most of the absorption
happens in the small intestine
yeah yet another thing we've hit on
today that needs more study
yeah i mean i i don't know what's wrong
with my mouth
i can't i can't feel i cannot feel
sublinguals
ever pretty much with i i don't know i
feel them like an edible like way later
you know all right so
let's let's move on to um the ever
popular method of suppositories and you
know even those suppositories get a
little bit of a giggle because we're you
know we're popping something into our
rectum
um there are a lot of patients that i
have worked with
that um you know it when they discover
this they they literally cry with relief
and joy
because um either they have got severe
stomach
problems and they have a hard time
eating anything
or b um they have
a um you know they've got an issue in
the liver
where they are not making the 11 hydroxy
so they're not feeling anything and for
whatever reason they can't smoke
or they're cancer patients and they're
trying to
you know take in absurd amounts of
of cannabinoids all at once and
and you know taking it orally
gets them super duper high and so they
introduce them
the cannabinoids to their body as a
suppository
um so there is absolutely a
need for it and and honestly some people
just say that they like the high better
i mean i've definitely run into
folks who are using their cannabis
recreationally
as a suppository and you know that's
pretty darn rare
but you know people are into all sorts
of stuff um
so so let's talk about it so you know
the as as i understand it
the the suppository will will break down
and then the cannabinoids
are absorbed by the tissue along the
walls of the rectum but i really don't
understand
what the chemistry is beyond that point
so i believe that suppository is also
bypass first pass metabolism which means
that it's interesting that you mentioned
that the high is different
from suppositories um because that
indicates that there is
like a difference in the metabolism or
the absorb like well not the absorption
but the metabolism
well also the location of absorption um
you know
so that there's no metabolism which
means that it's not 11 hydroxy right so
it gets absorbed and then it goes to the
brain
um i believe it's also faster because it
doesn't have to go all the way through
your stomach to your you know your um
small intestine and through the liver
and get metabolized
um you know i think it's like in terms
of like stigmatization and talking about
things that have to do with like our
private parts
like you know this is a really important
method that i think is very valuable for
the reasons that you've
mentioned like people who have severe
nausea it's also really i've heard that
it's been i'm i'm assigned female at
birth and i have a menstrual cycle
and i have heard that suppositories are
really really useful for people who have
pmdd
or who have other sorts of like hormonal
or like painful
um painful issues like endometriosis or
cysts and i've actually heard
qualitatively from
from quite a few people actually i've
i'm gonna blank on her name but there's
a there is a
research scientist who's looking into
this um specifically
and i think that in terms of like method
and and options i think i would just
describe it as like a very
like a very very useful option a very
very useful therapeutic method
that has definitely deserves its place
amongst like
cannabis products and i actually you
know when i see them and they sell out
here like crazy like i actually
haven't been able to get my hands on one
ever they sell out like immediately
yeah demand is really high and you know
a lot of people go through a lot of
effort
online to make um you know fancy ones
with like
shea butter and coconut oil and they put
them in
um you know little little formed ice
trays and
and put them in the freezer so they
harden and you know it's always a little
giggle when you
when you know when you when you when you
put it there because of it being cold
but
i know enough patients who
do this you know a couple times a day
where they just don't even bother
making the the the proper shea
buttery coconut suppository and they
just take a
um cellulose capsule put the rso in
there
and then apply it because the
the fluid that is in the rectum is
plenty to break down a cellulose capsule
and and and there you go so you know you
can be fancy and gentle
or you can just like get her done and
and you know and as we know
really sick people they usually just go
for the get or done
option yeah absolutely and i mean in
terms of like not
needing to well that's that's it that's
fascinating i never thought about the
do-it-yourself method for that i always
thought there was some sort of fancy
contraption
like an applicator i don't know well i
mean i mean i mean there are there i
mean you know the pharmaceutical
industry they can make everything more
complex right
right i'm sure i'm sure there will be
i'm sure there will be i'm sure there's
something about that
you know one thing that you said that
really stands out for me is that um
you know you said that since a
suppository would
skip the the level one
uh uh in the in the
liver and so the 11 hydroxy is not being
made
a suppository would be the only
non-smoking option that actually
delivers thc
the brain unchanged in
in theory sublingual too right but oh
yeah that's true too
right yeah in theory and then and then i
know and then i know yeah in theory for
me
other people with normal mouths that
happens
um i know also that there's been a lot
of research into transdermal
applications but to my knowledge um no
one has been able to crack the
transdermal
situation where it actually enters the
bloodstream so like so so far to my
knowledge like transdermal which i love
topicals also like
i think they definitely have therapeutic
validity but they don't enter the
bloodstream right it's like a very high
local concentration
hmm all right well that would be that
that well all right let's let's
let's go for it so so all right so let's
talk about that
so the uh at one point i agreed with
that statement
but but i have come across enough people
who are
using a topical that has got a
an ethanol component and they
they use a thc rich topical
and then if they use enough of it they
actually feel
the uh the intoxication from the thc
and um i have heard just anecdotally
that people will who don't smoke will
will test positive on a urine analysis
after only using thc rich topical
so are you saying that you have
explanations for that or
okay no i'm really interested also in
terms of like the ethanol
topical that makes people feel
psychoactive effects i want to talk to
you more about that but first
about about the drug testing um a lot of
the drug tests are
not testing for thc they're testing for
the metabolites
and so that's actually possibly it's
possible with with any of the topicals
because your body will metabolize them
and the metabolites can stick around for
like
months right it's the question of
whether or not it gets in the blood and
up to the brain
in like its active form interesting so
wait the metabolites
your body will produce metabolites even
if the thc
doesn't reach the blood or like by
i think what my thought process was by
the time the thc reaches the blood and
like is being cleared out of the topical
from topicals is that it already has
been metabolized and that's why
you don't get any activity because it
doesn't enter into the brain and
this is just that's just my like thought
process behind it i don't actually know
i should
i'll look it up actually later um but
interesting that you said that you've
had people who've felt a psychoactive
effect from topicals do you know did
they apply it in a very specific place
on their body
or is there well i can give you two i'm
going to give you two answers for that
so okay the the first answer is um
i normally find people say they have
felt it more
when they have to cover a large area
right
so this is usually people who have got
back
and hip or leg issues where
interesting they're covering their back
their shoulders
their their you know their hip bones
maybe their their tush
and so so you know it's it's not common
as a matter of fact i've never come
across it with somebody who's using it
for
like um like hands yeah hands
elbow arthritis tennis elbow stuff like
that
because it's a very small area it's
always been people who are
taking care of a large swath of the
human body and then
second you know i have been making
tinctures for myself
for over a decade for my brain injury
and i know
that um i had to start wearing gloves
when i made my tinctures because if i
had a spill and i cleaned it up
the the alcohol with
um the suspended cannabinoids in it
would i'm assuming soak through my hands
and i would
get like hella high and have to go lay
down and i'm like oh all right guess
who's going to start using latex gloves
and so and so that's my own personal
experience
so so my belief is certain that
that thc can be carried through the skin
with ethanol and then the topical people
who i have you know learned from
have said you know you know the emu oil
and all these other things
are all good for the skin but if you
really want to take cannabinoids to the
skin there has to be an ethanol
component for efficiency and expediency
i'm not a topicals expert so i am not
standing
here saying that this is all to be true
uh i'm just
saying this to inform the question that
is
so fascinating and i'm gonna go home
today mix my topicals with ethanol and
cover my back in it like
i am so interested in that i mean with
the back that's
it's interesting because you know the
spinal cord is the central
place where the peripheral and central
nervous system like interact with each
other
so obviously there's a lot going on
there um but i
i'm fascinated by that also like many
many scientists would be fascinated by
that because there's been a lot of
studies about penetration
like skin penetration like specifically
and um
wow that's that's awesome information
i'm definitely going to you know
i'm going to home trial that home
experiment right now
it's nice that that we happen to be
working with a plant that we can home
trial stuff right i mean i mean
anybody who listens to the shows knows
i'm a huge fan of citizen science
and i understand that often citizen
science can kick out bro
science and that's that's something we
always have to watch out for
but uh you know the even though we have
a larger and increasingly
larger scientific community around
cannabis
we have a hell of a bigger community of
cannabis patients who are trying to do
their own research at home to relieve
their suffering
and there's so much to be learned from
those folks
oh yeah it's exponential like the power
is in the people i'm a huge believer of
personal experience because like
when it comes down to it we are all
different so no one's going to know you
as well as you know yourself
like no one is going to understand you
and the way that you feel the way that
you do
yeah you know it's weird though not all
scientists are into citizen science you
know i have spoken with
uh cannabinoid researchers who will i'll
talk to at conventions and they will
talk trash about the patients doing
their own stuff and i can understand
their frustration because
there's a lot of inaccurate science
that's handed around by patients but
at the same time i don't think that's a
reason to discount
citizen science it just means that it
needs to be checked
just like i have to check regular you
know professional scientists to find out
who's paying for their studies you know
any kind of research needs to be looked
at
um you know with open eyes i think that
that just means that we should put more
effort
into public education so that people
doing the citizen science are
more educated in scientific theory and
like able to execute it themselves i
think that this
like the idea that we shouldn't be
experimenting on ourselves is just naive
like every single human in your entire
life all you're doing is experimenting
all the time like it's it's an n equals
one
or you know when you find your person
and n equals two or for people who are
polyamorous and n equals
x like number of people right but
no i i think that um i agree that it can
be
there can be negative like myths and um
like what did you do you called it bro
science right yeah yeah
i agree that there are problems that
that arise from that and that you know
that's unfortunate that people can
believe that that's true at face value
but i also think that there's been some
pretty important things that come out of
qualitative experience and historically
that was like
all we had yeah in the past like
previous 4
000 years yeah that's a good point i
mean
a lot of the new cannabis knowledge is
is just because
of the machinery that we're using to
look at it with
which comes with with like a bunch of
assumptions i mean i love my field i'm
obsessed with molecular pharmacology but
i mean we would we'd need a whole other
show for me to just explain to you all
of the assumptions
that go into what i did which is in
vitro pharmacology
right which is actually like screening a
drug molecule against a target and i i
did structural biochemistry of
endocannabinoid system targets
there is just an exponential number of
assumptions that
you make in research science that
doesn't you know they call it the
transition from bench to bedside
right from from the laboratory bench to
the bedside of a person
and i think that like discounting human
experience
is and like i'm invalidating it i think
that that's detrimental to the cannabis
industry as a whole because
we have so much information out here and
so much power
and people who are trying to increase
the quality of lives and so much
information that gets lost because we're
just going to devalue it you know
yeah you know i i'm chuckling to myself
how much fun it would be to do a show
called
uh invalidating cannabinoid science
and we just go into all the trash about
are we going to eat some mangoes and
then yeah totally
so he could be more high all right um so
thank you for that viabi let's go ahead
and take that
uh second break and get that out of the
way you are listening to shaping fire
and my guest today is cannabinoid
pharmacologist miyabi shields phd
[Music]
there is no doubt that autoflowering
cannabis plants have finally come in to
their own
and night owl seeds works tirelessly
bringing you autoflower genetics that
are reliable
thriving and with extraordinary terpene
profiles
night owl seeds is an industry leader
because of the focus work of their
founder daz
daz is passionate about the cannabis
plant and pushing what autoflowers can
do
and cultivators know that these efforts
show through in his seeds
and night owl seeds really are
extraordinary just take a look at the
thousands of photos
by fans on instagram the proof is there
and obvious
terpenes are complex and rich plants
have vigor
if you are a fan of mephisto genetics
like i am you'll likely also love night
owl seeds
night owl founder daz worked with mitch
mephisto to build the mephisto brand for
years
including breeding mephisto's much-loved
sour stomper and cosmic queen cultivars
i'm growing both night owl and mephisto
this year because i want the best
and night owl seeds knows how to
cultivate community too
daz puts out great stickers exclusive
packaging for limited runs
and desirable freebies he really draws
you in if you love creative branding
night owl even has the secret owl
society text club
just text the word night owl one word to
760-670-3130
for early announcements and exclusive
opportunities
of course you can see lots of photos and
find out about upcoming drops by
following the night owl seeds instagram
too
at daz dot night owl that's
d-a-z-dot night owl you can get your
packs of night owl seeds at several
distributors
including dc seed exchange insane seeds
and hemogenetics that's night owl seeds
there's a difference because we're
different
[Music]
sometimes the topics i want to share
with you are far too brief for an entire
shaping fire episode
in those instances i post them to
instagram i
invite you to follow my two instagram
profiles and participate
online the shaping fire instagram has
follow-up posts to shaping fire episodes
growing and processing best practices
product trials and
of course gorgeous flower photos the
schangolos instagram follows my travels
on cannabis garden tours
my successes and failures in my own
garden insights and best practices from
personal grows everywhere
and always gorgeous flower photos on
both profiles the emphasis is on sharing
what i've learned in a way that you can
replicate it in your own garden
your own hash lab or for your own
cannabinopathic health
so i encourage you to follow at shaping
fire and
at shango lows and join our online
community on instagram
[Music]
over the years shaping fire has been
invited to sponsor several cannabis cups
and i've said no to them all
it wasn't until the autoflower cup that
i really wanted to help promote
something
and the producers sebastian and carla
didn't even invite me i approached them
i told them that autoflower cup was
important to me for three reasons
first it was obvious that they were
going for a friends and family vibe
instead of some sort of commodified
cannabis vibe
this event was going to gather really
cool folks
second the event had a ton of cool stuff
to do and to learn and to participate in
the event isn't just about cannabis it's
about living life fully
enjoying community eating together
laughing and listening to music
and mushrooms third and most important
to me personally
the event was authentically for the
autoflower community
and the autoflower community needs a
place too
autoflower is about getting high sure
but i find that much of the autoflower
community is still focused on cannabis
patients
home grow sharing best practices sharing
seeds
and humility these are the ideals that i
share with the event
and i wanted to make sure i did my part
to help it succeed
announcing the 2021 autoflower cup
august
6th 7th and 8th in lillawup washington
just outside of seattle
this over 21 event is presented by camp
ruderalis
the autoflower competition is open to
everyone commercial
and home growers so get your skills
recognized and enter today
a cup win now will make you a leader in
the community
here comes the ear candy stunden glass
hookah lounge
pop-up magical butter chocolate shop
waterfront marketplace with an array of
vendors
there will be an old school autoflower
seed swap joint rolling competition
cannabis cooking demos solventless
squishing demos
and late night documentary screenings of
fantastic fungi
chef sebastian carosi's award-winning
classics like
elk chili kobe beef kimchi dogs
oyster po boys and razor clam chowder
wild oyster harvesting mushroom foraging
s'mores around the campfires each night
dan jimmy of mandalorian presentations
psilocybin mushrooms presentations
camping glamping
rvs and airbnb so check out
camprootoralis.com for those details
and follow the instagram at the
autoflower cup
2021 welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and our guest this week is cannabinoid
pharmacologist miyabi shields phd
so miyabi we gotta go back to the mango
right
like we threw it in there at the end
yeah we threw it in there at the end
and like you know there are so many
people still talking about having
mangoes before
you get high because it helps and this
is
this is untrue and let's get it directly
from a scientist please break it down
i believe that if you believe it will
make you higher that
it will that's what i normally say
well you know it's it's placebo right
essentially it feeds into set and
setting right if you believe it to be
true
your your your brain tends to you know
tell you that you're right
so let me if i break it down to like
what people normally talk about it's
mercy
right people are normally talking about
the terpene that is present in mangoes
that will then make you feel higher
um from what i've seen about like the
bioavailability of mercine and the
amount of mercine that is present
in mangoes which means that when you eat
it like how much of it actually enters
your system
um our body metabolizes terpenes really
really quickly specifically if you're
going edible
route of administration right um so
i it's hard for me it's difficult for me
as a scientist to believe that eating a
mango
which has relatively low amounts of
mercine that are bioavailable that then
get metabolized almost immediately
would like make it to the brain to have
like a significant effect
um but i i'm much more convinced of the
fact that if you were to believe that
that were true and you had that in your
head that that would absolutely happen
for you
and like i don't think there's anything
wrong with the placebo effect like while
we're just on the topic of placebo like
ultimately at the end of the day what
are we trying to do we're trying to
we're trying to
have an effect you're looking you're
looking for an experience
so people ask me sometimes like about
like i take cbd every day
and i it helps me a lot and people have
asked me about it being like how are you
sure it's not a placebo
and i'm like you know what i actually
could not answer that
for you with a hundred percent certainty
because no one can
and i don't think it matters whether or
not it's a placebo because it works for
me
and so i think that like coming to like
mango and the science and
um yeah from what i've from what i've
seen i don't believe like scientifically
that anything biologically is going on
other than altering your expectation of
what it will feel like
right on that's in line what uh dr ethan
russo shared with us during the shaping
fire
uh sessions video too when we were
talking about eating food to support
your
your endo cannabinoid system he also
agrees with you that it is
um um it's just expectation
and there's nothing going on at a
physiological level but you know that
doesn't mean that uh any of this
mango uh mythology is going to slow down
one iota
so so let's go ahead and move on so
so in here in set three i want to talk
about uh dosing thresholds for efficacy
because um in serious and chronic
patients
um this is something they're constantly
struggling with
um so many patients fall into like the
overall
bucket of immune disorders uh rheumatoid
arthritis multiple sclerosis lupus
hashimoto epstein-barr i mean there are
so many of these people when you put
them all together
and they're so many of them are using
cannabis now
some cannabis seems to help a lot
more cannabis helps some people
but heroic doses are hard to determine
and may not give increasingly better
results and so even though somebody is
really sick more cannabis may or may not
be the solution though
maybe it is because of their their um
tolerance
so so my question for you is what is the
efficacy threshold point
um uh between these serious imbalances
and knowing what is the maximum they
should take
that makes sense because we don't want
patients wasting money on too many
cannabinoids
but the difference between 50 milligrams
of whole plant
plant cbd and 200 milligrams of whole
plant cbd
really can make a difference in certain
patients
oh absolutely so okay i also have to
just say like just a little disclaimer
here
i am not a medical professional or
doctorate i'm like a research scientist
my right like all of my expertise is
just on like molecular pharmacology of
cannabinoids
in the body but i will speak to what i
personally believe
um about efficacy and dosing right
which is that i think in general what
you're looking for for every person
is what's called the therapeutic minimum
that
is the amount of cannabinoids that you
need to take in
so that you have a therapeutic effect
but
not any more than that because when you
start taking in more than what would be
the therapeutic minimum you can start
getting negative effects like tolerance
or withdrawal
right or like off-target effects and in
terms of like what is that therapeutic
minimum i mean this is where
unfortunately
it's again with what we were talking
about earlier between you and i
it's it's dependent a lot by the person
and
what therapeutic indication they're
looking for um
and you know what it's it's so
complicated because there
is no one-stop fill-out like
form for saying you are this tall you
weigh this much and so this much
is the amount that i mean you know that
very well um and this is something that
we've actually been struggling with
in terms of like adding like uh medical
validity to cannabis it's something
that's a that's a big barrier i think in
my mind
is that um some people can't wrap their
brains around the fact that we
we can't actually tell you what dose is
beneficial like
largely that responsibility is going on
to the consumer or the patient
right like more and more like what you
were talking about with citizen science
we're realizing that it's up to us to do
this experimentation to figure out what
it is and
a lot of people in the general public
feel like not
capable of making that decision right um
so i'm just going to explain something
that um and
this is it only works for people who can
monitor their symptoms with a number
um but it's basically call it's called a
titration
and a titration means adding something
slowly until you reach like an
equilibrium
that's like the i guess the layman's way
of explaining it
and whenever you go to a doctor and i'm
think i'm talking mostly right now
mental health is probably the
the easiest example you go to a
psychiatrist um they usually start you
on the lowest dose of something
and then you go back and you see them
like once a week for like a few weeks
and then they decide like okay we have
to increase it right
and then you increase it and then you
see them once a week for a couple weeks
and then like maybe you increase it
maybe you stay the same
what they are doing is a titration which
means that they're starting at the
lowest possible dose and then
monitoring the effects of that molecule
on you specifically as a patient um
so in lieu of being able to do that with
cannabinoids with with the
depending on your your medical
professional which also if you have a
medical professional that you can be
honest with
that would be the best case scenario and
you take down the information and you
give them that information
and then they give you you know they
give you what they think about it but in
in lieu of that you could also do that
yourself
so you keep a journal or an excel sheet
or you know any sort of
um you know has to be written down
though and you and you write everything
down
you write down what you're using and why
and you give
your symptoms that you're trying to
reduce a number
you you quantify them and i know it's
going to be subjective and i know
that it's going to be biased right
because you're the one writing it
but it's more information than you would
have otherwise and it's it's a
it's a good way to look at something
with numbers sometimes and see
um and so then you write everything down
and you see that's also the easiest way
to decide or determine whether or not
you're developing a tolerance
right and eventually like for people who
are just getting to know themselves for
for people like
like you and i who've been you know
using cannabis for years and years
um you know you end up just kind of with
an inherent knowledge
of yourself i think um but for people
who are just getting started
you know i say start small like it's
always
great to start small and then to
increase and like give depending on what
what you're looking at
at improving um you know you could give
it a little bit of time because certain
effects take time to um to see
you know there's there's different
effects level there's acute effects of a
molecule which is like immediate so
the acute effects of thc would be the
high right
but then there's like more long-term
effects like the down regulation of cb1
receptors that might take more time it
might take like a week or two weeks
might take three weeks uh depends on the
person
and if you're writing everything down
and if you're being very intentional
about your use and i realize this sounds
like kind of a lot of work
but once you get in the habit of doing
it it really just kind of becomes
um habit there also are apps out there
that will help you
like tracking apps and habit apps and
things on on the phone that i think are
that can be really really useful um in
in helping you to to find out like what
is the dose that's working and how is it
working for you
and i think that unfortunately this this
type of like self-evaluation
is really useful for people who have
symptoms that are that are outward
facing right
like that you can see um
it becomes much more complicated when
you talk about something like cancer and
you can't see your tumors or your mets
right yeah well at least in some of
those cases
um we can look at analytics but we'll
talk more about cancer in a minute on
the on the
you know what you are saying is is
accurate right essentially you're so
you're calling for patients to try trade
up
and then journal their results to get to
know their cannabinoid tone and their
body
uh and how that matches with
their relief goals and and you know
shaping fire is big fans of of
journaling and titration
um and and not to discount this but at
the end that just means that the answer
is trial and error which is what these
patients are already doing
you know it is and it's the it's the
appliance it sucks that we don't have a
better
answer for these folks because doing
that you know that
trial and error that that titration and
journaling
you're probably gonna hit like over
medication a couple times and have
some crappy paranoid experiences you're
probably gonna have to be
patient when you're feeling impatient
because
you're you're experiencing symptoms from
whatever's
you know going on for you and you have
to deal with those symptoms while you're
trying to
figure out if you need 20 50 or 200
milligrams of cbd a day
like like that can take so much time
especially if a patient has got
you know somebody who's got you know
hashimoto epstein bar
and ra plus migraines
it's like it's it's a total mess of
of of of symptoms that you're trying to
work your way through
and um and you're right all we can do is
you know suggest titration and and
taking a journal and talking with other
patients but
golly that's a disappointing
that's the best i can offer folks and
that's something it's honestly
one of the things that i would be i that
is most interesting to me is like
formulations and understanding how
specific formulations come into play
with this because
i think it's a huge i think it's a huge
problem and i also think that um in
terms of titration the other option is
to go
is to go outside in as i would say those
the other option that's not try
so titration is slowly increasing until
you reach equilibrium right
um the opposite of that would be outside
in which is
taking the smallest dose and seeing what
you feel and taking the largest dose
you're comfortable with
and seeing how you feel and then go
working your way in from that if that
makes sense yeah wow taking that biggest
dose uh that sounds sketch
yeah i mean that's not that's why i
don't i don't recommend it usually i am
just putting it out there as the
alternative option
of the in in general i believe in some
ways in some forms of engineering that's
a fast way
of finding the optimum yeah maybe maybe
i would recommend that
for all the cannabinoids except for thc
yeah i think that it's like it's a good
one for cbd
or cbg all right so
all right so then let's talk about uh
for cancer and
unfortunately it may be a similar answer
so
um you know taking tinctures for
symptoms
right so let's say um you know primarily
probably thc but certainly there are
applications for cbg and cbd
but let's just say generally 10 to 20
milligrams a day for thc
spread out over the day is a very common
dosage for folks who are in cancer
treatment
just to help with the side effects you
know so they they can get back their
appetite
they feel uh some muscle relaxation
they just feel better in this body that
they are inhabiting right so you know 10
to 20 a day
that's pretty typical versus the large
doses
of full extract cannabis oil also known
as rso for cancer patients who are going
for
a cure right for people who are going to
a cure
that 10 to 20 milligrams a day you know
depending on where they are in the cycle
will be 300
to 750 milligrams a day which is like
like a whole hell of a lot of thc
and and the thing is is that you know
the the go-to protocol
has been 60 milliliters
of of cannabis oil over 90 days
and and that usually takes a big thwack
at the cancer and um either the person
will decide to do another round
or it's solved or the patient
doesn't want to do it anymore either
because their
psa numbers haven't gone down for
example or
or they just can't handle that much thc
in their life it's a lifestyle choice
so so all of that is to set up this
question which is
you know how do we is is it even known
what the efficacy is against big
monsters like cancer
for thc or is this simply
you know how it's been done in the in
the past of
let's throw thc at it and see if it
sticks
and it just hasn't been updated with
appropriate science yet
so so the cannabinoids show anti-tumor
anti-tumor genic properties like
it's it's been established but the the
way that we test this
in the lab has a lot to do with usually
uh usually it's either a cell culture
or or animal model right um and then we
have all the human information out there
right like what you're describing all
the people
with the protocol with the protocol and
using really really high doses
of of cannabinoids um so like is there
science behind it yes
do i know or can we can we say like what
does
uh what threshold is the are the
anti-tumor
properties going to have effect no which
is also why
i think people lean towards more because
in general yes like if you're gonna err
on the side if you want anti-tumor
properties
and you're trying to err on the side of
getting those then
in in theory more or a higher dose would
be better than than less i had a patient
tell me that she was gonna go big or go
home right she's all like if i'm not
gonna do chemo i'm gonna take
all the thc that i can pack into my body
because that's where all my chips are
you know this is this is unrelated i
mean it's not unrelated from the
endocannabinoid system but it's
unrelated to cannabis um
but i think um one thing of interest of
whenever cancer comes up that i
i mentioned is fasting and the effect of
ketosis and which ketosis
is when your body runs out of sugar and
begins
burning ketones for energy instead it's
fat you're burning fat
the endocannabinoid system is a fat
signaling system it's involved in this
there's a big shift that occurs
so it is related to endocannabinoid
system not necessarily related cannabis
but
there's a lot of evidence out there that
fasting is very beneficial
um in terms of it's like anti-tumor
properties like anti-metastatic
properties um and it also just it's
beneficial in general this is like
this isn't the topic that we're on
whatsoever it's just something that i
thought was worth
mentioning um actually it's kind of on
topic here let me tie it in for you
because so many of the patients who are
on
um high thc dosage
um full extract cannabis oil for cancer
you know it's a very common that they
get sleepy right they just nap
all day long and their caregiver needs
to arouse them to get them to eat
and to go to the bathroom and and one of
the challenges with patients is to make
sure they keep their weight
up um because they're spending so much
time sleeping
and they they get over the munchies part
of cannabis really quickly
and and so generally patients
lose weight um in the
last you know say four to five weeks
of of using a full extra cannabis oil
for cancer and wouldn't that be
interesting if it is the decreased
calorie intake which in causes the boost
to the immune system which is playing a
big role in that
i would think that it's synergistic for
sure although i i also
like we have to mention that like
obviously getting proper nutrition and
like
not losing a significant right the goal
is to not lose weight but it tends to
happen so
important you know absolutely but it's
there's i mean in terms of like
so cancer is the overactive and i'm not
a cancer expert like whatsoever also i
just but but
just in general right like cancer is
what happens when
there's a mutation in your cells and
then they're over they overactively
um reproduce and grow and they they
are evading the immune system like
normally normally um
if our immune system was to be
functioning uh authentically or
correctly then the immune system would
identify those i mean
we have mutations in our cells all the
time we have we have errors every single
one of us like probably right now
has at least one cell in our body i
could probably guarantee it there's at
least
one cell in our body that's doing
something wrong all right like
with the our our bodies aren't perfect
um but we have a system
in place that like identifies those
errors and fixes it
and cancer occurs where somehow the
cancer cells
are evading that system right um
and yeah i think that and and the
endocannabinoid system
is integrally linked to immune function
and to
energy uh you know energy homeostasis or
energy balance
uh and cancer cells take up a lot of
energy they're replicating very rapidly
and so there's there's all the
anti-tumor properties of the
cannabinoids as well but then there's
all the endocannabinoid system
interaction with the immune system
you know it's it's really complicated
and um i
i could not imagine what i would feel
like if i was if i was diagnosed with
cancer so i can't
i can't speak for sure what i would
definitely do in that scenario because i
know that when
that happens and when you get that
diagnosis your life changes forever and
um you know i could be saying something
now that i believe i would do and i
maybe wouldn't do it right right
um but it is my belief currently that if
i were to be diagnosed with cancer that
i would
use cannabis and fast um and then i
would also be open to chemotherapy
i mean i would be open to it but i think
it would not be the first um
stop right on i wanna go back and i'm
gonna bite
like i heard you used a subtle change in
your intonation when you use the word
normally
and then in your next sentence all the
places that you would have used normally
you swapped out that word
and i want to bite why did you
not choose to use the word normally to
describe a function of the body
i don't think yeah that's funny shango
that you picked up on that
um i don't think that i don't like the
word
normal just i i dislike that word
almost in every context or
way that you could in any way that you
could use that word to describe
human functionality it doesn't fit um
so i think that's just kind of where
that came from is that i i even do i
slip up all the time i used the word
normally and then i think about it and
i'm like you know that's not the most
correct way
to say that um and that normal
and using the word normal implies
uh it implies that we have an
understanding of human
diversity and functionality that we just
don't have
so it's my personal opinion that i don't
i don't like using the word normal to
describe anything having to do with
humans
right on i'm with you and uh and and it
assumes that there
is an established standard that doesn't
exist
it just doesn't exist yeah you just yeah
you hit you hit that on the head with
that one i i slipped up i do it all the
time i don't believe there's a normal
right on well cool thank you because i i
heard you know how you can
hear someone's mind thinking as they
build their sentence
and i heard i heard you play with that
i'm like oh there's something going on
there i want to know
so so let's finish up this episode
with a follow-up question from part one
that we did a few weeks back
um you know we talked a lot about
tolerance breaks
uh during um part one of of this endic
endo cannabinoid mechanics series and
um and the number one com
question i got from folks was about
taking a tolerance break from
cannabinoids that are not thc
because you said something really
interesting you talked about how often
you do thc tolerance breaks
and how they're good for you but you
also said that you don't take tolerance
breaks from
cbd and that's what everybody was asking
me about they're like ask her why she
doesn't take them for cbd
doesn't she need to um you know
doesn't miabi need to take a break from
uh you know cbd because they may be
getting
a a tolerance from cbd as well
and then i got the same questions well
how about thca
and how about cbg then because patients
are all
taking these various non-thc
cannabinoids and
and they all expect that they need
to take a break from them uh
just like they would thc but by your
comment that you don't take one from cbd
left everyone in a quandary so will you
flesh that out
so i realized that i actually misspoke
because i use full spectrum products
so i don't actually technically take
breaks from thc either
because even there's even trace amounts
in your cbd stuff
yeah there's small amounts and then i i
use how i smoke hemp flour right so
there's gonna be small amounts of delta
eight in there as well
um but you know that's it's small
usually it's well under
it's gonna be well under one percent um
so i don't take breaks from the
cannabinoids i guess
in general there we go
that would be the main way of putting it
but in terms of like thc and like larger
like relatively larger doses of thc um
i i currently am taking like a one to
one
um cbg cbd extract every morning and
then like it has small amounts of thc
present
um and a bunch of other things right
like whatever else is in is in the plant
but um it's interesting because like do
i need to take a tolerance break from
these okay so what is a tolerance break
and what is that what is the point of a
tolerance break for people right like
uh in in general the added benefit of a
tolerance break there's a couple added
benefits like the first added benefit of
a tolerance break
is going to be to decrease your
tolerance um that means that you are
going to
be able to get a larger therapeutic
effect from less
right that's the that's the number one
reason why people want to take tolerance
breaks
um i don't use to from my experience
with
cbd and the trace amounts of thc and now
cbg that i'm experiencing with
i don't experience a tolerance effect
because i'm using them at relatively low
doses so it just means that like i'm not
taking more every day i'm taking the
same amount every single day and i'm
still getting the therapeutic effect
so i'm not experiencing tolerance so for
that reason like in number one like
there is not really a need for a
tolerance break
in that one way um in terms of like
that's the first reason to have a
tolerance break
the second reason is kind of like a
lesser reason to have a tolerance break
would be just to like judge your
perspective
of like whether or not something is
working for you whether or not it's
having a negative effect on your life
um i have taken breaks for
for that reason that's actually one of
the main reasons why i take regular thc
breaks it's the reason why i stopped
drinking a couple years ago
um just to like re just to check in
right to check in
being like how is this affecting my life
how is this affecting my health um
and i think that that's important to do
but for me personally
the giant added therapeutic benefit that
i get
from you know cbd now cbg and trace
amounts of thc
plus plus whatever else is in the plant
that we're talking about right like
the terpenes and the flavonoids and you
know bioactive fatty acids and
everything
like those benefits that i receive that
increase my quality of life i mean it
far to me it is far outweighing any
negative effect that it's having on my
health
of which i don't see um any negative
effect on my health
um that's obviously subjective that's
something that i'm determining for
myself although
um i have seen doctors that say that i'm
healthy so there's that
um i want to bring us back to the the
sharp edge point on the question though
we're talking about uh you know we we've
been talking about so far in
this answer like thc and how
you do your tolerance breaks but
specifically the question is
are tolerance breaks beneficial for
cbd cbg and thca
they work the same way yes yeah and
they're acting on different receptors
though so i mean i think that that's
like the main
thing to point out is that all of these
rare cannabinoids that have different
pharmacologies
when you take tolerance breaks from them
you'll be affecting different receptors
and
it'll be a similar thing though where
you're like re-sensitizing
your your body to the molecule although
i haven't really
seen a lot of people developing tau
unless they're taking very very high
doses um i guess it just depends
i and i'm i'm not like the most
knowledgeable person on this i would
love to hear from other people
uh what they think about this but you
know developing a tolerance it seems
like
at least thc develops a pretty rapid
tolerance like
it's easy for the cb1 receptors to be
down regulated and then for you to get
less of that intoxicating effect i have
not um seen that and i maybe
with the other rare cannabinoids and
maybe i also haven't looked hard enough
because to be fair like
there's not a lot of information out
there on the um
other rare cannabinoids i would be very
interested to hear from people
if they develop tolerance to the other
rares and like what that looks like and
what
it would look like for them to take
tolerance breaks i'm interested
the the common the common background of
this
is uh since this whole set three is is
focused on
dosing thresholds for efficacy in
chronic and serious illness
these are generally folks that have got
some
combination of of serious things like
you know ms and ra
lupus and r.a you know lupus hashimoto
epstein-barr r.a right like
like people who have got serious
dysfunctions in their body
and these folks describe this experience
of
going bouncing from solution to solution
because
their body adapts to the solutions
quickly and their suffering returns and
so
it is incredibly common for me to hear
from these these these
these high difficulty patients that
yeah i did you know cbd worked for five
weeks and then it stopped working
and so i moved on to cbg and cbg helped
decrease the inflammation for a few
weeks and then it stopped working
and then they moved on to mushrooms and
then that worked for a while and that
stopped working
and then they're like so then i went
back around to cbd oh cbd was now
working again
and so so many of these patients they
hop from method to method to method
to to i mean and and they're even
switching
from drugs that have different methods
of action right so it's not even always
the method of action
it's as if they need to keep um
goosing their immune system with
different solutions to
refreshing it right and so it's these
folks that are looking for
any way to refresh their body's reaction
to these natural plant medicines
and you know when you said you know
you know inaccurately that you take a
break from from
cbd people were all over this because
they're like oh
you know do should we not be taking our
breaks from cbd and i think that the
answer is actually yeah they should be
well i think it also depends so for
people who have really high inflammatory
and chronic disorders like this is again
i'm not a doctor i'm not a medical
professional i'm not a nutritionist i'm
just
a scientist and this is just my opinion
of my life but
you know it's not just the cannabinoids
that i use to manage my chronic
disorders i have
altered pretty much every other aspect
of my life
that you could that you could i
shape my entire life around
my chronic mental health chronic pain
and chronic gi
issues i try and maintain the lowest
possible
like systemic inflammation levels i mean
we talked about inflammation in the last
one
i think inflammation is at the heart of
a lot of these problems specifically
immune system problems
um and so i would say as just as advice
um in my opinion is that you have to
find a way to potentiate
the cannabinoids you have to find a way
to make them more effective
and there are a number of ways you can
do that right like by modifying your
diet modifying your
fasting or like your eating window i
take i take cold showers and do
breathing
exercises right like people who've heard
of them hoff um
and then there's like stretching yoga
mental health work like
cardi like low grade cardio strength
training like working out like there's
there's all of these other options that
you could do that potentiate they
increase the efficacy of the
cannabinoids
um and i know that for a number of
reasons those things are extremely
difficult to implement in your life and
they feel like this all
i mean when i say all of them out loud
it's like oh my god i can't believe i do
all of those
things um so it's really like about one
at a time and certain things will work
for certain people more
more than others right um but i can't
tell you what has worked for me or
like has any of the have any of those
one things work for me or
is it the combination that of all of
these things that
that are somehow working together um
you know i i don't know um that that's
actually a really good point is to
to bring us back to the holistic nature
of this and while i
while i know that the the
the inflammation patients that you know
i i've worked with
would would howl at the idea that that
they do weight training right
and that they they lift things because
most of them feel
so broken and weak um the body doesn't
really know i mean for this application
the body doesn't really know the
difference between a one pound weight
and a
20 pound weight all it knows is that
it's
it's being put into a stress and release
of the muscle sets
and so it is going through the the body
actions
um that that respond to that and there
is healing
and efficacy in that and so
you know i i like the fact that you
recognized the
mental impossibility of that for these
patients
oh it's and yet just find something
heavier than nothing
or just or just nothing just body
training start with what you know start
with what is good for you like i'm
i have hypermobility issues i injure
myself really really easily
i don't lift like i mean now that i've
been lifting for a while i've been able
to increase
like my weights but um you know it's
it's all about what you're comfortable
with and
what actually brings things to to your
life and that are that are manageable to
you
um to do i think that's like the
starting point and then like what you
said about a one pound weight i mean you
do a one pound weight for six months
it'll turn into a five pound weight
you do that for another six months it'll
turn into a 10 pound weight
and then you'll get to 20. you know well
uh miyabi thank you so much for joining
me again
on shaping fire um i enjoyed our first
interview for part one so much that i
was glad that you were open to do uh
a part two in endocannabinoid mechanics
and and people love it you know to be
able to hear
this level of scientific detail
from you know from a scientist who is
able to put it
in layman terms human terms
uh is a real joy for most of us uh so
so thank you so much for sharing your
expertise and good cheer
well thank you so much for having me
honestly i really i really enjoy your
questions and your your listeners must
be uh
they must be a pretty sharp bunch you
know so don't
i mean in terms of like the late in
terms of layman type stuff i'm
i'm excited the questions are not layman
questions right on excellent well yeah
i'm pretty stoked with the shaping fire
audience too people
people come here when they want to get
serious and i'm grateful they're here
so so thank you miyabi if you have
missed part one
of endocannabinoid mechanics with dr
miyabi shields you can go back and enjoy
shaping fire episode number 78 that was
the part one
it is fabulous and you should definitely
check it out if you just started with
this one
if you would like to learn more from
miyabi i strongly suggest that you
follow their social media
which is just absolutely filled with
rich content
and how i found out about them uh the
more reliable platform
for that right now seems to be instagram
and their
instagram is at miyabi phd and that's
m i y a b
e p h d so instagram seems to be the
best place to go
um however um uh you know
the the secret is that the tick tock
material is actually more fun
for the moment and the tick tock but
keep keep
tick tock keeps deleting miyabi's
account
but for now it is also at miyabi
hd so follow both the instagram account
and the tick tock account to stay up
on uh you know festive cannabinopathic
learning with miyabi
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts
if you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you would leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download
your review will help others find the
show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for insights
into the latest cannabis news
exclusive videos and giveaways on the
shaping fire website you also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast
that's at shaping fire and at changolos
on instagram
be sure to check out shaping fire
youtube channel for exclusive interviews
farm tours and cannabis lectures does
your company want to reach our national
audience of cannabis enthusiasts
email hotspot shippingfire.com to find
out how
thanks for listening to shaping fire
i've been your host shango lose
you