[Music]
the popularity of psilocybin mushrooms
has exploded in the last few years not
only are laws relaxing in many cities
across the country but cultivation best
practices are being codified and shared
online like never before
using mushrooms at different doses makes
for very different experiences a micro
dose is intended that you don't feel it
at all while a half to a full gram makes
for a fun day of exploration and of
course you can keep going up in dosage
from there to have a very powerful human
experience
anywhere along this range of dosing
though can change the trajectory of your
life
because mushrooms have such a profound
impact on brain function
but we really don't know why and isn't
that odd
mushrooms have been used by humans since
the beginning of recorded history and
yet they have been taboo and barred from
research in the modern scientific era
but happily those challenges to research
are coming down
this isn't to say that we know nothing
about how mushrooms function it's just
that most hallucinogenic mushroom
research has not been approved up until
now and scientists who were doing the
research during the dark days were
shunned if they talked about it
if you want to learn about cannabis
health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer i
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we're giving away very cool prizes to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter there's nothing else you need
to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shapingfire.com to
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and
i'm your host shango los
today my guest is neuropharmacologist
miyabi shields phd
dr shields is co-founder of real
isolates which ironically focuses on the
importance of secondary plant components
and synergistic cannabis blends so
essentially whole plant medicine
miyabi received their phd in
pharmaceutical sciences focusing on the
biochemistry of the endocannabinoid
system from northeastern university in
miyabi has authored or co-authored six
peer-reviewed publications and presently
has a patent under review for a novel
fungus and plant extraction method
miyabi also has a substantial list of
honors and awards including a 2016
international cannabinoid research
society pre-doctoral research award
their tick tock channel at miyabi phd
has 180 000 followers and is where i
first met miyabi
today's episode is really special i have
not found this information available
anywhere else during the first set we
will describe the interrelated body
systems that are stimulated by silicon
and how these systems interact at a
chemical level the second set is all
about dosing thresholds and mechanics of
tolerance
and during the third set we focus on
specific applications for this knowledge
and how to effectively use psilocybin
mushrooms to improve your health and
life
welcome back to shaping fire miyabi
i'm so excited to be here today i'm you
know it's really gotten to be fun to
have you back a few times and we clearly
get along and chat so well i've gotten
to the point where i'm not you know i i
mean i still get nervous before i record
most of these shows because i want to
get it right you know um but i'm so
comfortable with you and we have such an
easy time chatting like i was just
excited to get together and chat with
you today there was not the uh the the
kind of nervous anxiety so so i'm stoked
that we've gotten to that point
totally i feel like we just have so much
in common and in what we're interested
in and
i'm really really also just excited to
touch on these topics uh you know i'm
super passionate about molecular
pharmacology and i think these two
things don't often get talked about
together and i'm excited to uh to dive
into that right on so um i think we
should start this show off with a little
preamp because you know you and i came
up with the idea for this show from us
just chatting as as now friends
and uh we're gonna be going back and
forth
between um you know historical
scientific papers
new scientific papers
and i guess what i'd call like like uh
informed conjecture on your part because
you're like you're a pharmacologist
you're you know you're one of the
experts in the field in this area and
some of your some of the stuff that
you're going to say today is
you know we haven't been allowed to
study yet and i think it's important for
people to understand that you know
you're qualified to make these educated
guesses but you're gonna you're gonna
kind of let us know where the hard
science ends and your conjecture begins
right
definitely i mean we are gonna be
entering into a space of abstract theory
which is that we know about these
systems and we know like certain facts
about how the systems interact with one
another
but we don't know like how that could
directly be extrapolated into the human
brain because the human brain is so
complex at the same time we have all of
this information from the general public
and people who have
reported and written and shared all of
these experiences
activating one or both of these systems
and so we're going to be like kind of
piecing through the big gap between
those two spaces
right on cool so with that said let's
get right into it so um
i understand that when we consume a
psilocybin mushroom or you know uh we
might call it a philosophy mushroom if
we want to talk about you know the
species but that's a mushroom that has
psilocybin the chemical in it so a
philosophy mushroom has psilocybin in it
and
once it's in the human body it's not
actually the psilocybin which creates
the the the reaction in the human body
it's actually silicin and so a silicy
mushroom has psilocybin in it which our
body converts to silicon and so it's the
silicon that's the active ingredient in
the end for us so would you explain that
process because i've never actually
heard it explained clearly um how our
body changes the psilocybin into the
silicon
so it's actually really similar it's
it's pretty similar to decarbon cannabis
the difference is that our body is very
efficient at changing uh psilocybin into
salocin
and um
basically the molecule psilocybin has a
phosphate group on it and a phosphate
group is this like very negatively
charged like bulky
uh piece of the molecule and that group
does a couple things it prevents it from
easily crossing into the brain it also
prevents it from binding to the
receptors and all of the effects are
felt when a molecule is able to bind and
activate a receptor so that phosphate
group changes the shape of the molecule
right it's this big bulky
negatively charged like piece on the
edge of it and so psilocybin is not
active but our body contains an enzyme
an enzyme is like a little machine that
does a chemical reaction
and our body takes psilocybin and turns
it into cellosin
by taking away that phosphate group and
leaving behind just an oxygen and a
hydrogen or a hydroxyl group and that's
what makes it active so psilocybin is
actually what would be called a pro drug
in pharmaceutical sciences there are
quite a few pro drugs actually um i
believe aspirin is an example of a pro
jug which is something that goes into
your body and then becomes activated by
the body so it's just like a different
class of molecules and they're not
active on their own they become active
when our body either in this case takes
off that phosphate group and then
removes that big bulky negative charge
and allows it to activate the receptors
okay so so once our body has removed
that group and and it becomes this uh
more
i don't know digestible or that's
probably bad choice of words but um
a usable uh salosin um that i had i had
not heard that pronunciation of it all
you start using that um
what does it go and bind with because
like you know the other times you've
been here when we've been doing the
endocannabinoid mechanics
[Applause]
uh series we're always talking about the
endocannabinoid system right and and
we're going to talk more about the
endocannabinoid system in second set but
what is this solosin molecule looking
for to connect with
also quickly i don't know that that
pronunciation is right or wrong i think
it's kind of like tomato tomato and
people prefer to pronounce things the
way that in my in my opinion some of
these things are pretty just pronounced
the way um that you've heard other
people pronounce them
but back to your question um what do
they activate so they activate the
serotonin system and serotonin system
receptors there are so many of these and
if you have ever seen the molecule it is
really really similar to serotonin
serotonin is a
tryptamine
it's in a class of molecules that is
created from the amino acid tryptophan
and they have a very distinctive
shape to them and solosin is almost
identical to serotonin they're very very
similar and so what you were saying
before um instead of calling it like
digestible
um what i would say is that cellosin
like is a puzzle piece that fits it fits
into the puzzle better
after the phosphate group has been
removed because it's trying to fit into
the same spot
on the receptors as serotonin
and it's the similarity in those shapes
that allows it to bind to it so
silic
solosin psilocybin doesn't bind very
well to any of the receptors as we
mentioned before it doesn't fit but
silocin binds really well to many of the
serotonin receptors i've heard it been
called a pan agonist before pan meaning
everything right
but it doesn't bind equally to all of
those serotonin receptors it does favor
some over the other specifically in
terms of like psychedelic psychoactive
effects
it's been linked mostly to the serotonin
2a
receptor it's a subreceptor type i
believe there are 18 there's there's
quite a few different types of serotonin
receptors we don't have data for every
single subtype of receptor
monsolosin and i think the only one that
i saw that it does not bind well to is
the serotonin 3 subtype receptor and
that receptor is actually a completely
different like type of switch if you
imagine these receptors are like
on and off switches
uh in the body that start all of these
domino effects there are these different
types of of switches right like i guess
if i'm going with this metaphor there's
like a regular light switch that you see
there's like a dimmer switch there are
like those metallic on and off switches
there's switches that are just buttons
that you press on and off and the
serotonin 3 receptor is a different
subtype than all the others and i think
that's in my opinion probably why it
doesn't bind as well to salosin but in
terms of the the activation um otherwise
it it seems like solosin activates
almost all of the other serotonin system
receptor subtypes which means that it
mimics serotonin in the brain
it's interesting too if it's a
pan-agonist and to use your light switch
example it kind of kind of makes me
think of like when you go into um
like a big auditorium or something
you'll see as you enter you know often
they'll be like a string of like seven
or eight light switches for like
different parts of the hall right and i
imagine silicon just showing up in the
human brain going let's party and just
like flick them all on you know um
is is the serotonin
um
receptor the only variety of receptor
that that silson is connecting to i mean
as we know when you when you take
you know
hallucinogenic mushrooms your brain just
like lights up right when you know we
know it as a first person experience but
we also know that when they when they
put people in you know mris when they're
when they're using and stuff that are
and or similar and people's brains are
just like lit up um are there other
um types of receptors that accept
silicon as well or is it mostly just in
the serotonin group
so from what i've read it's mostly just
in the serotonin group but the fact that
it's all of the serotonin subtypes is
what makes it very very unique to that
activity um i i think it here's another
thing that i'm unsure about is um so a
lot of the literature in the scientific
the previous scientific literature
focuses on serotonin i'm not sure that
every receptor subtype has actually been
tested because often
you only see what you're looking for and
it's not i'm not positive that it's been
you know ruled out that it wouldn't
interact with other receptors i think
the only one i know for certain that has
been ruled out that i saw was the
dopamine d2 receptor because that's one
key difference between
serotonin and lsd
is that lsd does activate the d2
receptor and sorry not serotonin
psilocybin and
salocin do not activate the dopamine
system whereas lsd does
activate that system partially so that's
the only one that i know
that i can speak to um
for certain that hasn't been like ruled
out but i i think that in terms of like
are there other there's it's kind of a
trick question because um are there
other things that are in the mushrooms
that could be activating other systems
that is very very possible and also
unexplored
all right um
so
because you study the serotonin system
so intimately you've got a different
perspective than just about everybody
else and i would like to hear your
thoughts on how
rare and
neat it is that that this one
molecule lights up so many serotonin
receptors at the same time right because
by by you saying that it suggests to me
that that most other molecules would not
light up so many of the different
serotonin receptors like how cool is
that like talk to us about like the
rarity of that and and why
mushrooms are unique because of that
so i think the most i think one of the
most interesting things is this contrast
from from my background in
pharmaceutical sciences it's the
contrast of um
you know synthetic pharmaceuticals that
target the the serotonin system all of
them kind of are structured around
avoiding the serotonin ii receptor
family because they're trying to like
avoid the effects
and it's it is rare um in terms of how
strongly it activates it it's rare i
know that there are other natural
products out there and other
naturally occurring molecules that do
work upon the serotonin system but they
don't do it with such like veracity or
potency like it's it's a very potent
interaction
and the reason for that is because it's
very very similar to serotonin and
another thing that's interesting about
psilocybin that i've always wondered um
is
it's purpose i guess i've always just
wondered about its original purpose in
the mushrooms because it clearly must be
doing something for them as well
and it's this is something that's like
far outside but in terms of natural
products you know these molecules in
these plants and in these funguses they
they are serving a purpose for those
living plants and living funguses as
well
and there's this big um
there's this big like homology or
similarity between all of those
molecules in the plants and in funguses
and in bacteria and in other living
things and then in all of the molecules
like inside us inside our brains and
bodies and
like circulating around in our blood
causing signaling systems and immune
system responses and i think it's
amazing that living things produce
molecules that are so comparable and so
active on the human systems
and that's just it's always been really
magical to me it's been a magical thing
with cannabis and the endocannabinoid
system and i think it's magical with the
serotonergics as well i think there's an
evolutionary link there
yeah i would have to agree with that and
you know you know you calling it magical
is one of the you know least scientific
things i've ever heard you say but it's
also it's also like really true right i
mean there are reasons why
humans have
um
put
mushrooms on a on a spiritual magical
otherworldly pedestal because the
effects that it has on the human brain
are
like literally mind-blowing right and so
um and it's beyond our
present um
scientific knowledge though we're we're
getting able to research more of it now
but but historically like if you don't
know what's how something functions it's
magic right and so that's not really an
inaccurate term
no and there's and it's it's also not
inaccurate that there is still so much
unknown left in the world even with the
amount of science that we have and i i i
love science i'm you know science is my
my passion but one of the things that i
learned from it is just this giant you
know giant unknown that is still there
and
in terms of like spirituality and
that level of unknown and that level of
faith there we're not we're not at a
place yet where we actually can say we
have a big understanding of it and in in
the research on
psychedelics they use this word
sometimes
in ineffable which means like you can't
describe it in words i i believe is the
definition
and that is something that i think is
really fascinating about specifically
the serotonin system um also the
endocannabinoid system and how they work
together but specifically linked to
serotonergic psychedelic experiences
is that it can create feelings and
experiences that are ineffable they're
mis they're mystic and magic and
spiritual
and deep
and we have yet to be able because we
can't describe them because they're
ineffable it's very very difficult to
study them but the fact that that comes
from these molecules that are also from
a living thing part of this planet is
just it is magical and yeah i love
um i love describing science that way
and i think it's it seems like a
hypocritical like um
maybe not hypocritical but it seems to
be like it would be in contrast to
itself but i've always said that um in
terms of merging my my scientific
passion with my spiritual beliefs i've
always said that both both science and
spirituality are ways of embracing and
understanding this like giant unknown
in the universe and there's just there's
just so much unknown and i think that's
one of the things that exploring and i'm
so excited to see as we can like open up
research and explore these you know this
interaction with the serotonin system
more i'm excited to see what we find um
and i'm i wouldn't be surprised if we
don't just find even more unknown yeah
amen and now i'm gonna go one more i'm
gonna go one more step into this unknown
magical spiritual before we get back to
the hard science and that is
um you know this this idea of an
ineffable experience comes up all the
time when talking about dmt
dimethyltryptamine
the experiences that humans have on on
significant doses of that drug are so
beyond
human regular experience that um it's
it's really cool that that
whole new descriptors have evolved
when talking about dmt and the
experience and and how it changes and
rewires the human brain
it demands the development of first new
vocabulary to decide to describe it if
so that humans can share their
experiences and then once it gets in
hand the hands of like scientific
researchers like you then then that kind
of
potentially sloppy
um new magical vocabulary that people
use to describe it then demands
new specific scientific vocabulary
and understanding to describe it at a
scientific level and um i think that
this kind of
um growth of the ineffable
drug experience becoming more
um
malleable by humans where we can like
talk about them and understand them more
i think that we are right at the front
of this this huge explosion of this kind
of learning by humans everywhere because
we're all getting
easier access to
these these plant medicines
and
um and and scientists are more
encouraged to research them now for
whatever reasons yeah it's just so much
more available and there's so much more
communication in the community that
helps i mean i think it's incredible
that so many people can have such
similar experiences also dmt is very
very similar um molecule to cellosin
they are almost identical because dmt is
almost identical to serotonin and
they're they're very similar in that way
but what i was describing earlier with
psilocybin turning into salicin
when you remove a phosphate group and
you leave a hydroxyl group just the oh
if you were to remove that hydroxyl
group that would be dmt
and
they're they're incredibly similar
molecules but then they have these
different effects and then the community
and what i was mentioning earlier about
how we have all of this information from
the community and from people who are
actively you know using and
using these these molecules and then
reporting on their experiences and
they're they're comparable they're
similar experiences and that ineffable
um
you know that
that ineffable experience or that
mysticism experience it's also given a
third name in in scientific literature
called oceanic boundlessness and that um
you know that entire
like experience is linked to actually
better outcomes like better health
outcomes and it's it's in to me super
interesting because essentially i equate
that in in some way
this is this is like my understanding of
it is that that's equated to me with
like a spiritual wellness or something
that is ineffable it's not something
that we're quantifying right now but we
can
say that if you have that mystical
ineffable experience or if you have
something like that that there is a
significant chance that it increases
your health outcome
which is a physical
quantitative response and so that is
just a piece down this road of this
whole like mind-body connection that
i think um you know is under is
under-researched i would say even
in all the things that i've read and
this is one of my things that i'm super
passionate about we're just scratching
the surface on understanding the
connection between our mind our bodies
and then how we view that connection to
the world and the rest of like the life
that's on this planet
beautiful i love how you put that all
right so let's let's bring us back in um
for back to the the heart harder science
uh that was a good that was away from
the tangent yeah that was that was a
good tangent but so let's bring it back
so so on on the during the
endocannabinoid mechanics
a series that we've been doing together
um you mentioned kind of um as a passing
thought that
mushrooms interact with the
endocannabinoid system too which was
originally what gave me the idea for for
this episode um you've already explained
to us very clearly how the the um
the the silicon
molecule lights up so many of the
serotonin receptors after that
particular group is stripped off to
stripped off it um i'm curious how um
this the silicon molecule interacts with
the endocannabinoid system as well
so there's two different ways and it's
it's like an indirect way so the first
one
is that the 2a the serotonin to a
receptor which is the one that's been
linked to
um the psychedelic experiences like
that receptor when you activate it
actually leads to an increase in
endocannabinoids that's one of the
that's one of the downstream effects of
activating this receptor and so in the
first way you're increasing your level
of of endocannabinoids like after you
take psilocybin because it activates
these receptors and that's part of what
what those receptors do
the next way is a little bit more
complicated and it has to do with the
fact that we more recently have learned
that these receptors are not operating
by themselves so when i say like the
serotonin
um
5ht2a receptor you know previously to
let's say like 10 years ago
we were all assuming that that receptor
kind of operated by itself or it
operated with another version of the
same receptor like serotonin and
serotonin and it was only more recently
that we've discovered
that these receptors can actually
bind to another receptor in a different
system and that that will change the way
that it signals and not much is known
in terms of how it changes the signaling
and what the downstream effects of this
are but what is known is that the
serotonin 5ht2a receptor does bind to
the cb1 receptor which is the main
endocannabinoid system receptor and the
receptor that's responsible for the
therapeutic effects or most of the
therapeutic effects of cannabis
and so that piece of it is less
understood but
is there there is some population in the
brain of serotonin 2a receptors that
when they are being activated by
salosine will probably be attached to a
cb1 receptor at least in part like they
exist together in the brain cells
and will come together and
operate together and when those two
receptors are operating together their
signaling can be altered and we don't
really have a a great um tangible grasp
on how and what that does but we do know
that it affects the endocannabinoid
system because the cb1 receptor is the
main receptor for the endocannabinoid
system
okay um let's take one step back for a
moment um i think i probably should have
started the set with this but would you
give like a just like an easy thumbnail
explanation of what the serotonin system
is in the human body for for folks who
may not be familiar with it
okay sure yeah the serotonin system is
one of the best known like
neurotransmitter signaling systems in
the brain and in the body we talk a lot
about serotonin making you happy i think
that's usually one of the main
one of the main associations that people
have with it but serotonin is a molecule
and the serotonin system just like the
endocannabinoid system is made up of the
receptors and the enzymes that work upon
the serotonin molecule and serotonin
controls a lot of very very important
functions and i this is where my
interest originally came to the table is
that the serotonin system and the
endocannabinoid system actually have
like a huge overlap in the things that
they control and how they work together
and they're localized in some of the
similar areas in how they like modify
this control um one of the most
important ones being like the brain and
the gut or the gi tract interaction so
serotonin
just like the endocannabinoids is a
signaling molecule and the system itself
is all over your body and controls like
a huge number of things that's why
there's so many different receptors and
that's why they are
you know
expressed in different parts of of the
brain and the body that help to to
regulate these um
these different processes
so that sets up my next question great
because i was going to follow up with
you know
are are the serotonin system and the
endocannabinoid system
like standing next to each other at at
equal
levels of complexity and control or
does the endocannabinoid system
control slash
balance the serotonin system because
when we talk about the endocannabinoid
system we're all talk we're always
talking about how it's the
the body's natural thermostat and if
you've got a system that's running hot
it'll cool it down and if it's running
if it's sluggish it'll it'll pick it up
is is the serotonin cycle is the
serotonin system one of the systems the
endocannabinoid
system
modulates or are they are they are they
like two different cooks in the kitchen
sounds like there's a lot of overlap so
i'm not really sure how you're gonna
answer that
yeah it's it's a complicated answer i i
usually say that it's it's a
relationship the best metaphor i have
for it is probably marriage i think it's
like a marriage they both
um have things that they take care of on
their own and together but neither one
of them almost ever operates without
some form of feedback from the other
system
um so like for an example of this as i
mentioned earlier if you activate the 2a
the serotonin 2a receptor you end up
with elevated levels of endocannabinoids
so that's
an example of the serotonin system
modifying the endocannabinoid system on
the flip side the endocannabinoid system
is capable of modifying levels of
serotonin um is capable of modifying the
risk the the density of the serotonin
receptors so it goes the other direction
and they they fulfill very different
roles while they are also
modifying the same um like overall
purpose in in the body so they work
together sometimes they work against
each other other times and it's it's
incredibly complicated dance i think
all right so so we're talking about the
the complexity between these two systems
and how
they're getting turned on by by silicon
and you know we're usually talking about
the endocannabinoid system and and whole
plant medicine right because both you
and i are very much whole plant cannabis
advocates
and i know that mushrooms have their own
terpenes um are there reasons to make
sure that we take a whole mushroom or an
infused tea instead of isolated
psilocybin or
yeah they're probably psilocybin
crystals because like crystallized
psilocybin is becoming much more
available
as people have have made best practices
for that extraction process
and i know that a lot of people tend to
want to avoid eating the flesh of the
mushroom because
it upsets a lot of people's stomachs and
so like some people believe that you
should eat the whole mushroom some
people say you know since it's all water
soluble you do it in an infused tea and
then you can leave the flesh of the
mushroom you know in the strainer and
then some people just go for the crystal
because they see it to be more of a pure
easier on the stomach experience and i
don't think there's been a whole lot of
actual research on this yet except for
like you know individual psychonauts
doing it um but as far as like the brain
chemistry part of it you know is there
is there a justification for whole plant
mushroom
i i think that there is but i also you
know there's not a lot of research on
the different molecules that are in the
different strains of these mushrooms or
even just in them in the main strains so
in terms of like the active compounds
yes like psilocybin is the active
compound in in the mushrooms it's been
identified but there's going to be a lot
of other things present in the actual
living mushroom
and i i think that like the difference
between like the psilocybin there's a
pretty much a perfect analogy here
between that and
whole full spectrum
cannabis products and like say like a
rosin press or something that is like
extracted partially purified um versus
then like isolate or or distillate and i
think you know similar to cannabis i
think that there are advantages and
disadvantages to
each um
each version there are certainly
advantages to isolated forms of things
because uh for one it's reproducible
right like as opposed to whenever you
have a living um
whenever you have a living thing
producing you know a large number of
products there is the chance that they
will it's probable that you would get
different effects but i would argue that
that's also a positive um once you are
once you can understand it which we are
i think scratching the surface of of
doing that um i do know that there are
just so many things in all mushrooms not
just psilocybin mushrooms that are worth
investigating that haven't yet um there
are tons of like
different types besides even like its
own terpenes actually i recently read a
paper where they found molecules and
mushrooms that activate the
endocannabinoid system which makes them
cannabinoids um these are not psilocybin
mushrooms they're different mushrooms
but it's it's interesting because it's
it could exist in the psilocybin
mushrooms as well because we don't
actually have a ton of information on on
what that what that looks like and on
isolating those compounds and then
testing them against the receptors um
the order of operations would go first
like taking everything out of the
mushrooms and then kind of separating
them out into like types of molecules
and then like how many of them are
present and then testing those
individually um against each of the
receptors to see what is going on um and
i i haven't actually seen a ton of
information on the smaller what would be
like the rare molecules that are that
are in um the mushrooms but there's
certainly
many many that are there and probably
many that have yet to be investigated or
even discovered
what a great time to be
a you know a college or
or
post
postgraduate
student who is both a psychonaut and a
scientist like i remember back in school
you know there were there were
like the the odd folks who you knew were
doing drug stuff in the lab when i was
in school
but it was very shush and very frowned
upon and the school could not find out
but now there's like full-on programs
what a great time to be a scientist
psychonaut like all this stuff is open
to folks and we don't know it yet and
yet now we're allowed to research it i
think you just can't deny you can't deny
that there is therapeutic benefit
because there's there's therapeutic
benefit and there's also
you know it's the same thing that
happened the revolution with cannabis i
really think helped pave the way
for this to occur it's like something
that was so stigmatized and that still
is and i think that we still have work
to do
but you know it it has really changed
the culture around cannabis has really
changed and it's been a lot of work by a
lot of people who've come well before me
and you're one of them and has done a
lot of work in changing this this stigma
for the better and i think that that's
paved the way
because we are all able to see now or a
larger population is able to see like
wow there's a lot of therapeutic benefit
that has yet to be explored um
everyone's more open i think to that and
i i think it's really really exciting
because you can't deny that there's
therapeutic benefit here and that
understanding it will only help us to
like reduce the risk of the negative
effects
right on fantastic all right so um let's
wrap this up and go to commercial during
the second set when we come back we are
going to talk about the thresholds for
different dosages for mushrooms and how
that impacts the mechanics of the brains
at different thresholds
you are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is pharmacologist miyabi
shields
[Music]
there are a lot of good people launching
new businesses in cannabis psilocybin
and other psychedelics and it's very
strange time for us
in the same moment that psilocybin
mushrooms are illegal at the federal
level they are becoming increasingly
legal in states across the country
these businesses leading the way into
the future of plant medicines require
specialized legal representation by
attorneys who have depth not only in
litigation mergers and acquisitions but
also in psychedelic and other plant
medicines
green light law group has been
empowering cannabis businesses since
2014 and as the market has diversified
into psilocybin and other plant
medicines green light has been right
there evolving with their diverse
clients to provide legal expertise with
a high level of legal acumen creative
strategy and precision that comes with
an intimate and specific understanding
of both business law and plant medicine
if you are a business owner trying to
navigate the layered local and national
drug laws on your own you are at risk of
fumbling these confusing and quickly
changing laws complicate everything
green light law group is ready to help
you when hit with a lawsuit or because
you are shafted by a vendor or business
partner or simply because you want to
stay legal and could use some
preventative guidance before cultivating
a controlled substance as an
entrepreneur
green light law group is a collection of
folks who care profoundly about their
work and i know this is true because i
know the folks from green light
there is a huge difference between a big
legal firm who has decided to start
representing a few drug companies versus
working with a collection of high
integrity passionate lawyers who are
personally interested in new plant
medicines and firmly believe in their
power to heal contact green light law
group today and learn more about the
services they can offer your
industry-leading cannabis or
psychedelics company
that's green light law group at
greenlightlawgroup.com
[Music]
for 20 years humboldt seed company has
been family owned and providing reliable
high yielding seeds originating in
northern california while the current
trend is to slap one super male into a
line of hyped strains humboldt seed
company continues to breed with
precision and care by doing large sifts
and back crosses to emphasize the
absolute best traits that a line has to
offer this kind of breeding takes time
talent and space to work
no matter what kind of aroma you are
particularly into humboldt seed will
likely have something you'll love if you
love fruit you can choose from banana
mango apricot papaya blueberry blood
orange melon and lemons across their
various strains they have all gas glue
and classic sour diesel lines as well of
course there are the heritage california
strains like og kush jack hair and
headband and their award-winning
blueberry muffin is one that delights
just about everybody's palate especially
when concentrated
humboldt seed company is proud to bring
to market the infamous freak show
cultivar 2 which has a great thc high
but looks so much like a fern that some
folks can't even identify it as cannabis
it's a plant that really needs to be
seen to be believed
if you're looking for well-balanced cbd
seeds humboldt seed company can turn you
on to cbd strains that actually have
flavor like the dill and pepper terpenes
of willie g's lebanese land race
whether you are looking for regular
feminized or autoflowers humboldt seed
company has the gear to make this your
best growing cycle ever
visit
humboldtseedcompany.com today to check
out their line of vigorous genetics
download their catalog and find out
where you can pick them up you can also
check out their instagram at the
humboldt seed company to check out their
gorgeous flowers and the extraordinary
freak show plant
humboldt seed company let them know
shango sent you
[Music]
sometimes the topics i want to share
with you are far too brief for an entire
shaping fire episode
in those instances i post them to
instagram i invite you to follow my two
instagram profiles and participate
online the shaping fire instagram has
follow-up posts to shaping fire episodes
growing and processing best practices
product trials and of course gorgeous
flower photos the shangolos instagram
follows my travels on cannabis garden
tours my successes and failures in my
own garden insights and best practices
from personal grows everywhere and
always gorgeous flower photos on both
profiles the emphasis is on sharing what
i've learned in a way that you can
replicate it in your own garden your own
hash lab or for your own cannabinopathic
health so i encourage you to follow at
shaping fire and at shango lows and join
our online community on instagram
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and my guest today is pharmacologist
miyabi shields so in the second set
we're going to be talking a lot more
about specific dosing and thresholds for
dosing and so we're going to start off
by
defining some of these terms we're going
to be using um if you just simply google
you know mushroom dosage chart you'll
find a lot of different
um
representations of this chart and you
know there's a little bit of variability
but generally the doses we're going to
be talking about today fall into uh five
different categories um the first is the
micro dose and and while it's true that
you know how much is the right micro
dose for you is something that you need
to work out for yourself generally
speaking uh people discuss it as being
0.1 gram of of the mushroom itself and
you know um you know i prefer 0.08 some
other people may uh you know have their
own number but generally when we're
talking about a micro dose we're talking
about one um then there is a term i
actually learned from miyabi uh when we
were prepping for this which is a museum
dose which is
a little bit more than a micro dose
you're actually looking to have you know
a little bit more going on in your head
which is going to be about more like
like 0.5 of a gram so about about a half
gram there
um and then there is uh the mini dose
and the mini dose is more like one to
two grams so you're definitely going to
get some you know psychoactive activity
but uh you know you can probably still
be around people and um but then there's
then there's the macro dose which is
going to be anywhere between three to
four grams generally and at that point
you're going to be having a significant
response you know you're probably going
to be more likely to avoid people
um and and you know you'll be you'll be
seeing you know sacred geometry and
nature and and you're putting together a
whole bunch of things and um you know
often
often um
people can tell that you're tripping
by this point
and then above the macro above three to
four grams um you know you know above
four grams you know people go five six
seven grams sometimes more which
is
epic and then these are generally called
these like heroic doses or god seeing
doses something like that so
um so you can get yourself more familiar
with this scale by simply you know
googling mushroom dosage chart but but
those are the general those that's the
vocabulary that we're going to be using
today all right with that said
so miyabi like why do we often
experience permanent or at least you
know longish term temporary changes to
ourselves after taking mushrooms because
we we have the experience
during that the after we take it right
but but it feels like things change for
us for a while and there's like this
afterglow and then eventually it it
feels like certain certain attributes
wear off but certain learning stays um
so so i'm kind of wondering if there's
like a half-life for for a mushroom
experience as far as like the neurology
goes
so i think in terms of the after effects
or the after glow effects i think in my
opinion those are directly linked to
molecules or effects that the that the
slows and molecules had that are still
in your system actively in terms of the
more longer term changes and effects
that people can feel
i think that's a that's a different
that's a different piece but what both
of them kind of point to in what's
unique about the serotonergics and
activating the serotonin system seems to
be this disruption in what would be like
the default pathway and all of us have
like we we all have a ton of
subconscious
default brain activity that we're going
through and that our brain just does
automatically for us and we can try um
to consciously
think of things from different
perspectives but i mean i think most of
us have had a situation in our lives
where we've thought through something a
million different ways and we can't seem
to find a way through right or we can we
can't approach the problem from any more
ways than we're aware of and a piece of
that comes from our brain being stuck in
some of these like similar pathways and
so one of the reasons why i think that
there are these lasting effects has to
do with just the disruption of that
pattern the disruption of the same
patterns happening over and over and
over again
and the creation of new patterns and
sometimes i think that
in terms of like an after effect and
some of them staying or some of them
leaving it could have to do with these
pathways still being freshly activated
there is a saying that neurons or so
neurons or brain cells but brain cells
that fire together will wire together
and when a brain cell is activated and
activates another brain cell and it
makes this like new circuitry or this
new path there are actual physical and
chemical reactions between those two
brain cells that facilitate them firing
again
and it isn't until they are kind of
weeded out that they stop firing uh and
i think that when
you are activating your serotonin system
you know with mushrooms and as we
mentioned in the first set it's a
pan-agonism or it's an activation of all
different types of serotonin receptors
all over the brain you end up creating a
lot of new pathways or a lot of new
signaling
systems and you disrupt this this
default um i've heard it described as a
uh i think it's called the default
network or a default mode i've heard it
described that way
in terms of disrupting that you're kind
of taking
your brain
out of that that routine and like
showing your brain or
like facilitating your brain going down
these other pathways that are new
avenues to approach things and and new
perspectives
so that's that's one piece of it and
then and then the other piece i think is
something that we touched on a little
bit earlier which is mysticism or
oceanic boundlessness and or at the
higher do at the higher doses and
thresholds we were talking about um
changes in your perception of yourself
or your ego
usually called ego death right or ego
disillusion
and changing the way that you perceive
yourself and your identity and your
place in the world
and how that can have a
a huge lasting effect on the on your
perspective and how you approach like
the rest of your life um so i'm not sure
if that was too broad i've been
answering
for your question no that was that was
that was good but i'm also going to
follow up with something very specific
right so so
taking that as being true
would you describe
what what is happening at a very
specific biological chemical level when
we we all talk about these you know
mushrooms help
um create new neural paths and
um
mushrooms help
deepen your neural paths
what does that mean
in
um
mechanically in the brain like that
that's that's the storytelling way of
saying it what's the specific chemical
way of saying that
so
this the chemical way of saying is is
that um
if you imagine like your brain is like a
network right like your brain is a
network of transportation
and things are going to and from um
you know the stronger and more often so
the more often like two brain cells will
fire together the stronger that
connection will be and in terms of the
the biology and the chemistry of that it
actually strengthens it in terms of like
it will physically create proteins that
will link themselves together that are
like little velcro proteins it will
become a bigger and stronger like
surface area or synapse like area there
are multiple ways that your body can
make it so that that connection happens
easier it's faster and easier it's like
the equivalent i would say of like
having a dirt road versus like a freeway
um or a throughway where there's just
like tons of lanes and tons of cars are
moving and there's no lights or anything
um and the more often that you use
something or some pathway the more
likely your brain is to turn that
pathway into a freeway or a through way
and that
when you're
when you're in a pattern or a habit or
just actually as we go about our lives
our brain is constantly trying to find
the most efficient way to activate those
same pathways that it does all of the
time and so when it when you're saying
that when you take a mushroom and it
changes this neural pathway it promotes
neural growth and it like deepens these
pathways what you're saying is that the
molecule activates these serotonin
receptors then when it activates those
serotonin receptors it causes a new
pathway a new domino effect to occur and
that when this domino effect happens and
you have this
this new pathway being opened up it
deepens this connection between that
otherwise wouldn't be there between
these two brain cells because it's
almost like a false
connection it's it's stimulating or it's
mimicking what would happen if serotonin
had been released between those two
cells does that yeah and so and so but
when you say uh that this this pathway
is being deepened um
chemistry wise you're saying that more
of these
velcro
like meshing proteins are being formed
and so it's like having a a a thin
copper cord connecting things versus
a a big fat copper cord or some other
it's like your your bandwidth is
increasing along that path
yeah and and your brain cells are all
attached to usually they many of them
have multiple connections and it they're
constantly in flux like changing
changing these connections although as
we get older we do it less and less like
in general
it's often referred to as plasticity in
general our brains become less plastic
as we get older and so we start to only
we start to only strengthen these
connections that are currently being
used and it's not always like the the
proteins that um are like the velcro
molecules it could also be like the
levels of receptors that are present the
levels of enzymes that are present or
transporter proteins that are present um
there's a few different ways it's i mean
the body is very very
um complex and in this amazing way
there's a lot of like there's a lot of
different ways to do the same thing and
they all support each other um and so
when when i say that like when you're
when you're disrupting that pattern
you're activating new pathways and
you're you're kind of simulating uh
maybe a new interaction that wouldn't
have otherwise happened because there
wouldn't be serotonin there
right i totally thought so actually
there's like a whole series of processes
that happen it's not like
one thing happens to
to make the the neural net uh
more robust it's actually
making these vel velcro proteins it is
uh setting out in new directions to make
the neural network more complex and have
more redundancies
it's um
i don't know i don't know what the other
ones would be but the idea is it's a
bunch of others
yeah it could be even changing the gene
expression of certain receptors or
certain factors in the cell because
these i mean i won't i'm not going to go
into way too much detail on this part
but it's these receptors like there's
different classes of them and and we
know
so much about what they do with the
signaling pathway when they're activated
will go and it it can take this one
thing called a g protein and it splits
up into three other things and each of
those
three pieces that get split apart will
go to a different part and do a
different activity um and it's it's
incredibly complex and it's beautiful
and in my opinion
and there's there's so many ways in
which they end up being closer um tied
to to one another and it's it's similar
to um
yeah i guess it's it's a it's a rounded
approach
that it happens in general it's this is
not actually unique to any of the
receptor systems it happens in general
when you activate systems in tandem and
when your brain is is forming these
connections
all right so let's move forward and
let's talk about the differences in
um
the different results in in the neural
network based on these different
threshold doses that we set up at the
top of the set so
um because we know that like when when
we apply these different doses we are
trying to do different things and if we
are getting different results
um that's telling me that that the brain
is firing differently on these different
um amounts so so let's start by talking
about micro dosing so we're talking
about
um uh uh you know we'll just use point
one since that is generally um
taken as the as the baseline micro dose
so at so so more or less the the the
main protocols that people follow are
either like five days on two days off or
three days on one day off which you know
are wildly similar between the stamets
and the fatimid protocols one way or
another you're taking this small amount
of
0.1 for several days in a row and then
you're taking a little break and then
you're doing it again
what do we know about what is happening
for this repetitive micro dose
versus
what we'll talk about in a minute which
is like when we take you know a mini or
a macro dose what what is the
uh what's going on mechanically in our
brain that makes the micro dose um
efficient
very effective
yes there's a there's a couple there's a
couple different pieces of this one the
first the first piece is actually what
happens at a different dose to the
receptor and i'll just pick the 5ht2a
receptor since that's the one that's
classically associated with the effects
of mushrooms that receptor
when we're talking about like how a
molecule will attach to a receptor um
there's activating it there's
inactivating it and then there's like
everything in between there's all of
these ways in which you can do it but in
in just like the most general way we can
say it um solution activates the 5ht2a
receptor
but it does that for a certain amount of
time and there is a statistical
probability of it binding to the
receptor so let's say solution
is in the body like you're taking a
micro dose of it
there's not that much
so there's not a large concentration and
so the statistical probability that it
will bind to the receptor is less
which is part of how it makes it less
active because there's less of them that
will be bound to the receptors causing
these effects so that's one difference
is the number of molecules bound to
these receptors
as a result of the actual way like
smaller amount that's that's present in
the body
because this is true for all receptors
um all receptors and the interaction
with their with the molecules that
activate them whether that's you know
drugs or molecules inside our bodies
that um interaction is an equilibrium
which just means that it's a balance
between what is there and what is not
there and so the more of any of the drug
or any of the molecule that you have the
more you're going to push that
equilibrium to having the molecule bound
to the receptor and there will be more
and more of them bound so that's the
first difference
in terms of the micro dose you have like
a very low amount and so you probably
don't have all of your serotonin
receptors bound to solution
there's like it's highly likely that
it's only a partial number of them at
any given time because the dosage is
lower
and then that leads to differences in
the downstream signaling
because when the receptor is activated
as i mentioned earlier it starts this
really long signaling cascade and most
of the time it ends up with a number of
changes but those changes are additive
right so if there's one receptor that's
happening and then another receptor um
that will be different than if there's
only one
i follow that
um
is there
a
does the variable that you're doing it
so often adds something because like
certainly macro doses which we'll talk
about
are you know have their own
special
you know benefits but
uh i'm curious about the fact that
taking this small amount five days in a
row does does does hitting that same
note again and again and again is there
so like some kind of like
like training that is taking place or or
when it's that often you're you're
seeing reactions in other systems or
something um there's got to be something
to this um to doing it so often oh i'm
so glad you brought that up because i
would totally forgot about that was my
second but it was my second piece that i
was gonna say um the second piece of it
that is different is that you're doing
it regularly so on the first end you're
only doing a very low level activation
it's not it's probably not all of the
serotonin receptors right and then the
second difference being that you are
doing it regularly even regardless of
the pro the protocol it is it's regular
um and it's it's pretty consistent so in
this case in the micro dosing case if
we're gonna compare it to what your body
feels like is happening your body feels
a little bit like you just have a little
more serotonin in your body
all the time because you're doing it
regularly right so your body then does
have um what is called a homeostatic
change or a it's a um
it's a reaction all of our bodies are
constantly balancing what is happening
today and what happened yesterday with
what is going to happen tomorrow that's
one of the main
things that that our body is responsible
for doing
and so
in terms of there being like low levels
of your body thinking that there's low
levels of serotonin or slightly higher
levels of serotonin that are normally
there um there are definitely changes
that it will
induce that are different from
what we're discussing later in the macro
dose it's different from then a very
large scale uh interaction with all of
the serotonin receptors just once um and
it's actually the same mechanism or a
similar mechanism to
most of
the like long-term
like mental health medications also
function based on this sort of long-term
low-dose effect or homeostatic effect
that your body changes over time right
like i think it's very common for um
mental health prescription drugs for you
to be monitored over time because they
don't take effect for a couple weeks and
then you know it's it's a titration um
it's a it's a similar
thing or it's a similar scale of an of
an effect
all right so um with the microdoses um
we are
uh getting
some binding but not complete binding to
all the receptors and the fact that
we're doing it regularly
um
i don't know i guess i could say creates
new opportunities for the neural network
to use its resources differently would
that be a fair way to put it in layman's
terms
yeah
i think that's a great explanation i'd
say that doing it regularly induces
small changes in the brain as if you
had slightly higher levels of serotonin
all the time
will that cause me to produce less
serotonin like will will it leave you
like like if you stopped micro dosing
suddenly would it would it leave me in a
serotonin depleted state because the
the mushrooms have been
using those receptors
i haven't seen any information that
supports that but
is it possible that it increases the
levels of like enzymes that metabolize
serotonin um it is but
i don't i don't think i've seen anything
that supports that it would leave you
like with a depletion although there are
some um molecules out there that do and
that it's like documented that they do
um
or they can have that effect like one of
them um
i'm thinking it is um
mdma
and it does it does induce like a
a change and this is at like larger
larger doses but um it does induce a
change that leads to like a temporary um
feeling of like depletion
afterwards all right so let's jump up to
uh jump up the scale to macro doses so
now we're talking between like you know
three and four grams roughly of of the
mushroom flesh
at this point um we're not really
talking about doing this regularly like
a micro dose we're gonna we're gonna
take you know five days a week this is
more something that folks do
um you know
semi-regularly or a couple times a year
or once a year or this is more an event
this is this is a ceremony for a lot of
people unless they're just partying on
it for most folks this is you know they
are doing this to create meaning in
their lives or whatever and um
uh so we're not talking about doing it
regularly but we are talking about doing
a hell of a lot more of it so um
what do you see from your perspective of
the the differences between the macro
and the micro experience that you just
laid out for us
i think that there's a it's clearly a
big difference between activating all
all of the receptors at this at the same
time also because um so the other thing
that i that i should mention now about
the microdosing is that when you're at
these lower levels not all the receptors
will be activated equally either like i
mentioned like some of them will be
active and some of them will be inactive
um at the lower doses it's way more
likely that the solution molecules are
only activating
certain receptor subtypes that it's
especially bad it's especially attracted
to um and then as you get into the
higher and higher doses it will start
attaching to all of the serotonin
receptors because there's so much there
right that it's going to activate all of
the different types and all of them at
once and all all over the place and this
you know if you've seen them in the in
the brain scans you end up with these
like beautiful brains that are just like
completely lit up
and in this case um
in terms of like the the big long-term
benefit in in the bigger doses i
definitely think that it is linked to
the mysticism or oceanic boundlessness
and or ineffable
way of describing that that experience
um you mentioned that people do it to
try to like fix something or to you know
the set in the setting being really
important
um you know i think it's
i think it's interesting because i think
about it as like a problem or if a
problem um
is like a mountain one of my friends put
this really beautifully like if you have
a problem
and and it's a mountain that you're
trying to climb and you just end up
trying to approach it from different
trail heads eventually like you probably
will find a way to climb the mountain
but the problem is sometime
to a point in our lives where we've
approached that same mountain so many
times that we can't possibly see a
different way to you know climb up that
mountain and we're just you know we we
don't have that option
and i think one of the main um positive
attributes of a big macro dose which is
just one time
or way less frequent is that you have
this activation where you activate all
of the receptor subtypes
at the same time
and so you have a way larger
disruption in that default pathway and
you have a way larger
activation
of
the extraneous others or new types of
pathways new perspectives and new
thoughts
that you could then
reintegrate and
you know take from that take from that
experience in a different way
do we have any idea
what
what uniquely is happening when you
activate all of those receptors at the
same time if if a microdose is
you know
we're we're pushing the button on some
of the receptors and so we're doing this
kind of slow and steady wins the race
kind of improvement for
the neural network
versus taking a macro dose where you're
essentially taking all of the buttons on
all of the receptors and just mashing
the hell out of them so so you're you're
going from you know one person singing
every day to suddenly this whole coral
all singing together and the melody it
creates something that is way more than
the sum of its parts do we know what
that is in the brain when we're taking
macro doses is there some state in the
brain that we achieve
from
mashing all of those receptors at the
same time i mean we know how it feels
right but i'm curious to know do we know
what's happening
like chemically in the brain
that
um
at the same time we're having these
these spiritual experiences
i feel like chemically in the brain it's
probably chaos it's like
it's like you're activating every
serotonergic cell i'm not just in the
brain too i mean at the macro doses like
there's body effects there's like
stomach effects and other things but
we're talking about the brain
um you're activating and you're super
activating all of the serotonin
like neurons that then go on they go on
to activate other things right like i
mentioned earlier
um that they activate and can and modify
the endocannabinoid system but serotonin
also plays an important role in the
dopamine system and it's originally this
is like an older belief it used to be
believed that serotonin and dopamine
were like contrary to one another or
that they um
they were like opposites and they they
balanced each other out and it's been
the more and more that we've looked into
all of these systems for that matter not
just serotonin dopamine and the
endocannabinoid system but specifically
those three um they're very very closely
linked together and so you have this
massive activation of the serotonin
system but you're also going to have
this massive downstream activation of
the dopamine system and the
endocannabinoid system
and in terms of
of scientifically
and at my level what is what is
happening i
think
from from my understanding of of what
would happen to the receptors at that
point is that all of them are doing all
of their downstream signaling pathways
at the same time there is a massive
overlap between some of the pathways
being synergistic which means that they
increase each other and some of the
pathways being um antagonistic or they
they cancel each other out um like for
example the the serotonin 2a and 2c
receptors
often are viewed as canceling each other
out when it comes to how they affect
dopamine so all of this is kind of like
competing and happening at the same time
and what what i think we know at least
one of the things that
we're we're learning um increasingly
learning is that coming coming out of
this like for the health benefits and
where
where those come from
it appears to be linked to
this feeling of of a deep uh
connectedness experience that is
incredible to me that it's linked to a
system in the brain or in an interaction
in the brain
but that certainly seems to be
more profound at the higher doses
okay um one more question on this track
before we move on to the next topic area
which is um you mentioned that at the
macro doses not only are the serotonin
receptors all being mashed on
but also there's all these other effects
in the other parts of the body including
the endocannabinoid system and in the
gut and
you know certainly we know that the
bowels are lit up um and and you know
breathing is impacted in some ways uh
certainly your muscle sets react to it
um can you talk a little bit about the
the non
receptors that get lit by a macro dose
and kind of explain to us what's
happening in the totality of our bodies
because like mushrooms are a very whole
body drug
oh yeah so the easiest thing i think to
describe is the stomach one because
that's like very
it's it's part of the process um you
have the most serotonin receptors in
your gut and gi
area and in your stomach your stomach
produces huge amounts of serotonin
and so activating those serotonin
receptors that's part of what causes
that stomach upset there's also other
things in in mushrooms that i think add
to that effect but a piece of that you
know upset stomach feeling comes from
activating the receptors that are in
your gut and in your stomach and
other like otherwise there's this
there's this communication
back and forth always between your brain
and your body and between what is called
like the peripheral or like your body's
nervous system and then your central
nervous system so like one of the things
it's
like the the feeling of like how you can
have decreased pain or decreased um
you know like like temperature
regulation even just decreased like
sensory feedback in general right um a
piece of that comes from this another
disruption or a communication disruption
between like peripheral and central um
and when you are
flooding your body with a molecule that
activates receptors that are everywhere
um and that are so expressed in your
central nervous system and in the core
of controlling these things
um and that's a piece of what causes the
like whole effect or the whole
experience is that there's always a
feedback um between what's going on in
the brain and what's going on in the
body and these these little loops that
our our body goes through they're
they're regulated
along the way in in many different
pieces by these neurotransmitters and so
by taking something that mimics
serotonin you're modifying
every piece of of that loop for those
systems
are there serotonin receptors throughout
the body similar to endocannabinoid
receptors throughout the body
so it's similar i don't believe that
they have the same exact profile of the
amount so both the endocannabinoid
system and the serotonin system are
expressed very very highly in the brain
and both of them are expressed also in
the gi tract but the endocannabinoid
system i believe is more in the fat
tissue than the serotonin system is i
believe the serotonin system is also
found more heavily in like the cardiac
or the heart
area i both the endocannabinoid system
and the serotonin system are
all over the place um but in terms of
like how highly they're expressed i
think they have a slightly different uh
expression pattern
you know i think that if you asked me i
would have said oh yeah of course
there's serotonin receptors in the gut i
mean yeah of course but but i think i
also forgot that until you mentioned it
again and
if if i'm think if i'm now thinking more
holistically instead of oh serotonin
receptors in the brain and i'm thinking
about oh serotonin receptors in like
these groupings all around the body
suddenly it makes a lot more sense why
mushrooms activate so many different
places in the body
um
you know it's it's not that the mushroom
has to have a bunch of different
chemicals to reach these different
places it's just the receptors are are
all over the place and i want to follow
up on on
as you were explaining that you
mentioned that that you believe that
there are other chemicals in the
mushroom that activate in the stomach um
uh do you have anything more to say
about that about what these other
chemicals may be i mean i know that
there's
probably tons depending on the strain of
mushroom that you're looking at but one
of the type the class of molecules that
i'm really interested in has to do with
like sugars um mushrooms can produce and
mushrooms produce these really
complicated it can produce these really
complicated types of molecules that are
like similar to sugar or like linked to
sugars
um i mean
and then i'm also interested in very
very similar compounds to psilocybin or
cellosin that there are probably or
possibly
many similar other forms of of those
molecules that share a similar shape and
are just slightly different kind of
similar to the rare cannabinoids right
so if you think about like the
biosynthetic pathways that these
mushrooms and that the cannabis plant
they that the pathways that they go
through to create these molecules um
they are done by enzymes which are like
little machines like i mentioned earlier
that do chemical reactions and those
little machines are not always perfect
they can make mistakes and they can
create like little off-by-products and
things and sometimes they just will
create a certain amount of like little
amounts of things and so this is one of
the differences between
isolated extracts and like whole um
plant or whole or whole whole formula
yeah whole fungus extracts right um
is that you're not gonna like eliminate
any of those like mistakes or just like
trace
trace amounts that are slightly slightly
different right because um i mean this
is like an example you brought up
earlier with dmt
there's the different types um and
that's kind of what you're when when
people talk about the different types of
dmt i think there's like red and
all these different like versions versus
like the crystal
um versus like an oil you're you're
talking about like different like slight
modifications or derivatives that are
present in the plant um in small amounts
they're in smaller amounts than the
other than the other molecules and i
believe that you know psilocybin oslosan
would be no different i believe that
there would be small amounts and i'm i'm
not sure possibly it's already been
found i just haven't i haven't seen it
in the literature but i i think it's
it's quite possible or very very
possible that it's there and it exists
and that um in all the different strains
um it's that there are complementary
molecules um present and that that's a
piece of what's different between all of
these different strains of mushrooms is
what else is in there it's not the
psilocybin content that's different well
the psilocybin content can vary between
these different strands of mushrooms
absolutely but that they also have other
complementary molecules inside of them
and i have
like ideas of what i think that they
could be but um i would be really really
excited to look at it hopefully one day
in the future right on
so so when comparing the micro dose uh
permanence of change to a macro dose
permanence of change um
would you suggest that there's any uh
difference in permanence between the
two varieties or two thresholds of
dosages like if we talk about like the
event the the the benefits of micro
dosing stay with us and then and then
perhaps some of their attributes fade
away and that happens
with potentially different attributes
with a macro dose and potentially they
they you know some of them go away
would you say that that the the fading
of the benefits are like on par with
each other or that or that they they
last differently
that's a super
super hard question let's see
i
i think i guess i would think that
they're more just different tools
different tools for different uses and
different advantages right because um
on on one hand
i think that
there is a huge benefit and that that a
lot of people have experienced the huge
benefit from a profound experience
right something that is life-altering
and life-changing but that is very
subjective and i know that i've read
people's experiences with micro doses
where they have had a profound
experience for them on a micro dose
right because everything in this world
is is subjective
so i think that
um
i think it's a very difficult question
because i think so much of that has to
do with the individual person
what they are seeking from this and also
maybe even just a little bit about their
neurochemistry or their like specific
neurodiversity because i think you
mentioned at the beginning of this um
there are different doses of micro doses
for people who experience like certain
people are sensitive
um and
that's going to be true for the benefits
as well
okay so uh one more thing i want to hit
on before we we go to the second break
and that is tolerance um you know we're
all pretty familiar with cannabis
tolerance and that
um when you're when you're taking in uh
thc regularly
um your your receptors
can can stay full up and and perhaps
even get lazy
but but with um
with psilocybin um
if you take mushrooms on day one and you
take them on day two you're gonna have
to take more on day two but from from
what i understand from the literature
it's not really tolerance it's it's it's
kind of like a different mechanism but i
have no way to explain it so so would
you would you kind of teach us a bit
about about what that's like to take
mushrooms
day one and then day two and the fact
that you need more what's going on there
sure so usually tolerance is uh in
reference to the receptors which is why
i think um
why i think like usually this is a
different form or a different mechanism
of tolerance because
when it comes to mushrooms or any of the
serotonergics it's actually linked to
the enzyme that breaks it down which is
called monoamine oxidase this enzyme
takes the molecule and adds and and
makes it inactive it inactivates the
molecule and when you um the first day
that you would take mushrooms like let's
say your body has like five of these
ends of these enzymes to break it down
the next day your body would have like
50 like tons and so because you have so
many of these enzymes it would like
immediately break it down
and that's that's why it's a it's a
different mechanism because it's linked
to breaking down the molecule into
something inactive rather than being
linked to changing the number of
receptors that the molecule is binding
to
all right um and and and this last
question i i just stumbled into this
question so i may not act actually ask
it scientifically accurately but you
mentioned the maos and um
uh i re recall like back in back in my
college days i was taking uh saint
john's wort for anxiety and i remember
uh that that uh taking mushrooms was not
having the same kind of effect and i
remember at the time thinking being told
oh it's because the saint john's wart is
an mao inhibitor
and so so taking mao inhibitors um uh
lessens the potency of a of a whole
category of drugs um and i don't even
know if i'm asking that question right
but i'm sure you know what i'm talking
about so would you talk a little bit
about mao inhibitors
yeah it's actually very um
it's very dangerous and this is a
something a psa it's very dangerous to
mix two different types of serotonergic
molecules specifically maoi or monoamine
oxidase inhibitors
and serotonergic agonists which is what
mushrooms are it's what lsd is as well
because there is something called
serotonin syndrome that you can get if
you overload the serotonin like system
and it's very it's very rare and you to
to be able to do that if you were just
using one but it's way more likely to
happen if you're using more than one so
okay i'm going to stop talking about
that now but it exists um and it's more
likely i i have never heard about that
that it would decrease your
ability because in theory
taking something that is a monoamine
oxidase inhibitor would turn that enzyme
off right it would inhibit that enzyme
and so in theory you would actually have
more
of the mushrooms
present still and actually that's the um
premise of
ayahuasca because ayahuasca if you eat
dmt
it gets metabolized so quickly that you
can't feel it so that's why ayahuasca is
a very complicated mixture and it's
different depending on um but like
person in place the shaman who's
creating it and the and the tribe it's
different in a bunch of places but the
main ingredients that go into it are a
monoamine oxidase inhibitor that then
allows the dmt to not be metabolized so
i would say it's almost the opposite
effect but perhaps because you were
taking st john's wort
perhaps
it was actually increasing the level of
monoamine oxidase that was there because
if it has an inhibitor and it has like
this
um
reactionary effect in your body or the
homeostatic effect that then your body
upregulated it so that's that's possible
right on cool well that was that was a
fun aside so
let's go ahead and take our second short
break and be right back you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is pharmacologist miyabi shields
[Music]
cannabis folks are innovators and
problem solvers and we like to make
money have you developed a tool
technique or plant that you want to
protect and monetize
you'll likely want legal representation
that is experienced accessible and
shares your values
plant and planet law represents a wide
variety of clients who choose to respect
the environment while pursuing their
business goals
have you invented a machine or gizmo
that you're bringing to market did you
discover a breakthrough environmentally
friendly pesticide or fertilizer
formulation that you're about to start
selling
have you bred a cannabis plant with
attributes not found anywhere else
attorney dale hunt and his plant and
planet team have established genetic
patents in over 30 countries
working to help entrepreneurs scientists
throughout the life sciences plant and
planet represents environmentally
positive clients in cannabis and other
botanicals fungi water purification
clean energy emulsions and medical
applications
plant and planet helps people protect
what they've created
if you are an early stage company with
an established idea and are in the
process of fundraising often the
investors require intellectual property
protections happen at the same time
plant and planet can be your sole
representation or they can integrate
with your existing legal team and plug
in their specialties
plant and planet is made of scientist
lawyers with a real passion for cannabis
inventions and the environment they have
the scientific and legal depth to help
you establish patent protections for
your great idea
you don't have to go it alone
friendly qualified and honorable legal
representation is available to you
contact plant and planet law today to
start the conversation
email info at
plant and planet.com
that's plant and planet law
our clients make the planet better
[Music]
as a business owner you are incredibly
busy in reality you are responsible for
everything your company does you've got
so many responsibilities every single
day that often you just don't have the
time to really dig into your marketing
as deeply as you'd like
you know there's more that you could do
to reach out to new customers and
encourage loyalty and the customers you
already have but you certainly don't
have the time for it and you're not
ready to hire somebody full time for
that role either
for you i recommend blunt branding at
blunt branding kirsten nelson and her
team are focused on improving your
bottom line you know most marketing
firms are excited to make your logo
packaging and website very pretty but
they leave responsibility for improving
your bottom line up to you they don't
want that kind of responsibility but
that's pretty much the most important
part of marketing right
kirsten and her team will help you
engage new customers funnel them to your
point of sale whether it be online or a
storefront and keep them coming back to
you and telling their friends
now if you happen to be a new cannabis
company or an established company moving
from medical to adult use in your state
kirsten especially can help you not only
is she well reversed in marketing and
finance but she totally gets cannabis
whole plant medicine terpenes heritage
farmers and the particular needs of
startups
check out what she did recently for moon
time medicinals and humbled at moon time
medicinals.com kirsten and her team put
together a whole brand package for them
built their website and wrote their
sales materials
no doubt this is a paid commercial spot
but that does not mean they bought my
opinion i've worked with blunt branding
on five projects now for various of
their clients and every single time they
have done more than they have promised
and over delivered on results i love how
they generate new revenue and focus on
that as the goal instead of just making
a pretty logo similarly every single
friend i've referred them to has come
back to thank me and that just does not
happen every day grab a pen and paper
because the website address is coming up
if you want someone to implement
marketing programs that feed your bottom
line give blunt branding a call they
will share proven techniques to increase
your audience and generate sales while
using cutting edge technology solutions
in the background that make all of this
easy automatic and trackable go to
forward slash shapingfire.com branding
to find out more you can also click the
link in our newsletter blunt branding
marketing that makes you money
[Music]
after you've caught up on the latest
shaping fire episodes do you sometimes
wish there was more cannabis education
available to learn well we got you
shaping fire has a fabulous youtube
channel with content not found on the
podcast when i attend conventions to
speak or moderate panels i always record
them and bring the content home for you
to watch the shangolos youtube channel
has world-class speakers including zoe
sigmund's lecture understanding your
endocannabinoid system kevin jodrey of
wonderland nursery talking about
breeding cannabis for the best terpene
profile frenchy cannolis lost art of the
hashishin presentation
nicholas mahmoud on regenerative and
polyculture cannabis growing dr sunil
agrawal on the history of cannabis
medicine around the world eric vlosky
and josh rutherford on solventless
extraction and jeff lonefels on the soil
food web there are several presentations
from dr ethan russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system too while there
be sure to check out the three ten part
shaping fire sessions series one with
kevin jodrey one with dr ethan russo and
one with jeff lowenfels and even my own
presentations on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose cannabis business even though the
risks are so high as of today there's
over 200 videos that you can check out
for free so go to youtube.com forward
slash shangolos or click on the link in
the newsletter
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and my guest today is pharmacologist
miyabi shields all right so here's the
big finish in the first set we learned a
lot about how the serotonin cycle
interacts with silicon
and also with the endocannabinoid system
a little bit about
how dopamine reacts as well during the
second set we talked about the different
thresholds for dosage the mechanics and
and how it works during during this
third set though we're going to talk
about uh some of the applications for
this um so so i want to point out that
this really isn't an episode about the
spiritual relationship and
communications psychological benefits
of taking mushrooms um certainly
there is a lot to say about that but
we're really talking more about
physiological mechanics today so
um you know uh you'll you that that
information on the psychology benefits
the psychological benefits of taking
mushrooms um you can pick that up
elsewhere or or maybe i'll do a show
about in the future but that's not
really what we're talking about today um
we're gonna start though miyabi with um
i know that you're a big fan of taking
psilocybin and cannabis together because
they're synergistic um will you go ahead
and and kind of explain why you see them
as being such uh such uh good friends
totally i i think that the systems are
complementary and
there is so much overlap and interplay
between the
system and the serotonin system
and it's clear it's interesting because
there's almost no research on that are
done together on cannabis and mushrooms
and there's very very limited research
on on how the systems when they're
activated together in humans that is
but
there is tons and tons of information
out there in the real world community of
people who use mushrooms and cannabis
together and in general they are a
potentiating or they're synergistic
which means that you can use less of
both of them to achieve a strong effect
or that they don't necessarily um
you know one doesn't necessarily just
like strengthen the other but that they
complement each other in such a way that
the therapeutic benefits can be greater
when they're used together at smaller
doses than when they're alone and i
think that
i think it's interesting and i obviously
understand why because it's difficult to
study such it's complicated to study
cannabis it's complicated to study
mushrooms and there's so many molecules
in both plants but i think that it's
incredible and worth talking about that
their benefits can be used together and
that one of the main things that um
people talk about is about how
there are some negative effects to both
cannabis and mushrooms and that in
general you can limit those negative
effects by using less of them in general
using less of any drug is beneficial for
you in the long term
and yeah it is i think that it's it's
crazy and i would love to see more
research on the synergy between the two
and that it's very explainable in terms
of how i mentioned earlier the actual
receptors interact with one another and
then the the cells in the brain and the
brain cells that fire together also
interact with one another
it's in a way that that makes sense that
they're complementary and that um
actually
it's been a rece it was a recent
paper that showed that if you use
cannabis regularly you have an increased
number of those uh receptor the receptor
dimers the two receptors together so the
serotonin receptor
with the cb1 receptor i was mentioning
earlier they come together and they
signal
differently when they're together there
is actually very preliminary early early
evidence that regular cannabis use will
increase the number of those two
receptor subtypes together um which is
just interesting because it's kind of
pointing to or hinting at the idea that
you can modify either system to be more
complementary with each other or or put
it in a different balance per se
do you have any thoughts on on if you're
going to be
using mushrooms at what point to start
your cannabis uh
use as well would it be
you know start before it comes on do you
want to wait till it comes on are there
is there any mechanics going on there
that we want to be aware of
well i think one of the biggest benefits
has to do with the anti-nausea effects
of cannabis
so that's a big and in terms of in terms
of like onset of using them together i
think that would be um something like
worth mentioning is that like mushrooms
often cause an upset stomach and
cannabis combats upset
upset stomach and gi issues
one thing worth mentioning is that
because they potentiate each other
because they work together that way it
is you have to be very very careful and
this is not something for the first time
ever to do without considering what the
dosages are and how they interact with
one another
because they certainly interact with one
another in a way that potentiates the
total overall effect
one thing that i've found is really
useful
is that you can
because of cannabis um having a shorter
duration of action if you're smoking it
or inhaling it or you know
dabbing it vaping it it has a shorter
duration of action and so one thing that
i think is useful is that you can almost
use cannabis to like as a titrator or
something that is a very subtle
alteration of the effect and this is a i
mean this is something that i've seen
tons of people do it's just it isn't
talked about
and it isn't studied in the scientific
literature and i would i would love to
study it one day or for someone to to
study it because i think that there are
different benefits
that can be obtained by using them
together
so we know that cannabis is biphasic
meaning consuming some thc reduces
anxiety but taking more than your
personal threshold makes it anxiety
causing right
mushrooms also seem to cause both
relaxation and can cause anxiety too um
i'm guessing that they're biphasic this
is why we focus so much on like mindset
and setting right with all psychedelics
what effect will using mushrooms and
cannabis together have in regard to
anxiety creation or secession
okay so this answer is gonna be entirely
based on the experience from others that
i've heard and from the theory of of
what
is interacting with these with these
receptors and these molecules but
but
uh when a molecule is biphasic usually
it means that there's this opposing
effect right at the second dose you at a
higher dose or a higher threshold um
it's possible that that second threshold
that causes anxiety is caused by an
imbalance in these signaling systems and
it is possible that that imbalance has
to do with only activating one of those
systems at a time
from what i've seen in
in personal experiences and
qualitatively of others in general they
can have a curbing effect on that
anxiety um effect when used together
although it is also certainly true that
it can cause if you're unprepared or if
there's other
like
environmental factors in your setting
that it could go the other way and so i
think it's hard to say like with
certainty that there would be anything
that would happen for certain for any
specific person in that
scenario in any scenario but that i do
think that it's possible that they can
at least and to a certain extent curb
that effect by having it be an
activation of both systems at the same
time because they balance each other out
um while but while that's being said i i
don't think that we know enough to say
that
it wouldn't also
at times have the opposing effect
because it's definitely true that it
could
yeah and this is definitely one of the
experiences that falls in the
personalized medicine approach right
like like you know everybody's gonna
have to figure out what their own
biphasic thresholds for mushrooms and
cannabis are you know start slow and low
and and find your own right um and i and
while we're here i appreciate the fact
you giving me some of these answers to
these questions that honestly the
science doesn't exist yet and the fact
that you're willing to you know
take a professional
guesstimate i appreciate your
willingness to do that
i mean this is all that this is all just
an abstract idea at this point but there
is some very real world applications
that
are happening and i think it's i i think
we shouldn't ignore the fact that people
do use mushrooms and cannabis together
and that in in general there are
unexplored unexplored um options here
so we've been talking all day today
about how um mushroom psilocybin
interacts with the serotonin system
which is one of the reasons
why people turn to mushrooms for
migraines right and it's amazing i have
heard so many different ideas from
patients about
why taking either low or large doses of
of psilocybin mushrooms
helps their
their
their migraines either stopping it at
the onset or stopping it once it's
already on or used as a preventative i
mean i've heard so many different
strategies and i don't know if any of
them are better than the other but but
from from your perspective um what do
you see as far as the effectiveness that
psilocybin might have in the prevention
or cessation of migraines
i i think that there's so much evidence
in both the endocannabinoid system and
the serotonin system
so i mentioned earlier that when you
activate the serotonin 5ht2a receptor
which is the main receptor associated
with psychedelic effects that you will
increase your levels of endocannabinoids
as well
and for this one this i think is more
linked to the preventative
but
migraines are associated with clinical
endocannabinoid deficiency um which is a
theory by dr ethan russo
and
it's it's a theory but there's a lot of
evidence there's a lot of evidence
behind people with migraines and also
fibromyalgia and ibs or irritable bowel
syndrome having clinical endocannabinoid
deficiency having lower levels of
circulating endocannabinoids
um in their body and having this be one
of the reasons why they are sensitized
to getting migraines so in that that's
one
possible way that i think that it
modifies it and then the other way is
through the serotonin system
and actually the
like most or some of the most common
migraine
medications that are abortive or that
get rid of your migraines are tryptans
they're also molecules that activate the
serotonin system so this is actually a
very very similar mechanism to what the
pharmaceutical agents have as well
although it's slightly different because
the pharmaceutical drugs activate only
one of the serotonin receptor subtypes i
believe it's 1b as the type or 1a
but they only activate one for the most
part of the serotonin receptor subtypes
and it's a very very different um
effects profile and can actually cause
like rebound migraines and there's
there's certain like there's positive
things associated with they do work in
important migraines but then there's
negative things that don't appear to
happen with
psilocybin mushrooms and i think that
it's this um i do think it's a dual
approach i think it has to do with the
effects of
the 2a 2c receptor or perhaps the pan
pan agonism of activating all of the
serotonin system subtypes because
for both migraine and cluster headaches
there's a lot of really really positive
evidence of using
mushrooms to either prevent them in
terms of like a long-term usage or abort
them
now i i know that you are not a medical
doctor and you are not giving medical
advice so i'm asking this question
specifically from
what you are learning from the
literature and from your own knowledge
of how the neural network work works
based on though that information is
there one strategy for using mushrooms
to
uh thwart migraines that seems like it's
more likely to be effective than others
like you know uh micro dosing for
migraines or or or macro dosing for
migraines or taking it at this point or
that point like do you have anything to
add on that topic
you know migraines are such a
complicated
disorder and they're a trigger disorder
um which means that like once you once
you trigger a migraine attack like
there's a prodromal phase and then the
the pain phase so in terms of like what
the best um mechanism is i i really hope
we have that answer in the long term in
the short term i i say that i've known
people who i've known someone who's
completely cured themselves of of
migraines using mushrooms um and in this
case it was like somewhat regular um so
in that case i think that like somewhat
regular use and
like the microdose route of being able
to use it more regularly may be
beneficial in terms of like somewhat
permanently altering um the circuitry
that leads to you triggering your your
migraines um but i don't think that
there's enough
yet uh to say even just in in migraines
in general and what causes them because
um a piece of this of migraines is
vasculature or the the blood flow
in the brain um and so perhaps in that
sense too altering it somewhat
chronically would be beneficial um
yeah i
that's a really really good question and
i i honestly hope that i have an answer
for you like you know within the next
like i don't know maybe i'll give myself
time the rest of my life
right on um so um i know that you are uh
very very interested in inflammation and
and that is closely related to the
serotonin system as well um are there
strategies for using uh mushrooms or
mushrooms and cannabis together to help
fight inflammation
so i think that the the way that this
involves inflammation or the way that
mushrooms interact with inflammation has
a lot to do with um there's a type
of inflammation that's not like swelling
or like
redness or all rashing and this type
like this type of inflammation
is just like a systemic
um release of chemical inflammatory
factors in the body and in the brain and
there's two places in serotonin where
serotonin i think plays a big role in
that the first one is in the gi tract
and the second one's in the brain and
inflammation in the brain can cause
depression and there's one specific
subtype of depression that's caused by
inflammation in the brain that actually
leads to decreased levels of serotonin
and so in this
in this case this would be a way that
um you know perhaps you can rebalance
that or decrease the inflammation by
supplementing with more serotonin it's i
guess it's it's unclear whether the
inflammation causes the decreased
serotonin or the decreased serotonin
causes the inflammation or vice versa
but by rebalancing
the signaling in your brain you can lead
to a decreased
level of inflammation or the release of
these inflammatory cytokines um because
also in general
this is just a very very large general
statement but in general inflammation in
the brain is caused by like stress
and like that we could potentially by
decreasing anxiety and stress
then aid in our levels of systemic
inflammation
it really seems that one of the one of
the first benefits that people get from
micro dosing
is increased resilience to anxiety and
stress
people who i meet that start micro
dosing they're only a couple weeks in
before they're all like you know life
isn't getting me down as much anymore um
do we know what the
um
the the mode of action there is like
what what why that's happening
i don't know if anyone if there's ever
been anything published on this um but i
my personal belief is that it has to do
with this
low-level mimicking like mimicking of a
low-level increase in your levels of
serotonin that then kind of allow you to
restructure that default
and that
that a lot of people who begin micro
dosing for anxiety right or for
like managing stress um
you are sensitized to those pathways
that
like lead to like negative thought loops
and
um
can spiral down into like negativity and
it's it's not easy to change your your
structuring of your brain that way and i
think this that's the like part of the
um
book by michael poland how to change
your mind right is that in many ways um
you can use these microdoses as tools
for restructuring the way that you
process the things that you are and
aren't just about the level of stress
that your body or your brain takes it to
something stressful happens in your day
instead of
allowing it to go to
this
this changes everything for the rest of
my life and you know and going down that
entire pathway um making it more of a
habit let's say to
stop that and only allow it to stress
you out to the extent that is more
manageable it's and that's not an easy
task that's not something that is
that's not something that is easy it's
something that takes a lot of conscious
effort and
and work and i think that
micro dosing is a tool to make it easier
for your brain to like restructure to
that task
right on so in addition to restructuring
there is just simply
um optimizing and and brain healing and
um let's let's finish with this um you
know we have talked many times on
shaping fire about
the use of cannabinoids especially cbd
cannabidiol
for its um uh
neurogenesis benefits meaning the
creation of
more
uh neurons especially the uh the
dopamine excreting cells that when lost
tend to lead to like parkinson's
syndrome and and things like that and so
by taking by taking cbd we increase our
brains neuroplasticity
and because they
because of the neurogenesis and now and
now today we're talking about
the the neuroplasticity benefits from
mushrooms and perhaps neurogenesis
would you talk a little bit just simply
about how
um
micro dosing and you can you can add the
cbd component if you wish
just makes for a for a healthier
younger functioning brain
yeah so i think younger is an
interesting that's an interesting
adjective to use because
in general when we're saying younger
brain we're talking about more plastic
or like less
not finished is not the word we're never
finished our brains are always going to
be changing um but more like random
thoughts and random connections and less
like solidified and minimal connections
and the reason why um
things like in in general when things go
away or we lose we lose certain
functionalities
a piece of that has to do with our brain
not activating those pathways anymore or
those or making those connections right
um and i think one of the things that
mushrooms help and that by activating
the serotonin system in the way that it
does which is pan activation all over
um you really are sort of like
stimulating you're you're literally
you're quite literally
chemically stimulating a giant system
in the brain that kind of just like jump
starts and has all of these down there's
all these downstream things that it will
interact with and that it will then
activate
um to kind of like
give a bunch of different new pathways a
a
boost or at least like a little
activation
um and what that can do is it can start
a
you know it can start a bunch of other
like next level um things that can lead
to like eventually differences in the
way like your openness i guess
would be um
one way of putting it like how you were
describing about having like a better
way of reacting to anxiety the the other
thing i would say is like is like
openness in general and flexibility and
that those things are all
generally speaking associated with being
happier which is also generally
associated with serotonin um
so that would be mechanistically the way
that i think that
that this is working is that it
facilitates and encourages new
connections because it creates and like
sparks these new connections that
otherwise wouldn't have been stimulated
because there would be
limited places where serotonin would be
released because as we get older our
brains um are less and less plastic and
we release serotonin in more and more
specific areas or in pathways that have
been
you know kind of cultivated as opposed
to
introducing a new molecule that mimics
serotonin that will activate a bunch of
different pathways that otherwise maybe
would not have been activated together
wow that's a really great explanation it
reminds me a lot of like use it or lose
it right like as as we get older if we
if we don't stay physical we lose some
of our mobility and and our options
become
more limited right that i can imagine
that that would work the same way with a
neural network too if we're if we're not
stimulating these these various networks
eventually we're doing the same thing
every day and things are becoming a
little more rote and we start to lose
options because some of those those
neural pathways that that give us more
mental options get pruned or or or are
are less deep
and
so by using
by by micro dosing we're just giving
everything enough stimulation to keep
them online
yeah they quite literally do get pruned
our our brain cells look a lot like
trees and
yeah they do
they they look a lot like trees and they
do quite literally end up they they're
the purpose of that is to be more
efficient right and to
to
deliver the messages down the same
pathways faster and more efficiently um
but absolutely no that's
that's a good um analogy to use right on
well miyabi thank you so much for
joining me again um this was everything
i hoped it would be and every time
we talk i learned so much and
um i get so much fan mail for you
through my account people really
enjoying your ability to take these um
these pretty complex uh you know
biological mechanisms and put them into
uh examples that that anybody can
understand so um so i appreciate you uh
going down this path with me about uh
mushrooms today and and appreciate both
uh both your expertise and and you know
good cheer with all this
well thanks so much for having me and
also for going down the rabbit hole of
abstract molecular pharmacology
because there's there's definitely so
much more uh to be found out of this of
this unknown but i love i love talking
about this and that's why i love talking
to people who are open to you know kind
of
approaching it from from different
angles basically
right on so if you dear listener are
interested in knowing more about miyabi
um there are a couple ways or three ways
for you to do that
by far the best is to start with
miyabi's instagram account because while
uh their other
social media accounts come and go the
instagram seems to be pretty steady and
that's miyabi p-h-g
m-i-y-a-b-e-p-h-d miyabi p-h-d on
instagram and then also miyabi has a
gargantuan following on tick-tock you
know a six-figure following that you can
follow as well and and if you love
miyabi's uh explanations um you're gonna
love them even more with like 3d models
in their hands being manipulated so um
that is also miyabi phd they're on tick
tock
um and if you are curious to know more
about miyabi's day job you can go to
the website for their company smokanol
and that's s-m-o-k-e-n-o-l
dot com one of these days we'll talk
about um
about miyabi's invention for extraction
of cannabinoids from smoke
if you are
interested in hearing more about
mushrooms mushrooms and cannabis and
things like that there are a handful of
earlier shaping fire episodes that you
can check out going all the way back to
shaping fire episode 22 with dr ethan
russo on treating brain injuries with
mushrooms and cannabis
episode 67 also with dr russo on
migraine therapy using cannabis and
mushrooms
episode 70 about cannabis mushrooms and
terpenes for optimum health
with guests
dr ethan russo tony verzura jeff chilton
and burner focusing on chinese medicinal
mushrooms rather than psychedelic ones
and finally very recently episode 76
with adam bramledge comparing different
psilocybin microdosing protocols you can
find more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast and subscribe to the show at
shapingfire.com and wherever you get
your podcasts if you enjoyed the show
we'd really appreciate it if you leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for insights
into the latest cannabis news exclusive
videos and giveaways on the shaping fire
website you also find transcripts of
today's podcast as well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast that's at shaping fire and at
shangolos on instagram be sure to check
out shaping fire youtube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hotspot at
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire i've been
your host shango lose
[Music]
you