[Music]
as more and more athletes come forward
as using cannabis for training and
recovery many regular folks who exercise
to stay fit are considering adding it to
their health plan as well exercise in
cannabis are not obvious friends since
many people assume that when you use
cannabis you sit on the couch and eat
all the snacks and while that's
certainly a possibility many more people
are up and motivated hiking or working
or surfing or reading or writing or even
taking care of the kids the idea of the
couch locked stoner is really more of a
stereotype than an actuality the
inspiration for this episode came from
the movie American Beauty in that film
the Kevin Spacey character is going
through a midlife crisis and he turns to
cannabis weightlifting and fantasy to
get him through it he says that he's
working out because he wants to look
good naked and I think many of us
identify with that it got me thinking
about the relationship between cannabis
and exercise I wanted to understand if
cannabis and exercise were complementary
I wanted to know if cannabis could help
all of us look better naked if you want
to learn about cannabis health business
and technique efficiently and with good
cheer I encourage you to subscribe to
our newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out deliver right
to your inbox along with commentary on a
couple of the most important news items
from the week and videos - don't rely on
social media to let you know when a new
episode is published sign up for the
updates to make sure you don't miss an
episode
also we're giving away pretty cool
prizes to folks who are signed up to
receive the newsletter there's nothing
else you need to do to win except
receive the newsletter so go to shaping
fire com2 sign up for the newsletter and
be entered into this month's and all
future newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shaping fire and I'm your
host
Shango lows today my guest is Greg
Germann
Greg tournament is a neurophysiologist
with expertise in the endocannabinoid
system he has received research support
from the National Institute on Drug
Abuse and the National Science
Foundation and his articles have
appeared in the journals such as natural
science trends in neuroscience and
neuropsychopharmacology
his research while an assistant
professor of biology at Eckerd College
included the molecular physiology
of cannabinoid receptors and their
evolution within neural systems Gregg is
presently chief scientific officer at
three boys farm in Florida
welcome to the show Gregg thank you
thanks for having me against anger yeah
it's so great to have you back so so
let's start off with a quick summary of
the endocannabinoid system for folks
because while you know certainly more
people know that they have an
endocannabinoid system then used to know
it's still pretty new to a lot of folks
and honestly since you haven't got a
history of being a professor you're
actually really darn good at teaching it
so so let's start there so that we can
build on that throughout throughout the
show so so will you summarize what the
human endocannabinoid system is and and
how we want to work with it yeah of
course thanks for the compliment and
more people do know for sure having
talked about this for many years but the
endocannabinoid system is really how the
endocannabinoids work and we this was
discovered out of a quest scientific
quest to understand how cannabis works
in the body of course all of that was
mostly biased towards how it's bad and
hurt you and is wrong but even with that
bias we discovered the endocannabinoid
system which is intrinsic to our body as
a mechanism for resilience I believe and
in homeostasis the endocannabinoids as
players in our body can be called sort
of like the body's own THC or
cannabinoids they are if you're familiar
with with molecules at all they're
they're lipid molecules they come from
the membranes of cells not just in the
brain but all over the tissues of the
body and act at certain receptors in
order to dampen excitation and they do
many different things but on the basic
level we've got these endocannabinoids
called an and amide and to AG there are
molecules that act in many ways like THC
they act at receptors that are on cells
and they include cb1 and cb2 cannabinoid
receptors this is sort of a guest
tradition or if you will endocannabinoid
system those endocannabinoids and the
cb1 and cb2 receptors we now know it's
quite a bit more complicated than that
and this is a system that your body uses
all the time to regulate metabolism
motivated behavior the synchrony and
rhythms of your brain in fact you know
many people will know that when all of
this was discovered it was hugely
surprising to brain scientists people
like me who study receptors and how
drugs and hormones and neurotransmitters
work because the cb1 cannabinoid
receptor when it was discovered way back
in 89 and then in more thoroughly in
1990 we discovered that it's the most
abundant receptor system in the brain by
far so our brains - really highly highly
evolved to respond to cannabinoid
signaling you know of course we were
evolved with the endocannabinoids in our
body but the cannabinoids that cannabis
has been with us a very long time as
well so so if we're looking at the
endocannabinoid system as our body's
master regulator you know constantly
trying to bring us back to homeostasis
like you said or or it bring us back to
balance
if we're running hot in a category it
will help bring us bring it down and
bring it back to bring us back to center
if we're if we're if we're cool in a
category or slow or stagnant in the
category well it like amps it up so no
matter if you're high or low it's
bringing you back to you know best
best-case scenario for your body well
this makes a lot of sense then right
that this this body master regulator
would be impacted and might be an active
participant
every time we exercise right because
we've got we've got breathing and blood
flow and muscle sets and you know all
you know adrenaline and all these other
things that are playing a role in
exercise they're also playing a role in
the endocannabinoid system so so how
does cannabis help us work with the
endocannabinoid system generally when we
exercise what what are we doing when
we're interacting with the
endocannabinoid system generally when we
exercise well you know I I'm part of
what I think is so exciting is how much
we have yet to learn and that now these
kinds of questions are something we can
ask out in the open and really explore
it and with today's cannabis that we
haven't were able to understand the
diversity of it but you know from a
starting point what we've come to find
out and work that I did it was part of
this but other group many other groups
have shown that when you exercise your
body elevates its endocannabinoid levels
that's one of the kinds of activities
that can increase circulating levels in
the blood of an and amide at least as an
endocannabinoid and so there's part of
the benefit the physiological benefit of
aerobic exercise but it's also been seen
with resistance training and an amide
levels go up and to the effect that
there's sort of analgesic effect a
euphoric effect it may help to motivate
behavior in the first place this is all
just something that is intrinsic to to
how our exercise physiology evolved and
you're right the physiology of exercise
is a really unique case I mean skeletal
muscle and fat tissues and depth of
breathing and so much goes on during
exercise that is special compared to how
our bodies normally work and and that's
because the human being in our hominid
ancestors we evolved that of a lineage
that evolved to be exercisers and the
endocannabinoids system I believe was a
key part in what made that happen I'm
really on this idea that
endocannabinoids actually a part of the
evolved ability of these sorts of
processes let's let's take a little
deeper in that because when we were
chatting before you know as we were
setting up this interview today
I thought I thought it was really
interesting you're talking about the the
evolution of humans as a as a running
animal right as a running being and how
essential and integral the
endocannabinoid system is to that kind
of of long-distance running mean one of
the reasons humans could get meat is
that because over time they would run
down these animals that might be faster
but they didn't have the same stamina
that we had right right so so so why
don't want you to riff on that a little
bit because I think you've got some
interesting stuff there yeah they're
they're hunter-gatherer groups in Africa
you know to this day that hunt with sort
of persistence or exhaustion techniques
well like just like you said band of of
hunters can basically jog and antelope
down to exhaustion and for that but for
that kind of behavior to evolve would
have been a multi-step process over time
you look back tens of thousands of years
to when our hominid ancestors were
largely in trees or near them there was
a big shrinking of the forests of East
Africa and areas where Homo sapiens
evolved so that you got the development
of these big savanna grasslands and
whether it's hunting to exhaustion or
just foraging from place to place it's
it was adaptive so the field of
biological anthropology you know
believes this these aren't controversial
things I'm talking about it was a those
those ancestors who were better at
running were more successful whether it
was hunting or following a vultured or
something have been killed or just
getting to a better place to forage
endurance running was adaptive and so
traits that favoured endurance running
were adaptive and you see in in humans
skeletal muscular features like the
length of the Achilles tendon in certain
ways that the head and the hips sit in
their sockets in the length of the femur
that make running less energetically
demanding well
what would have motivated that behavior
in the first place because running
intrinsically increases your risk
predators of injury and and the
endocannabinoids fit in nicely as an
explanation in that when you engage in
the behavior and you get sort of a
runners joy out of it from increased
circulating endocannabinoids your sense
of wellness improves the taste of the
food you found is actually better
because of the endocannabinoids this is
all well steeped in research and similar
to how cannabis can affect you it would
have promoted behavior a culture of
behavior and that is a positive feedback
loop driving we believe the evolution of
humans to be you know quote unquote Born
to Run endurance runners and the
endocannabinoids are really involved
they don't just get activated when
you're from exercise but the way they
stimulate the appetitive food seeking
they help to desire and promote feeding
and that's something that goes way back
to deep evolutionary time even very
simple organisms like worms and Hydra
that are pre jellyfish are or have an
endocannabinoid system that seems to in
their interact with the control of
metabolism and feeding behavior that's
where our endocannabinoids system
evolved from but in vertebrate animals
that of course you know include mammals
became mammals became humans if the base
of the vertebrate family tree what we
call invertebrate chordates that's when
these cb1 and cb2 cannabinoid receptors
seem to have evolved and it only there
do you start to see a DNA sequence
that's like the cb1 cannabinoid receptor
and lo and behold in the timespan of
evolutionary development vertebrate
animals have these systems what's what
is special about a vertebrate animal
what an evolutionary biologist will
identify hat they have identified what
we call vertebrate innovations that
appear in our lineage and know
and they are including a peripheral
nervous system a very incredibly complex
and and large head and brain an adaptive
immune system that recognizes previous
you know threats and responds admit
remembers them these are things that the
endocannabinoid system is all about
regulating it is the endocannabinoids
and the cb1 and cb2 receptors are master
regulators of metabolism inflammation
the immune response and regulation of
the complex brains and nervous signaling
then that's not you know counter that's
not cannabis culture talk that's this
mainstream science get that dando
cannabinoid system is the master
regulator of physiology and you don't
see that talking in other literature but
you I could I can go on about this
connection you know well let me let me
point yeah let me point you in in a
continued direction because I like what
we're talking about because the you know
basing the endocannabinoid system in
this this long history of human
evolution I like how a it takes it out
of drug culture and like stoner culture
and and even out of science right
because science is often trying to like
pure medical science is often very on a
pedestal right but when you get to
evolutionary science and anthropology
suddenly things get a lot more visceral
right and and a lot a lot less cherished
and so so so going back to what you were
saying I love the beauty of the idea of
you know the endocannabinoid system
appears in us as as our DNA starts to
become more human and then part of that
is that we we when we when we say when
we spark the endocannabinoid system it
creates a state in us that we enjoy food
and we're also chasing our food so so
not only is the endocannabinoid system
modulating our running experience and
giving us that
joy but also we're chasing down our food
so that we can get more complex fats to
build our brain and oh yeah once you get
there and you capture the animal and you
eat it your your your endocannabinoid
system is already like primed for a
fantastic meal and and how that comes
together it's just frickin beautiful
right it's like ah it's like hell yeah
major it's beautiful because it teaches
us more about who we are and at
something I I like to say a lot that the
science of cannabis has taught us much
more about how cannabis works it's
taught us a great deal about the biology
of who we are and what it means to be
well but jumping into your scenario yeah
you run there's there's a control whole
of your metabolism and your and your
repetitive Drive but guess what has also
been very cleanly and repeatedly shown
in various animal research models the
endocannabinoid system helps to
stimulate neurogenesis it you're not
only collecting fats to feed your brain
you're stimulating mechanisms that
promote the growth of the brain that
help to create resilience to the
anxieties of life by promoting healthy
regeneration of nervous tissue which we
know does happen throughout life and
there's been lots of studies showing
that cannabinoids stimulate neurogenesis
including plant cannabinoids including
as a consequence of exercise and it
doesn't happen if you block the cb1
cannabinoid receptor even some some
under cited research that I really like
by a group in Germany a friend of mine
Susanna Wolfe was first author one of
these papers they a difficult experiment
to do giving animals an enriched
environment over a period of time you
know you may a lot of listeners may be
familiar with sort of this rat park
literature about a lot of well a lot of
animals are not housed in a in a good
situation and in research it's kind of
deprived and when you give animals
enriched environments there are lots of
measures of health benefits there and
for example they're not as likely to be
you
self-administering cocaine and that kind
of thing but the point here is Susanna's
work was that she did a very long
controlled experiment that's hard to
fund and found that animal enriched
environments stimulated neurogenesis
greater rates in in brain areas where it
occurs they hippocampus of the mouse
brain and that this was blocked in
animals that had cb1 receptors blocked
either with genetically they didn't have
it or they were blocking it with
chemical antagonist so back to the
running thing we know that over the
history of hominid evolution leading to
almost ap ins ourselves as greater
running mobility occurred in the fossil
record and Accor the course of evolution
as species became more mobile and better
runners their brain size also increased
their head size their brain size and
this makes sense from a natural
selection perspective in that as an
animal as a species is getting better at
running your survival demands are
different you're better at foraging
you're getting more metabolic support
but the complexity of the environment
moving traveling farther covering more
different terrains at different rates
your processing speeds you need for
processing speed is greater to be able
to see changing environments remember
your environment have flexibility to new
encounters that you're more likely to
have and so the evolution of humans as
were to be runners also included a
growth in the brain and endocannabinoids
we know are stimulated by running and we
know that endocannabinoids are linked to
neuro trophic factors and things that
cause increased neurogenesis we see it
we know the mechanism so part of the fun
about talking about evolution is it is
always going to be speculative right
because it's something you've had that's
happened in the in the past but then the
pieces are really beautiful to make this
perspective and support this perspective
that the endocannabinoid system helped
to support the evolution of who we are
as runners and the metabolic activity
that we have some of the thinking on
exercise and metabolism is that you know
Western community Western society is
dealing with such issues related to
metabolism diabetes obesity
you know sedentary lifestyles and we
evolved not only to be runners but our
metabolism evolved with a running sort
of set point there that were kind of
hard it plumbed to burn through calories
like we're running and if we don't have
exercise in our life that extra calories
that you want to intake because you're
just set to that it ends up going to
inflammation yeah and and when we run an
exercise end up that's another thing oh
by the way yabba noids clearly do they
dampen down inflammation and so yeah I
look I love the whole area and it does
support how natural cannabis medicine
you know as a complement to that
physiology is but it's not just about
cannabis it's about understanding
ourselves and how an active mobile
lifestyle is healthy it's how we evolved
and there's it it's it's a natural thing
to do you know I I work with patients a
lot around the country and you know
often I'll get people saying you know I
want to use cannabis because I am
insomnia right and we can talk all about
you know you know using THC short-term
and CBD to make the sleep cycle better
all that but I always start with are you
drinking coffee in the morning right
because because if you're if you're
drinking coffee in the morning the
caffeine half-life means that when you
go to sleep you still have active
caffeine in your body even if you only
had one cup and of course no one wants
to hear that right no one wants to
chimeric no one wants to give up their
cup of coffee
to get rid of their insomnia they want
to keep their cup of coffee and then
they want to you know take some kind of
purple flowered cannabis
to help you know slow them down at night
similarly to use your example you know
people are often you know you know why
do I have endocannabinoid deficiency or
why is it so common you know and and of
course we go through the the the modern
American things you know you know stress
poor sleep poor nutrition too many
pharmaceuticals environmental toxins but
really it's that lack of mobility right
you know like our bodies are designed
over you know generations and
generations to be mobile to do physical
work to take in calories to burn them
off and now we're you know driving our
cars and sitting on the sofa and I mean
hell I most of the time I'm working I'm
either like standing up talking to
people or I'm sitting at my computer or
on a plane sitting at a computer night
and and you know I'm one of those people
we all need to get more mobile and I
like what you said how you know cannabis
teaches us more or reminds us more where
we came from right because it's showing
that okay if if modern life is not
working for most everybody what what can
we learn about how thing we used to live
that can help us be helped healthier now
yeah yeah and you know a health and
fitness is not you know all about
endocannabinoids this we you know we can
sometimes get get into but in no
cannabinoids are a master regulator and
and I think it's it's legit to say that
you know the endocannabinoid system has
been under sort of a multi-pronged
attack with the modern that is to say
you know Western lifestyle with all the
things you're saying sedentary ISM and
not having as many leafy greens that
will support a healthy microbiome and
probably healthy fatty acid balances
that help to generate the
endocannabinoids themselves the quote we
know chronic stress wears down the
endocannabinoid system it's makes sense
and though cannabinoids are a buffer
against stress but when you beat up your
buffers you run you render a high and
you know that's a metaphor but promoting
a health and and and well-being from an
endocannabinoid perspective I think is a
exciting direction
- I certainly like looking at it that
way right on so so in our second set
we're gonna start talking specifically
about how cannabis can help us with with
different types of you know exercise and
athleticism but before we go to the
first commercial break I want to go you
know all the way back to where we
started this set because you talked a
little bit about how cannabis can help
motivate us towards exercise right and
and you know we've laid out this case of
that that we do need movement and and if
we move our endocannabinoid system will
reward us with all of this you know
increased health and thriving nature but
I know I'm not the only one who you know
I'm I'm busy and I travel and I don't
find the time for as much exercise I
want to even though you know I
continually am getting better at it I'm
not there yet but but I liked what you
said though that there are aspects of
using cannabis that can help motivate us
towards exercise when that is not the
general belief right most people are
thinking about local you know lazy
sedentary stoners and certainly there
are other factors that play role you
know a role in that but but what but why
don't you tell us a little bit about how
cannabis can help move us closer to
exercise and so that maybe you know some
of us can get a little more motivated
yeah well I mean I think that that's
very true and it's gonna in my view the
way we're talking about it cuz of course
we can talk more later that there's a
lot of talk about you know cannabinoids
in terms of recovery because of an
anti-inflammatory values and having an
anti-inflammatory a little on board
ahead of time exercising unnatural one
may be beneficial but we're talking
about motivation and we're talking about
that kind of sort of effect I think
we're probably talking about using it in
low doses prior to exercise and maybe
it's because you just learned that it
helps you get in a zone helps you less
be less
attached to other distraction so you can
focus on it one of the ìiî certainly
spoke I remember 20 years ago talking to
someone when I was first getting into
this research a scientist I was with at
Vanderbilt said yeah you know we I used
to be with this running club out in
Eugene Oregon and we would all take
edibles like half an hour before we ran
then we'd all like you know we'd go on
this like 12 mile run and he was like it
totally helped me get in the zone and
I've heard that many times now it's been
much more popular as a lot of ultra
athletes talking about that now but
whether it's that or even you know not
just a long-distance zone where you need
to sort of wear away the hours while
you're exercising there there may be
just a way to sort of let loose of
what's holding you back and you know I
think about in terms of weight room
training and that kind of exercising
where you might be self-conscious about
form or what your performance is how
much
something's weights or rattling and and
I think of judicious use of cannabis can
maybe help you get past that that your
own you what your own resistance is
holding you back like I was related when
I was talking to you earlier about hand
drumming which is something I I love to
do and have trained in and a lot of
times what holds you back from making a
great rhythm is yourself it's your
inhibition from actually making the
impact and with the drum and just
feeling it and I think the same thing is
getting in with the training I mean it's
like if you're if you're training you
and trying to get over a hurdle there's
a value to being coached through it and
and that's because it helps release sort
of your you're descending neural
pathways that put a little safety check
on your own actions and get coached
through something you can you're able to
push through a little harder and I'm not
trying to go too far about what I know
that endocannabinoids or cannabis does
or doesn't do but I like to think about
the idea that
having a little bit of cannabis on board
can help you to get past your own
resistance and sort of negative body
type or whatever and just do it and then
maybe maybe with experience then going
to the gym or your whatever your
training situation is taking that little
bitty and I am I do tend to say that
this would be what we'd call a micro
dose just a small little dose can even
kind of be a conditioned experience like
yeah okay there's my exercise zone let's
get this yeah well said you know during
the during the introduction I talked
about that that great scene in the movie
American Beauty where the Kevin Spacey
character you know he's having you know
all sorts of life problems right but but
to kind of reclaim his life one of the
things he decides to do is he gets a he
gets a weight bench and he's starting to
smoke some weed again and he's putting
on some of the music that energizes him
and you know I get that man you know I
know that if I get too high then then
you know using resistance by doing the
resistance training at the gym or
something like right being at the gym is
too weird and bright and I just don't
want to be there but but if I just have
like you know a little hit off my
one-hitter right or for many people that
would be a vape pen like nowadays right
just that little bit it kind of loosens
up the fact that I generally don't want
to be there lifting weights and and
suddenly I'm like alright I'm here and
I'm in I'm in a much better mood than I
was a couple minutes ago let's get going
and it kind of gets me over that initial
hump of oh my god I got these all these
other things I should be doing but you
know cannabis for a lot of people makes
you very you know emotionally present
with where you are and I find that's
really the only way that I can work out
is if I forget the rest of my life that
you know acts as a distraction all this
stuff I should be doing and you know you
know and most of the stuff we're talking
we're gonna be talking about today is
gonna be tincture based but for me
specifically with lifting you know a
little a little in inhaling followed by
some some weight training that that
really works for me and I think it does
for a lot of people yeah where's for me
I dig it and
I laugh a little bit about the American
Beauty reference because my buddy Mike
who got me back into training a couple
years ago and I'm in the best shape that
I've been since college and them and
I've been happy about that and it
doesn't always involve a little bit of
cannabis but it usually does and it's a
he laughed at me and refer to that exact
exact clip when I you know came to him a
couple years ago it was just like I'm
not happy with how I look and he jokes
cuz that character you know was asked
like why what are you trying to hit were
you trying to run certain you know eight
miles or whatever he's like I just want
to look good naked
hey look good but you know public health
and epidemiological studies have shown
that overall cannabis users tend to have
better lower body mass index you know
it's not that we are fatter and lazier
and actually so germane to this
conversation Shango you know a paper
just got it's not even fully released
but it was announced as a pre release by
group out of Colorado and Ken Hutchins
says one of the senior authors who did a
online survey amongst people using
cannabis and legal states had something
like six hundred respondents and the
questioning was do you endorse the use
of your cannabis around exercise and a
large majority I believe it was
approaching around 80% of cannabis users
associated it with helping them or
endorsing it without exercise more of
them were relating it to the recovery
phase but a significant number I look
forward to reading the actual paper a
significant number did discuss it in
just the way that you and I are that it
helped to to motivate them or support
their performance in some way and and
you know I was at a panel on the Emerald
cup in December with some great athletes
and they too were you know across the
field a lot of a lot of athletes do you
feel like there's a benefit to whether
its flow state or something of that
whatever you want to call it you and I
have just been talking about it in terms
of alright I'm there I'm ready to go and
I think these are all just fascinating
Epic's and and and moreover their topics
that are all about helping people feel
better yeah damn straight so after the
break we are gonna come back and we're
gonna talk more about cannabis and the
actual physiology of exercise so stay
with us you are listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is gregor
diamond chief scientific officer at
three boys farms this message is for
folks who grow cannabis I'm talking to
home growers patients and commercial
growers - I'm probably talking to you
when you plan out your next growing
cycle be sure to check out Humble CSI
seeds at Humboldt CSI dot-com Caleb
Inspectah and his family have lived in
Humboldt County for over a hundred years
for the last 40 years
three generations of his family have
cultivated extraordinary sense of Meah
cannabis in Humboldt Mendocino and
Trinity counties because of his lineage
and the hard earned experience that
comes from growing up smoking and
sifting large populations of cannabis
plants in Northern California the seeds
you'll cop from CSI will be winning
genetics based on longtime heavy hitters
and updated and Reese if today bring out
new and exotic traits and better yields
go ahead and ask around
Caleb also known as Inspectah and
Pirates of the Emerald triangle is a
breeders breeder he reaches way back and
works with significant strains
recreating them in new and interesting
ways that you'll love is a toker and a
grower as well as offering you some
surprises that will delight serious seed
traders and cultivators Humboldt CSI
goes as further step and selfs all these
chemo VARs so you know all the seeds
will be female these are not
experimental feminized seeds Humboldt
CSI releases some of the best female
seeds available anywhere and it will
show in your garden folks grew quite a
bit of CSI humble gen-x last year here
on Vashon Island and everyone was
pleased the patients had beautiful
female plants and didn't have to call
half of their garden as males the folks
growing for the fun of getting high grew
colorful flowers with exceptional bag
appeal and great highs and breeders had
seven out of seven females in a pack
which gave them a lot of phenotypic
choices take a moment right now and
visit Humboldt CSI comm you'll find an
up-to-date menu of both feminized and
regular lines along with photos and
descriptions
that's humbled CSI comm now that the
health benefits of terpenes have become
well-known in the cannabis industry
people everywhere are looking for the
purest terpenes without adulterants the
problem with most terpene providers is
that they're not sourced naturally and
instead are made as a byproduct of
refining petroleum and that's so sketchy
the terpenes sold by true terpenes are
entirely different they are certified
organic non-gmo and food grade that
means that they are extracted from real
plant sources there are no solvents of
any kind they are distilled only with
steam that's right only steam in fact
terpenes from true turbines are so pure
that you can eat them not only that but
you can stack them with better results -
what I mean is other company's terpenes
have got a few percent of impurities and
when you stack those terpenes to make
your blend you're adding a variety of
impurities that degrade your final
product true terpenes also have strange
specific terpenes for a wide range of
cannabis strains like Durbin poison
sunset sherbet and granddaddy purple
true terpenes has robust and supportive
customer service so your questions will
get answered fast and efficiently if you
shop for tips before you know how rare
that is so whether you want to cup your
hands to smell some betta carry off lean
to calm down after getting too high or
if you want to dab some pining so your
lungs feel fabulous and your mind feels
liberated true terpenes will provide you
with a truly natural experience if you
are a cannabis product developer these
are the Terps you want to add to your
oil or edible or capsule or whatever
true terpenes are simply the best your
money can buy don't try and make a
premium product with substandard terms
choose true terpenes for a top-shelf
experience go to shaping fire calm board
/ true terpenes to find out more or
click on the link in this week's
newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I'm your host
Shango Louis and our guest this week is
gregor demon chief scientific officer at
three boys farm so before the break we
were talking a lot about
the historical significance of the
endocannabinoid system and how we
evolved as mobile human beings and then
a little bit about motivation because as
we all know you know getting motivated
to exercise in the first place is you
know is a challenge for a lot of people
including me so then this set we're
gonna talk more about the impact the
interplay between the human
endocannabinoid system cannabis and
exercise and and and how they're working
together - I don't know build a better
human so so Greg why don't we start
there you know specifically how does
supplementing our body with cannabis
help us strengthen and build muscle well
that's tough I mean you know I'm a
scientist so I'm always gonna back up
and say well we're not totally sure
about that but it there's the
cannabinoid system in working with
cannabis in that it can help support
better you know metabolism and storage
of fats may may help and here's another
piece that's pretty mysterious is that
we now know that there are cannabinoid
receptors actually on mitochondria that
are the AP generating powerhouses of the
cell right that's really weird that
there's a neurotransmitter receptor
that's on the surface of neurons and all
over the body and it's also found on
mitochondria that's part of what makes
this receptor system so different and
it's it's literally a mechanism the
endocannabinoids system is not just a
system like here's a group of
cannabinoid producing cells and they
project everywhere that's like the case
we're talking about dopamine I can point
to every dopamine cell in the brain and
it they project everywhere but there's
the dopamine system right there the
endocannabinoids system is more like an
endocannabinoid mechanism that is a
fundamental cellular mechanism
it's all over the body so in when it
comes to exercise and you're talking
about building muscle I mean there's
certain aspects that well and though
cannabinoids may be involved in sort of
the healing of you know micro tears and
that kind of thing that is involved in
building muscle mass but here's
something I want to go into that that
you haven't heard from me yet it's a
recent study came out that I got I'm
really excited about that looks at how a
no cannabinoids and cannabinoid
receptors work at the at the
neuromuscular Junction so the
neuromuscular Junction is where and when
you're doing any voluntary movement
moving a hand finger a foot there are
neurons that are coming called motor
neurons from your spinal cord really
comes from your motor cortex down to
your spinal cord and then your spinal
cord sends motor neurons to your muscle
and the release of neurotransmitter
called acetylcholine at that
neuromuscular Junction is what causes
your muscles to contract a move so
that's the neuromuscular Junction and
whereas we know that cannabinoid
receptors and endocannabinoids act at
connections between cells and the brain
synapses like practically every synapse
in the entire human brain is impacted in
some way by endocannabinoids if not
using it on the regular studies of the
neuromuscular Junction have been less
obvious but a study just came out
recently it was in the journal
scientific reports just in the last
couple months showing that
endocannabinoids are released by
contracting active muscles and travel
backwards and hit the neuromuscular
Junction in this similar way that it
does in the brain that I hope to
describe like 2001 but in the brain
there's a key difference here in the
brain endocannabinoids travelling
backwards dampen the release of
neurotransmitters and kind of slow
things down at the neuromuscular
Junction where physical activity is
stimulated the endocannabinoids actually
increase the level of neurotransmission
they and this was a study done in mice
but there were some really key findings
first of all that they used they showed
it a synthetic cb1 egg and
did this as well I wish they had used
THC but such as big animal research they
didn't but nonetheless they mimicked it
with a cannabinoid agonist activator and
it increased at a very very heavy
research I mean they're like counting
vesicles of neurotransmitter released
basically they show that at that level
it's increased it's kind of the inverse
of what happens in the brain but why
would this be adaptive I mean maybe this
is an ability part of the ability of
exercising muscle tissue to to overcome
fatigue you just start increasing the
release of the how effective the motor
neuron is driving the muscle I mean the
the the cellular physiology of fatigue
and why it happens is not so obvious and
maybe this is a break for understanding
in that regard but secondly they looked
at a mouse model of a disease called
myasthenia gravis are you familiar with
this at all no I'm not
myasthenia gravis is an autoimmune
disorder and it manifests with muscle
weakness that can and clumsiness related
to that that's a short version you get
muscle weakness because again it's
autoimmune where the body is developing
antibodies to the receptors for
acetylcholine that respond to the
neuromuscular Junction okay so you're
you develop antibodies they attack your
own receptors that you're in a muscular
Junction so the efficacy the tightness
of connection between your spinal cord
telling your muscles to move is degraded
by your own immune system it's one of
these insidious that ways that
autoimmunity
[ __ ] us up in people that have
myasthenia gravis well it is something
that is very easily modeled in a mouse
you can make a mouse basically allergic
to their own acetylcholine receptors it
acts just like myasthenia gravis they
get muscle weakness and progressive you
know failures because of that and they
showed that giving the mouse that
cannabinoid helps to prevent and and
treat myasthenia gravis I mean
clinically if you have this
what you will be prescribed as a
medicine that helps to enhance the
release of acetylcholine or block its
breakdown this new discovery is that
cannabinoids acting at cb1 receptors
enhances the release of acetylcholine at
the neuromuscular Junction right there
it's here's another of the limitless
examples about cannabis we have I cannot
stand up in front of a group of doctors
and talk about clinical data and say
that there's any proof whatsoever that
the use of cannabis be it a tincture a
pill a joint I cannot say that the use
of cannabis can be a treatment for
myasthenia gravis
I have literally zero clinical evidence
for that
but the biological underpinning has now
been elegantly described that it may be
the case and I'm hoping that in this era
of new upstart cannabis companies that I
am involved in these kinds of things can
be dub tailed into studies you know if
not really expensive clinical trials
patient outcomes let's recruit people
who are using it for Mycenae gravis and
find out does it work that's
observational study it's not as strong
it's a controlled clinical trial but
they all start to justify one another
yeah and if we move in that direction
will be easier for us to to fund those
increased in size studies and you know
this is interesting too because well I
don't have a lot of experience with that
particular autoimmune disease I work
with a lot of other folks with
autoimmune disease most commonly usually
lupus and and you know a you know how
how these manifests for different
patients kind of is different from
patient and patient but but decreased
mobility is incredibly common right and
so and and we find that high doses of
whole plant cannabinoids really work to
help I've heard patients call it loosen
the joints right if to make them feel
less like they're they're rusting like
the Tin Man and Wizard of Oz right they
feel like they're loosening and while
I've never heard this explanation that
you get just gave it certainly seems to
be more evidence in that general
direction
that that you know adding cannabinoid
supplementation to our body from this
plant acts like an oil can on everything
that's trying to stop our mobility it
sure seems to act in a lot of places
like that yes they there's a a
redundancy of function that helps to
support these different directions that
would enhance mobility and you know this
piece I'm talking about if it could
cannabinoids help to increase the the
function of your neuromuscular Junction
on this subtle way but a way that could
underlie it when people were talking
about getting into a flow state maybe
that's part of it your neuromuscular
connection is just getting set up and
more you know high fidelity and you feel
it then you've got the sense of wellness
that comes from the way the
endocannabinoids are acting in the
limbic system of your brain and you've
got the sense of enhanced
bronchodilation that's happening from
endocannabinoids working on your upper
Airways and and it's it all fits
together in some pretty fascinating ways
then and then yeah it certainly does in
a matter of fact I'm thinking to myself
I'm like my god this is like a big
commercial for yoga
you know like low the low-impact muscle
movement of that kind creating you know
an increase of endocannabinoids let's so
let's circle this all the way back
around to the strengthening and building
muscle before we move on to different
types of athleticism so you know at its
you know I don't know a lot about a
sports physiology but my general
understanding is that how we're building
muscle is that we rip the muscle and
then as as our body goes to repair that
it repairs it you know bigger if you
will and so you're building muscle mass
and then so you know you rip it today
you heal tomorrow you rip it today so
that that's clearly something that is
going to be partially regulated by the
endocannabinoid system how will you know
that having the canvas to help us be
present in the moment is good and to
focus so that we can lift more
wait and have better form that's all
good but at that at the muscular level
how will this support our building and
strengthening of muscles well I don't
know that it will I mean honestly and
and you know that ripping and tearing is
is you know an intrinsic part of that
does include inflammation and I have
talked to a sports physician who has
expressed to me that he thinks the
anti-inflammatory actions of the
cannabinoids actually would be working
against bulking up and really if your
weightlifting to build mass that that
may be contrary I I don't know I've I've
got a little observation into my own
holes articles on use of cannabis
related to strength training and I don't
you know I I shouldn't even say but at a
molecular level we don't really know and
me talking about what happens at that
neuromuscular synapse is not really
addressing how the tissue is remodeling
during the recovery and that can help
build mast maybe there would be an
interference I don't know how important
inflammation is to the actual mass
building that goes on but it's it's an
interesting question because because if
we need some inflammation in the area
maybe we don't need as much as we have
because you know a lot of people love
cannabis for recovery right and so may
be okay we we rip up the muscles and
which causes its repair and inflammation
but maybe if the cannabis is decreasing
inflammation X variable amount maybe
that's where we're getting some of our
ease of recovery from these sports yes I
think so but you know again cannabis
isn't just a endocannabinoid system
isn't just a master regulator of
inflammation it's so much broader than
that and in many vascular beds
endocannabinoids act as vasodilators now
that's
may not happen all the time but it
vasodilation is something that is taken
I mean
supplements that is that are for example
nitric oxide donors are taken by weight
lifters to improve the amount of weight
you can go the circulation of of
oxygenated blood to the tissues is
enhanced may be cannabis does that add a
level that is not exaggerated but
supportive of sustained muscle function
during training and I mentioned
cannabinoid receptors on mitochondria I
mean the other kind of supplement that
is really used to boast both performance
and and recovery or are supplements like
creating phosphates and things that will
support the regeneration of ATP if and
this is certainly conjecture in my part
but if the cannabinoid receptors on
mitochondria are involved with making
mitochondria more efficient maybe that
has something to do with replenishing
ATP that's a very testable question that
I don't think anybody has gotten to yeah
well I certainly haven't seen anything
on it and that actually leads us right
next to our other our next category of
sports which is endurance right so if
we've got receptors on the mitochondria
we know that the the the efficiency of
the creation and burning of that energy
is going to be some way related to the
endocannabinoid system yeah right take
that as a baton I wasn't sure exactly
yeah so so so let's talk about running
and swimming right I mean we clearly
talked a lot about running at the top of
the show but these you know by our using
cannabis how do you see that for runners
and swimmers to add to their overall
training regimen well I mean I just
think if it if it improves their
experience and their adherence to the
discipline of their sport then it's
going to have
the benefits of sticking with it and and
it could be of great help
I I some of this could be this aspect of
getting in the zone or combating fatigue
that cannabis can be involved with and
like I'm saying there's lots of cellular
molecular basis for that the metabolic
benefits that may happen with using a
way of using cannabis and in your life
around training may help to support the
kind of changes that again help to seats
shift you to a different set point and
we're not my training partner now we've
talked about exercise as a vision of
homeostasis I mean you push yourself out
of your zone and part of the recurrence
of training to get your time better to
get your endurance better is you're kind
of forcing a homeostasis to a different
set point I mean that my my buddy used
to talk about me hitting the red zone
because I'm telling you when I first
started training in the gym two years
ago again since first time in a long
time I would work out with my buddy Mike
for like 20 minutes and I would be like
I would be redlining I felt terrible and
the act of continuing to train is really
pushing your body into that zone which I
do very much believe we evolved to get
into but you know 20 years out of shape
is 20 years out of shape and you have to
sort of re-engage yourself to be
adaptive in that setpoint and there may
be some consequence where you don't feel
so good when you go weeks without
training but that's another you know let
me let me ask this question in a
different way too because I was I was
setting you up because I thought you
were gonna tell me that that there are
ways that cannabis can can help the
performance of swimming and running the
actual physicality of doing it and you
went to mindset which makes me think
that maybe my whole direction I was
coming because I thought you you know
cannabis is considered a endurance sport
enhancing drug right and so it
is banned in many sports areas but this
actually creates this idea in me that
that maybe it's banned not necessarily
because it will make you a better
swimmer do the physical act of swimming
but maybe the reason why it's sports
enhancing is just because it keeps your
head in the game so much more and your
ability to ignore distractions you know
from the competitor in the next lane
over you know maybe that's it and and I
was actually yeah huh that's interesting
I I do think so you know like the
n-c-double-a right now it views CBD is a
banned substance of course because it's
right late Schedule one but you know
even thinking cogently about it I've
talked to a physician with the
n-c-double-a who's you know saying well
it's an anti-inflammatory and that's
performance-enhancing because
inflammation that's a wild story because
we're gonna stop letting people take
ibuprofen beforehand but yeah I mean
that anti controlling inflammation that
may occur during the course of a
distance sport certainly could help to
promote you know sticking with the
behavior but I think the mental focus
the letting go of grasping you know
there's a whole other dialogue out there
about cannabis and meditation you know
and and I think there's a intersect
there and that both are have a
relationship to letting go of your
grasping of your discursive mind and
that helps with getting into a
meditative place and it helps with
possibly like you said not thinking
about the competitor not thinking about
what you look like or even being able to
forget the fact that your ankle isn't
feeling very well I mean not like I'm
trying to tell people to push through
pain that's there and that takes me to
another little piece that you know when
we're talking about why cannabis could
be performance promoting whether it
should be used in sports I was I know
we're not primarily talking about things
like head injury but I was speaking at a
conference on traumatic brain injury a
couple months ago and I spoke to
I mean a fellow who's a doctor he's a
sports physician at a at a NC double-a
school works with football players and
he he was talking about the use of
canvas and sports and I won't go down
this whole wormhole but my feeling is
that whether or not cannabis or CBD even
on the sidelines of games could would be
preventing people from serious brain
injury and I think it could I think it's
more a question of our athletes
especially in contact sports our
athletes should have a absolutely right
to be medicating with this medicine
because we should be concerned not with
just getting them back on their feet but
with their longevity as human beings and
I think CBD and full spectrum cannabis
products should be part should be
allowed and supported but professional
athletics because it helps to promote
the longevity and health and well-being
of the athletes and the question of
whether they can get back on the field
real quickly you know and earn their
paycheck is not the one that the medical
profession should be focused on as much
yeah that's a that's a big cultural
shift to shift our view of of sports
players from entertainers to humans and
and have some kind of interest in their
in their longevity right yeah totally
and they're like being aware of them as
a human instead of yeah yeah we hang out
with a group of 55 year old NFL players
they're they're nearly near the end of
their natural life if they were like on
the offensive line those guys don't have
a long life expectancy and a lot of
times even with a lot of wealth it's not
very happy and I don't want to roll this
up in a whole different conversation but
that is something I feel powerfully
about right on fair enough so so let's
talk about the the last of the three
categories we talked about strengthening
and building muscles endurance sports
like swimming and running for myself I
play racquetball and I absolutely know
that I play differently
with a little bit of THC in my body you
know
if I if I smoked it it may actually
decrease my my breath a little bit
because I happen to have asthma but I
swear I've got like a sixth sense of
where the ball is gonna go I see the
physics better I attempt and succeed
more aggressive shots and and so like
what's what's your take on that is it
just am I getting more creative am I
just more less averse to risk like
legally what about these dexterity and
mobility based sports where you have to
visualize where a sport action is gonna
take place and then you have grow and do
it it's a the fun part about all of this
is that because the endocannabinoids and
the you know the receptors that cannabis
works on are so everywhere in the brain
then you can just think about the
neuroscience of performance and and
think well cannabis could totally
influence that all the ways you're
talking about whether it influences you
with greater risk taking or sort of
sensory motor visual performance that
said I certainly do have a way to
consider this and that the the neural
circuits in our brain and spinal cords
that are involved with executing motor
behavior or where some of the greatest
expressions that cannabinoid receptors
are and we know that the learning and
unlearning of behavioral habits are
involved involve endocannabinoids
signaling and for example I look at the
cerebellum the cerebellum is part of the
brain that sits in the back actually the
name means little brain it is anybody
who studied brain function knows that
the cerebellum is involved with
coordination and timing and and in
clinical symptoms of ataxia various
forms of ataxia and this coordinated
symptoms are related to cerebellar
damage the cerebellum what it does on a
neuro circuit level simplified is it
it's constantly processing where your
body is in space like what's actually
how
opening with your body and using input
from what we call proprioceptors if you
close your eyes and raise your hand you
can feel very much where your body is
because the proprioceptive input is
telling your brain and it's going
through the cerebellum to do so the
cerebellum is not only constantly
measuring where you what your body is
actually doing but it is comparing it
with what you intend to do and what you
expect to happen and all of these things
like the angle of the racket ball the
angle of the ball coming back off the
wall how you integrate that with the way
the velocity with which you saw it
hitting the wall you know how hard your
opponent hit it you heard the sound of
it you saw where on the you've got where
it hit you got a memory of how your
opponent throws a wicked spin on it all
of those kinds of things build a
projection in your mind of where that
ball is going to go and to get there you
have to coordinate what your body is
actually doing with what you're
expecting and what's going on by real
time and again the neuroscience of this
is very its course is fascinating and
it's very mainstream to think that our
heads and our brains evolved to make
these kinds of computations and the
endocannabinoids are really involved
with that in the cerebellar cortex where
a lot of the circuitry is involved every
single synapse is regulated by
endocannabinoids so in that route it's
not surprising and much of the research
has looked at and how does weed impair
you it's not surprising that high doses
of THC will gum up your coordination
you know there's absolutely a way to
overdo it and take so much that your
brain is gonna impact your game
negatively but if a judicious you know
more micro sort of dosing of cannabis
helps you get in your game and feel that
there's all kinds of biological
rationale for why that would be the case
and there are forms the very laboratory
controlled cerebellar learning
in animals that are dependent on
cannabinoid receptors to happen
it doesn't happen as well when you don't
have the cb1 receptor and you know
that's part of the I guess to step back
from that a little bit in segue into
what would be like a broad or sort of
Gestalt of this this conversation other
conversations I speculate a lot about
how cannabis could enhance performance
because I think the underlying
neurobiology and physiology is there but
also because there aren't very many
people in the world who worked with
these genetic knockouts earlier than I
did I'm talking about mice that don't
have can see be one cannabinoid
receptors I've been studying that sort
of genetic study system well I mean i'm
not in the lab 24/7 now but then it's
not about my experience the point is the
data show us over and over again lots of
different labs that and i'm also mammals
that don't have cb1 can have annoyed
receptors live lives that are shorter
more inflammation prone more seizure
prone more metabolically messed up and
and again they're prone to early deaths
all these kinds of things and they run
less we know this to cb1 knockout mice
are less prone to running on it on an
exercise wheel so it's part of part of
how our brains evolved for
endocannabinoids to be master tuners of
the rhythms of our brain and though
cannabinoids help to tune them and when
and where and how the compounds in
cannabis might improve that in a
beneficial way that that has to shake
out empirically you know and if you're
an N of one and using cannabis a little
bit helps you improve your game I think
that is every bit as believable and
justifiable you know explainable as it
is to say that Louie Armstrong was
better playing trumpet when he was a
little bit high for sure you know it's
these kinds of things and and not to
speak for
a past review musician who we know use
cannabis but I've been around a lot of
musicians in my life who again you can
overdo it but that it also can play a
role in your motor performance your
dexterity and wet we don't have any
clinical data to say you're gonna be a
better guitar player or racquetball
player by microdose in cannabis first
but this stud this science does help us
understand better who we are and one
thing I've learned from healers of all
stripes whether they are accepted by the
medical establishment or not is that the
story we tell ourselves matters our
perspectives on healing matters our
perspective on optimum performance
matters there are systems of our body
that help to promote that that we can
access the endocannabinoid system being
a master player among them and there's a
plant that helps us interact with that
endocannabinoids system and there's a
reason why it has been revered across
human culture since before human
language beautiful that's a great
wrap-up so let's let's let's pause there
and go to our last commercial break and
then we come back we'll talk about a
whole bunch of variables to this you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is gregor demon chief scientific
officer at three boys farm as a listener
of shaping fire you already understand
the importance of living soil when
growing cannabis when you have active
microbe communities in your substrate
you go way beyond simply fertilizing
with nitrogen phosphorus and potassium
having active microorganisms in your
substrate supports vigorous plant growth
throughout the plants root zone making
for higher yields and thriving flowers
mammoth pea is the first organically
derived microbial inoculant
that focuses on your plants nutrient
cycling processes to release soil
phosphorus and other micronutrients from
they're bound forms making them more
available to the plant increased levels
of phosphorus will also keep internode
shorter and focus your plants energy on
bud production not only that but the
microbes act as a defense shield for the
plants rhizosphere
by out competing potentially harmful
pathogenic microbes
pretty cool right mammoth P not only
unlocks the nutrients in your soil but
it also helps protect your plant from
disease mammoth Peas beneficial bacteria
act like micro bio reactors continually
producing enzymes that release nutrients
mammoth P was developed at a u.s.
University has been extensively tested
by Colorado growers and independent
laboratories mammoth P is proven to
increase growth and enhance blooming one
of the great things about supplementing
with microorganisms is that they won't
compete with whatever fertilizer program
you're already running simply dose on
top of your fertilizer schedule for
increased benefits to learn more and to
find out where you can buy namma P near
you check out their website at
www.petland.com I always record them and
bring the content home for you to watch
the Shango lowe's youtube channel has
world-class speakers including kevin
Jodrey of wonderland nursery talking
about breeding cannabis for the best
terpene profile nicholas Mahmood on
regenerative and polyculture cannabis
growing dr. Sunil Agarwal on the history
of cannabis medicine around the world
Ben Cassidy of Tru terpenes on using
terpenes for health in your everyday
life
Reggie Godinho of steep hill on the
cannabis genome and Jeff Lowen Fell's on
the soil food web
there are several presentations from dr.
Ethan Russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system and even my own
presentation on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose cannabis business even though the
risks are so high as of today there are
over 100 videos that you can check out
for absolutely free go to youtube.com
forward slash Shango 'lose or click on
the link in this week's newsletter
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango Louis
and our guest this week is gregor demon
chief scientific officer at three boys
farm so greg like let's take the take a
step back from the specifc of sports
physiology and let's talk about car
avascular help because even people who
are not actively working out or playing
a particular sport they want to have you
know they want to be heart-healthy if
you will right and and it's weird you
know you know I've been I've been at
ocher you know pretty much my whole life
I've also been a fan of the Beastie Boys
pretty much my entire life and they've
got this one song we're called heart
attack man and they're talking about
this guy and and he does a lot of stuff
that I don't do right like he's you know
he's into you know he's drinking a lot
and he's and he's going to you know fast
food and but but but the part that I
always remember is they talked about him
getting high and then playing basketball
and they're waiting for him to drop dead
on the court right and and so somewhere
you know that got that got put in my
brain that whenever I'm working out and
well like like you know and more
endurance stuff and my heart starts
pounding and I'm high I always just kind
of in the back of my mind think I'm just
gonna like drop over dead and I don't
have any evidence for it and I've got my
been to my doctor and she's all like no
you're not at risk like you're fine and
no she won't approve a stress test for
me so I can make sure but but she's like
your there's no there's no one no reason
for you to be concerned about this that
I'm only but the Beastie Boys and that
doesn't really get that doesn't get me
anywhere so so let's talk about
cardiovascular health because that's
like one of the the worst things in the
United States how can our use of
cannabis helped us to have healthy
hearts that won't crap out on us well I
mean if it helps to in ways we've been
talking about to promote exercise
there's a indirect thing but it's I
certainly don't want to come across like
cannabis being a magic pill towards
better heart health I there's good
measures I think public health outcomes
from you know survey basis that cannabis
users are are in general tend towards
better health but there there are
concerns around cardiovascular issues I
mean it it could be
that cannabis this is a weird thing I
stuttered because this is a place where
the human observation in in what I've
talked about like with better body mass
index for example doesn't exactly line
up with some of the concerns that have
been raised in animal research that
there's greater fat deposition for
example that part of what the cb1
cannabinoid receptor does is not only
promote feeding behavior but it helps
promote the storage of fats and if the
storage of fats helps to create
metabolic or cardiovascular risk well
then maybe that would be some indication
against high THC for chronic use but we
don't really know it hasn't been in my
view big red flags about cardiac risk or
long term cardiac improvement I'd like
to see more stuff about can't breaking
down cannabis users and controlled
studies and looking at real
cardiovascular performance profiles
whether its heart rate variability or
ejection fraction and under stress that
kind of thing I do know that again it is
animal research but a study that was
published very prominently a few years
ago out of Germany showed that and mice
which do get atherosclerosis and that's
you know like the hardening of the
arteries that is a sort of the primary
risk factor and predictor of larger
cardiovascular disease and in mice with
specially fed a Western diet
atherosclerosis actually absolutely
happens and in mice that were fed daily
really low doses of THC the the severity
of atherosclerosis and plaque formation
related to it was significantly reduced
I mean this was like published in nature
top scientific journal in the world and
it was very low dose it was something
like point zero one milligrams per per
kilogram is very low for an animal study
and and it should produce
atherosclerosis does that mean like a
low dose sort of wellness level regular
cannabis
consumption could help limit
atherosclerosis which is numb leads to
coronary vascular disease number one
killer
am i it might know whether you smoke it
or ingested some other way and it and I
should speak if we're talking about
cardiovascular health about the the
worry for adverse outcomes in that
smoking cannabis taking THC does lead to
a increased heart rate
you know clinically we'll call it
tachycardia there's a transient
tachycardia
increased heart rate that happens and
that's part of what supports panic
attacks when people have taken more than
they were expecting or knew how to
expect and when that edible starts
kicking in in the second hour and you
took way too much and your heart starts
racing that as can create a negative
spiral again it is transient and even
within sort of low dose sessions you'd
adjust to that but people who have
emergent cardiovascular disease and/or
maybe at a high risk of stroke for
example because they've already they
know they've got a club the the
potential for clots if they're taking
medicines for that then they should be
cautious around going too high with tea
because there are people who can suffer
a stroke or cardiac incident simply from
having an increased rate you know and
then that as a side effect it's
something for people recognizing people
even when we first our exercise study
showing that the runners joy is related
to endocannabinoids signaling I maybe
was you I'd certainly talked to people
who who asked me you know like all right
so somebody you wanted to get back to
exercise can be happy about it and like
yeah but you know if you're someone
who's recovering from a heart attack and
you are not used to jogging you don't
want to just boost that with a hit off a
joint and then go run without taking
some consideration even that said I mean
there's not strong clinical data that
people are at increased risks of heart
attacks but there have been
studies to suggest that patients who
there have been some clinical findings
of patient with a with stroke with a
heart attack who had been smoking
beforehand and that caused an effect in
those incidences may be related so um
it's always been my understanding or
belief I guess because I don't I don't
have a lot of evidence for this is that
the reason why the heart rate increases
with smoking THC or or I guess if you're
taking enough edible but the point is is
that it drops my blood pressure which
causes the heart have to have to pump
faster to make up for the dropping of
the the blood pressure and so so is
there is that is that scientifically
accurate or is that just a myth that I
grabbed onto oh no that makes sense and
that it can because it vasodilate it can
drop your blood pressure and that can
create exactly that it with with lower
blood returning to the heart it will
compensate by increasing the rate but it
also works in the in the autonomic
control of the heartbeat itself and and
can create a transient increase in heart
rate even if you're sitting down which
shouldn't really be accompanied with too
much problems from blood pressure right
on some people do take you know THC
based tinctures to lower their blood
pressure do you think that to get that
lowering of the blood pressure it
necessitates also having the increase of
heart rate I kind of you know I was
under the general idea that that the the
the the pounding of the heart rate was
more related to particular terpene
profiles and the excitement of the
adrenals but but then also I know about
this other decreasing of the blood
pressure aspect of it as well so I'm not
really sure how that dynamic works yeah
well I I think if somebody would said
they were sure about it they'd be
pulling your leg this is complex that's
fair a lot that hasn't been studied
I like mean you're bringing in the
adrenals on the release of epinephrine
from there
that could be part of it but no I don't
think anybody really knows and I - you
know there hasn't been a real well
controlled study that I know of just
looking at changes in resting blood
pressure in people who might be you know
sort of baseline hypertensive but I have
again with just these clinical anecdotal
findings of people who have found
success I've talked to many people over
the years who are like I started using
cannabis for XYZ and my physician came
back to me and said your blood pressure
is great what are you doing
keep it ha ha ha ha you know and is that
clinical evidence well you know not at
the standard that that we tend to
operate when we're talking about
medicines and improving medicines but
it's a clinical outcome that I've seen
I've heard discussed you know in a
repeated way and I'd love to know if if
cannabis use can increase and lower the
blood pressure of someone who's running
high I'd sure love to help find out who
benefits in that way and and when and if
there if there are variety variations
and terpene constituents that play a
role in that
that's perfectly conceivable but even
you know there you get into that whole
new angle of terpenes and all of their
mechanisms of function are far from
clear and in the most part that's
judiciously said things are effective
exquisitely low concentrations a lot of
times and you know people say things
like oh mercy and helps THC cross the
blood-brain barrier but this is
speculation there's not good data to
show those things so so so far today
we've talked about using cannabis in a
lot of different ways to help your human
body in a bunch of different ways
similarly cannabis can be ingested by
different methods right there's there's
there's combustion smoking or a vape pen
or my favorite tincture
what are your thoughts on you know the
best mode to ingest cannabinoids based
on the the different goals we've been
talking about today yeah I mean the
bottom line is always gonna be that it
depends on the person and how things
respond and will work well for them but
if you are if you're wanting a rapid
mode of action you know that maybe it's
certainly if you talk about breakthrough
symptom control you know we're talking
about medicine but today we're trying to
talk about performance and again you
know back to our earlier talk you know
if you want to sort of find a place that
you become familiar with that's a good
zone for your fitness then a fast onset
like a a vape vaping well they've been
flower taking a hit that maybe what is
most effective for you and and if you're
not scared of cannabis it may be the
kind of thing to suggest first because
you can get a better sense of yeah this
is how quickly this works but textures
and sublingual application can certainly
come on pretty fast too and I'm a big
fan and like you said of teachers and
sublingual oils I mean enough they both
for even-even I mean I'm a growing fan
of you know the decarboxylated I mean
the raw acids I think they're highly
underestimated and and that people could
be popping those and tinctures to great
health benefit whether it would improve
performance not sure but it is a quick
mode of action and then and then when
you've got again thinking back about
performance and mobility back to my
story of a buddy long ago told me that
you know they would eat edibles and go
on a run people who have the kind of
sport that involves endurance some sort
of edible product might be what they
find works to help prolong their zone
their you know flow state if they get
their block met and maybe through the
mechanism I mentioned earlier maybe
there's a way to help
prevent muscle fatigue or promote muscle
function so you know it does come down
to what people empirically find works
for them and and at this point anyway
and I'd love to I'd love to see a day
where we've got some stronger
repeatability and then I can give more
recommendations to the naive user but
right now I would be cautious about it
right on you know we talk a lot about
individualized medicine on this show
and I would say that that this feels a
lot like the same way it's like okay for
me I may like to use a 1 to 1 THC and
CBD tincture for overall endocannabinoid
health and after workout healing from
from you know running into the wall or
the racquetball court and all but when
I'm gonna go lift and I really want to
be in the moment
well then I'm gonna you know take a
small hit for my one hitter you know of
a little bubble hat or something and and
I guess that really is it I guess I
guess the the point here is for to
encourage folks to not assume that all
of these solutions are going to be
inhaled based and make sure that you
consider the the range of modalities
that we've got now which is the most
anybody's ever had in human history yeah
and so don't don't feel like it has to
be smoking just like when you explain to
patients that they don't have to smoke
only kind of blows their mind a little
bit for the first time right now and we
haven't even talked about topicals in
this performance piece because that is I
do tend to think more in terms a very
local inflammation but there are
different all kinds of different modes I
mean when we're talking about
sublinguals I mean some dissolvable
strip might be very effective as well
but you know it's I'm not gonna go out
proselytizing to people about that
bringing cannabis and a lot into their
life is gonna make everything or make
make it all better but a lot of people
are using and enjoy it feel like
cannabis increases their quality of life
and if you want to bring that into
of supporting a physical fitness routine
yeah do that because it might help and
it's so safe to experiment with think
about don't think that you're just
limited to taking yeah I hit off a joint
before you do it but try thinks you're
15 minutes before you start working out
and see it you may don't don't gauge
whether it's working by whether you feel
high gauge whether it's working with
whether it you're you worked out well
feel good about it yeah absolutely take
anything away from us to put value on
the medicine you know by saying oh the
medicine helped me it doesn't take
anything you helped yourself by using a
plant product that you that works with
how you evolved you know again the story
that we tell each other ourselves
matters yeah I uh there's a video that I
recently put on the the shaping fire
YouTube channel there's a running a
series there right now the the second
shaping fire sessions I did was with
Ethan Russo the first one with was with
Kevin Chaudhary and and you know Ethan
is very adamant that there is a great
deal of cannabis efficacy below the
intoxication mark and so many people
think that you need to get high to get
the benefits but you know
anti-inflammatory is a great example you
know serious anti-inflammatory patients
will take two point five milligrams
every three to four hours throughout the
day and be at work and they've got
active cannabinoids including THC in
their bloodstream all day long and yet
they don't feel anything yep absolutely
a right on I've learned a lot from Ethan
in that regard and I parrot him quite a
lot in here in Florida where we've got
you know medical cannabis landscaping
let me tell you it's hard to go to a
dispensary as they exist in Florida and
find those low-dose I mean to be able to
take something really easy at a 2.5
milligram level repeatedly the companies
that play in Florida are more interested
in higher dose products and you know I'm
not dismissing high dose and that that's
valuable medicine it's got its place too
easy so yeah but
but no exactly you don't have to titrate
the feeling high but to improvement
whether you're talking about symptom
management or in this case we're taking
it to a different level of wellness
performance you know improving you know
functionality and mobility and and open
us live our best self
oops you know what what do you what do
you think about these CBD isolate vape
pens that we're starting to see you know
you know sports people you know hitting
on during press conferences and stuff
you know I mean I know I know that
generally you're a whole plant guy like
I am right that we that you know we want
to use the whole plant but they're so
invoke and I know that there are people
who are listening to the show cuz
they're like Oh cannabis and exercise
and then they're sports heroes are like
pushing or being a coming attached to
these CBD isolate pens but for me I like
I think that I slit you know unless
unless you're getting your whole plant
somewhere else and you're just spiking
your your regular daily use with some
extra CBD isolate using CBD isolate on
its own doesn't sound like a great idea
to me but what are your thoughts I you
know I'm not interested I'm just not
it's see there's I don't want to
disparage any athlete stepping out
supporting CBD in any way and and I I
I've really enjoyed meeting some great
athletes in the cannabis space and I
praise them for coming out and helping
normalize it because nobody helps to
normalize the conversation and better
than these athletes that we really as a
society tend to worship you know and and
it's great and CBD is a great compound
you know I it's it's amazing how things
have shifted but tip for us to be
dismissing CBD in any way right because
CBD is great it's part of the medicine
but yeah the isolate that that's not
what I want to be involved in developing
it's not ever gonna be my first choice
as a product and it's got to be cut with
other agents because CBD now by that I
mean dilute
there's something else innovate pin than
CBD because CBD doesn't stay in solution
very well you know you talk to people in
the business and they'll might they
might say something like it sugars out
or it crystals up for what they're
meaning it comes out of solution and and
that CBD does that very well and so it
there will be something else added to
help it dissolve and that's something
you're breathing in and I'm cautious
about that stuff all right again I'm I'm
not trying to dismiss any athletes but I
also know that cbiit the CBD market is
booming because there's it's it's cheap
it's there's huge interest going into
the production and you know some a
subset of athletes I mean companies seek
them out to give them these endorsement
opportunities and you know again that
sounds like I'm speaking negatively
about them I am NOT but I think it's a
product not interested right on I hear
that and that makes sense and I think
that the only reason that CB isolate it
got so hot in the first place is because
it's an artificial market right we've
got we don't have got federal
prohibition of whole plant and and for
the moment you know CBD isolate is only
being selectively enforced by the
federal government based on the claims
that you're making from it right so even
though it's Schedule one they're not
actually going around the country and
busting people what they're busting
people is for saying you cannot say that
CBD will solve your whatever your issue
is so right you can't say that but
they're not busting people for having it
if if we had federal whole plant legal
everywhere CBD isolate would just
disappear because whole plant was so
much more effective but there's
artificial prohibitions on it and
therefore thus CBD isolate world you
know right right I think so and there's
so much cannabis a you know column type
three cannabis varieties hemp varieties
whatever that are CBD producers as you
know very well there's so much growing
now in North America and part of the
boom and that CBD isolates because it's
been imported in mass in huge volumes
not as helped flower but it's you know
this first extract sludge that
from so many different places and gets
then you know we're fine to distill down
into CBD and there's a if for all these
market reasons it exists and me now
we're living in a space where you know
grocery stores and health food stores
are talking about cell and CBD products
it's in CVS I think Urban Outfitters is
the last one I read today is gonna start
carrying CBD oils and I hope that they
are oils I had there's so much growing
now and a market to support farmers that
are you know growing and having a good
farming life that that that whole
spectrum are fuller less less processed
oils that don't isn't taken down to the
powder and sold around as a molecular
commodity let's keep you know let's keep
cannabis flower in cannabis extract oils
as the health and wellness and
supplement commodity and not just
boiling it down to molecules and I think
I'm you know I'm as classically trained
molecular pharmacology guys you get and
but that's where I stand with it yeah I
totally agree with you and I think that
this is another great place for us to
plug home growing right like you know
fight find a keema var that you like
grow it in your backyard or over the
summer make your own tincture and or
smoke it yourself and know exactly what
you have I'm never gonna speak against
home grow by entities that you know want
to have more of a market control but
whether it's a medicine or you know I
just I think we have a human right to
access this plant and nothing makes it
more accessible than having a plant that
you tan and learning from it so yeah I'm
not against that right on well Gregg
thank you so much for sharing your vast
experience with us it was really great
because you know you've got this unique
combination where you know all these
years teaching anatomy and physiology
but then also your you know
endocannabinoid research you
I did a great entree to this this nexus
is a nexus of ideas so thank you so much
for taking your time and joining us in
being on the show
it's my pleasure thanks for putting me
on fantastic
so if you want to connect with Gregor
diamond or are actually just a follow
along with with what he's up to
the best way to do that is to go to his
Instagram and that's gan-chan - so
that's at GaN J a n a sh and also while
you're at if you want to hear more
interesting insights from Greg go ahead
and go back to shaping fire episode 14
all about synthetic cannabinoids and and
Greg breaks down what the heck these
things are and why they are not
naturally occurring cannabinoids and why
they are so much more dangerous for the
human body compared to naturally
occurring cannabinoids which are not
dangerous at all you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shaping fire
calm and on Apple iTunes stitcher and
Google Play if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you'd leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where i'll be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hot spot at shaping
feiyr.com to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire i've been your
host
Shango lows
you