[Music]
it's amazing to see how much cannabis
extraction has evolved in such a short
time I mean if you looked at cannabis on
a historical timeline there would be
flowers and hash for millennia and then
right at the end of the timeline
suddenly humans start using alcohol
butane and carbon dioxide and even hair
straighteners to remove the essential
oils of the cannabis plant the beginning
of normalization has created a surging
demand for all sorts of extracts
including dab oil inputs to make edibles
and full extract cannabis oil or fee Co
each of these processes demand the right
technology employed by a knowledgeable
technician if you enjoy hearing smart
discussions that dive deep in a cannabis
health business and technique I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter every week you'll receive a
new podcast episode delivered right to
your inbox along with commentary on a
couple of the most important news items
from the week and often videos too don't
rely on social media to let you know
when a new episode is published sign up
for the newsletter to make sure you
don't miss a single episode you are
listening to shaping fire and I am your
host Shang golos my guest today is AC
Braddock AC is CEO of Eden labs one of
the original leaders of cannabis
extraction technology reaching all the
way back to the early days of medical in
California with normalisation Eden has
become possibly the most prominent
extraction technology company in the US
and one of the top 10 fastest growing
women lead companies in Seattle
Washington AC not only leads Adan but
she's a thought leader industry-wide as
well and often travels the world to
speak at international cannabis
conferences she's a founding supporter
of the cannabis women's alliance women
grow and women of weed she's also a
board member of the NCI a the NCI a
federal policy council and the cannabis
Alliance today we're going to talk with
AC about the rise of co2 extraction
technology and the importance of
kindness in cannabis culture welcome to
the show AC thanks Shango I'm so
delighted to be here so I'm excited to
be talking about Eden and your
experience with extraction for a while
you know Eden was in the
Tanika extraction business well before
cannabis what kinds of other extractions
were you designing prior to getting into
cannabis well the founder of the the
company for its chest began doing
extractions in about 1994 but actually
cannabis was always a part of that
process he did a lot of different kinds
of botanicals but you know for instance
he was the first one the first to
advertise in high times for a an
extraction system in 94 95 and that was
a small ethanol system and then he put a
large system in San Francisco in 1996
one proposition 215 passed so some of
the other botanicals if there's a wide
array is biofuels Masuda coals herbs for
acupuncturist herbalist actually the
abreast of extraction knowledge that he
has across multiple botanical structures
and industries is really amazing you
know it surprises me you know I thought
I knew your you know Eden labs
background in cannabis but I had no idea
that Fritz had gotten started so early
in the San Francisco scene that's
actually when I was living down there he
obviously has had an affinity for
cannabis medicine a long time did you
did you find that you were you're well
positioned because of that experience
when the first you know in Washington
and Colorado first broke out he pretty
prince was probably like finally I get a
chance to apply my technology in in
functioning markets yeah I mean you know
I said back in the mid 90s it you know
if it wasn't for California even allowed
to be a part-time job
oh yeah hobby so yeah he has been doing
this quite a while and it definitely was
a boon to Eden as well as the entire
industry to have someone with his
background and experience when those
markets
and live in later on for Colorado and in
Washington and in 2009 so if he was
beginning you know like you said if it
weren't for California be a part-time
job and I know that your extractors are
used across other industries for
different botanicals at what point did
did the threshold kind of get past where
you went it went from just being you
know you know Fritz and one or two other
people to oh gosh
you know it looks like we need to we
need to start hiring people because the
cannabis part of our business is is
growing so fast
yeah that's tipping point for especially
for cannabis was about 2009 and then
really kicked in in 2010 mm-hmm and and
and so I can imagine at that same time
you know you're early sales were to
medical cannabis companies in Washington
and Colorado and in in California which
had already been selling to but you know
those a lot of those new companies
wanted to use your technology but they
didn't have access to traditional
financing yet and while you know while
the eating machines are you know a are
worth the money they're also not
something that a lot of these new
companies you know had and financing
right away I can imagine that you had to
do some pretty creative financing to
help these companies get the ball
rolling also making sure that Eden was
first to market in this groundbreaking
industry yes so those early years were
very challenging for people to be able
to get in to you know get equipment that
would really help them be successful so
there was definitely a lot of creativity
and there still is I mean it's still an
issue obviously with you know not having
access to the federal banking system and
or you know companies can't get lines of
credit you know you have to completely
rely on investors and you know often
that can be problematic
I'm having those two worlds come
together so it has been challenging in
it and it still is but certainly a lot
better mm-hmm
that's for sure and also you know in the
early days of medical it was it was such
a legal gray area that it was a lot
harder to find you know even angel
investment capital and since and since
we're all pretty well at least fairly
confident that cannabis is here to stay
it's a lot easier to get individual
investment now than it was in those in
those early days you know the you know
in addition to the the early companies
not necessarily having the financing for
such a you know fine product as the
extractors you know a lot of the owner
operators didn't have proper science
backgrounds how do you make up for
operator error as they as they run your
machines you know a poor mish of poor
operator getting poor results looks bad
for EDA not because the machine is doing
anything wrong but because the quality
of what's coming out of the machine and
then is going for sale or to a patient
or whatever you know it might not be up
to quality and then they say always run
on an eating machine when when actually
the machine was fine but the operator is
the one who doesn't have the experience
what do you do as a company to to help
soften the likelihood of that well
several different things but the
foundation of all of that actually is
why it started engineering co2 systems
to begin with he was he was doing all
kind of different botanicals as we
mentioned earlier one of the things that
he had a hard time extracting with
ethanol because he started with ethanol
systems was called a kava and it would
not extract well in ethanol so I was
like all right well I needed I need to
try some temperature and pressure and
they start looking around at different
to two extraction systems there are only
a couple of companies at the time and
they were huge international companies
and the systems were very expensive they
were fully automated they were fussy and
of course none of these companies had
any idea
about you know extracting heavily
resinous materials so he said all right
well I don't want a system like that I
just want something that simple to
operate that will not break down that
you know I can I can run comfortably and
so that's what he designed and you know
22 years later the systems haven't been
based on that are very easy to operate
and they are extremely reliable and and
we as a company we obviously were
extremely invested in this industry and
we really want all of our people to be
successful so we have an internal
training for those people we have text
that they can call to help them with
things we have a really good obviously a
network having been in the industry as
many years that we share information
with a lot of our clients and we pass
some of that stuff on if they are
agreeable to to do that obviously some
of the technology or the protocols that
they come up with our there are IP we
don't share that but the systems are
there designed to help people people be
successful and we've gone through many
different reiterations of the system at
this point and we just released a new
version this last year and it's awesome
I can imagine especially in the early
days when turnover for lab staff was you
know pretty consistent that there must
have been some frustration from your
from your training department because
just as you got a company's lab staff
trained up and they could use the
Machine correctly you know they were
moving on for one reason or another and
you're like oh man we got to start all
over again I can imagine that you know
as far as you know startup and moving in
a new industry that must have been one
of the early frustrations yeah what we
we've dealt with that is we we train the
operators on this system that they get
and then we can have two four people at
a time from any given company
and part of their Morty is hooked into
the fact that a certified trained person
is running that system and if I have
somebody else do it what's their
warranty so it gives some emphasis to
have always have an operator who has
been trained and knows what they're
doing and that has worked very well for
everyone that's actually a really great
strategy to tied having a properly
trained person to the warranty itself
you know in the early days you know all
sorts of different people in different
labs running your machines I'm like do
they know what they're doing and there
has been a lot of that and there you
know it has and actually the industry
has been my opinion been held back quite
a bit by and lack of a real
understanding of extraction and I can
tell you Shankar you mentioned earlier
about all the traveling that I do and
the primary reason is just trying to get
in front of people to talk about
extraction and why extraction is so
important to this moving this industry
forward especially on legalization
because it's hard to legalize on medical
without a claim to your product so
that's one of the reasons why when I
came in as CEO I wanted to brand the
company as primarily as co2 and ethanol
we make all kinds of different systems
using all sorts of different solvents
but this industry needed an easy path
and it's hard to argue with those two
extraction methodologies yeah that makes
a lot of sense and I want to go ahead
and compare co2 to BHO but let's do that
after the first break here we are going
to take a first break and be right back
you are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is AC Braddock CEO of Eden
labs now that the health benefits of
terpenes have become well known in the
cannabis industry people everywhere are
looking for the purest terpenes without
adulterants the problem with most
terpene providers is that they're not
sourced naturally and instead are made
as a byproduct of refining petroleum and
that's so sketchy the terpenes sold by
true terpenes are entirely different
they are certified organic non-gmo and
food grade that means that they are
extracted from real plant sources there
are no solvents of any
they are distilled only with steam
that's right only steam in fact terpenes
from true drippings are so pure that you
can eat them not only that but you can
stack them with better results too what
I mean is other company's terpenes have
got a few percent of impurities and when
you stack those terpenes to make your
blend you're adding a variety of
impurities that degrade your final
product true terpenes also have
strain-specific turbines for a wide
range of cannabis strains like Durbin
poison sunset sherbet and granddaddy
purple true terpenes has robust and
supportive customer service so your
questions will get answered fast and
efficiently if you shop for Turk's
before you know how rare that is so
whether you want to cup your hands to
smell some betta carry awfully to calm
down after getting too high or if you
want to dab some pining so your lungs
feel fabulous and your mind feels
liberated true terpenes will provide you
with a truly natural experience if you
are a cannabis product developer these
are the Terps you want to add to your
oil or edible or capsule or whatever
true terpenes are simply the best your
money can buy don't try and make a
premium product with substandard terms
choose true terpenes for a top-shelf
experience go to shaping fire calm board
flash true terpenes to find out more or
click on the link in this week's
newsletter welcome back you are
listening to shaping fire I'm your host
Shang colos and our guest this week is
AC Braddock CEO of Eaton Labs so you
know during the end of the last set of a
see you were saying how one of the
things that you wanted to do as you came
in as CEO was to start to play this
evangelist role for extraction and for
easy to use co2 machines and you know a
lot of people have been you know in the
early days they were they were making
BHO butane hash oil and in the early
early days people were blasting outside
which of course was really dangerous but
one of the things that a lot of people
really like about co2 is that there is
no residue left in the product and it's
not a combustible hydrocarbon which a
lot of people are concerned about you
know getting any residue out of it
because it
be a carcinogen so you know what what as
part as part of your of your evangelist
presentation to people what do you say
when you're comparing co2 to BHO and why
co2 is such a great choice for folks
well number one marketability you know
even in the supplements industry many
years ago they started moving over to
co2 from hexane and they used it as a
marketing tool and their packaging and I
think there's a there's a movement in
this country for sustainable
environmentally friendly organic
products so and it's not just cannabis
it's it's all industries because most of
our our food products are currently
extracted with hexane which is very
toxic and in Europe has been banned
anything that's usually made without
light hydrocarbons from many countries
in in the in Europe are not allowed to
be sold in Europe but they are allowed
to be sold in the US so we have a little
bit of a problem with you know what what
we get is human consumables for many
different things that includes
pesticides and in our foodstuffs but in
cannabis you know we have this spotlight
on us about the kind of products that we
make and how they're grown which is good
but we want to shine that light across
multiple industries but you know as I
said earlier even makes all kinds of
different systems and including butane
and propane systems the reason why we
start against what we started focusing
on this is because as you said in the
early days there were so many non
experts utilizing butane because it was
inexpensive to get into and there were
horrific accidents and it was really an
Achilles heel for the industry the media
was having a field day with it and we
needed an alternative but these days
there are many companies who make really
good butane propane pro
products it just requires time to do the
post-processing and understanding of
what you're dealing with one of the main
problems with any solvent really
especially you know butane or propane as
it goes through pipelines and you get
what they call quote-unquote mystery oil
in there which is basically pipeline
lubricants so as long as companies are
being responsible and sourcing really
clean solvents and then purging it and
handling the oils properly it's it's a
viable production method and especially
since different kinds of solvents
produce different kinds of products so
when we deal with people we try and find
out okay what are you trying to make are
you trying to make an edible are you
trying to make shatter are you trying to
do bait pens because different
methodologies are better there for
different product lines I think that's a
really insightful point that you
mentioned about you know the the the
cleanliness of BHO or pho or what have
you it got a bad reputation in the early
days but it wasn't because of the BHO
itself it's because was because the
state of the industry was so young we
had the proper techniques and the
education to remove the residual
solvents just didn't exist in the
industry yet and you had a lot of non
science inexperienced people doing the
post-processing and then it would go out
and and you know you could taste it or
it would snap on the nail or whatever
and people could tell that there was
still residual BHO but the point where
the industry is now through through
education and hiring more scientific lab
staff to a more or less BHO and other
light hydrocarbons are going to be
cleaner than they ever were in the early
days of medical and a lot of that
that fear it's probably time for that to
go away yeah I already have it also
still falls back on the mission and
focus of whatever the company is - I
mean a lot of the people who really who
understand this is a long term plate
it's not a short term place it's not
about making a bunch of money quickly it
just isn't I mean anybody in this
industry knows that at this point so
you're either going to self-regulate and
be an example for the rest of industry
or you're going to be in it for a money
grab and it's pretty easy to pick out
who those companies are the problem is
the general public can't differentiate
yeah and there's there's not testing for
that that's mandatory none of the states
either so you have to you know you have
to self-educate
and then find some sort of brand that
you like and then stick with that brand
loyalty and that makes for a really
exclusive market yeah it does it
definitely hinders the market and you
know and I won the reasons I appreciate
you know you're inviting me on this on
this talk today - because the more we
can help educate each other and the
general public and come to some
consensus on the messaging that we're
going to be bringing as recreational
continues simply to expand we are going
to we don't want to get into a scenario
where the culture of this industry flips
and we're doing same old same old
business and you know we've got Monsanto
type companies and you know it's just
there's so much potential for the
cannabis industry to change our food
consumption civil rights you know
there's just so many different things
that is that are what keep so many of
these companies the tenacity comes from
the passion well I think you know I
totally agree with you and I think that
a lot of us who used to work in the
metal in medical industry actually have
that fear and we watch it because you
know cannabis the plant itself you know
it teaches right and the people who are
who tend to be
be attracted to cannabis and whole plant
medicine of which I know you're also a
big advocate for like I am you know we
saw the kinds of people who used to be
attracted the medical industry and as
states become recreational and licensed
and new forms of investment come in and
the players change out you know our
entire industry at is at risk to
becoming more of a commodity and lose a
lot of that you know original spirit
that I think you're talking about and
and there's got to be enough good
players in the industry who want to keep
the quality high who want to try to you
know stay as close to a whole plant as
we can and to continue to think about
the health of the consumers and the
patients and and and it takes people
like you evangelizing that and to to
remind people of that yes absolutely and
there are some really amazing companies
in this industry and there's some
companies that aren't so much and if we
can help bring them in but you know you
touched on it it's it's the investors
and other business people who are
looking at this as a green rush who come
in and expect big numbers and take
equity out of small businesses and who
are already under tremendous amount of
pressure to even just stay in business
with these people who are just talking
about numbers to them and having that
flavor start taking over what we're
doing is if it's not is not where we
want to go yeah it it's disheartening
that's for sure yes so before we go to
the second commercial I want to talk a
little bit about about flavor of co2 you
know I several years ago I was CEO of a
extraction company and we used Eden
machines and as CEO and as our
evangelist one of the things that I
often had to were to convince people
about co2 was that that it had flavor
and it could it could
really nice dabs compared to BHO and you
know part of what my stick was when I
talked to people was you know in the
early days people were not really sure
in the lab how to make a fine tasted a
boil because they weren't familiar with
the machines yet and the post-processing
and so they were just cooking the Terps
off and it wasn't this but it wasn't the
issue of co2 it was the issue of
inexperienced people using co2 but even
to today as the technology has gotten
better and as laboratory teams have
gotten better there's still this
remaining myth of that like oh you know
dho is always going to taste the best
and co2 is is not going to taste very
good but I know because you know I eyed
or co2 dabs I know the taste is there
what do you say when people kind of
slough off co2 and they say oh it
doesn't have the flavor because I'm sure
you get this pretty often yourself well
yeah we've been getting that for you
know a while but I think the system of
it is from where we are we're in
generally where we are in the industry
so the way I look at it is we are still
in bathtub gin mentality about cannabis
oil so a lot of people only care about
the amount of THC and it being
inexpensive so that lends itself to
trying to produce a product with as much
THC and it as possible
so the early and you know early on co2
is really trying to compete with the co2
operators are trying to compete with
trying to get as much THC in their oil
as possible so they over processed it
they would take it out of the system
they would post process at post process
it and to continue continue to
concentrate it until the THC levels were
high but of course then you've a per
eyes off all of the like light essential
oils or which are all the terpenes
so for about
five years actually been trying to get
our clients because our systems can
fraction eight off terms separately to
and you know then of course what they
are doing is they are taking all that
post process post process oil and then
trying to put it into a smokeable
product what what they really should
have been doing is just do an extraction
of the terpenes which come off really
quickly because they're live essential
oils they come off in like 15 to 45
minutes squirt that out set it aside
continue to run take the lipids and
waxes out of that bulk oil and
reintroduce the terpenes so you have a
whole plant extraction you don't have to
use additives for fluidity in the pens
or and - at this point we have multiple
clients who are doing a1 process where
they just run subcritical and and that
is starting to happen because the public
especially I think in the northwest and
in California some areas where all the
pot nerds quote-unquote which we are
aren't concerned with th - having high
levels of THC we want a full profile
cannabinoid and terpene profile we want
you know one of the things that I'm
really seeing especially here in
Washington is very high CBD strains
utilized with very low THC and those are
the connoisseur products and they're
just starting to catch on and we're
going to see more and more of that
because the high THC market is extremely
limited but the full cannabinoid profile
full terpene entourage effect that is a
massive market yeah and certainly one
that's going to keep on growing we're
going to go ahead and take our second
and last break you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is AC
Braddock CEO of Eden labs using
pesticides when growing cannabis has
been common for a long time nowadays
though we know better we know that most
pesticides formulated for food crops
have never been tested for use with
cannabis they've been tested to be eaten
in tiny doses they have not been tested
to be inhaled and especially not
concentrated
into a cannabis oil chemical residues
from pesticides are not healthy for
anyone but they are especially dangerous
for patients for commercial cannabis
growers this has become very impactful
cannabis enthusiasts and patients have
gotten educated enough that they avoid
growers who used pesticides not only
that but states across the country have
begun making pesticide testing mandatory
on all licensed cannabis crops the time
has come to find a better way to fight
garden pests than covering your cannabis
and chemicals and there is a better way
let some good bugs fight your bad bugs
beneficial insects and predatory mites
have come a long way since we were
buying ladybugs online and putting them
in the grow room and just hoping for the
best natural enemies biocontrol can help
you solve pest issues without using
chemicals natural enemies founder Shane
young learned best practices from
working in the ornamental plant industry
and has fine-tuned those strategies
specifically for large cannabis crops
Shane works with commercial cannabis
clients across the country to ensure
that they keep their crops safe and pest
free without the use of chemicals
natural enemies has proven solutions for
spider mites a feeds thrips Russert
mites broad mites shore flies white fly
and others - you can rely on natural
enemies for expertise and excellent
service for more information go to
shaping feiyr.com forward slash natural
enemies or simply click on their banner
in this week's newsletter welcome back
you are listening to shaping fire I'm
your host Shengo louse and our guest
this week is AC braddock CEO of Eden
labs so right before the break you were
talking about the difference between
super and subcritical and that some
folks were we're switching to
subcritical so that they could get more
flavor profile because you know the
future of cannabis is not just THC its
whole plant its flavor its taste and
it's healing and and a lot of folks are
not familiar with the difference between
super and subcritical all I really know
about it is that people wanted to try to
avoid
using subcritical simply because the run
took so much longer and it was less
number of runs they could do in a
24-hour period but when you kind of
break that out for us what the
difference between super and subcritical
extraction is yeah so the wonderful
thing about co2 unlike a lot of other
different kinds of solvents is that it's
very tunable where you can run the
material through it a wide array of
temperatures and pressures to get out
all kinds of different products where
it's primarily useful cannabis is to be
able to separate out the terpene profile
and that was a thing earlier that's a
low pressure low temperature profile
it's under 1,100 psi and a low
temperature so and that's also as I said
to know how the market is changing a bit
I mean any kind of quality product that
you make I don't care what it is takes
longer you know wines cheese's I mean
the list goes on any comments artisan
yes anything that's ours and that's what
we want this market to beat we want it
to be artists and we want it to be small
business we wanted to be a micro
business as opposed to a macro there's
certainly room for macro but the more
our small to medium sized businesses we
have in cannabis or anything is
beneficial
so the subcritical will pull lots of
terpenes but you also need to then go up
to supercritical to pull a lot of the
other cannabinoids and the THC because
th you can sometimes be hard to pull out
especially you know th VA which is
another product which is up coming up at
people or don't have a really clear
understanding about is having a product
with THC a in it so especially for
medical patients because you're going to
go with pain benefits without all the
psychoactive parts
in there so there's a wide range of
temperature and pressure to be able to
create a recipe that's unique to your
product and pulling out different
cannabinoid profiles at different places
in the extraction process which gives
you I P which is extremely important for
this industry especially when we start
start going back and forth between you
know pharmaceutical versus nutraceutical
or pharmaceutical versus you know
cottage market yeah this is how we're
going to be able to have some traction
so as as these markets get larger I
would think that the sales of Eden lab
extractors to particular locale in the
country or heck even the world is a is a
leading indicator of the next really
relevant Canada scene do you find that
to be the case and if so where do you
think are going to be the next hot spots
because that's where you're shipping
obviously California for sure division
is a huge market east coast there are
several states that look like they're
going to be you know Pennsylvania well
you know there were laws only only doing
cops concentrates which I don't
necessarily agree with I think that
there's a medical benefit for flour as
well but the technology going forward to
be able to separate out molecules to
pull out CB CVG for instance which is
one of my favorites because it's great
for pain and the Filmation but moving
all that forward so we're we have a we
have two distributorship now actually as
a company in israel and tapping into
some of those European markets like
Israel Australia they're several
different you know Germany the UK is
gearing up quickly I think Canada South
America it's uh you know it's kind of
disturbing to see because I feel like
Washington and the west coast should be
kind of leading this technology but
because of our federal regulations other
places in the world are gaining traction
which is fine I mean lots of clinical
trials are going on all over the world
it would just be nice to have to be here
it was it was so disappointing to live
in Washington and have us be you know
one of the First's and then because of
this you know dual-layer of our federal
laws and then the the confusion on
implementation at the state level I feel
like we're in Washington the the example
of how not to do it and and as soon as
the US government stopped international
pressure for cannabis it is amazing how
quickly it broke out everywhere as soon
as we stopped strong arming people to
not using cannabis medicine yep yeah it
was some of the things that Washington
have done is has been very very
disappointing and heart-wrenching for
many people and I know especially people
who were in medical previously and have
moved into the 502 market but it's
especially with how medical has been
handled here in the state which is
incredibly hypocritical yeah it's a
shame that you know the patients were
the first ones and the medical providers
we're the first ones that provide them
of course they're the ones who are left
holding the bag in our in the new system
here but heck we could do a whole show
just on Washington's failure so so let's
move right along so I know you and I are
both you know serious whole plant
advocates and and I don't know the
answer to this question and so I figure
best time is to now to ask you so so
what is lost during a co2 extraction and
I think that's from what I'm
understanding your answer sub is going
to provide more of the original plant so
what's what's what's in the plan that
you would get when you toke it or you
don't combust it that's not in the oil
that comes after it's derived by a co2
extraction
you know I can't say that I exactly know
the answer to that question obviously
different methodologies will leave
different things behind that's obvious
the difference between smoking and co2 I
don't know
personally I do know that sometimes when
I smoke I can become very achy depending
on what strain it is but that never
happens when I ingest so there's not
only what the difference in the
extraction method but also what happens
physiologically with how the plant works
in your body yeah that makes sense
what while I'm asking you things that
that you don't have ready answers to how
about this one um well you know when
I've spoken to medical doctors about
dabbing some think that we will
eventually find out that dabbers are
inhaling terpenes in a volume and in a
method that it can be toxic to humans
and obviously these studies have not
been done yet because we would know
about them but you know you are sure
around a lot of folks studying oils
thinking about oils developing the
technology so what are your personal
thoughts on the safety of dabbing well
yeah that has that is becoming quite a
concern and well another new trend that
we're hearing about is that a lot of vho
products there a lot of people who are
adding are now taking a Pho product and
taking terpenes from a co2 extraction
and putting that on the BHO product so
obviously you're going to have a pretty
significant terpene profile that they're
entertainers are light hydrocarbons so
you know it's been going back to a whole
plant philosophy if you've got a plant
and it never has more than you know
let's say 20% terpene profile and you're
mixing it together to create a 75%
terpene profile I I would say that they
there should be room for concern there
because it doesn't naturally occur that
way and probably that doesn't actually
occur like wait for a reason yeah that
makes sense you're you're like super
charging it and your body may have never
seen anything like it before know how to
deal with it yeah at some point it could
become poisonous or you know it just
it's just too much and and I think we
you know continually need to look at the
plant
as it is and what it offers I mean that
is why this industry exists so to
suddenly take a sharp turn has to be
fought should be thought through and
considered carefully yeah I think this
is a fun question I think that I need to
go find myself a really good a medical
doctor respiratory nerd get him on the
show and pick out one for you oh good
excellent I will ask you about that as
soon as we're done here
excellent so I want to finish this show
with a real serious well not real
serious but a really direct business
question because we've talked on this
show before about a trademark and
licensing and the importance of
companies to continually defend their
their brand marks and their trademarks
because if if they're not constantly
defending the use of their of their
product names and of their marks that
over time their trademark gets diluted
and and it becomes indefensible and and
you know I have seen a lot of different
extraction machines and and so many of
them look like your original machines so
my question for you is that you know I'm
assuming that you're being copied again
and again by other extraction companies
seeking to catch up with Eden's lead do
you find that you have to strongly
defend your design patents oh yeah of
course
but you know it's a little difficult to
with co2 because co2 was invented in
World War two and so it's not a new
process by any stretch but obviously
some of the different tweaks and
how we put a system together is
certainly pat herbal but yes there are
many in the last few years I would say
there's a dozen more extraction
companies who have come into the market
and to be able to hang on to your market
share while you're educating the public
on what the difference is and the
systems are because some of these
systems that come in
you know without naming names you know
one company that I know of there hundred
leader takes 64 hours to do an
extraction you know where ours would
take you 7 to 12 so it's really
detrimental to the operators and the
businesses who who get these systems who
don't understand the differences because
they're going to fail and they can't
they can't have that kind of overhead
and have that kind of length of time in
an extraction process but it goes back
to a whole extraction piece on every
level in this industry with as many
companies that are popping up doing a
building extraction technologies are you
to the point yet that you have have got
dedicated people on staff who whose job
it is to defend your patents and to look
for infringement or is it just your
engineers occasionally come across one
and then you hand it over to the lawyers
we probably primarily just let our legal
team deal with that you know I guess as
a business owner at some point you have
to make a decision and are you going to
spend a lot of your time looking at your
competitors and trying to compete or are
you going to focus on what you do best
and we did make that decision a few
years ago that we are going to do what
we've always done and that just do our D
and look at the science and continue to
make better extraction systems because
takes a tremendous amount of time energy
and just that they're constantly chasing
other people in a distraction from a
from an idealist point of view I
actually really love that answer because
you know I understand the importance of
defending design patents as you know the
importance of holding on to IP for
business but I'm also in the old school
idea of information yearns to be free
and and I also like you know rapid
prototyping and evolving so I find it
encouraging that that you are leading
Eden in a way that you're all like well
we'll defend when we have to but let's
just make the next thing and then we'll
just always be ahead of the crowd III I
appreciate that approach yeah you know
yeah it's like I don't I don't care it
it Eaton's the biggest company I just
want us to be the best company that's
what it's all comes down to because if
we're the best our clients will be
successful and they'll be able to then
become pillars of mission and in this
industry that will hopefully continue
the tipping point in the direction this
culture wants it to go and that's what
it's all about
well said well ACI no you have got an
exceptionally busy schedule I really
appreciate you peeling off an hour to
spend with us so that we can get caught
up thank you so much for your time Thank
You Shanga thanks for all you do as well
thank you ac Braddock is CEO of Eden
labs you can find out more at Eden labs
com
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shaping fire calm and on
Apple iTunes stitcher and Google Play if
you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you'd leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download your review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I will be
speaking you can check out Shango lows
calm as your company we want to reach
our national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot
shaving feiyr.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire I've been
your host Shango those
[Music]