[Music]
going into the California election three
weeks ago there was a powerful schism in
the cannabis community everyone agreed
that proposition 60 for releasing
cannabis prisoners from incarceration
was a necessary and overdue thing and
everyone also pretty much agreed that an
adult use law was necessary and over do
as well in California the schism was
whether or not you thought the design of
the cannabis market as spelled out in
proposition 64 was the right way to
legalized in california so now that the
proposition has passed the conversation
for the next two episodes of shaping
fire are going to focus on what comes
next in California in today's episode
we're going to talk with Amanda Ryman of
drug policy Alliance we're going to talk
about the new opportunities for
entrepreneurs looking to make a move in
the new adult use market we're also
going to be talking about the
forthcoming state rulemaking process and
lay out some timetables for
implementation then in the next episode
we'll present part two in part 2 i'll
talk with Hezekiah Allen of the
California growers association will talk
with him about the concerns of heritage
cannabis farmers of Northern
California's Emerald triangle and the
actions they will have to take to have a
voice in the creation of the state's new
adult use market will also have a
detailed discussion about market
consolidation in cannabis and how we
might preserve diversity in the cannabis
market and save the family farm this
week's recording does not sound quite as
clear as our usual episodes we ran into
some technical issues while recording
our guest the content is still very
engaging though so i encourage you to
turn your volume or trouble down just a
touch and enjoy the show my guest this
week is Amanda Ryman manager of
marijuana law and policy at drug policy
alliance in that role she develops every
aspect of DPAs marijuana reform work
where I'm enjoying DPA in 2012 after
working with the famous Berkeley
patients group dispensary as director of
research and patient services Ryman has
conducted numerous studies on medical
marijuana dispensaries patients and the
use of marijuana as treatment for
addiction regularly presenting her
research at the conferences of the
American Public Health Association
American Psychiatric Association
International cabin
research society and the harm reduction
coalition ryman served as the first
chairwoman of the medical cannabis
commission for the city of berkeley
currently serves on the canvas
regulatory commission for the city of
oakland and has consulted with various
cities states and nations on the
development of medical marijuana policy
Ryman is currently a lecturer in the
School of Social Welfare at the
University of California Berkeley where
she teaches drug and alcohol policy
substance abuse treatment and sexuality
and Social Work ryman earned her BA in
psychology from the University of
illinois-chicago and her master's degree
in social work from the Jane Addams
College of Social Work ryman moved to
oakland in 2002 to attend the university
of california berkeley where she earned
her PhD in social work in 2006 Ryman's
dissertation cannabis care was the first
study focusing on how medical marijuana
dispensaries operate as health care
service providers welcome to the show
Amanda thanks for having me I'm so glad
that you could make time with your busy
schedule are things calming down for you
a little bit more now that the now that
the election is over well yes and no of
course we are really excited that Prop
64 had victory here in California but
we're also looking to the horizon and
with questions about what the new
administration means for this new
industry amen everybody is kind of
scared about what might the next move
the of the president-elect maybe but
luckily we don't have to talk about that
one today we just need to tackle
California itself and you know
everybody's excited because now there's
a there's more clarity than there had
been before before you know medical
existed but it was you know parts of it
we're not quite as legal as some folks
wanted entrepreneur wise to get involved
but now with a clear green light from
the state folks are ready to jump in and
to bring you know their skills from
other industries so so we know that
California's going to be a multi-billion
dollar industry in and of itself as far
as the number of participants though do
you we have any idea of how many
cannabis companies will likely be formed
in California now Oh there'll be
thousands I mean we're not just talking
about companies that actually touch the
plant right so companies that
ro the plant that processed the plant
that distribute the plant but all the
ancillary services that go along with
the cannabis industry especially in the
tech sector and I think that given that
California has such a reputation of
being innovators when it comes to
technology that we're going to see a
huge cannabis tech sector in California
as well as the agricultural sector that
comes with actually producing the plant
and I think that's a really good point
to make because there are so many people
who see the opportunity in canvas and
they want to participate but it doesn't
mean that they have to go through the
highly regulatory structure of getting a
license or even dealing with the plant
there are so many support opportunities
when it comes to the licenses themselves
though let's talk about those and break
those out a little bit because
California has gotten more a higher more
variety of licenses than any other state
as legalized at this point what are the
different licenses well the licenses
were really outlined first under our
medical cannabis regulation and safety
act which was passed in 2015 by Governor
Brown as you mentioned even though we've
had medical cannabis in California for
20 years we've been lacking a state
level regulatory system meaning that
anyone that's operating in medical
cannabis currently in California is
doing so under a local license and this
is primarily just retailers we really
haven't seen the licensing of
cultivation manufacturing so our medical
cannabis regulation and Safety Act
outlined licenses for this purpose and
then prop 64 adopted that licensing
structure with a few key differences so
both the medical program and prop 64
outline licensing not just for different
activities but different levels of
production within those activities so I
think that the boat was go ahead I was
going to say so there's different types
we cover cultivation testing
manufacturing transportation retail but
within each license category there's
room for small growers vs big growers
delivery services versus
brick-and-mortar dispensaries so even
within
each type of license there's variability
based on how big you are and the exact
type of company you want to have so for
example volatile extractions veeram be a
butane and other combustibles is
regulated differently the non-volatile
extractions such as temperature or
agitation I think that will find that
California going head and blessing the
kind of model that they used for medical
with some you know with some changes and
making it adult use will have a lot more
success like in Colorado which used a
similar model of blessing what they
already have versus the the kind of mess
that they have in Washington where they
set aside medical and created something
entirely new from from scratch
reinventing it as they went I think that
with as big as the market is going to be
in California that's one big advantage
from day one that will be helpful to
entrepreneurs there oh I agree and I
think that you know honestly one of the
reasons why after twenty years the
legislature finally did pass something
in California for medical is because
they knew that adult use was on the
horizon and they understood because of
what happened in states like Washington
versus states like Colorado that it made
sense to set out a structure for medical
cannabis on and create that system
alongside the adult youth system or what
will happen would happen would be
similar to Washington which is to see
the medical system just kind of get
usurped into the adult youth system and
see patients not have the same kind of
access or the same kind of price
discount that they should have given
their patient status while we're talking
about medical there was a lot of concern
before the election that proposition 64
would would hearken the end of the
medical market and and you know there
were there were no provisions put in the
proposition to exclude it if anything
there were provisions to protect it but
based on what you know we saw in
Washington you know what do you think
the likelihood is that now that
commercial adult use cannabis is legal
that the commercial
lobbyists will will seek to squeeze out
medical because you know that's that's
now a computing market well I don't
think it's going to be a competing
market I think what's more likely to
happen in the coming legislative session
is a reconciliation of prop 64 and NCR
si they have the same agencies governing
the two programs there's no differences
in the types of products that adult
users can access versus medical users so
what I think we're likely to see at the
end of the day is a consolidated system
where patients get a financial break on
the cost of the medicine and those who
are 18 19 and 20 years old can access
cannabis with a doctor's recommendation
and that the price break for those
individuals is subsidized by the taxes
paid by adult users I think that that's
more likely going to be the model will
end up seeing given that the regulations
for medical and for adult use are so
similar well it sounds like the
integration of how they are going to be
regulated and since they're going to be
regulated by the same body will
definitely decrease you know conflict at
the regulatory side I just can't help
but think that the lobbyists in
commercial will will do everything that
they can to squeeze medical so that they
can start selling to those patients as
well and maybe with you know a different
tax rate but but to capture those folks
anyway because do you think that people
since they're selling the same things
won't people still tend to want to use
their medical cards and just to be able
to get the better price in the medical
market well I think it's primarily going
to be what I call a costco model where
if you're somebody that uses cannabis
frequently whether that be for whatever
reason it makes more sense for you to
get a medical card because you're going
to get a tax break every time you use it
versus somebody that uses cannabis maybe
every once in a while and doesn't really
make sense for them to go and get a
medical card and they'd rather just pay
the tax so I think that there'll be
options for people who based on you know
how frequently they use cannabis the
thing is is that even though
we haven't had state level regulations
for 20 years we absolutely have an
industry so keep achoo kiva bang I mean
all of these companies have been in
California dispensaries for years now
and so it's not as if there's a whole
new flood or room for a whole new flood
of commercial products in California at
the moment because we really do have
quite a variety of commercial cannabis
providers right now today in the state
of California so while I do think that
there will be some diversification
because there may be products that
people in the adult use market want more
often such as low dose we're seeing you
know adult users more interested in low
dose products where patients are looking
for higher dose products so we will see
some diversification but at the end of
the day patients will have access to the
same products in the same name brands
that they have right now you know the
point that California already has a
strong exists pre-existing market was
made oh I guess it was three shows ago
we had dr. Dominic Kaurava on the show
from casp and he made the point he says
you know everybody's talking about the
Green Rush and the new Green Rush in
California but really you know
California started a Green Rush in the
1970s and it's just never stopped that's
accurate that's absolutely accurate and
you know when I go and give talks to
younger folks today want to get in the
industry who are interested in it I say
you know you're not going to be a master
cultivator and you're probably not going
to have a dispensary you know these jobs
are taken and you know our job with
regulation is to allow people who have
already been working in this industry an
entree into a legal market it's not to
pave the way for all kinds of new
companies to come in and so you know we
want folks who are already operating to
be able to come into compliance and I
think that's where we need to focus on
first because we do have so many
operators already here in California I
think that's a really good point and
what I want to talk more about the
specifics of the opportunities for
potential new entrepreneurs let's go
ahead and take our first short break you
are listening to shaping fire
as a business owner you are incredibly
busy in reality you are responsible for
everything your company does you have so
many responsibilities every single day
that often you just don't have the time
to really dig into something as deeply
as you'd like you know there is more
that you could do to reach out to new
customers and to encourage loyalty and
the customers you already have but you
certainly don't have the time and you're
not ready to hire someone full time for
that role either for you i recommend
blunt branding blunt branding principles
Kirsten Nelson and Anthony Garcia are
focused on improving your bottom line
you know most marketing firms are
excited to make your logo packaging and
website very pretty but they leave
responsibility for improving your bottom
line up to you they don't want that kind
of responsibility but that is pretty
much the most important part of
marketing right Kirsten and Anthony will
help you engage new customers funnel
them to your point of sale and keep them
coming back to you and telling their
friends no doubt this is a paid
commercial spot but that does not mean
they bought my opinion I've worked with
blunt branding on three projects now for
various clients and every single time
they have done more than they have
promised and over delivered on results I
love how they generate new revenue and
focus on that as the goal instead of
just making me a pretty logo similarly
every friend I've referred them to has
come back to thank me and that just does
not happen every day so grab a pen and
paper because the website address is
coming if you want someone to implement
marketing programs that feed your bottom
line give blunt branding a call they
will share proven techniques to increase
your audience and generate sales while
using cutting-edge technology in the
background that make all of this easy
automatic and trackable go to shaping
fire calm forward slash blunt branding
to find out more you can also click the
link in our weekly newsletter blunt
branding marketing that makes you money
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host Shango louis
and our guest this week is Amanda Ryman
of drug policy Alliance so Amanda right
before the break you said something that
that stuck out for me you said that the
way that things are set up now it's
there's not really a lot of room being
created for new companies that really
the focus right now is going to be the
pre-existing market that exists in
California moving into the licensed
structure can you break that out for a
little bit for me more because you know
a lot of people who are listening the
show as are thinking about okay now that
adult use is legal let's take our skills
and move in to California cannabis and
and your suggestions seem to be that
just because the law has been passed
doesn't necessarily mean there's a ton
of room for new companies well I first
want to make the point that under prop
64 there is a California residency
requirement so you had to have been a
resident of California I believe back
from 2015 and that residency requirement
is until 2019 so if you're out there
somewhere else in the United States and
you live somewhere else you're thinking
I'm going to move to California and get
a license you are not because we wanted
to again ensure that those that have
already been living and working in the
industry in California have priority and
there's also priority to already
existing companies meaning dispensaries
manufacturers that have already been
existing but in this kind of gray
locally regulated area also have first
priority but that doesn't mean that
there's not room I think it's really
about where the need is going to be and
in California the need is not for people
to grow cannabis or sell cannabis or
even make cannabis products in
California the need is helping these
companies come into compliance so the
need is for software and for packaging
and for sustainable agriculture methods
and things that are going to help those
that are working in the industry make
the leap from the gray market to a very
heavily regulated system here in
California and I think the opportune
there are pretty much endless because
you're going to have a ton of businesses
that have been operating in a way that
is not satisfactory to California
regulatory standards and we're going to
have seed to sale and all of these
things that go along with regulation and
we're going to have to have companies
that can help those in existence comply
and be legal especially given the
scrutiny will likely face at the federal
level you know I think that's an
interesting aspect to point out there
that that just because licenses may not
be the way to go doesn't mean that our
listeners need to feel crestfallen that
they somehow can't get into the cannabis
industry because as you know I tell my
clients all the time you know if you can
come up with an idea that's not in that
this does not need a license you'll have
so much an easier time having your
business because your regulatory
structure will be so much less and that
when it comes to moving into any new
industry but especially the cannabis
industry that decreasing your risk as
much as possible is the name of the day
so so if folks are listening and they're
like oh wow are you telling me that all
the growers are already there it's like
yeah that might be the case but that
doesn't mean that it's there isn't tons
of opportunity for ancillary business
models absolutely anything that will
help those in the industry do things to
be more compliant make things more
seamless you know introducing processes
to streamlined to make it easier for
people and every level of production we
haven't had that you know we've had
people doing the jobs we've had really
no infrastructure in this industry and
that's what's going to be needed in
order to keep up and satisfy the
regulatory demand mm-hmm so let's talk
about a little bit about rulemaking
because you know the proposition only
goes so far itself and then you know
there are groups that then have to jump
in to regulate their part of the bigger
pie and and as we've not found in the
states that are already legalizing
sometimes that
that secondary wave of rulemaking can
get awfully messy so who is actually
going to be implementing proposition 64
in California and what does that look
like for folks who are who are trying to
understand the landscape so on both MCR
essay and prop 64 hand over the
regulatory structure and rulemaking to
the bureau of marijuana regulation which
is at the state level it's a state
agency and it includes representatives
from the department of food and AG the
department of public health the Board of
Equalization the Department of Consumer
Affairs and it also has an advisory
board made up of those folks plus
researchers from the public health field
people from the cannabis industry itself
patients right so people that have a
vested interest and prop 64 and mcrs a
really set out a blueprint for what
regulation will look like and now it's
up to this Bureau and with feedback from
folks in the state and in the industry
to fill in the blanks over the next year
not only is the bureau going to be doing
their due diligence and reaching out to
farmers and others to figure out the
best way to implement these practices
given what's already happening in
California but we're also going to have
to figure out how the licenses are going
to work you know how you apply for a
license I to kind of get all of those
wheels in motion that's something that
will also happen at the state level so
what's the time frame looking like you
know everybody was excited after you
know the election two weeks ago but now
now that that the the maybe even the
harder work has to happen if making this
all real you know how long are we
looking before the first licenses are
going to be handed out you know
obviously these are going to be
estimates but what are you what are you
thinking well the mandate from the
initiative is that January 2018 that the
state has to start issuing licenses by
January 2018 so it will take about a
year
that's what we saw in Colorado and
elsewhere now of course what we saw an
organ was that the state allowed
dispensaries to start serving adults
before the licenses officially came out
for the adult use only stores and so we
may see something similar here in
California given that we do have license
dispensaries across the state I wouldn't
necessarily be surprised if we saw the
bureau getting close to that date maybe
not quite ready to launch everything see
a compromise with well if you're a
licensed dispensary you can now start
serving people 21 and up who don't have
a doctor's recommendation given that the
products are the same now an organ that
wasn't the case of medical patients had
access to different products than adult
users namely medical patients had access
to things besides flowers here in
California both groups have access to
everything so it wouldn't be unheard of
for someone who's now serving patients
with a doctor's note to open up that
service to those 21 and up my gosh that
would be such a windfall for all those
retailers my goodness that they're
already up and going and then as part of
the transition they might be able to
sell to anyone who's over 21 wow what an
opportunity it would be but then again
you have to remember that here in
California it's no trick to get a
doctor's recommendation so you know for
the most part a lot of the medical
cannabis population here in California
resembles the adult use population so
different than in other states where you
have very restricted list of conditions
for which people can become patients the
adult use market is quite different than
the medical market it's not necessarily
the same here in California so over the
next year the new regulations are going
to come together how to apply for these
licenses will come together and also the
folks who don't want to see this happen
will be making their moves to you know
in other states we have seen challenges
with moratoria by local municipalities
does it look like there will be zoning
issues in California like that to where
you know this is passed at the state
level but individual cities are
we'll pass a moratorium that says no you
can't do cannabis business here oh
absolutely we've already seen that we
saw places passing that before prop 64
even passed you know it's no secret that
California is a bit divided on this
issue and you have localities in the Bay
Area and elsewhere that are very
proactive that are really wanting to
study this issue and bring cannabis to
their localities in a respectful way and
then you have places that just hate
cannabis and they're going to ban it
outright and they want nothing to do
with it the thing about prop 64 is that
it denies local revenue to localities
that ban commercial cannabis businesses
so while I think a lot of these bands
are reactionary what we'll see is that
counties and cities whose neighbors are
regulating commercially their residents
are just going to drive 10 miles down
the road by cannabis and then all the
tax revenue is going to go to their
neighboring city so you know we do see
even a patchwork of alcohol regulation
here in California with counties
regulating alcohol differently but the
decision to become a dry County or a dry
City definitely has economic
implications now the one thing that
localities cannot do is they cannot ban
personal cultivation for adults so the
ability for each household to cultivate
six plants indoors or outdoors in an
enclosed structure away from public view
that right went into effect November 9th
and localities are not allowed to ban
that activity what's the nature of the
difference in legality between a city
hosting of business versus a city
banning individual personal gross mean
what's the difference between those
legally that that one can be done away
with at the local level and the other
cannot well you're really giving a city
the right to regulate commercial
activity within its borders not personal
activity so if you legalize possession
of cannabis the cultivation of cannabis
as a legal personal activity the city
does not have the right to ban that
activity they can tell you where you can
do it which we already did in the
proposition we said you either have to
do it indoors or if you're trying to do
it outdoor
it has to be away from public view to
cut down on the risk of robbery so a
locality cannot make a decision to not
uphold the rights given to an individual
under the proposition what they can do
is make a decision about which
commercial enterprises they want
existing within their borders and that's
another vote for entrepreneurs to start
ancillary businesses as well because if
you're not holding a license you're just
an HR company or a marketing company or
a software company with cannabis clients
versus having a license and having to be
worrying about local moratoria that's
true i mean that's definitely true in
terms of getting a business license and
getting into the business but you know
just as a cautionary tale we have had
several reports recently of people who
are involved in ancillary businesses
related to the cannabis industry like
legal work that have been denied home
loans and other types of financial
benefits because of the nature of their
work so you know just because you're not
selling cannabis or growing cannabis
doesn't mean there's not a risk that
you're taking being involved with the
industry and that's one of the reasons
why it's so important for anybody that
wants to get involved in the industry to
understand the movement and to
understand the activism that comes with
being a part of this industry because if
you're not ready to be an activist I
would caution you against getting
involved in the cannabis industry you
know that's another good point that you
were making because you know a lot of
folks are like okay the laws passed the
activism has been done I can just come
on in and start my business now and it's
like oh no no you're playing it too
simple you know cannabis entrepreneurs
have got to be activists both to you
know protect their turf from moratoria
to make sure that it doesn't get rolled
back and and also to be active in the
state legislature so that as the
rulemaking evolves it evolves in ways
that don't exclude or challenge their
own business model oh absolutely and I
have to say you know I've been so
impressed with the Sun grown farmers and
their willingness to engage with the
bureau during this rulemaking period
because that's
one of the biggest mysteries is like
cannabis farming and what are the costs
associated with it what's the best way
to tax it and regulate it and without
the cannabis farmers themselves coming
forward and being open and honest about
what they're doing and how it works best
we would definitely not be as far as we
are in terms of acknowledging the
usefulness of sunburn cannabis so it
really takes people willing to come out
and to be honest about their thoughts
and feelings about the issue but you
have to be aware and educated on the
issue before you can be an effective
advocate we are going to take another
short break and be right back you are
listening to shaping fire businesses
everywhere are constantly striving to
reach out to people through advertising
we all know though that trying to reach
a cannabis audience with a quality
message is pretty difficult that's why
many people choose to advertise on the
shaping fire podcast advertising on this
show allows us time to talk about your
product service or brand in a way that
really lets people know what sets your
company apart from others bold people
who own companies know that getting in a
relationship with our customers is
essential that is what we offer we will
explain your service or product and what
sets it apart as desirable and help our
audience get in contact with you it's
pretty simple really advertising does
not have to be all whiz-bang smoke and
mirrors nowadays I find that people
prefer just to be spoken to calmly
accurately and with good intentions if
you want to make your own commercial
spot you can do that too because the
podcast is young but growing at an
exceptionally fast rate if you become an
advertiser on the shaping fire podcast
now you are going to pay a fraction of
the cost will be asking for in just a
few months and yet everyone listening
both now and to the back catalogue of
interviews later will hear about your
company again and again for years it's a
great deal for you pay a small amount
now because the show is new but take
advantage of the huge listening audience
we will have forever do yourself a solid
and contact us today for rates on
podcast and newsletter advertising email
hot spot at shaping fire calm to find
out more
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango Lohse
and our guest this week is Amanda Ryman
of drug policy alliance so Amanda right
before the break you were talking about
how important it was for Sun grown
cannabis growers to participate and get
their feedback and experience in into
the regulatory process and you know a
lot of people are concerned that with
the great increase of cannabis growing
across the country but specifically
right now in California that electricity
consumption is going to skyrocket
because the demand for cannabis is going
to get so increased so quickly now
California is one of those places that
cannabis just loves and a huge part of
your industry is is being grown outdoors
or in greenhouses by the sunshine and
not from generated electricity what are
some estimates that people have been
discussing in California about what
direction the industry might grow as far
as electricity usage versus doing it in
greenhouses and taking advantage of the
Sun well I mean cannabis traditionally
has been grown outdoors it's a plant you
know just like any other plant the
reason why we saw cannabis cultivation
come inside was because of prohibition
and the fact that people had to hide
what they were doing I think that
there's a culture around that still that
we're going to see dissipate with time
but there are some barriers to moving
full into Sun grown I mean you know if
cannabis was not as stigmatized and as
demonized as it is right now all
candidates would be grown outdoors the
problem is that we have states that
legalized but you're not allowed to ship
cannabis between states so Massachusetts
or Maine baking it grow cannabis outside
all year round they have very harsh
winters but they're not allowed to
import cannabis from california like
they would import wine or other
commodities and agricultural products
that grow better in other parts of the
state they don't say well hey we'll just
grow our strawberries and doors they say
no let's get strawberries from other
places
where it's still warm in december so i
think that the lack of interstate
commerce really put some states in a
bind in terms of their cultivation
because it's going to be very difficult
for them to do outdoor which means
they're going to have to rely more on
the energy consuming indoor model
eventually when we're able to ship
cannabis between states I see states
like California and others that are
naturally made for cannabis cultivation
outdoors to start to fill the need of
the other states that they don't have to
rely so heavily on indoor production I
think that is an assessment that a lot
of folks in legalizing states are
missing when they are setting up their
indoor grows not necessarily expecting
that they'll be eventually an interstate
market because that you know soon as you
allow interstate traffic it will totally
remake the face of the industry yet
again oh absolutely i mean when you
think about the wine industry and
especially the fact that we're going to
have Appalachians for cannabis folks in
other states are going to want to get
cannabis from certain Appalachians and
so we're really going to see a
difference once we start to do
interstate commerce and i really feel
that at that point the indoor market
will really start to dwindle of course
we also have a whole generation of
people coming off of prohibition when
nobody really knows what cannabis is
supposed to look like we all have our
ideas from High Times about what buds
are supposed to look like when I was
working at birthday patients group I
used to call that bag appeal because you
would have Sun grown cannabis that cost
two-thirds the price and tested at the
same level of THC yet people would still
gravitate towards these indoor buds
because they look tighter you know they
looked different and so people were
associating that with quality I think
that's going to change and people are
going to associate quality with things
like being pesticide-free being grown
outdoors being grown organically and
being grown in a specific appellation we
can already see that happening at a at a
brand strategy level with folks who are
using greenhouses not calling it outdoor
because outdoors kind of got that
reputation of you know i hit and grow
somewhere that's been done cheap and
fast vs. Sun grown or or similar words
which suggests that okay yeah it's
what's grown under the Sun but it
doesn't mean that it's not done without
exceptionally high quality growing
technique and you know you mentioned
pesticide and the other legalizing
states have had a lot of challenges with
that you know going to market with
flowers that we eventually found out
we're rife with pesticides does the new
regulatory structure in California is
that pre-baked in that pesticide testing
will take place or is or is the part of
the particulars for that still to be
evolved I know that's baked in so
testing for both potency and purity
right on so now we just need to get more
labs up and running but I guess I guess
also that's it that's an assumption that
doesn't necessarily play for California
because since you already have labs for
testing in the medical market a lot of
them will just be expanding more I guess
absolutely i mean most of the reputable
dispensaries have been testing their
product for several years now so and in
all of the big commercial edible and
other product companies have their
products tested as well so again you
know we've at one thing that's really
interesting is that when you look at the
evolution of the cannabis industry in
California and I started studying it
back in 2002 when you would walk into a
dispensary and you had to get a brownie
it was basically just wrapped in
cellophane someone made it at home and
brought it in and you had no idea how
strong it was or what the ingredients
were or if brownie a was going to be a
lot different than brownie be and then
you know looking just 10-15 years later
the sophistication in the packaging and
the testing nobody mandated that
companies did that that was all self
regulation by the industry in response
to patients wanting to know what was in
their products and I think that as much
flack as the cannabis industry gets for
just caring about money and it's the Big
Green Rush the folks that started this
industry they really cared about their
patients and about what they were giving
consumers and
they didn't we wouldn't see them taking
the steps to do packaging and labeling
and testing before the state absolutely
mandated it you know that's there's
reasons why the cannabis probiotic
growing movement homeland is the Emerald
triangle you know the growers there
early on for medical they were very they
had a lot of concern about what was
going into their patients because it was
a labor of love for them and it's great
that that that kind of a headspace is is
at the front of the new commercial
market as well you know I'm and up you
know there's one thing I want to ask you
because you know a lot of folks that are
listening they may be moving towards
cannabis and a lot of them may be new to
the industry they're going to bring
their their skill set from another
industry over into cannabis either with
a license or without and a lot of those
folks are going to run into a situation
like folks did in other states where
they want to hire a consultant to help
them bridge from their present industry
experience to cannabis and there have
been so many horror stories of
consultants from other states and folks
getting swindled I just like to you know
give you an opportunity to to share some
of your experience of what entrepreneurs
might want to think about when vetting
their consultants to to hope that they
can choose one that's going to really be
to their benefit well you're absolutely
right i mean everybody is a consult
everybody's been in the business forever
you know it's getting really crazy out
there so I mean be doing due diligence
is very important just because somebody
seems like they have their [__] together
does not mean they have their [__]
together because there's a lot of money
that you can pay people to make it look
like you have your [__] together yeah so
you want to really ask them you know how
long have you really been doing this
where did you get your start you know
what companies have you worked with if
you have somebody that's been doing this
for less than five years I would say
don't do it because the industry has
changed a lot by not having the
knowledge of where it was ten years ago
is really not going to play well for you
as a new business person and then all
so I would make sure that whoever you
hire has a working knowledge of
government how policies are made how
bills are passed in the legislature has
some kind of experience with lobbying or
knowledge about how policy works because
this is different than any other
industry and that the policies that are
passed will absolutely impact your
ability to succeed and if you don't have
someone that has a lot of knowledge
that's willing to go to Sacramento you
know a few times a week to really stay
on top of the hundreds of marijuana
bills that are going to come down the
pike this year you're not doing yourself
a service by hiring them so you know you
have to have somebody that's political
and you also have to have somebody that
has a working knowledge of where this
movement has come from you know recently
we had this marijuana business
conference in Las Vegas and a friend of
mine was there representing students for
sensible drug policy and she said that
three people asked her what the drug war
was Wow and I would say if that's you
and you're out there going what is the
drug war just stop just go turn around
walk away from the industry because
honestly you're doing us more harm than
good well that's a great segue to my
next question was going to be you know
cannabis entrepreneurs have got to be
active learners probably as much or more
than just about any other industry but
we also know that there's so much poor
information online when you're trying to
do your research now specifically for
California I'm going to ask you a
two-part question number one where can
clean information about what's going on
in the legislature and with the
regulatory groups be found online for
California and then second do you have
any other sources for information for
entrepreneurs that you would recommend
they go to instead of just blindly
googling whatever their question is yes
never blindly Google anything that's I
think is a good lesson for people so the
National cannabis Industry Association
which has a chapter in California the
California cannabis industry association
I would really recommend checking them
out you know
they have really stay on top of things
that are happening in Sacramento and at
the federal level they have lobbyists
they have a wide variety of companies
that they represent they have caucuses
that our industry specific so caucuses
for manufacturers versus distributors
versus cultivators and so you know I
think that's a really good way to stay
on top of things also the bureau of
marijuana regulation their website at
the state level will have updates on
bills that have been introduced and they
also have been doing these town halls
across the state for different sectors
of the industry where they want to hear
feedback from people that want to get
involved in kind of what their concerns
are so I would definitely recommend
doing those things and then there are
some great incubators and accelerators
out there one in particular is canopy so
canopy started out in boulder and they
just opened offices in Berkeley and also
down in San Diego and they are an
accelerator specifically for companies
that do not touch the plant so the
companies that we're talking about the
ancillary services the software the
streamlining they're the ones that would
support those kinds of businesses so if
you're in California you know I would
check them out because they have classes
and they have opportunities for people
to join their programs to help grow
their businesses fantastic fantastic and
you know Amanda before we say goodbye
here there's one thing I wanted to hit
on that's actually happening there in
your locale there in Oakland that I
think is interesting to point out you
know I've read a couple articles about
the the ideas of reparations for at-risk
minority communities that have been
unbalanced Lee a hit with the drug war
and and I believe it's the City of
Oakland has actually is giving deference
to licenses to folks that have are from
these minority groups i'm obviously not
explaining it very well but that's what
I'd like you to do could you explain
that policy sure so here in California
we have a law at the state level against
affirmative action meaning that we're
not
allowed to do set asides for women and
minority-owned businesses so some
localities like Oakland have trying to
figure out what is a proxy for that so
that we can make sure that those that
have been most impacted by the drug war
have as many if not more opportunities
to get involved in this new regulated
industry than others do so here in
Oakland the idea was put forth to set
aside half of the licenses for cannabis
businesses for people that have been
negatively impacted by the drug war
either because they live in a part of
the city that is heavily policed for
drugs or they themselves have been
incarcerated in Oakland for marijuana
related offense within the past I think
ten years or five years so that was the
original plan it's been a bit
controversial not because of its
intention so there are no people that
think this is a bad idea i mean people
agree that and recognize that there have
been communities that have been more
impacted by marijuana prohibition and
others however there's been a bit of a
political fight over who exactly should
be included in this equity program and
one of the city council members has
really derailed the process with really
quite crazy demands such as current
marijuana businesses have to give
twenty-five percent of their revenue
including retro actively to the city
just things that are really making it
difficult to move forward with this plan
so right now we're looking at
alternatives including you know opening
up the number of police beats that
people can qualify for the plan making
it so it's not just a marijuana
incarceration in Oakland but anywhere in
California and so right now we're going
back and forth with the city about what
exactly this plan will look like
unfortunately it's putting Oakland
behind our other neighboring cities in
terms of their licensing and regulations
around cannabis and this is concerning
because Oakland has always been kind of
on the forefront of cannabis regulation
and I think that for um they've kind of
been sitting on their laurels like oh
well
one's always out in front so we can take
as much time as we want because no one
else is going to do this licensing but
they're wrong and surrounding cities
have started licensing what Oakland
wants to do and so we're seeing
businesses unfortunately start to leave
the city of oakland to seek licenses and
other localities so we definitely
support the idea of helping people that
have been most impacted get into the
industry but we have to do it in a way
that makes sense and in a way that will
maintain oakland as a competitive city
in the cannabis industry for decades to
come wow that's a really interesting
situation talk about competing goods I
mean you not only are you trying to help
these minority communities that have
been impacted at the same time at a city
level you need to be able to protect
Oakland as a business entity and make
sure that these companies decide to set
up shop there well well we'll be very
interested to check back in with you on
that down the line as the regulatory
structure around all of this evolves so
I think that's we're going to stop for
today thanks so much for being on the
show today Amanda as my pleasure thanks
for having me you can find out more
about Amanda Ryman on the drug policy
Alliance I at drug policy org you can
find more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast and subscribe to the show at
shaping fire calm and on Apple iTunes
stitcher and Google Play if you enjoyed
the show we'd really appreciate it if
you'd leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too on the shaping
fire website you can also subscribe to
the weekly newsletter for insights into
the latest cannabis news and product
reviews on the shaping fire website you
will also find transcripts of today's
podcast as well for information on me
and where i'll be speaking you can check
out Shango lowes.com does your company
want to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hot spot at
shaping fire calm to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire I've been
your host Shango lowes
[Music]
you