[Music]
a couple times a month i get emails from
listeners in prohibition states they
always express frustration and learning
of all the cannabis opportunities in
other states while their own state
continues to live in the 1980s
my heart always goes out to these folks
i'm talking about you friends in idaho
utah south dakota nebraska alabama and
indiana where i went to college and
slanged
i also feel for y'all who live in states
pretending to modernize and yet having
cbd only cannabis laws thc maximums or
simply broken systems that don't feel
like they will ever be repaired hell
that even includes my own state of
washington where we don't even have
pesticide testing on licensed products
or homegrown yet somehow
u.s cannabis legalization is a wreck it
is mostly being run by politicians who
don't know cannabis or cannabis medicine
and are more focused on making donors
happy than providing informed leadership
between intransigent boomer politicians
and aggressive business-focused
lobbyists american cannabis is proudly
evolving the worst of all possible
situations
now this all sucks but understanding the
dynamics of what is going on is a major
key to us getting it all sorted out
while it is most common for we cannabis
folks to have a token mind our own
business there are a handful of cannabis
policy researchers out there who are
keeping score
looking at history to see what has
worked and failed in the past and are
coming up with novel ideas that help us
understand what the hell is going on and
why
these are the individuals who are needed
to lead us back to sanity
if you want to learn about cannabis
health cultivation and technique
efficiently and with good cheer i
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode also
we're giving away very cool prices to
folks who are signed up to receive the
newsletter this month we are giving away
the entire vashon kush series from
farmer fly selections 10 lucky winners
will receive one randomized pack of
these 10 new vashon kush crosses to
learn more about what the crosses are in
the drop check out at farmer underscore
fly on instagram there's nothing else
you need to do to win except receive the
newsletter so go to shapingfire.com to
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and i
am your host shango los
my guest today is dr dominic corba phd
dominic corva is founder and executive
director of the center for the study of
cannabis and social policy based in
seattle washington he is a sought-after
speaker on canvas policy and travels the
world to consult for government and
academic bodies on effective cannabis
policy
he is also co-director of the humboldt
institute of interdisciplinary marijuana
research at humboldt state university a
affiliate professor of sociology at
humboldt state university and the
cannabis policy specialist for the
california center for rural policy
he received his phd in geography from
the university of washington
dominick is also one of my most valued
friends i met dominic as i was making my
transition from the black market to
community organizing medical cannabis
cultivators back in 2013.
his mentorship connections and support
have been invaluable to my career the
forming of the vimeo organization here
on fashion island and my eventual
creation of shaping fire
it is likely true that shaping fire
would not exist today if dominic had not
encouraged me to pursue helping cannabis
patients and organized cannabis
education events all those years ago
finally dominic corva holds a special
place in the scene here in washington
state as is true in most states the
canvas seen here is pretty small and we
know each other and many of us came from
the underground dominic is someone
everyone embraces because he gets it his
depth on cannabis policy is immense
dominic understands the historical basis
for everything we see happening
nationally today and he way waves aside
the bro science that constitutes policy
discussion in most circles
dominic is a cannabis policy oracle and
he is a big-hearted lovable academic who
is embraced by everyone i know
today we are going to discuss the impact
of state licensing on long-term cannabis
farmers in california the awkwardness of
prohibition and licensed sales existing
at the same time
cannabis prohibition as a public health
issue
the profitable injustice of non-violent
cannabis prisoners
the latest on electrical usage by
industrial agricultural cannabis farms
and the rise of the citizen scientist
welcome back to shaping fire dominic
thank you shanko it's a pleasure to be
here i think this is my third time and
it's it's always great to be on your
show absolutely and actually you were
the when when i moved from the
gantrepreneur.com
podcast over here to shaping fire on my
own you were my very first guest of the
new show so
thanks for being back and also
congratulations on your new collection
of heavy-duty academic research entitled
the routledge handbook of
post-prohibition cannabis research
wow um what a colle amazing collection
of of research here
and you and your writing partner joshua
mizell edited quite a powerful tome
interpreting the the present with a firm
understanding of the past and how he got
here
the the 30 chapters provide a
substantial look into the most well
researched perspectives into these you
know rather complex cannabis topics
there's a lot written about cannabis
nowadays it's you know such a popular
topic in mainstream media but we know
they get a lot wrong all the time and it
frustrates us when we read this stuff
right also there are small cannabis
media companies inside of canvas that
aren't really mainstream who are just
slightly better but they still get
details and perspectives wrong all the
time
and then there is simply people with no
background fighting on the internet
the variety of research in this new book
is a different variety of any of those
three
it's vigorously researched and these are
top shelf
academics
looking at these cannabis topics and i
want people to understand why why this
is a different approach than most of the
stuff that they read out there so will
you start us out by explaining how a
collection of academic papers like this
is unlike the other examples i gave
yeah sure shango
so
there's really
two things that i define as you know
part of post-prohibition cannabis
research as opposed to just cannabis
research
post-prohibition first let's remember is
is a term that i use to refer to
cannabis with
not after prohibition cannabis
legalization with not after prohibition
and
the the concern as a social scientist
and as a geographer
was to collect
uh you know
to collect across five
meta categories
examples of research that did two things
one of two things and sometimes both of
two things
one of those i think people are more
familiar with which is you know now that
cannabis is legal
we can actually research you know
positive things about it
and the defining
prohibition research agenda was that
really you could only research things or
get funding
for research
uh to look at how you know cannabis was
bad right yeah and so that's that's the
kind of the first level and that's
that's a real accessible one i think you
know 80 wilson poe's opioid substitution
chapter is a really good example of that
but the other the other part of it is
that
you know
obviously we still have prohibition with
us we talk about cannabis legalization
often in a vacuum as though it's just
operating
and creating these just sort of legal
uh landscapes
when in fact those landscapes are
totally entangled with landscapes of
prohibition
and you know i'll just give you a couple
of examples the the most obvious one i
think readers will
get this right away is federal
prohibition still here and that means a
lot of things about what kind of
you know legal landscapes we can
construct they're
they're not
they're not for example uh you know
cannabis can't be agriculture in
california it's an agricultural product
and that means a million different
things for land use
uh it means a million different things
for other kinds of regulations and it
means a lot for about local control
right
uh local control being
you know sub-state jurisdictions get to
really do whatever they want
uh and that would be another aspect of
you know prohibition that continues
actually
because
as we we experienced in washington and
colorado a little bit but uh certainly
in california it's real obvious
that uh you know about two-thirds of the
jurisdictions in california and that is
56 counties and something like 450
cities
don't allow
uh you know cannabis businesses to
operate
which means we have a landscape it is a
patchwork quilt right of of
prohibitions
and uh and
legal
businesses that are operating
uh
and even in the jurisdictions where
legal jurisdictions are operating um
legal businesses are operating we
continue to of course have prohibition
on some things
so washington state most famously
obviously does not allow homegrow it is
illegal it is prohibited
so
in washington state therefore you know
legalization with prohibition means yeah
we've got legal cannabis but you can't
grow it at home without a license
and you can't get a license to grow at
home so
so
really the broad concept of you know how
legalization is entangled with
prohibition
it's really important to kind of start
with that uh for a lot of research
because
then the research agenda is
how do we disentangle
prohibition from legalization it's not
just how do we get legalization
it's that even though we're getting
legalization
we also still need to work to
disentangle prohibition from it and get
rid of it
and so
some of our authors are are really sharp
about this and focused on it
um
and i think that uh
you know sunil's chapter in public
health is a very interesting example of
a challenge to public health as an
institution as an
you know academic
meta institution
where they're still
still have a lot of those prohibition
assumptions that are attached to what
they do uh
and sunil talks about really like they
don't recognize the right to spiritual
health as part of what's on their agenda
so they they can't support research
that is is it about that kind of
positive
the last thing i want to say is that uh
there's kind of a third degree as well
uh and
it's a contextual one which is to say
that legalizations politics are
connected with and entangled with other
kinds of politics
and by that i mean
legalization
may in especially you know urban areas
be entangled with
what might be described as you know
especially public safety oriented
kind of liberal uh politics
that gets in the way of the
implementation of legalization you can
think about what about the kids as kind
of that research question that like
is kind of a liberal prohibition
question because it doesn't ask whose
kids right yeah um
uh and then also you know
there's a very interesting entanglement
with
maybe what are usually thought about as
libertarian and right-wing thoughts
about the free market right
um
and whether we should be you know
uh deregulating especially small
businesses let's say um which is not
traditionally something that is on
a left or liberal agenda so all of these
things have an effect on what kind of
legalization we get and where
uh and it's important to think about
those entanglements
so
we we're
promoting research agendas that almost
nobody else really
are thinking about the entanglements of
prohibition the entanglements
with other kinds of politics
um
and we do this it's a pretty big broad
set of observations
by
organizing it in
five meta issues right uh so governance
public health ecology and the
environment
markets and society and culture and
social change
and these are kind of interdisciplinary
clusters so when you say academic
academic means a lot of different things
um
academia is divided into a lot of silos
that we we we call disciplines usually
and so
the disciplines that really haven't
gotten as much run i think with with
either funding or recognition are the
social science disciplines
which have a long history of critical
analyses of prohibition
which is super important right so we
really got to draw on that right like
if we want a legal landscape that undoes
the harms of prohibition
then we need to draw on observations
insights and research
about prohibitions harms and those are
found pretty exclusively in the social
sciences
and so
we have a really broad array of folks
from different disciplines or from
interdisciplinary research clusters
uh
it can get a little complicated but
broadly speaking i think everyone kind
of understands okay governance is like
you know the law democracy
in you know institutions
you know uh public health includes
biomedical research uh as well as
uh
you know citizen science even um
um
the ecology environment isn't just about
you know
the impacts of outdoor cultivation on
you know water supplies it's about
energy right and energy use
um
markets in society
include a discussion of like
what's so difficult like
why is it so difficult for people to
actually make money as small businesses
it's an important question to ask
um
and so forth so uh culture and social
change also deals with you know stigma
ongoing
stigma which i haven't talked about and
is one of those slippery
slippery concepts
because you can't quantify stigma you
can quantify maybe the effects of stigma
but you need really qualitative research
methods
to
dig into
you know how is stigma changing where's
it at um
who is continuing to be harmed by
stigmas of prohibition even in legal
landscapes and i would point out that
often it's medical patients
as as new heart and dolphin do in their
chapter
so before we get into some of those
parts you know specific topics um just
for folks who are interested in how the
compilation came together
you know with a with an ever
increasingly pool of talented academics
studying and writing about modern canvas
policy how did you go about choosing
your authors um you know you've put
together you know
like a literal dream team it's an
incredible cast of folks who are writing
did you choose the topics first and then
find the authors or did you choose an
author first and then invite them or a
topic or maybe something else entirely
well it was an iterative process shango
uh and so
do you want me to walk you through like
the whole thing or
just just you know give us a just give
us a thumbnail because um
because uh
i'm i'm looking for like a
um any
any like agenda that might be like under
underneath the people that you chose
and and then particularly
you know um
how one pulls together such an
incredible group but you know you don't
have to go deep into it because we want
to move on to the topic swiftly right
sure sure well
basically once we had figured out the
structure
that we wanted
um
josh and i
both reached out to you know
academics in our network that was that
was one of the first things that we did
and of course we're not new to the scene
uh you know we have a history of
publishing and
working with and and uh following the
research of
folks uh you know as far away as you
know uruguay and morocco and the uk
um and so really it came from our
networks is the simplest answer to that
uh these were people who many of them
were you know
uh friends of ours already certainly um
and already kind of tuned in to what we
wanted to do
some were um like craig reinerman right
who who starts off the book was was
josh's uh dissertation advisor uh
at at um uc santa cruz
um
and craig is illuminary uh
wendy chapkis is someone that i followed
for a really long time and
i've taught her book and gotten to know
her basically by reaching out to her for
example and she's another superstar
in the public health section
and so
there weren't a whole lot of strangers
really
i'd say that
there were a number of people we reached
out to and
they
said no right uh we there were a number
of people we reached out to and they
said okay let's try it and and when
what they wanted to write kind of came
back
didn't fit what we wanted to do for the
book we kind of like
we either worked with them to come to an
understanding or let them
keep going so some of these were kind of
famous people
uh and i don't wanna bag on them so uh
and then then there was uh you know some
other folks that just kind of
let's say carl hart was very busy uh he
agreed to write a chapter and then there
were
just there was just a lot of a lot of
silence and kind of dropped the ball it
looked like he was relying on his
graduate students and so we just kind of
let that go yeah since his book came out
i can imagine the demand sign of his
time on his time have skyrocketed
absolutely and i really like this idea
that's coming you know clear that you
know you and josh mazel are area experts
you have both been doing this uh
teaching this at university level for
you know
like decades on your part i don't know
how old josh is but but you guys are
very much
area experts and discipline experts and
the two of you just worked together and
curated from all of the people they have
access to and and you chose the best of
the best who were you know also
interested so um so thank you for that
you know your your in your introduction
um co-written with josh um you say that
this book is intended to encourage
critical reason critical research
agendas that address the continuity of
prohibition in legal cannabis frameworks
as they remain entangled with the
continuum of global drug production
right very similar to what you said
during during our introduction today but
there's so much to unpack there right
but what piques my interest in that
heavy duty sentence is that no one
country's relaxation of cannabis laws
happens in isolation
countries are forever interdependent
even if they think
they're doing their own thing you and i
talked about that during episode one of
shaping fire when we talked about policy
transfer right
and this is especially true in regards
to the drug trade so let's start out
please talk to us a bit about how we are
seeing the global global dynamic of
cannabis production distribution and
prohibition shift around as countries
begin to embrace cannabis
yeah so i think that sense actually
ended with global drug prohibition but
production is is part of it so uh you
know
i think for example
you can look at uh you know the the
chapter on morocco by kenza of sahih
where basically they've been cultivating
cannabis
for thousands of years you know in that
area
and
the market for it
certainly has been you know they've
produced hash for example
for europeans for a long time
but it's only been in the last you know
maybe 20 years where basically um
genetics that were bred
you know generally by europeans and
and us americans uh
were taken to the moroccan fields right
which actually starts screwing with
their genetics and and at a very basic
level of course
what they had were land races that were
adapted their environment right and so
they were you know
resistant to whatever they needed to
resist there and
now with new you know genetics coming in
sometimes bred under conditions of
quasi-legality
um
uh sometimes not
but
generally speaking being brought in
because they want to feed the market on
the other end with something that that
that they've they've found
uh that market will prefer whether
that's you know europe or somewhere else
they bring in the genetics and it really
screws with
uh the basic agroecology
of you know moroccan cannabis
so
that's that's one example um
you can also
you can also think about
the opening up of of cannabis trade
internationally which hasn't happened to
the degree that i think some people
think
as of course being to affect
the livelihoods of folks who've been
producing cannabis in in other areas
um you know right now legally speaking
obviously uh colombia has done some
exporting right i think uruguay has and
i think both of those have been through
tilray
um
but
that's a shift towards kind of the the
the globalization that we've been
familiar with
you know
uh
around other commodities
you know for 30 40 years right the
supply chains that are
uh rely on cheap labor to produce a
low-cost product and get it to a market
that has money that will pay more money
for it
uh and so
that's sort of a mundane you know
problem with globalization
is that you know
labor gets screwed for example
uh in in the first world um
the the so-called first world
uh
but it's also kind of kind of funny
because
the drug war
did something during the age of
globalization which is kind of crazy
which is it was
anti-globalization we got domesticated
u.s markets
right uh we
the production that we used to import
from
mexico thailand colombia and elsewhere
uh has been displaced significantly and
you know starting about 20 years ago
pretty close to half of what what we
consume in this country
started being pretty much grown here
um and so
uh
there's a lot of kind of
counter-intuitive
you know explanations for what are what
what's going on and some of those
involve
applying critiques of globalization
to
critiques of globalizing weed right
um
and and some of them are
well then where does like you know
global prohibition come into it
and then you're then you're off down a
rabbit hole so um
obviously in countries that continue to
prohibit cannabis
it is much much harder for them
to
attempt to continue to do so
uh there's just a lot of product being
being moved around the world and in
different ways you have in peru
you know uh cannabis being grown
and processed into bho for example
um which has a higher you know price
per uh per weight than than uh cocaine
uh you know in lima
and so you're getting cultivation
practices shifting
from just coca out
out in the amazon area to coca and
cannabis and then uh you know
processing into the refined product
that's smaller and easier to smuggle
um and you know where does that go well
you know it goes to lima
uh
it probably isn't coming to the united
states um because we've had our
extraction game you know uh explosion
here already and there's a vast
oversupply of
you know for example bho in washington
um
so
those are just a few examples of what i
mean by that
i would think that this the the
patchwork
that you described that we're all aware
of in california really plays out the
same if you look at the global
uh presence as well and it must really
cause a whole bunch of odd imbalances
and contrasts
when you when when you know
countries as a pool
are both
holding on to traditional prohibition
that was pushed by the west
plus
now everybody wanting to
um you know increase
health with medical
and then also now this entrepreneurial
approach where people are trying to
commoditize cannabis and all three of
these are happening at the same time
and you know like um you know as you
know
these market inefficiencies must just be
um dazzling as a social researcher like
yourself
well yeah you know like uh i think
you're exactly right the the patchwork
quilt exists at the local level it
exists at the state level and by local i
mean city and county so there's
patchwork quilt upon patchwork quilt
upon patchwork quilt upon patchwork
quilt
uh you know
regionally north america globally
uh and so what i'd say that
it's almost like a logarithmically more
complex you know landscape
that regulators are faced with because
they're the ones who actually worry
about it uh quite a lot
and it's you know
it provides i think as you know
um
opportunities for
a lot of entrepreneurial
uh
activities that are different from and
scaled differently uh than we used to
have
um i think that uh
when you throw in the medical
um regimes as well and and medical of
course is
uh
in there in that gray area
of the entanglement between prohibition
legalization
you know i mean
you have the the the full-throated
embrace of
cbd for example like uh globally uh very
very quickly
um and global supply chains for it and
and actually
in countries that are also pretty into
prohibition they're absolutely driving
cbd you know production and so forth
uh like china
let's remember that even though the us
has you know probably originated and
pushed this that there are definitely
other
significant
you know geopolitical entities that have
that are hanging onto prohibition uh and
they will probably hang on longer than
the u.s will you look at russia look at
look at the philippines uh yeah which is
an absolute
war crime situation going on there
so um
yeah it's uh it's pretty crazy and then
that to me says like there is so much
opportunity for research and research
that actually shows how complex and
difficult this is
when you're stacking regulations on top
of regulations
that you know
may seem to work locally usually they
don't but like when you zoom out a
little bit and
you have your oklahoma you know uh
situation uh you know
uh headed in a different direction than
your
your california and washington oregon
situations
uh
so
it's it's pretty crazy of course what
does that mean it means that you know
oklahoma is a place where
a lot of people went to
uh you know become entrepreneurs that
then they can
they're not just selling it locally
right the same as same as the west coast
uh you know
uh even today but uh for washington
oregon or for washington maybe it was
you know eight years ago oregon still
exports but like oklahoma
has become an export
like a thc exporting state you know
uh which is crazy
so so your work and what we've been
talking about so far you've been talking
about teasing apart prohibition and
legalization because somehow they're
both existing at the same time
and and and i'd like to look at an
example from northern california where
cannabis cultivators went from working
in the medical gray and export markets
during prohibition
to a new kind of prohibition that's
actually being pushed by licensed
cannabis companies trying to protect
their markets from unlicensed producers
to the point that
you know folks are
you know licensed producers are suing
the state for not stomping out
the their competitors in the unlicensed
market either way growing cannabis and
minding your own business is still
experienced as prohibition as law
enforcement showing up with you know
wood chippers and to destroy family
crops
um is it even fair to call what we are
seeing today as legalization or are we
just using that word because it's the
closest thing that we've got
well i think you have to define the term
and define how you're using it and we
define it very very clearly in the
introduction
uh legalization is
the uh
the licensing and regulation of a supply
chain from cedar clone to consumer
basically um and
if you have that you've got a form of
legalization so it's it's do you have a
carved out space
uh whether or not you still prohibit it
you know in other ways where
cannabis can
travel entirely under circumstances that
are that are regulated and supposedly
tracked
so uh
so we we got this by the way from
harry levine in particular who who
defined it uh years ago with respect to
amsterdam back in 2004
uh which amsterdam of course didn't
actually have legalization either
it was
the supply side of it wasn't regulated
and the consumption side of it was
uh but levine had had begun to think
about well what is legalization at that
point and
it's it's to me you know it is is the
carving out of these supply chains that
are governed or at least supposed to be
governed
from the beginning to the end use
uh and so
that can happen that's actually
let's let's blow our readers minds
that's been happening since the 1970s in
the united states
right uh with the university of
mississippi and the um
investigative new drug program right so
there was a legal supply chain of
federally legal cannabis that went from
the university of mississippi
to medical patients like lv musica right
robert randall
um
and it was entirely legal so we've had
legalization united states since the
1970s let's let's be real clear about
that
um at the federal level and of course
that's still uh there's still a couple
patients still in that
so
once you think about that then you don't
think well legalization is not actually
a brand new thing
right it's it's existed before but we
didn't recognize it
because prohibition was sort of an
overwhelming fact total fact total
social fact
uh and so
uh
i'd like to make sure that we're
defining legalization i think that's an
issue in the media and with a lot of
other like policy scholars
they just assume legalization is
its own thing uh
and
uh it leads them to i think um
research agendas that are in that are
that often just kind of reproduce common
sense uh to be honest instead of instead
of actually anything new well with with
this very specific definition of
legalization it actually is a very small
niche and the word legalization does not
say very much about the overall
landscape it really only speaks to a
very small portion of the you know
cannabis legalization how it's used
casually right
absolutely and let me let me just jump
in real quick like that's absolutely the
case and and one of the one of the ways
this happens over and over and over
again are those maps of the united
states that are color coded for
legal state and you know
uh
cbd only and and well
usually there's there's like a legal
medical and and neither right right and
and it looks like okay
oh california and all these these states
are entirely green
it's just legal and so
as but actually if you broke that up by
jurisdictions california would look a
lot more like a patchwork quilt
and so people just kind of assume oh
there's freedom there we've got the
liberty we won
and
actually it's just a big mess
so what are your thoughts on the rural
militarization of law enforcement in the
emerald triangle right like you know you
and i have talked before both on this
show and personally about just the the
general militarization of law
enforcement everywhere
but you know almost daily we're seeing
clips on social media of heavily armed
officers and military transports just
tearing through the unpaved roads of
humboldt how can this not be seen as
simply an extension of the campaign
against marijuana planting camp of the
90s and early 2000s it's like it's like
yeah
legalization exists meaning that there's
this there's this path for the the
growing and distribution of taxed
licensed cannabis but at the same time
you know people
who you know heritage growers who are in
california their situation has not
changed all that much
so
let me address that because it's
actually a really great question for for
saying uh something for for a while here
and if you'll indulge me please um
one of that is that reminds me of your
earlier comments about uh you know legal
businesses you know suing the state for
not enforcing um
against unregulated ones and and let me
say there's a geography to that and is
in particular in southern california
uh and what they usually mean are
actually you know
storefronts retail storefronts
uh and so
often really the case is in southern
california the places that are
relatively high density with
legal retail um
what they are trying to get people to do
is you know enforce against
uh you know unlicensed storefronts that
that pop up
um
and you know
that is a can of worms itself right
because those unlicensed storefronts are
generally speaking
demographically underrepresented
populations in the legal landscape
because it's white rich people that have
been able to get these other types of
licenses
now
eradication is the is the rural version
of urban enforcement let's say that
right
um i think what people don't
necessarily understand
is that
in humboldt and elsewhere
over the course of the 1980s and 1990s
local law enforcement
backed off
from being
you know i think uh gung-ho participants
in in camp although they continue to do
that
there was an informal
regulation
pattern going on which is to say that
law enforcement
would stay out of certain neighborhoods
maybe they would have uh you know maybe
they they would you know
um
they would uh you know
there was a size and this and a scope of
operations that were
more or less just kind of left alone
right
because they weren't hurting anybody and
you're talking about rural law
enforcement and rural law enforcement is
is not really out there to bug the
sparsely populated uh folks you don't
have neighbors complaining because it
was all in remote areas
they get left alone right
um
meanwhile of course you know camp would
come around by the season and uh
generally speaking
as time went on with camp they started
focusing more and more on on larger
scale operations
uh that
sometimes were environmentally
destructive
and over time this this was definitely
evident you know when when i first got
the humble in 2009
over time a lot of those old timers and
small cannabis growers that since 96 had
been you know
not that afraid but especially like
after 2001 like not too worried about
their small gardens
were absolutely up in arms about what
they called the greed growers
and large-scale environmentally
destructive cultivation
at the same time
whenever policing that was maybe
intended for that would catch up a
heritage farmer in its net
which you know is almost inevitable
really
um
that you know the collateral damage of
uh you know focusing on larger scale
operations
uh you know that would be pretty awful
and and the old-timers would be you know
totally against that but
they also were kind of interested in you
know like
they didn't want the large-scale
environmentally impactful cultivation in
their backyards and it wasn't just
because it was environmentally impactful
it was also driving down the price of
their cannabis
uh because they were flooding the market
right so um
so the the enforcement situation today
is absolutely the continuation of camp
but
it's important to remember that that
camp changed over time
uh and often in directions that i think
you know heritage farmers had no problem
with and in fact cheered on and i think
some of that is happening today
but
really the smaller farmers are being hit
by code enforcement
more than by eradication like uh their
issues are now with
civil code enforcement
that do you mean like do you mean like
the satellites being used to see
greenhouses that are not supposed to be
growing
cannabis and so they just start hitting
them with fines before they even bother
sending in swat teams that's right
that's right all right yeah and and that
certainly i think is uh you know
the satellites really changed that game
yeah sure the satellites did um it's a
pretty expensive program mendocino is
next up for one of those um
but like
there's a 1991 article by joe lieber in
like the humble geographic with a map
that like
has a pretty damn detailed
depiction of where and how many
canvas plants are in the entire county
and so like
there's a way in which actually like
they've always been seen
um the question is whether they're left
alone or not
uh and to what use like where does that
information go well it used to go to law
enforcement but now it goes also to code
enforcement
and code enforcement is is
you know
it is a part of civil government that is
not always you know connected to the
broader maybe county vision of trying to
protect its citizens by its nature code
enforcement is
out there to weed out the wrong types
right uh the people you don't want in
your neighborhood the people with their
you know uh
if they're you know maybe there's
abandoned cars on their property you
know maybe their house isn't up to code
um
you know code enforcement is really a
form of law enforcement against poor
people usually
and so
this is
kind of different in rural areas than is
in urban areas but it's been real
significant across the landscape i mean
you have
sonoma county let's say
right which largely accommodated medical
cannabis and commercial medical medical
cannabis uh at that
um
in 2013
you know doing a joint task force you
know raid on uh
uh mostly hispanic uh you know
neighborhood
uh
called roselands right it's 33 houses um
you know and you look at what they got
and it only ended up with under three
pounds a house and under it's about six
hundred dollars
both of which were not really you know
an issue for the white people
right um
uh they were being left alone
uh you know you have the city of clear
lake which actually um at the onset of
the financial crisis in 2007
defunded code enforcement entirely
because they were broke
and for like six years you know they
didn't have code enforcement
and clear lake is
a very very very poor town there's
demographically more in common with like
a a city in the uh appalachians you know
to the east
than it is the you know state of
california
um
and what happened was like you know city
of ten thousand you know
probably half of the houses had
backyards full of cannabis being
cultivated basically right out there in
the open
so they once they recovered from
their budget recovered uh in 2014 they
reactivated code enforcement
specifically
to deal with their uh you know so-called
problem the the backyard cannabis
cultivation problem which certainly
had some negative effects and had
negative effects associated with it
let's let's you know
let's say that uh
the ripoffs are a pretty good example
of you know something bad that can
happen when cannabis is being grown
entirely out in the open under
conditions of prohibition yeah valuable
crops they're right there for the taking
and that stuff gets violent fast often
and that stuff gets violent fast right
exactly so the the landscape now is
certainly
yes you know camp is is out there um
campus is
and not just camp but local uh joint
task forces as well
and
depending on where you are
they may be concentrating on
large environmentally impactful you know
cultivation sites uh that that
are politically you know probably more
agreeable to a lot of legacy campus
farmers um but they're also
you know catching up certainly
uh and causing collateral damage for
smaller farmers
uh so
it's complex but it was always complex i
guess the short summary of this long
answer is that yes it's light camp but
camp isn't necessarily
something that was the same like the 80s
and 90s were really it's it's it's
gung-ho
uh you know hit the small people
you know uh
um political you know thing there's a
there's a
sense in which camp kind of
professionalized a little bit over time
uh and
uh
and also justifies funding by getting
plant counts so they weren't as
incentivized to go after smaller growers
so
you know whether it was a moral decision
or not
it became
uh you know more profitable for them to
go after
a very large-scale cultivation
right on so let me reintroduce you
before we go to commercial uh you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is cannabis researcher dr dominic
corva we're gonna take a short break and
be right back
[Music]
cannabis folks are innovators and
problem solvers and we like to make
money have you developed a tool
technique or plant that you want to
protect and monetize
you'll likely want legal representation
that is experienced accessible and
shares your values plant and planet law
represents a wide variety of clients who
choose to respect the environment while
pursuing their business goals
have you invented a machine or gizmo
that you're bringing to market did you
discover a breakthrough environmentally
friendly pesticide or fertilizer
formulation that you're about to start
selling
have you bred a canvas plant with
attributes not found anywhere else
attorney dale hunt and his plant and
planet team have established genetic
patents in over 30 countries
working to help entrepreneurs scientists
throughout the life sciences plant and
planet represents environmentally
positive clients in cannabis and other
botanicals fungi water purification
clean energy emulsions and medical
applications
plant and planet helps people protect
what they've created
if you are an early stage company with
an established idea and are in the
process of fundraising often the
investors require intellectual property
productions happen at the same time
plant and planet can be your sole
representation or they can integrate
with your existing legal team and plug
in their specialties
plant and planet is made of scientist
lawyers with a real passion for cannabis
inventions and the environment they have
the scientific and legal depth to help
you establish patent protections for
your great idea
you don't have to go it alone
friendly qualified and honorable legal
representation is available to you
contact plant and planet law today to
start the conversation
email info at plant and planet.com
that's plant and planet law our clients
make the planet better
[Music]
after you've caught up on the latest
shaping fire episodes do you sometimes
wish there was more cannabis education
available to learn well we got you
shaping fire has a fabulous youtube
channel with content not found on the
podcast when i attend conventions to
speak or moderate panels i always record
them and bring the content home for you
to watch the schengolos youtube channel
has world-class speakers including zoe
sigmund's lecture understanding your
endocannabinoid system kevin jodrey of
wonderland nursery talking about
breeding cannabis for the best terpene
profile frenchy cannolis lost art of the
hashishin presentation nicholas mahmoud
on regenerative and polyculture cannabis
growing dr sunil agrawal on the history
of cannabis medicine around the world
eric vlosky and josh rutherford on
solvent-less extraction and jeff
lonefels on the soil food web there are
several presentations from dr ethan
russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system too
while there be sure to check out the
three 10-part shaping fire sessions
series one with kevin jodrey one with dr
ethan russo and one with jeff lowenfels
and even my own presentations on how to
approach finding your dream job in
cannabis and why we choose cannabis
business even though the risks are so
high as of today there's over two
hundred videos that you can check out
for free so go to youtube dot com
forward slash shango lose or click on
the link in the newsletter
[Music]
for 20 years humboldt seed company has
been family owned and providing reliable
high yielding seeds originating in
northern california while the current
trend is to slap one super male into a
line of hyped strains humboldt seed
company continues to breed with
precision and care by doing large sifts
and back crosses to emphasize the
absolute best traits that a line has to
offer this kind of breeding takes time
talent and space to work
no matter what kind of aroma you are
particularly into humboldt seed will
likely have something you'll love if you
love fruit you can choose from banana
mango apricot papaya blueberry blood
orange melon and lemons across their
various strains they have all gas glue
and classic sour diesel lines as well of
course there are the heritage california
strains like og kush jack hair and
headband and their award-winning
blueberry muffin is one that delights
just about everybody's palate especially
when concentrated
humboldt seed company is proud to bring
to market the infamous freak show
cultivar 2 which has a great thc high
but looks so much like a fern that some
folks can't even identify it as cannabis
it's a plant that really needs to be
seen to be believed
if you're looking for well-balanced cbd
seeds humboldt seed company can turn you
on to cbd strains that actually have
flavor like the dill and pepper terpenes
of willy g's lebanese land race
whether you are looking for regular
feminized or autoflowers humboldt seed
company has the gear to make this your
best growing cycle ever
visit
humboldtseedcompany.com today to check
out their line of vigorous genetics
download their catalog and find out
where you can pick them up you can also
check out their instagram at the
humboldt seed company to check out their
gorgeous flowers and the extraordinary
freak show plant
humboldt seed company let them know
shango sent ya
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and my guest today is cannabis
researcher dr dominic corva
so you know chapter four of the book you
edited with josh mizell begins with a
provocative quote from oregon state
representative diane russell who said
that the conversation about who makes
the profits off this industry is
irrelevant she said this as a way to try
to focus activists on getting any
legalization passed in the state of
maine rather than nitpicking the
particular policy choices but as we've
all seen in california
prop 64 was immediately a slippery piece
of legislation that quickly became
weaponized and then with the removal of
the one acre cap that was promised the
entire market you know tilted towards
large industrial producers distributing
mediocre cannabis and driving prices
down to a point where the heritage
market has just been decimated and we
see this happening in one way or another
in nearly every state that is normalized
so far
and as we see these multi-state
operators weave their brands across the
country state by state the future looks
very exasperating for smaller heritage
players
what are your thoughts on who is making
profits now and into the future versus
how these laws were originally sold to
the public
well i think the public didn't care to
be honest who it was that was supplying
the cannabis uh to a large degree so
uh certainly not the part of the public
that needed to be convinced about
legalization
necessarily a a lot of folks who just
wanted easier access to cannabis
and i think access historically has been
culturally determined
you it's your friend you know that is
into cannabis and you know maybe comes
from
uh a place where where it's around a lot
uh maybe it's your friend that's a
grower um
it's it has been difficult for something
i remember a seattle journalist uh years
ago
uh happy that he could just go to a
store because his dealer was so
unreliable before um
and so
let's just say that the people voting
for legalization or at least the the
voting bloc that mattered definitely
were not the cannabis culture people
they're very very very tiny percentage
of the population
um
and literally they were going to vote
for
legalization
you know wherever
so first of all i don't think that um
legalization was sold originally
as an economic justice thing that
conversation has shifted
tremendously
in the last eight years
um and primarily because of the black
lives matter movement and the uh the way
that that particular social movement
has highlighted
uh the the whiteness and richness
essentially of ownership in
the cannabis industry but let's talk
about that let's talk about what that
actually means
when you refer to multi-state operators
we're usually talking about um operators
who are getting their funding
from being listed on the canadian stock
exchange
usually
um
and so who's making money
well
none of those msos are actually making
money or very very few of them what
they're doing is losing money until
their competitors can go out of business
that is
a tried and true
you know uh you know uh
method in the united states that
especially developed you know since you
know silicon valley uh and the tech
sector
that all you had to do was scale up and
and and buy everybody and it didn't
matter if you lost money you could
always go back to the stock exchange and
raise more money
uh until basically you could go in into
the green
and i don't know how many tech companies
lost money you know or even continuing
to lose money today
uh whose ceos and founders are making
you know tens of millions hundreds of
millions of dollars while they do this
so the companies aren't making money
but
the ceos and the founders and their
officers are making money because
they're being paid like corporate
america
right like
what do you pay a ceo a ceo in the
united states well usually it's
something absolutely ridiculous
because that's what
essentially uh you know
early 21st century financialized
capitalism has done
it's created enormous inequality in
terms of income
uh and and the people who are kind of
sitting at the bottleneck just like you
know
uh extracting you know
uh what would be an enormous amount of
money to any other individual while
their company loses money
uh you know those are the people getting
rich and they tend to be white and they
tend to be male that's absolutely the
case so
it
in in the cannabis energy industry
the media part of it really has fallen
down about this
because
so many people want to talk about how
much money is being made how much
revenue is being made in cannabis
and of course like that's a stupid
question how much money is being made in
cannabis
means nothing
if you balance it with well how much is
it costing us
to actually make that money right
because that's where you end up you know
uh with net revenue losses even though
you're you're raking in millions and
millions of dollars that just means
you've got a lot of sales
but you had to spend money to get there
and so
ultimately it's the large msos
that you know can lose money but while
small businesses can absolutely not do
that right
um
they will go out of business they will
get uh
acquired in fact that's probably the
strategy of a lot of folks who actually
did transition to legalization at this
point
is they've been barely getting by
or
not at all
and
they're positioning their businesses to
get acquired so they can get out of this
because they didn't sign up for
basically
a you know
a business model that was absolutely no
fun and had actually no you know reward
to it
uh and so
really they you know most of them got
into cannabis to get out of the rat race
right and so legalization puts them
right back in the rat race and and
nobody wants to be a rat racing around
so
this is a you know
this is a an interesting question across
the landscape but it's that that like
popular assumption that anybody who
starts a cannabis business must be
loaded
that is a problem and it's entirely
because of all the ipo pumping
that's been going on
uh you know the the media really is all
about celebrating how much revenue comes
in and they have absolutely no you know
on the other hand
uh these are the costs of doing business
and we don't get to you know deduct them
uh you know when we pay our taxes
because cannabis is still illegal
so
uh
that's an issue in a couple of ways and
i'd say that
it gets real messy when you start
talking about a lot of these equity
programs
that
are
you know
oriented towards diversifying ownership
in the cannabis industry
because being an owner in the cannabis
industry
is not the reward for
uh you know
someone who is not a corporation
that you would expect right like it's an
invitation to go bankrupt
um and so like
we both have this problem that yes too
many white people are owners
uh but especially too many white people
are ceos right of these large companies
and too many companies are in fact just
these giant financial conglomerations
that are you know
just whales trying to swallow all the
smaller whales until they're the biggest
whale
so
that's a problem and that problem is
almost entirely produced by
the you know
levels of regulation that are required
that you can lose a bunch of money and
just you know pay those costs of
regulation
and upkeep and unpredictability in the
marketplace
uh if you have access to essentially a
you know
a revenue source that is you know a
public stock exchange you just sell more
shares
uh and so
the shareholders themselves also you
know
have essentially
bought little pieces of something that
they hope will eventually become big
pieces
right uh and so they themselves may
eventually
uh you know cash out too so let's let's
acknowledge that shareholders are also
part of this landscape
what's the demographic of this the
shareholders right uh well
there should be more research on that uh
i think that's it would be an important
thing that
to uncover really is is how
financialized is
the cannabis industry
and what are the demographics of that
financialization
uh so who really is making a bunch of
money
uh and and why and when the answer is
well they're making a bunch of money
because they're doing exactly what
capitalism in the united states and and
elsewhere
you know uh
incentivizes them to do
and then you're like well how do we
change this
think about that for a sec well if the
problem is actually existing capitalism
then
maybe the issue is going to be you're
going to do something about
capitalism let me let me actually break
that down so it's not as vague by
capitalism let me refer to you know the
financialized sector
of our
gdp
uh let us separate out the capitalism of
small businesses and
entrepreneurs uh and and livelihood
operators who are also
if you you know depending on how you're
defining capitalism is for example you
know using waged labor right
uh you know they're practicing
capitalism but they aren't practicing
the kind of capitalism that operates
through stock exchanges
uh and when you have these regulations
the regulations work just fine for you
know
they're a small barrier for a
financialized company
relative to the kind of barrier they are
for small businesses so
if you don't want to be like me uh and
and you know
throw all of capitalism under under a
bus
you know it'd be good to kind of think
about this in terms of well
what do
regulations do in terms of you know
business competition
uh business competition and ownership uh
considerations
uh well
in the rest of the united states what it
does is it concentrates ownership in the
hands of the few
and and wrecks small businesses
uh
makes it very difficult uh
high you know heavy regulations are very
difficult for small business owners to
to
deal with
but they are not really much of a
barrier for highly capitalized interests
so you have this kind of
ambivalent thing going on here is we
need
big regulations for big business and
small regulations for small business
is is probably the most sensible way to
to uh to think about that
uh but
you know
we really aren't set up in the society
to uh
to think that way we're set up to think
oh there's either regulations or no
regulations well actually if you want to
democratize uh
the economy and maybe do a little work
on economic justice what you would do is
have big regulations for big business
and small regulations for small business
i want to tease out one particular
demographic that that you're talking
about here um
be patient with me this is kind of a big
setup so so you were just telling us
about how
um
the
these these large cannabis companies
that are creating a lot of revenue but
not actually necessarily profit because
they're spending so much money but they
are
paying their executive suite um
members
um they are they are able to take on
more and more debt by selling at a
profit until
the their competition uh including um
smaller financialized companies and the
entirety of the craft artisan market you
know the heritage folks until they are
all just you know crushed and go out of
business
or as you mentioned get picked up and
we're starting to see some of the
heritage brands that have been
successful starting to ally with some of
these distributors you know potentially
setting up a you know a future buy but
you know we'll see how that goes out
i'm very interested in the
vast majority of heritage growers who
are actually buckling under the weight
of the low prices and the fact that they
are not they don't have the same
efficiencies of scale that some of these
industrial agriculture cannabis
producers have
what happens when
their backs are finally broken in the
licensed
system and and they're all like you know
what screw this i'm not playing in the
license system i gotta interrupt you
shango like if
you've gone really staticky oh all right
all right let's uh let's figure out what
that is um
hold on let me figure out where we are
we're at um
time-wise
58-36 all right so what it what has
changed and when did it change
are you there
yeah yeah yeah um
was i i couldn't hear your entire
question because you were going in and
out all right um
is it staticky now
testing last sentence yeah so so no
static all right so maybe what i did
let's try something let me turn my head
this way is this what was happening can
you now hear me less well
no you're just kind of quiet now before
it was literally staticky you'd go in
and out all right well um
uh i guess i will
let's i guess we'll we can just blame
that on the internet i guess
yeah yeah it might have been a burp
you're sounding good now maybe maybe
just start that question yeah i will
start that question from the top cool
thanks
um
um all right uh so there'll be a moment
for me to edit into and i'll restart
your question okay
there's one group in that demographic
that i really would like to tease out
and and
you know be patient with me because this
this question takes a moment to set up
because you pointed out how
the large cap
cannabis corporations are
financialized and they are
they're they have a lot of revenue
coming in but they're actually losing
money but they're okay with that because
their goal
is like you said to be a bigger whale
and buy out the smaller whales and then
the much smaller people just run them
out of business and to the point that
prices are so low for cannabis that
there's not enough of a premium market
left
for the smaller artisan craft producers
um that i herald on this show all the
time you know the heritage growers who
who have been doing this for for decades
so there's going to be a certain point
where
um you know this this substantial
number of growers are no longer able to
see financial benefit in the license
system and so they're like all right
fine we're out and you know as we
already know a lot of these um
these these craft companies have got you
know two businesses going right they've
got the licensed one
that they're hoping to participate in
and they've got a second one that's
that's still exporting and and helping
pay the bills while the legal business
gets up and running but but if there's
enough strength in corporate cannabis
they're never going to grow to that
point and eventually they'll just have
to you know choose to give up their
license and air quotes go do something
else right but for the craft growers
that i know who have been grown who have
grown up in cannabis
cannabis growing is all they know
and and i wonder what that looks like
from a you know a sociological
perspective which you offer about these
people who grew up in illegal cannabis
and and then took a shot in the licensed
market
and became publicly known
and the public market was so broken and
monopolized by financialized
cannabis companies that they have to go
do something else and i suspect their
first choice would be to go back to the
the unlicensed market which has now
grossly changed um both in california
and in the
markets that they used to and still do
to a certain degree export too
so so what do you think you know from
from your perspective
seeing the grand landscape what's gonna
happen to this particular pool of
heritage growers who eventually give up
and say i can't do this in the licensed
market what do you think or what have
you seen these folks starting to do
when the black market is so changed
well let's say you know
let's acknowledge from the gecko that
probably 95
of them never made a go of the licensed
market right really i didn't i didn't
realize it was such a large share
of the
unlicensed market that never even tried
that's that's an impressive that's an
impressive number
yeah yeah i mean
i'm pulling that number a little out of
my butt but it's also a matter of uh
you know
uh
you know you look at humboldt but had
that had you know an estimated to say 15
000 you know cultivators
you know on the on the on the eve of
legalization and they have uh 800 you
know
uh
uh in 800 distinct you know owners
of cultivation or other kinds of
licenses
right now
uh that are going through the permitting
and licensing process
um so
that right there is 90 right like
roughly
and and humble you know
had a very high concentration also has a
very very large amount of licenses per
capita way more than anybody else
so
uh you know mendocino certainly uh
similarly
you're already actually seeing in
mendocino and elsewhere the revenue
reports of the last year of you know all
these people that had permits and were
operating but are not reporting revenue
this year and don't appear to be
operating so we're already going through
an extinction event
in that sense
and and so there's kind of two things to
think about here
one is you know
returning to
uh
the unregulated markets
or participating in it as a way to try
to stay in place and not become
displaced from their communities right
finding something else to do in terms of
an occupation
um
there's also
uh displacement you know like uh
definitely a lot of people went to
oklahoma lately right
uh
so
these are all you know different
outcomes you know staying in place
and if your name is already in the
system your property is already in the
system and you cease to be a licensed
or permitted operator stop reporting
revenues here
you stuck your neck out and so the odds
that you're going to be able to stay
there and do the same thing are pretty
low yeah
because
you know they're looking for you and
they're they're wondering what happened
to you
uh so
there's that aspect
uh i think that it's important
important to realize that
a lot a lot of operators you know
there's many different kinds of heritage
farmers is the thing i'm struggling with
here shango ah
and
some of them
[Music]
have been you know at the cutting edge
of indoor and you know breeding and
staying on top of the latest
cultivars and and
and regenerative agriculture and stuff
like that and
and then there's you know
a lot of folks that uh
you know were not they were you know
they were growing and and they had
places to to send it um
so adapting i think to to new things
especially you know
staying on top of what it is you can
export because it's not just anything
anymore
uh you know i i think that adapting in
terms of uh
what it is you're growing and how you're
growing it are two big things
uh and certainly reducing your inputs
and staying you know low impact and i
mean that you know
environmentally as well as
socially right uh staying under the
radar
uh you know these are all adaptive
strategies that people are using
uh
i want to say that also within the
licensed market
the problem isn't just the msos over
producing
the problem is that california cannot
open enough retail
that like you know again
two-thirds of its jurisdictions you know
don't have retail
and so what that means is that there's
more and more product going to
you know
amount of stores that is staying
completely
you know the same
and that drives down the cost of
uh or the price of
wholesale cannabis uh and eventually a
little bit drives down the price of the
consumer
but then what's also happening
is you know
distributors uh
this distribution licenses are operated
as burners
so then you have these entrepreneurs who
basically
acquire
distribution licenses
buy up tons of product
and then report it all lost or stolen
basically right
uh and so it's like
yeah your price on the uh
your wholesale price that you can buy on
the legal side is like down to
very very little here four or five
hundred three hundred
uh and then you can turn around and
export that somewhere else for
three times as much
you know per per pound
you know that's when i think we talked
about this before that's when basically
the legal market
becomes
the diversion market yeah the diversion
market
uh and so
uh
that kind of interplay between the
unregulated regulated you know diversion
and not diversion
dynamic is homeostatic in a certain way
because now the unregulated market gets
flooded
and drives the price down
uh
so anybody going to the unregulated
market and hoping that's what saves them
is going to get chased by this flood of
you know
uh diversion coming from the licensed
market in the license market so there's
a dynamic that's not just like what's
happening this year it's like what's
happening next year
uh and so
uh this is all very difficult right uh
but i what i will say though
is that obviously you know
there's there's no logical reason why
farmers shouldn't have direct con to
market access like why did they have to
go through distributors and retailers
why can't they sell directly to
consumers right
um
and so
you know if they if they got that
that right as any other farmer or
agriculture you know uh
agricultural sector has you know you
could sell your apples
you know on a farm stand that's not
nobody
you don't get arrested for that you know
like uh
then
that would help right
i think that uh
the other part is like if you are
producing the absolute top of the line
craft stuff right
then your market share isn't falling
because
basically those you know corporate
cannabis at large scale
can't produce
quality that is high enough to attract
the sophisticated consumer
right like the sophisticated consumer is
barely even patronizing the legal market
right anyway right uh
but
the fact is you know like
i remember in 1993 94 you know
my stoner buddies uh
you know coming to a party and they're
like
we got the kind bud you know like and i
was like how much did you pay for that
and they're like 400 an ounce
and i was like oh my god because like
what we were buying was like you know
100 ounces of mexican seeded stuff and
you know i didn't have any i didn't know
you know
why a poor college student would choose
to like you know
purchase a much more expensive product
you know until you consume it and you
see the difference
uh and and you're ruined forever from
mexican brickweed
exactly exactly and and the fact is is
that like
you know over the course of the course
of the 1990s and 2000s like
people literally chose to spend four
times more
you know uh on the on the consumer end
because they have they could have bought
the mexican but our entire you know
domestic market shifted
uh
towards the more expensive stuff
because it was that much better
and so like again there there is
like craft actual craft you know
uh
production
which not every heritage grower has the
ability necessarily to do
uh you know it will have shelf space
uh at prices that are you know much more
agreeable to the growers so you have to
actually hone your craft um
uh in addition to you know embracing
you know new marketing possibilities
like appalachians and
you know equity branded uh
supply chains and local branded supply
chains there are many other marketing
tricks that you can do
to kind of stay in the market but
the fact is if you can't pay your rent
you're not going to be
you're not going to go forward with this
and so
those are those are kind of the options
available is to you know embrace all the
things that you can do to add value to
your product
and and and you know
usually that
means smaller scale cultivation because
that's how you get really high quality
products not mass-produced
um
and as long as you can do that you know
if you're a heritage farmer
you know that's rural on your land you
know like
that was the point you're you're doing
this to stay on your land
uh and you can
grow you know organic
food and vegetables as well and and mix
it up right
uh heritage farmers that are you know
historically maybe more urban or
indoor focused
well
is it gonna is it paying the rent or is
it not you know like that's the question
you know and if it's not and if you
don't have access to market
then uh
you're gonna be displaced basically or
or or you're gonna
you know
you're gonna get a different job
and
let's say that you know a lot of those
those folks
a lot of those folks actually developed
trade skills
that are pretty vital to like indoor
production that are
not bad options you know uh going back
and going back into real estate going
into
you know hvac or or you know electric or
whatever else you know
those are options basically so
uh
like a lot of the rest of the
gig economy it's kind of cobbling stuff
together to
to move forward so
i think there's always been a difference
though between the folks who were doing
it to like
stay out of the rat race
and the people who were doing it to
basically cheat in the rat race
right yeah i followed this uh
you follow that yeah yeah and i i got no
moral you know judgment actually about
the latter let's just say as well
uh
not necessarily it's like screw the rat
race you know
anybody who's trying to get around it is
i totally understand it
uh but you know like
uh i think that's
the right to not be displaced from one's
community and land is a really important
principle and and that's the one that i
think we should be
we we may be able to do something about
um
certainly the state of california is
increasingly
uh maybe it's too little too late
but you know the equity program monies
are arriving
there's another million dollars that
uh humboldt county has taken out of
their general fund to help their farmers
this was just announced like a week ago
uh you know jurisdictions who are
collecting you know a bunch of taxes
that aren't supporting their local
businesses are going to lose those taxes
so they're going to start you know
saying okay well maybe you know maybe
we'll you know beef up our equity
programs try to keep people
uh but but the ones that do that are
usually the ones that recognize people
that are part of their communities their
mothers fathers sisters brothers and
daughters and
you know
they're not trying to make a move to
oklahoma you know yeah
so so for the rest of this set let's uh
let's take a let's pivot and move from
more the governance um
and cultural disciplines into
public health
and um you know
nearly everyone knows somebody who's
being helped by medical cannabis at this
point even in states that don't have any
sort of medical or you know wreck
cannabis they still have their sister
who lives in california or their uncle
who lives in oklahoma and and these
people are saying oh my gosh i'm using
this and my arthritis is so much better
so so people are aware of medical
cannabis use now
and it is very quickly tearing down the
the taboos and and moral panic that as
you refer to it in the book
and um
and
it has now shown this interesting
contrast between public health and
public policy
because public policy on especially the
local level because of the patchwork
regulations we've talked about
local level public policy can be
anti-cannabis and be decreasing access
or
or for example
not having pesticide
tests because the businesses are
resisting it
versus the public health drive for
cannabis
because people are finding unique ways
to get relief from cannabis that doesn't
have some of the same side effects as
some of their other options
so
um what are you seeing um you know from
from your 10 000 foot view of of this
this contrast this friction that we're
getting now
between public health and and um kind of
antiquated uh policy
well i think that uh
as usual i'm gonna point towards
complexity
yeah
because i think that often you know
public health institutions are actually
you know
uh feeding back on you know prohibition
stigma
uh and you know doing everything they
can to actually you know
uh
keep prohibition and legalization
entangled right uh
and so
uh you know an example of that would be
the ways in which you know
really strict zoning
in terms of like setbacks in particular
from parks and schools and so forth that
are way more harsh than alcohol
uh you know are supported by you know
usually public health you know
professionals
uh who are all very very very worried
about the kids yeah uh of course it's
it's usually the white kids ultimately
that they're worried about
um so
so let's just say that they're not
necessarily you know opposing each other
necessarily
there are you know
in terms of health research
more broadly speaking um i think
that
it is pretty important for
you know uh bioscientific research
to do its thing
and
uh this is where i want to give a plug
to the person you last had on miyabi
uh dr miyabi shields dr miyabi shields
man like
that's
pretty much like both of those
interviews
i would just say
you know are an answer to that your
question you know like uh
you know this is someone who
is talking about the science of it as
something that can be complementary to
the herbal medicine and traditional
medicine approaches
and not just
uh you know uh
another hierarchical situation where the
the pursuit for molecular
you know uh
double blind controlled
studies
you know
uh
runs herbal medicine out of town right
the
burns the witches at the stake
which is i think a situation that is a
problem for public health
uh but can be complementary and
synergistic with it um
i also think that uh
she had some really sophisticated
answers
when talking about the
you know
the the cultural value of trusting you
know the experts in terms of you know uh
bioscience and and this humility with
respect to like what we actually know
uh which is
you know not much yet you know i think
she
they sorry my apologies for the
um misgendering um
they pointed towards you know really
being at the very beginning of discovery
about you know the endocannabinoid
system and so forth which
is often not the attitude of researchers
getting big grants because they can't
say that in their grant applications
otherwise they're not going to get that
grant
so
there's there's this
culture i think
that is attached entirely to funding
that uh you know promotes this
hierarchical dismissive
uh approach to health that is you know
only worried about
danger
and is not humble about what it actually
knows as opposed to a you know health
research agenda driven by
uh
bioscientists like miyabi
who are
listening to you know what what patients
are saying about their own bodies and
respecting that right um that's what i
mean by a more non-hierarchical approach
that uh expertise is developed you know
with patients
not in spite of them
so um i would say that in addition to
um this non-hierarchical approach
um
this this contrast that that i recognize
that you're saying is very complex um
it's it's also complex in other ways
right for example the the limitations on
on on scientific research still that
even though we know
there's a great need for more research
into the medicine well it's still really
hard to get them approved using these
controlled substances or or another as
we've seen um play out recently in the
olympics you know the regulation in
sports making criminals out of athletes
who are just trying to recover there
seems to be
a culture-wide friction between the
public health benefits of cannabis
and
the the kind of hangover
of moral panic that drove prohibition
for the last you know
50 years
he absolutely absolutely so
the you know health research has has
been a part of the moral panic
historically it's been maybe uh the main
driver of it
uh
because nida you know again was funding
research for you know 40 years on how
harmful cannabis could be
um and so
i think that that's that's important i
think that that you know
the the olympics example is a really
interesting one as is the the general
field of exercise and sport that dr
whitney ogle talks about in her chapter
in public health
that
you know when when whitney went back to
do essentially a literature review what
she found was in the 1960s and 1970s
there were actually all these
the beginnings of a body of of research
that was about the potential public
health or health benefits of of cannabis
in exercise and sport
and it completely vanished
so much so that like when you're
starting a paper now and you're
reviewing the literature like
there's not much from the last 10 years
but there's a whole lot from the 60s and
70s and so it's like a thread to pick up
to pick up really that got just
completely obliterated and dropped
um
and in exercise and sport obviously when
it comes to the olympics
i think that
what the the scandal about you know
shikari richardson being disqualified
from the olympics
had more to do with like a public like
what you know like
like uh people being flabbergasted
people being flabbergasted then any sort
of like oh this is like a new thing
because being a ross roboglio the
olympic uh
uh you know 15 years ago was uh lost his
medal right but but nobody said okay
let's change the rules therefore like
now like this literally is okay wait a
sec like
this is a really weird thing
that we have disqualified a world-class
athlete for using cannabis
because we have listed it as a
performance enhancing drug
because that's how you ban things from
our
you know from athletes
uh it's like it's like backing into the
regulations it's just completely
completely and i do think that that
things will change although
here's the question for you shango like
is cannabis a performance-enhancing drug
can it be
uh
i i think that's like a next level
question that
you know i i would argue
not to the level where it you know
should be banned like steroids or
something like that right
but it is
anti-inflammatory it might help you
recover faster
uh you know world-class athletes that
use cannabis
including like mba players you know like
like at least half of them apparently
uh
you know
is that giving him an edge
uh and that's a research question
right
uh but you don't start from the point of
it's already banned and then then ask
that recent question you you say this
doesn't make sense on the surface and it
wasn't in here for any particular
research reason there's no research that
said this is performance-enhancing drug
therefore let's ban it
uh the the reason the research was like
is it illegal therefore let's ban it
right
uh but like
that's you know i think a very
interesting
research agenda which is is whitney's as
well it's like well how can cannabis be
integrated into you know
uh exercise and sport in a healthy way
and
i think that's a legitimate question but
it's you know
i think there there there's uh you know
there's a research agenda there about
whether cannabis can be performance
enhancing that shouldn't be connected to
an already existing rule that like you
know bans people
but
if we're going to argue that yeah
cannabis can be used you know when
you're exercising
then you have to embrace that as a
legitimate research question right on
well let's go ahead and take our second
short break and be right back you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is cannabis researcher dr dominic
corva
[Music]
there is no doubt that autoflowering
cannabis plants have finally come in to
their own and night owl seeds works
tirelessly bringing you autoflower
genetics that are reliable thriving and
with extraordinary terpene profiles
night owl seeds is an industry leader
because of the focus work of their
founder daz daz is passionate about the
cannabis plant and pushing what
autoflowers can do and cultivators know
that these efforts show through in his
seeds and night owl seeds really are
extraordinary just take a look at the
thousands of photos that by fans on
instagram the proof is there and obvious
terpenes are complex and rich plants
have vigor if you are a fan of mephisto
genetics like i am you'll likely also
love night owl seeds night owl founder
daz worked with mitch mephisto to build
the mephisto brand for years including
breeding mephisto's much-loved sour
stomper and cosmic queen cultivars
i'm growing both night owl and mephisto
this year because i want the best and
night owl seeds knows how to cultivate
community too
daz puts out great stickers exclusive
packaging for limited runs and desirable
freebies he really draws you in if you
love creative branding
night owl even has the secret owl
society text club just text the word
night owl one word to 760-670-3130
for early announcements and exclusive
opportunities of course you can see lots
of photos and find out about upcoming
drops by following the night owl seeds
instagram too
at daz.nightowl
that's
d-a-z-dot-night owl you can get your
packs of night owl seeds at several
distributors including dc seed exchange
insane seeds and hemogenetics that's
night owl seeds there's a difference
because we're different
[Music]
sometimes the topics i want to share
with you are far too brief for an entire
shaping fire episode in those instances
i post them to instagram i invite you to
follow my two instagram profiles and
participate online the shaping fire
instagram has follow-up posts to shaping
fire episodes growing and processing
best practices product trials and of
course gorgeous flower photos the
shangolos instagram follows my travels
on cannabis garden tours my successes
and failures in my own garden insights
and best practices from personal grows
everywhere and always gorgeous flower
photos on both profiles the emphasis is
on sharing what i've learned in a way
that you can replicate it in your own
garden your own hash lab or for your own
cannabitopathic health so i encourage
you to follow at shaping fire and
and join our online community on
instagram
[Music]
as a business owner you are incredibly
busy in reality you are responsible for
everything your company does you've got
so many responsibilities every single
day that often you just don't have the
time to really dig into your marketing
as deeply as you'd like
you know there's more that you could do
to reach out to new customers and
encourage loyalty and the customers you
already have but you certainly don't
have the time for it and you're not
ready to hire somebody full time for
that role either
for you i recommend blunt branding at
blunt branding kirsten nelson and her
team are focused on improving your
bottom line you know most marketing
firms are excited to make your logo
packaging and website very pretty but
they leave responsibility for improving
your bottom line up to you they don't
want that kind of responsibility but
that's pretty much the most important
part of marketing right
kirsten and her team will help you
engage new customers funnel them to your
point of sale whether it be online or a
storefront and keep them coming back to
you and telling their friends
now if you happen to be a new cannabis
company or an established company moving
from medical to adult use in your state
kirsten especially can help you not only
is she well reversed in marketing and
finance but she totally gets cannabis
whole plant medicine terpenes heritage
farmers and the particular needs of
startups
check out what she did recently for moon
time medicinals and humboldt at moon
time medicinals.com kirsten and her team
put together a whole brand package for
them built their website and wrote their
sales materials
no doubt this is a paid commercial spot
but that does not mean they bought my
opinion i've worked with blunt branding
on five projects now for various of
their clients and every single time they
have done more than they have promised
and over delivered on results i love how
they generate new revenue and focus on
that as the goal instead of just making
a pretty logo
similarly every single friend i've
referred them to has come back to thank
me and that just does not happen every
day
grab a pen and paper because the website
address is coming up if you want someone
to implement marketing programs that
feed your bottom line give blunt
branding a call they will share proven
techniques to increase your audience and
generate sales while using cutting edge
technology solutions in the background
that make all of this easy automatic and
trackable go to shapingfire.com forward
slash blunt branding to find out more
you can also click the link in our
newsletter blunt branding marketing that
makes you money
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and my guest today is cannabis
researcher doctor dominic corva
so dominic i've got another point i want
to bring up about public uh public
health
and um throughout the book prisons come
up again and again as an enforcement
tool that is applied unevenly both by uh
well i guess it's more by by locale by
race and who the judge may be sometimes
it's just the role of the dice
the the number of americans who remain
in prison
you know props up a
for you know for-profit prison system
that is of course severely broken
and now we see the strange inequity of
prisoners continuing to be held while
white-collar entrepreneurs receive
licenses to sell the same stuff
not only does that strike most folks as
wildly unfair
prison for non-violent cannabis offenses
continues to break up families and have
extensive impacts on public health
so would you
continue with an explanation of what you
see happening now along the prison
public health axis during this you know
difficult and rocky transition between
prohibition and prohibition alongside
licensed and taxed cannabis
yeah absolutely there's a lot to say
about that and and the first thing that
i want to point out is that
for example in colorado legalization
came with new criminal penalties
for people
under the age of 21
and that this is
often a knee-jerk part of legalization
is to
actually increase penalties criminal
penalties uh for uh
you know folks under the age of 21 which
is
you know
absolutely counterproductive um
and so you know that has to do with kind
of like deciding an age at which
cannabis is legal which is also part of
the entanglement of legalization and
prohibition
because like as far as i know
we will never be done with prohibition
you know uh
criminal prohibition sanctions against
people under the age of 21.
so um
perhaps these may get reduced like civil
ones but uh
as long as we have basically decided
that a legal consumer is only someone
over the age of 21 or someone with a
medical
uh you know uh authorization that's
under 121
then we're going to have
uh you know a criminal justice system
that tilts against the younger people in
cannabis
um
also as we pointed out before
demographically
the legal licenses are going to you know
whiter
wealthier people
and they sometimes have an incentive to
call for more enforcement and that
enforcement happens
against black and brown people
uh disproportionately
this is especially true in urban areas
so
the phenomenon we call mass
incarceration
is
a combination of federal and and local
you know prison systems basically right
uh that sometimes have something to do
with each other and sometimes not
uh
in large urban cities like los angeles
new york chicago
in the 1990s and 2000s
what those cities chose to do
in terms of policing and public safety
was to do broken windows policing what
they call broken windows policing
which meant that basically the police
had kind of a free hand to um
uh
identify
you know the metaphoric broken windows
uh signs of disorder
in any given community
and you know
come up with ways to uh you know
uh bring them into the criminal justice
system and of course
uh
you know
usually a broken window in a white
community is a black person right
there's a sign of disorder
so
uh in in urban areas in particular
that kind of
policy combined with that kind of
discretion
really intensified
the you know uh bringing black and brown
people you know uh into the criminal
justice system
um this is also true in rural areas but
the the
disproportionality is very very
different
that that black and brown people in
rural areas definitely are
disproportionately you know when you
look at the numbers
uh arrested uh for for for cannabis and
other drug crimes
but there is it is it is drastically
lower than in urban areas at the same
time their like arrest rates are often
higher than urban areas per capita
which means that they are arresting a
lot more white people
as well and women actually in rural
areas
often have
higher than state average um
arrests of women
and
this is in particular let me say to
because the data that i'm that i'm
thinking about is from california so
let's let's make sure that i'm not
trying to generalize i think that that's
a research agenda for everywhere else as
well by the way but we know this uh uh
uh of california and especially
uh legacy producing regions which are
the ones that i've been able to study
the data for um
so
the other part of it is
that
a lot has been done in the last 10 to 20
years
to actually reduce
um jail populations local local jail
populations in big cities
that there's been basically reforms
going on since the early 2000s
that are you know bail reform or other
things
um that are helping a lot with that but
folks in federal prison
it's it's a it's a population that's
much more stable and much more long-term
uh
and
part of this has to do
with
the power prosecutors especially federal
prosecutors
uh that basically
increase substantially relative to
defense or judges actually since in
given the the criminal justice acts of
you know 1986 1988 1994
that basically created these draconian
mandatory minimums
truth and sentencing
and all this tough on crime legislation
that basically means that whatever
whatever it is you did when you did it
is actually pretty important because if
you did it in 1988
you're you got like you know 40 years to
life or something for something that you
know uh today would not get you 40 years
of life and this is true for every
offense not just cannabis
cannabis is part of of course at the
federal level which means you know we're
talking about the federal prison system
uh part of
prohibition
that means not just that cannabis is
prohibited but like
all these other drugs are also
prohibited
and so cannabis is part of
you know this range of delinquencies
essentially that the state has decided
is worth like
you know all this effort time and money
to imprison people for and lock them up
for
and so
cannabis is kind of along for the ride
with the other drugs whenever there's a
moral panic about crack cannabis also
gets caught up and it's about fentanyl
cannabis is going to get caught up in it
at least federally right
it's you know
to prosecutors it's it's it's a drug
crime you know it's it's a felony it's
not a cannabis felony it's not a you
know
some other kind of felony so it's
important and this is actually
the other part that's that i think in
the introduction will really lay out is
like
don't forget the cannabis probation
prohibition is absolutely part of drug
prohibition
and that's an entanglement that is
absolutely meta
because
drug prohibition you know takes cannabis
along for the ride
um
so
with respect to you know
who gets prison and not
and in terms of you know wealthy white
people having licenses to sell things
people are going to prison for
i would just point out that like
even if those wealthy white people were
getting arrested
they would either not be spending any
time in prison
or they would be spending basically
their time in prison club med like like
martha stewart right yeah like that's
our criminal justice system it is
absolutely unequal in this country just
like our economy is
uh
the privileges you have when you have a
lot of capital
have nothing to do with whether that's
cannabis capital or whether it's oil
capital or whether it's pharma capital
it's privilege
uh and so it's very important i think
not to
not to be like militantly particular
about cannabis as an issue and and and
and the prison system
actually like our prison system itself
is just awful prosecutorial discretion
has driven mass incarceration
uh no amount of you know legalizing
discrete supply chains of cannabis
are going to have a large impact on
what's going on there
and like
you know sure it's very important to
advocate for people to get out of prison
but i i think that like a lot of people
are really kind of myopically focused
just on cannabis criminals and cannabis
crimes and actually
it's all the other ones too
there are a lot of people who just
are poorer and are you know people of
color
that are
caught up and trapped in this prison
system whether or not it's about
cannabis
so uh this is one of those things that i
think
in terms of the promises and and and
goals of legalization has shifted
like back in 2010 there was a lot talk
about you know ending mass incarceration
because you're legalizing cannabis which
is always a great exaggeration
uh and i think in 2020
what you have is actually more of a like
let's put our money where our mouth is
at this point um because back then it
was just kind of a marketing play
and in many ways it did a great
disservice to black and brown people by
legalizing cannabis and then absolutely
having no
no part of the legal cannabis system
oriented towards you know actually
helping black and brown people we use
them
we use them in in washington we
absolutely use them
as like let's legalize cannabis because
it's bad for minorities but then
legalization comes along it actually
doesn't do anything good for for people
of color
uh
and i think that's changed uh
significantly in the last 10 years
i think that the the aclu was probably
the worst offender
uh
is much more in tune now to uh the the
realities of the situation is no longer
treating this like advertisement
for for legalization right on
well thank you for that perspective
dominic you're you're always you're
always remixing my perspective and i
appreciate that
um
i've got two more questions left for our
conversation and each of them
hits on different different areas in the
book
i see that professor evan mills is back
with an update of his groundbreaking
research into electrical usage by indoor
cultivators
his his original paper kind of blew
everybody away back i don't know what
was it 2013 or so 2012 yeah and it just
floored everybody um the numbers he was
quoting that would
the electricity that was being used by
indoor cultivation and
for a while there anyway
it looked like it was going to influence
regulations and encourage a
preferred regulatory
environment for outdoor and you know
that mostly went away as um as indoor
interests um lobbied back um but uh the
the the press version of of of your new
book that i got did not have the the the
chapter from professor mills in it and
and i think that uh i and probably a lot
of other people who are familiar with
that work uh his early work are curious
to know what he has to say now so so
since i haven't read the chapter i don't
know how to direct you on this question
but it's other than to say
what what does evan mills say now
oh well
you know evan has a lot to say about how
this is playing out in the regulated
landscape
so he's not just engaging with like you
know
arcata california and the electricity
usage in houses he's
he's talking about a much bigger carbon
footprint when you're talking about
warehouses
um
and so uh what he really especially
engages really very well with is how
regulations
that are supposed to be about you know
uh
protecting the environment
you know because we're
real worried about as we should be you
know water
uh land use
you know um
uh
impacts the wildlife absolutely like
those are important things
so we've we've got all these regulations
actually
like
the ones that are probably most
difficult for you know uh heritage
farmers are these sql regulations
but at the same time we're basically
incentivizing carbon footprint intensive
cultivation
because we're making it so difficult to
grow it outdoors and on ag land
necessarily along with other crops
so
the perspective really is a is a bigger
and broader structural perspective
really um
he reviews information from like
california and colorado in particular
um
and
what's interesting is obviously
his paper had a big impact back
then and arcade you know raised its
electricity tax rates and everybody
moved to mckinleyville and just kept
kept going uh so
so
the the issue though is that like what
evan wants to talk about now isn't
unregulated cannabis impacts necessarily
at all like uh certainly he's concerned
about that and very you know
not in favor of indoor cannabis you know
cultivation because of his carbon
footprint
but the really big you know
uh
problems now are in the regulated system
and so this is a critique of
legalization
not just a critique of unregulated
cannabis
and that in itself is is you know
profoundly important and let's see
whether it gets the kind of attention
that his previous research did
because his previous research may have
been a little more convenient for
people you know uh that wanted to you
know
say
perfectly reasonable things about you
know the carbon footprint issues of of
indoor cultivation but also
uh you know it played a long play played
played into you know um
folks wanting to essentially you know
prohibit or or or reduce the amount of
cannabis cultivation going on
in this case now because that is very
inconvenient
uh once again it's an inconvenient truth
but it's inconvenient to the regulators
and and
evan is
uh
in
fine form
uh you know
addressing political and regulatory
interests and and corporate interests
that uh you know
are are making this carbon footprint
issue
you know uh
uh or metastasizing and just growing it
massively
um
of course with with the climate change
conversation being that much more
important now than it was ten years ago
um
we hope that uh
this is a an intervention that is you
know
spread as widely and as fast uh as
quickly as as his prior one
right on well i'm looking forward to
reading it and i am glad that uh that
evan mills is is still in the mix and
still looking into this topic let's
let's finish off our discussion with uh
the chapter by our mutual friend uh dr
michelle sexton
um this chapter two i'm excited to read
still because it wasn't in the press
edition because uh dr sex and i have
been discussing that for years the nexus
of institutional science and the good
work done by citizen scientists
and and it's fun because you know like
most of the topics that you cover here
it's a complex one
and and she and i have both um evolved
our ideas you know over our what 10
years as friends and
and and debating this topic and as a
citizen scientist myself i know that
often my sample sizes are low and my
control is perhaps not the most complete
but citizen scientists everywhere are
also working faster than institutions in
many ways and blazing new paths that
institutional researchers can you know
follow up on later plus i'm hearing
things from patients who talk to me
that are often you know not insights
that are are being heard um by
traditional you know clinical doctors
so what are the main arguments in this
chapter on the intersection of cannabis
citizen science and and institutional or
academic scientists
well shango that's a very good question
uh
and i also want to
just say that uh you know dr sexton is
an absolutely you know dear friend of
mine and and helped me co-found casp as
as did
sunil aggarwal
uh both contributors to this handbook so
it was especially great to have them
both in here yeah for sure uh and so
really i think
when it comes down to it's you know
michelle is very very concerned
to
address the entanglement of
commercialization and and citizen
science
uh and
citizen science you know
is one thing when it's listening to
patients and responding to them
right
and it's another thing when
it's manufacturing claims in the service
of selling you know
uh as much
you know
cbd as you know distill it as you can
and so like these are kind of the the
divergent
situations like one is kind of the
traditional herbal medicine citizen
science
that uh
i think uh you know
ten years ago or eight years ago when
you when you might have met her she was
at the forefront of
certainly uh first analytics lab in
washington state
um
a naturopathic doctor
uh
and then kind of this explosion of all
these claims that get made
that are
that have a lot of issues but the
primary one is that they're incentivized
by essentially the supply chain and
marketing
especially around cbd
um
and so these this can be problematic for
several reasons one is just like
taking an anecdote and like you know
uh turning it into a law of nature right
uh and saying this will always help
everyone
just buy this cbd you know that you
could get your
gas station
right uh
um and the delta eight and everything
else that's going to gas stations
um
so there are those claims made that are
bastardizations of citizen science
uh and i think i'm doing uh um
i think i'm doing her chapter service by
by by clarifying this that there are
those claims that that
they come out of a tradition of you know
healing and patient-centric
you know uh clinical observational
research in particular
uh that was not possible under
conditions of prohibition
just prohibition not just prohibition
with uh legalization right
um
and then there is essentially the you
know commercial incentive to take those
claims and completely divorce them
from the intimate social relationships
that characterize you know uh
traditional herbal medicine
right
and so
this is i think absolutely
a fantastic intervention that could have
gone in the public health section
but we chose to put it in to the culture
and social change section
because
it's it's it's about to me
this this cultural difference between
like the commercialization cult
basically cultures of commercialization
and cultures of care patient-centric
care
right so
citizen science is both
something that helps
and also something
that others have bastardized basically
to make a bunch of money off of
and so
that to me makes it an incredibly
important chapter uh because
what happens is a backlash and i think
you're seeing it a lot actually and you
will see more of it
and the backlash is from you know
policymakers and and health researchers
who instantly see through essentially
the the commercialization of these
claims
but they don't really
also understand that that that
the citizen science actually has been
doing a lot of important work on the
ground so they discount
really the traditional herbal medicine
thing and and hits their wagons to like
the
pharmaceuticalization of of of cannabis
entirely right yeah it feels safer to
them yeah yeah i feel safer they're like
herbal medicine like that's a joke you
know like look at these cbd companies
uh you know uh and so like
you know michelle shares their distastes
but doesn't have that distaste for
actual like you know
herbal medicine she's she's a
naturopathic doctor
and so like in many ways it's to
preserve the integrity of
actually you know the entire
you know tradition of verbal medicine
herbal traditional mission which is
finally be becoming recognized in the
united states in the last 30 years
as something that's actually valid
but still is kind of seen as you know
um
not scientific right because it's not uh
it's not working with molecules and
standardizations
uh as opposed to herbal medicine which
can work with like the whole plant and
actually address
differences in people's you know body
chemistry
that actually standardizing medicine is
a terrible idea
uh from a certain perspective
because everybody's bodies are different
right uh and so
uh it's a really really crucial
intervention um and and i hope to see
more of it but
it's really kind of this like
we don't want
cannabis to become snake oil
right like like when it comes down to it
and snake oil is all about marketing
over
you know safety
um
but safety is not defined by
pharmaceutical procedures like uh that
is something that is part of the the
herbal tradition as well
so i
if dr sexton is listening to this i hope
i've i've done her chapter
uh you know the kind of service it
deserves it's a crucial intervention
well it's also great it was i was very
happy to see dr michelle sexton's
chapter in the book uh
uh for for a host of reasons but but
what i like is that she's always been a
friend to the patient first
you know she has been involved you know
advising
different uh companies in cannabis and
and of course she's been working with
cannabis as an herbalist for uh for a
very long time
and even myself you know with with with
michelle and i being allies and and
having very similar agendas she would
often catch me and say well you know
shango you're kind of overstating what
we know about cannabis based on your
anecdotal you know
uh conversations with um with patients
and and sometimes that would frustrate
me but then then i had to come back to
to what's real and realize that you know
um you know relying too much on hype is
where we get into these problems
and um you know if dr michelle sexton is
anything she is anti-hype so
so yeah
i'm uh i am grateful for the chapter and
her participation as well
yeah
so dominic thank you so much for your
time um again congratulations on the
release of of this collection you edited
with uh joshua mizell the routledge
handbook of post-prohibition cannabis
research um uh where can folks get the
book
so first of all let me actually because
i haven't yet in this interview i want
to
express my profound gratitude
towards my partner in this project uh
josh
myself humble state university
sociologist uh
he was he's been just a we've been a
dream team together and we're doing a
lot of other things together too uh so
i just i'm so grateful for his
friendship and and
collaboration uh and
he deserves a lot of credit uh as well
and so
i want to make sure that i don't don't
leave him out but
uh so
the other thing is of course is that
you can buy the handbook on amazon you
can buy it on routledge.com routledge is
a global academic publisher
this is the hardback version right now
there's going to be a a soft cover
that's going to be much less expensive
the book is you know uh part of the the
routledge handbook series which is sold
to
universities around the globe basically
and so that's a price that
is essentially reflecting the
the you know business model of routledge
which is that universities are you know
institutions and they're gonna pay more
for books
and so and then there's also obviously
an electronic document which is also
often very good for universities to
to get because then they can their
students can use it
this is the kind of handbook that is
going to have a much wider appeal though
and a bigger audience
and so i recognize that and i want to
make sure that
folks don't feel like they're you know
economically squeezed out because of the
the you know
at 25 off 200 uh price of the hardcover
there will be a soft cover we'll be out
you know in a few months
and uh you know
uh strongly encourage folks who are
not you know particularly wealthy
you know not to go out of their way uh
and get the expensive one but the the
cheaper one will be available
right um well dominick thank you so much
uh both both i appreciate your
friendship and our very long time
working together uh every time you join
us here on shaping fire or on my prior
uh podcast um you always bring the truth
and uh and i really appreciate that you
don't let yourself get um
you know cut up in the cut up in all the
excitement in the hoo-ha and you're
always telling me well shango it's not
as simple as that
we need to look at this in a more
complex way so so i i very much
appreciate you and and and thank you for
joining us on shaping fire today
thank you shango i am absolutely proud
of uh
of uh your program and listen to it
regularly and
just uh it's been a pleasure and an
honor knowing him and look forward to a
long and
wonderful friendship right on thank you
brother so if you want to find out more
about uh dominic corva and his work you
can go to
cannabisandsocialpolicy.org which is the
website for his non-profit research
group
also
i can refer you all the way back i
didn't have to write this in my notes
episode one
of shaping fire all about um cannabis
policy transfer from state to state
essentially
um how it works that uh state policies
in one state uh get transferred to
another state uh for better or for worse
and uh and of course the book um uh
whether or not you want to get the
hardcover now or whether or not you want
to wait and get the the softcover
electronic versions um there will be a
link to that on amazon um on the page
for this episode on shaping fire.com
you can find more episodes of the
shaping fire podcast and subscribe to
the show at shapingfire.com and wherever
you get your podcasts if you enjoyed the
show we'd really appreciate it if you
leave a positive review of the podcast
wherever you download your review will
help others find the show so they can
enjoy it too on the shaping fire website
you can also subscribe to the newsletter
for insights into the latest cannabis
news exclusive videos and giveaways on
the shaping fire website you'll also
find transcripts of today's podcast as
well be sure to follow on instagram for
all original content not found on the
podcast that's at shaping fire and at
changolos on instagram be sure to check
out shapingfire youtube channel for
exclusive interviews farm tours and
cannabis lectures
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at
shippingfire.com to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire i've been
your host shango los
[Music]
you