[Music]
it was the summer of 2017 when I first
experienced autoflowering cannabis I was
standing in the fields with Seth and
Eric Crawford of Oregon's CBD seeds
looking at gorgeous and fabulously
smelling acres and acres of cannabis
that was ready to harvest in the
beginning of September my regular plants
at home had another six weeks left to
flower six weeks that would leave me in
the face of October rains but these
fields in front of me were finished and
ready to be cut and dried
that is when I first understood the
potential for OTO flowers then in the
summer of 2018 I grew my first OTO
flower seeds and spent the entire run
realizing the major impact that these
seeds were gonna have on home growing
and the industry as a whole over the
next 10 years
finally solid cultivars of OTO flowers
were available and I knew that home
growers patients and some commercial
growers were going to be astonished when
they had a chance to trial them by
September my OTO flowers were out of the
ground dried and in jars well ahead of
the rains my regular photo period seeds
were in the greenhouse still and
preparing for the harsh October cold
then it emerald cup last year I found
myself standing with Jeff Lowen Fell's
chatting about how I thought autos were
gonna change the face of homegrown and
Jeff smiled and said that he agreed and
that in fact as a gardening columnist
for over 40 years
he saw Auto flowers as the new tomato
plant that these new auto flower
varieties were the threshold moment
where cannabis cultivation made the
cross over to regular folks and that
Jeff had written a book about them Jeff
and I each looked at each other like we
shared a secret that was going to excite
everybody I went home and programmed an
entire year of Auto flower content for
2019 a shaping fire live on Auto flowers
at cultivation classic a Vimeo meeting
focused on Auto flowers for Canada's
patients standing room only presentation
on Auto flowers I did at endo
though and a slew of videos helping
shine some light on Auto flower breeders
and to get the message out that Auto
flowers had grown up this episode of
shaping fire is the last of the
autoflowering program I put together for
2019 and it's beautiful because it
brings me full circle to where I started
this cycle with Jeff if you want to
learn about cannabis health business and
technique efficiently and with good
cheer I encourage you to subscribe to
our newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter there's nothing else you
need to do to win except receive that
newsletter so go to shaping fire com2
sign up for the newsletter and be
entered into this month's and all future
newsletter prize drawings you are
listening to shaping fire and I'm your
host Shango 'lose today my guest is
gardening columnist and lord of the
roots Jeff low in Fell's jeff has been
an award-winning gardening columnist for
over 40 years he is a recovering
attorney who fell in love with plants he
is author of the seminal teaming series
of teaming with microbes teeming with
nutrients and teaming with fungi his new
book DIY autoflowering cannabis an easy
way to grow your own comes out today
today Jeff and I are gonna talk about
how Auto flowers are going to
revolutionize home grow welcome to the
show Jeff always a pleasure to be here
how are you doing today oh it's
absolutely fantastic here we've been
getting a lot of rain here which
concerns everybody who's growing in the
Pacific Northwest but we've gotten three
days of Sun so everybody's sitting in a
little bit of false hope yeah well
hopefully hopefully it'll come true yeah
totally is that actually that will play
into today's topic really well so
congratulations on your new book out
today on Auto flowers I am so excited
it's such a such a departure from what I
normally do but it was it was just one
of those things I just felt I had to do
and so it's out today you can get it on
Amazon you should be able to get it at
bookstores
we'll see I don't know it's hard to say
what the distributions gonna be you
never know it's a cannabis book and of
course there's still that stigma you
know but but people people uh taking a
look at this tell me that maybe this
book's gonna help lift that stigma a
little bit so we hope so let's see well
as someone who's already had an
opportunity to read it I think it's
fantastic I think it not only will
increase or decrease the stigma but
increase the number of people dabbling
in cannabis which is which is really fun
right because up to this point you've
had to have a certain amount of hutzpah
to get into cannabis and to grow it
either because it was illegal and you're
gonna have to go through all this hiding
stuff or if it was illegal in your state
to grow a few plants you had to feel
especially confident in I don't know in
your right in your right to do that
right because even though something
might be legal to grow you still might
get shamed by your family or neighbors
or whatever and so I think your your
book helps create support for those
people who just want to grow plants
really and then and that's that's really
the genesis of the book you know you
know me I'm so-called Lord of the roots
I write books about soil and and you
know the science behind how things grow
organically and and all of a sudden
here's a book on autoflowering cannabis
maybe I ought to mention the name it's a
DIY autoflowering cannabis a new way to
grow and so so why did I write this book
you know it was sort of one of these
crazy things that just doesn't seem to
be in character what people don't know
is that I also write a garden column and
I was invited to speak at the Garden
Writers of America oh gosh he must have
been six or seven years ago and and and
it was the first talk on cannabis that
this organization's had these are the
radio people the TV people and newspaper
and magazine people etcetera and so I
gave this talk about how I thought
cannabis was the next tomato and and the
talk was fine and people walked away
with a lot of excitement about CBD but
it didn't have the impact that I thought
I would
hoping it would have because I really I
really think that cannabis is a fun
plant to grow I know it is a fun plant
to grow anybody who's tried it knows
it's a fun plant to grow it can be a
little bit challenging but it's a great
plant to grow and if you're a gardener
and you like horticulture this is a
terrific plant well you know one of the
reasons it didn't it it didn't take off
as a subject is because these plants are
hard to grow they require a tremendous
amount of space to start with and most
gardeners don't have a lot of space
they're in a condo they have a deck you
know they have a small vegetable garden
when you say when you say these plants
you mean traditional cannabis plants
right yes exactly exactly so that so
that's why one of the reasons why I
don't think garden writers took to this
the second reason is is that these
plants require a photo period in other
words as anybody who's growing these
plants know they have to have the
traditional plants they have to have
more than 12 hours of darkness before
they will begin to flower now that
causes very little problem in lots of
places but in many places particularly
Northern Hemisphere places and I guess
if you're on this south of the southern
hemisphere places
you you know you don't get that period
of darkness until things begin to get
very cool so if you live in Anchorage
Alaska on September 21st when we have 12
hours of daylight and 12 hours of
darkness we also usually have a frost
well you know it takes another six or
seven weeks for that plant to flower and
those flowers that develop etcetera so
it's very hard to grow cannabis and I
and I became convinced that's why it
wasn't taking off in states where it was
legal low and behold my good friend Tom
Alexander the very same guy who told me
about the the fungus protecting a tomato
root from a nematode trying to attack it
which started my whole adventure into
the soil food web and began the whole
series of books and everything else
shows me some plants that he's going
called Otto flower plants now you know
we all know about all the flower plants
we've heard about them before they were
discovered you know and bred and finally
in around 1970 or so people started to
release these little things called low
rider plants and they were cute little
things and they didn't have a photo
period like the big guys did and they
were tiny you could grow them in little
6-inch pots
whoa so that was sort of exciting but
the but the cannabis that they produce
was low in THC and very the plants were
small cute novelty you know a lot of fun
to show people but not not something
really that you would grow to harvest I
was fast forward to when Tom showed me
these Auto flowers about five or six
years ago they were decent sized tomato
sized plants and they were without
question producing cannabis that was
usable and I started to grow them and
fool around with them and lo and behold
every time you you grew one it was a
better plant because the breeding on
these things has has just multiplied
like crazy and because of interests in
the in getting a plant that is available
for everybody there's been a tremendous
amount of work put into producing seeds
that produce plants that meet all the
requirements you would want to have for
growing this plant as a hobby plant home
gardener not a cannabis producer but a
home gardener your aunt your uncle your
mother you know your brother and sister
who don't like cannabis but love to grow
tomatoes and cucumbers and zucchini
boom these are Oh flowers now are at
that point and so just because you know
I've got a lot of a lot of friends who I
think would really love it I I sat down
and wrote a book and it's not the same
kind of book as the teimi book it's very
easy it's very light if you are a
commercial grower this is not a book for
you this is a book for Uncle Bob and
Aunt Sally at Christmastime so that they
can learn about cannabis and then learn
about autoflowering cannabis and the
opportunities that it presents
I can certainly imagine that this book
is gonna be under a lot of Christmas
trees this year and when you were
talking about Utah your your
presentation a few years back at the
Gardeners Association you said that you
know it wasn't immediately picked up and
embraced by the the writers and other
media people are there and you said
primarily you thought because of the
size of cannabis plants and of course it
was the the plant itself was still very
much in in legal prohibition transition
at that time but my question for you is
very specifically because you know that
your your your whole your book is all
about normalizing cannabis gardening
right and and as somebody who's been
writing a garden column for over 40
years and and you know you've won awards
and you're very successful at that what
is it about gardening columnist which
causes them to have to kind of err on
the conservative side you know I don't
really I don't know the answer to it but
but I bet you do yeah I do it's fear and
it's fear of your publisher which is you
know pretty easy to overcome you just go
ask your publisher whether it's okay for
you to write about cannabis it's it's
fear of your readership turning their
back on you you know a lot of times that
when I think about my my core readership
I think you know is and I'm I really
shouldn't be saying this but I'm gonna
say you know me I think you know the
little old lady in tennis sneakers and
and she's somebody who once wants me to
be writing about cannabis or should I be
writing about Mary goals and you know
how to harvest your potatoes so so it's
fear and Corey and then of course
there's that there's that that
possibility you know that that that you
say something that somehow gets you in
trouble with the law you know either
it's illegal in your state or you you
make a suggestion you know somehow it
doesn't fit with a regulation so so for
example in Washington State it's against
I think it's still against law you tell
me - no maybe it's not there's no
there's no homegirl here ya know
that's what I was gonna say and in New
York State when they were trying to pass
you know Governor Cuomo got convinced by
boy I'm gonna get you know slammed it on
this one
you know by madmen to not let people
grow their own plants you know so you
know there's there's there's the stigma
about and I'm gonna say the word I hate
it
marijuana you know when you hear the
word marijuana you know you're talking
to somebody that has a stigma about
cannabis because it's a disgusting word
from my perspective it's a you know it's
like putting a statue up to Harry
Anslinger who use that word to turn the
public against this drug and and this
medicine and this wonderful recreational
thing so yeah it's a big stigma there so
and I remember when I wrote my first
column on cannabis I always just tell
people you when you read my columns if
I'm writing about tomatoes you can apply
that you can apply that knowledge to
cannabis but but all of a sudden it was
fully legalized in Alaska and it's been
legal here since 1975 in the privacy of
your home but it became fully legalized
medical and recreational and I wrote a
column and I asked my readers are you
gonna be upset about this and boy oh boy
people were just thrilled they were just
thrilled about it because you know I
think deep down in you can be you can be
pro Trump anti Trump you could be Pro
you know any one of the Democratic
candidates and whatever deep down in all
of us understand that the ability to be
able to grow a plant is a basic human
right and they've taken it away from us
in so many places and and we want it
back and we're getting it back and now
we have to now we have to use it
properly and so anyway that's a little
bit of a short box stuff right there so
so let's talk about the the the the
little grandma in the tennis sneakers
that you're referring to so so so
clearly those of us in the cannabis
scene we love the idea of promotion of
cannabis because in most cases it's our
favorite plant but then but but but your
audience that you're speaking to this
time with your book you
your audience are people who primarily
love gardening and the love of cannabis
may be new to them either because
they're you they've they're spending a
lot of money on topicals and they want
to make their own or they fall in love
with tinctures or or hell maybe they've
just decided that they they're in there
you know they've gotten over the taboo
and they love puffins in their home
whatever their reason you're speaking to
this new audience of cannabis
enthusiasts and I would think that what
you're hearing from them about why
they're excited about the plant is often
different about what you hear from
cannabis people about why they're
excited about the plant and so I'm
curious what what kind of unique things
are you hearing from gardeners about
your introduction of cannabis and OTO
flowers that is different than what you
are getting from growers stoners like me
sure well first of all I've sort of
tested this over the whole you know I
don't I don't go out and just write a
book willy-nilly I got to do a little
bit of research and then I make the rest
of the stuff up but just kidding of
course but you know I so I talked to
gardeners in the Anchorage area right
where I live and about the fact that it
was legal and now they could grow plants
and and they were all trying to grow
regular regular plants what happens with
gardeners is we get bored you know it's
you can grow a tomato year in and year
out and get great tomatoes it's boring
it's too easy and so what we look for
are new things to grow let's start with
new techniques every now and then come
along but what we really look for are
new things to grow and you and I've
talked about this before I remember and
maybe ear old enough to remember when
the snap pea was introduced to the
American gardener oh my god people went
nuts you know and and snap peas are now
do-rag or hero snap peas in your garden
they're easy to grow but I blab that it
tastes great you can use them stir fry
and you know so so people grow snap peas
you know tomatoes people bored with
tomatoes got into heirlooms why do they
get into heirlooms because though it was
different it was exciting it was it was
a way to introduce new
plants to your to your palette and and
and so all of a sudden you get legalized
cannabis and people who are really into
gardening who can get their hands on
either a clone or seed they grow a plant
and whether that whether they're
successful in getting a harvest or not
they are excited about growing that
cannabis plant all the way through to
wherever they get because for the true
gardener it's not the harvest it's not
the tomato it's not the marigold flower
you know that that you that makes
gardening terrific it's the process you
know it's it's it's watching the plant
grow and develop and and it's the beauty
of understanding you know that there are
cells being added because you because
there are microbes down on the soil at
our feet you know there's a beauty to it
all that's that that transcends just at
one moment where you pick the tomato you
know or you take the tomato over to your
neighbor and brag about it you know it's
the process of growing that makes
gardening fun and and cannabis is a fun
plant to grow it's it's it's got a lot
of distinct stages and when you when you
then go to an auto flowering plant the
fun becomes compressed into the same
length of time that it takes to grow a
tomato the plant itself is small you can
grow it in a five-gallon bucket you
watch it go literally from seed to
harvest in seven to nine weeks it
flowers or it it shows whether it's
gonna be a male or a female
oh isn't that incredible I never get a
phone call and then all of a sudden you
end up with a plant that you can't take
your eyes off on because it's growing
new leaves every day is getting bigger
literally every day I almost compare it
to growing a giant pumpkin they put on
40 pounds a night forty pounds a night
well when you watch an autoflowering
cannabis grow you go to bed you get up
the next morning and it's bigger don't
we'll be so measurably so that's an
exciting thing to have happen and then
you add on to that what you and I know
that is that that this is just one kind
of Auto flower cannabis plant
there's cannabis or plants that
definitely do all sorts of things like
CBD production or THC production you can
get different colors you can expose them
to cold cooler temperatures they turn
purple you know they're there they can
become a landscape plant you can put
them around your you know your yard your
walkways you know on your deck they're a
terrific plant on on top of being a
cannabis plant so Wow
it made for a great subject book
fantastic well how about this Jeff why
don't we address that that call coming
in on your side and take a short break
right now
we'll be right back you're listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is Lord
of the routes Jeff Lowenthal's
cultivators who grow in living soil are
very particular on what inputs they use
in their soil they educate themselves
and painstakingly create compost and
nutritive teas to create thriving soils
that will produce the very best
expression of the cannabis plant many
living soil farmers now believe that
over time seeds become acclimated to the
kind of substrate they are grown in for
example a seed that was bred and
synthetic fertilizers may not
immediately know what to do in a living
soil environment slowing their growth
and decreasing yield the regenerative
seed cooperative is a different kind of
seed bank the regenerative seed
cooperative only provide cannabis seeds
that were bred in living soil and using
probiotic growing techniques that way
when you germinate in soil the seeds
genetics will recognize the environment
and immediately start interacting with
microbes and fungal networks these seeds
are described as bio intelligent the
number of cannabis breeders
participating in the regenerative seed
cooperative is rapidly increasing
already signed on our bamboos stalk and
bean pacific northwest roots ello s
Gardens dragonfly earth medicine ital
foundation Bob hemp hills cricket and
cicada Dutch blooms heart Rock Mountain
Farms pride of Lyon Sebring seeds and
Mount Baker highway with more being
every month these seeds are regulars
Otto flowers and hemp varieties a
significant amount of the profits go to
cannabis seed preservation projects
available to everyone do you want to
take every advantage that you can when
growing in beautiful healthy soil then
consider buying your seeds from the
regenerative seed cooperative at
regenerative seeds calm
that's regenerative seeds calm did you
know that shaping fire has a fabulous
YouTube channel with content not found
on the podcast when I attend conventions
or speak or moderate panels I always
record them and bring the content home
for you to watch the Shango Losey
youtube channel it has world-class
speakers including kevin Jodrey of
wonderland nursery talking about
breeding cannabis for the best terpene
profile nicholas Mahmud on regenerative
and polyculture cannabis growing dr.
Sunil a girl on the history of cannabis
medicine around the world Ben Cassidy of
true terpenes on using terpenes for
health in your everyday life Reggie
Godinho of steep hill on the cannabis
genome and Jeff Lowen Fell's on the soil
food web
there are several presentations from dr.
Ethan Russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system and even my own
presentation on how to approach finding
your dream job in cannabis and why we
choose canvas business even though the
risks are so high as of today there are
over 100 videos that you can check out
for absolutely free go to youtube.com
forward slash Shango lohse or click on
the link in this week's newsletter
welcome back you're listening to shaping
fire I'm your host Shango low sent our
guest this week is gardening author Jeff
Lowen fellows so during the first set we
talked a lot about your motivations for
the book and who the book is for and and
actually some really pretty poetic stuff
about the the enjoyment of gardening
that I'll share I'm sorry about that no
no that's good I think that's good and I
think that really speaks to the heart of
your book right this book really is for
people who are in love with plants
generally and to kind of encourage
people who are in love with plants and
gardening to come on over and and and
and start to share in the experience of
the black sheep of the family
in cannabis so so let's give people a
little bit of background on where Otto
flowers came from you know
clearly used we started the episode
talking about the 1970s and lowrider but
but I've heard you give your talk on
Auto flowers and and and you talking
about where they came from is kind of
exotic sure yeah so there was a
scientist he was working in the Volga
River area I guess that's in their Urals
and in Russia and and he he noticed
these little little teeny cabbage plants
and and he looked at him and he studied
them a little bit and sure enough he
identified them as a new kind of
cannabis which he called ruderalis and
which which apparently means ruble
because these things grew in these
little rubble a terrible soil areas and
what he noticed about him and the rear
and what really caught his attention was
that unlike regular cannabis these
particular plants bloomed before the
other ones did way before the other ones
did and and when he did his research he
discovered that in fact they were not
influenced by a photo period in other
words the the the triggering event for
flowering is is increased darkness
beyond 12 hours they bloomed because of
genetics so it didn't matter what the
daylight was or the darkness these
things bloomed and set a set period
apparently they came from the they were
escapees from hemp plantations and you
know they they escaped and because of
evolution they they you know they
figured out that if they didn't seed
right away they before the frost they
weren't gonna make it and so so they
they bred into themselves this genetic
disposition the flower as opposed to
having the normal photo period flowering
so so that happened you know I mean it
was it was of interest but really nobody
could breed them to do anything that
made any sense and and it really wasn't
until the 1970s when
bunch of stoner guys frankly you know
started fooling around with them 60s I
guess obviously and and I think I think
when they came out in 1971 it was a
little bit early they were just there
was just a novelty plant nobody ever
thought they were going to be any good
now again you know you know cannabis
growers they like to breed things and so
so people continually bred them not only
with each other with but with their
cousins the bigger sativas and indicas
but also different ruderalis because you
can find ruderalis all around the world
it turns out so the particular ruderalis
that is in theory the one used for the
lowrider is said to have come from
either Finland or Mexico which I found
to be shocking because I thought oh
there must be in some they must be in a
cold climate but no ruderalis in Mexico
there ruderalis in Alaska there
ruderalis all over so you breed them
with different different ruderalis you
breed them with different different
bigger parents and you end up with
different kinds of of autoflowering
cannabis plants one of the things that
you mentioned in your your live
presentation about autos is is how
ruderalis are the really only cannabis
variety that really thrives in really
crappy low nutrient environments and I
find that really interesting because not
only does it show the the vigor to live
that are in these genetics but you also
then go and caution people to not feed
them like they would a regular cannabis
plant we break that out a bit for us
sure they they do the the one hat one
set of the parents do grow in very poor
conditions they grow very quickly
they've they've adapted to be able to
get what they need from a soil food web
perspective in other words they're
actually its produce the right stuff to
get the right bacteria and fungi and
they quickly they quickly take up
nutrients and they and they are capable
of
being a very rapid pace of growth by
taking up their nutrients without any
help whatsoever from anybody now you
know we tend to forget that this is a
plant that we call weed and the reason
we call it weed is twofold one it grows
anywhere in theory and two it grows
quickly like a weed
well autoflowering cannabis is the weed
of weeds it really grows quickly and it
can grow anywhere what I've discovered
and I think other growers as well is
that if you feed these plants it messes
them up at least at least initially they
they have everything they need in that
seed if you if you put them in decent
soil living soil you're gonna get a
great plant if you feed that soil all
manner of nutrients as people tend to do
when they're growing cannabis you you
end up with a plant that's that's
confused that can adjust properly and
and they burn quickly they grow spindly
and you lose you lose the essence of
that great ruderalis that makes this
such an easy plant to grow I think this
is probably one of the reasons why so
many
I guess growers who've been growing for
a while have yet more reasons that they
personally don't like OTO flowers
because you know people work long and
hard to come up with their recipe for
growing and autos don't really fit in
most people's recipes they they really
do enjoy benign neglect like in a
perfect environment you'd have a no-till
pot that's already set up and you put
your seed in there and then you forget
about it and then you come back when
it's time to harvest and that freaks
people out yeah yeah it is pretty
amazing and you can see one of the
reasons why it was developed I mean you
know if you were if you were a
clandestine grower you know you could
grow these things under your under your
stairs without ever having to go in and
look at them you know you put an
automatic watering system in you leave
you leave the lights on
our 24 hours holy crow you know you
don't have to do anything to them you
don't even have to give them darkness
well that that that makes for pretty
exciting you know yeah time whoo so yeah
so these plants really are so easy to
grow that it does frustrate the
professional grower a little bit you
know they turn their nose up at them
they're you know by the same token a lot
of professional growers use their
current system to grow these things and
they don't do well and then they
badmouth the auto flower plant which I
have to have to tell listeners are now
becoming a normally used plant in many
commercial grows both hemp I should say
all hemp CBD and THC in Oregon the main
breeder of these seeds only sells now to
commercial growers and you know the
reason is is because they come out so
uniform right good seeds are right
because that that is one of the
challenges with auto flower seeds at
this point is you get a lot of different
fee knows in one pack generally but the
people at the top of the auto flower
game you know this is not true for all
seeds the top the top right seeds will
all be exactly the same in uniform but I
would say that that is a very small
fraction at the very top when most
everybody I mean this summer we popped a
lot of Auto flower seeds on Vashon and
we would get you know three footers and
5-footers out of the same pack right
yeah and I think I think part of that
has to do with the fact that they are so
easy to grow and so what you've got are
a lot of people who are who are buying
seeds in them and then further selling
them on so you got middlemen selling
seeds you know and and they don't know
what they are no and really you know
they haven't tested them etc etc now you
and I both know that that there are
companies that have perfected their seed
breeding programs and you can find most
of these companies I don't think we want
to give too many names
but I you can find these companies by
going on to the internet
autoflowering network.com
or is it auto flowering or no flower
Netcom has a whole bunch of discussion
threads about seed companies and which
ones are good and which ones aren't and
the companies themselves are represented
there and so that is the one area I
think needs to improve sort of
chicken-and-egg I wrote a book about
about a plant that you might have
difficulty getting seeds you know at
your local seed store yeah that's for
sure
and for the record it's auto flower
dotnet oh good yeah totally yeah it's
funny for being so simple it's really
easy to throw extra words in there but
it is a terrific site if anybody even
the inkling of interest in these plants
this is the place to go after you bought
the book because you will get all of the
bud porn that you're accustomed to all
of the ranting and raving z' of
technique and flushing not flushing that
you're used to you know it's just but
it's on auto flowers and I gotta say
that you know auto flower dotnet was
formed because the auto flower folks got
harassed and laughed out of so many of
the grower forums then they just went
and and did their own and you can still
feel that because the community is very
kind and I actually find that all across
the whole auto flower scene the people
who are growing them the people who are
breeding the seeds you know the the
green rush really hasn't come to auto
flowers yet and so people are very
modest and kind and you know the thirst
jerks in every scene right but but
overall I really enjoy being a part of
the auto flower scene because it it's
not as cutthroat as some of the other
cannabis industry let me put it in the
vernacular of the book it's because
people who grow auto flowers are
gardeners and gardeners share they share
information we'll talk about it later on
they share food you know that gardeners
share it's when you get into the
commercial world and you you know that
your
you want to get competitive that you
stop sharing and you stop being a
gardener and you start becoming a farmer
well you know well maybe don't share
quite as much as gardeners do but I
think that's a hallmark of gardening and
and I'm hopeful that gardeners who are
capable of growing these plants and have
seeds will share them and etc etc
because it's it's that's what gardeners
do perfectly right on so let's talk a
little bit about the growing of the
plant and some of the uniquenesses that
come with growing a plant that grows so
fast so right so I dropped in briefly
that that you know the plant loves to be
germinated in its soil because it's got
such a short life it doesn't like to be
trans transplanted very much because the
the momentary stress actually takes a
significant part of its of its lifetime
but I also said that it likes to be put
into a pot that's already been grown in
and has not been not fresh soil so what
we think of as no-till and and what I'd
like you to talk about is you know not a
lot of people use no-till techniques yet
people are still of the mind that you
have to use fresh potting soil with with
every new grow but at the same time the
mycorrhizal fungi that you need to form
to move nutrients around the pot barely
have time to form in the entire lifetime
of an auto flower plant and so how do
these plants I mean we you know we both
seen the flowers the flowers can be as
as large as your forearm they're huge :
or not they're not lacking in size how
is this plant doing so much in soil that
for most people it was what we would
consider new soil yeah well first of all
let's talk about that the concept of
throwing your soil away every time you
grow plant and then and then starting
over again you know that's that's old
school as far as I'm concerned for a
couple of reasons not the least of which
it's not regenitive it's not sustainable
at work you know we
we're losing soil like no one's business
in this world and
and we gotta be we got it we got to keep
it and we got to maintain it so but so
so what happens when you grow a plant is
it you know the root system develops it
drips out all these extra dates it
attracts the kinds of micro Rises are
you not migrate them well it attracts
both mycorrhizal fungi but it also
attracts you know the bacteria and the
other kinds of fungi that it needs in
order to be able to feed itself doesn't
matter what kind of plant it is that's
just the way plants work that's teeming
with microbes and and so this particular
plant when you plant it does just like
every other plant does all of these
things when you plant it in brand-new
soil it it it it has to create its own
growth channels it has to really scream
loudly to these to these microbes to get
in into the zone and you know it really
has to do do some work to establish the
kind of environment that it needs in
order to be able to feed itself when you
plant in a pot that's already had a
cannabis plant growing in it the
microbes that support cannabis are
already in that pot they're just dormant
they're there in the right numbers
immediately you don't have to you know
you don't have to attract them you don't
have to gather them together and this is
all shorthand for you know what happens
is the right microbes have to take out
the bad microbes so that the right
balance is there's all of this stuff has
already happened in your previous grow
and as important the roots of the plant
have an opportunity to grow in the
channels left by the old root channel
system and so it's easier for not only
is it easier for them but there are
decaying or carbon-containing old roots
in those channels that are helping to
feed and maintain those microbial
populations that are supporting the
plant so so for that
reason it makes sense to grow almost any
kind of a plant in a pot that's had a
similar plant growing in it previously
did you trust that before you go on did
you just say that there's karma left in
the roots okay well there's karma and
carbon/carbon okay carve it all right I
like the idea of karma though but it is
karma I mean you know that's what that's
what that's what makes the plants grow
it's that carbon you know
carbon is karma you don't have carbon
you don't have karma you don't have life
so anyway so then you take a plant that
has genetically developed to grow
quickly Wow you know well if you give
that plant what it needs from the get-go
it gets going
so we plant these things we you can
start them at using you know the paper
towel trick etc etc and I and I do I do
most of mine that way for one simple
reason because I then I dust both the
seed and that brand new root which which
appears incidentally usually within
about 24 hours as opposed to a little
bit longer or almost twice as long with
regular cannabis plants I then sprinkle
a rise of faggus interest CDs which is
the mycorrhizal fungi that feeds
cannabis plants I and so I know I'm
getting the exposure on the roots right
away and then I plant that in the soil
in the pot that I'm gonna grow the plant
in for its entire life these plants
cannot be root bound a root bound plant
while it while they're growing to their
initial to their to their size a root
bound plants we you know as a lot of
problems getting what it needs and you
don't want these plants to be root bound
because they're growing so quickly you
want him to be able to get whatever they
need right away and and so you put them
in a five or seven gallon pot three
gallon minimum and and that's it that's
the pot you want to use and you don't
have to transplant them
every time you transplant a plant you
are destroying root hairs then our that
take a while for the plant to come back
you stress a plant you can you can
stress a plant out it can slow down for
a week or so anytime you transplant it
and when you transplant these and they
lose a week that you're because they
grow so fast that's a significant part
of their life you know it's like being
away while your kids are going through
elementary school and then all of a
sudden you're back you go what happened
you know yeah exactly right he's got to
be there for these guys every single
minute of the day because they're
growing so quickly so Jeff oh sorry yeah
so so so then the other thing of course
is to make sure that you've got the
right soil we've talked about the fact
that you don't want to soil is rich in
nutrients it's great to have a soil
that's been used once before at least
but you gotta have a soil that drains
well any plant needs that these are just
like tomato plants and so in fact hey
guess what the same stuff that you can
use for growing tomatoes you can use for
growing these plants it's got a good
drainage it's gotta have lots of
organics we do not use chemicals on
these plants because we don't use
chemicals on any plants chemicals are
done organic we don't go non-organic we
only use organics because it's good for
the environment and it's because we put
this stuff into our systems so we want
to make sure that they're they're nice
and organic if you have to feed the
plant you wait for the plant to tell you
that it needs something and these plans
well if they need something because
they're growing so quickly you'll see
the sign very quickly and if you get on
it very quickly you you can you can give
them what they need now what would you
feed them with you know you can get a a
you know a good balanced you know I
don't know a two to two or something in
that area type type liquid fertilizer
organic and you can give that to the
plant and and you'll see a different
right away compost tea works very very
very nicely I like a little bacteria
to compost tea on these guys so so you
see some problems you can use that and
you can you always water with compost
tea all that all the way along because
she can't over water with compost tea it
doesn't over feed a plant so there we go
so when we've been talking about these
these fast-growing plants I remember the
first time I came across Otto flowers
and and then you brought it home for me
at Emerald cup when we talked about last
year when when we were talking about how
they go from germination to harvest in
90 days not 90 days of you know flower
but the entire life span and being
finished and being not being light
dependent which means that if you live
somewhere that's got inclement weather
or short summers like the Pacific
Northwest where I live or for goodness
sakes Alaska where you live but but also
you know the New England states and and
far far south of the Equator we all
don't necessarily have enough summer to
grow regular plants but then right
you've grits something like this and you
take an auto flower and you can
germinate on say June 1 and it grows
June July and August and you you harvest
on September 1st well before the rains
like when I first realize that literally
blew my mind because this opens up so
much for for patients and for gardeners
like you're talking about and and for
you know anybody who does not want to
deal with mold and botrytis at the end
of the year
where I'm going with this though is that
I had that mindset at 90 days but then
now there are these new cultivars that
are 60 days and now people are telling
me that they've grown these 30 days
which I have yet to grow but a 30 day
from germination to finish flowers you
know I'm like I can except it's not
gonna be a huge plant but the fact that
it goes through its life spans so
quickly blows me away my question for
you is is how do we get to 90 60 and 30
day varietals when they're all crossed
with rudy' right well there are
different kinds of ruderalis first of
all and so some some ruderalis take
longer bloom than others
and I was stunned to start receiving in
the mail different kinds of ruderalis
sees that people have collected and and
and so that's the first reason the
second reason is of course you're
breeding them with plants that also have
some genetics and and there's something
in some of those plants you know that
impacts the duration of the of the the
growth period so so it's sort of a
double whammy it's something coming from
the from the sativa indica z-- and then
it's the difference in in the genetics
of the ruderalis itself so let's go
ahead and take our second short break
and we come back and do set three we're
gonna talk a little bit about succession
planning from Otto flowers which which
is an interesting idea with cannabis but
also jeff has agreed to talk a little
bit about his background which we
haven't really heard a lot about so
that'll be cool so you are listening to
shaping fire
I'm your host Shingo Lowe's and our
guest this week is gardening author Jeff
Lowen fells we'll be right back living
soil and regenerative cannabis
agriculture are surging in popularity
and to implement these biological
solutions real science education is
vital if you are interested in all
things probiotic growing you will
probably want to attend this year's
science of organic regenerative cannabis
cultivation conference for the third
year in a row co-founders Joshua
Rutherford of Dutch blooms and Leighton
Morrison of Kingdom aquaponics have
lined up an incredible array of
educators with all new content for the
traveling event they're calling it
version 2.0 going deeper down the rabbit
hole this year's teaching staff includes
Elaine Ingham on soil biology Chris
Trump and Wendy Kornberg talking Korean
natural farming Kevin Joe tree on
cannabis genetics Kelly and Josh from
dragonfly earth medicine
Suzanne Wainwright the bug lady chip
Osborne on soil chemistry and many other
thought leaders rotating in and out for
different cities so consult the website
to knows who specifically is coming for
each location there will be a breeding
panel a QA panel with the entire
teaching staff and on Saturday night
there will be a bubble hash discussion
as well joshua has built in significant
informal time for you with the teachers
the teaching staff is just as excited to
work with you
as you are about attending there is also
no advertising during the event the only
vendor booths are for cannabis seed
breeders your tuition is what's paying
the staff so they all be present and
attentive to you not a corporate sponsor
even better the conference is not just
for folks on the west coast humboldt
california is hosting one event for sure
but the show is going on the road to
Vancouver British Columbia Portland
Maine and Whitmore Lake Michigan get out
your pen now because I'm about to give
you the website this is a fabulous
opportunity for you to hear from an
array of nationally recognized top shelf
soil educators all in one place not only
that this isn't just beginner stuff like
you get at most conventions this is an
intensive for people like us who totally
nerd out on the rhizosphere and growing
and living soil and if you attended last
year be assured that this year is not
simply a repeat of last year every
speaker will present different material
than they did last year the website is
regenerative organic cannabis calm
that's regenerative organic cannabis
calm this year tickets will be limited
in a number to preserve the intimate
experience and will only be sold in
advance online
there will be no ticket sales at the
door so don't wait and miss out on your
chance to attend this important
gathering of the regenerative cannabis
community cut through all the
misinformation out there and don't miss
this opportunity to learn real soil
science regenerative organic cannabis
calm cannabis is fun medicine and we
love to celebrate it cannabis connects
people and creates opportunities for new
friendships at the top shop we create
custom cannabis themed jewelry money
clips rolling trays and home furnishings
that I love and they also make great
gifts too i'm ashley Villafranca owner
of the taupe shop I came to cannabis as
a patient seeking an alternative to the
pharmaceuticals being pushed at me for
chronic pain and fibromyalgia I realized
that not only was cannabis a huge help
in controlling my symptoms but I found
cannabis to be wonderfully social too
cannabis makes friends so I took my love
of jewelry design and blended it with my
newfound passion for cannabis and began
handcraft
bracelets earrings and friendship
necklaces and then expanded to many
clips rolling chaise and other home
furnishings all made in sterling silver
14-karat gold
and aluminum so there's something for
everyone's budget I consider it all to
be New Age cannabis fashion and cannabis
couture I invite you to stop by my
website at the Tokyo at the tok shop co
you'll find a wide array of attractive
and fun cannabis items starting at only
10 bucks and if you're fancy there are
very fine luxury pieces as well and I'm
always happy to do custom orders with
your name or a particular theme come
check out my array of items hand stamped
with terpenes cannabinoids and other
cannabis themes that's the top shot see
oh thanks welcome back you are listening
to shaping fire I'm your host shingle
Osan our guest this week is gardening
author Jeff Lowen fellas so last set we
talked a little bit about how the plant
thinks and how best it care for her and
how rare her nutrient intake is one of
the things that we just hinted on before
the commercial was the the fact that she
grows so quickly that you can actually
do multiple rounds during the summer and
and and certainly you can do cannabis
plants end to end or auto flower plants
end to end where you you start something
in May and then you finish it in July
and then go ahead and replant right in
the pot but because succession planning
is so rare in cannabis for photo photo
sensitive plants Jeff I don't think that
a lot of people who grow cannabis only
and not vegetables understand the idea
of secession succession planning that we
get from other quick to bulk crops like
lettuce --is and stuff right so would
you go ahead and explain succession
planning and how it can apply to auto
flowers that you saw that you've got a
rolling harvest throughout the year well
there's there's a couple of ways to
apply it out outdoors if you're a
regular gardener you you know that you
just don't plant a you know a crop of
lettuce or rather
these quick growing things you plant
several of them and there's two ways to
do it one is you wait until your first
crop is finished you plant a second crop
or you wait a couple of weeks after you
put the first crop in and then you plant
the second crop so that you have what's
known as they continue as harvest at the
end of the season and and that's how
lots of people grow lettuce so that they
they have lettuce every every night
instead of just having it all you know
all at once where the Otto flowers you
can do the same thing you can you can
either plant the plant wait for it to
harvest and then plant a new plant in
the same pot or you can get another pot
after two or three weeks and start a new
plants so that you have a rolling
rolling harvest kind of a nice way to go
because it's a sometimes it's sort of a
pain to clean these plants and you know
prepare them for drying it's nice that
maybe maybe extend the process and if
you're an indoor commercial grower you
can use these plants in a similar kind
of sort of quasi succession way if
you're growing in your veg stage you
could put these plants in between your
your bigger the bigger cousins that have
a photo period and similarly once
they're in flower you can do this you
know the bigger cousins are and you go
to the flower stage you can do the same
thing you can either start new ones or
you can finish off your honors but
normally what happens is your Otto's
flower and and are harvested at the same
time you then flip the switch and get
into the flowering stage and on the big
guy so you go from vegetative and it's
it's just sort of neat that you can add
on to your existing harvest either by
repeating the same plant or by using
these plants to supplement what you're
growing elsewhere we all have the
experience of coming up to harvest and
then suddenly having a whole bunch of
plants to dry and trim at the same time
and for folks who are not professionals
you know normally we are hanging the
plants in our living room or our in our
basement or the garage or whatever and
we only have a limited amount of space
that I mean heck some people are drying
in their closets and that's one a thing
that's really great for the home grower
the patient grower the
gartner that if you want to start seeds
this week and next week and the
following week depending on you know
your room maybe amount and make it every
three weeks this idea that you could be
harvesting in you know the beginning of
the July and then the end of July and
then the middle of September and then it
really allows you to be more productive
with less space and also if you live in
a state that only allows four or six
plants and you're gonna bother to stay
within the law it's like okay fine you
know I'm gonna grow my six plants but
I'm gonna do I'm gonna do six four times
this summer instead of six that's caring
the last fall summer and that's all I
get and sure granted and generally the
the plants are still smaller than
full-sized plants but when you add all
the grams and the convenience together
at the end of the summer for most people
it's gonna make a lot more sense to do
this kind of succession planning oh yeah
and you get to grow different kinds of
plants so I you know I don't know about
you but after after a while you know
using the same cannabis week in and week
out like we used to do with during
Prohibition when you you know didn't
have a source of different kinds you
know you it's not the same it's not the
same high it doesn't have the same
effect but being able to have variety oh
yeah that's the waiting you know variety
is the spice of life and so so so the
OTO flowers it's just like Tomatoes I
keep saying this is the next tomato
plant you can grow so many different
kinds you can grow constantly always
have arborist and and so far we've
really really been talking about growing
them outside but they grow indoors in
the wintertime and everybody needs to
have a set of lights in the wintertime
anyhow for their other plants you know
your house plants need need like if
you're a gardener you need a set of
lights I always try to tell people in
America because I write nationally you
need a set of lights in the winter we
all need lights in the winter well
plants need lights in the winter well
you've got lights to grow your other
house plants you can be growing
autoflowering cannabis plants as well
and now that there's enough really good
you know full-spectrum
going lights out there it's gonna you
know the same location that can use
these plans most like up here us up in
the North right it also helps with our
seasonal effectiveness disorder from
lack of Sun for in in two ways the
product itself yeah yeah absolutely
it's fun it's there's so much fun to
grow I mean yeah you know a plant that
you've never seen before
unfurling before your eyes is a thing of
beauty it's uh you know it's oh wow you
know it's a mind-blower and these plants
are mind-blowing and one of the things
that I liked about it is actually one of
the things that some people complain
about it's like okay yeah sometimes the
seeds are you know they maybe they're
stable as far as like her mning but
they're not all the same right you're
gonna get a lot of differents Fino in
the same pack more often than not and
and they express some traits that are
from the ruderalis often though though
you know these generalizations are
certainly not applicable to the entire
you know family of cultivars right right
but after you know growing them this was
my second summer growing them I really
and you know as somebody who loves
cannabis loves the plant is interested
in cannabis botany it was interesting to
see all these different
terpene profiles and and how the plant
presents itself over the last two years
I actually had a grower here on the
island who is a cannabis patient and she
just does a few plants on her deck every
year and you know she grew a set of Otto
flowers in the spring and then she had
her full terms and and when she
harvested or where she was going to
harvest her Otto flowers she sent me
pictures he's like is this is this
smokeable this is this right and the can
and you know it was a particularly
unusual looking canvas plant it was it
was clearly a happy plant with lots of
trichomes
and it smelled great but for those of us
who grow regular plants it would the
plant kind of looked like it was all Fox
tailed and so for
for those of us who have been growing or
while I'll be like third that is a
that's a mutant that's a weird thing but
actually the plant smelled great and was
awesome smoke and it was just expressing
some of these oddities that come from
the Rudy side and so you know was it
necessarily something that you're gonna
want to put in the centerfold of High
Times well maybe maybe not it probably
would have gotten some really difficult
feedback from people but as somebody who
loves to watch nature express itself it
sure as hell is interesting yeah you
know if we could become so accustomed to
blood poured yeah which is which is sort
of meaningless when you think about it I
mean I had so much rather see I loved it
I mean but I'd much rather see a chart
that tells me what the terpene you know
a profile is but and the flavonoid
profile because that tells me what the
beauty of the plant is it's not how the
plant actually everything looks oh but
yes you're right you get some very
strange looking things sometimes and and
you wonder where did that come from and
then you you know you gotta just that's
part of the wonder of these things this
is a plant growing before our eyes
evolving before our eyes you this is
something you would have the capability
of being able to breed yourself you know
it's just this is why I think it's
America's next tomato plant it's just
something that's fun to be with and work
with and grow so and and your friend
your friend you know my I would have
said to your friend don't forget you can
grow these in the winter too
yeah doors by that would give so so Jeff
before we wrap up you know when you and
I did the the 10 video shaping fire
sessions which since this is going to
come out on October 22nd all 10 episodes
are now out and so so you and I got
together and we recorded these and we we
had some time in between videos and and
you were willing to share some of your
background with me because most of us in
cannabis know about you as the the lord
of the roots the writer of the you know
teeming with microbes teeming with fungi
and teeming with nutrients series that
is is you know essential reading and
cannabis which I didn't understand
to later is also essential reading and
gardening but you know for those of us
in cannabis it was it's a holy trilogy
but then you and I got to start talking
and and and I've done enough
introductions for you before that that
when I get to the part where I where I
say that you are you know a recovering
attorney everybody kind of chuckles and
we move on but it wasn't until we talked
that I realized what a serious big
player power attorney you were and at
the same time you were remaining
interesting and gardening so just
because I've never heard this covered
anywhere else will you tell us a little
bit about your your life as an attorney
that was running parallel to your
interest in gardening yeah well I went I
went to law school in Boston and while I
was there I was on a date with a lovely
young lady who happen to be a nurse and
and we were held up I was shot she saved
my life I woke up the next morning she
was there with my glasses in my law
school textbooks and I you know I got
shot in the neck I stumbled out Let's
Get Married you saved my life and she
said no you owe me but yeah okay and
then I said but we're gonna go to
Anchorage in Alaska and so we ended up
in Anchorage Alaska and I I had a law
degree and I always had a hobby
gardening but when I got to Anchorage
Alaska I was practicing law I discovered
that the local newspapers were both
published by different publishers and
one of them was a but they were both
printed by one publisher and distributed
by one publisher he handled all the
advertising long story short we had a
good paper and we had a really bad paper
and in a place like Alaska where we were
getting all of our news two or three
days late because we were so far away
and they had to fly the videos up etc
etc and no satellites back then you know
it was important to keep the newspaper
alive and we did and I helped quite a
bit and the publisher asked me what else
I could do and I said I can write a
garden column and so I started to write
a garden column as a way to help this
newspaper but also as a way to fulfill
my fee
the obligation to write a letter a week
to my parents back in New York and my
father's a big gardener and so I would
always write about gardening and so the
column who sort of became a letter home
to my father and then it became a
unbelievable legal tool I was an
assistant attorney general I was going
in and out of court on temporary
restraining orders all the time I was
doing a really high power oil and gas
stuff involving Exxon and BP and so hyoe
and you know all these big oil companies
that deal up in Alaska I was
representing the state and I was I had
the ability to be able to go in and you
know I needed to get a judge again on
this calendar or her calendar you know
and the secretary would always say oh
before what am I to do about my African
violet over here you know so it became a
a really great legal tool and and I
remember my first case in the Supreme
Court of the state of Alaska against
these oil companies sent their lawyers
up from all over the really high power
attorneys my first time in the Supreme
Court and the first question mr. Lowe in
Fell's my wife wants to know what does
she do about and you could see the ex
Secretary of Army who was representing
Exxon understand exactly what had just
happened to him I was an assistant
attorney general first for FiberNet for
six years back in the day when Alaska
didn't really have any Attorney
General's and so I represented all sorts
of terrific agencies ended up doing a
tremendous amount of a private practice
mining law oil and gas law environmental
law and I had a client who was the
governor of the state of Alaska named
Wally Hickel who had a dream to build a
gas pipeline that ran right along the
oil pipeline that took the gas that was
being produced with that oil but was
being pumped back into the ground bring
it down to Valdez converted to liquefied
natural gas and she
to Japan Korea and Taiwan and solve our
balance of payments with all of those
companies the country's as well as
stimulate the economy all around the
country so so I worked on that project
for years and years and years it was
purchased by a fortune 500 company I
became the president of the company we
permitted this unbelievable project even
in the face of the Exxon Valdez oil
spill we had an environmental impact
statement that basically came out you
know two months later in the same area
we got all of the permits for a project
that you've never heard of that was the
world's largest construction project
that ended up for political reasons and
I contend some nefarious ones at that
getting killed by the governor of the
state of Alaska and and so at that point
in time I decided you know this legal
stuff is is fun but it's it's it's time
to do something else and so I went
easily when you're doing the kind of law
that you could turn the keys on your car
and your car could explode yeah I was
you know I worried about the oil
companies blowing up my car there was no
question I would been told that I was
extremely hated and feared you know by
BP and some of these other oil companies
and well they should hate me and fear me
because they they didn't treat Alaska
well and they certainly didn't treat
this project well but but in any case
not to be too bitter about it all I
during the ten year at the end of this
project now you have to understand that
any big project that involves natural
resources in Alaska is a transportation
play it all comes down to transportation
we are so far away from everything we
are closer to Tokyo than we are to
Washington DC that everything involves
transportation and and the last couple
of months of my career were this project
a guy a truck driver walked into my
office and he said to me I've got this
special soil that we got up here all
over the place and and I want to get it
down to the lower 48 states and it's a
transportation play
and you sure know an awful lot about it
can you help me well lo and behold it
turned out this soil was very special
soil it had the highest microbiology
that anybody had ever seen in soil and
it was all over the state of Alaska and
particularly all over the Anchorage area
and it turns out to be the soil that
grew the big cabbages that everybody
knows about so I got involved with it
and through becoming involved with this
guy in this truck driver I I met dr.
Elaine Ingham I was introduced to the
soil food web and when I went out from
from the project and went into a
practice representing Alaskan inventors
I started to write teaming with microbes
for regular gardeners because I felt
that I had been so betrayed by the
gardening industry telling me I needed
chemicals and I needed Miracle Grow and
I needed you know we'd be gone on all
these terrible things when in fact it
was the soil food web that ran the
system that there was that truck driver
and then through Tom Alexander a mutual
friend of ours mine who I want you to
meet and who I dedicated this DIY
autoflowering cannabis book to Wow I
just I just got so turned down by the
soil food web that I wrote these soil
food web books and and I wouldn't have
done it had I not been a lawyer and ran
into this fellow fascinating great a
great way to pull it all together so
before I let you go I do want to hit on
one more growing related question and
you know anybody who has emailed with
you sees in your signature on all your
email it says plant a row for the hungry
and I know you're very passionate about
this program so why don't you tell us a
little bit to maybe inspire us and get
some some more people to participate
yeah it makes me cry you know but anyway
so while I was working on this gigantic
project I used to go to Asia once a
month and Washington DC once a month and
I was in Washington DC and
of course you would go to Washington DC
on a fortune 500 expense account you go
first class so I flew first class I
stayed at the first-class hotel the
Willard hotel and I ate first class that
expense-account restaurants and I was
there one week it was the coldest week
they had ever experienced in Washington
DC that gas was being shut off they
closed the airport they shut down
Washington DC except for tourists who
were stuck there and it was crazy
unbelievably cold and I remember going
to my home of my hotel to a restaurant
which was really glad to see me because
there wasn't anybody else around that
was a very expensive restaurant having a
very expensive meal and leaving with my
hands in my pockets because it was so
cold with money wrapped around you know
in my hands and a guy came up to me and
said I need some food can you give me
some money well in Washington DC there
signs everywhere that they do not give
money to panhandlers we have our own
system blablabla and so I refused to
give the guy money I and he followed me
and he said come with me watch me eat
and I still thinking of those signs did
not help him I ended up at the Willard
hotel the doorman you know saw me coming
with this guy following me he saw the
doorman and he ran away I went to bed
that night in my hotel room which had
not just a little little you know
chocolate on the it had a fruit basket a
bottle of wine I had the worst night's
sleep of my life
it was Scrooge I saw my parents you know
what did you do to that got you stiffed
a guy who needed your help
that's not Malone fellows way and oh my
god I woke up the next morning it was
still freezing I look for the guy all
over the place I had to take my plane
home they finally opened the airport I
got on the plight of flying first-class
I'm flying over over your area Vashon
Island you know having a great flight
drink I have a steak and zucchini and
I'm looking down at it and I can't get
this guy out of my mind and I think
about the zucchini and the joke that if
you
in Wisconsin and and you park your car
at night you always make sure you lock
it because if you don't when you get in
the car the next morning it's full of
someone's zucchini you know it's so hard
to give away and I said she's I you know
that's what I'm gonna do I'm gonna get
everybody in Anchorage to help us wash
my bad conscience for sniffing this guy
I can still see his face today for
sniffing this guy I'm gonna get
everybody to donate one row on their
garden through my garden column to
what's known as beans cafe our soup
kitchen up here and it was a very
successful program and it helped me feel
a little bit better I only had the
nightmare once a month you know I only
heard my father you know you know once a
month and and and then one day the
Garden Writers of America came came to
Alaska for a convention they heard about
the program they visited beans cafe and
we adopted it as a national program and
it exists still today we resupply tunned
hard tens and hundreds of tons of food a
year to supply the soup kitchens to
synagogues churches you know food banks
any place that will take food the
gardener grows it the gardener harvests
it the gardener takes it in nothing
slips between the lip and cup in terms
of money no administrative costs no you
know you know how to support anybody the
it's plant a role for the hungry and I
encourage everybody to plant one role in
their garden to feed the hungry and if
you're growing only cannabis then some
of your cannabis ought to go to a vet or
somebody that needs medical cannabis
because gardeners share and that's the
best way we can possibly do it we have
30 some-odd million people going to bed
every night hungry in the United States
of America unconscionable just just
incredible and then you know you go out
of your garden and - an island and you
look at somebody who's left broccoli
there or left lettuce because they're
sick and sick of it after that you know
no you take it to somebody that knee
this is has to be the basis of how we
live so there I am
you can hardly shut me up about it
that's beautiful Jeff thank you very
much for sharing that very personal
story yeah so with that it is time for
us to wrap up thank you so much for
sharing so much of your time not only
here to talk with us here today but to
put your passion into writing the book
that comes out today and links will be
provided for that everywhere the podcast
is but just thank you for sharing your
good share and your joy and your
experience and being well willing to put
it all on the line with us well you know
I I always appreciate your show and you
know now I got this book published it's
time to get to work on the next one do
you are you ready to share with us a
topic yet well I will share with you the
topic but I but I will tell you my
criteria and this one will be part of
the teaming series I hope the publisher
takes it but my criteria is it has to be
something that's usable by the gardener
you know and I don't mean just
scientific information that's
interesting I mean something that they
can actually employ in growing plants
that'll make them a better gardener that
they're not aware of and they're not
using today I think I've got something
right on well we will certainly be
excited to check that out when it comes
out and I know everybody's going to be
excited to have another teaming with
book and I'll have to like retrain
myself to no longer call it a trilogy
what are they gonna call me you know
Bock fourth a fourth I don't know what I
don't know sorry about that folks
haha call me anything you want but late
for dinner right on well thanks a lot
Jeff if you would like to hear more but
I just cut you off though I was just
going to say my pleasure
very good thank you brother if you want
to learn more from Jeff Lowen fells
there's a whole bunch of ways that you
can do that first you can follow him on
instagram at gardener Jeff just straight
one word he also has a website it's not
super updated all that often the best
thing to do is to follow him on in
Graham but you can also check out his
website at Jeff Lowen fellas calm
YouTube is where you're just gonna find
Jeff flow and fells gold though if you
just put Jeff flow and fells in the
YouTube you're gonna find lots of people
who have interviewed him and his
presentations on the shaping fire
YouTube channel I've got you know four
or five of his presentations plus we
just did a ten-part series of the
shaping fire sessions with Jeff flow in
Fell's talking entirely about the soil
food web and and life in the rhizosphere
and then and then of course after
hearing about the book today you're
totally gonna want to pick it up for
somebody for the holidays for a present
or something and so that books link is
available on the shaping fire comm
website on Jeff flow and fells is
Instagram and then if you go to the
shaping fire Instagram or my personal
Shango loss Instagram it there's a link
in the profile both of those so it's
easy to get your hands on of shipping
today and so do not delay you can find
more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast and subscribe to the show at
shaping fire calm and on Apple iTunes
stitcher and Google Play if you enjoyed
the show we'd really appreciate it if
you'd leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever you download your
review will help others find the show so
they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire web site you can
also subscribe to the weekly newsletter
for insights into the latest cannabis
news and product reviews on the shaping
fire website you will also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
for information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango
lowes.com does your company want to
reach our national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire i've been your
host
Shango lows
you