[Music]
as cannabis cultivation continues to
normalize across the united states
more and more research and development
is being invested in cannabis genetics
our heritage growers made the cannabis
crosses we love today
based on intuition and experience today
though
a whole new variety of cannabis breeder
has evolved not only using
intuition and experience but also using
heavy computing and laboratory analytics
as well
while there is certainly no replacement
for experience and intuition
technology assisted breeding greatly
decreases the time it takes to actually
attain breeding goals
because successful cultivars can be
analyzed and confirmed
on the spot in a spreadsheet instead of
having to grow
all the plants to maturity and having
all the breeders friends smoke the
flowers hoping to confirm the results
with analytical breeding sex cannabinoid
content
terpene content and overall potency can
be determined in just a few minutes
several thousand times over making
extraordinarily large sifts a real
possibility
the application of these technologies
does not create genetically modified
organisms
they simply allow traditional mendelian
breeding decisions to occur
much much faster today we're going to be
talking about
triploid cannabis genetics these
triploid plants are only available to us
due to the availability of computing
power to cannabis breeders
these plants have three chromosomes
instead of two
which makes them sterile and impervious
to unintentional pollination
they also exhibit other traits many
cultivators want like
increased yields and resistance to pests
and molds
triploids occur in nature in a great
many species and in nearly all cases
these plants are superior to the other
plants in their species
so long as you don't intend to breed
with them
if you want to learn about cannabis
health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer
i encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too
don't rely on social media to let you
know when a new episode is published
sign up for the updates to make sure you
don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter there's nothing else you
need to do to win except receive that
newsletter
this month regenerative farming nutrient
company everflux is giving away their
full line of products to one lucky
subscriber to the newsletter
you'll receive a full bottle of their
bioflex fermented plant booster
their bamboo wood vinegar bio stimulant
and a big bucket of terraflux
their infused biochar blend you'll get
all three
make sure to listen to their commercial
during the show to learn more go to
shapingfire.com to sign up for the
newsletter this week and be entered into
this month's and all future newsletter
prize drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and
i'm your host shango
los my guest today is seth crawford
seth is a de-institutionalized academic
with a masters in public policy and a
phd in sociology
his focus up till now has been on the
political economy of cannabis
for years now he has been consulted by
lawmakers and policy specialists
for a better understanding of how the
cannabis economy works
seth is now co-founder of oregon cbd
seeds
a company researching developing and
wholesaling
specialty novel cannabinoid dominant
cannabis seeds
seth appeared on episode 25 of shaping
fire to talk about the convoluted cbd
market
and again on episode 37 to discuss the
nexus
of the medical cannabis and hemp markets
today we're going to talk about the
dramatic evolution of triploid seeds for
cannabis
welcome back to shaping fire seth thank
you for having me oh so glad to have you
here so
let's get right into it talking about
triploids so you know triploids are
really
common in other agriculture and food
industries but
i'm figuring the place to start with
today would be if you were to start with
the story of your entire valley
getting pollinated a few years back
right
yeah that was definitely the impetus for
us um this was uh back in 2016
uh we had a it was the the second year
of
industrial hemp production in the state
of oregon and it was the first year
of legal uh adult use
outdoor production so it was the the
inaugural year for thc
and uh the first i would say big year
for industrial hemp
and we had a neighbor who was about
three miles away
from one of our facilities and six miles
away from our major field
who had about 75 acres of
densely planted male and female
industrial hemp or what was
supposed to be industrial hemp
he pollinated our our field our facility
he pollinated you know neighbors that
were 15 miles to the east
15 miles to the north 15 miles to the
south
it really demonstrated the viability of
cannabis pollen
and just how far it can travel uh so i
will grant him that it was a good good
science experiment
but on the other hand it devastated a
lot of other farmers in the
in the valley and unfortunately um you
know
in in ensuing years it it continued to
happen in in
uh in smaller i wouldn't say it was to
that scale but it's definitely been
happening
in our in our valley and then also
throughout the state and other areas
especially in southern oregon it's
really really demonstrated to people
that
you know even if you have good
communication with your neighbors
there are just some folks who cannot be
convinced
that their right to farm is
less important than the common good of
everybody else being able to have a crop
as well
so it's really an outgrowth of uh of
that experience for us
so folks who are listening in the show
who aren't super familiar with pollen
why don't you explain why
it's lame that a neighbor's crop
pollinated
your crop uh you know if you if you have
a
an all-female crop that you're growing
four cannabinoids whether it's thc
cbd cbg etc uh or even
just for terpenes in cannabinoid free
plants if those
female plants end up being pollinated
you're going to lose about 50 percent of
your overall biomass
in about 30 percent of your total
cannabinoid content just because the
female plants are putting all of their
energy
into that seed production rather than
into the stuff that we want
very very problematic from it from an
economic standpoint
yeah and essentially you're also ruining
good medicine right
so there's a there's a real human aspect
to it as well
most definitely and the other the other
side of this too and it's gonna it's
going to uh be a part of this larger
story
is you know if you're a farmer and
you're you're let's say you're trying to
grow a grain crop
in the the midwest and you're trying to
feed your cattle a very particular type
of grain
in a lot of cases that grain while the
the seed itself
is uh highly impacted by the female
that ends up producing the seed it's
also impacted
from a from a you know omega-3 and
omega-6 and then
other other components of the the seed
is healthy and you know good for
nutrition
that can be influenced by the pollen
donor as well
so if you're trying to have a pure type
of seed
even if it's just you know for your
cattle uh pollen contamination
can really play a play a significant
role in undermining that as well
so it's not just cannabinoids it's it's
also in seed production
and also you know it's it's even more
than just uh commercial
cannabis as well um you know when
i appreciate the spirit of people who
want to
um gorilla grow um you know cannabis
plants right they let the cannabis be
free and they you know they make these
little
fertilizer balls and they chuck them
into you know vacant yards and you know
uh things like that and the problem with
that though
is that if you have these feral cannabis
plants
growing around um you could have a
patient who's got their little home grow
with four or six plants or something
and you know they are growing their
medicine and it's important and you know
somebody has thrown some feral hemp
you know you know a few parcels down and
one of those
seeds becomes a male and all of that
pollen is blowing
uh windwardly to this
patient's house suddenly their medicine
is going to get
all of this pollen and ruin this crop
which you know could be
literally a life-or-death situation for
them so
i'm constantly encouraging people to not
gorilla garden
you know uh irregular
sexed seeds because it's kind of
dangerous
for everybody it really is you know you
can't imagine a worse punch in the
stomach than
to have that small outdoor grow that you
put all that time and energy into
uh you know in your backyard in oregon
it's for plants
you know you get to the end of the
season and and your plants are finishing
up and you realize
oh no there's there's seed in all of
this you know
you basically lose you know three to
four months of your life and all that
time and energy you put into it
um it you know it's a in a way it's a
lot like
legalization you know at the very
beginning before there was any
uh any form of uh legal thc consumption
in the united states
at the state level uh you know a lot of
advocates would say
ah we just have to legalize it just
legalize it you know
and well yes that's true we need to
legalize it
uh the process of legalization once you
start to get into the
the weeds of policies and rules and
and how that gets implemented becomes
much much more complicated
i think the same thing is definitely
true in industrial hemp
we have a lot of folks that are big
advocates of hemp in general
who have constantly criticized some of
the farmers
over the last few years for growing you
know cbd or other cannabinoids
and not putting energy into uh you know
fiber crops
or grain crops and that type of stuff
and it's that same question
it's you know hemp can do these amazing
things however
how how can we make all of these
different uses coexist
peacefully and i think that's one of the
biggest challenges that we have in the
21st century of being able to adapt this
crop
both to the landscape into the the
social landscape
of being able to have people interact in
a way that's not going to be negative
for
either party we talked about that quite
a bit last time you were here about how
you know after your valley got
pollinated
um you know you tried to pull together
the local farmers
to create what what i called at the time
a pollen exclusion zone for lack of an
official term
and uh and you said that you know it was
actually really challenging because
um you know farmers are some of the most
independently minded
people that there are as similarly with
you know liberation-minded folks and to
kind of
pull people together to kind of agree to
not
do certain things on their property
there's a lot of pushback
and you know one of the things that
we're going to talk about today is is
why triploids are great and i think that
this is a this is going to be an
opportunity today where's where science
is going to make the politics of living
in your neighborhood
easier exactly exactly we had tried from
a policy perspective and from a social
perspective
to try to get people to engage and agree
and come together and it just it wasn't
possible
um but there's other ways
so so during the during the introduction
to the show
you know i mentioned vaguely what what
triploids are so people
knew what they were in for today but you
know since you are
you know deep into uh polyploidy science
um why don't you go ahead and give us
your definition of what a triploid is
yeah and i would uh first couch this and
say
uh the reason that we even have a ploity
breeding program here at oregon cbd is
uh because we hired
a recent phd shen chen
who is an absolute genius when it comes
to
both plant breeding and for the the
manipulation of ploiety
so he's really the one that is uh is
the driving force behind this at our
company um so dr shen chen
and brandon rojas who who works with dr
chen
um are really the really the
intellectual
uh weight behind this project um so i'm
i'm just basically the uh
the communicator of general science
so triploids are so cannabis is
traditionally a diploid species which
means that it has
uh two sets of homologous chromosomes it
inherits
one set from uh one parent and the other
set from
its other parent uh unless it's a
self-pollinated plant in which case it
is inheriting
from that that previous uh just from
that initial parent
so two copies of chromosomes are great
it gives you you know the opportunity if
you have
say one bad gene or two good genes to be
able to
you know basically have a fully
functional plant
or a plant that ends up expressing
things in a in a really profound way
triploids are plants that have three
sets of homologous chromosomes
which uh you know if two sets are are
good three sets ought to be
really really good but
to get to that point you have to have uh
tetraploid plants
so tetraploid would be a plant that has
four homologous sets of these
chromosomes
so what i just described is diploid
triploid
tetraploid uh you can continue going up
the the polyploid scale and having more
and more sets of homologous chromosomes
however as you as you start to increase
those numbers
there tends to be uh uh
basically a dropping off of the positive
impacts and an increase of some of the
negative impacts
so one of the challenges in employee
bringing polity breeding
is to identify at what level of ploity
does this particular species end up
having its maximum expression of health
vigor vitality etc
so um so the fact that these uh triploid
plants were kind of like superhero
plants with the
this extra chromosome really um
struck me you know i understood right
off the bat
that a you know that a triploid was not
going to reproduce right and
therefore you know it was not going to
be impacted by pollen
and i'm like you know cool seth that's
that's a great thing but then as i
research the scientific papers
preparing for the interview today i'm
all like oh my gosh
the list of um increased
benefits to plants from triploid
it's it's really astonishing so so here
here's a
short list of what i've picked up from
the science um
uh pest and disease resistance stem
straightness
increases in chloroplast number which
results in strengthening
photosynthesis flowers of
aaa plants are generally larger and more
colorful than those of their diploid
counterparts
because the energy is devoted to instead
of seed formation is used for
flowers and other organs height and
yield
so i mean my god it sounds like by
adding this
third set of chromosomes that you're
creating these super plants it's exactly
true
and really what it comes down to it
it's a little bit more complicated than
that um in the sense that
all of these things that you're saying
are 100 percent true but um
the the challenge for us has been to
identify which combinations
of genes uh will result in the
attainment of all of those wonderful
attributes um what we have seen is that
in the same way that you can you know
take a specific combination and create
incredible triploid plants you can also
get the wrong combination of genes and
create a plant that is
i would say less than a diploid in terms
of
its ability to be very successful in any
given environment
so the real challenge this summer has
been
doing field trials to identify which of
those crossing patterns are going to
give you the best results
wow that that you just put the my whole
idea on its end because so so
so technically you could get all of
these
um you know good variables in the plant
but but you also could uh breed
something that's especially bad it kind
of reminds me of like
you know maybe with your earlier
breeding product projects you were
trying to solve a rubik's cube
but now it's a cube like with like 10
rows instead of just three rows or
something like that
uh you're spot on with the metaphor
uh as you as you increase the polity you
begin to increase the complexity of what
you're dealing with
um and you know with a with a plant that
is as complicated
as cannabis uh and up until very
recently
so little known about the underlying
genomics uh
it was in a lot of ways a guessing game
and to be perfectly honest going into
this summer
we we had ideas about what could work
and uh
what should work and you know some of
those did
definitely have have panned out already
um but others have been
huge huge surprises and we basically had
to go back to
the underlying data that we're able to
luckily in-house
generate using our whole genome sequence
equipment
to produce these these really high
resolution genomes
we can basically figure out you know
you've got
gene a and gene b we've got two copies
of gene a and one copy of gene b
and you end up with a plant that is uh
12 inches tall when it finishes
if you get one copy of gene a and two
copies of gene b
the the inverse happens and you end up
with a five foot tall autoflower plant
that's
you know yielding two and a half pounds
of 20 cbda flowers
um so it's it's really really important
to be able to get those
those proper combinations mapped out
what what is the tool that you use
to figure out the percentages
of variability for all these traits
showing up because
you know i'm i'm imagining that triploid
kind of like
makes breeding uh squares cry you know
where you're figuring out what what
traits are going to be passed on right
i would imagine that triploids makes
that very complex and at some point
you want to you know just dump all of
these data
points into a computer and say okay
figure out
of these uh of these genetics
which ones are expressing which how many
of them we have that are advantageous
and which of these parents we actually
want to bring together
to to secure the most
most of the traits what we want is that
is that simply dropping it into a
database or what it what is the tool
that you use to help move you ahead on
that
when the variability is so
mathematically high
uh two two things and you know i'm
coming from my
we've talked about this before but my
phd is in sociology and one of the
things that we have to do in
sociology is take very disparate amounts
of data
to try to explain a particular social
outcome and in those situations you end
up explaining
you'll come up with a list of variables
that are you know eight to ten really
really
explanatory of variables have a big
impact
on your on your final outcome and
they'll end up explaining
you know if you're lucky thirty to forty
percent of the total variation within
any given population for any given
question
uh i think the same thing is pretty
accurate when it comes to this
particular crop we're dealing with
in a diploid plant you're dealing with
over roughly 30
000 different genes that are in the
plant
and you have to deal with you know
different alleles and different
combinations of those in crosses
that obviously is going to increase to
about 45 000 when you have
a triploid plant so that the tools that
we use
uh you know the whole genome sequence
data is is really useful
um but at the same time we're also
basically in discovery mode
trying to figure out what each one of
those genes are and
what they actually do in the plant
chemical data is also really useful
so we're using genomic data chemotype
data and then
you know that the the last leg of this
and triangulating
which crosses work the best is just make
the crosses and grow them in the field
uh it's your phenotype data
so for us i think we can kind of
we can create a broad a broad stroke
broad outline of what
could come out of a cross based on the
underlying genomics and we have a really
good idea of what the chemical data is
going to look like based on that
underlying
those underlying genes but the actual
things that mean the most to us
outside of of chemicals the the vigor
the flowering time
the uh the ability to deal with with
plant stresses
and uh you know drought disease pressure
etc those things really only show up
when you're in the field
and it's field trials and growing them
out and
and just visually taking a look at
each combination seems to be the best
approach but
you can't do you really can't do modern
breeding without
all three if you're not using all three
you're really just kind of swinging in
the dark
right on it probably also keeps you a
better balanced person instead of
keeping you in the lab you have to put
on your boots and go out into the field
exactly well i mean that's where you
want to be in the first place so it's
what an excuse you know one of the
things that um
is of remark in in the state of the
of the science right now is you know
with you trying to like
um you know activate these different um
parts of the genome to see what they do
it it's it's as if we're still at a
state of science where there's still
some intuition involved
whereas a lot of other plant species
where triploids are very common
and everything's become very mechanized
and just kicking out
seeds you know that that science has
already settled
whereas the cannabis genome is still so
tasty and fresh
that that yeah you've you've got your
analytical equipment
that that helps you quantify what's
happening
but really since we're talking about
real world
expressions that mean a lot in the field
it really takes for you to go out walk
the plants
see the ones that you know strike your
fancy
touch them feel them smell them and then
go back to the lab with that information
and um i you know i like the idea that
there's still some analog
left in this kind of breeding oh it's uh
once you're once you're able to kind of
nail down the the science side of it and
you have a good data collection
process going from the genomic side from
the chemical side
uh and even on the phenotype side there
really is an
art to to the selection process there
always has been i think there always
will be
um you know and this is true in any type
of breeding program
we're uh we're in close contact with a
lot of the folks at the usda ars
here in uh in corvallis and at the
university at oregon state
um because we're part of this larger
plant breeding community at this point
now that there's some uh
some acknowledgement that you know this
is a legitimate industry and it is
having a big impact on oregon
agriculture and and farms across the
country um
at the end of the day there's always
going to be art
involved you know this you want to you
know take berries for instance you know
you want a blackberry that has you know
the right sugar content
and the right harvest harvestability and
you know all the all the right variables
all the boxes get ticked
but at the same time you also as a as a
human you have a
if you have a fairly developed pallet
you can pick
you know and discern between a berry
that has just the right amount of
sweetness versus a berry that's say
overly sweet or under sweet or whatever
it happens to be
and i think that's where the beauty is
at because everybody has
it everybody has a different
interpretation of what that
that ultimate is going to be what that
perfect version is going to be
and it it leads to all of these
different spaces being available for
different breeders to to come in and
sort of make their mark
so um before we go to the first
commercial break because i think we're
all excited about set two
where we're actually going to talk about
you know the science and how they are
uh triploids are actually made since
this topic today is actually triploids
and not like a profile of your company
you know can you is there anybody else
in the cannabis industry
who is uh working on triploids that we
want to give a nod to
is also you know being a leader in this
area
uh not commercially at this point um
however we are working with uh the
university of connecticut
uh just as a sort of an informal
research relationship
um i believe we're a little further
along uh in our process and our breeding
program than they are
however they are definitely definitely
involved in doing some really really
cool work
uh there there's uh
uh it's jessica level brand i believe is
the professor there
her and her husband and then uh there's
two or three graduate students who are
working on projects
they're doing some really cool stuff and
there's also some folks at oregon state
university that are working on this as
well
but in in terms of uh commercial uh
adaptation of triploids and being able
to release them i'm i'm
confident that we're the only ones uh
right now in the world that will be
releasing
uh triploids for 2021. man you're gonna
be making a lot more
uh commercial seed buyers cry just like
when you brought out your
auto flowering cbd seeds or they so
the goal it's the goal every year you
have to get better uh you know if you're
not getting better at what you're doing
then
there's you know i think it's
questionable whether or not there's room
for you in the space
right on so uh we will start talking
about how these uh
seeds are made after the break um we are
going to take that short break now
you are listening to shaping fire and my
guest today is socioecologist
seth crawford if you listen to shaping
fire and you grow your own cannabis
chances are high that you are very
particular about the inputs you use for
growing
people like us painstakingly
self-educate on cannabis nutrients and
techniques
so we can cultivate the best tasting and
cleanest flowers possible
and when we go to purchase those
nutrients we want to be sure that our
supplier shares our values and is
providing
exceptional quality this is why i
recommend
buildasoil.com to my friends who care
about quality
build a soil empowers organic growers to
do their best work
by sourcing and shipping only the finest
cannabis growing supplies
from organic inputs soils soil testing
and pots
to lights growing tents sprayers and
cover crops
build a soil founder jeremy silva
doesn't just stock his store with what's
available
he goes deep to personally vet each
product for quality
and determine that there isn't a better
version of the product that he could be
selling
because of this arduous process you know
that your options on buildasoil.com
have been carefully curated to create
the results you are looking for
not only that but the build a soil way
is a philosophy that will permeate your
interaction with the company
from website design to pricing and
shipping to after purchase support
jeremy and his team always strive to do
their best
and give you the best customer service
in the business
check out buildasoil.com today
for top-tier quality cultivation
supplies and a friends and family buying
experience
and check out their educational videos
and extraordinary social media while
you're there too
quality organic growing supplies at
buildasoil.com
[Music]
while i love growing under the sun
there's a lot of good reasons to grow
indoors
and if you're like most folks you want a
lighting source that grows high yielding
healthy plants without using excessive
amounts of electricity
bios lighting creates biological
lighting solutions
that brings the natural brilliance of
the outdoors into your grow room
bios lighting has the attributes that i
look for in a horticultural lighting
solution
i've bought those cheap lights online
and they're difficult to work with and
fail in no time
in contrast my bios led light is
industrial grade to last a long time
it is ip66 wet rated so little foliar
overspray won't harm it
it is easy to clean without taking it
down and of course the most important
aspect
it is built for the exact light spectrum
i want for great yielding healthy
cannabis plants
and it doesn't hurt that their lighting
rigs look badass too
many horticultural led lighting systems
are based on irrelevant performance
metrics and people love to argue online
about these numbers
i prefer to judge on par photon
efficiency and how happy my plants are
and the bios lights exceed my
expectations in these categories
bios lights have an optimized broad
spectrum that maximizes photosynthesis
and plant growth
while also providing the ideal
conditions for superior par efficacy
and a comfortable visual experience i
also love their attentive and
over-educated customer service folks
bios starts with a team of biologists
before getting the electrical engineers
involved
they have studied how light impacts
cannabis plants and devised an overall
strategy that works
i encourage you to check out their
website at bioslighting.com
to learn more about how this strategy
can work for you
and shaping fire listeners can get a
special deal use the discount code
shaping fire all one word no caps for 10
off your entire purchase that's
biosliding.com
[Music]
one of the reasons why no-till cannabis
growing is so valued by farmers
is because the mycelium networks in the
soil remain established from year to
year
and we know these fungal networks are
essential because they are the nutrient
super highways that extend far and wide
in the substrate to feed your plants
the trouble with growing in new soils or
blended cocoa substrates
is that it takes most of the plant's
life just to create these mycelium
highways
dinomyco endomycorrhizal fungi inoculant
reduces that time and gets your plant
eating a wider array of nutrients faster
and it's three times the concentration
of the current leading brand in the u.s
at 900 propagules per gram of two fungal
species selected specifically for
cannabis cultivation
this new product called dinomyco is the
result of 30 years of research and
trials at the vulcani agriculture
research institute in israel
it has also been vigorously trialled by
cannabis and food growers
across the u.s since the product first
arrived here last year
you may have already even heard about
dynamico by its original name
dynamic now dynomico is available at
grow shops and online in the united
states for the first time
i love using dinomico to both speed up
the growth of mycelium networks in the
soil but also as a biostimulant
to make clone cuttings more virile you
can see side by sides showing the
comparative growth on their instagram
at dinomyco if you demand reliable
growing results and appreciate the
importance of an active root zone in
creating a thriving plant
i encourage you to check out dynamico at
dynomico.com
and find out where you can get yours
that's d-y-n-o-m-y-c-o.com
whether you are starting with new beds
or pots or if you want to add some
zing to tired soil choose dynamico to
maximize your plant's potential
dynamico endomycorrhizal inoculant
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and our guest this week is
socioecologist
seth crawford so seth we got everybody
all excited about
uh triploids during the first set
because uh we're gonna make these uh
you know these superhero uh chemovars
that also can't be pollinated
accidentally
so of course the big question is how are
they made and i know that there are
people
listening that are saying man f that gmo
stuff
and so let's start there by being really
clear
that this is not genetically modified
organisms so would you go ahead and make
a clarification
on the science so that people can be
really clear that this is actually
nature these are not genetically
modified organisms
[Laughter]
uh yeah this is it's actually something
that does spontaneously happen
in nature on its own and when you maybe
step back and and take a look at some of
the most successful
invasive weeds that have propagated
across the country across the world
many of them are tetraploids because of
all of those previous
uh evolutionary advantages that we were
talking about before
in terms of you know vigor and and
chloroplast count and
efficiency of using resources um so it's
something that
you know in the long span of history
happens regularly
and has actually given rise to most of
the uh
the diploid species that we've seen
today so
what you end up seeing is a spontaneous
transition to say a tetraploid
and then sometime in the future uh
you'll have a
having again and you'll go back to to
diploids
and it's it's part of the reason that we
see a lot of the diversity in
in many different plant species is
because of these sort of
go to tetraploid go back to diploid over
the over these long periods of time
in our program we're taking plants
that have been very specifically bred
for characteristics
that we felt were important and are part
of our our
previous diploid breeding program and
now we're bringing in uh
new what what were new characteristics
of new traits
in diploid form and then we're putting
them through
uh essentially a chemical transformation
so we're taking a diploid plant and
doubling its chromosomes
uh not inserting anything new but taking
what's there and literally just doubling
it
um using using chemicals in vitro
and then having to grow those plants out
repeatedly
take cuttings grow them out again
take cuttings grow them out again and at
every single one of these
stages it's anywhere between six to
eight months to make this this happen
from start to finish
we have to test every single one of
those plants with a flow cytometer which
is a
very fancy piece of science equipment
that is able to
tell you the size of the underlying
genome of the plant that you're looking
at
so we're having the screen to make sure
that these formerly diploid plants have
been successfully
transitioned to tetraploids
you know one of the things i think it's
important to point out is that you know
while you use a lot of technology in
this sort of breeding
um you know the use of technology itself
does not set it up for being gmo and the
way i normally talk about it with
patients is that
it's kind of the difference between
technology between a magnifying glass
and a scalpel you know when it comes to
a magnifying glass
you're you're looking what is there and
then with a scalpel you are
cutting and rearranging and and all of
your technology that you're using is
essentially different forms of a
magnifying glass
you are you are using analytics and
testing
and uh and gene mapping to see
what there is so that you can have
a better grasp of what's naturally
in your plants so that when you have
your plants
naturally interact you get it right the
first time-ish
instead of kind of like just shooting
from the hip without knowing what's in
your
um genetic makeup like most of us
pollen chuckers do do you think that's a
fair
characterization most definitely yeah
and uh
the the magnifying glass versus scalpel
is a good metaphor
the the way that i usually describe it
is uh it's we're reading rather than
writing
um so like our our pack bio sequel ii
it's a whole genome sequencer that
allows us to
get every single a t g and c that
makes up the entire basis
of each one of these individual plants
we're able to read
all of those letters you know up to 100
times
to know with 100 close to 100 certainty
99.99
is where the accuracy is at now what is
actually in those
and in the case of these tetraploids you
can
liken it to a copy machine so rather
than you know making some sort of big
edits and changing things
we're taking what's already there and
just making an additional copy of it
and that's like i said before that's
kind of where we get into the
you know that the nitty-gritty is being
able to figure out which of those
which of those genes are good which of
those genes you know when combined with
themselves again end up being bad uh and
which of the more importantly which of
the plants
uh in these crosses which one do you
want to have
two copies of the genome versus which
one do you want to have just one copy
uh on the triplet crosses so this this
this next question is probably going to
be dry for some folks but i know that
there are
serious breeders listening who are
really going to be grateful that we took
this extra step down this path and this
is what i'd like you to do if you would
you know since you're talking to me that
since you're saying that each of these
cycles and trying to find you know tease
out the attributes you want take you
know six to eight months
would you just give us um a timeline of
milestones
on the creation of a of a triploid
kimovar
like and what i'm imagining is you're
like okay we start with this
and then we do this and then we do this
a few times and then we end up with this
just because i know that the breeders
want to be able to
picture the process in their heads so
they can wrap their heads around it
so would you would you go through that
process for us
yeah so we release f1s which means that
you have to have two
independently developed highly inbred
parents one is a pollen donor one is a
pollen recipient
uh those just getting to the point where
you have developed
the two parent lines is you know roughly
a three year process
and i have explained it elsewhere um
over the
over the years but it's you know you
find a you find a cross that you really
like it has the attributes that you want
you inbreed that plant you take the
seeds off you grow those out you test
them
you find the best one uh you grow that
out you self-pollinate
over and over and over as many times as
you possibly can to lock in
all of the traits that are you know
exactly what you're looking for in terms
of stabilization with that one variety
simultaneously you're doing exactly the
same process
with a separate line uh inbreeding
inbreeding
inbreeding etc doing your selections at
the end of all this
you know four to five generations down
the road then you can actually bring
them back together
and create your f1 so you pollinate one
highly inbred line with another highly
inbred line
that results in seeds that would
actually go into the farmer's hands and
go into their fields that
rather than being highly inbred they're
they're very heterozygous which gives
them
hybrid vigor and allows them to thrive
in a field
that's a that's a three-year process
when you add the
when you add tetraploids to the mix to
make a triploid f1
you basically take you have to choose
and this is the important part choose
which one of those parents you want to
have
the the two copies uh donated to your
your triploid
um identify which of those
you want and then go through the process
of chemically transforming
uh those plants and we do that basically
from uh from cuttings and you have to
have
hundreds of those cuttings treat them
with the chemical
most of them are going to die a handful
of them will survive and those survivors
end up being the the tetraploids that
then get
cuttings taken off of them tested again
grown out
cuttings taken off of them again tested
grown out and then they become if they
pass all of those tests and remain
tetraploids then those plants will end
up going into our
our production environments to make the
triploid seed so
you're really looking at what used to be
if you were really
if you were really pushing uh and and
doing your hybridization programs
quickly
and still giving yourself a year to do
field trials it's about a three year
process
now we're looking at closer to four four
and a half years
from the time that we start a project
until we can we can get seed into a
farmer's hands
as a triploid f1 well i like the
compactness
of that explanation it's always nice to
interview somebody who was formerly a
professor
my question for you though is if
if did so you started this project like
five years ago
uh so the inbreeding to get to the point
where we had the
the diploid parents uh you know we've
been working on that this this whole
time
um basically where we're at right now is
we can we can take any of these parents
that we've developed over the years
and we're continually developing
obviously new parents uh so like
this upcoming year we're releasing cbdv
dominant plants and cbgv
dominant plants so new compounds all
together that allow
industrial hemp farmers to meet the
super stringent usda enforced
0.3 thc limit uh even at
harvest so uh it's basically a fairly
revolutionary development for farmers
um so we've got these plants hold on a
second we need to stop there for a
second you know
all of these growers whose chins just
dropped
what you just said is like a bombshell
we've got two brand new novel
cannabinoids
that that don't test hot at
um at harvest
correct that's a that's a pretty big
deal to just slide on through
so yeah it's kind of it's kind of big um
and it's not just like one variety
we we've spent the last three years
working to completely
uh remake our entire library so
all the varieties that we've released
over the last couple years super haze
special sauce
lifter etc etc those have all been
converted into these
varen rich triploid forms
so we're releasing uh fully compliant
uh fully infertile uh female flowers so
this is
veren rich triploid varieties for 2021.
that's uh very exciting all right so i
uh so i interrupted you but essentially
you were saying that you can take any of
these varieties
um that you've been bringing in the
market for the last few years do this
dance remix on them
and boom now they can be uh triploid and
so you're you're taking stuff that
you've already proven and and you know
upgrading them essentially
yeah that's exactly right exactly right
so
so one of the things that i found
interesting is that you know
when you're using these three sets of
chromosomes
um there are all of these attributes
good and bad that are
bouncing around that you're trying to
get a a handle on
um but a lot of these um are not good
and they create imbalances you know uh
like you know epigenetic changes and
genome size
and you know you know increase and
decrease genomic diversity
um what are some of the imbalances that
you have seen
are common in cannabis to come out when
attempting to you know find a triploid
that's in balance
you know that the number one thing that
we're seeing is
uh you know that process of inbreeding
while it does lock in very specific
traits that you target
it can also lock in uh deleterious
alleles
over time and what's really problematic
is that you don't always see uh
the full expression of the negativity
that goes along with those particular
genes
when there's only two copies but they
are coming out when there's three copies
on a much more regular basis so you
could have a variety that you know
you've worked over a long period of time
to stabilize
and it seems to be you know hitting
hitting all the marks that you want
but as soon as you add one additional
copy then everything goes haywire
um basically it's just it's that that
accumulation of of negative alleles uh
over time now i could also see this
being problematic
uh we're we're very specific in
uh flowering time it's something that
we've been spending a lot
of time on the on the genomic side and
just in in terms of data collection
being able to catalog every possible
permutation that is
that's out there with these different
flower time genes
and flower response genes that all end
up working in concert together
to end up forcing a plant to go into
flower at particular times
what's really problematic with triploids
is that if you get
say two copies of you know for example
uh uh
the gene set that goes along with say
a haze plant you know an old haze that
is
uh equatorial in origin
two copies of that will even when you
have
say a copy of an autoflower gene also
you're going to end up with a plant that
doesn't finish flowering until
december right so it's understanding
which combinations
end up leading to the results that you
want and for us right now that is
identifying different flowering genes
that allow you to have staggered
harvests
from say early august all the way
through the end of october depending on
the the bioregion that you're in
really being able to nail that down is
is critical but it's also probably one
of the most
uh problematic areas i think where it
will be a problematic area as folks get
into triploid breeding uh just
understanding what those
those genes are and how those gene
networks interact when you increase
plating
and when you're using this at a
commercial level and you're using
thousands of seeds that becomes really
important
for the simple reason if you think about
succession planting
in your home garden your food garden you
know we're
we're planting you know lettuces and
things that grow
quickly you know sometimes once a week
maybe every other week
and the idea is that so you get lettuce
all through the summer and you don't
just get a hell of a lot of lettuce
just one week right and and for a lot of
commercial folks
they don't want to have to harvest all
of their
acreage all at the same time and so
they'll plant some and then a little
longer later they'll
plant some more but but that kind of
succession planting
only really works if you if those seeds
are
locked in to go from germination to
being finished in
in a set number of days say 90 days so
that
so that if you if you sow seeds a week
apart you know
that they'll be ready to harvest a week
apart
and uh so i can imagine that is probably
why you
you know you put so much focus on that
because if that doesn't work then this
doesn't work at scale
that's exactly right and you know when
you're when you're talking about
non-psychoactive cannabis
farming uh you really are talking about
large scale
um you know it's there are smaller farms
and it's great we
love them we we are doing everything
that we can to support them but on the
biomass side
uh you know there there are really
really large farms
and as a plant breeder you're standing
naked before the world
when you've got a thousand a thousand
acres of your seeds in a field
you know and if there's any type of of
hiccup in terms of that flower response
time
you're going to hear about it and the
farmer is not going to be successful
and for us if farmers aren't successful
then then we haven't done our job
and unsuccessful farmers are nasty so
you don't you want to be real you want
to make sure you do your job well
so that they're not coming with
pitchforks and uh
and fire torches and such exactly we'll
save that for the government
yeah so um so let's talk a little bit
more about some of the challenges
um when making uh triploids so you know
um alba albinos albinism is a pretty
common
when making triploids and that would be
no chlorophyll
and so those die pretty quickly because
of a lack of photosynthesis
are you seeing that pop up with working
with the cannabis genome
because it's entirely possible that
albinism is more just common in other
species you know we we do see that
but uh we have not seen a heightened
expression in triploids
and that is that's the case even on uh
say the poorly performing inbred
varieties um it is not popped up now you
know in a field of of
you know hundreds of thousands of plants
you're definitely going to see that and
we we've seen it in certain crosses
in field trials in previous years with
diploids
uh it's not a high frequency but it's
definitely something to
to to be concerned with um the flip side
of that though
i would say is that if you can lock that
trade in some of those uh
some of those plants that either have
albino
expressions or have uh uh
significant extreme variegation or say
even a belief shape change
that is becoming very popular right now
you can make those express in particular
ways
that would be fantastic for say like a
home garden
so there's there's challenges for
large-scale field production for
say cannabinoids or fiber or for food
but there's also some i think some
really unique opportunities
from just a home gardening uh ornamental
plant standpoint that we haven't seen
with cannabis before which is
kind of exciting well here's a
non-sequitur for you so if you've had at
least one or two
albino cannabis plants through all your
trials
i would love for you to compare and
contrast what you
saw as an albino plant versus
you know very often we will see indoor
plants a photograph posted to
instagram or similar and there's always
the ensuing fight in the thread below
arguing whether or not this is an albino
plant or whether or not this is a plant
that was bleached by being too
close to a uh an led
light and so visually i'm assuming
you've seen these photos too so yeah so
so
compare that those those those stark
white
plants that we that were grown under
leds
is that how a cannabis albino
presents itself because i know some
species look more pink and some look
more white
i don't think that i can know
scientifically
true that i have seen an albino it's
always been someone showing me
a picture so so what does an albino
cannabis plant actually present as
uh what's really interesting is that it
very rarely will it actually encompass
the entire plant
um more often than not you'll get a a
you know a sport
a side shoot uh or you know say a half
of a
the really interesting ones or the uh a
shoot that half of the plant
or excuse me half of the shoot is green
and half of the chute is white
those are pretty good examples partial
partial albino-ism
the ones that you're seeing on the
internet uh you know if the top of the
flower is you know a half an inch from
the led and the only thing that's white
on the plant
is that bleached out spot a pretty good
indication that it's
it's uh from the light rather than
genetic abnormality
one of the things that's really cool
about uh especially the
the variegated plants that have a
tendency towards albinoism
is uh two years ago we found a beautiful
example of this in the field and
eric in his infinite wisdom uh dug it up
and you know i'm like what are you doing
why are we spending this time to dig
this plant up
so he digs it up puts it in a pot and we
took it back to our
to our uh other farm and just stuck it
in the shade
that he had this idea that uh you know
if you just take that plant get it out
of the direct sun and put it in the
shade it would actually start to
put uh you know chlorophyll back into
the leaves lo and behold that's exactly
what happened
so essentially what you've got is a
plant that
thrives in shade grown conditions rather
than a plant that's thriving in these
high intensity you know solar radiation
in the in the field
just really really interesting i think
it it lends itself
to the explanation of just how plastic
this
cannabis plant really is give it a
different environment
uh it would thrive but for you know
field production it may not necessarily
be the best case
um kind of as a side note i've i have
been really enjoying seeing all these
um atypical morphologies of cannabis
you know kind of have their heyday as
there's more people breeding and more
people being able to share and feeling
free to share their photographs
you know on instagram we're seeing lots
more pictures of variegation
and the ensuing argument about whether
or not it's variegation
or whether it's mosaic or something
so there's there's a lot of that but
it's it's cool to see people sharing
pictures of
variegated plants that historically we
haven't been able to see
because everybody is seeing these in
hiding right during the prohibition days
and um and that's really cool and then
of course like the um
the freak show plant that like has got
everybody
you know tantalized for the last couple
years it you know it looks more like a
tomato plant than like a cannabis plant
and then of course the newly arrived
australian bastard
uh genetic line that that again looks
like a you know a fern of some sort
instead of a cannabis plant and and you
know all these different morphologies
it's um you know i never thought there
was a thing and now there's these kind
of
you know interesting plants to grow and
experiment with for people who just like
love
the cannabis plant itself you know you
know at this point
and and maybe never they will never be
production level
plants but i really like my freak show
that's on my deck right now
it looks super cool you know yeah and
one that's the whole idea i think
you know in in previous years if you're
capped
with you know a certain number of plants
and you're going to obviously want to
call the
the individuals that are not going to
give you what you need
you know in most cases that was
cannabinoids uh
now everything is a little bit laxer and
people are starting to look at the
potential
of not only you know the
the medicine but also the food and the
fiber and
quite honestly the just the fundamental
beauty of
a unique you know a unique individual
from a population
um i mean there's the entire ornamental
uh plant breeding industry is
is built on that and i think we're going
to probably start seeing ornamental
cannabis plants in people's yards
you may not be able to tell that it's a
cannabis plant anymore but i think
that's part of the fun and the beauty
and the plasticity of this awesome
species
yeah i totally agree with that that is
going to be nice too
you know the to be able to grow the
plant for
you know the joy of gardening right
instead of
feeling like you have to do it in
prohibition
mindset you know yeah yeah so this next
question
i think to a certain degree i'm asking
this next question just because i want
to get this phrase into the show
and so um there's this uh there's this
uh
this thing called mixoploid chimera
right
and so a mixoploid chimera happens
sometimes when breeding triploids
and and its definition is an
inconsistent ploidy from one plant right
and so in my mind i'm i'm picturing that
like
like in instead of the the breeding
process
kicking out all triploid seeds it's
actually
kicking out seeds that have got
different
numbers of genetics in them different
different numbers of sets
and so the resulting seed stock is going
to be not ubiquit not
uni comprehensively ubiquitous they
won't be the same right
so so how hard is it when you are
ramping up the scale right after you've
done this
long arduous process that you've already
um
described to get the plant that you
actually
want how challenging is it to then
make you know tens of thousands or more
of of these triploid seeds that are all
exactly the same so you get the success
in the field
uh that's a it's a great question um and
it
the answer comes down to just repeated
testing um so even though you know we've
as i described before you know you take
a significant amount of time to test and
test and test over and over using the
flow cytometer
to establish that you have tetraploids
and you have diploids in your breeding
population
um you have to continue to do that and
it gets even more complicated with what
we're having to do for 2021 which is
also you know making these these varan
rich plants
uh in the in the process it means that
every single pollen donor that goes into
one of our
our uh our greenhouses has to be
individually tested both for its ploiety
and for its varan content to ensure that
we've got everything that we're looking
for
in terms of being able to produce seeds
that are and i wouldn't say 100 uniform
on the seeds because there still is
variability uh however
they they are hitting all the marks for
the traits that that we're interested in
um
what's kind of interesting is to to
actually get to
a plant that is a 100 percent uniform
would require a different type of
ploiety
induction so rather than increasing the
ploidy level you decrease it
to a haploid level where there's only
one chromosome
uh one one set of uh
excuse me a single chromosome uh
from the parent from the donor so
that would be an individual haploid that
could then be chemically altered to have
uh two sets two copies of those same
chromosomes but they're identical and
that's when you end up being able to
produce
they're called doubled haploids which
are essentially uh
seeds that act just like a clone would
um but
come along with all the benefits of seed
vigor
and having no no diseases no pests that
sort of thing on the clone itself
no that sounds like a gold standard
right there it really is
um and it's to be honest i know there
are other groups that are working on
this they have been for a while um we're
we have a research contract with oregon
state university uh
working on this just to figure out if
it's viable um i think in the long term
it's an interesting area for me because
what you just described and saying
uh you know your triploids are are
uniform
they're uniform to a certain degree
we're we're very interested
in maintaining some diversity within
these different genotypes
to ensure that if there is some kind of
you know if you have some sort of
environmental problem or you have a pest
pressure
you really do need to have a certain
level of diversity
even in your seed crop that's in a field
to be able to handle those types of
pressures
and to identify you know certain certain
genotypes or certain uh phenotypes
that can withstand those types of
pressures um so it's
it's kind of that that idea of trying to
trying to get towards a monocrop in a
monoculture crop in the sense
of uh you know maximizing your
productivity of acres
while at the same time balancing that
with the necessity to
not have a monoculture in your field you
know having that enough diversity to be
able to respond to
um you know short-term pressures so
let's dig a little bit more into that
uniformity question because you know one
of the
biggest aspects of uniformity in
cannabis that's important is with
feminized seeds right because it doesn't
take
many sneaker males to ruin a crop of
otherwise female plants and and you're
kind of
adding another variable that really must
be
at you know if not 100 percent
really damn near 100 like we are with
feminized seeds
this fact that the seeds won't pollinate
right
so like how uniform are
these triploid seeds that are being
produced
in their uniformity and they are
pollen impervious yeah that's it's a
really good question uh
in two two two questions all bottled up
there
uh one is you know what what sort of
feminization rate are we seeing with
these triploids is it comparable to the
diploids
um with our diploids it's 99.98
so one in four thousand roughly uh
would end up having a male phenotype in
the triploids we're seeing exactly the
same numbers which is
super interesting to me and we're going
to dig into that a little bit deeper on
the genomic side to get a better
understanding of it
but the other side of it is given uh you
know a triploid plant
uh exposed to pollen how how seed free
is this plant um and what we're saying
is that it is
nearly seed free in the sense that
last summer we had an experiment in a
sealed greenhouse this is a 7 000 square
foot
sealed greenhouse no air coming in no
air going out
where we had a triploid that was
pollinated by
i believe we had 300 different pollen
donors that had all been reversed and
they're they're
making copious amounts of pollen um you
know you walk into that greenhouse and
you would get sick if you're allergic to
pollen
uh the triploids that were in that
greenhouse produced
um one produced i believe four seeds
and another one produced i believe five
uh
which we were comparing it to the
diploid uh sisters right next to it
um those those plants were fully seated
and on a weight comparison you're
looking at about 1 4
000 of uh which is pretty phenomenal
the interesting part about that too is
that the seeds that come off of those
triploids are actually non-viable
so you would end up with you know like i
said four four to five seeds
per plant in a greenhouse that is
completely inundated like
inches of pollen on the benches when we
were all done with
you know at the end of the day uh
they're they're highly
highly resistant to to pollen which is
really really interesting because not
only are you you protecting your
your neighbors from you know your own
crop if you're planting all female seeds
you're already doing the right thing
but now you're basically guaranteed of
not you're not going to pollinate your
neighbors because the pollen coming off
of those triploid plants are also
non-viable
uh there's no risk to yourself you're
not going to you self-pollinate because
you know honestly the plants don't get
pollinated
so it's really a win-win and they are
are
very very uh very difficult to pollinate
it's interesting too that it's not
simply an on or off switch
where the triploids that did produce
seeds
it wasn't like oh yeah these produce
and now they're full of seeds it's like
it's like oh yeah
the the plant produced seeds but it's
only like three or
four it means that you know even though
some of the individual flowers
you know kind of failed if you will to
be pollen resistant
it wasn't the plant as a whole and so
there's like multiple layers of
threshold
there to resist the pollen exactly
exactly yeah it's like
like we'd said earlier these are they're
super plants
yeah and you know really interesting to
think about so
so let's go ahead and take our second uh
break here and when we come back we're
going to talk about some of the
some of the uh applications of triploids
and and where this is going to go
you are listening to shaping fire i'm
your host shango los and our guest
this week is socioecologist seth
crawford
[Music]
for years organic cultivators have been
looking for a replacement for using peat
moss
peat moss has long been the go-to soil
amendment for water retention and
container growing
but organic growers know that peat moss
is an unsustainable resource
and the mining of peat bogs destroys
habitat and releases sequestered carbon
but peat moss works so well that many
have continued to use it
but now there's finally a revolutionary
replacement for peat moss that shares
the same benefits
while also being sustainable pit moss
sounds and axe like peat moss but
instead of being mined from fragile
ecosystems
it actually is made from upcycled
organic paper and tree bark
pit moss is excellent at retaining water
in your substrate and creating air
pockets and
tiny living environments for microbes
pit moss
instantly increases aeration nutrient
absorption
and water conservation too carefully and
locally sourced
pit moss is the result of decades long
research into the use of recycled paper
fibers
pit moss has the fluffy nature of peat
moss and handles exactly the same
and like peat moss pit moss is inert so
it won't change your ph
available in a range of preparations
including a nutrient enhanced blend
a coco coir blend and also as an organic
soil conditioner with no added nutrients
pitt moss is also available as an animal
bedding
so go to pittmoss.com now to learn more
that's p i t t m o
s s dot com growing healthier
more sustainable plants pit moss
[Music]
for many transitioning to organic
gardening can be overwhelming
there's so much to learn about soil
biology and fermentation
bioflux fermented plant boost from
everflux
simplifies organic farming so you can
start growing organically today
invented by a california farmer growing
organic for 40 years
bioflux is a fermented natural farming
preparation
for those who want a natural micro
booster without having to brew their own
this extraordinary chemical free growth
and terpene enhancer
improves root development accelerates
the conversion of organic matter into
humus
increases nutrient use efficiency and
uptake and increases beneficial microbe
activity
in addition to the bioflux fermented
plant booster everflux also makes an
activated biochar called terraflux
that is infused with the bioflex plant
booster
imagine combining the buffering and
rhizosphere enhancing qualities of
biochar
infused with a range of earthworm
castings insect frass
kelp and crabmeal oyster shell and other
ingredients
i'm using terraflux infused biochar this
summer myself
and it smells alive rich and potent
these products have been scientifically
proven to match yields and increase
flower quality and pest resistance
when compared to traditional npk inputs
if you are looking for reliable organic
fertilizers that will free you up to
focus on other aspects of your garden
consider using the range of all natural
regenerative fertilizers and natural
biostimulants from everflux
find out more at
everfluxtechnologies.com
or by following their instagram at
everflux
[Music]
for 20 years humboldt seed company has
been family owned and providing reliable
high yielding seeds originating in
northern california
while the current trend is to slap one
super male into a line of hyped strains
humboldt seed company continues to breed
with precision and care
by doing large sifts and back crosses to
emphasize the absolute best traits that
a line has to offer
this kind of breeding takes time talent
and space to work
no matter what kind of aroma you are
particularly into
humboldt seed will likely have something
you'll love if you love fruit
you can choose from banana mango apricot
papaya blueberry blood orange melon and
lemons across their various strains
they have all gas glue and classic sour
diesel lines as well
of course there are the heritage
california strains like og
kush jack hair and headband and their
award-winning blueberry muffin is one
that delights just about everybody's
palette
especially when concentrated humboldt
seed company is proud to bring to market
the infamous freak show cultivar 2
which has a great thc high but looks so
much like a fern that some folks can't
even identify it as cannabis
it's a plant that really needs to be
seen to be believed
if you're looking for well-balanced cbd
seeds humboldt seed company can turn you
on to cbd strains
that actually have flavor like the dill
and pepper
terpenes of willy g's lebanese land race
whether you are looking for regular
feminized or autoflowers
humboldt seed company has the gear to
make this your best growing cycle
ever visit humboldtseedcompany.com today
to check out their line of vigorous
genetics download their catalog
and find out where you can pick them up
you can also check out their instagram
at the humboldt seed company to check
out their gorgeous flowers
and the extraordinary freak show plant
humboldt seed company
let him know shango sent you welcome
back you are listening to shaping fire
i'm your host shango los and our guest
this week is socioecologist
seth crawford so seth we've talked about
what triploids are
and how they're made but you know this
conversation brings up all sorts of like
interesting side questions
and so in this third set let's hit a
bunch of those side questions
and start with you know it is possible
that most people who are not breeding
are going to want these seeds
as well right this idea that they can be
you know
super plants showing all of these
incredible triploid
you know expressions i mean me as just a
simple
patient home grower i want to grow this
stuff even though i'm not growing acres
of it
um are these you know is anybody doing
triploids
that are thc dominant right or or
is it just other novel cannabinoids at
this point
which are being designed for the uh for
the medical hemp market
yeah it's a great question uh and every
home grower
once they have grown a triploid uh i
don't think you will ever grow a diploid
again
uh that much there's some fighting words
i i i i'm not a betting person but i
would uh i would
definitely wager in that in that camp
um you're looking at a good example
there's
really good papers uh scientific papers
describing the differences between a
triploid
uh hop versus a diploid hop
very similar families and what you're
seeing is uh essential oils so that the
terpenes and the other olfactory
components that make up the flavor
profile
of a of a hob um are more than double
in a in a triploid versus a diploid uh
the same thing is true
in the triploid cannabis plants that
that we're creating right now
you've never smelled you've never
smelled a plant that had a stronger
flavor
than these triploids um conversely
they're also producing more cannabinoids
uh so you end up with a plant that's i
mean it's basically the ultimate
expression
of what a cannabis plant can be
um so to answer your question in short
no unfortunately there are not uh
triploid versions of
thc plants that are available right now
um
but it would not surprise me if there
are a bunch of folks who are claiming
that they have them
after uh people hear about this because
they are they are
just so awesome um one of the things
that we are working on
is uh you know obviously we're an
industrial hemp seed research and
development company so we have to
to honor the uh the federal rules and
the usda's guidelines on
who we can give seed to and and that
sort of thing but i will say that we
are pushing very hard at the federal
level to be able to
offer seeds to home growers i think
we're going to be able to do that in
oregon for 2021
just trying to work it out nationally at
this point for others to participate in
that process
but i will say that as part of the
research and development process we end
up with a lot of plants that are
considered type ones
type one are high thc plants uh in
addition we also have type
2 plants and this is something to think
about from a
from a gene stacking perspective if you
have a type 2 plant that's both
has an active cbd and an active thc gene
what does that look like in terms of the
underlying ratio when you have
three potential copies so you can stack
these in different ways to achieve very
different results
we're definitely working on
making sure that we have tetraploid
versions of
many very very famous and
[Music]
useful thc plants we're allowed to keep
those as part of our genetic library but
we're not allowed to
flower them out they would they would
not meet the obviously not meet the
industrial hemp
standards however we can do the
transformations uh
on site at our company and then because
we live in oregon you know we take these
plants home and we can
we can make seed with them and make make
triploid seed you know say in your
basement or your garage
we're not doing commercial quantities of
that and we're not legally allowed to
sell them at this point but
they're definitely out there and they
are definitely awesome
so so
if i understand this correctly you can
develop
the genetics legally in your hemp
company but because though that is not
a viable product under your license you
have to stop
there so if theoretically the laws were
to change
and and hemp breeding you know hemp seed
manufacturers were
able to now produce type ones you
actually have got a
library of this seed that you'd go oh
we're just going to put this into
production now even though they're kind
of um
they're kind of it's like it's like
spin-off technology from the work that
you're actually trying to do
that's exactly right that's a very nice
way to describe it
we are basically just in a holding
pattern waiting for federal legalization
to open up
uh we're cannabis breeders and the
underlying
chemical compounds are very very simple
targets in terms of breeding
it's the rest of it that interests us uh
but you know
as as good plant breeders we're always
keeping our work backed up
and uh are always ready to move forward
when the time is right
so so let's say that you did you know
take one of these
these uh type one seeds that's triploid
and you take it home
and and you make that your patient
garden and you grow it and
everything's all nice and legal is are
the differences between
a triploid and a diploid seed
growing is it so remarkable that you can
tell
that as the you know assuming that you
have some experience growing cannabis
plants right already
like if i grew this plant would i be
like holy hell this is a different kind
of plant
or is it like yeah you know yeah it's
it's a better seed like how how
remarkable is it
uh you know in terms of uh say like
olfactory components you know not just
terpenes
we know now that terpenes make up about
50 of what actually
smells in a cannabis plant the rest of
them are
different forms of alcohols and
especially aldehydes
the triploid plants tend to have
anywhere between 30 to 50 percent
uh increased expression of those
particular compounds which means that
they are
the loudest flowers that you that you're
going to uh
that you're going to end up smelling um
just as an example uh
we've got one of my my favorite plants
of all time is uh chem dog number four
so it's uh one of the chem dog um
there's kim dog d
chem 91 in uh chem four chem four has
always been my personal favorite
in diploid form now when you see it in
tetraploid form
it's a whole other animal same smell
same giant flowers same great structure
same over-the-top resin production but
the smell and
the uh trichome content on it when you
look at it under a microscope
or even just a you know a loop a
jeweler's loop uh
unbelievable like the the concentration
is is incredible and the smell is just
overwhelming so you can you can take
that
and then say like in in the case of uh
chem 4 you can cross it with something
else it has a completely different
flavor profile say like a train wreck
with a terpenoline
dominant expression and then end up
creating this new flavor profile that is
not only
incredibly intense in a plant that's you
know
really really vigorous but it's incre
it's
completely unique it's an expression
that has never been seen before because
those two
types of terpenes don't end up lining up
when you're
when you're making crosses so it really
opens up the possibility
not only of having a a more vigorous
plant with higher yields and better oil
but also just increasing that total
amount of diversity that's present
wow that's pretty sexy i should we
should have started the show with that
question we would have kept people a lot
longer who
we lost because of the science wow
that's that's really exciting to be able
to try
these plants you must have been
flabbergasted because they're like you
know i know you're
you know uh uh you know you're a breeder
and a professor
and a and a business person but like
you're also a toker
you know what i mean at the end of the
day i love cannabis yeah
so this is my flavor cannabis you must
have been blown away
to see to experience chem 4 as your own
triploid
yeah yeah and we're basically doing that
process
right now this is a shout out to to csi
humboldt
and uh caleb's work uh i've been
following his work for a number of years
and have just always appreciated
his level of detail when when hunting
for different phenotypes and making sure
that things
are quote unquote real uh he does a lot
of work
making s-ones so taking these really
famous plants these famous cuttings
self-pollinating them and then offering
the seeds and
for a plant breeder sifting through
s-ones is where the
a lot of the magic really happens you're
able to lock in the traits that you
really want
and get unique flavor profiles so
for a lot of the thc varieties that i
personally work with
you know if it's not a cutting or
something that's been shared by other
people in the community
uh we're going to seeds from you know
reputable
uh reputable underground breeders who
continue to stay underground and i
appreciate
that who are making these s-ones of
famous plants so we've got things like
durban poison california orange
train wreck purple oracle uh you know
all of these different s1 varieties
that have been released and we're now
basically sifting through
figuring out which ones have exactly
what we're looking for both on a genomic
standpoint and then from the chemical
standpoint and then we're going to make
tetraploids out of them and
basically be ready for 2022 when we're
hoping that federal legalization happens
and everybody in the world can taste
these flavors
damn that's exciting uh i also love uh
caleb's s1 packs like you know
people will put out rag seeds and call
it a breeders pack
and you know it'll just have more seeds
right so you get
more more phenos at a good price
but for me caleb's s1 packs
are like the gold standard as far as
breeders packs you know
there's so much variety he he describes
that he was actually on
shaping fire episode 49 talking about
feminized uh cannabis
and he's all like you know these these
s1 seeds if you have enough of them
you kind of have a a snapshot of what is
possible
you know in that line of seeds and you
know it's it's actually a lot of credit
to
caleb as well uh you just mentioned him
as somebody that you respect
and a couple weeks ago we had ryan lee
on the show
and he mentioned out of nowhere that he
respect caleb inspector from csi
humboldt as well so
that's you know that that that's a lot
of that's a got a lot of good love for a
guy who you know
mostly tries to stay in the underground
yeah and i i
feel bad just for bringing his name up
i'm sorry but uh
well you know he he's not in the shadows
he's just
uh he's just uh happy to stay uh small
and local to humble you know
it you know and it's one of those things
where he's actually doing a tremendous
service to other breeders by being able
to
uh to take these these famous clones
and not just you know reverse them and
make c but he's actually
doing the due diligence to make sure
that it is what it is
uh and and verifying that to the best of
of his ability and i think anybody's
ability at this point
but then also making something like that
available so you know it used to be that
we would ship
clones around the country in you know
dvd cases and that was how the
underground
stayed alive it's how we shared cuttings
with each other and and made sure that
there was
not only you know cannabis plants across
the country and you had sour diesel in
you know new york and in oregon
uh but it was a way of basically
creating culture and camaraderie
uh with people who were taking the same
type of risks that you were
he's been living that and also making
these
these seeds available uh from a breeding
perspective if you can get an
s1 of say train wreck if it's you know a
legitimate
cut which in this case it is you have
all of the possible
permutations of that particular variety
in seed form available to you
and because it's an s1 you're actually
getting uh
expressions of both of the parents and
you can start to sift through that and
figure out well what was it that made
that particular plant
the original train wreck so amazing and
for us we're doing it from a chemical
and a genomic standpoint so
really exciting it's exciting to to be
able to have that as an
opportunity and it's exciting to be
alive at this moment at a time
being able to subject all of these
classic flavors these classic varieties
to really unprecedented analytical
capabilities
this summer actually we got a couple of
the skittles
s-ones uh from caleb here on vashon
and we just opened the packs and we
spread them around different patients on
the island
and um you know we we spread them around
before
the pandemic got more serious and the
idea that we were going to do is that
everybody was going to grow
different seeds from the s1 pack and
then we were going to do kind of like a
a progressive you know wander your way
around the island and
and check out everybody's gardens and
everything and so we're gonna have to do
that somehow more creatively with masks
and crap this year
uh now but um it's really enjoyable you
know for anybody who loves the plant
to check out these s-ones where you're
all like oh
yeah these are all skittles plants i i
can see and smell that
but they all have got you know subtly
different
uh personalities and you know if you're
a nerd for the plant that's just a lot
of fun
but i would love to go along on that it
sounds like it's not going to happen
this year but man what a great idea yeah
i love that
actually you're probably going to
appreciate it more next year because we
also got some of the
the chemdawg s ones and so that's what
we're planning on doing next year
so so let's talk about something that is
uh really a theoretical because
um we'll talk more about you know uh
licensing issues uh here in a little bit
but um
you know i know that the way that your
seeds have to be
sold you know due to the government
regulations is you need to you know you
need to sell to particular farmers and
you can't just sell to the public
and but but as we know you know
occasionally some of those seeds will
find their way into like you know a
friend of a farmer's hands
um what would happen if if
uh um if if you know a home grower
tried to replicate these triploids like
you know some pollen chucker
oh is it like uh pollinating a triploid
yeah totally like like they
you know like well essentially like
people were doing with your other
autoflower cbd seeds right
your autoflower cbd seeds would be put
into the market
there you know the farmer who bought
them from you isn't supposed to share
them
yet somehow miraculously their neighbor
gets some and
and they hit him with pollen in the
basement to try to keep
going on the triploid yeah the the
unfortunate for uh the folks that are
trying that um
you're gonna waste your pollen uh
because just because the flowers are
non-viable
and that's the whole point that's and it
you know we're not doing it to
to stop people from breeding with our
work uh we're trying to help farmers
from being you know cross-contaminated
by a neighbor that's not being
wise in their their planting decisions
or even you know for a farmer that's
uh say planting near a feral population
of hemp like we see all over the midwest
you know basically from
uh you know the southern united states
all the way to
minnesota um yeah you're just not going
to end up with anything except
uh probably increased allergies if
you're you know you have viable pollen
in your basement
so what does the future of triploids
look like right so if we've established
that
we can do a lot more with three sets of
chromosomes than we can with
two and we're just putting our big toe
in the pool of triploids in cannabis and
where we're
you know where you're starting is it for
to be pollen resistant
and you know you're going for you know
yield
and you know pest resistance and drought
resistance and such
i'm assuming that there are a lot other
traits that
can be toyed with um but just aren't
going to be
in you know the first rev of of seeds
what what do you expect us to see coming
from triploids
you know over the next few years it's a
really good question
and uh to be perfectly honest outside of
different flavor combinations that have
never been seen like i was describing
before
uh in the these new cannabinoid profiles
um
you know your flowering time disease
resistance those big things that you'd
already mentioned
uh i'm i'm really just scraping the
surface
uh you know every single week we're
getting another
four whole genomes sequenced and
assembled
and uh you know available for us to uh
basically start digging through and
mining
uh trying to figure out which of these
different genes are
contributing to different aspects of the
plant that could potentially be useful
um i i think in the in the longer term
the way that i view this you know i i
don't have a specific answer but i think
in the longer term what we're seeing is
that these plants are going to have the
capability of having greater
evolutionary adaptability
uh this is a you can go back to the
notion of punctuated equilibrium it's
the
this specific concept of evolution and
how it operates it was put forward by
stephen j
gould one of the most brilliant 20th
century evolutionary
biologists um notion that
over long historical periods you end up
with essentially stasis not a lot of
change that happens
and then in specific moments you have
what's called punctuated equilibrium the
equilibrium is punctuated by
uh either external events that end up
challenging a particular
organism uh an organism's survival
or you know something that is localized
say in the soil or
you know predators coming in and eating
the plants
the idea here is that the more
adaptability that a particular species
has
for any of these particular challenges
the more
fit it is actually going to be so as we
see you know the ravages of climate
change
or uh issues with you know
weeds and in fields or you know some of
the the larger ecological pressures that
that are undoubtedly going to be coming
down on us in the 21st century
these plants have the capability of
responding to that
in a way that we we can't even foresee
at this point
right on that's very exciting and it
also sounds like it's a real
open-ended kind of answer right the
the answer is um we don't know what
might still be in these plants because
we're still
learning the genome and also we're not
sure what we're gonna
need them to do yet because our you know
as our
as climate change continues we're not
sure
how it's gonna manifest so it's kind of
like a you know a big
open-ended question which actually makes
me feel really like
enthusiastic for you know the the
the the i don't know the the future
geneticists
and probably even more so the pot
smokers that are in college right now
who are studying these sciences
what a great time to be a you know 18 19
21 year old something like that in
school where you're able to actually
study this in the classroom get into a
lab
and then find yourself matriculating out
of school and go
into legit companies that are working
like this and have this be
your life's work i mean how badass is
that what a great time to be coming into
your career in cannabis
yeah and i i only got here because i you
know basically got let go from the
university for being a proponent of
cannabis uh so i'm incredibly thankful
to be in the position that i'm at
but you know the younger folks that we
have in our company right now who are
recent graduates you know with
horticulture degrees or botany degrees
or plant breeding degrees
uh they they have a really hard time
uh keeping a smile off of their face
because this is like this is
the moment in time it's this golden age
of cannabis breeding and discovery
that you know you really only get to be
around
one time you know as it's happening and
it's it's happening
um one other thing that may be
worthwhile noting
is this idea that you know one of the
problems that the midwest has i brought
that up
it's good to have a triploid because you
can't be pollinated by the feral
populations that are left over from
uh you know fiber farming uh in the
first part of the 20th century these
native populations have established
themselves and basically continue to
thrive because it's a fairly adaptable
and plastic plant um one of the ways
that we can end up
dealing with that i think over time it's
a bigger concern here in oregon where
you know you had a
huge explosion of industrial hemp farms
where people were using male and female
seeds inappropriately
and then basically just leaving the area
and they let you know
we're seeing it right now there's fields
all over in the willamette valley and in
southern oregon
where the farmers farmed last year
didn't take care of their crop
and they're gone now but the seeds
remain and so you have male and female
populations popping up
creating a feral population where there
never was one before
um that's a very very difficult thing to
control
one of the things that we're working on
is being able to use uh
tetraploids and diploids in rotation so
you basically grow
your tetraploids for four or five years
in a specific area and then you can
switch back to a diploid
to make sure that you don't have uh
feral populations that pop up
you can use the ploity to your advantage
to basically
stop uh feral populations from emerging
that reminds me a lot of those
mosquitoes that are in the news right
now
where they they gmo'd up some mosquitoes
that don't breed and they're introducing
the population so the mosquitoes are
breeding with
with sterile other mosquitoes
and even though you know we're talking
about triploids which are not
gmo we will repeat um the idea is kind
of the same what you're talking about
this weed you know
this feral reduction because it will uh
it'll stop them from producing um usable
seed
that's exactly right and again just to
highlight that
not gmo we're taking something that
naturally occurs
it's just we didn't we didn't know it
and to be perfectly honest i bet there
are people who are growing cannabis
plants right now
in their basement in their garage in
their closet
that are tetraploid and they just don't
know it because these these plants do
pop
up naturally in populations it's just
very very rare and
most people don't have a forty thousand
dollar piece of uh
uh science equipment to be able to test
in their home you know whether or not
it's a tetraploid or a diploid so it's
basically using this new knowledge
uh to really be able to push
both farming and ecology forward
um you know we don't have to insert
genes from other species
to have a good outcome it's you don't
have to genetically modify
organisms to be able to be good
ecologists we can actually use what's
naturally available
and use the tools that we've learned
about in science to make the
success rates much higher and much
faster uh
to actually push us forward right on
that's beautiful i don't think i'm going
to top that
so as we as we wrap up here you know i
want to do something different you and i
have talked
you know this is your third time on
shaping fire and
each time you come on you're usually
coming to share
some some new aspect of science with us
um and then after the interview
you get bombarded with emails and
contacts and all this kind of stuff
more more than you can handle so um
why don't we go ahead and answer a
couple of the questions that you get hit
with
well this stuff's all on your frequently
asked questions on the website
but let's just let's let's let's hit the
big two
um like how do people buy your seed
and i guess that's pretty much the
question and is there any
and is there any left for this year
because
like people are generally pretty
disappointed when they find out to get
your seed
that they generally have to be a prior
customer so why don't you lay that down
real quick before before we wrap
up uh yeah great question i appreciate
it um
we can always get seed from our webs not
always we can get seed from our website
oregoncbdseeds.com
at this point you have to have an
industrial hemp license issued by
either your state or by the usda there's
really nothing that we can do about that
we did stop sales and we do this every
year
unless you are in a state like
california or florida where there's
different growing seasons
we shut our sales down for for each year
july 1st because we don't want to take
advantage of farmers
if you're trying to get plants in the
ground or seed started after july 1st in
the northern hemisphere
you're you're really missing out you've
missed the boat and you're not going to
have a good crop
so we halt um we'll start sale uh sales
for
2021 on these new triploid veren rich
100 compliant with the usda 0.3 thc rule
uh on january 1st of 2021 and hopefully
by that point
uh we can have a little bit more clarity
from the usda on who's actually allowed
to
to purchase seed and whether or not we
can get these to home growers
so we'll be working diligently to try to
make that happen in the meantime
after you brought your uh your cbd
autoflower to the market which honestly
kind of remade
the cbd market globally
you sold out of those wicked fast
because of course everybody wanted tens
of thousands of them
should we expect that with triploids for
the next few years as well kind of like
we're still
seeing with like some of the cbg stuff
is it you know you're here
talking about it because triploids are
the
cutting edge of of cannabis uh breeding
but is it gonna take three four years
for enough of them to be produced that
they're going to be
widely available how how much should we
expect on seeing these
uh we have enough production capability
to take care of the entire country
next year uh no problem we've spent the
last two years
focused on uh building out our our
facilities
and basically taking everything that we
made from seed sales and putting it back
into science
people and in our production environment
to make sure that we could
we could meet those goals and get
everybody taken care of
right on well congratulations on that
scaling because it was only a few years
ago that you were all like
damn we keep on selling out
it's true and then all that frustrated
people to no end
it's you know you do everything that you
can to try to uh
to meet the demand and keep people happy
um but
sometimes it's hard it takes time to
build capacity
but we are there and we're we're really
happy to be able to
to get people what they need fantastic
well seth as always thank you so much
for joining us and
sharing your very unique perspective
from where you're sitting
in in cannabis it's always cool to hear
about the the new things that uh
you know cannabis scientists in general
are working on but
since uh since genetics is your
bread and butter it's nice to hear what
you are going to be bringing out before
it comes out so thank you so much for
your for your kindness and your stories
well thanks for having me this is the
the best show on the internet and
you got some of the best people
listening to it i can't wait for him to
hear it
awesome thank you brother i'll see you
again soon if you want to find out more
about oregon cbd seeds uh you can go
ahead and go to their website at
oregoncbdc's.com um also it's great to
follow their instagram
at oregoncbd you can find more episodes
of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shapingfire.com
and wherever you get your podcasts
if you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download
your review will help others find the
show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for insights
into the latest cannabis news exclusive
videos and giveaways
on the shaping fire website you will
also find transcripts of today's podcast
as well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast
that's at shaping fire and at shango
lose on instagram
be sure to check out shaping fire
youtube channel for exclusive interviews
farm tours and cannabis lectures does
your company want to reach our national
audience of cannabis enthusiasts
email hotspot at shippingfire.com to
find out how
thanks for listening to shaping fire
i've been your host shango los