[Music]
in the days of complete cannabis
prohibition
cannabis folks didn't have as much
access to advanced science
to complex analytical technology or most
of the great scientists who are now
feeling more comfortable to sign on to
cannabis related research
because of this our entire scene
including heritage cultivators
newcomers to cannabis and big
agriculture are all rejiggering their
relationship to both cannabis
and technology some of the science like
terpene and potency tests
are clearly a win and few question their
usefulness
even though we are still questioning
their accuracy
the other end of the spectrum is full on
genetically modified cannabis dna
and while that is already happening in
labs the vast number of cannabis
consumers are not very supportive of it
each cannabis consumer needs to decide
for themselves how much science they
want in their cannabis
no part of today's discussion is gmo
no part of this discussion involves
genetic insertion into the cannabis
genome
today's discussion is heavy on science
technique though and much of it
describes lab techniques that are
new to cannabis so even though some of
the vocabulary may be new
and some of the techniques may sound
like science fiction they in no way
degrade the cannabis genome or the
pool of available genetics most of the
techniques actually preserve cannabis
genetics for the future
today's episode is all about tissue
culture i wanted to do this topic
because i have a poor understanding of
it
and i have a general adversion to
laboratories as well
and yet there's so much science in
cannabis discussions today
and from my early research into tissue
culture i realized that most cannabis
folks were using the term
tissue culture really loosely without a
firm understanding of the concepts we
were talking about
including myself the goal of today's
episode is to translate tissue culture
for the lay person
with nothing more than a high school
understanding of science
most of the episode will focus on
micropropagation since that is mostly
the sort of
tissue culture we use in cannabis but
we'll round out the show in the third
set by discussing all the tricks that
fall under the umbrella
of the general term tissue culture so
wash your hands and get ready for some
time in the lab
if you want to learn about cannabis
health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer
i encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter we'll send you new podcast
episodes as they come out
delivered right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week
and videos too don't rely on social
media to let you know when a new episode
is published
sign up for the updates to make sure you
don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter
there's nothing else you need to do to
win except receive that newsletter
this month we are giving away two prize
packs each with a bag of happy endings
root stimulation tea mix and ocean
bounty flowering tea mix
from our friends at green bicycles kevin
jodrey turned me on to this
mix about five years ago and i've been
using it in my gardens ever since
so go to shapingfire.com to sign up for
the newsletter
and be entered into this month's and all
future newsletter prize drawings
you are listening to shaping fire and i
am your host shango los
today my guest is ryan lee ryan is a
professional cannabis researcher
and plant breeder specializing in
cultivar design
and the inheritance of the therapeutic
compounds in cannabis
his background training is in
neuroscience and studying the
endocannabinoid system
with a strong focus on genetics his
post-grad work at the university of
british columbia
was in plant breeding and biotechnology
ryan lee is founder of chimera genetic
resource management
and the kimovar corporation chimera is
essentially a seed bank and cannabis
germplasm firm
operating in europe for 20 years
keemvar corporation is based in canada
and focuses on breeding specialty
cannabis varieties
laboratory analytics cultivation
consulting
cultivar selection and germplasm
sourcing
licensing and importation for licensed
producers
kimavar has guided clients worldwide to
navigate international regulations
surrounding the movement of cannabis
genetic material
ryan recently appeared on shaping fire
episode 64
about feminized seeds and female-only
breeding
today we're going to talk about the
application of tissue culture techniques
in cannabis cultivation welcome to the
show ryan welcome back brother
thanks so much for having me again shane
so man let's let's start by clarifying
what tissue culture really is because
i think most folks throw around that
term pretty darn loosely
um would you give us a quick overview of
like the total breadth of the term but
then
hone in a bit more on what people in the
cannabis industry usually intend when
they use the term tissue culture
yeah absolutely um i think tissue
culture is really like an overarching
term
it's kind of like saying cultivation
there's so many different ways that you
can grow a plant
and and tissue culture is really the
same thing when we say tissue culture
really what we're doing is we're
culturing
plants or parts of plants in a glass
test tube or a
some type of plastic or glass sterilized
vessel
and we call those pieces of plants
explants
i guess a little bit of history might
help around the turn of the 20th century
like 1900s
scientists were starting to learn about
bacteria and fungus and how they could
grow these things on petri dish
petri dishes and i guess a german
biologist wondered if he could do the
same thing with plants or plant parts
and so he started harvesting leaves and
you know cross sections of stems and
little bits of cells and they would take
the cells and mash them all up
and and create something called a
suspension culture and they would see
you know like we can grow these very
small bacteria and fungi
fungi can we also do the same with plant
cells
and that it that brings up a term called
total potency
which really means the ability of any
cell to regenerate a whole plant
from that one cell is that like stem
cells
yeah we have it canon or not cannabis
all plants have
uh they're the equivalent of stem cells
we call them callus which is really
stem cells are what we call
undifferentiated tissue and usually when
we make callus
it's a d-differentiated tissue and so
that means you might have a cell type
that was like for example
here's a perfect example when you when
you make cuttings
the cells along the stem they're at that
point in time they're stem
cells i don't mean stem cells they're
cells of a
from the stem of a plant and when we cut
those little branches off and expose it
to a high oxygen high
moisture environment like you'd find in
a rooting
pack or a rockwool cube or something
that
um that encourages the cell
to change its cell type and become a
root cell
and so when we actually see roots
growing out of the side
of a cutting that's d differentiation
that cell has differentiated itself from
a stem
type cell to a root type cell
and so we can we can manipulate that
processor we've learned that we can
manipulate that process
and we can take very tiny pieces of
um of plants like we can section out
just the meristem which is a
a very small structure in the tip of a
plant chute
that produces the entire plant lit but
that's where all the cell division takes
place
and it's about the size of a pin and you
can cut those out and grow them on
these agar mediums like we're talking
about
and uh and eventually culture that
little piece into a full plant
is it is it the dna of the plant that's
driving all this because the
instructions are there in every single
cell
yeah i would consider the meristem
actually an organ so it's an it's not
just a dna it's a
an organized cell type that are dividing
uh in a specific genetic program
so it's it's probably a little more
advanced than just the dna
thinking of it as just the dna or a
couple of cells it's actually a an
actively dividing organ yeah
all right so so if we've got this big
umbrella
which is tissue culture and and you know
over the course of the show we're going
to talk about a bunch of things that are
under this umbrella of tissue culture
um my i guess my best understanding of
it
is that you know 80 or 90
of what we're doing in cannabis as far
as tissue culture goes
all falls into the subsection of
micro propagation and then the other 10
or 20
are like all this random things that
we're going to talk about mostly in the
third set but
but would you you know does am i getting
it right that micro propagation is
really what just about everybody
in cannabis is talking about when we
talk about tissue culture like off the
cuff
yeah that's really the focus right now i
think that serves an industry need
to be able to produce large amounts of
virus free mold free pest free plants
and and we can do that using
micropropagation but there's other
other types of things that we can do and
um there's something called a
metabolite reactor or a bioreactor and
uh
you know at one point in time scientists
were trying to figure out if we could
get cannabis cells to produce
cannabinoids
um you know without having to actually
grow the plant during this
crazy pro prohibition area that we've
kind of just graduated from
but you know you could do something like
you take some leaves off of a plant
and chop them up very very finely using
a
you know a delicate blender or a some
kind of
sectioning device and then you suspend
those cells
into a big um like a big erlenmeyer
flask one of those big
kind of triangle-shaped flasks that sits
on a
orbital shaker or a spinning shaker and
that just kind of shakes the
the the soup broth gently
and provides lots of oxygen and these
cells just float around
in the in the medium and the thought was
that you know perhaps we could get these
plants to produce
uh cannabinoids because that's actually
been you're able to do that with other
plant species
but it turned out that of course the
production of cannabinoids needs the
resin
the resin glands the trichomes so we
actually can't do that
um but you can you can use that same
technique
to grow embryos or produce something
called artificial seeds
which are essentially little shoot tips
encased in a
like an alginate or an agar jelly it
looks like a little jelly bean
and i'll try to put some of those up on
my instagram page so people can see
those while we're
we're talking about it yeah but they're
just essentially little ways that we can
produce different plant parts in in
these glass beakers
um but like you said the most common
thing in the cannabis industry is to use
those
to grow plantlets sterile plantlets
which we can either section by
subculturing and
multiply them into a whole army of
plants
army of plants i like that you know so
many of us we just want you know
overgrow right
army of plants bring it on yeah well i
mean the truth is
you know these large production systems
that we're seeing start to be grown all
over california washington
they require armies of plants i mean you
plant you know
the grape growers are pretty lucky they
or even hop growers are pretty lucky you
plant the crop once and then
it just keeps growing year after year
whereas cannabis i mean if you're if
you're planting
or if you're harvesting maybe two times
in a summer or three if you're really
organized
you know you need a full complement of
plants to be planted every year
or every planting so it really it the
production of armies of plants
will be um part of this industry
right all right so if we are talking
about creating armies of plants
as being like the primary usage
of titu culture in cannabis um
let's focus on this micro propagation
because it's it's you know it's what
most
everybody's talking about anyway so this
is a strategy to
multiply a plant very quickly under very
clean
controls in a lab and i mean my
understanding of it is essentially
cloning but with exceptionally immature
plant material like
at the cellular level um cellular level
would you walk us through what that
you know the science of that because the
the idea of even
handling and manipulating the cells
um is you know one step removed from my
understanding so walk us
walk us through that process yeah so
these
these agar containers we'll call them
are tissue culture vessels
um you you really have to think of it
like a plant in a pot so just like
you're making you're transplanting
any plant into a container
the the tissue culture vessel holds
it it does all the same thing it's got a
place for the plant to grow
it has the medium or the the sorry the
hormones and the food source the
nutrients that are needed by the plant
we also put some sugar in there and some
other hormones that'll help
help help the plant grow as it goes
along
but it's such a perfect space and a
perfect environment
you got to remember when we put a little
piece of an explant or a little piece of
a plant
into that tissue culture medium there's
no roots
right the plant is just it's just like a
little cutting so the plant has to be
able to
be able to absorb everything that it
needs
from that um that jar
and one of the problems is that that
environment is so suited to growing
anything even even other
molds and and bacteria that if the plant
part is not
completely sterilized before we put it
in the jar
it may bring in a virus or a bacteria or
a fungus with it
and that fungus or bacteria will then be
able to
um propagate itself much much more
quickly
than the the plant part that we've put
in there and so that's what we call
contamination of the vessel
so we have to uh autoclave these jars
at very high temperature and pressure
before we put the plant in there it's
all sealed up
you make your medium you add your
hormones and your food and your sugar
and that all goes in the jar and then we
put it in the pressure cooker or an
autoclave
and that sterilizes the plant medium and
so
the next step is is cooling that
material down and letting the agar
harden
and then we use something called a
laminar flow hood which is essentially
a very high quality
uh hepa filter that creates an
air flow that passes through this filter
process so
any air that comes in contact with the
plant has actually had all the fungus
and viruses and bacteria been removed
from the plant is that the same kind of
hood that i'm talking about with people
who are
growing psilocybin mushrooms very
similar yeah very similar same kind of
process again the same with the idea
is that you want to maintain sterility
like you really want
the only organism that you're putting
into the pot is your target
yeah your target so either cannabis or
like you said mushrooms before we go on
let me let's break down a little bit
about
this uh this petri dish so so first of
all um what's
what's agar agar is like
um it's an extract from seaweed i mean
many of you walking by the seaside you
can
you sometimes you pick up seaside and
they've got these little kind of jelly
balls on them or whatever
um it's that kind of thing so they take
it then they ex you know they'll they'll
extract it from these these plants boil
it all down and purify it
and really all of it all that it does is
it gives a matrix
um it adds some solidify it's a
solidifying agent
for your liquid like we were talking
about the bioreactors before
or the embryo culture reactors if you
have these little plant parts in sugar
water with all the right nutrients and
hormones
and the the your solution is actively
moving around so that it's being
oxygenated
you can actually grow these plant parts
just in the liquid
um but the agar adds like a solid
aspect to that it just solidifies the
medium and it kind of makes it more
stable
um you know we can the plant can remain
upright in in that ag
so is it kind of like a neutral and
inert thing
absolutely okay i get it so it's just
they're kind of kind of like to hold
[ __ ] there
yep it's just it's just a medium all
right
so then you also said that uh in this
agar
um you're putting these uh you know tiny
plant cuttings
well like we've we're already talking
about at a cellular level right
and i you know when i make a clone it's
a pretty big cutting
so how small of the cuttings
are placed in these petri dishes like
are we talking about
like you know an inch that we've cut
with a scalpel or are we talking about
like a
sliver like what how small is small
yeah well they ca they ideally you want
them to be small because the bigger
the bigger the plant the more
opportunity that we're going to have
missed
some of um the bacteria or the viruses
or the molds
in our sterilization process so we want
to get down to pretty small just by
getting down to a pretty small part like
a centimeter
you can go that small you can get the
pet like again we're talking you know we
can do all these different types of
medium you can actually use pieces of
leaf
you can use cross sections of stems you
can try to do roots
or you can grow the meristem like i was
talking about or or even the auxiliary
bud
like you know if you imagine a plant
that's growing we've got the shoots
coming off the top and then you might
have say three leaves coming off
uh you know two on one side of the stem
and one on the other side
and everywhere that a leaf stem or the
petiole
meets the the main stem junction that's
there's a a space where a new branch
will grow and any grower knows this if
you if you watch plants
that the leaf the the new shoots always
come out between
a leaf and the stem and so that little
spot
on the on the crotch of the you can call
it the crotch of the
the plant in between the stem that shoot
that actually
has um what it was called an auxiliary
bud
or a and that is just the place on the
plant where that shoot will grow
and so we can actually cut we can
actually cut all the
leaves off and and just plant
the node where that piece of the the
chute will grow
and so there's no you got to consider
there's no leaves
right we've cut them all off and so
because there's no leaves
that plant can't harvest co2 from the
air
right and so we've put sugar
into the medium directly because photos
sugar is
sugars are the byproduct of
photosynthesis so by putting sugar in
the medium
we kind of bypass that photosynthesis
step and allow the plant to have access
to these
these molecules so they can just
incorporate them rather than having to
synthesize them themselves
so is that little growth that occurs
in the crotch uh is th is that the
meristem
yeah there is a there is a meristem in
the auxiliary bud yeah so
define that would you mirror stem
so the meristem is it's kind of like the
center of generation for all the plants
like
if you look at the top of a a growing
plant
where the leaves are growing and you can
you know you can get in there and fold
the leaves down and try to get to that
most central point that most central
point where everything is growing
out of is the meristem so
um you know
think of it like a worm like i don't
know if people have ever heard of this
experiment where you can take a worm and
cut it in half and both hats
will live they and they can regenerate
their own parts it's kind of the same
with cannabis plant
anywhere that there's an auxiliary or
an uh or a an apical meristem in the
apical meristem is just the one on the
very top of the plant
that thing can generate an entire new
plant from it
so kind of think of it like the the
source code you know what i mean that's
like the
is is the central meristemness
of the cannabis plant only uh
present in certain parts of the plant or
is it
uh everywhere because you know like like
you know
i'm not super good at making clones
right and like you know i have put a lot
of effort into
making my cone or my clone uh
cuts you know right there at the point
where
the you know the new growth of the
leaves are on the side so i'm like oh
this is supposed to be where all the
the new hormones are and i'm like really
careful but but are you telling me that
like
most of the plant can be used as a clone
in kind of like a random way or are are
these meristems only a few places on the
plant
no anywhere anywhere that the stem meets
a leaf junction there's going to be a
meristem oh i see
okay um so but using tissue culture
we can actually also get the plant to
produce new meristems from other parts
of tissues
where they don't exist so you know yeah
it's kind of a weird thing but we can we
can take a leaf
and grow what we call people might have
noticed when you
when you're rooting cuttings for example
they go the the stem goes through a
stage before the roots start growing out
where they kind of swell a little bit
and they become
like a little bit of a rough bumpy
texture that's called
callus and callus is kind of the
intermediate or what we think of as the
as the stem cell it's d
differentiated tissue it's tissue that's
kind of
it hasn't been genetically destined to
do anything
so it can kind of become anything at
that point in time callus can become a
root it can be encouraged to become a
shoot
but you really have to encourage the
plant using hormones to do
you know to guide it down the path that
you want it to go through
all right all right cool well thank you
for going down that with me there's one
more
um ingredient in those petri dishes i
want to talk about
you said that we're going to add a
little sugar so i'm curious to know
like what kind of sugar and why sugar
i mean we use it in compost tea and we
talk about that all the time on the show
but
um you know in this particular
application why are we using it
so like i said sugar you know sugar is
the end result of photosynthesis
light comes in it hits the cells in the
leaf
and there's a whole reaction that
happens but what essentially comes at
the other end is sugar
and so we there is a form of sugar and
so we actually use sucrose just go to
the grocery store and buy a couple of
pounds of sugar
and that gets you know it get it gets
mixed in at like
i can't even remember it's like a few
grams per liter
um and and so essentially we bypass
the photosynthesis and we just put the
sugar directly into the into the food
source and that way the plant has a
carbon source because
like i said if you cut off all the
leaves and we're just trying to grow
a little auxiliary bud from a small
piece of stem
and there's no leaf there's no way for
the plant to harvest co2 from the air or
the explant to harvest co2 from the air
that makes sense and so we kind of
bypass that process and put the sugar
right into the
into the medium so that the plant can
actually suck that up through
um you know the the piece of the plant
that's in contact with the medium
so you were talking earlier about how um
like what an opportunity this
environment is right you're like okay
we're gonna we're gonna we're gonna try
to grow
cannabis you know plantlets in this
thing
but but it would love to grow fungus
and you know probably bacteria and
anything else that happens to be
in the room um what are
the you know what are the sterile
conditions that have to be
set and generally how are those made
in this tissue culture environment i'm
assuming this is you know a tissue
culture
lab yeah it's all done in the lab but i
think i like to use the
cut finger analogy so i mean if you're
out working away
in the garden or in your shop or
whatever and you cut your finger you get
a big old deep gash on your finger
the first thing you do is you run it
under water and take the blood away but
you want to sterilize it right you want
to clean it up so that there's no
bacteria or
things that are going to start growing
in the cut because our bodies
you know the inside of your body we've
got all these nutrients it's like a
perfect place for a bacteria to come and
set up home
and and so too is the tissue culture
vessel it's kind of the same thing
so we want it to be completely sterile
and sterile just means that we've we've
killed 100
of the bacteria the fungal spores
and any viruses or any other organisms
that might be living
in the medium and we do that by we make
a big batch of this
of our agar and then we pour say 25
milliliters into a small baby food
size jar and then those get special lids
on them and then we can stack
you know a whole bunch of those in an
autoclave or a pressure cooker
and uh for anybody that's ever done
canning you know
canned fruits or jams or or even
you know different vegetables or
whatever that you can can meets
we seal up the lids in these jars and we
put put them in a large
container like a pressure cooker
that's essentially like a big it's more
or less a bomb
it's like a big metal container
that we heat from the bottom and we put
water in the container obviously we seal
it all up and then we heat it from the
bottom
and the the heating it from the bottom
creates
a steam inside this big vessel and so
you have all these big really locks and
tighteners and fasteners that hold the
lid down i mean it's a serious piece of
equipment and we actually by
by letting the steam build up
it gets to a really high temperature but
the pressure also increases immensely
inside this vessel
and um that is that will actually
sterilize
anything that's in the jar it kills all
the bacteria and it kills all the the
funguses
fungal spores or anything that are in
the medium so that when we take it off
uh the stove and we let it cool back
down and releasing the st
the steam from the container those jars
can then be taken over to
the laminar flow hood you actually take
the whole autoclave or the whole the
whole autoclave but the whole container
over to your laminar flow hood and we we
take the jars out and let them cool
in the laminar flow so once they've come
out of this
pressurization process the sterilization
process
they only exist in an environment where
there's no bacteria
so like i don't have a lot of lab
experience and this question
very well may illustrate that but it
kind of sounds to me like this
this this pressure cooker that you're
talking about is the exact
opposite of of using a vac oven
that we use in a lab as well like where
the vacuum
is you know uh trying to create
different different atmosphere
by creating a vacuum whereas this is
doing the opposite it's trying to
ultra pressurize it also to create an
unlivable environment am i anywhere
accurate on that that's exactly what it
does
it creates an unlivable environment
right and so that anything that's gone
through the process
dies and then from that point on it's
what we call
sterile and so think of you know when
we're talking about the lab
or the laminar flow hood this sterile
air environment
think of that literally like a surgical
suite or a surgical room
um you know when when the doctors and
nurses go in to do surgery
they're all gowned up they've got
special gloves on and masks on that are
stopping them from breathing you know
just like we already know is about
mastering kovid right i mean it's the
same process
you want your doctors to have on a mask
so that they're not blowing out bacteria
into the open patient that's lying in
front of them
right and and that's kind of like this
think of you can kind of think of the
sterile
uh jar as like the patient right any
time you open it
um there's a risk that we're gonna
introduce
again either a virus a bacteria a pest
or or
uh some fungus into it and we really
this whole process
we want to do in the absence of all
those organisms
all right now that we've established
really well really really well
what are in these petri dishes um let's
kind of reorient ourselves
so so explain how the
cannabis industry right now is using
uh this for um for cultivation
is is one of these petri dishes
going to make a gazillion plantlets and
all these like
like little tiny ass clones or is it is
it going to be
one petri dish per clone
uh no no it really won't be one petri
dish
per clone at the end of the stage it
gets to be that but
so when we think about it there's really
a few parts to tissue culture the first
part is
sterilization and then what we go into
something called initiation where we
actually put the
the sterile piece of plant material into
the jar
if you put that plant material into the
jar and let it put the lid on
take it to your sterile culture room
that plant will actually grow
inside the jar for say two weeks okay
and then after two weeks you come back
along
you can take that plant part or that
grown
plant part out of the jar under
laminar flow again in this sterile
environment and you can cut it up into
probably
two or three or maybe five new shoots
and plant each of them again in their
own jar and that's called subculturing
where we actually take one culture
vessel we take it out divide it into
multiple plant parts
and then create five new vessels okay
in doing that we've skipped the step of
having to sterilize
five times those individual plants that
are going in so
the the beauty of subculturing is that
you can
you can mult you can essentially
multiply your plant material
without having to go through the
initiation process again
okay so so if you think of of doing that
one plant goes into the jar
two weeks of vegetative growth we take
it out you've now got a plant that we
can cut out five plant parts
each of those goes into their own
individual jar they can go back into the
culture room for another two weeks
and then what comes out is 25 plants
right so overall it reminds me of
mothers right just
like regular old mothers yeah it is it's
very in the same way it is very much
like the mother process but the the
mothering process
is all done in a greenhouse environment
or a grow room environment
and you're subject to bacteria and molds
and fungus and anything else that's
floating around in the air or what's
brought in with
um you know the cultivators as they come
in and out maybe they're bringing bugs
in on their clothes
so it's it's just a different way of
doing the same thing
uh in a sterile environment and you can
imagine the logarithmic curve that you
get you know after
like i said if you go 1 to 5 5 to 25 the
next multiplication is
125 the next multiplication is you know
we're well over 600 so
it it it really starts to grow
exponentially
um and so that's that's it it takes a
period of time i mean you're not gonna
you know if you want to plant a million
cuttings in a year you have to start
today
right but it does allow you to hit this
critical mass where
the the like i said the multiplication
becomes exponential
so all right so if we we've got this one
original plant um for for lack of
vocabulary i'm going to call this the
mother right this is the plant that we
want to make a bunch of
because we want to micro propagate it
because we're gonna fill our
field our cultivation facility with it
or whatever
um you know i would think that there are
some attributes we would want this
mother to have i mean like sure
sure we wanted to have a good terpene
profile and good potency and all and all
the regular stuff we're used to right
but because
we are doing it in the lab and we are
doing the sorcery with it
i would think that there are other
attributes that we would be looking for
in our plant that makes it appropriate
for micro
propagation so so what do we look for
in a plant that makes it especially
a good candidate for micro propagation
yeah that's actually a really good
question
and the answer is that not nobody is
currently doing that
um wait like we don't even know we don't
even know what plants make good
micro propagation plants no i think so
cannabis is a really interesting species
in many many ways
but in one of the ways it's really
interesting is that like every single
trait that we can consider the in the
plant
there's usually there's usually almost
always
a great amount of variation like for
example let's just talk about height
you can have tall plants medium plants
short plants right yielding plants
low me low yielding medium yielding high
yielding uh
terpene plants you can have low low
levels of terpenes high levels of
terpenes
cannabinoids the same thing so the point
that i'm trying to make is that any
trait that we can look at in the plant
there's a continuum of performance right
for that trade
and and currently the way that we're
doing tissue culture is people are
growing
cannabis the way they normally do
they're selecting the plants that they
want to be
ideal for their production environment
and then once we've selected the plant
you know we get our blue dream or our
cookies or
og comes out at the end of whatever
process we're doing
to to select plants we then take those
plants back into the tissue culture
system and see how well they they
perform in tissue culture
and we've come to learn over the past 15
or 20 years
that there is actually different plants
perform either well or poorly in micro
propagation right some planets just
don't like the process
they want more vitamin b or they want a
specific hormone
they just don't grow quickly when you
put them in into tissue cultures so
it might be in the future that the
question of
does this plant propagate well
under tissue culture is actually a
criteria that we use
for um selecting individual plants but
currently we're not doing that
man i can't i can't think that we're too
far off from that you know with the
with the increased interest in corporate
ag
and everything and these like crazy huge
fields they've got in california now
i've got to think that's the future as
much as it may not mean my flavor
yeah well the more listen the more we
move towards scientists being involved
in the selection of plants
um these these added
characteristics are going to start being
looked at before the problem with
handing it all over to science is they
just don't get the culture right i mean
you have to it's kind of like you know
if you're making wine
the people that make the best wine in
the world like they consume wine
right because they understand the things
they understand the processes that go
into production that
yield quality at the end
and we just the scientists aren't at
that point with cannabis where they
really under the the vast majority of
the pure scientists
that are being brought in to cannabis i
mean
the the most successful companies that i
see operating in cannabis space
they have a science team or a group of
people that are bringing science to the
the the venture but they're also people
from the cannabis community that
understand
all the important things that go along
with you know
cannabis production and it's really the
marriage of those two things that that
makes the win
right yeah i don't i don't really want a
scientist
who has been over in ornamentals
you know making plans for somebody's
freaking landscaping to be making these
choices
i want mean gene to be making those
choices you know
somebody who i respect because they have
done the
the propagation and the in the in the
sifting in the old ways right
i want i want somebody like that but
with this
ridiculous science education to be
making those choices
and you know i don't know there's maybe
there's a handful of those people
nowadays but i would guess that those
are probably these
freaking lucky kids who are in their
early 20s now
who are coming up in this post
prohibition
environment who are going to learn that
stuff and they're going to come up and
and they're you know they're pot smokers
who also
are getting science degrees yeah well
you know i
i see plant breeding or plant
improvements as really
it's not a one-man sport it's a team
sport
right and it's kind of one of those
situations where it's like it takes
teamwork to drape make the dream work
right like
you know it's a cheesy thing but it's
like if you could pair
you know mean gene with a really high
advanced
uh plant scientist that understands
things
about plants that maybe mean gene
doesn't understand or someone like
myself doesn't understand
that you can actually you know get a lot
farther of the synergy between
the experience the two those two
different worlds of experience meeting
together or being married together
that's great i i can already start to
imagine
the teams that i want to put together
now um all right so we should probably
take our first commercial break
thank you very much ryan uh you are
listening to shaping fire and my guest
today is
cannabis geneticist ryan lee
with the national hemp program in flux
due to stringent thc testing
requirements
brother seth and eric crawford continue
to release seeds to hemp farmers that
will be legal
no matter how you grow them or when you
test them
these new varieties from oregon cbd
seeds have substantial amounts of cbdv
cbgv cbcv and thcv
while always staying below the point
three percent thc limit
and guaranteeing complying crops for
farmers every time
also these new varieties cannot be
pollinated by your neighbor's
uncontrolled pollen
or a rogue male in your own crop either
oregon cbd seeds are non-gmo certified
too
oregon cbd seeds was founded and funded
in 2015 by seth and eric
maxing out their personal credit cards
without outside
investment they continue to refuse
outside investment that would change
their company culture
oregon cbd grows tons of fresh food on
their research farms for local food
banks
literally tons of food they also give
away tens of thousands of pounds of r d
flour to patients as their company began
to succeed
seth and eric started donating money to
the cannabis medicine and hemp fiber
cause 2
by giving millions of dollars to oregon
state university
in order to establish the world's
leading cannabis genomics research
program
and they treat their employees right
oregon cbd pays for full health and
dental coverage for their employees
a 401k program and their minimum
starting wage is 20 bucks an hour
plus everyone shares food from the farms
seth
has been on shaping fire a few times to
talk about novel cannabinoids
you can check out episodes 25 and 37 on
cbd cultivars in the hemp market
episode 66 on triploid cannabis genetics
and the very first shaping fire live
episode 47
with seth and soil expert jeff lowenfels
talking about autoflowers
if you are a hemp farmer and you want to
grow reliable seeds that are sure to
thrive in past testing
check out oregoncbdseeds.com to learn
more about buying seeds for the 2021
season
that's oregoncbdseeds.com
dissolved oxygen in the root zone is a
challenge gaia's brand of ultrafine nano
bubble systems will help your garden
thrive in ways you may not have
considered
no matter if you grow in soil
hydroponics or aquaponics
gaia's ultrafine nanobubble systems will
increase your dissolved oxygen
and increase your yield often the first
sign of inadequate oxygen supply to the
roots is wilting of the plant under warm
conditions and high light levels
insufficient oxygen results in an
accumulation of toxins
and an insufficient amount of water and
mineral absorption
if oxygen starvation continues mineral
deficiencies will begin to show
roots die back and plants will become
stunted
healthy roots supplied with sufficient
oxygen are able to absorb nutrient ions
selectively
from the surrounding solution as
required in studies
this has shown a 30 increase in plant
growth
not only do ultra fine oxygen bubbles
allow your plants to thrive
but they will keep your drip lines and
irrigation pipes and plumbing clean too
because algae pythium and other invasive
species only survive in low oxygen
environments
and the gaia system only costs about two
dollars per day to run
gaia ultrafine oxygen nano bubblers
are also great for making compost teas
and wild crafted nutrient teas
the smaller bubbles of truly dissolved
oxygen
allow more microbes to reproduce faster
go to gaia's website at h2o5.com
to learn more about using dissolved
oxygen and how to purchase this simple
yet amazing technology
that's h205.com
as cannabis regulations become more
demanding and consumers become more
educated
it is increasingly important to avoid
the use of chemical pesticides when
cultivating cannabis
beneficial insects have been used for
decades by the greenhouse vegetable and
ornamental plant industry
and today many cannabis cultivators are
moving from sprays and chemicals to
beneficial insects
covert biological systems has the
mites and nematodes microbials sticky
cards and air distribution units
you need to partner with nature to
defend your garden
whether you manage acres of canopy or
have a simple grow tent in your home
cobra is ready to help answer your
questions and help you transition away
from chemical sprays towards clean and
natural solutions
since 1967 culprit has assisted growers
in identifying pests
and devising reliable solutions while
providing healthy insects and mites that
will protect your yield
since the 1990s cobot has been a leader
in cannabis
pest and disease control worldwide and
have highly trained consultants to
assist you in canada and the u.s
from coast to coast no matter where you
live
covert biological systems can help visit
cobert.com
choose your country and get detailed
information
that's covert k-o-p-p-e-r-t
dot com for the most up-to-date cannabis
related biological control information
you can also check out their instagram
at covert canada
you know getting away from pesticides is
good for health and good for business
and cobert is ready to help visit
cobert.com today
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and our guest this week is cannabis
geneticist
ryan lee so now we have selected
our mother plant we have harvested
plantlets we have
incubated and multiplied them in the
agar growing medium
let's talk about transitioning them to
the garden
so how do we move the plants from the
growing solution in these petri dishes
to rooting into soil and becoming plants
okay it's a it's a really good question
i think we should probably walk through
the whole
process we've already started the
process but um
there's different phases in tissue
culture and so
we we start with our explant which is
the piece of the plant
that we've cut off which is then
sterilized and initiated into the tissue
culture process or into the jar
that plant then grows um we talked about
already the
process of multiplying it and
subculturing those
plant parts again into their own
individual jars
and that process kind of goes on over
and over and over again until like i
said we have our army
but at that point in time we still have
a tiny little plant chute
in an agar uh medium in the jar
with no roots if we were to take that
plant outside and either try to clone it
or
try to try to stick it into soil it
would just die because again it needs to
have that
set of roots on it and so depending on
the hormone mixture that we're using in
the agar
we might have to create a new specific
mixture
or it's a new specific rooting medium
and which we plug those just like we do
with clones we plug those little pieces
those little plant shoots into the
rooting medium and over the process of
say
7 to 14 days just like a clone these
things will grow roots
but again that little plant part is used
to being and it's like happy little
jar sterile greenhouse it hasn't
built up the type of protections that it
would need to just be taken and put it
under a
like a thousand watt light or in a
greenhouse or something the plant would
just welt and die
and so we have this process where we
take the the rooted plants out we wash
away the
the agar medium and we put them in the
soil and they kind of go through this
real babying phase which we call
hardening off
um you might think of it like the
nursery in the hospital where the babies
go right when they're born
it's just like a happy warm little
environment with just the right it's a
funny idea that the nursery in the
hospital is hardening off the humans
[Laughter]
so when one of the things that happens
when we grow these plants in tissue
culture
they grow very small and they're just
because they don't they don't need a lot
of inputs they're not really harvest
they're pulling
sugar from this from the agar they're
not harvesting it through sunlight
and they're not exposed to wind and all
these other things right
and so we have plants have when you grow
plants in a greenhouse or in a grow room
environment
you can actually look tell on the plant
they've got something called the waxy
cuticle
and that waxy cuticle is kind of like a
like think of it like an
anti-transpiration barrier it stops the
plant from just
losing all of its water um
and so we have to baby these plants in a
way
and kind of encourage them to to get to
toughen up
enough to the point where we can
actually take them and put them into the
into a tissue culture
or sorry into a standard production
environment
and uh and so that it might be like a
warm environment with lots of humidity
right um it's just
they don't go i think the important
thing to realize is that they don't go
from the jar to the field
right but you have to have this
intermediate step where this
intermediate step is this still
happening in the lab
it's kind of it's like it's kind of in
between the lab and the field
right so it's less so it's not
it's not sterile but it's also not
exposed to the elements
exactly right yeah yeah it's kind of
like a really it's like i said it's like
a nursery it's like it isn't
it's exactly what it is a nursery right
it's like we want to
take these little babies and encourage
them to grow up just enough
so that when we then take those plants
and move them into the production
environment
either in a grow room or in a greenhouse
that they can just take off
how big are they physically at this
point it's not really to do with size i
mean you can do it on very small plants
but you kind of want to do it on what we
you know staged
like three and a half four plants
they're like you know maybe
three four inches tall so so
in that petri dish a plant has grown
that's about three or four inches long
and that is the size of the plant you're
going to take
out of the petri dish and put into your
soil in this nursery
yeah and the later phases of the tissue
culture process i mean we might start
with baby jars
or actually even test tubes but but you
can actually upscale
the size of the container and so they
use like those i don't know they're like
you know 500 gram um
yogurt containers you've probably seen
them at like fast for not fast food
tickets but like uh
maybe like a slightly higher end you
know vegetarian
takeout it's like yeah clear clear
polypropylene so
they're actually like like transplanting
they're potting them
up even in micro propagation in the lab
yeah as they get too small you know
you're growing these little trees
they they it literally looks like a two
foot tall bush
but it all happens in the size of a baby
jar a baby food jar
right and so if you want to get if you
want the plant to grow
past that size you make a bigger jar
right so that's why we call it that's
why these tissue culture vessels come in
various sizes
all right so um let's talk one more
moment about this waxy cuticle
so the waxy cuticle if i understand it
correctly it is preserving like the
moisture in the plant and is
is kind of just kind of protecting it
during the hardening off process
does the waxy cuticle
go away during the hardening off process
and is it like reabsorbed into the plant
or does it like
fall off and is in the bottom no this
oil
sorry i maybe wasn't clear when i said
that the waxy cuticle is what develops
in this hardening off process so it's
actually growing more
thick during the or thicker during the
hardening oh i see so
so it's like the outer layer it's the
defenseman it's the the outside
skin it's the skin is toughening up
during the hardening off process
exactly and there's there's actually a
product that you used to be able to buy
that people would take i think it was
called no wilt
but it was a it was a product that you
could actually put on cuttings
and it was kind of like a waxy spray
that you'd spray on the plant
and it it kind of seals the plant up and
it stops that's one of the things
i mean when we when we take a cutting
off of a branch cutting off of a plant
you've cut off the way the plant is
going to get access to water
right and so that's why we use uh a dome
on the clone trays right is it it
maintains that humidity if we were to
take the dome off
and put a even a fan blowing lightly
across clones that were freshly
planted they'd all wilt because what
you're doing is you're encouraging them
to transpire all that water
out of the plant and they can't reabsorb
enough water
to compensate for what they're losing so
they wilt
right and the idea is that we kind of
create this little mini greenhouse
with these domes and that prevents them
it holds the water in it prevents them
from
from transpiring so
this this the waxy cuticle that's going
to grow on the outside this actually
reminds me a lot of
um wax grafting tape
that you know after after you you make a
graft you
you wrap it with this waxy tape that is
semi-permeable
and but so it closes off the
the the cutting spot for to disease and
a bunch of stuff um it kind of reminds
me of the same thing
how how wax is product generally
protective
yeah absolutely and you know we we know
that these waxes are all on the plant i
mean if you don't ever seen
these big co2 extractors in the process
but
you know they actually pull out a large
amount of wax
in the in a co2 run which is usually why
they do that winterization step right in
the extraction process where they
they take the cannabis oil and they put
it in a big vat of
um or a big container of ethanol and
then they drop the temperature really
really low like well below freezing and
what happens
is all the waxes and the ax in the
extract they precipitate
out of the solution and you can actually
filter the waxes away
so those waxes though are coming from
the trichomes and not the
plant material right probably both oh
okay
yeah all right so it's it's you know
it's
it's common in the literature to read
that micropropagation produces plants
that can be
more robust than their traditionally
cloned counterparts
has this been your experience i think
probably what we're seeing i don't know
if they would be
any more robust than a healthy plant i
think that probably what we're seeing
is that some of the plants that are
coming out of tissue culture
compared to the plants that they came
from
they might be a little more vigorous but
it's probably because the plants that
we're comparing them to
have had more uh they you know they've
they were talking about like dotted
plants you've heard of these dudded
plants
right they've got a viral or bacterial
load like the plant has essentially
become
infected over years you gotta again
remember cannabis plants are annuals
so their natural life cycle is to grow
and live for a year
and then they set seed and the whole
life cycle starts again
which is kind of a way for the plant to
shed any bacteria that's growing
that's growing in the plant right but if
you're if you're growing a 1996
jack herrera plant chances are um
it's picked up some garbage along the
way yeah and that's actually one of the
things that we're seeing in tissue
culture is
you know there's we've seen some some
groups identify like
bacteria that are actually living within
the cells of the plant or in between the
cells of the plant
um and and so part of one of the things
that you can do in tissue culture is
is is play around and try to actually
find a way to kill those bacteria and
viruses in the plant
so in instead of it being oh tissue
culture plants are by definition
you know better and more vigorous it's
really
like yeah it's really about the fact
that the preparation
that goes into creating a
tissue culture mother you're cleaning up
the bacteria and the viruses
so so you're just making a better plant
it's not necessarily that plants that
are grown in petri dishes are somehow
more vigorous
yeah i suspect that's what it is again i
don't i can't say that with 100
conclusivity
um i think the truth is also is that you
know while
well yeah some of these companies are
starting to do tissue culture in
cannabis
i would say that we're probably three to
five years away or maybe even 10 years
away from having
a completely bulletproof system that is
producing perfect plants every time
um well in in the category of
bulletproof you know one of the things
that
people who want to complain about tissue
culture will
they'll point out that some cultivars do
not
grow true to type after they're grown
out
from tissue culture um is this a
failed expression common in cannabis
like the plant
or is this more or less common in other
species
and and like what might cause this yeah
so that's something called
somaclonal variation um
semiclonal variation just means
the variation that we see due to
possible genetic changes in the plant
uh through the tissue culture process
and and we actually know that some of
the
hormones um that are used
in in the tissue culture process
actually do
increase the rate of genetic mutation in
these plants so
we might be seeing um
genetic changes it could also be that
we're seeing epigenetic changes
epigenetics is essentially you know
it's it's a way that genes are regulated
by the environment
and so a plant or an organism might go
through
some organ or some environmental
insult that changes the way that the dna
that their genes are expressed
is this like nature versus nurture from
high school biology
yeah a little bit it's it's it's it has
it has to do with that for sure
so so let's let's hit on that a little
bit more then because i find this
interesting
so did you just say that like you know i
mean i know people
are you use the term epigenetics a lot
and you know one of my favorite breeders
modern epigenetics is making cannabis
seeds but you know
the word epigenetics i'm not like super
intimate with
are you suggesting that um environmental
stresses can change the dna
they they change the way the dna
is expressed and so yeah
like there's something called dna
methylation and so
there's these little tags that can be
put on a dna which say
transcribe this gene or don't so the dna
itself doesn't really change
but it's what's being altered is the
regulation of those genes
and so epigenetics literally means above
genetics or standing upon genetics is
really what epi
genetics means and so this is a type of
regulation that occurs
on the dna without changing the dna
interesting so so it's kind of like all
right the dna
says do this but then there's like then
there's like an epigenetic post-it
note next to it that says yeah do that
but like
don't don't do that a lot or or yeah do
that but do that a whole bunch
yeah i mean without getting into a whole
show on
epigenetics i think that that's pretty
like i think the post-it note is
actually like a really good way to think
about it
you've got your little piece of
machinery that comes along and it reads
the dna
and it encounters the post-it note and
that post-it note is a little
instruction that says
hey read this dna a little bit
differently
and so the the the message that's
on the post-it notes would that be
considered
soma clonal variation no somo colonial
variation is the it's like the change in
the observable
observable phenotype is how i would
describe it so the soma clonal variation
is the variation from the nurture
not the nature exactly all right i got
it yeah
it's the off type it's like i said it's
the way we put known genetics in
and two percent of those plants that
come back out look different
those are soma clonal variants yeah like
like you know
getting getting if i if i get genetics
up here in the pacific northwest that
grow
totally kick ass and humble and i bring
it here and people are like oh that's
not that plant
you can tell by the photograph and i'm
like yeah well you know i got it from
jodry
and it's definitely from humboldt but
our weather here
sucks and so i'm experiencing some
clonal variation well that's
yeah that's really environmental
differences
all right i went a little too far yeah
it's it's really the variation that we
see coming out of the tissue culture
process i wouldn't
try to extrapolate extrapolate it past
that
but we do know for example there's a
there's one chemical that was really
used a lot
um in in cannabis tissue culture called
thiazeron or tdz
and tdz is known to cause genetic
mutations
right or at least to increase the
frequency of genetic mutations
and so by using some of these hormones
in the process yeah we can lead to
changes
um in the plant there can be changes in
the process
and that's that's really part of what we
want to do is
monitor these these types so that we can
make sure that as we're cloning you know
you don't want to take a variant
or an off type and then use that to
start your whole new sub culturing
process
because everything that every plant that
comes from that cell line
is going to be changed right and the
idea is that we want to be
have them being true to type aka
blue dream or whatever the variety is
right you want you want to use
the plant that is true the truest
expression of the genetics
that you want exactly right on so this
would be a great place for me to ask you
about genetic drift because
oh my god all the crazy stuff that is
said about genetic drift and
people pointing fingers and like you
know all the bro
science god help us you know people
argue a lot about whether or not
genetic drift is even a thing so so
you know generally people are when they
talk about genetic drift they're like
okay you had a mother
some time ago let's say well for the
sake of this conversation let's say that
it was five years ago there's this great
plant
and then you made a clone off that
mother and you grew that up
and then you made a clone off that plant
you made it
so like now maybe we're like seven or
eight or nine
clones off of the original
plant that was grown from seed and
and you know what people normally tell
me is like oh
there's genetic drift because
the cutting that you are growing now
nine
cuttings later is so far from the mother
and um the clone that you have now is
the same
age as that mother was way back nine
cuttings ago
and so the the the genetics have
drifted from the original expression of
the seed
is that a thing and if so what's what's
the
what are the mechanics there
yeah those are again so those are why we
call off types
genetic drift is actually something else
genetic drift really means
the change in the frequency of the genes
in a population
from one generation to the next
and those typically the frequencies of
genes if your population is large enough
your breeding population is large enough
the frequency of those genes don't
really change in the population
unless we're exerting some type of
selection of pressure
like you know either through artificial
selection by humans
or pests or molds or if you use a small
breeding population
those are the things that can really
cause a change in the genetic frequency
but that's probably different than what
we're talking
about it's just the community has
started using the wrong term that term
genetic drift
already has a specific meaning and i
think that what
the community is really talking about is
more
results of soma clonal variation or some
type of
epigenetic regulation that's either
happening on the plant
or the change in phenotype is being
induced by
something like the plant has acquired a
virus right so it's not it's not really
age related it's not time related it's
because
over time your cuttings of cuttings of
cuttings are actually picking up
you know diseases and viruses and stuff
and getting weaker
i think that that's more likely we have
shown through the sequencing
you know that has been done in the last
10 years that
that you know clones what we call clones
you know on the i don't know you
remember the the phyllis galaxy but they
used to have these
clone groups yeah right and that's
really what we're talking about is
like you know if if two people if you
got one cutting from joe
jodrey and somebody else got the same
cutting from him like 10 years ago
and took it to the east coast as those
two plants are now they're
they're divergent branches on an
evolutionary tree
right and so they actually may go
through little bits of
of dna mutation you know that's that's
how
um pinot gris and pinot blanc came about
right like those
those grape varieties actually started
as
pinot noir and then
you know somebody in a in a vineyard in
france 300 years after they started
growing
pinot noir found one group of branch or
one group of grapes that was
like slightly gray colored and it was a
it was a white grape not a red grape
anymore
um and that was just because that one
branch
produced a mutation and the mutation was
in the
in the gene that was responsible for the
color of the pigment in the grape
right and so when you actually take that
if you cut that branch off and root it
genetically except for that one mutation
it's the same plant as the pinot noir
right um but it has just acquired a
mutation that allows it or that has
caused it to have
a slightly different phenotypic
expression
all right so um let's before we go to
the commercial break let's talk about
one of the risks that people talk about
with this entire process because you
know
you take your original um mother plant
shall we say
and she is the
best expression of the genetics that you
want to
micro propagate to make your
cannabis clone army and
um and so then you you know go through
the process
of tissue culture to micropropagate it
and now you've got you've got you know a
gazillion of these plants and you're
gonna put
5000 of them out in a field or
you know in a series of warehouses or
whatever
you know one of the things that i like
about growing outdoors from seed
is that all of my plants are slightly
different
so if i get a pest if i get crappy
weather if i get a fungus if i get like
whatever my
threat is not all of my plants are going
to be equally
susceptible to it so like okay i might
lose some of my plants
but i'm not going to lose all of my
plants because they're like slightly
different people you know
when you do this micropropagation though
since you're targeting on this very
specific expression of the genetics
you know these 5000 plantlets that
become plants they're all going to be
exactly the same plant and
you know you know i agree with a lot of
folks that like you're like okay
well that might give you a whole bunch
of
plants that will produce flowers that
will look appropriate in the same bag
because they look the same but it also
makes them susceptible as hell
to all of these pests and
you know i think that that would
decrease
the the defensive posture
of all these plants making your plant
your
your field or warehouse more at risk
to everything um how realistic
is that concern and and how do we weigh
that
well that's you're talking about
monoculture and this is
this is always the risk of monoculture
right when you grow
one genotype in an environment the
possibility always exists
that a pest is going to come in and
really love the plant that you're
growing on and if that's the case
they'll run through it like locusts
right i mean
they literally will spread the whole way
and
it's kind of one of the negative aspects
that we have in the way that we grow
cannabis currently
as a monoculture is that we're very
susceptible to
invasion of pests or even specific molds
i mean if something shows up
it's going to run through the entire
population
and really the only way to combat that
is to plant some level of
heterogeneity or some level of genetic
diversity
um that it kind of acts as like a shield
or a barrier
you know to the the mass expansion of
the past right
if you have a quarter of your production
space
is a plant that spider mites for example
don't find very tasty
you know they're gonna they're gonna
stay away from that one plant
or that one genetic type and so you can
actually kind of create barriers through
throughout your room you create a mosaic
of different patches of genetics
and you kind of set it up in a
randomized way
that they you know you don't have all
your blue dream in one area for example
so that
if it gets contaminated it's going to
run through them right
all right but yeah this is a my
follow-up is really freaking specific so
i hope i can get us all the way there so
here
so so you said that we want to
decrease the risk of the monoculture by
creating this mosaic with different
genetics
and so my question is is this mosaic of
different genetics
all cannabis plants so like
you know to use your example plant one
is a blue dream but then plant two would
be
skittles and then plant three would be
wedding cake or whatever
and and then and then like when you know
plant five would be blue dream again
so that plants two three and four
have got different genetics and may not
be
as attractive to whatever the pester
or fungus is that's attacking plant one
now do you mean that or we talk a ton
about polyculture on this show because
i'm a big fan of
you know planting cannabis plants
alongside other plants like comfrey or
whatever
and because those plants might might
attract the pests or repel the pests
because of their terpene profile
depending on the nature of the plants so
are you saying that that you know the
better
solution for mono culture as we've been
talking about it now
is to produce is to plant you know five
or more different types of cannabis
plants but
interweave them or are you saying no no
you can actually do a whole field
of one variety of cannabis plant
but then we want to solve it with all
these different
um species of plants
you can do it both ways i think for the
context of this discussion i mean
it's more about planting different types
of cannabis i wouldn't intersperse them
plant by plant that's just not an
efficient way
to either plant or grow or track you
know through production
you might do blocks of say you know
whatever 20 by 20 or 100 by 100
um of one genetic type and then you you
you rotate your blocks
right um in in a completely
integrated system i think that we're
going to start to see
more farms more small farms that aren't
just growing cannabis that they're
adding cannabis as a value-added product
to their production of what they can
grow on their farm i mean they'll grow
their
blueberries and their garlic or whatever
flowers they're going to grow and then
like a little bit of cannabis that helps
with the bills
and i see that the future of cannabis
being really integrated into
more of a holistic system of a holistic
production system
one step less advanced though is even in
a cannabis grow
is if you're say you're growing five
varieties that you don't just have one
big block of each of those five
varieties
that you have many blocks of those
different varieties interspersed
yeah you know that idea of growing your
blueberries or whatever
and then cannabis around it was what i
really thought we were signing up for
when we started going down this
legalization path in my head
cannabis was going to save the family
farm you know
because you could take the the sales
pressure off of the vegetables or the
fruit
that has to be harvested at a very
specific time and brought to market
there's so much pressure on the family
farm for these these you know
smaller margin plants for food
i love the idea of like oh you do a row
of your
your fruit tree and then a row of your
cannabis plant right and then
the cannabis plant can make sure that
the mortgage is paid and then you can
make a you know
a good profit but at a lower margin off
of whatever your food plan
is and we save the family farm but
you know unfortunately like no states
are are encouraging that with their
regulations and
i think that it's i think it's a
disappointment yeah we're allowing it a
little bit up here in canada and i've
seen a few
um smaller farms try to integrate
cannabis
unfortunately they don't do it in a
professional enough way like you
really you you know growers know what
they're doing at this point in time but
i think that like
as an industry we're still in the very
nascent you know we're in the nascent
stage where
you know we're trying out big large
public companies and they're not really
working out because they just produce a
bunch of garbage
it's hard to quote to maintain that
level of quality
when you scale it right and i think that
there is going to be a sweet spot
but you the smaller family farms
also need to learn how to integrate that
information in
um and it's actually something that you
know oregon and
southern washington even northern
california there's there's some people
that are really doing it right
um but i think that it's going to be a
learned experience that that people need
to learn how to
integrate
a good amount of candida not a small
amount i'm not talking like a small
amount but a reasonable amount
of cannabis that they can grow they can
maintain
the level of care and attention that is
required to produce
a crop of that level of quality because
again you can't
in today's market you can't just produce
a bunch of average bud
and expect to get a decent paycheck for
it on the market i mean there's just way
too many people growing cannabis
and the stuff that gets turned into thc
distillate
you know it doesn't really matter what
it looks like because again you're just
going in for that one compound it's kind
of like
you know farming for high fructose corn
sugar right
um but i think that we all recognize
that
the people that really consume cannabis
and are passionate about cannabis those
aren't the products that they want to
consume
right they want to consume either really
high quality flowers or extracts made
from really high quality flowers
yeah the only the only time i've ever
seen
the inter planting of real food crops
and real high quality cannabis
in the way the kind of ideal way that
you're talking about is when i visited
happy day farms casey and amber down in
mendocino
they actually do that but it takes so
much work
and they've only got a few acres of it
but um
you know i know that they're a small
craft farm and they're they're probably
not interested
in scaling up to you know you know
mega acreage levels but but that's what
i would like to see you know like where
you have
acres of of beautiful cannabis plants
alongside
beautiful food and we can feed everybody
and get stoned at the same time while
resisting pests and viruses but
i don't i don't think we're there yet
well and i don't think the small farmers
are there yet i mean
running a farm even a couple acres of
any crop it's it's there's a lot of work
there
and some crops are more forgiving than
others but i don't think that cannabis
is very forgiving in terms of
it's like you said earlier like when it
needs to be harvested it needs to be
harvested
you know you can't just put it off a
week or cut it a week earlier and expect
that it's going to maintain that same
level of quality
right yeah so yeah it's it's hard to
juggle
those acre-sized balls in the air and
keep everything humming
you know yeah for sure all right so
we're gonna go to commercial but stay
with us when we come back we're
to start talking about the other aspects
of tissue culture we've already covered
micro propagation very seriously
but there you know there are a good five
or six other things that are included
with tissue culture and we're gonna do
that
after the break you are listening to
shaping fire and my guest today is
cannabis geneticist
ryan lee
sometimes the topics i want to share
with you are far too brief for an entire
shaping fire episode
in those instances i post them to
instagram i
invite you to follow my two instagram
profiles and participate online
the shaping fire instagram has follow-up
posts to shaping fire episodes
growing and processing best practices
product trials and
of course gorgeous flower photos the
shango lost instagram follows my travels
on cannabis garden tours
my successes and failures in my own
garden insights and best practices from
personal grows everywhere
and always gorgeous flower photos on
both profiles the emphasis is on sharing
what i've learned in a way that you can
replicate it in your own garden
your own hash lab or for your own
cannabinopathic health
so i encourage you to follow at shaping
fire and
at shango lose and join our online
community on instagram
as a business owner you are incredibly
busy in reality you are responsible for
everything your company does
you've got so many responsibilities
every single day that often you just
don't have the time to really
dig into your marketing as deeply as
you'd like
you know there's more that you could do
to reach out to new customers and
encourage
loyalty and the customers you already
have but you certainly don't have the
time for it and you're not ready to hire
somebody full time for that role
either for you i recommend blunt
branding
at blunt branding kirsten nelson and her
team are focused on improving your
bottom line
you know most marketing firms are
excited to make your logo
packaging and website very pretty but
they leave responsibility for improving
your bottom line up to you
they don't want that kind of
responsibility but that's pretty much
the most important part of marketing
right
kirsten and her team will help you
engage new customers funnel them to your
point of sale whether it be online or a
storefront
and keep them coming back to you and
telling their friends
now if you happen to be a new cannabis
company or an established company moving
from medical to adult use in your state
kirsten especially can help you not only
is she well reversed in marketing and
finance but she
totally gets cannabis whole plant
medicine terpenes heritage farmers
and the particular needs of startups
check out what she did recently for moon
time medicinals and humbled at
moon time medicinals.com kirsten and her
team put together a whole brand package
for them
built their website and wrote their
sales materials no doubt this is a paid
commercial spot but that does not mean
they bought my opinion
i've worked with blunt branding on five
projects now for various of their
clients and
every single time they have done more
than they have promised and over
delivered on results
i love how they generate new revenue and
focus on that as the goal instead of
just making a pretty logo
similarly every single friend i've
referred them to has come back to thank
me
and that just does not happen every day
grab a pen and paper because the website
address is coming up
if you want someone to implement
marketing programs that feed your bottom
line
give blunt branding a call they will
share proven techniques to increase your
audience and generate sales
while using cutting edge technology
solutions in the background that make
all of this
easy automatic and trackable go to
shapingfire.com forward slash blunt
branding to find out more
you can also click the link in our
newsletter blunt branding
marketing that makes you money
after you've caught up on the latest
shaping fire episodes do you sometimes
wish there was more cannabis education
available to learn
well we got you shaping fire has a
fabulous youtube channel with content
not found on the podcast
when i attend conventions to speak or
moderate panels i always record them and
bring the content home for you to watch
the shango los youtube channel has
world-class speakers including
zoe sigmund's lecture understanding your
endocannabinoid system
kevin jodrey of wonderland nursery
talking about breeding cannabis for the
best terpene profile
frenchy cannolis lost art of the
hashishin presentation
nicholas mahmoud on regenerative and
polyculture cannabis growing
dr sunil agrawal on the history of
cannabis medicine around the world
eric vlosky and josh rutherford on
solventless extraction
and jeff lonefels on the soil food web
there are several presentations from dr
ethan russo on terpenes and the
endocannabinoid system too
while there be sure to check out the
three ten part shaping fire sessions
series
one with kevin jodrey one with dr ethan
russo and one with jeff lowenfels
and even my own presentations on how to
approach finding your dream job in
cannabis
and why we choose cannabis business even
though the risks are so high
as of today there's over 200 videos that
you can check out for free
so go to youtube.com forward slash
shangolos or click on the link in the
newsletter
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i am your host shango los
and our guest this week is cannabis
geneticist
ryan lee so we have reviewed how
tissue culture can be put to work
multiplying plants
but sometimes before a plant can be
multiplied it needs to be cleaned
up we've talked earlier about removing
these viruses
and bacteria and different things that
might be in it that kind of weighs down
the plant
over the years but we haven't really
talked about a lot about
um how that's done so so ryan at what
point in the process would we put the
target
plant through a pcr test
to see how contaminated it might be
well really it's something that we
probably want to do repeatedly and
over you know at different points
throughout the tissue culture process
and that's really how we we go about
certifying
something that's pest fungus or virus
free right we
we test them we prove that there's no um
that these organisms aren't in the plant
and and and that's how we certify them
just to clarify how pcr does that
pcr is a technique for multiplying
specific genetic markers um and so for
example
you know powdery mildew has a genetic
sequence that's unique to powdery mildew
and so do spider mites and every virus
you know covid we all know that the
covet
these covid uh plants can be uh
identified through
specific genetic sequencing so we can we
can kind of do the same thing with like
the hops latent viroid or any of these
other viruses that are affecting
cannabis we can look first we can look
and try to amplify
these specific genes from those species
and if we don't show if those if those
pieces of dna
aren't amplified we can't multiply them
then we can say that those
organisms are absent from the you know
from the population
so it's like turning up the volume of a
song so that you can hear the
instrumentation
but you turn it up and you're like yep i
really don't hear a triangle in that and
then
and so then you can certify it's
triangle free yeah it's a great analogy
in fact because
you know those those things are just a
genetic single and that's what pcr does
is it amplifies that genetic signal
and so if the signal is free if we're
free from the signal
then we're also free from the organism
that creates the signal all right
so so after we've put this these plants
into
the pcr and we've turned up the volume
so that we can hear all these different
signals
very clearly and and we go like oh
we hear the signal for i don't know
powdery mildew
um how do you go into the plant and
separate
these these
these pollutants out well let's
i'm not exactly sure how you would deal
with powdery mildew you'd probably have
to use a chemical that suppresses
powdery mildew
but let's what's a better example then
let's let's use a virus
um and so you know like the hops latent
virus for example
you know when when when humans get
infected by a virus one of the things
that happens
is we get a fever right and the reason
that your body has learned to give it to
to raise your core temperature is that
viruses or
at least subset of viruses don't
actually do very well
um they don't replicate well they're not
very happy
when the temperature is higher than you
know 37 degrees celsius or whatever
the ideal human temperature is right um
so your body ramps up the temperature
terms of the thermostat
you get really hot and sweaty and you
know you maybe develop a fever
but it's actually giving your bodies um
just creating your body's creating a
system where
your immune system is going to be uh
tougher than the virus that it's
fighting at that point in time and it'll
it gives it a chance to kind of take
over
so if we apply that same logic to
um to plants
imagine as a plant cell is growing
you've got the meristem and so the
meristems producing new cells
that new cell is initially born without
any viruses in it
and then the virus moves in afterwards
okay
and so if you can actually grow a plant
in a raised
temperature condition as new cells are
created if the temperature is high the
virus can't actually infect those cells
because it's
at a disadvantage because the enviro the
the environmental temperature is high
and so you might have a little section
of the plant where the whole tip of the
plant becomes virus free
because it's growing in a high
temperature environment and the
viruses aren't able to take over and so
if you were able to go in at that point
and cut out the new healthy unvir
the cells that hadn't been infected via
by a virus and you subculture them and
plant them on their own
you know their own agar plate grow them
for two to three weeks
again monitor them with a pcr test to
see if the virus is there
and if it is you just go through the
process again but after a series of
subcultures
theoretically you're able to get a group
of cells
that are true to the plant type
but free from virus infection and if
that plant
the plant that grows from those cells
then becomes your new starting line
you've now actually removed the viruses
from your plant line
i had it all wrong man i like i wasn't
even close i was
like i i can see how
novice or amateur my picture was but i
was literally picturing the lab
scientists there with a scalpel
cutting around the virus you know so
that
it's not in the cutting but in a way
they're doing that
but it's just that you're using the
temperature to create the barrier for
the virus
right another way to do it you might i
mean if it was a bacteria
you might put like antibiotics on the
growth medium for example
right so you're creating a chemical
situation in the in the medium and thus
in the plant
where the bacteria can't grow right and
then you go and you do the same thing
right so so so after you run it through
the pcr
and you you've turned up the volume and
you can see all the crap that your
plants got
then you create a strategy for like okay
what are the different steps we're going
to do to this plant
to allow new growth to be uh
contaminant-free so
maybe you know you know you have to turn
up the heat for a while to get rid of a
virus and then maybe you need to
douse it with some kind of you know
organic chemical to get rid of something
else and like maybe maybe it's a three
or four step process but in the end
you are getting new growth that is
free of these contaminants that's
exactly it
yeah and then and that's you know what a
pain in the ass
it really is but i mean hot blatant
virus is also a pain in the ass
right i mean it completely devastates
your production space
so um or broad mites or anything any of
these types of pests that you can go
through so
you can think about it we can get down
to this very small little world inside a
jar
where we add maybe just a very little
bit of pesticide or fungicide
um and and those cells then grow out of
that
but it's a lot different than having
taken a whole big tall plant and
soaked it down with you know five liters
of pesticide
right i mean yeah and have to get that
whole plant clean when you're only
trying to get a little cutting to put in
your petri dish
exactly right and there's less
environmental damage because again
you've
you've released like maybe two three
microliters worth of pesticide as
opposed to
you know 500 milliliters all right so
earlier i thought you misspoke when you
said that we're you're talking about the
things that we were going to
you know remove from the plant like we
talked about the virus
earlier said spider mites and now you
just said i think you said russets but
um like i thought that the these
these pests are coming from the outside
of the plant the plant attracts them
are you telling me that there are things
within the plant
that is making them either attract or
more susceptible to these pla these
pests
yeah so typically insects
should be removed during surface
sterilization
um and so that's really like the when we
go through that sterilization part where
before we put the plant into the jar for
the first time you know we might cut it
cut out a little stem section and you
know we use like bleach it's like you'll
create like a 10 15
bleach solution and just shake your
little plant parts in the bleach for 15
minutes
well it's like really hard on the plant
material right i mean when you when you
take it out
there's all this dead plant material
that you actually have to cut away
before you
um you section out the part of the plant
that you want to try to live but that's
what we're doing is we're really
and they use all sorts of nasty stuff i
mean they use like
you know mercury compounds and all sorts
of little different poisons
to do that initial sterilization process
and that's kind of one of the reasons
you don't want to keep reinitializing
plants right it's because
you're always introducing them into into
this chemical ideally they go through
a short chemical insult and then what
comes out from that
is your starter culture material right
so you could find yourself in a
situation that a plant's got
so much pollutant in it where you're
like man i don't know if it's gonna be
able to live
through like four or five of these
treatments to get rid of all the crap
and like i i guess that's where the
artisan
and expert level comes on where you can
where you can expose a plant to these
various things and actually
have it like living on the far side yeah
you have to have a strategy to it like
again you know
if a plant's really weak and like really
hurting it's almost
dead that's probably not a great
candidate plant for tissue culture
but you know there are certain forms of
tissue culture where you can do
essentially what's like you know what's
called rescue and you you can
you know by shedding the plant the the
tips
shoots of those plant from the rest of
the collet carcass
right the infected parts of the plant
you're actually freeing it from that
disease
but yeah it's a targeted approach and it
has to be done
with care and attention so i i know that
with all the variabilities this next
question isn't really
fair but i want to talk about cost um
so this all sounds incredibly expensive
um let's say that that you you know
say that i don't know what's typical but
but i'm just gonna assume for a second
that a plant you need to clean up before
you can micro propagate it
is gonna have like yo let's say that
there's a virus and
a fungus in there somewhere and you're
like okay we need to clean you know we
found these in the pcr we need to clean
these up so that we get a nice clean cut
so that we can micro propagate it so to
take us from the
the the pcr analysis through the
cleaning it up
so that we have our one set of mother
platelets
that were then going to micro propagate
like can you just give me a ballpark
figure about what it's going to cost to
get us through the cleanup stage
yeah i don't know what it would actually
cost in terms of reagent materials to do
it yourself but i know that
um there's companies both in canada the
united states that will
that will do this for you now and i've
heard quotes from anywhere of five
thousand to twenty five thousand dollars
per per genotype so you know if you have
a cutting of blue dream and a
cutting of cookies that you want to have
this process done to it's
you know minimum 10 grand kind of thing
for both right
cool idea yeah and it can go up from
there you know i mean like again if
you're
if these people are offering services to
these public trading companies it's
going to be closer to 25 right
yeah i get you um all right cool well
then let's let's bring this episode home
you know we've spent the most of the
show talking about micropropagation
because
that is what 90 of the cannabis industry
is doing
under this this umbrella of tissue
culture
but we know that there's other cool
stuff
that is under this tissue culture
umbrella
that's only being dabbled in in cannabis
right now
even though it is incredibly common
with like food and ornamental crops so
um
you know you had mentioned in our in you
know in a previous answer
the issue of total potency the the idea
that plants have stem cells
and these stem cells can become any
other part of the plant
using this knowledge there are a few
other more rare
tissue culture applications that we're
not going to go into deeply in this show
but you know any anybody who's still
listening right
it probably actually cares about this
right
so would you go into um
a few of these different applications
that fall
under the tissue culture umbrella so
that like when we end the show people
are like okay
i understand the micro propagation that
makes up 90
of tissue culture but i also understand
kind of topically or tangentially these
other
areas that are also under the tissue
culture umbrella
yeah well there's some really neat stuff
i mean kiss your culture is just a great
way to
to kind of ship plants around the world
and store them
you know for long term we have what we
call ex-situ
storage of germplasm so you know they
might go into a forest and find a very
rare
plant and then you can take a cutting of
that plant and bring it back and keep it
alive
uh under tissue culture um i bet you
that i bet you people are smuggling
plants that way too
absolutely well we'll get to that one
but i think the first really cool one
that i think that we're going to start
seeing more of is something called a
process called cryopreservation
and so cryopreservation is exactly what
it sounds like it's like
you know on the what's it futurama they
had the frozen heads right
yeah yeah it's that same kind of thing
like you can take like a very small
shoot tip
and you can subject it to a freezing
process again you load the plant up with
sugar and
these anti-osmotic if you've if you've
ever seen
ice form under under a um a microscope
for example
you see it start what starts off as a
clear liquid and then you get these
crystals growing
in the in the liquid as it turns to ice
and if you imagine that process
happening in a cell
those ice crystals will actually grow
and they'll pierce right through the
cell wall
okay so as soon as you stab the cell
wall with like an ice crystal or
a needle or whatever the cell's done
right like it's going to leak all of its
contents out and it just it's
it just can't take that kind of insult
but
if you do it properly you can actually
get
you can you can do something called
vitrification whereas
think of it like the life in that still
that cell going from an animated alive
state to completely frozen
into a glass-like state immediately
and when it just happens faster it
happens
incredibly fast and it happens through a
very specific process of
dropping the temperature um in a very
specific and quick way
and if you can actually get that um that
vitrification to happen
think of it like trying to walk through
the mud okay
or walk through cement you got like
rubber boots on up to your knees
and you're trying to walk through like
some freshly laid cement like it gets
stuck right and if if you got stuck in
there and you really tried to like
really force moving your leg like you
might actually break your leg
right um whereas if you were frozen
solid
you're not gonna break anything because
you're not moving
right so if you can actually get a cell
or a group of cells
to undergo this vitrification process
from
essentially live to completely frozen
like in a split second that
you that's called vitrification and it
turns out that if you can actually
freeze life
till at that speed and size we can then
store whatever biological materials you
have
at like you know minus 120 degrees
they do it in like a liquid nitrogen
they have these special
containers that hold liquid nitrogen and
say the bottom
third is filled up with liquid nitrogen
and the top third is the gas that's
coming off that liquid nitrogen which is
still very very cold it's not as cold as
the liquid
but that gaseous phase that fills up the
top part of the container
is cold enough where you can actually
store biological samples for
you know an extended period of time say
indefinitely
right and as long as the temperature
doesn't change those
those biological samples are safe you
can then
take those things and reanimate them
and grow plantlets from those shoot tips
that you've
you've frozen under cryo preservation
and so
um it's a difficult process it's we've
only just figured out how to do it with
cannabis um but it's it's been typically
done in other species you know
uh pine trees and all sorts of trees
that they use for forestry
and hops there's a place in oregon
hops research center is doing all this
kind of stuff with hops as well
um but you can imagine i mean anybody
that's a grower and collects
you know special plants from all over
you know you you learn pretty quickly
that it's like you know keeping 50
different genetic types
and having to like grow them and take
cuttings and cycle them like
that's a real process and it takes a lot
of time and energy and resources
if you could just submit those things to
a frozen gene bag
knowing that you could then go and pull
those plants out of crowd preservation
and yeah that
process to pull them out of cryo
preservation it takes like six months
right until you're you've got a cutting
back in your hand
but if you think of like
the space saving and the time saving and
the the the resource saving that happens
if you can cry preserve these plants i
mean it's pretty it's something pretty
special
yeah just keeping a regular mother
library is a big difficulty i mean my
god i can't imagine if you were trying
to
you know take a snapshot of all the hype
strains right now and like we're going
to preserve them all for the future
it's like oh my god yeah but you could
preserve them all in a
you know in like a small 50 pound doer
right like
a small like a it's about the size of a
propane barbecue tank
right that you could probably store oh
wow two or three hundred cell lines in
there like no problem
um so that's that's pretty attractive
and as a breeder
you know if you're doing selections it's
also a very attractive thing to be able
to do that
um the next step i think the next one i
think i'll mention is something a
concept called artificial seeds
and that's really like a very small
shoot tip call it like
you know three or four eighths of an
inch
uh maybe half half an inch and
that gets embedded into a little jelly
matrix
and hardened in a solution of calcium
carbonate and it's like
a little mini tissue culture shoot in a
seed
like you know it doesn't look like a
seed it looks more like a jelly bean
but those artificial seeds again can
generate a full plant and
you can think about how easy it would be
to ship a small piece of plant material
instead of a jelly bean around the world
i mean
you know you get on a plane with a
handful in your pocket and you could
pretty much go anywhere right
so those are those are another
interesting little thing there's
something called embryo rescue but
people might have
read in the newspaper you know some of
these russian scientists found a
a 30 year old seed in a
um i'm not sure if it was an ice core or
it was thawing out of a
out of a melting glacier but they
collected these 30 you probably don't
mean 30 year old you probably mean more
like
30 sorry 30 000 30 000 all right because
as soon as you said
glacier i'm like yeah i think he means
more than 30 oh yeah
yeah yeah miss smoke but yeah 30 30 000
year old season they actually were able
to grow these things back
in to into plants and it took some doing
but yeah this this idea of being able to
take seeds and and baby the you know a
seed planting a seed is
you know it's they're tough but again
you know when you have a 30 000 year old
seed you really have to baby it and make
sure all the conditions are perfect and
you know tissue culture is kind of one
of those one of those
ways that you could do that i can't i
can't even get seeds to pop from 1978.
you know let alone 30 000 years yeah
those are all possible candidates you
know i mean once the seed is dead it's
dead but
if it's stored properly you know
sometimes you have like a lot of that
what the seed is is
it's um part of the test is actually
just food source for the seed that's why
you can plant a seed in the ground
and they'll grow to like two sets of um
leaves all really eating the food that's
in in the seed already i've never
actually heard the term
dead seed before so what is actually do
you mean from that
i mean just based on what you were just
saying about food
does that mean that the food that was
contained within the seed
that keeps it viral has all been used
and therefore you have got genetic
material with no
food in the seed and that is therefore
called a dead seed
it's not really that it's used it's
probably that you know
we're talking about 30 000 year old seed
it might be that the starches or
whatever the compounds or sugars that
are in the plant
have broken down due to whatever it
could be a fungus or whatever
but yeah within a seed there's a very
tiny little embryo
right and so that embryo could could
theoretically be cut out and provided
with all the nutrients and vitamins that
is need and hormones
a typical a typical cannabis seed that's
let's say that somebody's got
their typical scent cannabis seed uh
let's go old school
and saved in a 35 millimeter film
container
right because that's how they used to be
how many years do you think that seed is
gonna go before it's air quotes dead
well it's that's really a tough thing to
say if you
if you store a cannabis seed it's
properly dried
it's packed with a desiccant something
that's gonna absorb the moisture
you can put those seeds into a fridge
and we're pulling seeds out that are
like 25 years old
and still germinating at like 85 90
percent oh wow
right um and listen like i said earlier
that also varies by type like
some genetic lines or they don't last
that long and some will probably last
longer and my
personal hypothesis is that it has
something to do with the oil content
that's in the seed
before it goes through that process but
whatever it is it's just another trait
that varies
right that shows variation so um
yeah the the question about it being in
a container
is really what what was the temperature
and what was the
humidity that those that it was subject
to right
like like i said if you if you put it in
a four degree celsius fridge
for you know 20 years they're going to
be fine um if it's in like
uh a 35 millimeter film camera
in your attic your attic or your trunk
or your car whatever like your odds are
gonna go way down pretty quick
which is probably why these seeds that
we're getting to pop after these
thousands of years are coming out of
freaking tombs
yeah exactly yeah exactly they were in
like a one environment that was stable
for that long
yeah um so that's so that's really cool
um
there's also something called uh
anthroculture um
where we we grow what you think about
when a male plant or
even a feminized reverse plant a plant
a female plant sprayed with the sts so
that it's making male flowers
those male flowers are
um you know they go through a process
until they drop the pollen and say that
takes 30 days
right so you can actually cut those
branches off at like 15 days for example
and go into the forming male flowers and
within those flowers
there's the cells that are growing to
become
pollen grains you can actually culture
those cells at that stage
and and try to culture them and in rare
circumstances
if you've done everything right you can
actually grow the the pollen
or the pre pollen green grain cells
into a plantlet um
and we can subject those things to a
chemical called colchicine and
colchicine effectively doubles the
chromosome number and so you can imagine
that a pollen grain like sperm or you
know
an egg in a female
in the female reproductive system
context of an egg
when those things come together they
actually
in you know in cannabis when they come
together we get two sets of ten
chromosomes
so so each the sperm and the egg only
have
one copy of the ten chromosomes and so
that's called haploid that's
like a essentially you need to have
two halves to make the whole that when
they come together in the new
organism that that new organism has a
complete genetic set and so
we can grow these plants that have half
the set
double the chromosome number and now we
have a plant that is 100 true breeding
for all traits
right and so that's those are called dye
haps that's some mad scientist [ __ ]
right there
it's it's serious mad science and stuff
but this is these are the techniques
that they use in like
corn and wheat breeding to create seed
lines
where all of the seeds you know you can
plant
a hundred like a thousand acres and
every single plant looks the same do you
know anybody who's doing this in
cannabis now
yeah there's people there's a couple of
groups that are working so so this is
happening wow
that's some hard hardcore science yeah
and you can again
like you know you can if you can figure
out the process to grow these pre-pollen
grains into plantlets and you can say
get a thousand of them
you can then go in and subject those
thousand plants to genetic screening
and find the ones that are really ideal
right
um so that's all really interesting
future stuff that's coming uh
towards cannabis that'll be that'll
really exceed our breeding
and the last real thing i think that's
that's probably interesting to talk
about is the concept of somatic
embryogenesis
and so embryogenesis is like you can
think of the word the genesis of an
embryo
it's the process of creating embryos and
so the somatic
part of that word means it comes from
the body of the plant and so you can
actually take
imagine you could take for example your
favorite plant
doesn't matter what it is called
skittles you take your skittles plant
you encourage those um that plant to
grow
callus and that cal callus can then be
coaxed into like a pre-embryonic cell
state
okay and once we have those cells
those cells can be grown and multiplied
on mass
quantities and then divided into little
groups or clumps
and those individual clumps can then be
coaxed into embryos
and so essentially what you have at the
end of that process
is say 10 000 embryos that all came from
your skittles plant
right but they're what we call bipolar
they have a
a top chute that goes like a top
meristem that grows
skyward and they have the root meristem
that grows towards the soil
right whereas in the context of the
tissue cultures that we were talking
before
you know we had to actually put them
through a separate process
to get that root meristem to grow
right so they were really unipolar at
that stage they were only growing
skyward
right and so having a plant part that
will grow a shoot
and a root it really makes things easy
for automation
because the plants ready to just do what
it does normally it as a
as if it were a normal seed right so
think of it like
having a hundred thousand seeds that are
all twins
and and do they have the virility that
you know like when we when we
normally say we're gonna grow from seeds
most people say like yeah the
the a plant from a seed is going to be
more
energetic and more virile than a cutting
are these going to have that that that
you get from a seed
yeah because again part of that of comes
from the having the taproot that grows
straight down and it taps down into the
soil and goes searching for the water
table
whereas clones you know when we have
clones they're coming out sideways so
the roots kind of
they don't tap they don't they don't
seem to tap down as much they kind of
they kind of grow more along the surface
of the soil
and so there really is something about
having that taproot that drives
straight down into the soil that has to
do with
vigor right wow wow
um you know uh i'm i'm kind of glad that
we focused on michael propagation
as the major umbrella because i don't
think i would have been able to follow
you
uh in a conversation with these five
things that you just laid out this is
like some serious science and
i don't you know like you know there are
some good
people that have got capital that are
probably doing these things but this
really sounds
like like mega you know
mega ag companies that'll be doing this
stuff
yeah i think probably i mean you know
someone like
mr mean green i mean he could go and do
this with a university lab and partner
with someone like them so there's there
are definitely ways to do it
um i like you interjecting hope in there
i like that thank you
yeah well we you know none of this stuff
is about beyond the community i think
that we've kind of felt
you know especially in growing out a
prohibition that it's always been like
us versus these big corporations but
yeah there are there are opportunities
for people to go
you know it's rather than being acquired
by those guys
why not go and find ways that we can
partner with them
right so it's not like it's it's more of
an equal relationship
not one of being told what we're going
to do and when
right it's like hey look we have all
these unique genetic resources
can we partner with people that have
knowledge of how to do these techniques
so that we can advance the species
that's a beautiful summary i appreciate
your you uh ending this on
on a good note this idea of of
partnering with scientists and
laboratories where we're on equal
footing
uh pleases me extensively more
than the idea of this idea of us having
to
defend ourselves because big ag is just
going to come and steal all of our good
stuff i
like this idea of of we who've been in
the scene
for 10 or 20 years or whatever we
just go directly to scientists who
who smoke weed and say all right let's
get together and let's
let's use your let's use your academic
knowledge
and then you know um our
ability to smell flowers and determine
terpene profiles that cause joy and then
let's
work together and you know do it
ourselves
before the genetics get taken and
patented by somebody who doesn't have
our best interests at heart
yeah we it's all in our hands to do it's
just
you know being able to envision a way to
make it happen and i think that
as we move into this more legal world
there is a lot of opportunity for
collaboration and the truth is
these scientists they're not i think the
most the people that are really
truly interested in the science they're
not out to get rich they're out to
change the world through
breeding plants and you know making
these species into things that are
really
valuable tools for humans right and um
you know the somatic embryogenesis is
maybe is a little more of a dream but
the dye haploid breeding and
using um anthraculture these things are
they're standard methods that are used
in other crop species other major crop
species
and there's there's no reason we can't
use those same technologies in cannabis
well that's a really positive note for
us to end on ryan thank you so much for
sharing
uh your your vast experience and your
time
and your friendship with us um you know
your your um
the reaction to your your last visit
with us was just like so
positive i got all these pos or these
private messages they're like
you had chimera on the show hell yeah
you know like you are
um you are a unique person in our scene
and i appreciate your your willingness
and your ability to explain
some of these really hard ideas in
layman's terms
so that the rest of us can follow along
with you so i i appreciate your your
your interest
and your willingness to join me i
appreciate you giving me the venue to
share the knowledge so
it works for everyone and and thanks to
all your listeners and i hope someone
puts this info to good use
awesome brother all right so if you want
to either
like you know reach out to ryan lee
himself
or if you just want to keep up on what
he's doing uh the best place to do that
is on instagram he is at breeding
cannabis
and that's a good place to follow along
um
if you want to hear more from ryan lee
i recommend that you check out episode
64 of shaping fire
we did this beautiful show on feminized
seeds and
female only breeding
which was not only very informative but
um it caused a whole bunch of
mind-blowing and argumentation in the
threads so
um it's very interesting stuff you
should definitely check out episode 64.
it is enlightening and then also uh the
other place i'm gonna mention
is uh the emerald cup uh in 2018
um i was there and recorded a great
panel
that was titled analytical cannabis
breeding programs
and oh my god what a panel this was it
was uh
ryan lee who's our guest today seth
crawford from oregon cbd
um uh plant uh patent guru
reggie gaudino josh wertzer from
sc labs and then it was moderated from
uh by jeremy plum
from proof cultivar that was just
awesome a bunch
a bunch of folks who really know their
stuff and
came together to talk serious uh science
and trash
uh at emerald cup 2018 and you can uh
you can check that out on the on the
shango los
youtube channel you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shapingfire.com
and wherever you get your podcasts
if you enjoyed the show we'd really
appreciate it if you leave a positive
review of the podcast wherever you
download
your review will help others find the
show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the newsletter for insights
into the latest cannabis news exclusive
videos and giveaways
on the shaping fire website you also
find transcripts of today's podcast as
well
be sure to follow on instagram for all
original content not found on the
podcast
that's at shaping fire and at shangolos
on instagram
be sure to check out shaping fire
youtube channel for exclusive interviews
farm tours and cannabis lectures
does your company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts
email hotspot at shippingfire.com to
find out how
thanks for listening to shaping fire
i've been your host shango los
you