[Music]
Cannabis extraction has blown up and it
will continue to blow up and become
bigger and bigger for the foreseeable
future the array of products in the
market and the number of extraction labs
and the varieties of final products
possible coming out of these labs have
all increased at a wicked fast rate if
extraction is exploding in every
direction and nug runs our standard now
not a rarity like it was just five years
ago it's a really good time to be a
professional extractor or an extracts
connoisseur if you want to learn about
cannabis health business and technique
efficiently and with good cheer I
encourage you to subscribe to our
newsletter will send you new podcast
episodes as they come out delivered
right to your inbox along with
commentary on a couple of the most
important news items from the week and
videos too don't rely on social media to
let you know when a new episode is
published sign up for the updates to
make sure you don't miss an episode
also we're giving away very cool prizes
to folks who are signed up to receive
the newsletter there's nothing else you
need to do to win except receive the
newsletter this month were giving away
several packages of the Happy Endings
compost tea mix and ocean bounty
flowering soil amendment from green
bicycles I use this stuff in my own
garden and I love it in fact I talked
with green bicycles founder Patrick
Smith about his tea on the You Tube
channel recently so you can go to a
shaping fire com to sign up for the
newsletter and be entered into this
month and all future newsletter prize
drawings you are listening to shaping
fire and I'm your host Shango lowe's
today my guest is Jeff will Hoyt you may
know Jeff Wilhoit as cannabis Reverend
on instagram or as Jeff Church another
name he used during the early days of
cannabis but now that he's working
solely in the legal cannabis industry
he's allowing me for the first time to
use his real name Jeff has been in
professional cannabis for decades
working as a Canada cannabis patient
rights advocate and providing cannabis
medicine for patients throughout this
time he was refining his skills and
mastering all of the modern extraction
techniques and many of the ancient ones
too he's been running licensed
professional cannabis extraction labs
for several years now he is presently
still an ardent patient advocate but
he's also director of X
tracks at puffin farm today we're gonna
start by explaining co2 extraction and
then move on to the recent improvements
in co2 extraction and modifying co2
machines
welcome to the show Jeff glad to be here
thank you
right on so I'm excited to have you back
on the show so that we can kind of
update our prior conversation talking
about co2 extractions because you know
the last time we had you on the show is
a couple years and a lot has changed in
co2 in that time and you know I'm lucky
that when I did my stint as CEO of green
lion farms I got to be in the co2 lab
and was able to learn a lot but most
people have never been in a co2 lab let
alone any extraction lab would you walk
us through generally how a co2 extractor
functions and most importantly the
differences between supercritical and
subcritical extraction yeah definitely
definitely so it's you know like any
other solvent extraction you have a
solvent that is fed in through an
extraction vessel where you have plant
material packed in there and then
there's a secondary vessel that is
downstream from there where the solvent
and the extract that cannabinoids
terpenes and other constituents are
separated from the solvent and so you
know with co2 it's done either in a
subcritical liquid or supercritical
phase and so kind of the difference
between that is is relative to
temperature and pressure the state that
the solvent itself is in so at regular
atmosphere we have co2 as a gas if you
chill that dat and pressurize it so put
it into a vessel where it's where it's
able to hold the pressure it will turn
from a gas into a liquid and and then
that that liquid
can then be further heated and
pressurized even further to take it
through the subcritical phase and at
higher pressures and temperatures up
into the supercritical phase so they're
all just kind of different ways that the
solvent acts when it's a liquid it acts
just like a liquid a little saturate a
medium it'll extract when it's
subcritical it goes a little bit deeper
and the basically the the different
constituents are going to be soluble at
different levels so if you have a higher
pressure certain things will be more
extractable there than they are at a
lower pressure terpenes in particular
are extractable at low pressures with
co2 so you know I relative Leeloo you
know you can definitely do atropine
extraction at 1100 psi if you want
cannabinoids you're gonna have to go to
a higher to a higher pressure or take
longer to do the extraction because
they're less extractable at the lower
pressure so that's kind of the main
difference between every other solvent
that's used and co2 is this pressure
component to it you know with butane and
alcohol heat is a considerate
consideration when you when you run
either of those solvents hot you're
going to produce an extract that has
more constituents in it all right
there's there's going to be more
chlorophyll with a with a hot extraction
you know yeah so so basically co2
extractions very simple liquid fed
through the plant material the plant the
cannabinoids and terpenoids are
extracted then that higher pressure
liquid goes through a valve
that is that regulates the flow but it
also sets the pressure in the extraction
vessel at a higher point than in the
separation vessel what that does is it
takes that liquid or super critical or
subcritical subcritical fluid and it
changes it into a gas state right so
you'll also have heat on the separators
that are there aiding in this as well
but what happens there is you've got all
of your extract is in the fluid and then
once that fluid is turned into a gas the
extract is left behind and the gas is
able to rise and be funneled off it
through the piping into another into
another part of the extraction machine
having that having that flexibility
between supercritical and subcritical
it's almost like you get to two tools
for the price of one because you've got
some flexibility on how you run your
material well I mean it's really a
rainbow tool set not just two tools
because you know subcritical at low
pressure is going to extract one set of
constituents and the higher the pressure
gets and the higher the temperature gets
the more constituents that you're going
to extract until you hit supercritical
you know and then it just keeps on
further opening up what the constituents
are that it's going to easily extract
the higher the pressure is so but you
know it's it's it can be selective you
know so you can remove you can target
certain constituents and leave other
ones behind with with pressure there's
there's a there's some really
interesting things that are done on some
extractors where they have a separation
you've got your higher pressure
extraction then you have three cascading
lower pressure separators where your
cannabinoids and thicker wax your
constituents are gonna fall out in the
first separator because it's at a higher
pressure then as the pressure goes down
you know terpenes become insoluble in
that liquid co2 and so they drop out and
and so on so you're able to kind of
fraction things out that way with
different pressures right on cool so so
fright for anybody who's listening who's
like oh my god this is gonna be a really
technical show don't don't worry it's
not gonna be like this the whole time
because actually what we're it's mostly
gonna be talking about today our
applications for co2 and and how co2
extractions are being used now so so I
well you know we needed to make sure we
get through the supercritical 4 versus
subcritical but but stay with us here so
so so let's talk about that of our first
application Jeff so so you know the the
oil that is coming out of co2 labs for
for dabbing or vaping now is incredibly
tasty and it's and it's way better than
the stuff that was coming out of labs in
like 2014-2015 where we're unfortunately
a lot of co2 got a bad reputation for
not being tasty what has changed during
that time between like you know 2014-15
and now that's made such a profound
impact on the tastiness of co2 products
yeah so so a lot has really changed in
the marketplace so uh I would say for my
practices in the lab I've really come
full circle you know jumping into co2 I
was originally producing products that
were very akin to the oil that I'm
producing now back then and then you
know and that was really on quality of
material right you know I was running
full nug back in 2013 at the you know
first runs that we were doing we had
some really amazing oils that came out
that didn't need any winterization and
you know the quality of the material was
just spectacular but the reality is is
back then that quality material was not
going to produce enough oil to make it
profitable so everybody can turn to the
other direction and said oh well
this trim makes really you know good
fiscal sense and so I'd say that the
majority of processors went that way
there's a couple processors that I know
of that always have tried to strive for
having that highest quality input
material to make that highest quality
extract but it really wasn't the case
and so ninety five percent plus of the
market has really kind of just been this
oil that's like blah it doesn't really
it doesn't really excite you too much
you smoke it you'll get your high but
it's not a very unique high it's very
similar to you know most other
cartridges that that are out there so
it's kind of yeah and and really you
know back in the day you know there was
so little knowledge about how to retain
terpenes and your extract and and do
this that you would just do your
extraction you'd get this big puck of
waxy oil you douse it in alcohol and
then you would cook the cook the extract
in a row to vape to to remove that
alcohol well when you do that you're
removing the majority of the terpenes
right and most companies they would just
go all the way down until they had like
a thicker oil that way they knew that
the majority of the alcohol was out of
it but they'd end up with an oil that
for the cartridge technology was not
feasible to smoke and so a lot of
companies back then they would cut it
with propylene glycol as a viscosity
altering agent and you know we know that
propylene glycol vaporizing it is really
unhealthy you know it's there's there's
been a lot of you know government
studies have come out about the tobacco
vaping industry and it's the same thing
you know a propylene glycol we've just
been a little bit
candidate or they you know people back
in the day we're putting cannabis in
there which you know might even be a
little you know a little bit better than
vaping nicotine because you've got some
cancer-causing orchid anti-cancer
potentials in an oil right
anyways that's that that's not our there
but now now people are starting to get
to the point where they're making a
product that instead of having to
compromise and add in these these cuts
or leave alcohol in your extract to keep
the viscosity right there were all kinds
of things that that were done to kind of
make this alcohol extracted or
winterized oil be something that the
market desired but nobody was really
able to make it unique you know I mean
you'd have a little flavor of the strain
that you were vaping but it wasn't it
wasn't like smelling the flower and so
that's that's really where we've come to
you today is you know we're back to the
point where cannabis is worthless you
know the the wholesale market on on
cannabis it's it's so cheap
so now if you're an extractor you know I
mean sure it still costs twice the
amount to buy flour as it does to buy
trim but if the product that you're
getting is way way more than twice you
know preferable by the consumers then it
makes sense to do that so you know what
now what we're doing is just using full
flour and in a lot of cases it's trimmed
flour that we're using as well so
something that would be bag ready and
would have been sold as flour back in
2013 because it was worth so much now
there's so much cannabis on the market
that it's not worth as much
so yeah that's that's really you know
what we're doing now is sourcing this
this amazing material and we're able to
do complete our extractions without
having to winterize if we were running
trim we would have tons and tons of wax
a lot lots of lots of lipids in our
extract and it wouldn't be something you
would want to smoke out of vapor you
know smoking lipids is it they're pretty
harsh you know they're they're not
something you really want to want to
take a nice fat dab of so you know I was
thinking - the market dynamics that you
were describing where you're able to get
these not only an uh drun but a trimmed
nug run compared to what it was like
before a the you know where the value
has shifted in the market the prices
plummeted on flour which is really bad
for the producer grower on the farm but
on the other side it's a huge boon for
the customer who's now getting a much
preferable product at the same price
that they were getting you know cart
sand dabs for back in 2014 and also you
know in your role as the extractor I'm
you know I just got to assume that it's
way more satisfying to be working with
full flour let alone trimmed flour again
than just using the trim I mean it's got
to be so much better and unfortunately
the farmers losing but but you and the
customer are winning yeah and and you
know I don't know if it's so much that
the farmers losing yeah sure they're not
getting the same prohibition dollars
that people were getting back in 2013
but it's a commodity and the market has
set the price and you know that there's
gonna be a price for how much is being
produced you know so yeah you know it's
it's definitely sad the farmer is always
always kind of losing out in this market
no matter which way you look
the price is going to go down until it
hits that spot where it levels out but
but yeah it's it's amazing you know when
I when I crack open a you know nice big
8,000 gram bag of flowers and I'm
pulling out these nugs that are 6 8 10
inches long some of them and shoving
them into the extractor I mean it's it's
just an amazing thing
yeah way way more satisfying so so I got
one more question for you before we go
to our first break and and you know you
and I have known each other for a long
time now and I and I know that that you
know you go back working with patients
and you know you have you know helps
patients understand what RS Oh Rick
Simpson oil also known as ethanol hash
oil preferably is and how to use it and
stuff so I know it's got a place close
to your heart and I also know that co2
is close to your heart as well and you
know in this in this new adult rec
market I'm finding people are selling
stuff as co2 RSO which to me sounds like
an oxymoron because the whole point of
co2 is that it's a it's a partial
extraction and you're not getting the
whole plant lipids for example like you
said you don't want for a dabble oil but
you do want in an RSO do you believe
that there's you know realistic room in
a market for a co2 RSO or do you think
that as I do it's people trying to get
to an RSO product by cutting corners
well you know if you were gonna cut
corners it would not be extracting it
with co2
you know RSO is is something you know
Rick Simpson oil right for for lack of a
better name I mean he's the one that
popularized this this is a solvent
extraction technique so you know doing
it with ethanol is is probably the most
cost-effective way to do it and yeah
it's gonna have more
it's gonna have chlorophylls in there
where your co2 extract
is going to be devoid of chlorophylls
you know it's it's just it's a
constituent that is not as extractable
with co2 so Canada to answer your
question it's it's a different product
for sure you know so I don't know if co2
RSO is the is the best term but I think
that what they're trying to get at is
we've got this oil that we're selling
you as a vapor izybelle product but
really we're calling it RSO so that the
consumer knows that we've decarbonise oh
I think you know even though they're
completely different as far as the
appearance of the product you're gonna
have a much a much different product
from co2 but I think that the effect and
the desired you know the desired effect
is going to be the same you're gonna
have a D carbs cannabinoid load in a co2
oil but it's much more expensive to
produce so you know I don't know I'm not
sure if that's the the best way to
produce an RSO yeah I guess I guess if
that's the equipment you have that's the
equipment you use right if your lab is
your co2 lab and you don't have an
ethanol lab well looks like you're
making co2 are so and I got to admit
that you're kind of repackaging of my
perspective on it makes me feel actually
a lot better because when I see it in
the stores I feel like people are trying
to cross market a product that's clearly
not a whole plant ethanol hash oil from
co2 but I like your interpretation of
like you know maybe they're not trying
to get away with something maybe they
have to use the term RSO to signal to
the consumer that this is ad carved
edible product because we don't we
haven't really developed that language
yet for marketing well here's here's the
you know as far as what the Liquor
Control Board allows you to
you're only allowed to sell 10 milligram
size servings if it's for eating right
so there's no way you would be able to
sell an RSO for eating so they've
confused it in that sense to wear all of
these processors are having to produce
an RSO and sell it for vaporization
which is not what anybody should be
doing with you know so yeah it's it's
definitely interesting but there are
lots of RSO carts out there on the
market which really surprises me that
you know people put this chlorophyll
rich alcohol extract into a cartridge
you know but that's that's a whole
nother thing you know other you know I
think that the the term RSO is I don't
know I think we need to get away from
that you know my personal thoughts are
if it's an ethanol extract should call
it eh-oh ethanol hash oil just like BHO
is butane hash oil Pho is propane hash
oil you know what it's it's more
scientifically correct than calling it
Rick Simpson oil which really describes
a man who brought this medicine to to
the public you know the the ability to
make it and actually no I would I would
venture to say that nobody in the
recreational market is making RSO the
way that Rick Simpson did he is naphtha
which is a really kind of nasty solvent
but it's readily available and even
though it's got some carcinogenic having
a really heavy load for these patients
was the most important thing so at that
time you know even though there was some
bad coming in with the medicine the good
outweighed it and he saved a lot of
people and so that that's really where
where it came from you know the RSO it's
it's really just that term because this
guy was popularized it but technically
RSO rick simpson didn't have anything to
do with that co2 oil that's the co2 RSO
or any of the other RSO on the market
other than the fact that his name is
what they're using right on right on
yeah it's amazing how many people talk
about RSO four things without actually
knowing what it can you know what it's
made of in a particular process but you
know I get that's just all part of being
in an early market and us figuring out
ourselves what to call it to communicate
to the consumers and God help the
consumer trying to get educated and you
know as this as this education drifts
down slowly but surely do the retail so
let's go go ahead well we're on that you
know so co2 when you when you look at
what the consumer perceives co2 as it's
got a really bad name and you know most
co2 is pretty bland and so at puffing
farm what we've done is we've kind of
said we're setting a standard that it
has to be of at least this quality for
it to be extra virgin flower oil and
we're not really you know we say on the
package its processed with co2 so it's
it's full disclosure to to everybody
that that's what's being done but we're
trying to set it apart from co2 by
calling it the EVF oh the extra virgin
flower oil to kind of make this new
subset because our co2 doesn't really
fit in with you know what most of the
market is still today and the difference
is the difference is the flower the
difference is the non winterization
the difference is it tastes just like
the flower like if you took that flower
and broke it apart and smelled it that's
the flavor that you're getting from an e
vfo cart if you're not getting if it
doesn't equal like that and if it's not
lipid free enough it goes into
winterized oil and that gets sold to a
processor for making edibles right on
dude and that is why when
I'm shopping in Washington I buy your
puffs and farm oils so there you have it
so let's get to that commercial now
you're listening to shaping fire my
guest today is Jeff willhoite a director
of extracts at puffin farm as a business
owner you are incredibly busy in reality
you are responsible for everything your
company does you've got so many
responsibilities every single day that
often you just don't have the time to
really dig into your marketing as deeply
as you'd like you know there's more that
you could do to reach out to new
customers and encourage loyalty and the
customers you do have but you certainly
don't have the time for it and you're
not really ready to hire someone
full-time for that role either for you I
recommend blunt branding at blunt
branding Kirsten Nelson and her team are
focused on improving your bottom line
you know
most marketing firms are excited to make
your logo packaging and website very
pretty
but they leave responsibility for
improving your bottom line up to you
they don't want that kind of
responsibility but that's pretty much
the most important part of marketing
right Kirsten and her team will help you
engage new customers funnel them to your
point of sale whether it be online or a
storefront and keep them coming back to
you and telling their friends now if you
happen to be a new cannabis company or
an established company moving from
medical to adult use in your state
Kirsten especially can help you not only
is she well versed in marketing and
finance but she totally gets cannabis
whole plant medicine terpenes heritage
farmers and the particular needs of
startups check out what she did recently
for moon time medicinals in Humboldt
County at moon time medicinals calm
Kirsten and her team put together a
whole brand package for them built their
website and wrote their sales materials
no doubt this is a paid commercial spot
but that does not mean that they bought
my opinion I've worked with blunt
branding on four projects now for
various clients and every single time
they have done more than they've
promised and over delivered on results I
love how they generate new revenue and
focus on that as the goal instead of
just making you a pretty logo
similarly every single friend I've
referred them to has come back to thank
me that just doesn't happen every day
grab a pen and paper because the website
address is coming
if you want someone to implement
marketing programs that feed your bottom
line give blunt branding a call they
will share proven techniques to increase
your audience and generate sales while
using cutting-edge technology solutions
in the background that make all of this
easy automatic and trackable go to
shaping feiyr.com
forward slash blunt branding to find out
more you can also click on the link in
our newsletter Blount branding marketing
that makes you money join me at the
upcoming can met event in Los Angeles
for a gathering of the top minds in
cannabis medicine field experts will
present their latest findings and best
practices in treating a variety of
conditions with cannabis including
epilepsy pain traumatic brain injury
cancer autism and more laboratory
professionals will share their
revolutionary technologies in
cannabinoid and terpenoid extraction
delivery methods and quality and safety
testing can med 2018 is October 22nd
through 24th at the Luskin Conference
Center at UCLA and while the final
speakers list is still coming together
the speakers who are already announced
give you plenty of reasons to get your
ticket today prepare yourself to learn
from fifty four thought leader
presentations focused on furthering the
convergence of medical cannabis research
treatment and product development
speakers include the father of cannabis
research Raphael miss ulam Michael door
chief medical consultant for the Israeli
Ministry of Health will be there to the
list of esteemed speakers participating
is long and includes shaping fire guests
cannabis neuroscientist dr. Ethan
Rousseau and Kevin mckernon of medicinal
genomics you can view all the speakers
at kin med events calm this year's kin
med features a special education track
on the application of blockchain
technology in the cannabis market
including cannabis banking seed to sale
tracking sequencing the cannabis genome
ICO financing and more if you are a
medical care provider be sure to arrive
a day early to participate in the
pre-conference CME course find out more
about that at kin med events com that's
c-a-n-n-a me d events calm 95% of
attendees said
can mid-2017 met or exceeded their
expectations that's a serious vote of
confidence that can med 2018 will be
well worth your time and resources so
don't delay visit can med events calm
today to reserve your seat and find out
more welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire I'm your host Shango losan
our guest this week is Jeff Wilhoit
director of extracts at puffin farm so
before the break we were talking about
you know just kind of some general
questions that have been coming up
contemporarily about co2 and co2
products but but Jeff I want to talk
more in this second set about best
practices and some of the things that
can happen in the lab to make a better
product so you know in this section I
will be upfront that you know I get over
my head fast in a lab and I'm not gonna
front and pretend to know extraction at
your level so I'm gonna I want to I want
to lean on your depth a little bit and
have you guide where to go next so so
let's talk a little bit about best
practices in your lab so so you know you
know what I would like you to share with
us is some of the simple things that you
have realized in your lab between you
know the the early days of 2014 and now
that is causing you to develop this
product that's you know winning awards
and is clearly popular in the market and
and and so when we talked about this
setting up the show some of the stuff
that you had to say was actually really
quite simple so so let's start what
would you say is one best practice in
your co2 lab that is that is leading to
these these championship oils that
you're putting on the market well so
there's there's one one thing I've
already talked about it quite a bit is
quality material you know it's it's that
quality in quality out you know we call
it extra virgin flower oil because it's
flower oil not trim oil and you know
having that high quality material leads
to an extract that you're not gonna have
to winterize and you know if you
winterize your your you're losing
terpenes it's it's it's just that plain
and simple your most volatile terpenes
which are the ones that you'll smell
when you break open a bud those are
going to go out with your alcohol when
you when you when you do that and it's
it's a little bit more of a full plant
extract if you leave a little bit of
that in there if you're not removing
anything with a secondary solvent you
know that that's selective and basically
won't extract certain constituents then
then you're you're really having that
full plant full plant extract it's you
know I'd say another really really key
thing is we don't deconstruct things you
know it's it's all one extraction if you
deconstruct things if you if you take
the terpenes and and and separate them
off and then you take the cannabinoids
and separate them off you've got these
two different fractions and then then
you winterized the cannabinoid fraction
to remove lipids and then get that you
know as clean as you can and then you
add back the terpene fraction things
don't always match up very close to what
the flour was that it came from because
I would think that as you're as you're
separating out of the parts you're
you're separating an analogue source
into kind of digital parts and there's a
little bit lost and each part so when
you put it back together
you're losing quite a sum there's
definitely lost parts there's changed
parts so if you if you have to to heat
something up to the point where you know
or pull it into deep enough vacuum to
the point where it's going to distill
out like the terpenes so if you if you
remove those terpenes first
there's something that's been changed
because they were removed if you extract
it all with a single solvent all of it
has been treated the same way so you're
gonna have a product that is very very
close to what the plant was rather than
removed and then you know deconstructed
had been reconstructed right on so so
would you throw in a quick description
of what winterizing is because while you
and I use it as common parlance a lot of
folks in the industry don't yeah so
winterizing is simply the act of
removing the lipid content and so what
what you do is you take your oil and you
put that into alcohol you dissolve the
the oil into alcohol lipids are not most
lipids are not very soluble in alcohol
and so they'll stay kind of they'll
they'll not dissolve into a suspension
right so you're able to filter them out
now if you freeze that alcohol and oil
mixture or winterize it even more lipid
lipids will solidify and the terpenes
and cannabinoids stay in the liquid
solution of alcohol so winterization you
put your oil in the alcohol you put that
alcohol and oil into the freezer you
freeze it then you filter it usually
with some sort of vacuum filtration
basically pouring it into a filter and
having a vacuum draw on the bottom of
that filter so that the alcohol soluble
constituents come through and you're
left with a puck of lipids on the filter
so that's that's winterizing right on
the brief got all of this oil that's
diluted in alcohol and you've got to
remove the alcohol
so to bring this full circle and bring
it back home and the reason why you do
winterize is because you want to remove
these lipids which are harsh so you go
through this process so that the the end
smokeable product is much more enjoyable
to the consumer
exactly exactly you know it's yeah right
it's it's a clear product as well so so
to the eye it's a little bit more
desirable
winterization had been used to put it in
earlier cart technology right so
cartridge technology the lipids would
just gum it all up nowadays you could
put raw co2 that's full of lipids into a
cartridge I wouldn't recommend it to
anybody but the technology is there
where we're able to smoke thicker and
thicker things you can put pure
distillate into a cartridge and you know
that's the thickest okay but you're
gonna have you know terpene free for the
most part into a cartridge so and the
benefit of that is from all these new
carts because that would never have
worked with a wicking cart no exactly it
you know the C cell technology in
particular is is really making for the
ability for us to vaporize anything yeah
big big big fans of C cell as well yeah
so so let's let's lock down another best
practice so what's something else that
you're doing in the lab that that you're
finding a lot of value in so you know
one one thing that that I really like to
do in the lab is is reuse the co2 and
you know so Eden labs and and other
companies they'll tell you don't reuse
your co2 you can have too much water in
there one reason another your co2 is
going to be less pure you know there is
some truth to that
but in practice I've noticed that
there's not much less ability to extract
from reused co2 as there is from fresh
co2 and you know co2 production it uses
fossil fuels it uses energy that we have
to create those bottles of co2 then
there's diesel in the trucks that are
used to ship that co2 around and deliver
it to your location so we're using
energy to deliver this and so I think
that the the best thing that we can do
is reuse everything that we can you know
it doesn't is there any degradation to
the product I mean you mentioned a
potential for water or at least the
suspicion of water in there reuse 'el
but but have you noticed any different
in your final products because you know
you run using recycled co2 all the time
no you know I have it I mean I've used
just fresh and gone straight fresh co2
and I haven't noticed a yield difference
I haven't noticed anything different as
far as you know what the product is I
mean realistically there's very little
water that's going to make it into your
accumulator tank on a co2 system you
just you're not really gonna have much
there because most of the water is gonna
drop out and your separator you know
that the separator should be at a low
enough pressure or low enough
temperature that the water is not going
to boil right because you wouldn't want
that hot you know with your oil sitting
in there so so your oil and your water
from every run is going to be in your
separator and not it doesn't carry over
as a gas into the accumulator at least
not in a large part there there is some
carryover just like there's some
carryover of terpenes
and so you know you could say that that
there's going to be more terpenes that
that will collect in the accumulator as
well and so using it you're kind of
recycling those terpenes but yeah so you
know I I just like to do everything as
green as possible and and be as little
of a burden on the earth as I can while
I'm producing the extracts that that I
want to produce so I got to tell you
that that hearing this as one of your
best practices is heartening but also
not you know not what I was expecting I
was expecting you to give me another you
know very technical thing but but it's
you know considering how bad our
industry is right now as far as you know
green footprint go or our co2 footprint
goes between you know making all the the
packaging and and and you know using
plastic for a one-gram Doug and and all
the lights that we need to use to grow
indoors I mean the fact that that we are
able to even take baby steps and to
start bringing you know green ideology
into the scene I think is overdue and a
good thing you know and one other thing
that we do some other companies do it
but most companies don't we sell a one
gram cartridge so in Washington state
were limited to one gram sales that's
the most extract that you're allowed to
sell in one package with all the wicking
cards or cartridges that were out there
one grams were horrible it was you know
you would have almost every time you
would have a leak by the time you got
through a gram of extract so the
majority of people went over to a half
gram cartridge because it was much more
reliable you were only going through a
half gram of oil you had less less
chance for that to leak and the profit
margin is a little bit better on selling
the half grams right you're able to you
know you're selling two units and you
have a little bit more markup on each
one so the majority of the industry has
gone to
half gram cartridges and we sell half
gram cartridges because that's what most
consumers want but we also sell gram
cartridges and really would prefer to
sell gram cartridges you know so that we
have less waste there's so much waste
that goes into this product you know
we've got to try every step to improve
what we're doing so that we have less
waste I got one more question for you
before we go to commercial and it's and
it's on the same idea of
efficiencies of scale so you know you'll
you'll get a half gram cart for X amount
of money and then you'll get a full gram
cart for you know usually slightly less
than double the price of the half gram
but then you know they call them
different names different places some
people call them tankers some of people
call them syringes essentially it's a
it's a it's a packaging that is sold
with the assumption that you have your
own empty cartridge at home that you're
gonna you know squeeze this syringe into
yourself and and and tankers or syringes
tend to have a really nice price like
whenever given the option I will always
buy a syringe and refill my my my
Jupiter cartridges that fit my C cell at
home but honestly it doesn't seem like
it's all that much more hassle to put it
in a cartridge as it is in a syringe why
what's going on behind the scenes in the
lab that explains why tankers or
syringes are so much less than a 1 gram
part yes so so filling the filling cost
is equal on a cartridge or a syringe
might even be just just a hair easier to
fill the syringe but I you know not
really it's it's it's almost equal
almost equal what's really going on is
the the price of the package so I mean
we we go with
with the best syringe that we could find
and that's an all-glass
syringe no Pyrex no I mean no plastic no
silicone plunger it is glass on glass
and the cost of that is way less than
the cost of either a full gram or a half
gram cartridge okay so so it's it's
really I mean we're selling the oil for
the exact same price it's all the
packaging that is changing what what the
cost is to the end consumer right on
cool and actually I actually way prefer
getting the syringe not only because I
like to use my own carts but you know I
have a hard time throwing those glass on
glass syringes away cuz they're so nice
you know I don't know what I'm gonna use
them all for someday but I've got a
bunch of them now so waiting for the
application I think that's really the
way the way to go and and you know I
would really push anybody that's
thinking of producing a high terpene
content product get away from the
plastic syringes you know don't even use
something that has a silicone plunger
and a glass barrel go for the full glass
on glass and it's it's that much better
you know when you have a silicone
plunger or you've got the plastic
syringe you have terpenes in there that
are going to be eating it
you're good it's it's getting into your
oil you know when you buy like a gram of
distillate let's say and one of those
things that has a silicone plunger in it
by the time you plunge down towards the
end of it you'll notice the the
distillate that was clear at the
beginning of the gram has now become
cloudy and that's because of the
lubricants that are used in in these
syringes or tankers whatever you want to
call them and because of it you know it
yeah it's it's it's just the
manufacturing things you know the the
the silicone lubricant set and terpenes
themselves are corrosive their solvents
they they are you know they're alcohols
so they're going to break they're gonna
break down anything that they can you
know dissolve so there you have it so go
with glass oh not just not just a glass
you know tanker with a silicone plunger
glass on glass so let's go ahead and
take our second short break we'll be
right back you're listening to shaping
fire and my guest today is Jeff Wilhite
director of extracts at puffin farm
using pesticides when growing cannabis
has been common for a long time nowadays
though we know better we know that most
pesticides formulated for food crops
have never been tested for use with
cannabis they've been tested to be eaten
in tiny doses they have not been tested
to be inhaled and especially not
concentrated into a cannabis oil
chemical residues from pesticides are
not healthy for anyone but they are
especially dangerous for patients for
commercial cannabis growers this has
become very impactful cannabis
enthusiasts and patients have gotten
educated enough that they avoid growers
who used pesticides not only that but
states across the country have begun
making pesticide testing mandatory on
all licensed cannabis crops the time has
come to find a better way to fight
garden pests than covering your cannabis
and chemicals and there is a better way
let some good bugs fight your bad bugs
beneficial insects and predatory mites
have come a long way since we were
buying ladybugs online and putting them
in the grow room and just hoping for the
best natural enemies bio control can
help you solve pest issues without using
chemicals natural enemies founder Shane
young learned best practices from
working in the ornamental plant industry
and has fine-tuned those strategies
specifically for large cannabis crops
Shane works with commercial cannabis
clients across the country
to ensure that they keep their crop safe
and pest free without the use of
chemicals natural enemies has proven
solutions for spider mites a fidex
Russert mites broad mites shore flies
white fly and others - you can rely on
natural enemies for expertise and
excellent service for more information
go to shaping feiyr.com forward slash
natural enemies or simply click on their
banner in this week's newsletter as a
listener of shaping fire you already
understand the importance of living soil
when growing cannabis when you have
active microbe communities in your
substrate you go way beyond simply
fertilizing with nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium having active microorganisms
in your substrate supports vigorous
plant growth throughout the plants root
zone making for higher yields and
thriving flowers mammoth pea is the
first organically derived microbial
inoculant that focuses on your plants
nutrient cycling processes to release
soil phosphorus and other micronutrients
from they're bound forms making them
more available to the plant increased
levels of phosphorus will also keep
internode shorter and focus your plants
energy on bud production not only that
but the microbes act as a defense shield
for the plants rhizosphere
by out competing potentially harmful
pathogenic microbes pretty cool right
mammoth pee not only unlocks the
nutrients in your soil but it also helps
protect your plant from disease mammoths
peas beneficial bacteria act like
microbial reactors
continually producing enzymes that
release nutrients mammoth pee was
developed at a u.s. university has been
extensively tested by Colorado growers
and independent laboratories mammoth pee
is proven to increase growth and enhance
blooming one of the great things about
supplementing with microorganisms is
that they won't compete with whatever
fertilizer program you're already
running simply dose on top of your
fertilizer schedule for increased
benefits to learn more and to find out
where you can buy namma pee near you
check out their website at WWF microbes
calm partner with microorganisms to
create beautiful thriving cannabis
mammoth pee welcome back you're
listening
shaping fire I'm your host Shango Laos
and our guest this week is Jeff Wilhoit
director of extracts at puffin farm so
Jeff this next section I want to talk
more about getting hands-on with the co2
extractor itself because you know when
we first met one of the first things you
had told me is that you were you were
modding yours and I'm that scared the
hell out of me right I'm like you're
taking this you know this 80 hundred
thousand dollar machine and and you're
gonna fix it somehow but I'm like dude
are you sure but but you know you've had
a lot of success with that and now
you've mentioned some other things to me
over the years that you've done so so
let's talk a little bit about modding
machines so so if I remember correctly
let's let's start with your first mod I
think it was a retrofit of some sort and
if I remember correctly you owned an
apex machine and you wanted it to do
something that it didn't do out of the
box so kind of break that out and
especially if it's still relevant today
right so so okay so it's kind of funny
you know apex was born out of Eden labs
so auntie Joseph the the manufacturer of
Apex machines
he was the welder for the high-pressure
welder for Eden labs and so he was out
of Ohio Fritz the owner of Eden labs was
from Ohio as well so that's that's how
they knew each other and at some point
they had this falling out you know and
and you know things things happen and he
decided to make his own machine and
started a company I I didn't purchase
the apex machine but it landed in my
hands and and so we had this machine it
was gas booster technology which was not
you know the cutting edge it was kind of
an old technology at that point and this
machine that was built by Andy that kind
of had everything good on paper he was
good engineer but he didn't really
understand cannabis extraction and what
was gonna be happening while the
traction was was actually happening so
there were some things about the machine
that didn't quite work very well so we
would be running our runs and have our
separators icing over because the the
heater capacity wasn't wasn't enough we
would have all kinds of different issues
with the machine and no matter what we
did we were not able to get a very high
yield you know we were hitting 5% yields
as kind of our highest highest that we
could get this was a old 1500 psi
machine and that was based on a lot of
the technology in the machine itself not
necessarily the extraction vessel the
vessel was rated you know above 2,000
psi and so we were talking with Eden
labs because they're here in Seattle and
Andy was all the way over in Ohio and we
get you know one story from Andy but he
didn't really know exactly too much
about it in 2013 he didn't know too much
about running the extractors to extract
cannabinoids so we had had eaten labs
here and they were happy enough to reach
out and help us any way that they could
they lent us heat baths to try and
overcome the issue so where we would
have you know our heater wasn't capable
of producing enough heat to stop it from
freezing over and so they would lend us
heat baths and and finally it came to
the point where we were like yeah you
know what we really need to do is have
an Eden high flow liquid system so it
would be instead of a gas booster where
gas is compressed by the pump into
liquid and then that liquid is shot into
the extraction vessel it would be a
liquid pump where liquid was pumped from
an accumulator
hang on the machine through the through
the extraction vessel and then it would
end up back as a liquid in the
accumulator tank after it goes through
the whole machine so kind of the way
that the the machines were running were
way different the the liquid aspect
allowed for a lot more a lot higher flow
rate of co2 and since you know
extraction is really based on flow rate
it's how much solvent are you moving
over the material and how much time we
just decided hey let's let's do this so
we worked with Eden labs on designing a
retrofit that was kind of custom to the
machine that we had and got a secondary
skid that sat right next to our machine
that had a pump on it and we were able
to double our extraction yield and cut
down the time that it took to extract
you know we were running up to 12 hours
and getting only 5% on the apex 2013
series machine and we were able to cut
that down to 4 hours and and be able to
reliably get 8 to 10% winterized oil out
of it after we were done but yeah so so
you know the retrofit it's it's really
you know it's kind of this leap of faith
that we took we said hey you know we
think that this other system is going to
work better for us all of the numbers
seem to to equate let's try it out
so we we had them design it manufacture
it and we tried it out and everything
worked great so that doesn't that
doesn't sound like a cheap mod though
that sounds like that probably cost you
a couple tens of thousands of dollars
yeah it was expensive but doubling your
yield and cutting your time by 60 per
say t 70ish percent that sounds like a
great win though
yeah yeah I think at the time it was
like 36 grand to do it which compared to
the price of a new 5 litre extractor at
that point which was like I think they
were like 86 or 90 thousand somewhere
somewhere around that range at that time
it was way cheap and they were nice they
worked with us and helped us be able to
make it happen right on that that's a
great solution you know another thing I
like about it too is it you're I'm
always a fan of extractors not being
afraid to get under the hood and and
make some non stock changes to their
gear good oh I was just gonna say
because you know so often they're like
well you know we won't we want to keep
it just like the the it was sold to us
but so often the the machines are sold
kind of like at it as a mean like okay
this is the kind of machine that people
everybody generally needs but if your
specialty is one thing or another you
know you might as well hot rod it in
that direction
yeah you know these machines are built
with safety in mind there's pressure
relief valves everywhere on the system
so if you do get into a situation where
there's an overpressure in any of any of
the vessels it's gonna just blow it off
and and you're gonna have to say oh what
did I do you know what you know what
caused this figure it out
fix it so you know there's really
nothing to worry about as far as hurting
yourself with one of these machines
because they're just so they're built
soberly you know yeah so and after that
retrofit it really kind of opened us up
to say hey look you can change
everything on this machine let's look at
the flow path let's look at how things
are going and try to come up with a
better way
extract so we actually started doing
subcritical runs so the way that an
Eaton Labs high flow machine is set up
your basically it's set up to run a
supercritical run if you modify it a
little bit slow down the pump and put a
chiller on the extraction vessel instead
of a heat bath you can do a subcritical
liquid extraction that's going to get
you a much different constituent profile
you know we've we extracted lots of
subcritical runs and and really kind of
came up with a product that's similar to
what we what we have today at Puffin you
know really high terpene content extract
that's that's free of lipids for the
most part lipids are just like the
cannabinoids that the higher pressures
they're more extractable so if you're
gonna extract it you know 1100 PSI say
for a subcritical run you're gonna have
a much cleaner extract that needs much
less post-processing and you know kind
of the way to go now with with
subcritical the disadvantage there is
your yield is sacrificed so because it's
harder to extract those cannabinoids at
those lower pressures you're not gonna
get quite as much there but but yeah so
you know I mean what we did put a
subcritical mod we took a chiller and we
cut into the line where the heat bath
was and put in a three-way valve in
there where we could select either the
heat bath or the chiller and kind of hot
swap it so we'd be able to do like a
cold subcritical run get this really
chirpy extract and then
then do a supercritical run after that
kind of swap that over and you start
pumping the heat bath in there and
you're able to get more of a cannabinoid
rich secondary cut that then you could
winterize and then you could put those
oils back together that first
subcritical run that you haven't
winterized and the the final would
driest extract from the supercritical
run so kind of you know just just trying
to go different ways about it
and good idea actually of running at two
different ways for two different types
of benefits but then putting together at
the end to make something that's better
than the some of both yeah yeah
definitely so we hit and we've hit two
mods we hit the retrofit mod and the
subcritical mod do do you have one more
that you might find interesting
yeah so so you know really my favorite
one and the one that I need to do myself
right now and so if you buy an Eden lab
system it comes with two heat baths one
for the extractor one for the separator
and so simply getting a PID controller
which is what you know your email uses
to you know keep your it reads a
thermocouple which is a thermometer
basically and has a heating element
attached to it so it kind of cycles on
and off to keep your email hot same
thing on a heat bath and what that
allows you to do is is have just this
ultra stable temperature so you're not
having drift when we were working down
in SoDo just where we were on the power
grid there were fluctuations in the
quality of the power that was being
delivered you know I don't know if it
was just we were near the end of the
line there's some really really heavy
power consumers down there in the
industrial district in Seattle and so we
would notice a variance of quite 10 10
degree up to 20 degree shift in
temperature of our heat bath where it's
you know it's at the same setting but
because of the quality of the power that
was coming into the building we would
have this fluctuation between you know
the morning and the evening and so we we
just drilled a hole into the heat bath
put a thermocouple in there that had a
gasket fitting on it so you know the
heat bath wouldn't leak hook that
thermocouple up to the PID controller
and then had the PID controller it had a
relay that switched on and off a the
outlet that the heat bath is plugged
into so basically turn the heat bath on
it's analog dial all the way up and then
you set the PID controller for the
temperature that you want and it would
cycle on and off the power.keeping your
heat bath at the desired temperature
rather than running into this you know
issue of the quality of the power
changing it and even you know I I
noticed some fluctuation during the day
you know if it's if it heats up outside
you know if you've got a ambient
temperature fluctuation you're gonna
have a fluctuation and what your heat
bath is is is getting so you know to
have a stable repeatable temperature
that you're extracting at a heat bath
mod is really the way to go
yeah the idea of keeping it at one
temperature you know it's not just for
convenience we're doing science here
people yeah it's it's it's because it's
gonna extract exactly the same
constituents of that temperature and if
it if it fluctuates it's getting
something different right on right on
well Jeff thank you so much for taking
some time to join us again on the show I
always love chatting with you and
you know honestly you know with a lot of
my other shows I've got a very stringent
set of questions that I'm gonna walk
somebody through but one of things I
enjoy about you is that I don't actually
always know where we're gonna go because
I just kind of follow follow your path
and and your good things come out so I I
appreciate both your willingness to
share your experience but also your your
good cheer and ability to tell stories
so so thanks so much for your time Anne
yeah definitely and thank you very much
for having me out it's it's it's always
a pleasure to be on the show and chat
with you about all things cannabis I
just I love to talk about cannabis
anytime right on cool man
so if you want to follow Jeff on his
Instagram it is a great place to follow
along and that's at cannabis Reverend on
Instagram we've also got a video that's
going to be coming out here in a couple
weeks where I'm gonna be working through
with Jeff or he'll be explaining to me
rather the the genesis of the hash star
rating system because he was there in
the early days when it came about and so
we're gonna talk about that a little bit
you'll find that on the youtube channel
and actually you really should go over
to the YouTube channel and hear and
actually watch a couple of Jeff's
presentations made here on Vashon Island
where I live for patients he does he did
a one presentation on doing making
bubble hash at home for patients and
then a second one on making ethanol hash
oil
aka RSO for patients as well and so so
if you're a commercial producer these
are probably not going to be the videos
you want because he's focusing more on
using limited materials and ease well
it's not really a you know necessarily
scalable but but if you're a patient and
you're looking for a simple way to get
involved with it those are those are
great videos to check out and the
YouTube channel is at youtube-dot-com
forward-slash Shango lowe's you can find
more episodes of the shaping fire
podcast and subscribe to the show at
shaping fire calm and on Apple iTunes
stitcher and Google Play if you enjoyed
the show we'd really appreciate it if
you'd leave a positive review of the
podcast wherever
download your review will help others
find the show so they can enjoy it too
on the shaping fire website you can also
subscribe to the weekly newsletter for
insights into the latest cannabis news
and product reviews on the shaping fire
website you will also find transcripts
of today's podcast as well for
information on me and where I'll be
speaking you can check out Shango Laos
comm d'azur company want to reach our
national audience of cannabis
enthusiasts email hotspot at shaping
fire calm to find out how thanks for
listening to shaping fire I've been your
host Shango lows
[Music]