[Music]
there are some things in life that take
a lot of effort to make are made with
quality in mind and are really truly
premium I'm talking about things like
shoes that were handmade by an actual
cobbler or a coat that is so impervious
to weather that you feel safe when you
put it on some coats like maybe the one
your grandpa used to wear hunting are so
well made that they just look better the
more wear and tear they get some
expensive sports cars to have a certain
/ that just sounds expensive we may not
always have the money today to buy these
luxury items we desire but there's no
doubt that we respect them for their
beauty quality and craftsmanship there's
not much like down the cannabis market
so far most products are whipped
together and put on the market as
quickly as possible that's why we see so
much uncured cannabis flower out there
and why some vaporizers are so
unsatisfying to hold today we're
focusing on one of the few cannabis
products anywhere in the country that
drips luxury and craftsmanship you are
listening to shaping fire and i am your
host Shango Lohse today we are going to
profile lyric Anna gars now I want to be
clear that this is not a paid spot I'm
focusing on them because of their
leadership in the industry and because
I'm just totally a fan of their
attention to detail today's guest is
Ariel pay up a founder of lyric Anna
gars liras canna gars are handmade
contain ultra premium ingredients and
have a style and price to match welcome
to the show Ariel hey thanks for having
me so area you know in an industry when
so much retail packaging is ugly and we
have to question the quality of the
cannabis contained within you know it's
encouraging to come across a product
like yours that is not only beautiful
but also packed with top shelf cannabis
why did you decide to serve the ultra
premium market instead of the mass
market um because there's a lot of labor
put into creating a category and so it's
like impossible to make it cheap and for
somebody to be paying that amount of a
420 dollars for 6-inch category you know
you want to make sure you have premium
cannabis and no complaints
um I don't want to sugarcoat crap you
know so uh Jesus my did you do were you
excited about the ultra premium market
because you wanted to reach out to that
particular audience or is it just
because you are a connoisseur and you
really only wanted to work with ultra
premium inputs uh kind of both I just
saw I just saw opening for it cuz I'm
nobody was really marketing their
products that way and there are a few
but I just felt like this this category
would would set a garden apart specia to
have premium product and if people want
premium product don't pay the money for
it so it's nice to to you know be in a
position that you're in we're not really
competing on price you know so many you
know cannabis product folk they're all
trying to get the cheapest inputs
possible so they can get their price low
so the maximum number of people can buy
it but you know I've been an
entrepreneur for a long time i actually
prefer you know not having the cheapest
product in the market because there's a
there's a certain satisfaction in
providing quality and that sounds to be
your approaches as well yeah yeah cuz
I'm there's there's a there's a couple
counter our companies and I'm starting
to see a show up which is pretty cool
what I was expecting but when i started
my brand I told myself look I'm sticking
the premium quality materials
solventless oil and that so it was it
was a big challenge trying the perfect
trying to find that perfect garden that
that met those own qualities there came
a point where i did get laid off with a
job and I I was desperate and all these
gardens that I was meeting weren't
meeting my expectations and I almost
jump ship and just went with it and just
hopefully hope that my categories would
work out but I was like still worried
because the quality wasn't that great
but luckily a last minute him an
opportunity was brought to me by by gold
leaf they contact me I was like oh my
god these guys are like perfect all
organic and
they care about they care about the
product that they give their own that
their customers versus like you can tell
when you look at other gardens they're
just all about creating large yields and
making that profit and I didn't I didn't
want that with my brand so as far as how
you judge quality mean obviously all of
the legal states are having issues with
pesticides in all different flavors but
what were you looking for that you would
call quality flower to go into your
categories I mean what were what were
the standards you were looking to have
met that you didn't really seem at being
met until you met gold leaf um I was
just looking for a good garden that
cared about their customers and they
grew organic and didn't use any like
crazy pesticides um and they had good
flower um do they make her do they make
your rasen as well or do you do that in
house no we make the Rossignol so well
so we get a my friend which is crazy he
started working after me we've been like
best friend since high school his name's
uh he runs polar ice track so he's good
for making like full milk bubble hash
and he created the hard press um Rasen
press and he started working there so
now we get we collect his bubble hash
and we press that into a rasen for our
category so everything solventless
everything's handcrafted um there's
nothing I try to make sure that there's
nothing negative people can say about
our products mm-hmm so you know when I
first found out about your canna gars
and I was looking into him I'm like wow
these are incredible and you know if you
just would have used you know premium
gold leaf flower they would have been
amazing just in and of itself why do
what possess you to go ahead and put
dabble rasen oil in there as well
because the more the more concentrates
foot on there the slower the burn and
plus you get more flavors and if people
love rosanell Rosen's like the new thing
since um
since people are trying to be clean with
her with her cannabis know so I just
looked at it like this when I when I
before I got into this i saw i saw was
going on with food everybody's talking
about on GMOs this and that and then you
see the cannabis market booming with
like hydro setup skoko cells just
feeding bottle nutrients and I was like
well these guys are trying their best to
make their money but nobody's really
trying to create that premium product
where where you let the plant grow the
way it's supposed to be grown you know
with living soil and and gold leaf is
the only garden that I that I know of in
Washington state that that can provide
that and we're stuck with them it's
crazy it's just like wow how did that it
was like a perfect match like I told you
if I told you a story from beginning to
end well it's nothing yet but like
everything is just falling into place
somehow i don't know how how it happens
but you got the top flower producer in
Washington not the top bar but premium
flower producer in Washington and then
when the premium bubble hash producers
in Washington and also started his own
rasen press um and then now you have us
account guards all under one garden I
mean like what garden you know in the
world that has that and can say they're
clean green yeah right and then like
that's where you get the whole ultra
premium by behind and you know it was
actually about a year ago actually like
very much a year ago that I first got
turned on a gold leaf we were on our way
driving down to Emerald cup and Aaron
Varney of dockside was in the was in the
van with us and he whipped out some of
the gold leaf tangi which is just like
insane you know like like if you smoked
Angie and go in somewhere you don't
smell like weed you smell like tangent
Angela yeah it's incredible and it was
like you know and their packaging is
nice so so yeah if you're going to be
stuck with somebody those are good folks
to be stuck with so um that's an
interesting point you made though about
how adding the Raza noil slows the burn
on the canna gars because you know we
all know that that you know when you're
smoking a joint it can run a
it can or can burn down faster than you
want to and I can imagine that when your
candor gar ZAR are you know big and long
and and you're passing it around a bunch
of folks because you know your your
canna cars can just a they're there they
can serve a lot of folks I can imagine
that having the rasen in there so that
the burn is slow is a really good thing
about how long does a typical category
are you know last I mean they've got to
be more than 20 minutes right elbow yeah
almost definitely on the the corona the
six-inch one can last from I've heard
from five to six hours oh I had a I know
of a couple that took it to feed you and
that's all they brought had left them
for two weeks so they just took drags
her in there so I know the longer ones
they burn a lot slower than the petite
ones I don't know what why maybe because
it's just longer but when you first like
that the tip of the longer ones like you
don't see it budge hardly ever take it
as it's it's it's a it's crazy um you
got experience it to like an estate what
I'm talking about it's just amazing so
once and once I figured that out I was
like damn I got it I got a I got a brand
new sand I got a market too so so what
what sizes do the categories come in and
do you see them being sold to different
niches in the market um so we have we
have our petite corona which is eight
grams of flour and 2 grams of rasen and
it's wrapped with the cannabis leaves
that one is a retails for 300 dollars
and that's around 4 inches and then our
big one is the corona which is six
inches 12 grams of flour and three grams
of Ra's and that retails for 420 um this
isn't it is it's interesting because
like at first you know some people get
sticker shock off of the price it's like
oh my god four hundred and twenty bucks
but then when you see it on you know
like your Instagram or something you see
that there's this beautiful koenig are
and it's and it's wrapped with
multicolored leaves and
in this beautiful packaging and you know
how long does it take to make say for
example a corona because obviously
there's a lot of of hand artisan love
going into it mmm yeah it takes it takes
around an hour and then up to three to
four weeks secure one of the flourishes
that really makes the final product look
you know really regal is that you know
you you you seal the ends with purple
wax what brought you to decide that you
wanted to do something extra like that
uh man because when I was in medical man
like packaging is horrible everybody had
horrible packaging they always talk
about how great of a product i had like
by my but by this is the greatest it's
fire and then they throw it in like a
mylar bag and like come on dude like
show that you care show that you care
about your customers given the full
experience and I'm all about that like
that from from the first visual
appearance to wrapping it to like
everything this I want my customers to
get that full experience you know people
remember that total your that's a good
point it is an entire brand experience
especially since I would imagine a lot
of people are using these for for
celebrations so we're going to take our
first short break and be right back you
are listening to shaping fire as a
business owner you are incredibly busy
in reality you are responsible for
everything your company does you have so
many responsibilities every single day
that often you just don't have the time
to really dig into something as deeply
as you'd like you know there is more
that you could do to reach out to new
customers and to encourage loyalty and
the customers you already have but you
certainly don't have the time and you're
not ready to hire someone full time for
that role either for you i recommend
blunt branding blunt branding principles
Kirsten Nelson and Anthony Garcia are
focused on improving your bottom line
you know most marketing firms are
excited to make your logo packaging and
website very pretty but they leave
responsibility for improving your bottom
line up to you they don't want that kind
of responsibility but that is pretty
much the most important part of
marketing right Kirsten and Anthony will
help you engage new customers funnel
them to your point of sale and keep them
coming back to you and telling their
friends no doubt this is a paid
commercial spot but that does not mean
they bought my opinion I've worked with
blunt branding on three projects now for
various clients and every single time
they have done more than they have
promised and over delivered on results I
love how they generate new revenue and
focus on that as the goal instead of
just making me a pretty logo similarly
every friend I've referred them to has
come back to thank me and that just does
not happen every day so grab a pen and
paper because the website address is
coming if you want someone to implement
marketing programs that feed your bottom
line give blunt branding a call they
will share proven techniques to increase
your audience and generate sales while
using cutting-edge technology in the
background that make all of this easy
automatic and trackable go to shaping
fire calm forward slash blunt branding
to find out more you can also click the
link in our weekly newsletter blunt
branding marketing that makes you money
welcome back you are listening to
shaping fire i'm your host Shengo Lohse
and our guest this week is ariel pay up
a founder of lyric anna gars so before
the break we were talking about the the
artisan craftsmanship that goes into
making these and how you know these take
in an hour or more to make and all of
the very ultra premium ingredients that
go inside did you already have a
pre-existing background in making cigars
and such or did you have to teach
yourself how to do this i I kind of
taught myself like I saw people doing
the categories with the with the string
method where they formed the cores
around the skewer and I just I mean it
looked awesome to me the first person I
saw do that was an artist called afgoo
afgoo head and he's the one that like
blew my mind with these categories like
well you could actually make categories
it with
with cannabis and I just watched how he
did his thing but um I thought in my
head I was like there's no way this
could be a done in full-scale production
because like that would take hours to
like slowly tryna buds around a skewer
um so I didn't even bother doing that
but I was just always in my head trying
to figure out a way to speed that that
core process up because building the
core a clean course of the biggest
foundation to creating clean counter
guards and my buddy I told my buddy
surrounding the hard press guy um he was
he also got fascinated by the counter
guards and he got into it but he was
still doing the string method and I was
like there has to be there has to be
another way around this because I'm not
doing this thing the string and this is
not going to sell to like a garden or
anything if I told him I wanted to go
into business with this so he later on
as he was rolling these categories he
just quit because he said it was just
time consuming but he told me a tip he's
like you know what if you're going to
get into this try this method it might
work and sure enough I took off with it
was like yup this is it this is this
what this is what it takes two to make
these categories and production
full-scale production and so I just
attacked it I figured it out and and
that was just abstract enough of a
description to let us know that you
develop some best practices that are not
your trade secrets right yeah yeah so um
did when you were trying to figure out
how to make the production as reliable
as possible did you find that you were
just doing trial and error or did you go
back and research how cigars are made
and then kind of like cross apply that
manufacturing technique or did you not
even really bother to go to how tobacco
cigars are made oh man I watched men
yeah I love you too because I watched so
many YouTube documentaries and on how
they roll can't rolled cigars and just
because you only need that one little
tip to just spark that idea in your head
and man i watch hours and it only took
me like a minute of all those hours that
I
to figure out like certain tricks on my
counter gars I mean if you really want
to figure out how to roll a category
you'll get it but if you're just gonna
keep bugging people they're not gonna
trade secrets so that that's that's how
that's how I am with a lot of things
like I don't have patience for people to
teach me stuff or do stuff for me so I
like to figure things out on my own
which is why which is a cool thing how I
got into branding it and stuff like that
because i was i got a top much wine and
teach much i went to school for graphic
design and I have little like
photography skills so I figured I just
combined it and help brand my help
market my product usually certainly you
certainly have an aesthetic quality
because the whole package from from you
know from your Instagram and and showing
the pictures to creating the product to
all the way to to the displays that you
make for the stores I mean it's it's an
entire ecosystem of gorgeous which which
you know it's probably demanded to be
able to get the prices that that you're
asking for you know when when you are
having so much success I can imagine
that you have to continually add more
folks in manufacturing rolling and and
you know you spent all this time kind of
being mentored by YouTube and trial and
error do you find that it's challenging
to teach the new hires how to do this
properly and do you find some people
that just don't have the chops for and
you just have to like get somebody else
um well right now I just taught I've
taught my brother and then my wife and
also my sister-in-law how to roll in my
brother only took him like a week to
learn same same with the girls it took
them like a week or two and once you get
into it you're flowing after that um the
the real the real problem is is like
streamlining the whole process like
making sure that we're always have like
a stock of fresh leads that we can use
or making sure the Rosens was always
there enough flowers always there but
the biggest the biggest pain is is the
leaves because you can't just use all
the leaves you got to use the nice ones
you know and at all the leaves we
gravity on these like a small percentage
of them
one of the things that is especially
cool about how the Canada gars look is
that a lot of them have got two tone
leaves and you know we all love how you
know different ladies express themselves
in the lead especially you know if it's
outdoor and fall time comes you know and
they start to they start to change color
and that's gorgeous but you know it
really adds to the artisan vibe of it
you know you can you're reminded that
this is a product that's from nature and
that these are being made by hand when
they're not you know uniform all the
same each one of them you can almost you
can see the variety of nature in that I
think people really dig that yeah yeah
that's what i've heard like when i first
got into like thisor i always thought
like should there be a way we can make
these like perfect so they look all the
same and in a lot of people's like nah
it looks it looks original like each one
looks unique just keep it that way so
they okay um with your relationship with
with gold leaf did that come with a
distribution deal as well are you out
there going to retailers yourself trying
to encourage them to carry your product
almost we don't have enough product to
supply the retailer's us so we only work
with certain retailers um yeah so um so
are you planning on on increasing your
production is that the idea right now is
that you're setting up you know best
practices and figuring out how to do it
and then scaling up or or is it you know
like hey you're using everything that
that gold leaf has available and and
your kind of restrained because of the
the inventory of quality inputs that are
available um I'm kind of in the middle
of that right now trying to see which
direction I should go with my company um
I have some advices that I'm speaking to
that I'll help me find direction because
you know business is all new to me and
doing this is all new this crazy unlike
doing everything and
yeah I thought about like either
licensing out my brand and to other
states or even getting my own facility
to to a bigger market such as California
or maybe New York or something like a
large a large market like that our
people are you asking you about the
licensing you know are you already
fielding calls from people who want yes
I get a lot of messages about a come
here come there let what how can we
carry your product and this and that
it's like a lot of people don't
understand is you can't push these out
like joints and balance or whatever
they're all handcrafted so a lot of
investors they get when they look at
that they they want to see a big return
with these um with these categories but
with the large with large volumes but
you can't you can't do that yet there
you have to respect it as an art because
if you rush this you could ruin the
product the quality of the product you
know yeah and you know and people are
only going to pay the premium price if
it is actually a premium product and I
can imagine that all sorts of folks who
are more interested in the margins than
in the quality of the product would
quickly dilute the quality of what
you're putting into it whether it is in
effort or n inputs yeah yeah yeah yeah
right on well we're going to go ahead
and take our second short break we will
be right back you are listening to
shaping fire businesses everywhere are
constantly striving to reach out to
people through advertising we all know
though that trying to reach a cannabis
audience with a quality message is
pretty difficult that's why many people
choose to advertise on the shaping fire
podcast advertising on this show allows
us time to talk about your product
service or brand in a way that really
lets people know what sets your company
apart from others bold people who own
companies know that getting in a
relationship with our customers is
essential that is what we offer we will
explain your service or product and what
sets it apart as desirable and help our
audience get in contact with you it's
pretty simple really advertising does
not have to be all whiz-bang smoke and
mirrors nowadays I find
that people prefer just to be spoken to
calmly accurately and with good
intentions if you want to make your own
commercial spot you can do that too
because the podcast is young but growing
at an exceptionally fast rate if you
become an advertiser on the shaping fire
podcast now you are going to pay a
fraction of the cost we'd be asking for
in just a few months and yet everyone
listening both now and to the back
catalogue of interviews later we'll hear
about your company again and again for
years it's a great deal for you pay a
small amount now because the show is new
but take advantage of the huge listening
audience we will have forever do
yourself a solid and contact us today
for rates on podcast and newsletter
advertising email hot spot at shaping
fire calm to find out more welcome back
you are listening to shaping fire i am
your host Shango Lohse and our guest
this week is ariel pay up a founder of
lyric anna gars so before the break we
were talking about you know how much
time it takes to make one of these canna
gars and how huge the demand is and and
that you really can't meet the demand
just because you know you can only put
out so many of these while keeping the
quality high it would seem to me that a
big reason for your success is how
gorgeous your social media feed is you
know do you have a background in social
media or did you hire somebody on I mean
what what's the secret to your special
sauce that that that just makes your
stream so gorgeous um no I don't have
any background in a social media I just
been watching how other brands do their
social media like well for one I know my
counting cars were very limited so I try
to like model off of like um clothing
brands such as like supreme how they do
their their marketing in nike just just
showing little snippets of the product
and hyping people of what's that what's
that or you know um I just would like to
I just like creating hype you know I I
want to change the I just want to change
the also the the lifestyle of that the
image of like your cannabis user you
know it's just people think so negative
about people who smoke cannabis and
I want to change that they're like
successful CEOs business owners that
smoke cannabis every day but they don't
like to admit to it but now that they
have my product they're like oh yeah
yeah that's what kind of this is what I
smoke and people look at different like
Oh what is that and it's crazy like I
did my first wedding and they order like
20 categories for their wedding and like
who ever thought about having a cannabis
at their wedding like that is um is
crazy is it certainly makes it a lot
easier for for you know wealthy family
wealthy stoners if you will to identify
with your product right because you know
so much of canvas marketing is like big
clouds of smoke and people you know you
know let's just say not not acting in an
you know premium market kind of way
let's say okay and so and so you know in
your stream is filled with you know
people who are having some success in
their life and they're all like you know
I work hard and and I deserve nicer
things because I you know I put in so
much effort and so and so I'm enjoying
this this category we can do that I bet
you that that market is is not only
large but really grateful to have
something that speaks to the amount of
effort they put into their own lives
yeah it's crazy it's just seeing people
from all walks of life in just being
interested in these categories like even
people like I have a lot of cigar
aficionados messaging me um some of them
they've never tried cannabis before or
they'll be like oh that that is a great
product you have I never tried cannabis
but if that was in front of me I
definitely smoke it or you had that
cigar smoker that just uh they always
something like I grew up smoking weed in
my high school years but as I advance in
life you know I came home and I smoke
blunts and joints or out of a bonnet it
just seemed like a never grew cannabis
grew up and now that you've created this
more mature side of cannabis I want to
start smoking weed again
so is this kind of crazy I always ask
people like I have a lot of friends
that's used to be big stoners in college
or this an adder and then they tell me
they just grew out of it I was like what
it mean you grew out of it like you
still drink nobody nobody grows out of
drink unless they just want to quit due
to health reasons or something and so I
want to know why people want to quit
smoking cannabis and they just basically
told me just it just got tired of it
just then you feel like they're
advancing or anything so now I got that
top shelf product or they're like yeah I
want that that's something I won't look
forward to this weekend or for the
celebration or you know yeah it is
certainly a desirous thing you know I
mean there aren't a lot of products in
cannabis that I kind of fetishize over
but you know I've been following your
Instagram free for a while now and I'm
like oh my precious you know what I mean
I see these things I'm like oh man I
want one of those for my selves there
because they're there they really are
you know they're an art object as much
as they're a smokable thing when you
were when you were mentioning these
folks who you know you know toked back
in college or whatever and then they got
into business and they haven't talked in
a long time now they suddenly do I bet
you those folks need to be careful to
because going from like talking you know
all these years ago in college to
suddenly hitting a tangi and roz Encana
gar I mean one hit could you know put a
novice away yeah yeah well well it's
crazy to like when you smoke these
categories like yours super super high
alike but um you're not tired which I
don't understand i've smoked rolled it
with indicas or sativas and you're just
not tired just you're just super higher
maybe just because I'm around people i
know for one when i smoke the tangi like
I'm I'm very high and a lot of people
are just talking joking around and it is
it's cool thing cuz like uh yeah it's
just it's really a product that's meant
to be enjoyed with like everyone or or
maybe just intimately ER you know it's
just do you find that most people who
buy it are buying for celebration I mean
do you even come in contact with your
customers do you know who's buying them
oh yeah yes a lot of people buy them for
celebrations or then I have those
customers are just smokin right as they
get emoji that was a funny thing like
when people would pick up alara they
would the vo thank you then they just
crack it open right there and lightest I
know dude save that for like a special
occasion I could just buy another one I
was like okay you got money like that
it's like damn yeah totally that's
pretty cool i aspire to that as well so
it yeah and so you know some of those
people they're coming to get your cigars
from all over the place we've got to
talk about your recent Koenig our sale
you sold a 36 hundred dollar Koenig are
through Diego Pellicer retail store
there in Seattle it contained 21 grams
of Gorilla Glue number 44 grams of
peppermint cookies rasen and was wrapped
with two-tone canvas leaves dude who the
hell bought that I I can't really say
but the the person that bought it flew
in and in his private jet just just for
that product oh man that's that's so
baller did he contact you or the shop
ahead of time to say hey I'm flying in
old that for me no no the owner of Diego
felis Eric told told me told me about it
and I was just blown away I was just
like wow I didn't Wow first I was just
wondering who's gonna buy that the
cannon gar but someone had to fly in a
jet to make a statement okay yeah yeah
it's it's funny it's funny to what I see
you know when when you were originally
moving into the licensed market you know
via your social media you were you were
sharing with people like all right you
know we're moving from medical 250 to
hopefully they like my stuff here too
and then you started posting you know
images of sales receipts and you're like
damn this is working and like everybody
who's following is like yeah and you
know when shared in the astonishment
that people wanted that kind of a
premium product but you know in
retrospect it's it's not really all that
surprising I guess yeah it's just I
don't know I'm just I'm just really
amazed by all the attention that I've
been getting all the attention and the
help that i've been getting with this
product um
a lot of people this is like magazines
and websites have been asking for
interviews with me and or or they just
place my product in their magazine for
free you know and usually have to pay
for something like that which is which
I'm very appreciative for because they
see the image that I'm trying to do you
know is I'm not just trying to to have
my product out there I'm trying to
change the stigma of cannabis and and
that's what that's what they see in with
this luxury market it's it's working I
think that's something that you know
companies that are trying to do things
the right way naturally will attract
mark do you mean heck even even from me
right I mean you certainly didn't pay to
be on the show today I reached out to
you because I'm a fan right and and when
you make fans you know everybody wants
to show you to their friends right so I
think that's I think that says a lot
about the efforts you went into to you
know source quality organic material you
know get the best rasen you know the
fact that you're even hiring your your
your friends and families is really cool
too you know you keep you keep that
loyalty close at home and I think it
sets a good example so thanks for being
on the show today Ariel this has been
really interesting and hopefully it'll
inspire some other folks to do to do
businesses in their own area that is
just as righteous so lots of lots of
success to you and lyric Anna gars oh
thank you thanks for having me Ariel
peepee is founder of lyric Anna gars you
can find out more about lyric Anna gars
at Lyra canna gar scom and Lyra is
spelled le IRA but also make sure to
follow their fabulous instagram at ford
/ Lyra canna gars you can find more
episodes of the shaping fire podcast and
subscribe to the show at shaping fire
calm and on Apple iTunes stitcher and
Google Play if you enjoyed the show we'd
really appreciate it if you'd leave a
positive review of the podcast wherever
you download your review will help
others find the show so they can enjoy
it too on the shaping fire website you
can also subscribe to the weekly
newsletter for insights into the latest
cannabis news and product reviews on the
shaping fire website you will also find
transcripts of today's podcast as well
for information on me
where i'll be speaking you can check out
Shango lowes.com does your company want
to reach our national audience of
cannabis enthusiasts email hot spot at
shaping fire calm to find out how thanks
for listening to shaping fire I've been
your host Shango lowes
[Music]