here we go now for real so I welcome
everybody to the 1:30 presentation
solving lussac's traction strategies for
success if you haven't already done so
please silence your cell phone so that
we're not hearing those I am shake the
Laos host of the shaping fire podcast if
you like listening to smart interviews
with the top minds in cannabis I invite
you to check out the show at shaping
fire calm we also have an extraordinary
YouTube channel with over 150 speaker
videos that reported at events just like
this one in fact our philosophy one of
our speakers already appears on the
channel teaching about rosin tech Josh
Rutherford is one of the founders of
pure pressure as well as owner of push
masters and award-winning processing lab
based in Boulder Colorado
Erik loskis director of marketing for
pure pressure and the two of them
operate pure pressure the
industry-leading saltless equipment
supplier so please welcome Josh and Eric
awesome thank you all for coming we
appreciate your time we've got a really
good seminar here to empower anyone
either if you have an existing business
that's running solvent list and you're
looking for tips and tricks on how to
make it better
or if it's a form of extraction that
you're looking to get into either as a
complete net new or as one that you're
gonna be adding on to an existing
operation so the whole point of this
presentation is to give people advice
tips and strategies that you can be
successful with solvent lists it's one
of the extraction forms that needs the
most education and that's what we're
here for so Josh and I will be you know
tag-teaming these topics we've got a lot
of great ideas to share with you guys
and we're gonna go through this
presentation in a cadence kind of
leading you through how to really think
about being successful with solving this
processing because there are a lot of
elements to it that if you're not really
orienting your business in the right way
you can make some missteps you can
stumble and it'll make it a little more
difficult for you to do so so we're here
to help anyone who's trying to do salt
and let's do it right so the first big
point is in today's market with
concentrates if you are not making samos
concentrates you do not have a premium
extraction brand and a lot of our
customers solvent list might be five
percent of their business and some of
our customers it's a hundred percent of
their business but if you are trying to
make concentrates solvent list is the
way that you attract influencers and
come source because that's really the
product category that that specific
segment of the market is looking for now
we go to tons of trade shows we talk to
business owners I mean business owners
of co2 companies hydrocarbon companies
those guys that are owning and running
those companies are smoking processes
that's what they tell us the absolute
secret I mean it's the clean concentrate
as well you know the solvent is
concentrates it's also fleshing the
highest dollar you have
a variation of skews that you're able to
create with rosin with ball hash and
really escalate what you guys are doing
whether it's an existing lab we're
trying to start justice all tooless lab
or having a solvent and solvent this
labs it's really really important to be
able to have and we'll get into this a
little bit later is a variations of SKUs
and saltless can bring you that and you
know it's a definitely one of the
cleanest concentrate forms that I enjoy
smoking laws yeah
so another quick note here is that many
of our customers are doing all kinds of
forms of extraction and and most labs
should be so that is the perfect segue I
don't know if anybody checks out MJ biz
they put out a fact book every year they
updated we are not affiliated with them
in any way I'm not a salesperson for MJ
biz but they're Factbook provides some
of the best data in the industry and if
you're serious about learning where
trends are totally recommend it and
that's where this slide is coming from I
know the resolution isn't very good but
what this very complicated set of bars
and numbers is trying to tell us is that
the profitability of processing
operations increases dramatically when
you're making a number of SKUs so for
processing operations that are making
one two three different products only
six of them are reporting that they're
profitable that is very very little now
you get into four to six 20% but then
once you get to that bottom what that's
really saying is that processing labs
that are making between 11 and 15 unique
SKUs unique products 83% of them are
reporting profitability that is a
massive Gulf in the difference of how
many products these labs are making and
their profitability as a result yeah and
the reason you know you kind of see that
trend in the industry is because we're
in a limited market you know wherever
you're opening up whether it's Colorado
whether it's you know Illinois or
California you know there's only so many
dispensaries licenses so being able to
capture more skews more volume with each
of those stores and have a bigger
presence in those stores is very
important in order to be the most
accessible with yourself in this
business or so and most importantly
solvent lists is the least expensive way
to add additional SKUs when you compare
cost you know for the equipment for
everything that need to go in on to
actually release a number of Samba SKUs
it's Ovilus tends to be the least
expensive of all of them so it's the
easiest way the cheapest way to add
additional SKUs to your product mix if
you aren't already good so yeah that's
all about the post process cost process
that you're actually using to make those
SKUs so whether it's going to be topical
edibles carts you know rather than
batter there's a bunch of different jams
and micro-diamonds all sorts of
different things each one of these can
be ask you for your business to be
selling and what it's going to come down
to is also the material that you're able
to source or grow so that's also
something that we're going to get into
here down the line yep absolutely
so helps you attract more consumers
there are consumers in the market and
I'm sure a number of them in this room
right now that you probably will pretty
much only smoke salt list or maybe
really good live resin but the high-end
the connoisseur the influencer consumers
this is the product that they're looking
for and if your lab isn't producing it
then you're not even competing in that
market in the first place so now we're
going to talk a little bit about the
different types of products that we see
as the most popular that are being sold
the most and right now really catch
rosin has risen over the last couple
years to be pretty much the dominant
solvent list product in terms of quality
in terms of volume being sold at
dispensaries so Josh you know running
coach master
and making a lot of hydrocarbon solvent
list he makes a whole variety of
products not just solving list this is
what you can see right oh yeah it's
definitely the industry trend and my
career I was just mentioning you know
there's many different consistencies
that you can make off of your cell phone
this concentrates so it's really off of
the post-processing and actually
maximizing and using industry specific
equipment so that you're optimizing
yourself on this metric because you
don't want to leave 2 3 % behind and you
know end up you know not having the
extra that you could have that it's
gonna actually make your business Bible
yep and we're gonna talk about food
grade solvent lists and kind of
dispelling the myth of how to get a
better yield out of your product with
hash drawers and specifically you're
seeing that people are really developing
a taste for live rosin products just
like live resin coming from fresh frozen
plants that terpene profile and for a
whole variety of other business reasons
labor time there's all these reasons
that companies are doing live products
and live rosin is pretty much the king
right now in terms of high-end Abbeville
concentrates now full metal six star is
also starting to make you come back a
lot of the people that have you know
been enjoying hatch for a long time it's
a pretty unparalleled experience
experience to get great full melt now
more and more places are trying hard to
produce full mel bricked hash is making
a comeback as well we are seeing some
really cool ice water cash products and
not to leave sift out of this there's a
lot of companies also making really
great stiff crossing flour rosin however
is a product that we're not seeing as
much of in mature markets like colorado
in newer markets it's easy to produce
we're seeing a lot more of it there but
as markets tend to mature we're seeing a
little bit
consumption of flour oven yeah and we
kind of talked a little bit about that
and why you kind of see those trends
those trends are also because of the
price point of the flour compared to in
that relative market so you know for
example if the East Coast I mean I'm
sure pound flour on the recreational and
medical market are still going for three
thousand plus we're here in Colorado
there two thousand and below so you
start to see those trends and those
shifts within those camp cannabis
businesses and those mitts so those nips
were basically going to be able to
create different SKUs and varieties
based on the price points they're able
to start sourcing material yep so these
are kind of big dogs right now
and then where we see and have seen
really great opportunities for existing
and new businesses to take advantage is
with leash saltless products there's a
number of them out there and there's
producers kind of all across the country
that are building their brands and their
businesses today on these CBD and CBD
rosin we're going to talk about that
cartridges the proliferation of true
rosin cartridges is just going haywire
right now concerns there's just so many
of these high end hash makers that are
now starting to make cartridges topicals
and salves that's another thing you know
just having a product that is based in
rosin that is solvent list is
immediately a differentiator that people
can identify with and one that will can
also increase the price point of your
product because it is a higher quality
product to begin with
yeah and topical themselves and edibles
and stuff like that your grams of
concentrate you know it might not be a
demo to dabble gram or something that
you want to hit the shelf well then
you're able to take that type of product
or even a second press rosin and really
ship those into those type of products
and that potency is going to go so much
farther than selling one gram
your dog and you know coming from my and
the things working in marketing talking
with so many of our clients and kind of
their marketing endeavors you know this
is one of the most powerful tools you
can give a marketing team and your
company is to say this product is
solvent list this product is full
spectrum this product that has these
quality identifiers z' to it whether or
not it was made from a food-grade rosin
or not so there's a lot more flexibility
with solvent list now than there was a
year ago when we were giving this talk
and we're seeing a lot more businesses a
lot more of our customers you know
really diversifying what they're doing
with their material as they press it and
turn it into a variety of different
things yeah now more than ever setting
yourself apart this industry is exactly
what you need to be able to make a stamp
and a brand so just before I move on
resolution very good but poplin Barkley
one of our biggest customers out in
California they've become famous for
what they put out our mainly topical
zein I mean they're one of our biggest
customers and the majority of what they
do with their rosin is is making
topicals in California I mean that is
the clearest example of a brand in an
extremely competitive and difficult
market California is extremely tough to
operate in right now using a food-grade
high-quality rosin to make topicals and
being extremely successful with it so
one small example obviously really nice
packaging doesn't hurt but they do a
really good job
another thing CBD rosin this is
something that unlike ice water hash and
sift is still very much in the mastering
process I think a lot of businesses are
really trying to figure this out right
now and a lot of people are interested
this is farm house hemp they're located
in Fort Collins Colorado we did a video
with them talking about that but that
they use browsing for all of their CBD
products there are some issues depending
on the concentrations of course but
using CBD rosin is a
a huge differentiator and there's a ton
of things that you can put it into it's
not just selling a CVS Ram and within
you know they'll CBD and you know you're
pressing something you're activating it
next y'see well you're just
concentrating it you know that will
happen whether you're distilling it or
you're using ethanol or whether you're
using solvent list you're gonna end up
having a higher concentration of THC in
that product which is going to make it
uncomplaining within you know the farm
bill to be shipping so what you do at
that point is you end up mixing it into
you know MCT oils or you end up making
products themselves that because even if
it has 1% THC in the overall concentrate
after you've done after you've made it
well after you've diluted into that one
ounce jar for that pet now you're maybe
0.1 percent THC and we're always allowed
to point three are there any products
that you've seen on the CBD side that
are particularly popular right now I
mean that products tinctures salads are
probably one of the most popular that
I've seen right now just totally on the
market but pet products you know I feel
like you know anything well anybody will
do anything for their pets so yeah
definitely I know so another big thing
that we really get a lot of questions
about and now we're gonna kind of lead
into you know really actionable advice
and items for your business or any
business that you're planning on
starting is kind of explaining what
yields with solvent this look like and
and what they mean so and it's really
shifting so when you've got flour rosin
you're looking at ranges of 18% or above
and all of these ranges are what you can
expect and what you should strive for
with your business now with ice water
1/2 specifically since we've been
talking a lot about that when we're
talking four to eight percent that's a
fresh frozen product that is a product
that is about three-quarters wet weight
we're not talking about a dry to a dry
we're talking to that a wet product
yielding into a final dry state yes so
taking a frozen and a dry pod basically
your frozen pond will basically be like
a quarter pound dry so I always use the
math to 7525 when you're talking about
frozen weight so you're talking about
frozen way for true frozen pounds equals
one dry pound so when you're doing your
math and you do your numbers based on
these numbers there's actually pretty it
equals you know that eighteen percent
range compared to you know that four to
eight percent it's the same math it's
just a different volume of water within
that cup within that but mass yep and
we're about to talk pretty heavily about
genetics because that is going to be one
of the key factors here and how to
achieve yields that are profitable for
your business and the way to really
think about this is if you're trying to
make a full milk product you're trying
to you know capture the best trichomes
you possibly can and sell that as a
standalone product what you would do as
a business is watch that product very
gently at first and then you're gonna go
back and you're gonna re wash it for a
full spectrum you're not just gonna
leave all of those trichomes in the bag
and weave them behind this is a
multi-stage process to get multiple
products out of a single strain or
cultivar that you're working with so
that again you can diversify the amount
of products that you're actually selling
here same goes for sift you know you
might tumble what you've got very very
gently to make a really high-quality
sift that you're gonna press into your
best sift rosin and then you can
continue sifting it getting more out of
it to create other products yep and
that's what I was talking about earlier
where then you take that stuff that
you're not going to end up hitting the
market with that is a what I call it a
bubble concentrate and you're basically
putting in top of clothes you're putting
in edibles you're putting in it or
distilling it you know
doing all sorts of other post-processing
to create it into a final violent
consumable product yep so with yield and
solve unless it really comes more down
to the types of plants that you're
running and the types of strains that
you're using so with other types of
extraction salt Neum solvent based
extractions one of the key questions we
get asked all the time you know what
what really is the difference between a
solvent and a solvent list extraction
process look I'll take them real quick
wait huh he makes more so you got to
look at a solvent process so at the
solvent process we're liquefying ANCA
trichome heads and so since we're
liquefying were looking liquefying them
and then reclaiming that gas and leaving
the THC and then purging it purging that
gas off later in the post-processing and
so with solvent list what we're doing is
we're basically stripping it with either
ice water
you know co2 dry ice or just tumbling it
in itself and or just pressing it in
itself so we're got to be a little bit
more delicate with it as well and you
know with saw the list you're stripping
it you're basically keeping it as a
whole plant so hold about I'm sure
you're all familiar you have different
micron screens well at each different
micron screen you're gonna have a
different grade and those different
grades are gonna create a different
final product for you
and what it will allow you to do is
stretch that solvent less material that
much further to create that anymore
skews to make yourself as business that
much more viable ultimately what we are
trying to do is solve unless is isolate
the resin glands intact and then create
various products from those isolated
trichomes whereas with solvent based
it's a dissolution process graphically
exactly see they're stripping at your
liquefying it and you're also taking a
bunch of fats and lipids with it where
we're actually able to keep it more here
throughout that process and as we get
rougher with that process we're able to
you know get that higher yield for
topicals edibles also
different products yep so sourcing
proper material whether you're growing
it or purchasing it through your
business is one of if not the most
important steps to be successful assault
unless and I'm sure as people in here
who have created solvent list but no you
know we talk to our customers and you
know sometimes they run tangey their
cost program to produce it is there they
are losing money on that gram whereas
with other ones they're making a lot
more you know if you're watching math or
you have some of these other strains
your price for gram to wash and create
that product there's a giant range there
so being able to actually get material
that's going to work for saltless is one
of the most important steps here and
when you're vertically integrated that
gives you a lot of control because if
your head grower is on board and
actually looking for genetics that they
know will do well and their strain
hunting then that's really gonna help
you yeah the lineage in the genetics I
mean we'll get into a few strains and
crosses and stuff like that we have a
list out of you know just some you know
things to look out for you know as
you're going out buying seeds as you're
going out and you know buy clones from
these different businesses making sure
that the lineage is there so that those
trichomes structures which we have a
slide here coming up that will shows
Tricon structures and how full those
trichome heads are and if they're just
shelves because when you look at a track
go ahead and if it's gonna be full
you're gonna end up you know having a
much higher yield than the salt and ice
extraction process compared to if it's a
shell you just wash that away when we're
that's where you're gonna have a half
percent or 1 percent and that's gonna be
more on your high higher Terpening of
like tangi those type of flavors you
want more 10 type of flavor and cross
its case but yeah get into that a little
bit yeah so what we like to tell people
is that if you're growing your own it's
really important to
identify strains that are gonna work
well like we're just about to go into a
whole bunch of crosses and strains that
you can start hunting for yourself or if
you're purchasing from the third party
you really need to make sure that they
are aware that either this product has
been washed in the past or the strain
you want to ask them you know can I get
a little bit to do a test wash does the
is the grower aware that this may work
well or not for solvent list in the
first place there's a lot of questions
that you can ask before you go all-in on
a batch that you're gonna produce and
turning into Roslyn yeah that your grows
and you bet your sourcing material that
is probably the best advice I can give
each and every one of you you know I
test washes you know buy three pounds of
each strain that they're growing in XY
and Z and you know see how they do in
each different type of salt in this
process and then that gives you data and
then it also gives you partners you know
they're able to rely on you you're able
to rely on them and you have this nice
symbiotic relationship where you they
are learning how you want it to be come
to your facility how you want impact how
many increments all of those things are
going to lead you to very very
successful business so just a slide here
on the different try some of the
different trichome structures and what
they look like
across the top even though it's a little
hard to read you know that's so small
it's a spike 20 it's gonna go pretty
much straight through your bag and
there's a lot of hemp strains actually
that those are the types of trichomes
kind of a top across the top row there
that you're gonna see that are common in
certain CBD strains which is why they
can be really hard to wash whereas with
you know d here in the bottom left
corner that is pretty much your ideal
trichome structure for pressing the
rosin washing or sifting because it's
large enough to be captured well and
it's got a large glandular head yeah and
it's full you know you're gonna see a
lot of trichome heads you might be able
to see those track dome heads underneath
the microscope but it might be empty and
even if you see that track on that
that's how people otherwise you're not
going to end up having a successful
yield of on your salt less material yep
so with many of our most successful
customers how they've gotten that way is
by being relentless and detail-oriented
about how they select the material and
strange that they choose to run through
solvent list so that they can increase
their yields and increase their chance
of success you know getting a jeweler's
loupe looking at the plant seeing where
the trichomes are how big that are what
kinds they are you know it's that
attention to detail that will make the
biggest difference in selecting genetics
that you can really be profitable on
really build your brand on and get
connoisseurs and influencers you know
behind your brand online for your
solvents products here are some strains
take a picture happy to send this out I
mean this will be on shaping fires
podcast and yeah we're doing it on our
website on our website is not secret
information but these are some of the
strands that we see with many of our
customers and some of the biggest hash
makers online that the cultivars and the
lineages associated with many of these
are so popular and they yield so well
that they deserve special attention and
you know kind of like we have a node at
the bottom here I mean there's so many
great breeders that come to this show
and sell their stuff a lot of breeders
are now really really trying to make
strains specifically for rosin and
solvent lists Josh has had some pretty
incredible results with a couple of
these at his own lab Eric Simpson who's
with us in the audience told us that he
had a record-breaking wash of nine
percent on a related strain so you know
the money sitting right over there so
these are some really great strains to
start with now a caveat here is that
just because you pop a chem dog scene
does not guarantee that that streams
is you know gonna yield five six percent
in your wash but that's not what that
means but that these are generally
lineages and cultivars that have proper
tricone structure and that have the best
shot at being able to give you a bud
structure a tri comb structure and the
turkey profile that's going to play nice
with salt and stretch exactly and this
is the thing you also have to think
about if you're fully integrated you're
going to be growing these are the
genetics and stuff that you're going to
want to be sourcing and buying because
that also not only is going to give you
a versatile product but it's going to
give the mipzor whatever boy labs say
you have an influx of material you're
able to sell that as salt on this
material and hydrocarbon material it
doesn't limit you one route or the other
now you're probably getting 25 50 bucks
more per pound you know just because you
got a versatile product and also you're
gonna end up with clients and you know
you're gonna end up with crosses and you
know I can arkad you that we did
together you know we talked about
artisan blends
where you end up having to compete grew
it completely sucker and then you mix it
up into the washing process to make you
know a very interesting terpene profile
like the pumps trunk that we put out at
you know there's some essential extract
is to do that very well - yeah and they
were around here so yep it's keys to
being successful you know what as your
sourcing material purchasing seeds and
you know definitely keep that money yep
so again keeping an eye on the genetics
you know many hash makers and growers
are really proud of the products that
they put out as they should be and they
are not shy about what kinds of strains
are working well for them so highly
suggest going out you know following
hash makers on Instagram that are making
solvent less being successful with it
they're always talking about the new
strains that they're running they're not
going to give you a cut of it I can
pretty much guarantee that but you
should have any opponent
sure yeah or find a client's daughter
who has a similar one you know
cookies-and-cream is a huge one the
cream crosses ice cream just on this
list along GMO mac the cake and the chem
dog crosses and lineages are by far my
favorite on this list and we'll do you
really really well you know hit that
nano a at nine percent there's a lot of
good options here we've been told that
roughly a quarter to a third of
phenotypes and strains out there are
gonna be in that profitable yield range
for what you're good so it's not every
single one but there's more of them than
people expected absolutely so here's a
really really big one you know once
we've kind of gone through the idea of
what kind of SKUs you're thinking about
making and whether you're an MSO a
multi-state operator looking to install
the same lab in multiple states or
you're a boutique grower who is just
building your brand around a core line
of solvent list products really thinking
about your lab space is one of the best
things that you can do for yourself
early on in the process I mean it can be
very exciting - yeah man we're gonna Rob
the press we're gonna get in there push
this [__] awesome you can make a solvent
list lab be very successful in under a
thousand square feet and we see people
and they are making their rising in a
closet and they are winning awards with
it so square footage is one of the
smallest concerns but planning against
it is one of the most important things
you can do so streamlining your floor
spent floor space and you know really
making sure that it's optimized for what
you guys are really doing at your lab is
important so figuring out the SKUs not
only that you want to produce in the
future but that you're going to be
really see
when you go to market or the excuse that
you have in the market all of those
things have to be factored into place
before you say I'm gonna go put that
route and press on that table and this
at the freeze dryer up here and the wash
machine over there
you know because that includes plumbing
that include you know there's a lot of
little things that will make your life a
lot easier if you put things in the
right spot yeah and for anyone who is
considering getting into this or already
is and is looking to upgrade like we're
talking about the very beginning if you
have questions about you know how many
free strawberries do I really need or
how much space do I need to plan against
that's something that we can actually
help you guys out with and those are
some of the most popular questions that
we get asked on a daily basis is you
know I've got X amount of material and
I'm trying to wash it week you know what
do I really need how do I really lay out
my space how do I lay out my lab design
and and we've become you know pretty
much the top dogs in helping lab build
and grow out with that so happy to help
there anything else you want to add on
this all right so we're gonna leave you
know good 10 to 15 minutes here for QA
since the last time when we do
presentations that went way over that
they kick us off the stage
so we've got some predictions here that
we're expecting for 2020 and beyond just
based on the trends and speaking with
our customers browsing cartridges are
coming in hot people are really excited
about this product it's not available in
that many markets yet but now businesses
are really starting to see that if I
master my solvent list process a
cartridge is a product that is the
luxury cart that is it is the
top-of-the-line product that your
business can sell pretty much that's
going to appeal to the widest range of
consumers so that's gonna be huge you
wanna have something that
and I think it's gonna be one of the
bigger things that we're gonna see in
2020 you know and it will take you know
some time you know to get your business
there to be launching you know all sorts
of carts all sorts of you know hash rods
and you know it is a learning process
and sourcing the right material to be
coming out with these exotic SKUs
yep so there's a lot of businesses
coming out in Colorado with it and
really the progression is you know
mastering the hash rods and mastering
the SIP rosin and then doing the Rd to
create a product like this and I mean
it's crazy we're talking 70 to 90
dollars for a half gram of these type of
cartridges so very high price points and
then niche solvent list products like we
were talking about before CV rosin
topicals edibles especially a major new
opportunity there's just not a lot of
businesses out there that are promoting
that and that are using those products
and the solvent list as a differentiator
to do so but now that but now people are
really picking up on that as competition
is increasing people are looking for
different ways to differentiate
themselves in the market these are going
to be products you're gonna start seeing
a lot more of and then many more labs
that are not doing solvents processing
are starting to realize how much they're
missing out on by not competing in the
first place so we're getting a lot of
calls and a lot of people are coming to
us saying you know hey I've been
thinking about this for a long time or
you know I'm just not really sure if
this is gonna work for me but all of my
guys in the lab like will not show up
about they will not stop asking me when
but when we're gonna start releasing
rosin so we're seeing a lot of these
businesses really starting to come out
of the Woodworks and realizing that you
know this is an area to compete in
there's a lot there I mean you don't
need you know a thousand square feet you
can do it start with 500 you know or and
then move up to a thousand square feet
or you know if you have extra allocated
space I mean the cost to get in to solve
unless extraction or add into your
business and add all of those SKUs I
mean I can guarantee you six months down
the road if you did you know half of
what we said on here you're gonna
an extra three to six skews or at least
and all those hundred of sub stores that
you're already in are going to start to
pick those up and then those invoices
just paint keep going up but no enough
so the last thing we'll close with here
before we go into the Q&amp;A is you know
from my perspective and from speaking
with many of our customers it's hard to
understate how big of a brand builder
solvent list can be and in a really
really flooded market with cannabis
products having your brand be something
that people recognize on the Shelf
whether it's through your packaging you
know really through the quality of your
product that these are the kinds of
products that people are really talking
about and especially the influencers I
mean I just cannot understate that
enough and that's how some of these big
brands like push masters you know having
come out won an award that if people
talk about it on Instagram all time like
that is free advertising for your
business and and the value cannot be
understated exactly go let's get some
questions so that's it Cheryl Mike with
Joshua sure so we've got about 10
minutes for questions go ahead and raise
your hand and we'll get right to it we
came in late you may have artists talked
about the equipment that you're using
and if so I apologize but you did
mention the freeze-dried line yes
peer pressure equipment you know we have
everything from you know solvent lifts
equipment to freeze dryers to sift
equipment you know we're basically a
one-stop shop for you know all saltless
products that you would need and we try
and source everything you know that is
going to end up coming with certs for
doing all sorts of different you know
and help you build your
business and it's also about when kind
of touched on this earlier about
industry specific equipment we built
designed all this equipment from the
ground up and made it functional from
the ground up to make sure that this
saltless is viable because five years
ago you know it really wasn't no I mean
one thing talked about because you
couldn't do it on the commercial scale
well now you can and now it's you know
really one of the highest quality
highest price point things I'm shelves
fed and after this if you like you know
with our booth at 411 if you want to
come by we'd be happy to talk with you
about just the different options and
what kind of equipment you need and it's
really all based on what your processing
needs are and so it every business is
gonna need a different solution and
that's really the approach that we take
I know you showed kind of the
percentages that you're coming out but
just straight away unlike an average
kind of run that you're kind of seeing
from fresh frozen to year green a cash
frozen one and a half percent two
percent what do you really think that
the average market is and I know there's
monsters that dump
I know that's X gifts so to rosin I mean
you're looking at around 3% to rather
than on your average you know frozen and
you know you'll have those dumpers that
are going to offset you and you know
create it because yes there is loss in
each post processing that you do which
will then determine your yield at your
finished product but then through that
it's though also those byproducts that
we were talking about earlier from that
post-processing that you're able to
extend and save and create that many
more SKUs that now you it wasn't a loss
you see what I mean
know the highest quality is really going
into the carts and that's a you know
partly the tricky part and why you don't
see as much of them on the market
yeah for states that have just gone
medical or states like Illinois or
Missouri have you seen any problem with
production of fresh fresh frozen and
like the supply of fresh frozen not
being adequate yeah I think the supply
is an issue in some newer states because
as markets mature is what we've seen
pretty much consistently across the
board is that you know smokeable flour
is the dominant product when a market
launches because people have not had
access to this
it before other than buying it on the
street or from friends or whatever it is
so getting fresh frozen product can be a
challenge for some businesses in
emerging markets but I think some of
these markets are starting to leapfrog
each other whereas a couple years ago
you could barely buy it in some of the
emerging markets but then now in
Illinois you know things are getting
more sophisticated and that people who
are coming to shows like these going to
the trade shows and learning things are
thinking like okay well smokeable flour
is going to be big today but in five
months from now I know that I need to
get a great source of fresh frozen so I
can be washing and making these kinds of
products as that trend goes down and as
that price point goes down as well like
we were talking earlier you know in that
market more people will convert because
there won't be as much of a demand for
dry flour they'll convert it to fresh
frozen and then you'll see an increase
in fresh frozen and you know it's kind
of like Colorado now where you know you
can get fresh frozen all the time where
you can get dry material all the time
and it's just about the way the market
sits and the how all of these grows set
up their business for you know whether
it was that frozen model or that drug
to your model and you'll see a lot of
these dry material models start to
change and start to go to fresh frozen
as that price point drops have you seen
anybody take the wash material and then
process it with solvents after so you
know you know drive material and then
you know throw a co2 machine or hydrogen
and if so what's the best way to get
that material correct to run of those
pieces absolutely and I mean if you have
a giant facility I mean it's totally
doable but once you actually factor in
the profitability on the material what
you've made on it and you if you
utilized at all you know it's not
necessarily worth it the labor that it's
gonna take to be able to read extract it
dry it you know you're gonna have a lot
of moisture and if you don't read right
after you just washed it and then you
have price to melt you know there's
there's definitely problems with it
today you know couldn't be down the
lines and machines that you know will do
that but you'd be having around a 2% 3%
yield I mean you look at solvent
extraction when you read you know don't
you know solvent over it after you've
just extracted it again you're looking
at a 3% yield or less out the door and
then you know it's basically waste
material at that point we have heard of
some people taking that approach but
like Josh said it's very uncommon
because once you actually total up the
labor it ends up really digging into
what you can do with it what most places
are doing is doing they're getting
multiple washes on the same material to
start you know with that 3% which really
dry weight is like 12% to getting that a
grade hash product and then washing
again into more full-spectrum into more
of a food grade and just getting
everything out of it so that your actual
yield on your first grade you know it
might be that 3% but the total yield for
you know these more sophisticated
extractors it's going to be a lot higher
than that or at least a bit higher than
that by re extracting it but through
solvents ways yeah yeah all right this
will be our last question
is there any like tricks that you do in
your grow to tell what's gonna wash
better any like ways of you know kind of
something super greasy is it gonna wash
well it's it's not gonna wash well or
what's like kind of tips or tricks again
see if I'm at ya
so I'll start up to present really get
input on this again one of the tips that
I talked about in the beginning that
we've heard from a lot of places I'm
Church oft as well you know using
magnifying glasses and other
magnification technology to look at the
trichomes beforehand and you can even
you know brush your finger on something
and see how well they attach because
detach ability of your trichome heads is
a really important thing to figure out
what a lot of places do is also a very
small test wash so you could even I mean
the people that have done this I think
can wall was one who put some info out
that most recently was just you know
putting some in a jar and letting some
of the trichomes just naturally separate
and then seeing how they settle and
really eyeballing it and seeing you know
how much is in my jar right now does
this look like a lot does this look like
a little you know if you're doing a test
wash there's a lot of things that you
can figure out before you're committing
you know tens of thousands of fresh
frozen grams to actually doing it yeah
and I mean it's basically test watching
all of your genetics and looking at
those trichome heads are keys but you
know starting with genetics that you can
know our fee knows that are going to
wash well and you know you're gonna have
maybe 14 seeds and of that genetic that
you washed and you can watch those
trichome head structures you can watch
all those fee notes and then you can
decide okay this one has a dumper the
structure looked really good you know
it's healthy that's the those are the
three that I want to go into my grow
moving forward that's gonna be the keys
to dialing in your girl definitely trial
and error right oh that is all of our
time thank you very much thank you
[Applause]
you