welcome everybody to the 12:30
presentation I am Shango Laos your host
and I'm also host of the shaping fire
podcast if you love learning from the
top speakers in the industry I encourage
you to check out shaping fire com where
my podcast is hosted and also our
YouTube channel where you'll find over a
hundred videos unique there and not
available anywhere else
I require speakers like today and take
it home and I put it on my youtube
channel so if you are not able to go to
all the conventions and you want to hear
some of these hot speakers that aren't
speaking near where you live I encourage
you to check out the shaping fire
YouTube channel our presentation right
now is from Erin Pulaski from go pure
pressure will be speaking on solve
unless extraction explained rosin bubble
hash dry sift Erica was a founding
member of mass roots and is now director
of marketing at pure pressure in Denver
Colorado Eric has worked with canvas
companies in every facet of the industry
and today we'll be talking about solvus
solvent 'less extraction techniques
all right thank you all for coming
I'm gonna try and make this as
informative and interesting as possible
I'm really excited about solving this
extraction and thank you all for being
here by show of hands how many people
here feel that they are at least
somewhat familiar with solving this
extraction great that's what I was
hoping for the beginning of this is
going to be a little bit higher surface
level and then we're really going to
kind of get into some details some of
the topics we're going to be covering
today it will be about 30 minutes of
presentation then I'd like to leave you
know at least 15 for Q&amp;A at the end we
were getting a lot of questions at the
booth so I want to make sure that we can
answer as many of your questions as
possible so what we're going to go
through today is a lay of the land of
extraction in general and we're a
solvent list fits into that some of the
advantages and challenges of solvent
list extraction how it might fit into
your facility or someone that you know
the popular types of products and
textures as well as you know myths and
what's almond less can and can't do
so this should give everyone in here
good idea of what solvent less
extraction is all about where it's
heading in the next year or two things
are changing very quickly and the main
products that we will be focusing on our
ice water extracts you know otherwise
known as bubble hash dry scepter Keef
and of course rosin kind of which is
becoming the big daddy of them all so
I'd like to preface this conversation by
basically saying that you know the
future of cannabis really is processing
in your average grocery store anywhere
from 10 to 20 percent of the perishable
items are actually produce virtually
everything else in a grocery store has
been processed in one way or another so
what we're really looking at is cannabis
being pretty much the most versatile
drug for recreational purposes and
medical purposes that can be turned into
so many different things everything from
every edible that you can ever imagine
people are already seeing that vape pens
abs and concentrates of every texture
that you've ever seen and perhaps have
never heard of we are pretty much on the
cusp of a global market and it's easy
for us to kind of lose sight you know in
our states where we can't even move
products across state lines
things are very siloed and segmented in
the northwest some of the concentrates
are starting to make their way up here a
lot of the popular textures that people
are paying $100 a gram for in California
are now starting to be produced in
Oregon and Washington where you know
they've been in California and Colorado
for a year or two already so a lot of
the trends are coming out of Colorado in
California but I think as time goes on
we're really going to see products that
are sold out for potentially a year at a
time Boutique growers that are so
popular with their concentrates and
their products once those products can
cross state lines that you'll be seeing
people backward for who knows how long
and this is kind of focusing a little
bit we're solvent less really fits in is
in the boutique end of the market really
high-end products so going more from
that
you know more and more consumers or
seeking concentrated products and we're
going to go into some facts and some
data a little bit later in the
presentation but anyone that follows MJ
vis new frontier had said a lot of these
great data sources pretty much
concentrates are being consumed more and
more at the expense of flour so a high
amount of flour is basically being
converted into concentrates and as
Colorado Washington Nevada California
those are some of the main areas that
decent data is available on your over
your concentrate consumption growth not
just solvent list but all concentrates
in general is increasing and we expect
to see that same trend over time and
pretty much all maturing markets that
once cannabis becomes legal people are
very excited they're purchasing joints
and flour and you know this is great and
then their taste preferences tend to
change they say oh well how about
edibles and what is a DAB and and what
is that going to do for me and of course
as people's tolerances grow they're
looking for different experiences so
pretty much across the board in Colorado
and California concentrate growth is
right around 25 23 percent depending on
where you're getting your data from that
as a percentage of the products sold in
the northwest the data that we've been
told is right around 18 percent so
there's definitely still room there
where it's growing there's a lot more
consumption of concentrates that's going
to be happening virtually everywhere as
the markets expand so to really define
solvent was extraction what we're
looking at is a process of mechanical
separation and mechanical separation is
different from using solvents because
what you're having is various physical
forces that are separating the trichomes
and the cannabinoids as opposed to
dissolving them into solvents so when
you're running butane any hydrocarbon
co2 any of those solvent based processes
what you're running into is a
dissolution of
avenues and terpenes and then your
reforming that taking things out you
know recovering your solvents so
mechanical separation is anything from
shearing breaking things open with rosin
and we'll get into that but that really
is the main distinction and what I'm not
gonna spend time talking as much day is
what's better because people have all
kinds of different taste preferences we
believe in peer pressure that there are
solvent based concentrates that are
absolutely elite and made very well and
when urged properly but what we've also
seen is that a lot of companies will
take products that aren't the highest
quality necessarily and then they will
use that to put that through certain
hydrocarbon and other systems so one of
the big things that we're going to talk
about today is where quality fits into
the equation and how quality is such a
big part of being successful with
solvent --less concentrates but it's
important to understand that when you're
actually making a solvent less
concentrated you're not dissolving it
with a solvent seems pretty
straightforward but that's one of the
questions that we get all day every
single day to go back a little bit you
know hash is being made for as long as
of millennium almost the the earliest
reference that I could find when
researching for this presentation was
eleventeen 23 that there's references of
hash being made in middle east so
solvent list concentrates called that
have technically been around for maybe a
thousand years or more people have been
making hash in various ways all across
the world mainly concentrated in Asia
the Middle East where it was getting
started collecting resin from cannabis
plants forming in different ways I'm
sure a lot of people especially people
who have been you know consuming and
been around for a lot longer than I have
Thai sticks Turkish hash all kinds of
different products that before were the
concentrated potency increases that
people were consuming and now we're
seeing this absolutely massive
proliferation of different textures
concentrates extraction methods
everything that you can imagine so cash
has been around for
a really long time I'm sure a lot of
people here may finally remember you
know sprinkling Keef on a bowl or a
little bit of round bubble hash and you
know increasing the potency of whatever
they were smoking and layering into a
joint and now you've got you know 99.9%
pure THC a distillate that will take you
to the moon and back in a tiny little
dab so we've seen a massive massive
evolution in the way that concentrates
are being produced and we expect that to
continue I mean this is really the tip
of the iceberg with solvent Wisconsin
traits as well as solvent based and who
knows if there's other categories that
are going to get developed that we're
not even really aware of right now I
mean this is really all just getting
started so pretty much where we're at
with the main separation here so I just
wanted to give everyone a little bit of
a lay of the land I think a lot of
people have familiarity with
concentrates in general but just to kind
of educate everyone on where things
break down these are the primary methods
of solvent based distillate is can be
run without solvents such as in steam
distillation or it can be used with
solvents and of course the main solvent
list categories that we're going to
spend most of our time talking about
today so
one thing that you'll notice here is
that on the bottom of this fairly busy
slide is that there's a lot of textures
and one of the things that we run into a
lot is that people are saying well can I
can I make sadder with a rosin press and
the answer is that you can most of the
time now with hydro carbon you're
looking at a much bigger array of great
you know various textures that you can
actually access compared to co2 for
example or ethanol or distillate simply
put hydrocarbon and rosin tend to be the
most versatile in terms of the textures
that you can actually create with those
systems so you know blog Reza and
terpene separation diamonds shatter wax
butter I mean there's a lot of ways to
skin a cat with how many different forms
and textures there are a lot of it comes
down to personal preference
you know if you could go back in time 3
4 years and start talking to people
about diamonds and sauce they would have
no idea what your apple sauce like what
are you even talking about they don't
know shatter was of course this huge
revolution people were taking dabs and
it was pretty much all made with butene
sometimes at home sometimes in a very
sketchy on fire now not a very friendly
environment to be doing that kind of but
now people are figuring out all kinds of
very very interesting ways to make
kaleidoscope of textures with different
terpene concentrations all kinds of
different flavors it's really becoming
such a boutique industry across the
board that now as well as in the solvent
list category where before we were
really just looking at Keith's bubble
hash older forms of hashish you know if
anyone's familiar with Frenchy canola or
someone you know the big name older hash
makers you know there's all these
different ways to make solvent list but
now rosin has really come on to the
scene as a popular concentrate that's
growing very quickly in the past couple
years one other thing I'd like to point
out
- is that well co2 ethanol and
distillate I just have them listed as
oils a lot of these products are being
used and substrates for adults so
depending on what you're trying to do
virtually any of these products can go
into edibles which then of course your
complexity of the products that you can
offer is times a million because how
many things can we eat there are better
and less better ways to make edibles
depending on what you're shooting for
but one of the things that we run into
again a lot is that you know what what
can Roz and really do what can you
actually turn rosin into and the answer
is that almost everything that you can
with hydrocarbon which we've actually
been surprised by some of our clients
who have been actually taking us to
school on what they can do with some of
our equipment people are doing full-on
terpene separations live rosin with
fresh frozen bubble hash that they're
washing people are making solvent list
diamonds you can make shatter with
certain strains depending on the terpene
concentrations
I mean wax all the other textures are
all being made by certain companies on
rosin presses as well so it's pretty
cool to see that you can spend a lot
less on equipment and potentially make
some of these textures I'm not going to
spend time talking about the hydrocarbon
and the other systems in this
presentation but I just kind of wanted
to show everyone where the textures
break down because there's a lot of
variation here and it's something you
hear about a lot so I wanted to cover
some myths that again these are all
based on questions that we get in our
inbox and get a call all day every day
is that solvent list is less potent
that's the first one people have found a
way to isolate THC a with a rosin press
where you're getting 99% potency with it
or it's white crystals that are coming
out and they're nucleating those
crystals into the large diamonds and
then
sometimes they're putting them into
other products but the fact that matter
is is that with a solvent was set up you
can actually make extremely potent
concentrated products at chalice of last
year the highest rosin test result of
just a dabble oil product was in the low
90% range so extremely potent and
generally speaking in this some we're
going to talk about a lot is it really
boils down to quality and what's in
there in the first place so if you're
running very high quality material the
potency of your solvent Wisconsin traits
can be extremely high
60% tends to be what we've seen test
result wise to kind of be the bottom
threshold and that's not necessarily a
bad thing not everyone wants to take a
dab of THC isolate I mean I know I don't
it's too it's not really what I want
some people are looking for a little bit
more of a mellow experience and they can
have that with a solvent list product
the second one shattered does not equal
VH oh you know one of the biggest
misconceptions that we hear is can what
what is shattering you know what is this
even and shatter is simply a texture of
cannabis concentrates that behaves like
a thin glass you can break it with your
hands it flakes there's a couple
companies out there that have really
perfected the process of making rosin
shatter and it's one of the more popular
products that a lot of companies
especially a couple of years ago you
know it is popular it was popular it
depends on what state you're in but
sometimes shatter is the buzzword
shatter equals concentrates people
almost don't even think about the other
textures it's just Cham Cham Cham people
are making shattered with solvent less
concentrated setups the third big one
here is that solvent list has less
terpenes you know terpene content we've
seen tested as high as 16 percent or
more just slightly over with salt on the
sauce that's a company called a vlog if
you're in Denver that we work with it's
pretty incredible some of the test
results that people are getting with
their material they're able to get I
mean even some of the lower range bubble
hash frozen's are getting 5 to 10
terpene content so when you open that
jar it you know it's hitting you you're
smelling it it's extremely potent and
what you're really finding is that
you're getting a full spectrum extract
with most rosin you're finding that as
well as with bubble hash and just as an
aside even though it's not about beer
just for everyone's information full
spectrum basically means that you have a
range of cannabinoids and terpenoids
concentrates are going to offer a full
spectrum package meaning you haven't
distilled it down to simply just THC a
even though just like we talked about
that can basically be done here but
you're offering the full range of
terpenes and cannabinoids depending on
what the plan is giving you which can
lead to the entourage effect more
palliative effects for certain people
it's basically going to be the most
genuine representation of whatever plant
that was grown when it's being processed
into solvent that tends to be the most
genuine and authentic way of making a
concentrate the last one can't be used
hemp is being processed into CBD hash
and people are selling that even on the
Internet I mean in Canada it's the Wild
West right now it's absolutely bonkers
up there you can buy CBD hash rosin on
the internet today and have it mailed to
your door I wouldn't recommend it you do
not want you know people don't want the
FBI know that you're buying that from
Canada
one thing that we've heard a lot too is
people haven't had great experiences
with rosin you know for all the people
that have had burnt popcorn flour rosin
I'm sorry you know the industry is still
learning but now out there you will find
products if you look for them that are
the highest end that you can pretty much
imagine and we're really excited to see
where can be used with rosin it's a
process that doesn't play as nice with
solvent less extraction for reasons I'll
get into but it's pretty exciting what
people are doing across the board here
with extremely potent concentrates the
textures that we're talking about the
terpene content and being able to use
hemp in it as well
so to kind of get to the beef here we've
got our three primary categories of
solvents concentrates ice water hash
this is one probably most people are
familiar with at least at some level and
that's where you're using cold off cold
water and ice they're breaking and
making the trichome heads and stocks
brittle and they're breaking it off of
the canvas material itself into a slurry
of water which is then filtered through
different micron screens and then it's
dried so that that's the basic process
of making bubble hash it's made by hand
and drums it is made in portable washing
machines that people would buy for using
out in the backcountry people make
bubble hash in all kinds of different
ways and probably something that will
continue to be improved upon we feel
that that is actually one of the
categories that is expecting to see the
greatest evolution here in the next
couple of years because many of the
professional bubble hash washers out
there either washing by hand
or again using one of these you know two
or three hundred dollar you know
portable plastic washing machines making
grams of bubble hash full melt that
sells for $100 a gram California you
know there's something there's something
not right there but if that's what it
takes to make that product then people
are doing a very good job of it the
drying process is something that has
been extremely tricky and has been the
realm of virtually experts only until
just recently
drying bubble hash you have this wet
sopping mass of trichome heads and
stalks if you're doing it right and then
actually dry that down so you're not
getting mold microbial issues it's a
very tricky process doing with air
drying but now people have found out
that with the life--all ization process
using freeze dryers you can pretty much
take all the headache out of making
bubble hash by popping it in a freeze
dryer and 24 hours later it comes out
perfectly dried it's a little more
complicated than that but a point being
it's a lot easier to
than air-drying and you don't have to be
an absolutely tried true 10-year veteran
of drying it dry sister Keith again this
is probably going to be the most
familiar category my picture is pretty
blown out there so you can't see it just
pretend that there's Keith in that
little box what we've got here is
instead of taking your cannabis material
and putting it through water to break
off those trichome heads with cold
temperatures you're just sharing it so
the best Keef is usually made very
gently we find that a lot of the bubble
hash when people come to or excuse me a
lot of the dry sip that people come to
have us press for demonstrations is
sometimes less than 50 percent trichomes
and the rest plant material that reduce
all kinds of stuff and that just doesn't
do very well so when you're making dry
Ceptor Keith you know you definitely
want to be gentle on it less is more
sure everyone has smoked Keith and joy
Keith seen it and smelled it
Keith can be a little tricky though
because people want to beat it up a
little bit too much but the goal with
both of these products is to keep the
trichome heads as intact and unbroken as
possible when you start feeding up Keith
you're gonna find that those trichome
heads are splitting open you're getting
your oil and all these other things in
your mixture which is not going to be
conducive to rosin which is where pretty
much all this is heading and polo hash
and sift are now mainly being used as
precursors that are being pressed into
rosin because consumer preferences for
Keith have come way down people simply
aren't buying very much of it a lot of
the dry sift on the shelf isn't very
good in some places so a lot of places
are taking that Keith and processing it
into rosin and same goes with ice water
hash you know what could have passed is
high-quality bubble hash a couple of
years ago is now something that might
not ever move on a dispensary shelf
because of people's preferences and how
they've learned to you know love other
dabs basically a lot of places that are
doing all of these are still making full
melt bubble hash which is something that
is fairly difficult to create but what
that essentially means is that is the
highest quality level of your trichomes
that you are receiving through your
bubble hatch washing process sometimes
when you're watching hatch none of your
trichomes are full mountain and full
metal basically meaning that if you put
it on a nail you melt it you're trying
to dab it there's zero residue left
behind so what many solvent lists
extraction Labs are doing that are
focused on this are they will take their
full melt bubble mash if they're able to
produce it they will sell that in grams
or half grams for high prices and then
the rest of their grades that wouldn't
pass as full melt is what they're going
to go ahead and do is mix those all up
together and then press it into rosin so
with rosin you're using heat and
pressure to break open the trichome
heads and stocks which is releasing the
oil and then it's being filtered through
a fine mesh bag so that leaves a lot of
the plant material and the other stuff
you don't want behind it has the oil
coming out it doesn't need to be purged
it's ready to consume pretty much
immediately and this picture here again
the fidelity isn't there but that is
actually an example of rosin chatter
that's classed over that somebody
pressed out so I just want to talk a
little bit about the physics of rosin
and how rosin is being made because
people are gonna find that rosin is
extremely disruptive to the concentrate
industry in general rosin is something
that people can safely make at home
rosin is something that any amateur
grower can purchase a rosin press and
make dabs at home with their own
material knowing that they grew it it
doesn't have pesticides in it they're
comfortable with the quality that
they're growing hopefully and that they
can process it themselves so what we've
got here is a little bit of diagram that
one of my co-workers put together for us
which is either using compressed air or
a hydraulic cylinder you're pressing a
bag that is full of Kieff bubble hash or
flour one of your substrate materials
the pressure is being applied and then
in between heat and then you have your
oil coming out and depending on the
distance between the center of the bag
and the edges of the plates that's
really going to dictate sometimes how
high-quality your oil is sometimes
people will press rosin on a giant
t-shirt press the evolution of rosin
presses has come a long way from hair
straighteners to t-shirt presses to
commercial rosin presses too now you
know we're on the verge of releasing a
pretty much fully automated version of
our press that press buttons it presses
it goes so in three or four short years
you've gone from you know guys Shanghai
and their girlfriends and wives hair
straighteners to squeeze the juice out
of a nut to you know a fully automated
system so it's pretty incredible to see
how fast things are changing here now
this is one of the really big categories
that we get a lot of questions about
which is you know what are some of the
advantages of solving lists and then
where does solvent lists tend to
struggle and I wanted to present you
know very honestly and openly where
solvent list has challenges is where as
some of its advantages come in so I'll
start with the good which is that it's
vastly cheaper to get a solvent less
extraction system going I mean if you're
trying to do bubble hash and rosin and
you need sinks you need you literally
have an empty room and you were gonna
start making solvent less processing you
give that going anywhere from twenty to
forty thousand dollars you can get
started much much cheaper more easily
it's very simple and you sit and you
don't need that much to get going it's
much cheaper the yields are comparable
to hydrocarbon and other extraction
methods popular contrary to popular
belief this all really boils down to
quality which is something I'll get
the challenges section but that you can
get solid yields with solvent lists if
you know your grower and your genetics
or high quality that's really where
you're going to be the most successful
one of the biggest advantages is that it
doesn't require into safety
considerations you know see what do you
want rooms people that are familiar with
extraction rooms and build-outs
it could be extremely expensive some
people can spend as much as a hundred or
two hundred thousand dollars just
getting a C one D one room architected
and put in place not even including the
equipment that they're putting in there
so when you're pressing rosin we were
making bubble hash there's no solvents
there's nothing flammable it's pretty
straightforward the safety protocols or
much more simple fire departments are
very friendly we work with the Denver
Fire Department and I actually gave a
talk in LA earlier this year to fire
departments and they they almost laughed
me out of the room because of what I was
talking about like I'll solve unless
like why are you even here we know
that's fine so the last thing we've got
under the advantages is it retails for a
really high price per gram so again
every market in every area is gonna bear
different prices depending on different
consumer preferences but like I was
saying you know in California in
Colorado you're seeing premium grams of
these products retail from anywhere from
sixty to a hundred dollars sometimes
more on the recreational side of things
think craft brewing that's kind of the
best analogy that we have is you know
it's easier to get started with it it's
cheaper most the time that people are
really involved in this they have you
know boutique genetics that they're
really emphasizing and trying to put out
there some of the big challenges with
rasen scalability especially compared to
co2 or ethanol I mean if you're running
co2 machine you can put tons through
those with our equipment which has some
of the highest throughput on the market
you're looking at 10 to 15 pounds of dry
sift or hash in a day which is a lot for
a rosin press but compared to a ethanol
or a co2 machine you know that's that's
a drop in the bucket for
massive massive processing so again
smaller production if you're if you've
got a bunch of low-grade trim or middle
stuff that you're trying to run you know
rosin pressing might not be the right
method for you because you have so much
you have to go through the quality might
not be there it's probably not going to
deliver the results that you're looking
for the real real big thing here is that
it demands high quality material and
certain genetics to be successful so if
your material is very high quality you
can be successful if your material is
not your yields will suffer you are not
going to be making good bubble hash you
are not going to be making great Keef
and you are not going to be pressing
good rosin frankly so you know people
sometimes they'll come do demos with us
and they bring their all this swaggiest
material they can find and they think
you know I saw this all this gold
pouring out on your YouTube channel can
you do that and you know we're not
alchemists you know rosin and solvent
list is not alchemy you cannot turn lead
into gold and when it comes to solving
lists it's really an arms race to who
can be the best grower to make the best
nugs the top-shelf crystal mugs to put
into their solving the system
so Dad logic for example one of the
companies in Colorado we work with they
probably made more rosin than anyone in
Colorado they work with a company called
Verde natural which is their grow arm in
the business there are two companies and
what they do is with Burt a natural
every time they pull a harvest down dab
logic comes in and they take all the
buds they want they get first pick they
come in they pick out all the best stuff
and then they sell everything else on
the shelf daba logic washes it now to
some people that is a horror story
because they're selling a flower they
want to sell their best notes but again
as these markets evolved resin farming
is going to be more and more of a thing
where people are actually growing
specifically for the purpose simply of
extracting Green Dot labs and Boulder is
a great example there are innumerable
examples in California and of course in
the northwest as well there's last but
it's a growing
practice where people are simply growing
just to extract they are not even
selling their buds they are watching it
they're blasting in everything and then
again it works best with premium flower
whole plant fresh frozen or high-quality
Siddiqui
you cannot just run trim through a rasa
press it is not going to be successful
there's too much plant material in the
bag itself your yields will really
suffer so there's always a little bit of
post-processing going on to make some of
those premium products whether you're
washing your stuff and hash whether
you're sifting it there's a little bit
more work on the front end a little bit
less work on the back end because you
don't have to purge it whole plant fresh
frozen is really the way that a lot of
the elite labs are washing bubble hash
to make the best quality products and
then one of the real big ones is it
doesn't reduce or remove contamination
so if you've got PM in your product and
you're trying to press it into rosin
well you got PM in your rosin and that
is bad nobody wants to smoke that so
please don't do that it's my humble
request to all of you whatever problems
are having in your grow it's gonna come
through the bag there's just no way to
get around it you would need a micron
screen of a coffee filter three four or
five microns to be able to filter that
out and maybe not even there so you know
it has to be clean and if you've got a
big crop of stuff that's contaminated
rosin and solvent list will simply not
work unless you're trying to poison
people so you know a lot of people
they'll take that material and they'll
blasted co2 there are better efficient
ways to process material that's been
compromised solvent lists just simply is
not one of those ways so just some
market information just kind of go over
what we got here
premium full melt bubble hash and live
rosin to retail for sixty five hundred
dollars a gram in 2017 rosin was the
fastest-growing subcategory in Colorado
in Washington the growth is really
happening there and then overall
concentrate consumption growth has grown
by 11 percent Oregon last year
MJ Piz I'd highly recommend anyone who
does
purchase or check out their Factbook
they come out with one every year them
and had said they it's worth the money
if you want to learn the data this is
where this is pretty much all coming
from and then 13% of the processors pull
reported using solvent list as their
primary extraction method so to us we
were surprised to see that we thought it
would be less than that but there's
actually a lot of companies out there
really pushing solvent lists and that
number is absolutely growing so getting
towards the end here premium fresh
frozen bubble hash can be turned into
some really really cool products that
people would expect on the bottom left
here you have a hundred percent solvent
less cartridges that are being sold by
dad logic no PG no VG no holes of fires
is coming off the press exactly as it
goes into the cartridge that is
absolutely possible can't tell you guys
how it kill me but it is happening
solved it with sauce that retails for so
much it's crazy and then you've also got
THC isolate these are things we talked
about as well as food grade oil from
leftovers so whatever isn't your primo
stuff can also be made into high-end
edibles so pretty much you can use all
parts of the buffalo with solvent less
no matter what you're doing there's a
place for it and again the premium fresh
frozen derived bubble hash is really the
building block for a lot of these exotic
concentrates textures and things that
are being made with prosit
so in some solvents concentrates are
really quickly becoming a huge part of
the market here especially the high-end
market because of versatility someone
can go buy arroz impress make all these
different textures at home and you could
be a one-man band and and make some of
these products you don't have to invest
a million dollars and getting your
extraction lab started most of our
customers are actually existing
processing labs that might do
hydrocarbon or co2 is their primary
extraction method but they add on
solvent list to create a premium product
so doesn't take up a lot of space it's
easy to get started it's also very
simple to learn so we really see solvent
list as becoming you know one of the
bigger ends of the boutique concentrate
market as things evolved in the United
States and abroad
it's a highly versatile system you can
make all kinds of different products
with it it's not very expensive and it's
very safe and easy to learn so you know
as it becomes more known we're expecting
more and more and more people to really
latch on to this and have you know my
little girl I'm gonna process some of
this and then I'm gonna share it so
these are some of the big companies we
work with Willamette Valley alchemy is
here in Oregon same with Queenie labs
they do really great work and we were
actually at a dispensary yesterday and
we saw some bull valley alchemy hash we
were really excited to see that there
are definitely companies out here making
really good products so I'm pretty much
right there thank you all for coming
love to answer as many in all questions
and whatever questions that we don't get
through in the next couple minutes we're
at booth 406 right in front please come
talk to me and come talk to us we're
here all weekend and love to answer
whatever questions don't get there so
so every question go ahead and raise
your hand we've got about 10-12 minutes
for questions and I'll bring you the mic
the back back in the back so if you have
a pound of really high premium flour and
you take it through a good rosin press
site from your company what kind of
yield in grams of rosin comes down the
bag and a typical situation yeah great
question there's a range of yields we
see anywhere from ten to thirty percent
so with premium high resin strains you
know well grown gorilla glues chem
strains there are certain strains that
really overperform you're gonna see in
the high teens low 20s and that's just
with flour Oz and the highest I've ever
personally witnessed was 31 or 32
percent roughly out in California some
guy that's the material that didn't even
look good and it just important so to
expand on that question just a little
bit too with Keith and sift you're
looking at 30 to 60% for a sift rosin
and then to bubble hash anywhere from 40
to 80% we've seen it go as high as into
the high 80s some people have claimed
low 90s we're not really sure where that
falls but with bubble hash it goes way
up from there raise your hand if you've
got a question they're very good
we I used the freeze dryer and now you
put like you put like four or five
pounds of web-savvy
you know if you don't wash it with a
freeze dryer and when you bring it out
you get like these you get wafers anyway
like nothing I mean but then the liquid
that comes out of the freeze dryer
smells so good you slap your own mother
for what's in there let me just have
this cloudy foggy material with this
light oil that like builds up on the top
of it why is all my wonderful yummy
smells leaving my bubble hash and a
freeze dryer man yeah so what happened
how in God's name yeah so when you're
freeze drying bubble hash is what's
happening is you are warming up and
freezing it's the sublimation process of
your trichome head so when they're in
the freeze dryer they're gonna be warmed
up slightly it's all happening under a
vacuum so that water that's coming out
that's draining out can have a lot of
terpenes in it you know it's coming out
of the drain
wow this this smells so good yeah yep so
the short answer is that it kind of
comes down to process you know we we
come come by the booth and let's talk
about that because temperatures dry
times how long are drying it there's
ways to try and minimize terpene passive
turkey loss through your you know the
water that's actually being extracted
there are definitely methods and things
that we can you know hopefully point you
in the right direction on that you know
good bubble hash when it's being
freeze-dried right in the terpene
content you know hopefully your hash on
the other end is still smelling is still
smelling really good but there's
definitely some ways and things that you
can even do with that water potentially
so
[Laughter]
I'm gonna have the same thing yeah so so
some of my clients are running into
processing rosin that's really Turkey
okay and it has a hard time staying
shelf stable because the tur player
tends to separate do you find that that
is more process-oriented or more
cultivar or strain oriented good
question so what we find a lot is very
high terpene content rosin tends to be
less viscous so it's very oily it can be
hard to work with a lot of it comes down
to a storage properly so making sure
it's in an airtight container as best
you possibly can making sure it's in a
refrigerator or a freezer you know
slowing that process down because with a
lot of rosin if you leave it out it will
naturally tend to auto butter you're
gonna get that separation it kind of
sweats so it depends on the strain it
depends on the material all kind of the
the the short answer is storage can
probably have a huge effect on how well
the separation slows way down we tend to
have customers telling us that when
they're doing it right that their shell
stability is somewhere in the realm of
two to three months if they're using
those techniques if you leave it out at
room temperature if you're leaving it in
a non airtight container it could I mean
24 hours big-big can auto butter
sometimes so and then the strain itself
again I think that oils more down to the
terpene content within it and what kind
of textures you can have available to
you other questions
what would you say in general are the
best strains to put through one of your
pieces of equipment yep so the component
at the baseline more resin higher
potencies gonna there's more to work
with there when you're making rosin so
again grill glue almost a little played
out at this point people still love it
huge producer a lot of the chem strains
really really do well chem dogs there's
there's a million back crosses in the
chem strain one of the one of the
companies that we work with a lot Oney C
code Tropicana cookies there's some
fruity strains that work really really
well Crockett's farm some people might
be familiar with them strong Nana
there's some fruity strains I wish I had
a more specific answer about the exact
terpene profile that some companies have
latched on to that they know overperform
I was given the explanation once but it
kind of fell right through my head
because it was super high level but
basically you're very resinous high
yielding high potency plants are always
going to be typically over performers
when it comes to making solvent listen
right now we got time for one more
covered everything well if you're Eric
thank you very much
[Applause]