all right this should be fun so welcome
to the 2:30 presentation on
autoflowering cannabis please silence
your cellphone's we even have a lot of
runs with that today I am Shane golos
host of the shaping fire podcast if you
like listening to smart interviews with
the top minds in cannabis I invite you
to check out the show at shaping fire
calm we also have an extraordinary
YouTube channel with over a hundred and
fifty speaker videos I've recorded at
events just like this one
this could presentation will be posted
there next week there are post cards in
the back near the door to help you
remember the names shaping fire the
upcoming presentation is titled success
with modern autoflowering cannabis from
Shango lows oh that's me so it looks
like since I'm moderating the room today
I'm also introducing myself so here we
go a summary of the points that were to
be talking about today is number one
we're gonna talk about who is likely to
benefit most from autoflowering cannabis
we're going to talk about where autos
come from we're going to talk about the
most common objections to Auto flowers
and we will point you in the direction
of some quality breeders and where to
find more information so the important
thing to start out at the beginning is
to realize that even though Auto flowers
have become awesome there's still a lot
of variability and so a lot of things
I'm going to say float somewhere between
best-case scenario and the better seeds
that are on the market a lot of people
righteously hate Auto flowers and and
those folks generally come into three
categories either they were growing
autos back in the day of the lowrider
days when it was a cool idea but the
yields and the terpene profiles were
atrocious and it just it wasn't very
rewarding and so they got a bad
reputation as we all know reputations
are hard to change the second challenge
can also be that
people just like to grow fricken trees
and Otto flowers have not really hit
that that point yet and then third some
people are just using seeds that are not
as well developed as other seeds so the
vast majority of what I'm going to tell
you today is kind of based on the
cutting edge of where Otto flower seeds
are but does not is not representative
of every seed in the market so it's
really important to do your own research
this is not one of those situations
where you're all gonna be like this pack
of seeds says Otto flowers and I want an
auto flower and so I'm gonna buy a whole
bunch of this one seed and and and
devote my entire crop to it I don't
recommend that I recommend you getting a
lot of variety of seeds from different
folks and do a trial and then decide
okay these are clearly the ones that
meet the needs that I'm looking for
myself ruderalis crosses are not
something that's new they've been around
for a while what's new and why everybody
is talking about it today is because the
latest seeds that come out by some of
the top companies are just smoking and
if you are part of a very particular
audience they could be well very
literally life-saving if you're a
patient so we're going to first start
with by talking about cultivators who
are most likely to benefit from the
autumn flowers first and foremost my
heart is always with home growers right
I do business consulting and I help
commercial folks as well but I really
have my heart I am patient in home
grower centric so we're going to start
there but the number one reason why home
growers adore auto Flowers is because
their speed from germination to to
harvest there are a handful of different
lengths of time depending on that chemo
bar at this point but generally they
followed us sixteen ninety or
hundred and twenty days and for those of
you who are here for Jess presentation
earlier
you've got to see his pictures of you
know how fast a 60-day plan goes from
termination to being prepared to harvest
and it is really astonishing and it's
it's crazy to when people talk about a
60 date or 60 day auto flower you know
since we're used to regs flowering for
eight weeks you're like oh yeah well
that's just like a writer claims like no
I don't mean 60 days for the entire plan
to took it to flower I'm talking about
60 days from germination to harvest and
then that's run on that point is where
people start you kind of start to see
the mind get blown a little bit they're
like wow how many how many rounds can I
do in my tent how many rounds could I do
outside this summer for example I did
two rounds I did one round that I popped
in April and harvested the end of June
and then I put some more in the middle
of June and they're gonna be hardest at
the end of September so getting two
cycles in one summer with no
pain-in-the-ass light down the second
thing is that of course where the
flowers get their name they get their
name from because they do not flower
based on photo sensitivity right most
cannabis plants they will start to
flower sometime mid-august when the
light cycle gets down towards you know
nearish 12 12 where we live in the
Pacific Northwest it never gets to 12 12
right so so most of our plants kind of
like get crawl into flowering and about
you know 13 and a half hours or so which
is one of the challenges of growing in
the Northwest and another reason why
these Auto flowers are great what
triggers Auto flowers to a tube flower
is is more maturity right you know in
the early days people were telling me
how you know it's when then it's when
the roots hit the bottom of the pot and
it causes them stress and I even
repeated that a few times and then I'm
toward a worried in CBD seeds farm in
Albany OR in and they've been you know
all these fields full of beautiful
Otto flowers that I'm label how are
their deep roots need to go down in
order to hit the bottom of the pie and
this so this can't be right information
so I stopped saying that and got further
educated and found out that actually no
it's it's when the plants hit their
maturity level they just automatically
go into bloom and that makes a lot more
sense both scientifically and
observational II another reason why home
growers really like Otto flowers is that
you know home growers have got a lot of
unexpected things in short opportunities
for example let's say that you're moving
and and you know I hate it when you know
I want to move up when I have my grow
but we're gonna create a plan on moving
September 1 right so we'll get all my
veg in but before the plant even
finishes flower somehow I've got to go
so that means that you're gonna you know
rent a u-haul and move all your plans
and hopefully you don't break off all
the branches and go through all that
malarkey or you just don't grow at all
so for people who are home growers the
idea that you can say okay I'm gonna
move September 1 so I'm just going to
make sure that I plant June 1 or May
mid-may and be like hey now we harvest
it and move into my new place instead of
my new 10 and start there also there's
other opportunities like let's say that
your roommate doesn't like you know
cannabis around maybe they're concerned
about it and you know you rightly want
to respect their interests at the house
too well fine
they're gonna take off on vacation for
two months with their family and
something you're like buying here going
I'm gonna grow a sixty-day and you're
getting like totally wheat up while
they're gone these are the kinds of
things that you know you have to be
aware of when you're a home grower also
another thing is that the plants are
very naturally resistant to pests and
deficiencies due to their short cycle
and I've experienced this last year last
summer and was the first year that I
really lagged into Otto flowers and I
realized that the cycle was so short it
didn't give me a lot of time to eff it
up and you know it's you know I'm a
novice grower nope no question about it
I am NOT a pro grower and I'm not a
breeder but what I am is a student and I
care about it and so I do my research
and so what I realized after I grew it
is like wow about the time that it's
it's flowering it's done and so you know
we all know that when you're using rags
one of the things all right you don't
want to spray during your flower right
so that means that you have to be very
proactive for pests and botrytis and
p.m. during your veg so that you can
kind of hopefully coast and maybe even
upgrade to beneficial insects during the
flower to get to the end
well if that's going to be eight to ten
weeks that's a long time hoping to keep
you know the plant in good shape whereas
if the entire life cycle of the plant is
going to be 60 or 90 days you have a
much smaller window that you have to not
screw up and for home growers you know
that that's that's a real benefit we've
got lots of home growers that they're
new to growing its new in their states
new to them they're just learning about
cannabis medicine you know for whatever
the reason is just because you want to
grow does not mean that you need to have
you know that you've given yourself an
epic amount of education on it auto
haulers are just that easy
also you know because they're the plants
are crossed with the ruderalis plant
which we'll talk of in detail well in
more detail about where it came from
it's a hardy plant right so it's it's
from the nether regions of Russia it's
got small stomata on the bottom of the
leaf that makes it less less likely to
get molds and and pests which is just
helpful to any home grower especially a
new grower any any extra you know points
to your advantage you're going to take
because sometimes the plants just feel
like they take forever and you've got so
much invested in it as a home grower I
mean so I'm sure you've got you know the
things that you purchased and you're
using the room in your house or in your
yard but also home growers are very
emotionally involved with the plants and
I know it myself firsthand and they're
like adding extra kids into your house
we're like your you know the unzipped
attending
morning everybody no this is not a
comment and you groan at home you know
you've done this and so when we have
that kind of an emotional connection
with the plan because we're only growing
four or eight plants using Auto flowers
are helpful because it makes the entire
process more manageable and lastly
they're easier to fit in a tent so you
know growing in tents are fine and you
know we can top our plants to keep them
short but there is something really nice
about being able to choose you know
between two and four Auto flowers and a
four by four ten can grow those all at
the same time instead of committing to
one or maybe a second plant that are
going to become monsters in a four by
four tent because you've got less
Shimabara choice it's got less strain
choice when when the stuff comes out of
the jars you won't have as much variety
to smoke so for me I find that I'm
really enjoying growing for autos in
soil in a 4x4 tent instead of one plant
that's going to be really large also
they're easier to hide in your yard and
that's important right because look for
those of us who live in neighborhoods we
want to be respectful for our neighbors
and more importantly if we are growing
in a state where cannabis is not allowed
or if you know we've got picky neighbors
or we've got neighbors who will want to
smoke all of our weed we just don't want
them to know right and so one of the
beauties is these plants are you know
generally shorter there is a lot of
variety as I said at the beginning about
you know between the seeds so I have
seen plans that top out at two feet
consistently but I've also got other
plants that top out at four four and a
half feet consistently and the crazy
thing is is I've used some folk seeds
and and within the same pack some will
top out at two feet and some will top
out at 4 feet so that's some of the
variability that you've got to look for
when you're buying seeds and and before
you commit to a lot of any particular
seed make sure you do are you know
ten or whatever - before you go ahead
and do a whole field of it
they're also smaller size meaning that
they're going to produce less smell for
your neighbors if that's a concern for
you especially if you're an apartment
building or you're living in these like
you know tall thin townhouses where
everybody is in really odiferous ly
close let's say and so you know it's a
smaller plant but because it grows so
swiftly you can do two rounds of small
plants to replace what you may have done
before trying to do one large plant
during during the season but the great
thing is is that even though they are
smaller plans and you're going to get
less overall turf stupid the neighbors
the terms on the plants can be very
excellent and again this is a variable
thing that not all breeders are at the
same place with the lines that they are
working they're certainly standout
breeders in the scene right now and so
it's important to know though that even
though I'm saying you're your neighbors
won't complain as much about their
terpenes it doesn't mean that the
turbines are poor it just means if a
plant is smaller next they're easier to
hang to dry now you know some people
like to take their their large monster
trees maybe cut them in half and just
you know hang them in long rows but most
home growers don't have that kind of
space and certainly you can take a tree
and hack it down to individual branches
and hang all of those but when push
comes to shove a home growers are almost
always short on space the picture that
you see here is actually my own bedroom
last summer and and so I pull my my my
stock and hung them above my bedroom
because I live in a one-bedroom house
right and that's that's what I had and
and the only space of my house that was
not being used actively was the airspace
above my bed and so that's what you get
note to self I'm not doing that this
year
because I realized that this is totally
a JV error but I realized that when you
cut plans and you hang them during the
first week all of the inhabitants come
down so I was getting crab spiders and
other spiders and who knows what and
they were all repelling down into my bed
has a plant was dying as it was supposed
to and that's so sketch and and if you
wanna you don't want it like really
repress or significant other you know
explain to them that there's gonna be
repelling spiders coming down into the
bed it's just 10 days baby so gonna be
okay
so it's also great because you know a
lot of us who are home growing you know
we're working a lot of hours and there's
just no question that the otter
flowering plants take less work that the
cycle is shorter they're not as big I
mean they're you can you can easily call
them cute right and because of that they
really just take a lot less maintenance
and you know growing regs you know I
have been in the situation where I'm
working my day job and then maybe I meet
a friend after work for a moment and
then I go home and the rest of my
evening could be in the garden just
making sure that this this reg plan of
mine that which is which I'm all in on
right so I'm only going to get one round
you know it's going to be in good shape
but with the auto flowers I find that
I'm spending a lot more time just
sitting around with them looking at them
enjoying being a cultivator and being
able to interact with for me as my
medicine and a brain injury in 2011 and
so I think that there is something very
heartfelt about growing your own plants
and and Auto flowers give you more of
the enjoyment and less of a hassle so um
let's see here
alright so that is it for home growers
let's move on to a subset of home
growers which is going to be patients
and this is actually where I spend most
of my time working with patients on
Ashland Island where I live and
traveling the country to talk to doctors
and naturopaths about how to use can
have an empathic medicine so so patients
of course really enjoy all of the stuff
that we've already mentioned about home
growers all that stuff easily cross
applies to patients who are growing at
home but the reason why I was originally
attracted to Auto Flowers is because the
compactness and the lack of deficiency
just makes their less work for a patient
to do which is important because a
patient is mostly trying to cultivate
themselves right they are spending their
time going to the doctor or making sure
they're taking their meds or sleeping a
lot or whatever they have to do for
whatever they need relief from which
leaves them less time for the plants and
the fact that they are so easy to take
care of is is a wonderful thing also a
lot of patients that I work with have
got decreased mobility right so how is
the patient gonna like harvest an 8 9 10
foot plan it's very difficult to do and
it creates a challenge that just doesn't
need to be overcome
same with trying to hang these types of
plants the compactness of an auto flower
plant really makes it just perfect for
for a patient grower so we will just hit
on that and move on so let's talk about
commercial scale growers so the first
time I saw a commercial scale grow was
last summer when I visited I actually
had been two years ago now when I
visited of Oregon's CBD seeds in Albany
and you know I've seen pictures of
fields of cannabis from you know you
know Pakistan or Afghanistan and you
look at and you know as a enthusiastic
STONER I'm all like I would love to
smell that field right you know you know
they say that in the old days in India
they would they would get naked and run
through the plants and collect the
Shara's on their nude skin and
love it off their skin and then and then
start that with the hash and I'm all
signed me up you know and so it's not an
opportunity that we've had but when I
went to visit the Crawford brothers down
at their farm I was all like you know I
really the fields right there nobody's
out here we've got seven acres I could
probably get covered with something or
other you know and so I'm but but you
know joking aside it was it was powerful
emotionally I was there two weeks before
harvest and the entire aroma of their
their RNA the really nice Otto strain
that they do that's high in CBD it was
powerful right we all know that the Terp
profiles of cannabis are there to put us
in a good mood to stimulate us to to
soothe our endocannabinoid system and
when you're when you're standing in
fields of it and having that experience
it's it's pretty fantastic so there are
definitely advantages for commercial
growers so number one is their compact
size now there is no question that there
are certain commercial growers who are
going for monster plants and honestly
that we're getting to be the time where
that's going to be more about prestige
and marketing and Instagram photos than
it is more about getting the most out of
your acreage because if you can do two
rounds in the same location and have the
plants be compact and easier to work
with it just increases your efficiency
and I'm one of the first people to go
that efficiency because I'm all about
artists and growers right but I also
know it's unrealistic to think that that
the the industry is going to be only be
artists and growers especially with the
like wicked fast onset of hemp grown
right and so if people are going to be
doing acres and acres and acres of him
if you were to try to do that with all
10-foot plants it would be a real pain
in the ass at the end of the season but
if you are instead harvesting a whole
bunch of three footers suddenly if
you've left enough room between the rows
you can just pull down
sled and chop and drop the chop and drop
and it makes it very efficient and you
have repeatable results now there's
certainly smaller and larger Kingdom
ours right if you like the idea of the
uniformity of the uniformity of the
plant but you really feel kind of
disgusted philosophically by three-foot
plants so go find yourself a bunch of
seeds that will grown between four and
five so that you feel like they look
more like the plants that you're used to
and you'll be getting more yield off
those plants generally speaking anyways
just because they're larger size one big
advantage to using autos for for
commercial is that there is almost never
a need to cage or steak for two reasons
number one they don't get as monstrous
as some of the trees do from regular
plants but also because they're crossed
with ruderalis and genetics these are
like strong like balloonist Siberian
Russian genetics and and all the autumn
flowers that I've had even the ones that
were kind of crappy you know from from
from folks they all had uniformly thick
stalks and and so with the thick stalk
and they're a bit shorter and just
because they lit they think they exist
in the world a shorter period of time
you're not going to get the same yield
you it's really nice not to have to cage
them and then uncage them as as steps in
your commercial cultivation it's also
nice that that plants treated the same
will likely grow in the same you know
there aren't a lot of red seeds that you
can get that while the genetics
themselves may be stable where whereas
they're gonna smell and look the same
they a lot of them still act differently
when you actually pop the seed and I
know at the beginning I said you know
there's a lot of there can be a lot of
variability within one seed pack that's
why this is still an evolving part of
the industry
I'm not here to tell you that that this
is a complete system and this is down
and you can just walk away from your
regs what I'm saying is is depending on
what your needs are especially if you're
a hemp cultivator you should really
consider Auto flours and get yourself
some trial seeds and start educating
yourself because you know there are very
good you know there's a very good case
to be made that auto flours are the
future of commercial cannabis and the
large monster plants are going to become
things that we grow for
artisanal reasons and just for vanity
because it's still cool to show off
pictures of like a 10-foot plant so it's
also really great if you're going to be
doing something indoors and outdoors so
we all know how fast how fickle the
buying the buyers are right if they
won't it just they'll come to the store
and they'll say I would like you know
this and they get something and they
come back and the bunch under says you
want that again they're like no it was
great give me something else well you
already said you like the first thing
yeah but I'm expanding my palate one of
the great things about Auto flours is
that they cycle so quickly you can be
bringing new flavors onto the market in
half the time and that really means
something especially if you're working
with retailers who want the new new and
if you know we've all run into the
situation where the retailer says listen
you can't keep product on my shelf 365
and because you can't I'm going to give
it to somebody else who can keep product
on my shelf all the time well if that's
the case instead of you're doing one big
run of rags and then your harvest date
just gets older and older and older what
you're doing what you can do instead is
run Auto flowers and the harvesting
these things every 60 or 90 days and
continually be pushing new
new flavors into the market and and
you're more dedicated buyers are gonna
love that because they can stay brand
loyal to you and also they can be
exciting their palate and continuing and
changing ways oh yeah and one other
thing commercial growers you know I know
a lot of the speakers in this room today
have talked a lot of trash about
defoliating you know removing leaves and
and you know there that's I think that's
a worthwhile debate to have but people
are still doing it right and because
auto flowers tend to be a little more
open and give you a little more access
you know not all of them a lot of them
are will still be tight but generally
speaking they're a little more open
there's a lot less need to do foliate
four four get to get air in and to allow
light to get to get to the lowers and
the big thing is is that no doubt one of
the most attractive attributes of Auto
flowers are that most of the big
providers of seeds are also feminizing
them and you know whether or not you
like feminized seeds that can be a whole
secondary debate and also another seed
that is coming back from a from a
difficult reputation but if we're
talking about the people we have so far
home growers patient growers and
commercial scale acreage growers all of
them love feminized seeds the only folks
who would really be pushing against this
our folks who are attracted to the old
ways and the old school and they and
they want these these these taller seeds
or maybe they just love cloning so so
let's talk about where Auto flowers came
from because we're starting to get an
idea that they might be very useful in
some situations so here is a map of
Russia and you can see up towards the
top of Russia there that's the Arctic
Ocean and it's cold there and it gets
they get snow there
and so what we found was that rules was
first identified and described in the
early 1900s and it was found along the
whole river system in Russia and many
say that the it is its own species but
that is also something that's up for
debate it certainly acts a lot different
than cannabis sativa but really the
jury's still out on that
the original plant was it had no little
an insignificant amount of THC it was
there but but he would smoke it and
nothing would happen and the terpene
profile was like kind of a kinder dirt
but what they found was that it was
super Hardy and that there was the
important part they're growing it or it
was growing feral in like really bad
rocky soil and and because of where it's
located of in northern Russia it was it
had adapted to a wicked short potential
growing season because it's winter most
of the time there and also during the
time that the plant would be growing
depending exactly where you are in
Russia you're very likely to have 24
hours of daylight then and so scientists
are saying that you know chances are
that between the short opportunity for
growth during the summer and also the
inclement weather and the the poor soil
quality low nutrients that this kind of
combination pact these auto flower
characteristics into a plant that was
just waiting to become raw material for
for breeders nowadays one of the other
things that I thought was interesting oh
I guess I already gave you the
information the slide will go through a
real quick short summers it was great
for Rome it didn't have THC and life
cycles are 60 90 and 120 but they
actually the reason why I put this slide
in here is for that photo so so that is
a huge feel of cannabis it's not autos
but it's in Pakistan and since we were
talking about Siberia in winter I just
wanted to point out that what
this picture is is the first heavy snow
in Pakistan on this small community and
they let the first snow lay on their
plants to make them cold and then they
will cut them this day and go make a
shop so think about how we all are
making with ice water hash right they're
making snow hash so so anyway it's on
topic but whatever it's cool so let's
talk about objections to Auto flowers I
feel like this is pretty much what I
have done for the last year since I like
came out of the closet as an auto flower
lover because you know everybody has
their thing they hate about Auto powers
and you know a lot of them live it's
pretty legit most of it though is just
precious so let's say numbers number one
it's not a large size this is my friend
Matt storm and emerald feingold organics
and humbled standing next to one of his
typical plants right absolute monster
people love this right I would say
anybody loves this who's into cannabis
but dudes really love this this kind of
like monstrous bowel thing that they
created and then will then get them
stone right a lot of dudes push back
against Auto flowers as being cute
elegant dismissible and and they just
need to kind of get over that if they're
going to interact with Auto flowers you
know do they have to no but it is a
common objection
but it's only me it only matters if you
are really kind of emotionally connected
with growing a monster plant I mean
everybody likes bragging rights right
but for me after after meeting Auto
flowers I realized that I would much
rather be bragging about the killer
terpene profile and then then the size
of the plant especially when you bring
it back to the fact that I work so much
with patients also it limits horizontal
space so you need to go up right let's
say that you have
a canap limitations in whatever state
you're in and so you can only get so
wide well if you can only get so wide
growing double the auto flower plans may
not be a workable business decision for
you
even with two cycles you're gonna have
to work that out for yourself but if you
can go up well then there's gonna be a
really good case for you to stick with
regular seeds that are going to be extra
fall because not only do you get the
with space you get the vertical space as
well you know Auto flowers don't have an
answer to that but I got to tell you the
people that that applies to is very
small and and may not include you also
some people are all like all right oddly
shaped flowers and it's true you know it
really depends on whose seeds that you
buy and there's a lot of people breeding
OTO seeds right now and I've seen a
handful of different types of flowers
you know I would say most of them look
just like you would think a regular
flower look but some of them show more
of the ruderalis in them and a lot of
them will look like kinda like fox
Cailin for those of you who know that is
there's kind of like comb out and he's
kind of like jagged foxtails
and so and people look at that and like
what what plant is this as a matter
going to give a patient on Vashon Island
who won some Auto flower seeds from I
guess I won't say who and and they grew
them this summer and she sent me a
picture and she said is this is this
okay is this smokeable and I said well
how does it smell if she says smells
fantastic I said I think you're in good
shape
you know like dry it and go for it and
and so it was just that that that one
moment of like is this the same cannabis
that I grew up with and so as the seeds
develop a little bit more in their looks
and and you know as these lines get more
stable you know so occasionally you
might run into oddly shaped flowers a
lot of people say I can't breed with
them yeah that's
true right certainly you're gonna run
into more challenges trying to breed
from a feminized Auto flower but I'll
tell you man I am you know when I when
I've had events now people hand me rag
seeds of autos all the time now and if
you've got boys and girls and you're a
willing to up your research game there
is a lot of fun then you can have
greeting Auto flowers and and your you
can even be doing this just as a home
grower you know and so there's there's a
lot of fun to fun to have they're so so
people are saying yeah you can't breed
with them what it means more is that you
just need to up your game on how to
breed it's not it's not quite as simple
as rent
so we've hit on this one server already
but um low-yield is still an issue as
well and again it's really about the
seeds that you choose and so do your
research in advance but you know over
the you know when you when you add
together the the two cycles and that
they're so much more convenient and if
you find the right seeds for you you'll
maybe a non-issue for you but it is
legit that the plants are smaller and on
some of the plants the spacing between
the flowers are a little wider you don't
know your genetics it's not just they
buy and go it's about educating yourself
about your purchase before you move full
forward and then also there's there is
still some variability from seed to seed
that we talked about about and you know
this is this legitimate concern but it's
not like these people are saying you
know Otto flowers suck they've got low
yield
you can't breed with them they're small
and they taste like crap well those
attributes might be true about some
small subset of the seeds in each
category but anything that is got all of
those is not being sold on the market
anymore because that's not what the
market demands there are plenty of
really good readers you know even right
here in Oregon that are selling premium
seeds that will you know cause you to be
overjoyed
whether you are a home grower a patient
or cultivating at mass size so
next steps let's say that you are now
elated by Otto flowers and you want to
know more these are some of the
companies that I have personally ground
their gear and had great success with
Oregon CVD right here in Oregon
Mephisto is is regarded by most to be
you know top tier zero zero seed bank
out of Spain just started shipping into
the United States and they've got US
distributors now a new upstart that is
great Sebring seeds
this guy is a rather radical Pro patient
grower he makes his seeds and he sends
them to patients across the country for
the cost of shipping just badass right
and that's one of the things that I like
about working with Auto flour people the
green rush has not hit the auto flour
scene as much as it hit the rag scene
and there's still a lot of people who
are really doing they're growing from
their front end and growing and trading
from their art not saying that's not
true stolen right I got lots of great
friends who are eggs but but but there's
so many red seats being bought when you
see what it feels like an emerald cup in
the seed tent you can feel that it has
changed a little bit and and that's you
don't really get that from the auto
flower folks as much unless I wasn't
able to get his logo up but you could be
sure that when this video goes on the on
the You Tube channel the logo will be
there
mandalorian genetics you can find him on
Instagram too I called him and I told
him I said dude I got to give you some
kind of award for termination rates he
sent a bunch of seeds for us to spread
around all of the patients on Vashon on
where I live and our termination rates
were a hundred four hundred and nobody
else that sent seeds was a hundred four
hundred and didn't think about it -
these are patients who barely know what
they're doing in many cases and they're
still popping and so we're big fans
of mandalorian so if you want to get
educated I am going to repeat the same
forum that Jeff suggested earlier today
which is Auto flower Network net this is
the home of Auto flowers and it's a
really cute story too because you know
Auto flower people wanted to participate
in the regular cannabis growing forums
and they were ridiculed and made fun of
and like as you can imagine in that kind
of environment and so a few years back
they said alright forget it we're gonna
take you no we're gonna take our Auto
flowers we're gonna go set up our own
sandbox and so they did an auto flower
dotnet was born and that is a great
place to get reviews of seeds and seed
companies learn some tricks that people
have learned about growing Auto flowers
and you know if you really want to get
steeped into it if you are a cannabis
you know enthusiast to the nerd level
this is where you want to go for the for
the premium premium info and finally it
would not be an auto flower presentation
without plugin Jeff's new book that
comes out on October 22nd I am very
grateful to have gotten an advance copy
and read it and it's a it's a good book
one thing to know about this book would
be besides the fact that you should buy
it is that if you're already a
professional grower this this book is
going to be much below your knowledge
set but if you have got family and they
are sick and you've encouraged them to
grow their cannabis so that they can
feel better or if they're just like bad
ass gardeners and they love working
their garden and they'd like to expand
their garden to something new and cool
and easy this book is just really great
it will bring anybody even people who
are resistant to cannabis along from the
very basics of cannabis and why you want
to try Auto flowers and how to actually
do it so it's a great book comes out
October 22nd and if you want an easy
link to the pre-sale on Amazon you can
go to my Instagram
at shaking fire and there's a link to it
if you follow my profile link to it
today
alright so with that I've got four
minutes left and I'll take a couple
questions and since you know I'm
moderating the room and I'm the one who
was running the mic I guess I'm just
gonna have you yellow it out so so yes
sir
Amelie you try that again with different
words the only way to do it is to trial
right there there I would never suggest
that you commit to a big purchase
without running a couple packs you know
yourself and for a lot of people who
Auto followers are going to be
appropriate for they're growing for fun
and for smoke anyway and so for those
people to see some variation in the
plants that might actually be kind of
cool because you're comparing and
contrasting and that's pretty cool but
if you are growing either at the
commercial level either in the license
or the unlicensed market I would not
just jump into these I would say do a
run that's R&amp;D buy a bunch of different
packs and then just run them and then
after that use those data points to
either say this gives me the bud
structure I want so that I've got good
bag appeal and then there's other stuff
it may smell good and smoke good but
maybe that's going to go to my head
stash
to move the other stuff is already gone
into flowering stage so quick sure so
I'm gonna give you a better give you in
the the usual answer and then I'll tell
you that I'm probably wrong so so the
youth the usual answer is that autumn
flowers cannot be cloned because the
stress immediately causes them to flower
in my experience that has happened every
single time because even though I got
the warning on the researcher I'm going
to try it anyway right but when when I
talk to like my heart or greeting
friends right they'll say oh no you can
do that you know and we're trying this
and so I'm thinking that the state of
the art right now is that you may be
able to clone and do some breeding magic
with some of the lines right just
but I'm only really basing that on
second hand information but but you're
right the rule of thumb though is that
auto flowers are I can't be cloned
because that stress causes of the flower
so I might be like on photo period
defense but because I want to try Auto
flowers for sure human Jeff abaut said
you know six nine months this long
period as well as for what for the
period for photo period oh god plans to
finish in giant plants and then also the
the time the light needs to be on I
think Jeff that reference is when I was
20 22 even 24 hours on so if I don't
have planet count I can select the right
photo straight plant coming and so I'm
going to plans eighty five six inch
cubes or
something right right straining being
like sixty days or less
I just want to emphasize like photos
don't have to go or they don't have to
be Giants there is a learning curve
there or like the Dutch table method I
think it's called work you can grow a
whole bunch of photos really squat and
still have some attributes and there's a
learning curve there too but I guess
it's just because we're both preaching
pretty hard on the photos don't have to
be huge outdoors they get huge it's
almost impossible but fully control must
really know what you're doing well you
said a lot of flowers you don't mean you
mean rags yeah yeah so alright so I get
you I get way again what you're saying
and you're right
rags are great too they shouldn't go
away but it also isn't a question and
since I'm making the case for Otto
flowers I'm gonna use the worst case
available wherever the ranks right so so
you know there there are certainly
having hell you mean you could if you
wanted to keep your reg small you can do
what I have to do in my my small or
outdoor hoops was just like top though
several times during the air so that
your flowers don't end up you know
getting wet from condensation so yeah I
mean there's ways that you can manage
your regs so that some of the downsides
that Jeff and I were both talking about
don't happen but but you know in general
this was less a comparison of regs to
auto flower in every situation and more
like frickin try Auto flowers alright so
so I've run out of time and I've got one
more thing to say so so not for
commercial folks in the room but if you
are a patient if you identify as a
patient and you grow for yourself for
your own health stop by and see me
because Mandalorian Sebring seeds and
mountain rock farm from California I'll
give you some packs to give away to
authentic patients so if you've got a
company go buy your seeds but if you're
a patient I've got something to give
away so that's it if you want to show
your friends this you can find it on the
shaping fire youtube channel next week
thank you very much I'm tangled
you