thank you thank you thank
you so this is so for those of you who
have been to vime meetings but not one
on the very first ones this is how we
used to do it in the early days when
when our goal was to help people find um
out whether or not they want wanted to
apply for a license it was simply 15 or
20 of us sitting in this room and me
just kind of teaching the regulations
and then then after the wave of licenses
came out um we still wanted to get
together and so we started bringing in
some of the top speakers in the world uh
to talk about candidates and none of
them are here
tonight um so
so I've tried to do this other years
with different speakers because the goal
was to have have a speaker at the
beginning of the season to to present a
really easy strategy for growing that
anybody could do and the last two years
when we had those speakers they did
great presentations but they very
quickly got above the beginners head
space because they themselves were so
Pro and so this year instead of booking
someone to do the speak to do the
presentation I figured since I keep on
thinking I know how to do it right I
might as well just do it this year and
and present the the super simple
beginner guide to growing so so that's
what's going to happen this year and um
so there are some immediate assumptions
going in so number one we're assing that
you're growing Outdoors um this is all
about uh having some plans in your yard
for the summer growing it under the sun
and and and so we're not going to talk
anything about um indoor growing
specifically even though some of it can
be cross applied very easily two we're
also assuming that you're growing for
yourself and not for sale uh two reasons
number one um that's that's that's
legally sticky to to to suggest that I'm
going to try to teach you how to grow
for commercially but more importantly
I'm not going to be teaching how to grow
uh in volume or necessarily how to grow
for the best looking in a bag we are
looking for you to have the skill set to
grow for your own usage to get the
relief that you can that you're looking
for
um we're also going to be teaching
another assumption is that we're doing
this for ease of e easiness over
production volume right so we're looking
for that the easiest route at every turn
instead of because there's certainly
things that you can do that to get to
get bigger plants with with more on them
and and and and the way it goes to make
more money right but that's that's not
really what we're doing here what we're
doing is we're trying to make it simple
so that everybody can have an
opportunity to grow and then finally I
recognize a lot of the established
growers in the room they all know more
than I do and in the past that's been
part of the problem is because people
have started to talk over their head so
if you are a grower in the room um I
know that there are different ways to do
this and I know that there are better
ways to do a lot of this but that's not
our goal today it's not about me trying
to impress with what I know about
Advanced growing this is about
simplifying it so everybody in the room
can
grow all right so with those assumptions
in hand part one do you really want to
grow so the law says right now if you do
not have a medical authorization you do
not have any right in the state of
Washington to grow a
plant if you have a medical
authorization you can grow four
plants if you have a medical
authorization and you choose to sign up
for the state
registry your four plants become six
plants if you have a medical
authorization and you're on the
registry and your doctor writes in at
the bottom of your license of your
authorization you can grow up to 15
plans so the best possible scenario that
is legal for you is if you have a
medical authorization and it's on the
new form and at the bottom your doctor
has written that you can have up to 15
plants and that is the maximum that you
can have on your partials 15
plants now if you don't have a medical
authorization um there is a possibility
though it's remote that the Washington
legislature will uh Pass personal grows
here in Washington like they have in
other legalized States but I wouldn't
hold my breath for that and so what we
see is that every year more individual
Americans are choosing to grow
regardless of what their state law is
because they feel they should be able to
while I'm not here to give you um legal
advice I would say that what I'm what
we're teaching here tonight can be used
in the face of your state laws use your
discretion and figure out how much risk
you're willing to go for in order to
provide your own medicine here on Bashon
the only place to get medical cannabis
is about to close because as of July 1st
all the dispensaries in the state have
got to close and because we are such a
small population and most of us grow for
ourselves it's going to be a while
before we get a recreational store on
the island so that means that after July
1st you can either go over town and shop
at a recreational store
oh yeah or that's it so this is why a
lot of people started have been asking
me about simple basics in growing and
this is why we are getting together
tonight so your family and your
neighbors probably have an
opinion so think about that um you may
have neighbors who might give you a hard
time you might have family who come over
for your barbecue this summer and they
might give you a hard time think about
that in advance because because once
it's happening
um it's it's not that positive it may
not be a big deal for you but think
about that in advance and also consider
um that you might want to stand with the
plant and even though your aunt or your
friend or your neighbor might have a
little bit of a problem that you've got
three plants on your porch maybe
consider just being okay with that and
and causing a conversation that might
open up somebody's eyes whatever you
decide make sure you consider it before
you go in to put in all the work that it
takes part two where to grow at your
home so a couple things to consider are
these iight from passers by it is a
classic sad story and they're known as
rippers people who go past your garden
every day and they see your cannabis
plants growing and they know just enough
that if they they know that if they wait
until the end of September or the
beginning of October they can stop by
your place and pick up your plant right
before you
harvest that's such a drag and so um it
is important to place your plants
somewhere out of line of sight from
people who are passing your property
second um you're also going to want to
do it close to water and you'll
understand why after you grow for the
first time because you're going to be
bringing water over there all the time
for the entirety of the summer like
pretty much through Halloween and and
and bringing water to your plants
Mother's Day through Halloween that's a
lot of water so it makes sense to have a
plan to have the water there um have it
be a location that you remember exists
so that you don't forget that the plants
are there it's incredibly common for
people to say you know like oh I went
over town and then oh the next day we
had a family party and then oh my gosh I
haven't water my plants in 3 days and
the weather's been so great and you go
back there and the plant has burned and
damaged so you want to make sure that
you're putting it out of sight a passers
by so that it doesn't get ripped but at
the same time you want to put it
somewhere where it will be an ey shot
for yourself um so that you remember to
tend it since you're just building these
habits and finally
deer deer love cannabis in its
vegetation stage um they seem seem to be
prefer some strange more than others but
they really like just to bite that top
green delicious top of the V vegetating
plant and so recognize that if you have
a garden with a deer fence as many of us
do here on Bashon Island I encourage you
to consider putting your plants in your
behind your deer fence um it is
incredibly common for people to grow
outside of a deer fence and have no
problem especially if you don't have
deer and instead you have more coyotes
on the island
um but be aware of that possibility
because it would be a shame for your for
your plants to get to the point where
they're just about to flip to be start
blooming and you come outside and
they've been chomped and and you know
they'll still grow but it it really
impedes your success so those are all
things that you want to consider when
choosing where to grow your
own next is the decision of do you want
to go into the ground or do you want
want to go into a container and there
are a couple different things to
consider here so so first of all the
ground is great it's got the natural
microbial life that exists in the ground
um The Roots can go as far as it wants
to into the ground and it allows your
plant to really stretch up because it's
got this fantastic base to hold itself
steady and that's fantastic
the hard part is though is that when
you're in the ground you can't move the
plant and one of the challenges that we
have here in the Northwest generally but
definitely on Bashon island is most of
the different uh strains or cultivars of
plants that are available to us in the
Northwest they're not going to finish
blooming until probably the first to
third week of
October if you're lucky and you get a
strain like shisa Berry or something
like that that blooms in 6 weeks you
might be out and done the end of
September but more often than not you're
going to be looking at your plant the
first week in October trying to decide
to cut it because you're looking at your
phone and it says rain and fall for the
next 3 days and and and if you're in the
ground that decision becomes a lot more
difficult because you have less
flexibility in contrast containers are
really really convenient
um you can grow in any container that's
at least 5
gallons um you can move it around your
yard if you need to um some small
Growers on the island even have gotten a
special hand truck just for moving their
plants around their yard and some of the
more resourceful folks that I've met um
they'll have three or four plants on
their patio and they'll get one of those
circular trays with the wheels on the
bottom and now they're sliding it all
around their deck depending on where the
sun is and if it's raining you slide it
underneath the uh the roof do hicky over
your deck it's a pretty great plan um uh
if you're in the ground you better plan
on on covering your plant at some point
and so there's lots of ways to do that I
have seen uh creatively placed beach
umbrellas um I have seen um a thick
plastic VIs bought from Home Depot that
has been attached to the house and then
brought down at an angle for poles over
the plants so that the rain uh sheets
off um you know maybe you even have um
you know some kind of structure outside
that um uh that you can you know uh rig
up to somehow but you really want to
think about this ahead of time because
our weather normally changes to be
threatening before the plants are done
and this is something that Bashon
Growers have been having to deal with
since their early 70s so you're not
alone and this is not a new problem but
do think about it ahead of time
especially if you're going to go into
the ground because once you're in the
ground you're there for
kees um all right I think that's that
there so so let's move on to soil and
nutrients also known as part
three so there are so many different
strategies for building your own soil
for for creating your own nutrients for
buying expensive and sexy nutrients at
the hydroponic
store we are going to talk about the
simple and cheap way and so these are
some of the suggestions number one the
the path of lease resistance you can
simply go to one of the the island shops
and pick up bags of soil and put it in
the
pot I don't usually recommend that for
indoor because so often the bags of soil
here on the island when you open them
they're going to have bugs in them and
that can ruin an indoor garden but you
got a lot more room for error Outdoors
because when you grow indoors um you
have got an artificial environment so
you are God you have to do everything
that nature would normally do but
Outdoors if you use soil with bugs there
are predators for those bugs also in
your yard and so every time I've ever
used I mean I I use I use I use insect
soil outdoors I swear and every year the
natural world just cleans them up um so
so so that is number one uh is you could
just use Simple potting soil from the
shop if you do that do your plant a
favor and grab some compost out your
compost bin or or or grab ask your
neighbor for some compost out of their
bin and mix it in with the soil because
honestly potting soil is as close to
Inner as you can get without putting it
in the oven first and and the idea is to
create an environment where the soil is
is as alive as you can get it to be so
that it's a constant Buffet of nutrients
for your plant to pull from as it's
growing so that's your bare minimum just
get some potting soil throw some compost
in it call it good second version you
want to do a little bit of upgrade um
you can still do the plain bags of soil
but also throw in some store bought
fertilizers and and you can Google
cannabis fertilizer
and learn how to spend a lot of money
and and and many of those fertilizers
are worth the effort and the money but
again this is the simplest thing
possible and so another possibility is
mixing with your bag of soil um just for
the first half so this would be from
when you grow it uh to when the the
daylight changes which we'll talk a
little bit more uh in a minute just use
simp fertilizer for growing vegetables
if you've got a food Garden at your
house like most of us do on the island
you probably already have vegetable
fertilizers and so uh following the
directions on it mix that in with your
soil for the first um for the first part
the vegetative state where your plant is
just trying to get um as large as it can
before it starts to make
flowers um professional Growers will
talk so much trash about using just
regular vegetable
nutrients but again you can get
sophisticated but you don't have
to
after uh August
15th the days will become 12 days of
light and 12 days excuse me 12 hours of
light and 12 hours of Darkness this is
what causes the canace plant to start
creating flowers and so now um your your
your vegetable nutrients are you know
they're still going to be decent but
they're not really what you're going to
uh what you're going to be looking for
if you're looking um if you're going to
spend some money switch on over the the
um the True Value now Ace has got a
fantastic selection of nutrients that
are for Bloom and that's what you're
looking for you are looking for Bloom
mixtures and it says Bloom on it you're
probably going to be good to go
um and uh I always encourage folks to
please lean towards the organic stuff
and the reason why I say this to you is
TW full um first and
foremost a lot of the a lot of the um
nutrients that use petrochemicals or
some other synthetic chemicals that you
can use in your food
Garden they are used to being in the
food Garden having rain on them getting
washed off and and then eaten in small
doses that is a big difference from the
plant picking up the nutrients putting
them in the flowers and then you
potentially burning them a lot of the
chemicals that are okay for our food
crops have never been tested for
combustion so you might have a plan to
make oil or edibles out of yours if
that's the medicine you prefer but a lot
of us are just going to be rolling
joints and and and and a lot of these
chemicals have never been tested under a
lighter so that's number one I want you
to be healthy um second is is just like
all chemical fertilizers there's going
to be runoff and you know if you if if
you saw the red tide we had around the
island last year red tide happens when
the fertilizers and the nutrients from
the island run off into the drains
and they they they hang out around the
island and then it gets hot and then
suddenly we've got this thick algae
bloom which makes um all of our filter
feeders and our clams and we can't eat
any of that stuff because of the red
tide it's terrible for the environment
and and it's just generally lame so what
if at all possible I encourage you to go
towards things that are marked organic
or have got natural sources both for
your health and the health of the
island
yay
woo so cannabis really does not like to
have her feet wet and so it's a really
good idea to put something in your soil
mixture that will allow it to drain
really easily um that's done a couple
different ways uh some folks like to mix
pearlite or coconut clar c i r into
their soil which allows the soil to hold
the water it needs but not longer than
it needs it and um my mentor puts uh a
bunch of Pebbles about an inch and a
half of pebbles in the bottom so that if
there's any overwatering it will collect
down there and be pulled out of the soil
um so that it can the the you know the
little holes on the bottom of your of
your pot uh it makes it easier and they
don't get all clogged up and the water
just runs out and so um that will be
something you know again if you want to
have the expenditure or if you have
bevels on your property that's another
good way to go to to give you more room
for error because that's what we're
doing here as beginner Growers is we
want to create as much room for error as
possible because there will be error and
you will learn from them and then next
summer you will have an even more
successful crop because you'll have all
this new
knowledge if you want to upgrade from
bag soil I want to tell you about living
soil so we won't dwell on this too much
but I'm a big fan of it if you can
afford it one of our sponsors is Ion
organic soil they're out of Tacoma and
we also have another sponsor uh keep it
simple Organics out of redond and they
both make soils that are micro
microbiotic alive and and ion Organics
even says that with their soil that all
you have to do is add water it's already
so living that throughout the entire
life process of the plant you don't have
to add any nutrients at all because the
soil itself is alive and the biological
processes are are are offputting
everything that your plant needs it's
super cool and it is absolutely the way
of the future
and it's expensive and it is also
reasonably priced because then you don't
aren't buying any nutrients and it makes
it much more foolproof so if you want to
look into that and and you know it's
it's it's usually about three times the
price of of just regular potting soil um
so if you're if you're trying to do it
on the cheap it might not be the option
but if you've got a little bit of room
to work with I encourage you to reach
out to to so you know either ion organic
soil or somebody else after you Google
living soils and go for something like
that um I used ion soils for the first
time myself last summer I've never seen
my plants be that good ever um the soil
is lighter which makes the the the pots
easier to carry um and and it is so
nutrient Rich that it's it's like this
buffet for the plant that anytime it
wants hm I think I want some phosphorus
or whatever it's like bam got it right
and so so it's definitely a step up but
but but know it exists if you want to if
you want to go that
far so the F the last two things are um
uh so my day job is um doing brand
strategy for entrepreneur.com and also
hosting their podcast and um and we've
had two podcasts recently that that if
you really want want to get into your
soil I suggest that you listen to and
they're both with uh Tad hussy who is
the is the founder actually the son of
the founder of keep it simple Organics
and Redmond and you can find either of
these by going to Gan preneur domcom in
the podcast section um or it's uh in
iTunes as well you can subscribe in
iTunes and the two uh shows specifically
that you'll get a lot of use out of are
the first one which is on on
wildcrafted nutrient teas and what this
means is Tad explains how you can go
around the island and identify certain
plants like for example comrey which may
be taking over your yard anyway and you
you pck these plants and you put them in
a 5 gallon bucket and you soak them for
a week to 10 days preferably with a
little bubbler but even that's not
absolutely necessary and after those
days you you take a Ladle out and you
pour that into your plants and he goes
through a whole series of plants that
will give you um you know silica or or
um whatever comfrey gives you I don't
remember them all but but um what you
say everything everything there you go
so so he he goes through a list of like
six or seven of the different nutrients
that you can find naturally in your yard
and by wildcrafting them which just
simply means picking them out in the
wild um you can create for yourself
Ultra
natural um
Solutions um without having to go to the
store and buy bottled nutrients which
can be expensive but are super
convenient so that's the first one is is
nutrient wildcrafted teas with Tad hussy
the second one is also with Tad uh and
this is the second of about three-part
series that we're doing with him on the
show and it's all about building your
own
soil and so Tad will explain most of the
these inputs you need to pick up
somewhere but um you know between you
know crushed shells and and and other uh
components of building a soil that will
may or may not necessarily be living by
the ion organic standards but is a damn
good soil uh and and you will have taken
this this uh essentially inert potting
soil and and super packed it with with
new nutrients that your plant is going
to want and it's really fun to build
soil I mean it really it really gets you
a feeling like a farmer you put down a
tarp you throw the soil out you throw
the nutrients on top and you know in a
in a similar recipe that's on the
entrepreneur show or just Google
marijuana uh soil recipe I mean there's
a bunch of them out there and then
actually if you just want to Google it
the one that we recommend on the show is
by this guy named Clackamus coup
and U he is a brilliant dude who
understands soil biology fantastically
so clus what what's his name Clackamus
like Clackamus Oregon cou c t so
Clackamus cot I mean just just looking
him up and and seeing what he has to say
on growing boards and things like that
it's a good time I mean that's a quick
way to lose in evening but um but but
the goal through the presentation
tonight is to give you the basics for
growing and to open the doors for you in
case you want to get obsessive because
you can you know you'll you'll learn
enough tonight to grow something this
summer um but if you decide that you
have a passion or if you already know
you're passionate grower this may be
something that you enjoy doing for the
rest of your life so so be prepared you
know they say that uh cannabis is the
gateway to horiculture
so you might get
[Music]
addicted
all right so let's talk about the plant
itself so now you you understand like
where your yard you're going to put it
you understand that you're going to have
to deal with rain and fog and general
moisture come the
fall and and and and now you got to
figure out a plant so what we're not
going to talk about today tonight is
particular strain or cultivar types um
you know they've got names like you know
Granddaddy Purple mandarina Dutch tree
Sweet Baby Jane all of these are are key
words that that tell you a little bit
something about the plant's um genetics
where they're from
um to make a gross overgeneralization
essentially you've got indicas which are
going to help you relax and and help you
with pain you've got sativas which are
going to be motivating mentally focusing
and helping you with depression and then
you've got high CBD which are which uh
you're either going to have lots of CBD
and no THC or little THC or or lots of
CBD and some
THC
um so um so the goal here is not to help
you choose the strains but to let you
know that you're going to want to figure
out what you're looking for and then you
have to make a decision about whether or
not you want a clone or to grow from
seed and there is without a doubt a
preference to grow from clone if you are
a beginner um there are a lot of great
reasons to grow from seeds and I will
recommend seeds if you are this kind of
a person but clones are made from a
mother plant that's already growing the
grower that you buy it or your friend
who you barter with it or gives it to
you or whatever they will take a
snipping off their plant put it in some
rock wool put it under lights let it
root and then it ends up looking like
one of
these and that is a really easy nearly
foolproof way to start
um putting the plant into the
soil the clones have got the age though
of the mother so if the mother has been
cared for by your grower friend for a
year 6 months a year and a half
whatever your your clone is that age as
well and sometimes maybe it doesn't have
the same gunion as a younger plant from
seed will
have if you are interested in food
gardening already if you think you're
going to become a horiculture nerd as
well you may want to consider seeds and
here's the story on seeds seeds are
always going to be more robust and have
more Moy than a clone
does the pro the challenge anyway it's
not really a problem the challenge with
seeds though is number one you need to
go through the germination process and
it's not hard to germinate or pop seeds
and you can find tons of videos on how
to do this on YouTube um it's usually
some version of put it in a wet paper
towel until you start to see plant come
out
um some people like to put it in in a
cup of water for a few days and soak
them and then put them in paper towel
but there's a certain amount of risk
because once the once the seedling
starts to come out it's really easy to
dry them out so there are some initial
challenges in that category probably
more importantly though is is when
you're growing from seeds you don't know
if they're going to be male or female
and when growing cannabis we really only
want to grow the females to get the
medicine from males are useful for
pollen if you want to create your own
crosses or create your own seeds and the
vime organization we keep a library of
males every year and uh we usually have
between 12 and 20 males and they're kept
at a viia member's house that is not
growing females that year and um and
when when they are full P we shake them
into little bags and the people who have
donated or said that they're going to
make seeds this year we give them a a
bag or or a little jar of pollen and
then they take a paintbrush and you can
paint it onto the flowers and you'll
cost seeds but generally speaking males
are not what you're going for you're
going for the females where the THC is
uh that you want for your relief or the
CBD so so you're going to have to get
educated on how to delineate the males
from the
females which is super super easy with
10 years of
experience so
um again Google is really helpful in
this category um you know there good
cameras are everywhere now there are a
lot of people who are posting pictures
and videos about how to sex your plants
um it's just some time and some effort
and so if you want to go that extra step
um popping your own seeds can be a lot
of fun the plant that comes from them is
going to be more robust generally than
clones even though clones are plenty
robust you'll get a little bit more and
if you're the kind of person who likes
to jump in with two feet you may really
decide that you want to go with seeds
Plus for those of you who live on mashon
um we have got some fantastic seed
makers here on the island um including
if you if you already know in your head
that you're going to want to go with
seeds because because the jumping with
both feet is how is describing you
already um we've got our top seed
producer in the room so Michael raise
your hand so if you're interested in
seeds I asked Michael to bring seeds
with him tonight and and if you want to
talk with him um he'll be able to tell
you what what he's got available right
now and um and so if if you don't uh get
seeds tonight and you decide you want to
um even though it's illegal you can do
mail order and also if you have a
medical authorization they're now
selling them at many medical
dispensaries so again if you live on
Bashon also just like ask around there's
seeds all over the
place if you're drawing proce how long
does the plant need be grow before you
do the sex it sure um it won't be sexed
until just about the time it starts to
bloom because that's what's starting to
show right so you need to start growing
the pl and um I know you're going to do
indoor but for most of us who are
outdoor the the clock flips over um you
know in and around August 15th right so
depending on the cultivar bar some of
them start a little earlier some of them
start a little bit later but the moral
of the story is you won't know until mid
end of August generally speaking and so
so you're putting time and resource and
and and maybe repotting them up if
you've got a few just to decide that
you're going to either you know snip
them and throw them in the compost or uh
call me and add them to the the pollen
library for Vivia if you have on island
so question you can sex the seeds though
right so you can pay to have uh seeds
sexed but you can't do it yourself like
microscopic no I am aware of no way to
do that um there's new technologies from
Steep Hill labs in California where
they're doing genetics testing but for
the kind of price point that we're
talking about here tonight I I would not
consider that a realistic option yeah
so oh uh another option is um uh for
seeds and this is also where I'm going
to suggest that you can go for clones is
if you have a a medical authorization
you can go to the pce the patient
cannabis exchange uh that's in Tacoma on
Sundays it is one of the most wonderful
experiences that you will have as a
cannabis patient to go there and check
out this family environment of like 50
cannabis producers all sorts of flour
and Edibles and seeds and clones it's
like it's like Willy Wonka for
canis and um but you have to have a
medical authorization to go there and
that is the first place that I would
recommend that you go if you have an
authorization and if you want to work
from CL
um clones Northwest who has got a booth
there um they have fantastic clones um
they're very reasonably priced they
they've got a rotating list of of
strains every Sunday and uh 99% of the
time they're in great shape and and if
they're not in good shape um sometimes
we'll just give to so so I I can not
recommend going to the patient cannabis
exchange enough if you have an
authorization um if you don't have an
authorization uh this is where you need
to get a little bit more creative by
talking to your friends you know um if
you're here if you're interested in
cannabis you probably already know
somebody who's growing and if you are
let them know that you'd like to have a
clone from them in June and that gives
them enough time to make you a clone get
it rooted so that you're ready to go
outside and we'll talk about when to go
outside soon but generally speaking it's
um it's Mother's Day is kind of like
rule of thumb uh so so if somebody were
to start a clone for you now it would be
in great shape by by that
time um another opportunity is that um
uh the last viia meeting before the laws
change um here in Washington is going to
be uh June 15th and actually that's a
really awesome meeting to be at because
the fellow I was just talking about Tad
h
who did the the podcast with me on
building your own soil and wildcrafting
your own nutrient teas he's going to be
here talking live so so that's going to
be pretty awesome I'm actually really
excited about that myself he's got a
fantastic National reputation for all
natural organic growing and and um we
have also invited um two clone providers
uh to join us as well to provide so so
um you know maybe come back to the June
15th meeting as well and you may be able
to uh get a clone at that time as well
here I'm a little confused you generally
though you want your clone in the ground
on Mother's Day what was that piece so
um the the the important aspect is that
we need to have uh nighttime
temperatures above 50 every night and so
if the weather stays like this um people
will start going into the ground or
going outside as we say
earlier um The Challenge though is that
our Northwest weather is really fickle
and so if we have got a week like we
have had where you know evenings are 46
and today was like what 82 or something
ridiculous um people you know Growers on
the island are already starting to get
that kind of that itch you know where
they they're they're really really being
tempted to go outside but all it takes
is like you know 10 days from now we
could have 4 days in a row of low 40s
rain with morning fog and you're you
know you'll have wasted your efforts
because there's a really good chance
that your plant won't make it through
that unless you do something extra like
build a Clos or something like that or
you know some kind of a hold frame to
keep them warm at night so you know you
can you can buy yourself a little more
wiggle room with that but the the rule
of thumb is that you want your evenings
to stay above 50 and generally speaking
by Mother's Day you're in pretty good
shape for
that so the last thing I want to focus
in on on on the seeds versus clones and
choosing your plants is um sometimes you
just have to grow what's available if
your friend is growing three strains and
they're the ones who's going to be
giving you your clones you just need to
take what they've got and and this will
be you know you'll just go with that but
if you're going to order seeds or if
you're going to go to the patient
cannabis exchange or or if if you're
going to have some choice I encourage
you to choose something that has got a
as slow or as as short of a flowering
cycle as you can find um indicas
generally will have a flowering cycle
around eight uh 8 weeks if you get into
sativas which are more tropical you're
talking about 12 weeks
and and some of them like never and so
and so um but but again uh I had a lot
of luck last summer with a strain called
Shish Berry which claims to be finished
in six weeks and it was done for me in
six and a half weeks it was amazing and
so um the because of where we live if we
lived you know farther south um you we
would be able to grow more sativas and
we be able to finish without all the
covering as as much but you you
continually have to go farther south to
be growing sativa outdoors and that's
why Bashon has got the 30-year
reputation of of growing you know some
of the best Indica in the country
because that's all we do is Inda and and
a lot of the seeds that are produced on
the island year over year people are
picking their best plants and just
seeding the flowers on the bottom and so
year overy year the seeds get better and
better and better just for where we live
those same seeds are not going to be as
good if you take them down to Sona
County because the weather is different
there but but if you buy seeds on Bashon
that were produced on Bashon you're
going to be in a much uh better
situation so uh in summary try to get
the shortest flowering time as you
can when to plant so we've already hit
most of this already um you go try to go
outside at Mother's Day or if you're
feeling confident when you see um the
the evenings staying above 50 you know I
absolutely have put him out when I when
the evenings were 47 48 and hoped for
the best and some years I got the best
and some years I had to go get new
clothes and start and it's kind of a
crapshoot we all have got different risk
tolerance um but uh but that's what
we're looking for our our 50
evenings
um some people also like to start them
indoors under a grow light now this is
not something you have to do but if you
think about it if there's two stages for
the plant if there is a vegetation stage
which is the plant trying to get as big
as it can before it changes its
priorities to making
flowers if you put your plant outside
you know at Mother's Day day you got
between then and around August 15th for
the vegetation stage and then the energy
is put in the flowers but if you were to
start now like many professional Growers
are you can start that plant under
lights and get it growing now and then
when you put it out when the evening
temperatures are 50 you know it's
already this big and it goes outside and
then it just you know you are rewarded
for your efforts but your efforts look
like um you know either either
repurposing or buying uh a grow lamp and
you know there are we can have a whole
actually we have had a whole other
evenings on lights and we're not talking
about uh indoor growing specifically but
you can really do a lot of good with
just buying a decent plant grow light in
the natural light spectrum from the
hardware store and and you know you
screw it in you put a couple starts
under it um if you start them early
enough and they get too big maybe you
decide you want to get a second one but
the goal here is that um uh you just
want the plant to have an opportunity to
get it start before you put it outside
if you're going to go this this route um
there's a lot of there's a lot of
discussion about um how long to have the
light on while it's in the house but
suffice to say that if you have your
light um on for 18 hours and off for 6
hours you're in good shape um there are
some people who will suggest you know 24
hours of light to get all the growing
you can and I've seen some amazing
plants from 24 hours of life I also
think it's it's not b i I think that
it's really smart to give the the plant
an opportunity to rest a few hours every
night so just putting on putting it on a
timer for 18 hours on 6 hours off
and and doing that until you're ready to
go outside um you can have your plant
get a big jump on nature and and
honestly you may you may increase the
size of your plant by a third and you
may increase your U your volume of
flowers by as much as a half so you know
if if you've got you know if you've got
the 20 $30 to throw at just some simple
uh plant lights at the hardware store um
your your efforts will be
rewarded so watering the goal with
watering is to water the pot evenly I
guess in this case I should say the soil
evenly
um but you also want the soil to have
the opportunity to nearly dry out
between waterings because that's how it
is in nature the plant doesn't like its
feet wet
and there is a very prevalent philosophy
that it's good to let your plant work a
little bit you know give it a little bit
of stress so that it feels like it has
to earn its key right and so um uh the
great way to water is is is you know
water it enough that everything gets wet
but not enough that you're that it's
going to stay soaked necessarily for the
rest of the day um the rule of thumb
that my mentor has taught me and has
worked out well for me is just plan on
giving it a good solid watering once a
day
outdoors and if the weather is hot like
it is today plan on watering it
twice and if it's gray and kind of foggy
or raining skip a day and if it's
raining for 3 days in a row maybe just
give it a little
bit part of growing good cannabis
is developing a relationship with a
plant so that you can listen to her she
will tell you what she needs if she's
starting to wilt chances are you're not
giving her quite enough water there's a
lot more other things there's a lot of
other things that could be too but just
generally speaking um if the leaves are
starting to turn yellow chances are
you're giving her too much water just
like the rest of your house plant right
so again um if you really want to dive
into this
you can Google watering cannabis plants
and learn far more than we have the time
to offer you here but the rule of thumb
that will get you to a good harvest is
just plan on giving it a good soaking
once a day let the excess drain out the
bottom of the pot and uh if it's hot
water more and if it's our typical foggy
rainy weak uh water
less when in doubt don't water and come
back you know in 12 hours and check it
again because it doesn't hurt to have
the soil dry out some uh in nature it'll
dry the soil will dry out regularly so
the plants genetics are used to this
what you don't want is the kind of dry
where the soil detaches from the pop and
you can start to see lines and you get
the
the kind of tubble weed that's that's
that's not good because at that point
you're going to start drying up your
root system and you're going to start
causing damage that may be irreparable
so there you go
blooming so depending on your uh the
cultivar that you end up with the
blooming will start somewhere around
August 15th because nature goes to 12
hours of daylight 12 hours of
Darkness um it would be at this point if
you are choosing to purchase Bloom
nutrients you're going to want to start
adding this properly to your water some
of the blooming nutrients are called to
to put them on the soil and put a little
soil on top and then water that but some
of them are are add to water as well so
if you're going to add Bloom nutrients
now is the time to start that and this
is also when your plant is going to
start to
stank and some people don't like the
smell of cannabis and for them my heart
goes out
I love the smell of a really stinky
cannabis plant the same way that I love
the smell of a really stinky cheese that
smells like baby diaper
right that smell though as the plant
blooms is going to get more and more
potent and this brings us back around to
the conversation about your neighbors
right so so since we're talking about
your growing for your personal use we're
probably only talking about a few few
plants here and if we're talking about a
patient legally in Washington we're only
talking about four unless you're under
registry then you're up to six or
15 however you know if you're if you're
doing well and if your plant is is
having some success um it especially if
you've got a smelly strain say for
example
skull um you want to be aware that your
plants are good to smell and so uh
consider that when you when you're
choosing the part of your yard and also
consider that because it's going to be
really fun it's it is my personal
favorite part even more than harvesting
because harvesting means I'm going to
have to trim um uh when the plants start
to smell and give off their unique
turfing profile it is Nature's aroma
therapy and and you know you will feel
Joy in your heart and you will know
you're having success and there is a
certain connection with nature when you
start to smell that that that you just
don't get anywhere else than than from
smelling flowers which is why we give
them in Romance right so so once
blooming starts um you will notice that
the that the the size of the plant will
slow down in its increase and you will
start to see either sex if you're coming
from um seeds um or if you're coming
from a clone uh you know you we should
be darn well guaranteed that it's a
female
and so um you will start to see the
blooms um uh start at the nodules where
the branches are meeting the uh the main
stock so right nestled in here you'll
start to see flowers all the way down
the Plant and at the beginning all they
are these like little tiny usually white
hairs um but that is a that's a promise
of future awesomeness so so um so so
that'll happen around August and that is
when um if you know what your your
strain or cultivar is I recommend that
you Google it say for example um it's
blue dream go ahead and Google blue
dream strain flowering time and find out
what the flowering time is for the the
plant that you're working with um it'll
tell you how many days sometimes it'll
just tell you round it out to weeks but
from uh August 15th put on your calendar
forward that long and that will give you
an approximation of when your plant is
going to be done we'll talk about
harvesting more in a minute but that'll
give you a general idea and the reason
why I suggest you put it on your
calendar is number one it will help you
be patient during that time and it will
it will help you resist harvesting early
because when the plant starts smelling
potent and when you see it and the
weather report starts getting worse
you're going to be tempted to Har to
harvest it early and you really don't
want to do that because the THC sets in
the plant just in the last few weeks you
know the CBD in the plant it sets in
about 2 to 3 weeks earlier than the THC
does so so you know for commercial
Growers who are growing indoors you can
actually cut off a crop early if you're
just going for the CBD and over the
course of a year you can get work in
actually an extra crop but we're talking
about growing outdoors and so um uh you
want to be able to let it go its entire
length how do you decide when to
harvest the best way I know is to spend
eight bucks on eBay and pick up a 30X
and a 30X jewelers loop l
o you can also use a 30X magnifying
glass what you'll find on the flowers
are these little stocks that are called
troms inside the tricomes is the
cannabis oil which is the goal of all of
this and if you've got your little Loop
you get on in there and for the whole
first part of the blooming cycle you
will see these stocks but they'll be
first they'll just be small and clear
and then they'll get taller and clearer
and then they'll be taller with a kind
of a bulb on the top and be
clear and then they'll start to get a
little cloudy or
milky and that's when you want to start
paying attention and then they will
start to turn
Amber there is a lot of different
opinions on once it turns Amber what to
do some will say the whole plant should
be Amber some will say say as soon as it
starts getting
Amber I kind of like to pull a tweener
it's always a judgment call but when
when some of the tricomes are Amber I go
ahead and harvest at that point they may
not all be but on Vashon where we are
fighting the
weather if if if a good group of your
tricomes are Amber and the rest are
cloudy and about to become Amber you
should just cut and run because you have
got CBD that's sitting in the plant
ready to go you've got your txc that's
sitting in the plant and is ready to go
and it's time to just go ahead and cut
it without magnification it's very
challenging to decide when to harvest
the plant if you really don't want to
spend the eight bucks or ask your friend
to borrow their magnifying glass you can
just Harvest based on the the
recommendations blindly um you're
probably going to leave some tricomes on
the table though and I recommend that if
you're going to go through this and put
all of your time and effort and love
into this plant then you go ahead and
pick up a $8 with free shipping jewelers
loop on eBay um plus once you have it
you'll be surprised how many other cool
things that you can use it for it's CU
kind of cool to have around the house um
it's amazing to look at bugs so yes
about so looking at the tricomes um so
you it sounds like you're talking about
looking at them for their uh THC content
like that the Amber it means that this
the THC is going to be higher correct so
if you're just looking to harvest for
more more for
CBD what will the tricomes be an
indicator of will that help sure so so
it's kind of a Sticky Wicket here so um
if you have a strain that's going to and
you're not growing for THC at all let's
say let's say that you are growing for
seizures and you want some THC in there
to take advantage of the Entourage
effect the whole plant medicine aspect
of it right um You
can um Harvest you know a week to two
earlier than recommended and there will
absolutely be CBD matured in the
plant it's a kind of a dangerous game
and it's that is usually something that
I would only recommend for professionals
who are familiar with their strain that
said if you're about to leave on
vacation or if the weather is just about
to go to hell you know and you're only
looking really for the
CBD um yeah there a case could be made
to to U Harvest a week or two early and
neglect a lot of the THC in most cases
though we're going even if you're going
to get a CBD plant you do want some
amount of THC in there and you don't
want to end up with with it um not matur
so so I would still go to let the
tricomes become Amber um but you got
more room to cut early if you're just
going for the CBD but but really um as
far as as far as the general rule it's
going to be when when when some of the
tricomes are fully Amber cut and pull
inside especially it's going to rain
tomorrow so so so now it's time to
harvest and uh for many this is
bittersweet because you've had this
relationship with this plant all summer
and and now uh it's time to end it and
so um uh people have got different ways
they like to do it some folks like to go
starting at the bottom and and cutting
up the plant just cut off Branch Branch
Branch branch and just kind of set them
aside um I learned from uh from Alex um
from Solstice who spoke last fall here
on harvesting and curing Al [__] he
said that he that his team always
harvests from the bottom in case there's
any mold on the plant which we'll talk
about a little bit later he'll cut and
the mold Falls and then he goes higher
the cut and the molds Falls whereas if
you start at the top and you cut if
there's any mold up there it drops down
on the lower plant so by time you're at
the bottom any mold that's above has has
come down on the lower so always start
at your
bottom um the other way to do it and and
a lot of folks do this if they don't
have a lot of room to hang their plant
which we'll discuss in a minute is just
take some big Cutters and and cut the
stock if you've been really successful
you may not be able to cut it just with
pruners you may need um a
hacksaw one way or another um you need
to uh cut it and hang it um you've got
uh at least two options at that
point actually this uh this wire here is
perfect for hanging Canada scrub um it's
wire so it's not going to have much Bend
to it I don't recommend you hanging on
string because
string right so hanging on uh wire or
cable or um or or a a type of of taut
filament is a good way
ago um uh one of my friends who's on the
island who's a retired Professor um he
doesn't like cutting all of his
individual branches because it fills up
too much space so what he does is he's
got a a cable that's already run in his
garage he just cuts the whole plant and
he hangs the whole plant all in one and
every summer he just does five plants so
he's got 1 2 3 four five done and
they're all hung at the same time and
and uh and then he he trims off that
which we'll talk about minut yes uh
prior to harvesting you sto fertilizing
the plant a few couple weeks before
that's excellent so it should be on the
instructions of your Bloom fertilizer
about how many weeks to do this but
generally since we're going to be uh
consuming it uh folks recommend that you
stop fertilizing at least 2 weeks before
um and then at that point you do what's
consider called a flush and so you're
just you're just watering it to flush
out the nutrients in the soil and uh so
that um it gives you an even taste and
um and you don't waste nutrients a great
question I wasn't going to mention that
so good call thank you
um so the room that you're hanging in
this is probably going to be a punt for
most everybody um uh there's some
differentiation about humidity in a in a
in a in a drying room uh 62 % humidity
is is often what's gone for uh if it's
if it's less humid your plant will dry
faster and The Taste will develop a
little less if it's more humid it may
never dry but really most since the the
most important aspects are cool and dark
you may not have a choice so you might
just put it in your cool dark place you
have um because even if it dries
quickly um you know it's not like the
it's not like it's going to be ruined
um it would be you know Troublesome if
your goal was to sell it um and people
have got really high standards for flour
now but but since we're talking about
growing for yourself if you just hang it
in a room that is dark and cool you're
probably going to be in good shape if
you really want to get dirdy about it go
ahead and Google drawing cannabis and
you'll get a exhaustive conversation
on on different techniques um but for
for this what we want you to do is just
hang it to the point that the
branches when you bend them they
snap if you bend them and they Bend it's
not ready yet if you bend it and it
snaps you're good to go to the next
stage I have a question about I know
it's but uh I have a b po occasionally
and uh I put it in a dehydrator M and
you know I you to sell it it really
saves you know I mean it seemed like it
was okay is that a rough thing on the
THC or is there any other other than
maybe problem
thatat yeah so so I have absolutely
heard of folks dehydrating but with the
heat off so they're dehydrating with
just the air blowing
around um normally that's not going to
be um efficient enough though because
most dehydrators are pretty small but if
you're if you if you only have a couple
plants and you've got a big dehydrator
um I don't see any reason why you
couldn't go in that way well by last
year buil insulating right with that 2
in R insulation and built a 4x4 box and
put a dehydrator inside it and it
actually work really well see that kind
of mad science works all the time right
like you know and see and so that is a
perfect example right you can you can
chop it hang it in your garage come back
in two weeks after checking on it every
day right and you're done boom right it
can be that simple or you can do this
kind of mad science and and have it dry
at a slower rate and and as it slows at
a as it as it dries at a slower rate
um The Taste I actually don't know the
theot of it but but the the tastes are
able to develop and mature in a way that
doesn't happen when it gets dry really
quickly you want to know why that is
yeah so it's about the plant material
it's not about the troms or any of the
Turpin or anything like that it's
actually the Vegeta PL material much the
way that they cure tobacco in a in a
slow way is that if if you dry that
plant material very quickly it'll burn
quickly and it'll be like harsh but if
you cure it in that slow way and you
remove the most moisture slowly the
vegetative part of the pan will burn
more slowly and it'll smoo the burn and
it preserves like the moisture in
the so so more taste less off right sh
it's also a conversion of of starches
into sugars and that's part of that part
of that process of the plant still
thinking it's alive during the first few
days after's been cut so it actually
still thinks is alive so it eats itself
of its star and those starches get
combined sugars and those sugars are
actually what gives a marijuana better
flavor use a dehydrator something like
that sometimes you can pull some of
those sugars out too quickly yeah right
thank you Joshua and like I said when I
started the room is filled with Growers
who know more than I do right Josh being
one of them and and and um as much as
you want to get into this growing
unfolds itself and and you can learn
more which which I continue to do yes
are they talking about
dehumidifiers uh no like a dehydrator
like to make like beef jerky or or or
just a food dehydrator it's a it's a
small box and it's got shelves that pull
out right okay a heat Source yeah yeah
exactly and so if you're going to use
for cannabis though most everybody
detaches the heat Source cuz you don't
want you put a de humidifier in in your
garage or shop um that would probably
take a humidity too low yeah cuz idea
like you saiding moist out of the yeah I
think I think well if if you've got
really high humidity in you might need a
dehumidifier to bring it down some but
just be careful because um in my
experience dehumidifiers you know cuz
because we'll use them in the grow room
so that the grow room doesn't get like
indoors so it doesn't get too moist but
but um you're kind of playing with fire
doing that in your in your curing closet
because um if you're humid is on too
long it'll pull all the moisture out of
the air and then they'll get really
rigid really faster what about how books
in your curing closet does that help the
community I don't have any experience
about the books I would avoid books in
my curing closet just because of
potential mold risk yeah yeah Adam um is
there a level approximately around like
humidity level in a drying room where
you do need to start worrying about
facilitating mold growth and whatnot
like a percentage like you know if it's
like like how much over 62% humidity in
that drying curing room could start you
know contributing to too much moisture
and like you know mold or whatnot you
know the short answer is I don't have a
good answer for you the longer answer
though is that um even at 62 or excuse
me 62% you are still going to be dealing
you know if there's mold on the plant
that you're bringing in um it's going to
continue being mold once once the plant
is molded it should be thrown away so if
you see mold on your plant don't bring
that mold into your dry room cut it off
and and leave it outside somewhere
because you don't want to bring those
spores into the the drawing room where
it can contaminate the other
plants so
um so let's talk a little bit about
mold this is a mold is a bane of growing
in the northwest
and there are two primary kinds of mold
that are we have to deal with um the
first and most common is powdery mildew
powdery mildew is um it is looks like
white splotches on the
leaves and it makes grown men
cry um there are really uh you know you
you can you can Google online for
powdery Milo sprays and people will give
you all sorts of amazing concoctions
that they think works for them to make a
long story short though um the choice
for many is either you rub it off with
your hands and then you rub your hands
on um a disinfectant and then you
continue to rub it down the Plant where
you see it or a lot of people just once
there's powdery mildew on the leaf they
don't want it it becomes you know as if
it was a contagion and they just remove
the the the leaf from the plant if
you've got a serious powdery mildew
problem though you could be taking a lot
of leaves from the plant and there are
definitely two different schools of
thought one is that it's not a big deal
to take plants off or take leaves off
the plant especially in bloom because
why bother to grow to keep that leaf
alive and then some people think that
every time you take a leaf you are
causing stress to the
plant if you don't have a huge powdery
mildew problem and you've got a lot of
leaves I think there's a strong case to
be made to just remove the
leaf if your plant is being taken over
by Pottery mildew at that point um
you're probably going to want to look
into just spraying it and just trying to
do whatever you can to save the
plant the second kind of build do or the
second time of mold that we have that's
a real drag is called
buritis and buritis um manifests in two
different ways the first is um it will
be at the crown uh of the flower right
at the very top at the tip and you can
start to see it get gray and fuzzy
that's a drag but at least you see it
the other way is it will be in the very
core of the flower so you'll grow this
beautiful flower and you're like yeah
and then you break it open and it's all
fuzzy and you can't smoke it anymore
it's it's no good for you it's terrible
for a patient and and it's really sad
and and why it's even worse where we
live is because while we try to keep a
trius out of our crops they spray btis
in Oregon for their late bottled vintage
reings and Ice wines because it causes
them to uh mature in taste and
mold so um so that blows up here so we
have got a a really serious betrus issue
and you should expect to lose um you
know a percentage of your crop to mold
just because of where we live so plantet
[Music]
all right
so in summary let's let's let's rewind
it back to the
beginning so you're going
to figure out what your kind of soil
you're you're going to have you're going
to pick the area in your garden and you
are going to get your hands on either a
seeds or a clone you're going to plant
it all up together you're going to go
through your vegetation period which is
going to allow your plant to grow up
large August 15th is going to come
you're going to start seeing flowers
come on it's going to start to
smell you're going to reach the point
that some of the tricomes are starting
to turn Amber or are Amber you're going
to harvest you're going to hang it and
you're going to let it
dry once it's dry you want to there's a
there's a preference you can either trim
the flowers of uh down uh of the their
small leaves Sugar Leaf we'll call it uh
to make them pretty when they're wet
some people like to do it and you drop
it in a jar and some people like to wait
until it's dry um we don't have enough
time to go into that right now um
suffice to say though that
um once it is dry enough in the curing
process that it the the the branch
snaps it should go into uh glass jars
like a mason jar
for about two
weeks and open it once a day and let the
air
exchange because what you're doing is
the the drying that you are done in your
room to the
snap that's that's that's the the main
part of the drawing once you bring it
into glass jars you are now slowing down
that uh process to to its end so that
the last of the starches convert to
sugars and you get a finished product
that is very pleasant to smoke there are
a lot of different strategies for how to
do this there really isn't a way to do
it wrong by the time you're putting your
flowers in the jar you've already won
and we're talking about differentiation
of taste at that point and over time
over talking with other Growers if you
want to do some more research online you
will get more sophisticated in how you
do that but but in a beginner's course
if if if you get through this whole
process and you've hung it and you get
them into jars and you're opening the
jars once a day for two weeks what you
have there is a huge success you can
take that and you can smoke it for pain
you can make tinctures if you prefer not
to smoke and use that on a wide range of
issues you can turn it into oil and use
it in Edibles you have won you've
already won at that point so from that
point on the next year you're just going
to be fine
tuning so so with that that is what I
have we've got about uh about 10 minutes
for for questions if you have them and
because like I already said I am not the
best grower in the room I'm just the one
doing the beginners part uh forew um we
might we might share some answers too
from the more uh professional folks in
the room so so who has a question yeah
are you friends by all while
you're or you just letting them go uh so
so there is some difference opinion
about whether or not you're going to
prune them uh you're definitely not
going to uh prune branches because
they've got flowers on them uh uh well
into the bloom cycle some people will
like the idea of taking off some of the
extra branches with that either don't
have flowers or have got like emaciated
flowers so that the plant can continue
to put its energy into the robust
flowers um some people people think that
that stresses out the plant so it's
certainly a debatable issue I do like
like prune to get off um the fluff right
and I and I move on but but really uh I
don't really think there's the right
answer it's a technique yes yeah um what
about hours of sunshine when you're
trying to decide where you're going to
place your
pots all you can get so so yeah because
really the the more Sunshine that your
plant gets during the day the more or
you know it can do photosynthesis and
take care of itself um if you have got a
place in your property that's going to
be shaded most of the day that's
definitely not where you want to go and
if you're going to um uh you know if you
got a a a a Southwest facing side of
your house that would be a really great
place because not only do you get all
the the the day sunshine but you get all
the reflected Sunshine off of wall and
and also at at the end of day when
you're getting that awesome end of day
bash on light the the the house will
still be warm which will keep the
ambient temperature up high but but
really your goal is to be in as much sun
every
day yes say got the some other plants
that I like the strains and they're
they're they're doing really well and
they they live like maybe a year like
you were saying year and a
half how is it like converting them to
seed producers at the end of that cycle
do they are they still strong enough to
do that or in my experience yes um
you'll just want to uh you know you can
either put him in a room or put him next
to a guy or you can get pollen out of
the viia pollen library and um and then
paint them on but um while this is not
my specialty I don't think that I mean
people put their mothers seed all the
time okay yeah are you with that Jake
yeah all right cool
yeah when PL done to seed is the flower
useless for smoking no definitely not as
a matter of fact some of the coolest
gifts I've been given U by professional
Growers is a is a little paper envelope
with a seated flower in it because it
kind of gives you a sample of what it is
right so you just simply you know use
your thumbs and get the seeds out and
then you smoke what's left and so um uh
you know traditionally people will
complain about because you don't want to
get in the bowl they'll pop they they
they do you know the energy from the
plant will be taken from flower
production into seed production so
you're it's not going to be quite the
you know the Burly THC as you would get
if if the plant wasn't seated but if
your goal is to produce seeds for the
next year go ahead see the plant pull
out the seeds and then just you know me
it's not be pretty anymore but um it's
it makes a great joint yeah so you said
um that with the doctor's form you can
do 15 plants is that per parcel or per
patient per parcel
okay analyze parel thank you uh well on
the keing county um partial viewer one
number you know so it could be 100 acres
or it can be a quarter Acres correct
don't run your Parcels together into one
parcel well and see the other great area
is um there is there they're still
hashing this out but there's going to be
room for patient collectives for for a
couple people to get together but but um
there seems to be issues with the rules
between letting a couple people get
together to grow together versus how
many plants on a parcel and and we're
not going to we're not going to
deconstruct the law here tonight but
we're still hoping that the legislature
cleans up some of the rules um during
this session uh so that it becomes less
of a mess it's so muddy right now nobody
knows anything right yes it is
incredibly muddy right now which is
which is why you know we're I'm teaching
this information right and and it may be
legal to grow not being a patient and it
may not be legal to grow to a patient
this summer but if you're a grower you
have to make these decisions here in the
next few weeks so um but you know the
the legislature is not really concerned
with our preferences and we've seen that
they really don't care our patients so
we got to take care of ourselves
wow like in in the past I've had
helicopters flying over taking pictures
and all this kind of thing do you get a
sense of what their uh aim is coming up
or well secretive about that yeah the
short answer is that we don't know what
their plans are the longer answer though
is that at the um the the Cannabis
ethics meeting I was at 2 months ago I
was spok speaking to uh senator Cole
Wells and um and I asked her about
bachel I said you know we have a Trade
Organization we had
152 medical Growers which are now all
having to make the choice for their
families to either give up this extra
income or become criminals in the eyes
of the state what are these people that
the state encouraged to get involved and
all the rural Economic Development we
did what are they supposed to do are you
going to send the King County Sheriff
out here to start busting families and I
didn't get an answer and what I mostly
got was shock looks because people
hadn't really considered all the people
who on who had intentionally built
businesses across Washington that now
have got to make this terrible choice
you know we've got 502 members in in the
organization and I support them and and
their right to try to make uh you know
some profit from Canada is just like the
medical folks were as well right but the
the the medical Growers families have
got a decision to make right now that's
really challenging um we are all
watching to see what happens uh you know
the the DEA is not spending any more
money on cidis interdiction so they're
out of the game um our local King County
Sheriff seems to be um you know there's
no problem if there's no problem right
if you're growing a couple plants at
your house and there's no problem
nobody's going to give you a hard time
but if you're growing a couple plants at
your house and you're beating your wife
and you have weapons and they come to
your house and you're a jerk they may
use the Cannabis to take you in because
they need they need to put together a
case against you right so so the best
advice I'm getting
is be be polite be private don't grow
too many plants don't be to too
flamboyant don't sell it and keep it
away from kids right if you do those
things regardless of what the letter of
the law is probably no one is going to
have enforcement I certainly don't
expect the huge helicopters to be back
like they were in the '90s scaring the
hell out of everybody on the
island but we'll see what happens right
uh things could change in a really bad
direction if uh depending on who's in
the Oval Office too right so
all right so with that we want to get on
to the door prizes so thank you very
much