our guest this evening is my good friend
Ben Cassidy Ben his co-founder of true
terpenes in Portland Oregon and he was
kind enough to drive all the way up just
for tonight's event to terpenes provides
exceptional quality organic steam
distilled terpenes both soul as well as
in handcrafted and his profiles tonight
Ben is going to talk to us about
terpenes and improving our health
through aromatherapy both width and
without cameras give it up event
[Applause]
so will this dope right into the actual
kind of beat of Everton and that is a
look at the definition of terpenes from
a few different perspectives
I hope feminists would say that terpenes
are aromatic hydrocarbon made of ice
cream and what does that mean I'm gonna
break it down turbines are the largest
most diverse class for ecologies odds
are you smell something and it is a
natural airhead
opponent it is a turkey or it started as
a turkey and integrated into something
else
the difference between a turkey and
turkey noise is subtle but I think
everybody in this room should know what
it is instead ytterbium is produced by a
plant while it's living not to say that
once it's been removed from the plant
all of the chemicals become terpenoids
the terpenoids are oxidized to turkeys
so rather than just being a hydrocarbon
which just doesn't sound means that it's
made just hydrogen and carbon
therapeutic application at that point
different sense continues to be able to
create over time
turkeys are also lipids reflect Mets
which we're all familiar with when it
comes to canvass lipids generally are
hydrophobic and they're unable to
solvent water so the same thing with
marriage proof derbies in all essential
oils you can't just put them in the
water having dissolved you have to make
sure that you have some sort of other
fat based substance that they can so for
something to be called aromatic this is
pretty interesting to me
we'll see what you think it has to
contain at least one benzene ring
benzene is the central structure of
thousands of organic molecules and
composed of six carbon atoms most of the
common psychotropic substances that were
familiar with the containment team
that's betadine FDA lsd-25 mescaline and
all of the cannabinoids as well there's
a CVD is going to even all of their
various formations are also considered
aromatic benzene ring this term was
actually coined because when they
aromatic brother was coined because when
they started looking into terpenes the
chemistry wasn't there for
identification at the time so they
started to notice that a lot of these
scented solvent like compounds also had
sweet and aromatic pleasing smell this
is about 1955 since then the term
aromatic chemistry has been repurposed
and it doesn't actually mean
something that's sin but it means that
it is has a certain structure so just an
important note when it comes to
essential oils just because you hear
that something is aromatic doesn't mean
that necessarily bad smell Terk so their
aromatic hydrocarbons either carbons
means that it's made out of an
arrangement of hydrogen and carbon
molecules be a majority of micro carbons
that are found in earth naturally
occurring crude oil and this is because
decomposed organic plant material
basically in these and there's an
abundance of hydrogen carbon that can be
formed into all sorts of Airy shapes and
chants and then like I said the final
part of that definition is that they're
made of an ice cream and ice cream is a
building altar means are made of
classified by the number of units of
isoprene under made up which for
simplicity's sake you can just remember
means that it's a five carbon molecule
and if it's there's more it's heavier
and if it's heavier it means that it's
going to be less volatile it's going to
stay put you were to fill up some graphs
here but it's not going to necessarily
evaporate quickly so if it has it's a
lighter molecule it's gone
oxygen about already to complete it's a
heavier amount of fuel it's going to
stick around longer it also probably has
a scent that stick around longer so two
three terms three terms of everybody
probably should be
monoterpene monoterpene makes up the
majority of the terpenes that we're all
familiar with
I mean limonene piercing will go kind of
it's more just a moment but those are
all monitor beats they are 10 carbon
atoms it's a little bit confusing money
I think one but just remember in this
case mono means to assess perturb use
which are made up of breathe and are
slightly heavier these different care
for these different classes of terpenes
have different characteristics
monoterpenes tend to be antimicrobial
and antibacterial whereas for instance a
lot of suspects her penis being another
heavier have properties more along black
music pain relieving anti-inflammatory
and the third term just to kind of put
into perspective how many things in the
world are terpenes there's been about
50,000 identified but rather than actual
interview like I said so if monitor
means are two units and Sussman terpenes
our research units rubber is any variety
of proteins that have more than a
hundred units of ice cream
so just so what an aromatherapist might
say about what intermediates yeah and
I've also loved in as consumers into
this aromatherapies the practice of
using aromatics
volatile plant oils for psychological
and physical well-being keep in mind one
one more time
and aromatic doesn't mean that it
necessarily is actually incentive it's
more along the lines of what the
chemical structure says so there's quite
a few more chemicals than we might think
as an aroma therapist might say
scorpions are the building blocks that
collectively come together to form the
essential oils that so many of us are
jointly and just two quick examples
little wolf is found in lavender about
33% acetate and then from the largest
list that I've seen there's 38 to bat
and that kind of seems like to be the
rule of thumb when it comes to the oil
whether it's cannabis or its or it's
Hanks or herbal preparation seems like
there's a couple outliers that really
define the sample and then there's a
multitude of small just as important if
not more important a lot of cases
components that really add that the
other thing that I'll just kind of off
the cuff mention is limiting which can
make up to half of lemon oil and I think
a lot of us are familiar with that it's
used in all sorts of different
commercial products like Google fast
orange any really sort of orange or
citrus scented commercial product so
being that turkeys make up such a large
portion of the
oils and our aromatics as well
cannabinoids as I said a moment ago is
also found in that same price they are
aromatic compound so really that makes
cannabis use aromatherapy by definition
we're using aromatic plant oils for our
psychological and physical well-being so
I don't really think that most of us
think of ourselves as practising around
apparently you know probably all of you
cannabis needs a little bit different
but I think we should really all add
this to our toolbox to be able to say
let's go have some aromatherapy rather
than say let's go stand in a circle up
front or whatever version of that you
want to say it's really acknowledging
the fact of what we do should be
normalized that it's not it's not
druggies so generally I think most
people at least if you were like me
maybe three or four years ago you think
of aromatherapy and I thought he will
inhaling the scented candles or plant
oils without a protocol that without a
methodology really just relying on what
feels good and that's what cannabis
abuse is mostly in our culture today
people consume enough until they feel
good sometimes you go too far but mostly
there's not really at least for myself
until recently there's not much about
protocol or how we consume something
this that's not entirely because data
there hasn't been a label on our
packaging that says these chemicals are
in this in this sample and based on any
other than I can look at it based on
what I know I could say oh I better stop
after one or that that hasn't been
available but it is coming so I'd like
to point out that with in aromatherapy
which has been used for its ink until
about three decades ago there would be
any sort of peer-reviewed research that
shows that aromatherapy practice with
Orion or reason can have great patient
outcomes and I just really want to
encourage everybody in this room to
really look at that we're getting there
we're going to get to standardized
results and that's something that I'm
extremely happy about it's one thing to
I don't want to take away the crap
cannabis I don't want that kind of side
of things that disappear but for people
that are seeking relief I think the
ability to really identify what it is
that they're consuming and come back to
that and purchase it and use it
consistently is the next evolution for
us we especially to grow to grow as a as
a body of people that are that are using
this sort of medicine and really promote
it I think that for us to reach the
greatest number of people we have to
give duplicate results so finally in
this section here we're gonna look at
what like a botanical you wanna stir
beans are what what a biologist might
say and terbium is a biological molecule
sorry organic molecule that produced by
living organisms in order to communicate
with the world around them they are not
produced in cannabis for instance just
because I like Angela's not they're not
there for that they have very specific
roles they are their part they are
manufactured within plants in order to
adapt with the world around them they
certain varieties have progeny and in
parts of the world where there is a
deserving microbial correct there's a
certain fungal spread and because of
this the plant has over time developed
the ability to thrive because of the
essential oil content serving content
that's fun in that plan
turkeys are found in just about every
living organism organism like I said
that includes plants algae fungus
mammals and very brilliant vertebrates
and reptiles there's been over 50,000
the 15,000 of them isolated and I
through google searching and asking out
and thank you
two different university professors that
have specialized with intervenes in
organic chemistry
have not been able to identify a living
organism in this house to stay there
even during all of us and that's because
turkeys are part of the class of
chemicals some of their produced by
living organisms known as hormone
experiments they are to kind of define
those returns real quick a hormone is a
chemical which communicates within an
organism and a pheromone is a chemical
which communicates with other organisms
so you know the Musk that humans create
the scent that all sorts of variety of
mammals leave behind in your yard
those are pheromones and they are
they're potentially containing circuits
in a recent Journal article by the
Netherlands Institute of ecology it was
claimed that serve uses is the most
widely spoken language on the planet and
that's because microbial creatures and
concrete and fungus were found to be
communicating with one another for
germane interaction and that's really
beautiful picture of what tributes are
are actually for the world I think that
being organic living biological
creatures were fortunate to be able to
take advantage of the fact that we can
go and extract or harvest terpenes from
all sorts of plants that really use them
to our benefit but at the end of the day
none of us would be here without
terpenes and none of the bulliest or the
fauna that we really
and get you enjoy as members of this
world would be here without so when it
comes to cannabis Turkey exact
experiments in various ways and I'm
sorry in obvious ways and likely as
formulas as well though I'm not only
familiar those side of cannabis I'm
familiar with what they do externally
and communicating with other things so
their merits and they communicate
externally and they're used as and
defense agent primarily their producing
the greatest value to the trichome notes
although they are found in the breath
and the stems and leaves and they
specifically do things like to thank
books from creditors small microbial
threats or insects are not able to
tolerate your being the same level that
we are they they have solid link
properties and they probably most of you
aren't like me but I've overdone it
orally or another pretty bad chemical
burn in my mouth and I can only imagine
that that's what happens to some sort of
light that's munching down on the wrong
plant for instance they also primarily I
think especially you guys are very
familiar with this the right turning
content can make all the difference in
fighting off a fungal or bacterial
infection you know your powdery mildew
certain varieties do very well it's not
just the terpenes obviously is the
structure and morphology of the plant
foot the right chemical
the right environment really does make
all the difference so in the evolution
of terpenes it's obvious that Pleasant
smells also have have a benefit that
what that really is is that the
predators of herbivores are drawn in by
these Pleasant smells and early humans
is surmised by Robert Clark actually
were brought to the plants and shown
that they were special because of the
scents in the beautiful flowers and
because the turbines also make the
flowers rather unpleasant to consume we
left them alone but we admire them and
our presence can't wait
other mammals that might interfere with
those plants and because the plant
really isn't usable to an early human
until the seeds have been produced
we were Co contributors in allowing
these plants to run their lifecycle to
be pollinated and to progeny seeds so
they completed their mission and then
we've even helped them by picking those
thrashing them against the ground
allowing some of them spread and it's
you know a lot of that had to do with
the pleasant smells that these plants
have so kind of one picture and I think
at a level that most of us can
understand terpenes really as far as the
lifecycle of cannabis have contributed
to the evolution that it seemed so I've
read the
so what one thing that I think is
notable for Kansas consumers is that the
when were consuming cannabis we're not
really getting it as Peter being content
because that plan does not produce
turkey and spring use after its diet as
new uses for them so really about ninety
percent of the way through flour really
you're introduced to the most beautiful
aroma at candis's able to produce
because that plant is screaming to be
minded
you know it's secreting the most amount
of resin so they can capture so the ball
a so they can pull moisture but also so
that I can capture some collagen bring
it itself in and produce those seeds and
that's what it's trying to do the most
amount of terpenes because it's trying
to it's trying to prevent itself late in
season from molding or becoming
susceptible to some sort of other
invasive so I just I think a lot of you
who probably went into a grow room right
after your rights and switched on and
experience this you know you get in
there it's kind of
earthy scented the lights come on 70
degrees hits things start to volatilize
right around there you get the all the
paintings burst balloon Rises you start
getting into some of the citrus notes
and keep going I might get into some of
the earthy tones but very awfully and
things of that nature meaning and the
same thing will be set outside in
hillside and outside bro you go from
those cool mornings when you're out
dragging lines to get water in the
ground and then as it warms up you go
from the cooler the morning to be to the
oral at citrusy in a tiny sense I think
that that's a big part as to why growing
cannabis is so therapeutic we're in the
room with these plants that are
respirating chemicals levels that are
definitely detectable and definitely
therapeutic it is way that putting
essential oils in them to be diffuser in
the back room twist them in this I know
from experience and putting them into a
room like this it really allows people
to loosen up and become a little exudate
and the space where anxiety kind of
melts in you know obviously we all come
from these that were different before
this but I really like to think that we
were consuming the same essence we
really starts us get into a vibe
so that's kind of what I how I would say
that there's three different fields that
really contain the terpenes that were
probably interested in we've got a
biological mechanical
I look we've got a chemical outlook and
we've got a aromatherapy and cannabis
outlook I think I'm a little bit better
answering specific questions on that so
afterwards I think we have any questions
that we move down those paths I never
invite them what I'd like to move on to
right now is the extraction of terpenes
however getting them out of the plants
and kind of then we'll go into what to
do with them so turkeys are extracted by
a few different methods right now it's
primarily done through the reduced
elation of a central way or through the
use of food refuse like for instance the
greatest amount of limiting comes out of
the refuse from orange juice factories
they're cold they're cold-pressed
through the process called expression
basically a spike that presses and it's
really the only turkey that's done like
this and it made me start to think
recently about how rosin is is a very
unique aromatic preparation because
there's not very many plants that are
produced under under pressure for
certain rather everything aromatic oils
that are produced under the expression
technique and the use of pressure in
this in this regard just is unique so
just as just doesn't thought or kind of
looking into why that particular
preparation is unique all these other
processes we're going to go would say
the next one is steam distillation I
think most of you are probably familiar
that basically taking a flask you're
filling with water you're putting plant
material above it the water is passing
through it and it's it's not actually
dissolving the terpenes
because they're oils they're hydrophobic
it's actually it's creating pressure
which is
lifting them off of the plant materials
and then it's going through a cooling
chamber where it then read condenses
into the liquid all down and the water
has separated there is solvent
extraction which produces products known
as absolutes and basically this is the
process that most of us familiar with if
you're making if you're after you're
hanging you've been a natural oil or co2
is kind of on the edge and its own thing
but butane propane ethanol these are all
producing absolutes and basically it's a
process where you're washing plant
material lot of us are familiar with
that and then you've got to remove that
solvent from the final liquid and what's
left over is a different version
instance you know it's not the same
thing as an essential oil which is only
the youth it's mad we can't live didn't
turn me about the plant its got further
phytochemicals that are in there and I
think it's our assumption the cannabis
community just think oh there's there's
more phytochemicals that must mean that
it's better medicine not necessarily the
case absolute primary generally are not
used for consumable products just
because they can't have leftover
solvents in them and it's it's it's just
not quite as messes and then what my
company primarily relies on is backing
this delicious which is very similar to
steam distillation but we're doing it at
lower temperatures and under vacuum oh
so you're taking that same last where
and you're putting it under vacuum
you're suddenly after the atmosphere out
of it through removing the oxygen so
that the boiling temperatures go down
because these are volatile chemicals
both than the heat they expand when they
expand when they come back the molecule
is distorted it might begin to oxidize
there's a variety of different chemical
reactions that happen depending on what
were working with and what the vacuum
distillation allows you to do is to use
less energy just to distort that
molecule less in order to get it to
travel up that path come back down and
then I was actually a surprise with mass
nobody tonight who does this method of
turning or rather an essential oil
extraction it's not primarily used in
terpenes but it is used in essential
oils and I think would just be good for
everybody to know how far we come I
actually think of vacuum distillation
often it's like space necessary because
we are removing the atmosphere we're
literally doing an experiment that could
not be done on the surface of Earth
without that pumps and highly advanced
equipment invested so that the original
form of the extraction was actually hot
for us which is taking which I might get
corrected every business evening which
is taking animal fats flavoring plant
material in them and because it because
terpenes are limits because the animal
fat you're able to get intervenes to
dissolve into the animal bath and then
basically just continually continually
layer layers of plant material by
replacing it and kind of give this this
rich fatty essential oil preparation
yeah it's not something that I
particularly find it's not something I
would necessarily
you see life but it is just kind of a
picture you know people did whatever
they could at beginning of kind of
modern era of getting these oils into a
format and they found that that fat
would do it and it was worth so I kind
of touched on what my company does that
we create a quick rundown on what that
looks like we will take it as simple of
particular interest and we will send it
to a canvas lab if we're trying to get a
quick result or we will send a tan for
me and left they work with the company
that's at the University of Indiana
actually was founded them then they kind
of separated this bunch of guys from
there then they separated out started a
company and because their human lab and
they built this specific library for
their GCMs gas chromatography mass
spectrometry they are able to identify
more individuals than any other lab in
America and maybe the world at this
point
and that's good because more data allows
us to get closer to a profile
yeah and niceness so-and-so will
basically send it off for a report and
they basically sent us back a recipe it
says in this sample of oil that you
mailed to us we have down the list
generally we're getting somewhere
between fifteen eighty hits from this
particular lab there's a lab in
Vancouver Canada that's able to do over
250 but it's extremely expensive
processing you've got wait why am I
getting so with that data we don't even
have a lot of components to actually be
able to redo it so any things to be
about the ones that I actually see it's
giving us a lot of great results that
are also kind of cost effective energy
state market so we're getting this
recipe we take from our isolated stock
intervenes we've rebuilt the profile
it takes some because we're not
identically replicating the process it
takes some trial and error to actually
be able to produce something that we can
sell out into the market that's you or
myself or anybody could take add to
distillate add the CEO to you and get a
product I think like we provide a recipe
for
profile as to how much you should use
them in concentration pretty
straightforward so the application of
terpenes and product development like I
said there's there's taking trip
products that are devoid of terpenes
like distillate reintroducing a profile
of your favorite of your choice what we
really encourage people to do and what
we work off those whenever were able to
with those canvas lab samples is we try
to reproduce the flower grow bottle
rather than the profile and extract or a
distillation specifically because in you
know my experience in cannabis medically
in kind of an overwhelming majority on
the community obviously this is exactly
exactly so they wanted and they wanted
you to say exactly but you can't really
get flowers so we really try to recreate
the profiles as if I'm a flower and then
because of that it gives people the
ability to concentrate it and they like
to think it needs more
double up you'd be closer to an extract
for a bottle in a row so I kind of
making a quick shift here I want to just
point out a couple things that people
could do at home pretty easily all the
components that I'm going to talk about
are available on our website you give me
a call and said we're here I'll give you
a real good deal experience it so addict
terpenes first two aromatherapy diffuser
Zhai think is one of the easiest things
that you can do at her business or at
home we put them in our accuser every
night before we go to bed and you know
if you think about it a lot of these a
lot of these compounds have all of these
visual properties that were suggesting
or anti-inflammatory they are bacteria
like Romeo there by fungal and it's it's
my thought that getting them in our
environment frequently can lead to
better basically putting something
that's antibacterial into the air in
your bedroom you know what does that do
overtime to your he'll never lose that
sort of thing so aromatherapy diffuser
'he's extremely easy to use one of my
favorite things to do is to take beta
terry awfully medicare at Leena's the
terpene that is in black peppercorns and
cloves primarily it's a success which
hurt me and it's heavy it's spicy and I
like to combine it with olive oil or
coconut oil in either a one-to-one all
the way up to like one one part baby
periodically five parts olive oil
formulations kind of
is the most rapidly anti-inflammatory
substance that I've ever encountered
I've read things that say it's 300 times
more anti-inflammatory the traffic
aspirin I didn't come up with this I
actually have Asia out of Texas the
gentleman that has he's a quadriplegic
basically said you know over the last
thirty years I've used every single
available topical treatment to work on
the phantom limb pains that I that I
deal with and nothing has ever worked
for me there's that nothing as you know
things that have worked I've taken time
and he said basically from about two
minutes in from using the substance he
was he went from having like a knife
digging through his skin to really just
being needed healing healing just
pressure but not the feeling pain and
uses it still to this day give him a
really good deal kind of just to keep up
with us and giving us feedback on it but
it's a very easy preparation is one of
the early things that I
we first met that I think really
impressed him another thing that I hear
from a lot of our clients is using
limiting or per gastro esophageal reflux
disease or you know basically you're
calming your Commons acid reflux or
indigestion it is pretty simple but I've
been told by people again I'm not a
health care professional but what I've
been told by people is three five drops
add to a glass of water consumed before
a meal and then basically it's people
are placing another thing that a lot of
people are using right now that I find
an interest is they're using geranium
which is if you wanted to take a common
phrase rephrase it you would say take
time in life to stop and smell the
cranial it's the primary serving that's
funny roses this substance is being used
diluted in water and sprayed on golf
courses in Florida right now
one of my largest clients as a specific
pesticide to keep insects off of the
greens I don't I've looked at so there's
a couple of set asides that are made for
the Kansas industry right now that are
using turbines and all of them have to
raining all this to disturb my merry
active degree
so that would give that for people
looking to and then kind of going back
to limiting what a lot of people use it
for as I mentioned earlier is or
increasing things whether that's
cleaning the kitchen or their hands
after doing some auto where that sort of
thing a organic means moving by itself
uncut is one thing that you want to make
everybody aware of is that limiting is
photosynthesize since tighten it so if
you are putting it on your skin directly
and I would really highly advise
avoiding the Sun right because you can
get burnt very very easy it enhances the
effects of UV and formatic we got very
very severe burst of someone be careful
sure alright so fun time I'm going to
ask Shane going to be again here right
whether it's showing people your kit or
just having acknowledged really identify
things I'm gonna share just real briefly
usually this is we have attendance what
published literature and my own
experience to say about each one of
these terpenes and basically I'd like
you to take it out to know about
business these are the terms that are
taught in the greatest quality but they
are not necessarily the terpenes that
contribute the most amount of smelt and
he's one particular strength so the
example that I would use as my company
makes a blue cheese replica it doesn't
smell and as an adverb you can call the
next America has this absolutely acid is
less than a tenth of a percent less than
100 percent the entire profile but it is
overwhelming and the first thing that
will smell another Turkey is similar to
that metal door cabinet which is mystery
and
so keep in mind small small bodies can
have great dramatic effects and they
also contribute greatly to the actual
therapeutic effects so when it comes to
meetings more is not everything I sell
food great so we'll start with your seat
it's gonna have an orange label on and
I'm going to so you're seeing as a
monitor view it is 13 to 20 feet it's an
aroma that is suggestive of hops and
clothes and proper vetting its regular
botanical sources are hops
I'm lemongrass basil and Bailey's it's
the most dominant turkey in common
circulating strains of cannabis and
that's partly due to as we all know many
of us know the drug war we require that
we drive up the THC in order to get the
least amount of drugs out there the
greatest bang for their buck and steep
hill Labs defines any strength with over
0.5 percent by volume you're seen as an
industry and of anybody's titled it here
but many people have been led to believe
that mangoes contain a large amount of
you're seeing a notable amount I found
analysis which goes over 20 varieties of
mangoes and they found one at most in
one 3.86 milligrams of Nursing whereas
even middle-of-the-road varieties of
cannabis my two milligrams per gram
so what that's not to say that using
that mangoes don't get you higher but
it's really probably more of an
entourage effect because there's quite a
bit of terminally in mangoes there's
also yeah so there's not your scene
mangoes its mangoes are an incredible
botanical source of variety turkeys so
the next one is going to be cycle day on
the carpet I can see it you're seeing is
gonna reduce pain and inflammation it's
highly sedative right now my company's
playing around with a sleep aid that
isn't here than you're seeing
multiplying into the substance that
makes it much more by order I have not
next up we have a couple couple test
subjects from the clinic that I met that
suffer from severe pain and insomnia and
you can easily knock them all out you
don't wake up you don't wake up with any
sort of after lingering effects and it's
you know it's actually kind of
pleasant-tasting SOI 6 also I've been
looking good there will be producing
something along those lines and just so
kind of look out with that it's also
who'd elevated just like most terpenes
are the next let's go to be limiting
limiting is also a monitoring it should
be in there with a green label it is
fresh and sweet and citrusy clean we've
all experienced mr. bean in our
household cleaners a lot of people are
quick to say
limiting as a solvent it's in hospital
consume I'm just saying that limonene is
an incredible organic compound has a
wide variety of uses primarily as well
because there's no evidence that shows
that it is a stimulant but it is against
clinic that reduces the anxiety and the
way that I really picture is that it
allows you to take all that energy that
you would use on a stress or some of it
and you're you're not only saving that
and here able to do that put it towards
other life processes so it is mood
elevating and stress relieving its
focusing and it's got a wide application
like I said
gastrointestinal or it's also having
anti-inflammatory it's been used to
dissolve all stones political settings
there's a couple studies that show
outside of the human body that it
destroys breast cancer cells and it
affects cell permeability so a presence
of beer scene allows other
phytochemicals to actually break through
the blood-brain barrier and take effect
at a greater dramatic next one
prevailing interview it's fresh neural
is sweetened piney when I smell that
I've smelled like and it is sourced from
Apple's human Lila tea tree and - it is
very popular in the United States refuse
and flavors and fragrances is heavily
used in soaps and detergents the
permission to cancer cells as well it's
the state specifically suggest that my
down-regulating specific proteins
terminally help slow the spread of
breast cancer it's scented and calming
and also an antioxidant and one quick
note that I just wanna make is that
there is quite a bit more information
about each one
on our website and also the things that
I'm saying about these are the textbook
answers now your anecdotal experience
and that's a realistic story that one
particularly is from groceries next one
we help is red label help ie is pretty
incredible it's definitely the top of my
list
it's earthy plenty sharp flavor to it
it's sourced from coniferous trees
rosemary and sage it's also founded a
couple varieties of citrus
anti-inflammatory and acts as a
bronchodilator I think when I first
heard this I have five is silly but then
I've met so many people that use it you
know we've heard candles we've been
present and I think that it's the
strains high amounts of all tiny ivenna
created with that as far as
pharmacologically it's great when pain
inflammation it's one of the few
terpenes that has to do stimulant
properties it's also good for focusing
[Music]
so our company is always done because
there really isn't any complaining whole
standalone isolated turkey we've always
looked at is what is the highest amount
that we could find in a gram of cannabis
so in the six that were looking at right
now but really say it's really were kind
of self-discovery I think the next one
is going to be baby carry ethylene so up
until this point everything that we've
discussed has been a monoterpene baby
carry athlete as a secretary and just to
remind you that's a heavier molecules if
you were to you know the consistency of
all the ones that we felt up until now
you find that they're rather thin they
leave us like you can screw the top on
that doesn't have that vanilla top on
that little cone inside of it and they
will leak their way out of it because
definitely each other in silicone most
herpes is oh don't be a baby really very
nice a light green label also that that
particular beam is sweet and spicy it's
actually sourced from black pepper
caraway clove Mouse basil oregano
it's notable because it's the only
biomechanoid that's found in nature
outside of the cannabis family it acts
the cb2 receptors which i think many
people have probably heard that black
pepper and cumin come together to make a
new plant or a combination I think you
mean you're expert right thing and
that's very often you coming together
create a synergistic powerful so bakery
awfully like a center they are massively
anti-inflammatory relatively safe or
topical from everything that I've been
able to read and I used a lot of it's a
plate so I would say that so far I
personally have a Kennedy negative
reacted with it obviously there are
applying oils Papa please you're gonna
want to put that on a very small portion
of your skin wait to see what happens
for a couple days before you dive into
that and really you know with essential
oils and mr. Bean's it's not so much a
single application that might get you
but it's the application over the course
of maybe 30 days just make sure that
you're not doing that
definitely yourself time to observe what
happens in their label lines they're
known to spend another kind of label
it's a model chirping it's floral
attempt got kind of a spicy sweet
overtone on it it's sourced from a
variety of plants primarily those the
mint family and then also baby and pours
lab near lilac and I said earlier little
itself makes up the stimulus blacks the
stimulus that causes us pain under a
logical level studies have shown ins
have linked it to decreased depression
symptoms which is likely due to the fact
that amplifies serotonin receptor
transmission so it's got a pain and
depression kind of cover there which it
also touches on inflammation
as well as highly scented and that's the
kid I really want everybody to use it as
they let's see miss I'll survive with
device ready to take one of my cards off
the back and give me feedback
how are you using on the website I'm
working on a very similar building
[Music]
so we take the connections so he said
what is the relationship of Dean's
display the first thing I think is just
fascinating that I think we're all many
of us are Isleta that we think flavonoid
explain it but it's actually that black
and white lattice is is Latin before
yellow and it is the fact that that flat
interaction pigments that color plants
and so it's not that flavonoids are so
much related with the flavor of things
they're just another classic white a
chemical that's found a lot of plants
contribute to all sorts of varieties of
memory a therapeutic benefit but don't
have any new flavor so it's not really
so much that being said
variety of different we were in there I
understand various ones get the last
[Music]
just providing nice lips for kind of
like starting then you move into the
profiles and I ask myself the same
questions what I really came up with is
people are making products they are they
are in this marketplace right now
they're taking THC digital era co3
they're putting it into a big planet for
sylveon and they need to cut it
something and if I don't sell them sure
beans and they're using maple they're
using all sorts of varieties of
propylene glycol MCT which has very
little very little therapeutic value if
not detrimental value where's that so
really you're absolutely right you know
we're talking about
some of the smaller smaller percentages
are actually having a career request
that suggested it's all based on the
ratio of a draft so so you know also the
ratio to entertain small animal reserve
that's order of magnitude complexity to
figure out how those things yeah so so
we're talking to us incredibly
fascinating thank you but but you know
combining that with some of our global
so yeah no I appreciate you is I think
one of the benefits of what we do I'm
not an expert to make this determination
but what I found fascinating for myself
is learning above what the terpenes that
we do have access to actually do to me
like having access to very op I need
opens up my lungs rapidly so that's
something that we also really fixated on
is learning how individual components
affect you obviously like you said
thickness on fragile there's the
symphony and these minor components
matter and that's really what we're in
the race to discover and one porous I
will right now we work with everything
be natural but to really recreate
everything the material at least for us
self-discovery purpose I think
later
[Music]
there are people that are able to go in
the universities and we haven't be done
Thank You quickness I wanted to support
I think what you're saying what I hear
you saying is you're producing products
they're allowing people to
they replicate which is an option for
medications right and that even though
you're distilling some of these certain
complex whole plant formulations down to
simpler combinations right much can be
said for the benefit of using aspirin as
opposed to creating a teacher or from
willow bark baby aspirin works willow
bark might work better for certain in
certain situations but I guess my
question is so I think it's great kind
of closes what were you're doing since
and I think help that locations
tremendously have that consistent
effective and reliable medication I am
wondering how far along you guys are in
terms of determining whether some of
them were limited combinations for
specific applications when you say
limited do you mean racing mountains
yeah well no like instead of 18 to make
sure you know
oh so that how many we're putting into
our blends basically yeah let's like
whatever 30 to 50 up to right now so
right now we sell 23 different blends
released another six next week and
depending on which stream that was you
know some
[Music]
to lend them I mean aromatherapy looks
at holes
we come back better so listen I know we
could do questions on like we really do
to wrap up now thank you