everybody was really surprised and and
some like me pleasantly when when we
found out that your your new book was
not going to be another soil science
book I mean we all loved the original
trilogy and we're all waiting for
something new from you and then and then
you you know tell me an emerald-cut
ah the new book is otto flower which
which caused me to decide that I want to
do you know this whole year of auto
flower programming but for you you know
what inspired you to choose you know
auto flower and cannabis plants as your
new topic and and would you share with
us that you know a bit about your new
book sure interesting question
you know I am oriented towards the
science stuff and I actually as I was
thinking last night and I have another
one of those coming but in the back of
my mind I see some other stuff but this
one was totally out of the blue
first of all writing a book is a painful
experience for me and all I love doing
it and I'm happy that I do it and it's
what I love to do it's painful you have
to go into a rabbit hole and stay down
there and you have to organize
everything in that rabbit hole so nobody
will touch it and then when you have to
come up for something with the wife you
know you got to get out of that rabbit
hole all the way and you don't want to
because you forget we put stuff in
everything so I swear every something I
would never write another book again
it's that people experience even though
I love it and so my wife was gone and I
was tending some auto flowers and I said
to myself you know this isn't nice to me
I'm gonna write the book and I sat down
and in a week while she was gone because
that's the only way I can really do it I
wrote a book you know wasn't the best
thing in the world by oh my god
she this enough here for a book I think
this might work and I really think we
need to spread the word about these
things and I realized that as I wrote it
it wasn't a book that I was writing for
you
or myself even I was reading this book
for people like my mother who grow
tomatoes and you know would love the
idea of a brand new plant that they'd
never heard of before and commercial
growers have never I'm so surprised the
reaction is something we want to talk
about as well but so here's a plant that
that nobody's heard of before brand-new
it's the same size as this tomato plant
it grows during the same season as a
tomato plant you can also grow it
indoors like it tomato plant basically
you take care of it exactly like it to
me it's good to share like a tomato oh
my god share like crazy it's it has
trichomes like a tomato plant and and
everything you know about Tomatoes
applies to this thing a couple of things
you have to learn different flowers
obviously two different kinds of flowers
as opposed it tomato you have to learn
how to handle that kind of stuff but wow
this is a plant that anybody can grow
and so the book really evolved put a lot
of history in the of where cannabis came
from you know to explain landraces which
I think people need to understand
because we're going back getting some of
that genetics into the system explain
the chemistry of the cannabinoid system
a little teeny bit explain that it's not
sativa can you know sativa indica
anymore it's all about flavonoids
cannabinoids and all that great stuff
mixed together talk about the needing
means of this stuff how it all got to be
where it is and certainly how to grow
this stuff and then words are going in
the future because I think there is a
spectacular future this plan I really do
believe that once the stigma goes away
from cannabis and it is disappearing
quickly I read today that all but three
states have something to do with
legalizing cannabis all for three
politic well in such a short period yes
that that stigma aside you said earlier
in your answer you said you know if
there's something worth to be said about
the reaction of professional ornamental
growers to the arrival of Canada what
are you nuts in well you know all of a
sudden even the nurseries that grow you
know they're going is a begin to think
hey wait a minute now of course we don't
have a license and everything else but
but but this is a plant people can grow
at home we should be selling it but now
lots of places you are not even sure
even Washington State you're allowed to
buy plants and for a while thing you
were allowed to grow them well you still
can't grow them in Washington yeah yeah
and then I know in New York State there
they're talking about legislation when
they're thinking about being they're
growing their plants whoa whoa whoa whoa
this is a plant couldn't shake it so so
I think this book has been this first of
all a lot of people who've never heard
of this plan you know they they're
waking up even commercial growers of
cannabis have never heard of an auto
flowering in cannabis think that's any
good I think once people start to see
that this is a regular plant the stigma
starts to fall tea is just like a tomato
we don't limit people growing tomato
plants why are we limiting you know what
do you mean I'm not allowed to grow this
plant it's legal I can buy it in a store
and I'm not allowed to grow it so I
don't know that stuff's gonna change I
think this is them this is the
thing that's gonna stimulate this
auto-fire well anything that we can do
to normalize right that's a big win and
and I think that for Otto flowers a lot
of folks you know just like early
feminized seeds right mean you don't
want to use feminized seeds to breed so
they and they're for particular types of
growing people but I think Otto flower
is the same way some of the early stuff
was a little sketchy and and but but the
new wave of Otto flowers are just like
out of this world they are out of this
world then it's so it's too gotten to
the point where you want the seeds
because it's that good yeah oh my god I
can make this even better my breeding
and so so I think you know we'll find a
lot of it that will not be feminized and
I noticed that a lot of the companies
are selling non feminized water flowers
which can this is so much fun
you know when you think about it you get
your tomato plant you look at at the end
of the season you go boy this was a
really good time I would save the seeds
for this particular water put it early
or whatever whatever it might taste
different surgery you know you might
breed it with another one stick you know
Russian you know it's just so easy to do
this is the same kind of plant and I
think people who are in the gardening
they don't want to just stick something
in the ground that they buy at a nursery
they want to start it from seed first of
all you're not real gardener unless you
start up from seed they want to start a
from seed and they want to play with it
this is their hobby well this is a hobby
planet if we ever saw one and we know
that because we've grown the bigger kind
the little kinds are every bit as much
as a hobby even more so because they
grow so quickly so you have a specific
particular kind of disease someone says
see why don't you turn this kind of Otto
flower you grow it you improve it you're
growing your own medicine truly in seven
eight nine weeks Wow pretty amazing
so what's happening and that's why I
wrote the book because I think everyday
gardeners are really going to get it
into this plant not for the THC not for
the CBD just because it's a fun plant to
grow and then then within that you find
the parts you want right yeah so the
book comes out in October this year 2019
you can pre-order it now and the link to
it on Amazon is in the first description
so Jeff thank you so much for taking all
this I don't know those songs with the
singers everything else you know they
compete in it they give that a little
mouse button in the background that guy
goes but don't forget the other ones you
bet yeah totally whoo and make sure you
pick up the trilogy and the trail inks
to the trilogy is in the soil science
trilogy or in the first description as
well thank you for taking all this time
to do this shaping fire session with me
I'm a huge fan and it's great to be lab
this time with you well are you so my
lawyers and I thank you for having me
for fabulous
you