so this next question is a manufacturing
question because you know I know that
you have hunted terpenes and done big
sips your whole life and you know the
value of a really good terpene right and
so when it comes to extraction you know
almost all of us lean towards really
clean whole plant cannabis extractions
to get our chirps but if you're making
edibles and you want to add some
terpenes to that the price point doesn't
make sense to do cannabis extracted all
the time and so so you've got different
levels of terpene both extraction
processes and whether or not their
cannabis sourced or whether or not
they're there food source and a lot of
folks get confused you know they'll just
bash one or the other without
understanding that when you are trying
to design a product to bring it to the
mass market yeah it can't just be cool
it has to work on the spreadsheet as
well so when you are helping your
clients think through what level and
what source of terpene to choose you
know how do you help them think through
that challenge you when it comes to that
that's just pure business because once
we start to say we're gonna go from
whole plant full extract to where we're
gonna do crude distillate added turps it
becomes how much what's the price point
of the product that's going to get sold
downstream and we have to go all the way
backwards through the chain to figure
out what do you have to sell it for it
in order to be profitable and with with
these questions before we're always done
with like don't anybody talk about the
dirty product we're going to put in
right but now with testing no matter
what it has to be clean and so I don't
have any issue with with plant derived
Terps because fundamentally for me
people people that have little money
shouldn't be precluded from using
cannabis and so if all they can afford
is bulk cannabis that was cleanly
extracted and then someone like Ben from
true terpenes who does some really nice
work who's about it he lays you out a
floral pattern that is red
shann you consume it you go by that's
beautiful and it's way more affordable
than steam distilled Terps that you
derived or you did closed-loop and you
pull them off and put them back in if
that's not your price point that's not
your price point but if your price point
is that and that's what you're selling
then that's what you focus on I think
that the fight you hear so much is
because each individual believes that
their system is what works best for them
and it does but it doesn't it doesn't
diminish either or they're two radically
different worlds and you just have to
understand why you're doing it and
what's the end goal and what is the
price that it's going to sell for and
when you when you look at it like that
it becomes a question you asked your
accountant so you sit down with your
accountant what kind of trips can I
afford can't afford and what is my real
margin on the sale and when it starts to
become too low to be profitable you know
that you can't do that that's just an
emotional response that's something you
would do for yourself privately for your
own stash but you definitely can't sell
it like that and so I don't see any
issue with any of the different
formulations because really what it does
is it allows you to deal with the
reality of income you have people who
make very little who are in pain and
could use homeopathic pain relief they
have psychological issues either
depression or anxiety and they can use
certain forms of cannabis to either
increase or decrease these things why
should they be precluded from consuming
when they can't afford the greatest farm
growing product ever done that's just
not fair the supermarket has food for
all people I think cannabis has always
historically been for all people and so
with the advent of technology it allows
you to be able to drop the cost of
production dramatically well that
doesn't mean that that it changes
everyone's reality but it allows you to
cover a large spectrum of the lower-cost
portions I don't and and as we go
forward there is a difference no derived
package
complete as the natural package and I
just know this from as a consumer that I
play with all of them and I don't care
which one I play with if that isn't
pulled off directly from the from the
varietal because the Terps and the
cannabinoids is a union you you you're
trying to take something apart trying to
deconstruct something and then say look
this is the important part the rest of
it wasn't there the reality is it's a
synthesis it's a it's a homogenous mix
the plant created all these things in
some form for some reason it has it in
its genealogical background to produce
these things how do they interrelate
we're not smart enough to know yet and
when we start to think with that smart
we already know we're going the wrong
way because this is too complex a
molecular equation so you have to just
say for whatever reason for reasons
unknown these things seem to be best in
this form and that's the people who can
discern that and afford it and when the
education is present then people will
know look is a reason why we pay a
higher price for this because of the
subtleties but for people who don't have
the money I don't see anything wrong
with a crude that's been cleaned and
derived terms that have been applied
just don't apply them so heavy you
creating a solvent that night my problem
with adding Terps back into mixes is
that they're going so heavy with the
turfs to create this unbelievably turf
experience that people forget that it's
a solvent especially limonene and so
you're adding all this citrus into your
product to get this incredible
monoterpene explosive grabbing hungry I
want more but we don't know what it does
to the lungs and so you want to make
sure that you're really trying to keep
it within some range and balance that's
been here because we've had so little
medical damage done to people using from
cannabis use that I believe and I talked
to Ben the same thing we both believe
that as they start to turn these dials
we'll see changes in how people are
affected by it and both in cannabinoid
levels which are unusually high and
interpret levels that are unusually high
and so we don't really have any R&amp;D on
that we're the guinea pigs and we'll
know as we go forward but to me you
as long as you turn those back to
realistic so that you're not trying to
make someone believe hey my manufactured
product that's accentuated is definitely
better than the real product cuz the
numbers are higher they may be but
they're radically different and subtlety
and experience and experience of the
smoker will determine it and money will
allow you to make those fine choices
it's like the difference between a
really high-end whiskey and a low-end
whiskey they both whiskey you drink a
bottle of it you're gonna know you drink
a bottle of whiskey and one of them is
absolutely alive in the mouth and the
other one is a little less so who can
afford the qualities and they'll be the
same here
Yeah right cool thank you