so another question I want to ask you is
that you know lots of different strains
are being extracted now at all different
levels of expertise but one thing that
we're seeing more and more are people
who are extracting flowers and the
terpene profile or in the enjoyment
level of the final extraction doesn't
taste like the original flower a good
example from it for that is Washington
skunk right was involved with a run
recently where you know the the
Washington skunk itself it had you know
the you know the kind of alcohol esters
and the skunk enos that we all loved but
when it was concentrated it tastes like
burnt rubber and it was like it was a
clean professional extraction so it
wasn't like there was anything wrong
with the extraction but the the hint of
that burnt rubber that's in those skunk
strains when you took it when a flower
it was it was nice at that density but
then when you extract it suddenly it
tasted dis pleasurable and so we made
back hash out of some of it and it had
the same experience so so when you
remove the plant material and you really
hit on those notes it became something
that people were first suspicious about
smoking because it tasted like burn
rubber but then when we realized it was
just legit the terpenes that were in it
um you know no one wanted to buy they
would choose something else so for
people who are strategizing what flower
to set up to extract how do you how
would you approach that that that
challenge of the final product not
tasting like like your your your origin
flower you know the only way that you
can do this is you have to really look
at a development cycle for outdoor
farmers it's basically a year so you
have to look into next season so every
year we would test a number of varietals
and see what we liked and then have them
blown in some small capacity so we could
say did this transfer and the way we had
hoped because you'll smell things and
you'll be like mmm that's fascinating
out
could increase some of this intensity it
would be highly attractive and so
sometimes you hit it head-on and you
pull out these wonderful notes and tones
that you could barely detect and then
other times you intensify components
that become undesirable and the only way
that you can determine that to me
personally in terms of how the
individual determines it is through
testing where you grow it you run it you
determine is there a value if there's a
value you commit next year I don't think
cannabis fluctuates so quickly in a
bigger market people like distrained is
your but the reality is it's it's
profiles that kind of hold for time and
for the farmers what they want to be
able to do is do the testing to find
varietals that work for them on their
farm location cultivation techniques
skill level and then determine where did
it shine and so for me certain flowers
like skunks look like for me chasing
skunk the skunk project is really about
smokeable and joint form for people in
my age group who still know how to roll
cannabis and that way what could happen
is individuals will want to experience
in that way to find out what is the
attraction to it but I knew that once
you get into skunks you weren't going to
have the the extraction capabilities
because of the fuels and the esters that
were you're going to lose a lot of these
subtleties that mask some of these other
dominant flavors that are aggressive so
burnt rubber in the joint is really neat
but when you intensify it it's not
enough effect is edgy and hard and so
depending on what you're trying to do
and I think most farms really need to
diversify their product lines in a sense
of what works well for you as a farmer
on your property and then what do you
believe your sales market is and that's
really doing the research on what is
moving in the market in general and then
breaking up your distributions to match
that and so you I'm gonna grow all three
roles that's dangerous I'm gonna grow
all extract that's dangerous you want to
be able to put yourself in a stratified
market with those different positions
that you're taking and I think that
the individuals who are doing it if
there have been successful with selling
cannabis they have an ability to
determine this and if they're not they
should get a hold of somebody that they
know who sells cannabis that has a good
palate that says this is something that
people would like or it wouldn't and
that way what it does it allows you to
make the correct decisions but for me
it's a full-year a cyclical time I'm
into our guys it's going to be you know
every two and a half three months so
indoor can allow you to do a much
quicker cyclical run and if you can work
with people that are doing indoor it
lets you see the subtleties of how your
flower will respond but ultimately it's
going to be what it's going to be where
you put it and it's going to pick up the
environmental changes meaning the impact
of the environment on the cannabis
flower and it's gonna pick up what
you're using to grow it and so if you
model it exactly well then you get the
exact same result but when you start to
do it under different lighting different
nutrient changes it changes the profile
in the mouth but it lets you get kind of
close and so the ability to use indoor
tools to help you narrow the scope of
what you're trying to grab and then you
take those cultivars that you sifted
into a smaller population bring them to
your location and say hey these shine
here and they work now we know it works
the creme brulee cut that I like to work
with there's been a couple years in
operation of first we sifted it out out
of a big population and then we took a
look at it and said what happens when
you run it live and then once we found
out what it did live we committed to run
a farm live or a good portion of the
farm so it was a multi-year process
because I know that when you get
something that's exceptional in terms of
how you perceive it
you can go out of bold that quickly good
is good and there's all these little
micro trends but ultimately people want
things that have a quality and that
quality is just real and if you can
satisfy that then you have a couple
years of stability and I think farmers
need to work on that concept more than
every year I have to be red-hot because
you'll never match that trend you'll
always really be behind it when trends
are pop and people are setting them
anybody who's not setting it shouldn't
follow it until it becomes developed and
what am i lawyer tell me it's better be
the leading edge than the bleeding edge
and so I think that that's how you
really approach it I think that really
points to the importance of if you
really want to make a great product
allow yourself the product development
cycle to do it I mean so many people
they're in a rush to get them to market
because they need to get revenue or to
satisfy to investors so they need to
make their house payment you know
whatever it is a lot of people are
rushing product to market and they
haven't done a short run to make sure
it's a properly like they just assume
and then they jump ahead people are
doing this with packaging now too but
but if you want to make something
excellent stretch out that product
development process and have a clear
idea what is you're trying to do you
know you if you look at Apple when
and Jobs came back to Apple they were
they had hundreds of ideas that he
looked at and he narrowed it down to
basically iPhone iPod he cut out we cut
everything out what those things and he
said everybody focused these are the
things that have a validity that have a
reality and I have the ability to say
that I think this will work from my
prior history and so you have to be able
to honestly ask yourself do you have
that vision in your field so obviously I
know nothing about electronics but in
cannabis I I feel that I understand the
market well enough to say this is
something that is not that attractive
and I don't see the value and this is
something that I believe is highly
attractive and I see the value and that
way it allows you now to figure out how
do we optimize it because it took us
another year to figure out the picking
time at the creme brulee because the
first year we took it about five or six
days later than I took it the year this
at the subsequent year and they were
different profiles one of them was
sharper harder less aromatic and then
when we picked it a little bit earlier
we dialed in the curve a little bit less
than perfect on the flower resulted in a
far more active concentrate live and
that's where I found the sweet spot and
that sweet spot is you just honestly to
yourself into your crew that you work
with let's just do product test and say
are we satisfied and are we satisfied
and why are we satisfied and do we think
it could be better or do we think we it
could be worse and that way you start to
honestly shape this process because a
lot of it is you just want to feel good
and you want to say we do great but a
lot of times you have to say you know I
don't think this is what we wanted and
then you have to take another cycle to
dial it and if you can't then you
realize that's what it is
and with breeders you know they might go
down the road two or three years on a
line and realize that there's nothing
here they have to go all the way back
and go down another road and that
dedication to it over time is I think
where you get the success in a stability
of a product because what you do is you
really find stuff that resonates with
the customer that works well for you if
they don't intersect you're you're
really gonna do poorly
the customer loves it but you can't grow
it at your property and you love to grow
it but no one wants to buy it neither
one of those extremes work there has to
be some little Venn diagram in the
middle where it touches and and that's
the part of R&amp;D that's needed that you
really connect grow ability work ability
sell ability