so Ethan you know you've spoken for
years about your vision of the future
where people are growing specialty kima
bars that are being grown with a terpene
mix and a cannabinoid mix that are
specifically for different types of
patients and that with you know a little
bit time and a lot of effort we would be
able to get to these custom cultivars
for these for these different patients
but of course the the cannabis industry
right now is kind of going in another
way at the same time which is moving
towards distillates and and and and
terpenes and kind of putting them
together in kind of a cocktail and
trying to customize cannabis medicine
for patients that way as somebody who i
know is very much into whole plant what
are your thoughts on trying to get to
those goals of customized cannabis
medicine through dinner isolates instead
of through growing whole plants in in
one plant well to me that approaches a
little bit backwards it is clear that
the cannabis plant has a very plastic
genome this is a way of saying that you
can make it do anything if you take the
time to selectively breed it for
specific components and combinations
that you want this has been amply
demonstrated that's always going to be
better in contrast we have the situation
now where many people are producing CBD
isolates they they might use a hemp
source for example and they realize that
on the world market they can get forty
dollars a gram for this material but we
know that many patients with a severe
seizure disorder would go through that
in a day it's also been amply
demonstrated that CBD alone although
it's a great medicine for severe
epilepsy for schizophrenia we could do
the same thing probably a lot better
with
much lower doses of CBD when it's in
combination with its other natural
friends let's say the other components
in cannabis so a little bit of THC with
a bigger amount of CBD is good for very
many conditions there was recently a
meta-analysis this is a situation in
which someone reviews the literature and
crunches all the numbers from multiple
studies together to create an overall
impression so fabbrizio pamplona did
this in relation to a comparison between
CBD is a pure drug versus CBD as an
extract in treatment of severe epilepsy
what they found was that although there
could be comparable levels of efficacy
that it would work for seizures about
the same the doses required for the CBD
extracts with other components included
were about 20% of what was required with
CBD alone and the side effects were much
lower because at very very high doses in
combination with other drugs CBD can
produce some drug drug interactions that
you just don't see at the lower doses
when it's a whole plan of medicine so
that's a factor now what about the
situation of using either a pure
cannabinoid or a cannabis extract and
then adding terpenoids from an outside
source well I I'm really against this
first it's often done with synthetic
terpenoids from chemical producer that
were never designed for human
consumption
and they might be 95% pure but we don't
know if I percent is important yeah it
could be we don't know what it is and
what its potential toxicity could be
additionally we don't know that it's
going to be the same stereoisomer that
cannabis produces
molecules have three-dimensional
structures and if it's turned the wrong
way if it's the mirror image it can have
a totally different effect it can smell
different it can have different effects
in the brain or other parts of the body
so I realize what people are trying to
do with this but to me it's vastly
preferable to take the time and
selectively breathe cannabis for the
components and proportions that you wish
to target when I think about people
using eye slits and putting them
together to try to reach a clinical goal
with a patient it feels like a analog
versus digital music to me where if
you're taking you know one part this
terpene one part THC one part a couple
of different you know minor cannabinoids
and put them together you're getting
these zeros and ones but with analog
music when you're putting a needle on a
record you get all of the depth of it
instead of just the composite of the
pieces is that an appropriate way to
think about it well maybe I like a lot
of digital music but with respect to the
plants it's my considered opinion that a
properly constituted extract is going to
beat these combinations any time and
clearly if we're talking about
development of a pharmaceutical it has
to be from one species if we're
combining species that becomes a
combination medicine and then you're
probably tripling or more of the work
because you have to do toxicology
analysis on each component separately
and then all of them together and it
becomes cost prohibitive so if let's say
that we were talking about using these
isolates as a bridge because these
custom chemo VARs don't exist yet
I'm guessing they don't exist there's no
but it's and so and so it's I can see
someone watching thinking myself well in
the shore
we're going to use you know terpenes and
isolates together until we grow these
plants and I'm wondering a can that do
more damage than help the patient and be
if you know where these plants are what
are your thoughts on that well the
problem is that yes these plants exist
but in very limited jurisdictions for
instance some of these types of Kim
Avars that I'm describing or available
in California and Washington DC but
they're not generally available because
our federal laws prohibit these crossing
state borders let alone international
borders so that's the first thing that
needs to happen I'm not in favor of
combining external synthetics as a
stopgap measure because again these are
potentially toxic the amounts use may
not be proper at all and it's just not
not a proper approach mm-hmm
last question on this so for people who
are using isolates and terpenes to you
know try to have this bridge until these
plants are more more accessible is there
a way for them to know when they're
reaching threshold points that could you
know be toxic like offering terpene
toxicity because you know I know that
it's it's pretty well regarded that
because we've had the relationship with
the cannabis plant for so long and it
generally moves slowly in its changes
that we continually are checking in with
the plant whereas if we grab a bunch of
isolate and we put it together we
haven't had a long relationship with
that particular combination and so we
put ourselves at more risk yeah that
that's true
people should keep in mind what the
relative concentrations would be under
natural conditions so if we have total
cannabinoids in the 20 percent or 25
percent range
many of the chemo VARs only still have
about one or two percent terpenoids 5%
which I've seen is really good so you
can get to the point that it's a five to
one ratio of cannabinoids to terpenoids
so people certainly shouldn't be
exceeding that plus they need to keep in
mind that too much of a good thing is
really possible let's take the example
of beta pine or I'm sorry alpha piny
piny n-- is a bronchodilator
it opens up the lungs but when there's
too much it's irritating to the lungs
and can have a reverse effect say and
someone who's asthmatic
a little bit of alpha pining will
counteract the short-term memory
impairment the THC produces but too much
potentially could be too stimulating and
we know that acetylcholinesterase
inhibitors which is the activity that
elephant pining produces boosts memory
in low amounts but if the dose is
excessive they could make it more likely
for someone to have a seizure in other
words alpha pining has toxicity if the
dose is too high and the same thing
would apply to any other terpenoid
another example would be essential oils
which are combinations of terpenoids
essential oil of lavender is okay to
place on the skin what's called using
meat so if somebody has a burn and puts
lavender essential oil that will help
with the burn and it won't be bad for
the skin however many other essential
oils would be caustic if applied
directly to the skin on produce burning
or other reactions so I really worry
about safety and relation to these kinds
of practices if people are not being
cognizant of
the proper proportions or the need to go
slowly with these things and if you want
to learn more about this we actually
have got a link to dr. Russo's paper on
this topic in the first comment below
thank you dr. Russo