so Ethan you know um we're starting to
see Tarpin added into everything right
uh for better for worse um sometimes
they're just trying to make a product
taste a little bit better um and
sometimes they're actually adding tpin
like like oh we've added you know
citrine to this product it will make you
happy right um and then and then other
folks are just straight up adding Tarpin
to you know you know dabbable oils and
things like that so so there's a lot of
different implementations of tpin right
now and something that people ask me all
the time is at what point does a tpine
become um effective in the human body um
is there a threshold point where you
haven't had enough of the tarpine you
haven't had enough of the tarpine and
then at some point you're like oh this
is this is your threshold point where
you get the advantages of it and then
and then somewhere up here suddenly now
the tpine is doing less well for you
which you've talked about extensively
but this area to know when um a tpine
added to a product is actually giving me
any benefit how how would we weigh that
well uh it's difficult but uh good gauge
would be uh if someone finds a Cho ver
for which they like the effects say that
they're vaporizing uh kimar they like it
it might be a good thing uh to uh
extract ra uh to make an edible product
uh which would be particularly an
advantage for someone who had a chronic
condition where they wanted to uh be
able to dose effectively two or three
times a day as opposed to many times a
day if they were
vaporizing um part of the problem uh the
reason this has come about is there's
been a big move particularly in
Washington state towards
concentrates and in the state 60% of
sales now concentrates but um often
these are have developed an
imbalance um so
particularly uh with the CO2 extracts to
some degree as well uh with buttine
extracts which I don't particularly
recommend we're getting upwards of 70
even 90% THC to the exclusion of of
turpins and this is a real problem um
this is a situation where even
experienced cannabis user might take one
hit of a concentrate and pass out from
what's called orthostatic
hypotension uh just because it's a
slowed down there hard enough that they
can't get blood flow to the brain and
they hit the deck uh so that part's
dangerous but
additionally you've lost the turboid
because of the way that the material was
concentrated um and
processed but there are ways around this
concentrates rather should be made in a
way that preserves the terpenoids there
are two common ways to do this one is
with cold ethanol extraction and this
tends to get the terpenoids out at the
same time as the cannabinoids and and
preserve them so tinctures even though
they're oldfashioned remain a good way
to extract and to store cannabis uh
stably uh the other way uh is with CO2
extraction which is notorious for
causing a loss of terpenoids but instead
of doing one run that usually will get
the cannaboids effectively but lose a
lot of the terpenoids is to do one run
aimed at extracting each and then
combining them and there's nothing wrong
with this it just takes longer um but uh
would be a better way uh to do this in
terms of the amounts um everything is
relative um there was one analysis of
things
that tried to demonstrate how potent
terpenoids are and indicated that uh a
concentration of
.1% uh can have a measurable effect but
it really didn't say how that was
administered so if we look at how
terpenoids are most effective certainly
they are on inhalation and I think most
people realize that there are also
effective when applied on the skin and
this is the ba basis of aromatherapy
massage um people shouldn't think that
this is witchcraft because you can
produce measurable levels of the
terpenoids in the serum after
application on the skin um they are
somewhat less effective orally uh but
that's not to say that there's no
benefit uh at all and so people
shouldn't shy away from that um
but um in general um we need to see
higher amounts of terpenoids in
cannabis-based medicines it would be
easy to exceed the necessary
concentrations if they're added from an
external Source MH you know I think that
um I think at the that the heart of this
is is customer and patient education
right because um the the market is
providing these um you know 70 80% ta
THC oils because when people are going
in they want the most bang for their
buck and so they they look for the
highest THC content not realizing that
as you're increasing your THC content
you're you're lessening the space
available for the minor canabo and the
Turpin and every and and especially CBD
which will help moderate and actually
make your THC High more pleasurable and
so um um you know what would what would
you recommend as far as you know trying
to uh I don't know backfill the market
to to to perhaps you know reach the
reach patients so that maybe the demand
changes so that what's being brought to
the market is changed sure well uh this
is a problem I've had this conversation
with many Bud tenders um and uh the
average consumer goes into a a cannabis
dispensary and usually ask for the
highest THC available a good bu Bud
tender will try to disabuse use them of
the notion that this is what they really
want um and try to explain that the
quality of their experience might be a
lot better with a more balanced
chovar um CBD has somewhat of a
reputation as a buzz kill uh but this
really isn't accurate either in the
olden days
um more often cannabis had a balance
between THC and
CBD um and and uh that was still
pleasurable for people in the
recreational Market um it takes a
tremendous amount of CBD usually given
before THC to totally eliminate uh its
ability to produce a high rather what it
will do when they they're used in
conjunction is it might blunt the Peak
High somewhat it also delays the onset
of the Peak High um and most importantly
prolongs the overall effect uh so that
people don't need to dose as often
whether they are using it recreationally
or to treat a specific disorder uh so
there're many advantages and then again
with the other terpenoids these very
much modulate the high of THC um can
reduce short-term memory impairment can
reduce anxiety and uh all the other side
effects uh that we associate with too
much
THC uh so uh really depends on what the
consumer is seeking uh but education can
help a lot in guiding people towards
what be might be better uh for their
overall health and reduce problems right
so butt tenders it sounds like it's up
to you you're front lines teach the
people thank you Ethan