every year farmers everywhere are
preparing their soil for the new season
and and no a key part of this soil is
everybody wants these complex mycelial
networks because these these fungal
networks move around nutrients and
communication and and they you know they
create a thriving soil food web and this
is why people are so in a note oh right
because you go from season to season and
this this web if you will stays
consistent from season to season but
lots of folks have got to move into new
soil either they're expanding their grow
or there's something wrong with the old
soil or whatever and but if you're going
to transplant cannabis into one of these
pots you want to have some kind of
maturity in the pot already so that you
know you can end up with by the end of
your cannabis cycle that's when the soil
is actually good right because it's
gonna take the whole life of the
cannabis plant for the my ceiling
networks to to come into being what
would you recommend could be done to
these pots before season so that by the
time you're transplanting into these
pots they're already mycelium rich and
ready to rock good question
really good question let me go back
first over corrected no-till it's one
reason you don't know till there are
lots of other reasons not the least of
which is that the whole soil food web
not just the micro zone network gets
gets messed up on you when you fill up
the song you know like say when you kind
of warm in half you don't get to worms
so so you gotta be careful that's that's
that's you know only one reason as far
as the mycorrhizal fungi are concerned
they require a plant to survive so there
are no mycorrhizal fungi ink
when I when I give advice when I advise
indoor cannabis you know people call me
up and say okay what do you charge back
back back and so so my advice is always
a stunner to them when they find out
that that what they need to do is do
what you're doing
start early get that so conditioned put
a cover crop in get that cover crop to
feed a throw or to grow a thriving
mycelium Network you got about a month
month and a half that's that's probably
enough time it certainly can't hurt and
and then when you put your plant in
there it sends out signals to get the
mycorrhizal to come to it there may be
mycorrhizal already growing which it can
feed into so that's key I also take
mycorrhizal fungal product and I mix it
in my soil so that as the plant grows
during the season the roots grow into
mycorrhizal fungi and are able to
establish new colonies and you end up
with colonies on the new rooms as well
as the older roots which is key so you
want to add it to your soil when you put
your pots together by the way you want
to keep that that phosphorous in
particular but nitrogen as well those
numbers need to be low or the
mycorrhizae fungi will never grow and
then put in something so that you get a
signal from a plant that activates the
memorising it's like the spark of life
that gets things going and it's
definitely the plant I think it's I can
see them they named it after a plant
stigma something other and the plant
definitely sends the signal out the
fungi and says come hither and if the
plant doesn't do that don't make noise
has no idea that the plant is there Wow
but you're right the network then
becomes a wonderful feeding network now
maybe we should just spend a little
teeny bit of time talking about why do
people use new soil all the time tends
to be a knee-jerk reaction again when I
advise growers particularly indoor
growers because that's people come to me
more often than outdoors you know
they're dumb fabulous no that's where
your phone that's where well even with a
male plant don't throw that soil out
chances are when you think about it you
realize wait a second I mean that's
wrong on that so it's been used once
before it might need a little bit of
nutrient in it but that plant that I had
in it before set out extra dates there
in that soil already Wow
if probably brought in the microbes that
I want there and that soil already there
are there are root color passages that
the new plant can utilize and grow with
much less effort there's organic
material left by those old roots the old
rhizosphere is still there holy all this
stuff is valuable so so really think
hard and long about what do you want to
use the new soil it really is amazing to
people again particularly these large
commercial indoor growers of a big
advice whoa whoa they say you would save
money oh my god isn't it huge savings so
I and I think yeah that would better
soil so last year was my first year to
experiment with with cover crops right
and it does make a huge difference
especially in keeping the soil
pleasantly moist yeah that's right here
I also realized that there's a lot of
variability in cover crop right some of
it grows more than you wanted to do and
get to be a hassle what do you recommend
as being a good easy cover crop yeah you
know
I like the red clovers it's it's it
depends not where you live like thank
you so what I do in Anchorage Alaska's
gonna be different than what you do down
here is it clover the same everywhere
well it is but I mean there were other
stuff that people have and - oh I sinned
and yeah well in some places it really
grows crazy in Anchorage it grows nuts
and so if you're not careful the
seedling can get inundated but once you
get that plant up and running then it
doesn't matter what you have in there
but oh my gosh it's fun to do it looks
kind of fun
and it's a living mulch so the many ways
it takes care of that mulch and buffing
that particularly as these as they die
and start feeding stuff it's just do
encourage that you said as they die and
I know that some folks when the the when
they get certain pipe they just go ahead
and scissor and cut them through and
like that's laborious right not for big
you know big
rows but it's for hunger so do you think
that's worthwhile at all or just ignore
just let it die on their own their own
sometimes sometimes it turns out where I
am you're one that when I'm traveling
what not but yeah you know we do we do a
lot of work and sometimes it's just pays
not to it's just too much work
well not fun yeah one more question on
the on the cover crop so one of the
common opinions against cover crop is
that that cover crop is stealing my
nutrients for the plant know that cover
crop should be putting nutrients in the
soil for your plant so if it's stealing
nutrients for your plant using the wrong
Carver crop it's supposed to be making
nitrogen that's why we use nitrogen
fixing when you will you use those
nitrogen fixers with mycorrhizal fungi
you get increased nodules you get you
know it's just you got to use the right
stuff so I think it's properties on a
misunderstanding of just thinking that
oh the plant is growing and therefore
it's a zero-sum competition between the
handless plant and the cover crop and
that's just false s-pulse that's
completely false and you're getting soil
structure I have a friend who did the
yeah landscape real in its debut for the
st. Louis Arch and he got there and she
thought it was terrible and it was
compacted so he he in the fall he
planted long turnips
people are saying Louis look at the hell
are you doing this boy this is art look
an acre is next you you know maybe
that's Ireland and the finest greatest
stuff in the world cover crops work
there's a reason people use them and
they make a great deal of sense and
people might want to think about it
again I tell you indoor growers this as
well you know sometimes you have a
fallow field you don't so you just put
the cover crop it you don't put the
cannabis in it for a crop let it just
spend half a season or season growing
the cover crop yeah there you go yeah I
think I think you know we kind of expand
our thinking about this stuff where were
too we're too fixated on a hydroponic
model because that's what we all had
back when I was a kid and we don't
happen anymore
I was I was at the regenerative cannabis
conference a few weeks ago and and
layton Morrison was talking about how he
really likes radishes as a cover crop
because I guess they've got a very long
tap root turnip concept no so so that's
gonna say is that the same idea except
at a more reasonable size for container
yeah absolutely the only problem I have
with using radishes and turnips for
cannabis is they are you know
to be allopathic to micro resolution oh
well that's kind of a big deal yes I
think you gotta pay ten time pretty sure
that's the truth I don't think back here
now I think they are members of the Cole
family are they radishes cabbages are
they on the same yeah yeah there anyway
run for it so so if somebody's going to
you if somebody's gonna think about
using radishes double check on that yeah
double check on that certainly don't
want to use cabbages I can tell yeah
yeah nothing nothing in the rossion
family because they are they are
allopathic and so yeah you know if you
plant in that soil the next season you
get a tough time getting the microscope
all right fantastic thank you yeah
you