so Jeff you know last night when you
were talking I heard something I had
never really considered before I know
that I can't be the only one who has a
history of going to the grow shop and
buying nutrients with the highest
numbers because you know as far as NPK
goes because it feels like it's the most
bang for the buck like like like I want
to get the most nutrient possible for my
money but last night you said that in
actuality you recommend purchasing lower
numbers because it's overall going to be
better for the rhizosphere
would you break that out a little bit
sure of course yesterday I was talking
about wattle flowers but it applies to
all plants and not just cannabis plants
as far as I'm concerned you know the
tendency is to want to go get the
highest knife you can you possibly can
that's that first number in the NPK
trilogy we've all been inundated over
the years with television ads and
television ads and television ads about
how that high nitrogen number that I
mean if they're green long and gorgeous
green plants and it's gonna make things
go fast and so we're all custom to the
idea that you want to have that high
number and then of course comes the
hydroponic people who say okay look at
this man to give this stuffing and I
don't think people sit back and think of
a number of things so let me first start
by by explaining you're not feeding the
plant when you're dealing with soil
you're feeding the microbes those
microbes will then feed the plant
through the cycling of their bodies and
what's in their bodies so you're feeding
the microbes you want to have a food
that the microbes are gonna be able to
digest and eat nicely you know you don't
want to have a you know something that
just one kind of microbe wanted or the
impacts of the diversity and and you you
you you want to have something you know
obviously that contains more than just
NPK so I go for the lower numbers and I
go for the
and the lower numbers I'm talking about
things like you know three four three
that kind of a number if you if you have
a number over the middle numbers the
phosphorous number if that number is is
over fifty parts per million somehow I
think that equates to basically like a
10 or a 12 and that middle number so
like a a 1012 would be that middle
number if it's that high provides enough
phosphorous so that the mycorrhizal
fungi which would normally go out and
get the phosphorus for the plant doesn't
do that the plant says I don't need to
feed these guys I'm getting the
phosphorous for free and so it changes
either the signaling of the actually
makes everybody lazy it makes the plant
appreciate the free lunch all right yeah
yeah it makes it makes not so much lazy
it makes the plant just not attract to
the rhizosphere those microbes that
would normally be there because it
doesn't need them and and so so then you
have to you know supply those until a
plant stops doing that and and when you
put it in that high number for
phosphorus the plant is stopped same
thing with nitrogen so it makes sense if
you want to have a good healthy soil
food web to feed the microbes not the
plant and to not become a microbe
yourself that's what happens when you
use those side numbers you kill off some
of the members of the food web you have
to become them otherwise the plant
doesn't eat right so if you look at some
of these packages I won't mention the
evil people but if you look at their
package you've got a reply they're stuff
in every two weeks every two weeks
because you're the soil food web and
you've destroyed it no because you've
created this artificial environment
right no planet says I don't need to
support that I don't need to attract
these michaelis forget the concept that
in some instances these hi Michael
decided nitrogen fertilizers and I
okay we'll actually change the diversity
I mean that's that's a serious problem
in some instances it will actually kill
off the microbes in some instances it
increases one kind of micro because
they'll they eat this stuff but you
really want to have a nice balanced even
system you want the microbes to do the
work you don't want to have the planet
make a decision I like that idea that
that were our job as farmers is really
to take care of the microbe community
and the microbe community takes care of
the plant right when I was first getting
an organic food as a serious follower of
Joel Salatin from Ohio based farms and
one his thing he said he says you know
I'm not a cattle and chicken farmer I'm
a grass farmer and so long as I produce
good grass now all the animals eat
similarly we're trying to create you
know a good microbes so that the plant
has something that it wasn't eat so
herders yeah well that's exactly right
in and I think people forget that and
the reason why we forget it is because
before World War Two that's all people
did and all of a sudden these artificial
fertilizers came in after the war hmm
where do they come from
munitions a Senator Sarah so yes it's
just one of those systems that have
gotten out of hand and so when you
talked about it to go back to your
beginning of the question you know your
concentration levels you thought you
know by those higher ones it's cheaper
ultimately in terms of the economy but
that's not really true because you have
to apply it more and your plan is by
more susceptible to everything because
it doesn't have the micro community to
help it fend off yeah yeah I mean I mean
given how many decadence I got you know
once you change the diversity then
you're really screwing things up and so
yeah absolutely so you want to pay
attention to what you're doing and
frankly when you buy these things you
know you might want to think about where
we don't see if I park compost the
compost is made out of manure could come
from a cow that can't we mmm maybe you
want to buy this stuff that the cow eats
you know so there's all sorts of ways of
thinking different about this it's as
opposed to remember that TV commercial
right and one more question about the
NPK numbers and so very often we will
want to you know use soil additives that
have got of several different types
right and they've all got their own NPK
numbers how do you how do you think
about stacking those right do we add
them together and suddenly now we've got
an N of 18 because we've used five
different things that are three I mean
like how does that work it's very
confusing you know at one time we're
trying to understand these moles
percentages you know so confusing and
and even the NPK numbers themselves
don't really represent nitrogen 5 you
know the phosphorus is really not
phosphorus I think it's phosphoric acid
I know you know it's just so confusing
but all I know is that what you do mix
them together you are additive as
opposed to subtract them and you're
increasing the number as you go
once again it's sort of one of these
situations where you gotta make sure
that you're giving the plant what it
needs and what a lot of people do is
just knee-jerk apply these things so I
would say the other part of the question
should be or the answer should be you
need to test to see what your plant
really needs and most people don't do
anything thanks for sure
we really are deficient in that regard
and there's so many neat ways to test
that you know from saw food web
microbiome owner and PK it's all good
stuff we want to do it
informations power so yeah so let's see
if we can go back and summarize the
answer you want to keep those numbers
low because you're feeding the microbes
not feeding the plant the microbes feed
the plant by keeping the numbers low you
keep that micro set healthy and the
plant does not rely on the food you're
applying there they were still relying
on the right work fantastic thank you
very much
you