in cannabis growing forums there's a lot
of trash that's talked about
all based bottled nutrients right people
call me I don't I don't grow as salt sir
I wouldn't grow with those bottles and
you know especially in the forums that I
frequent that are all natural growing
technique related right but I think a
lot of people they just they they give
these family of store-bought nutrients a
category without actually understanding
why we don't like them right and so I
hope that you would review why folks
should not consider salt based bottled
nutrients and because of how that
impacts the soil food web yeah I mean
they're also salt salt nutrients that
are not in the bottle right now yeah
there's just powders that you buy yeah I
always tell this story and I got it I
have to be a little bit careful because
I don't want to get taken to court yeah
but I tell the story about sitting in a
garden writers meeting once and a
gentleman named Horace magadhan came to
speaking he was the founder of Miracle
Grow and he got up and gave a talk about
Miracle Grow this must have been 25
years ago and every garden writer in the
United States of America used Miracle
Grow we get free samples all the time at
something and and sounds like a
pharmaceutical industry right and and
you know was before the organic movement
really really took off before I like to
say teeming with microbes but anyway he
gave us talk and he explained how he got
into the business and he explained that
he graduated the University of
Pennsylvania with a degree in
advertising this is a big tip off of
course and I see there is all the time
and he went to work for a company in New
York that sold butter and he'd learned
about two minutes into the job all
butters to see the difference is the
package you know they put a red label or
agreement you know it's all USDA is all
green it's all the same but it all comes
from the same place you know senator and
he kept thinking about his his friends
who went to work for Joe heck and
other places where they were having new
some new razor blades everyday uh and he
hated this job and and he would spend
his weekend driving around trying to
straighten his head out and one weekend
he came upon a greenhouse that was
growing wonderful plants and he asked
the guy why why his plants was so
different than the guy said my name is
Otto Stern I have an invention bla bla
and they decided they were gonna go into
business together and try to sell this
stuff and so they put it in the New York
Herald Tribune 1952 before and after
miracle-gro plant we've all seen them
and he made like $20,000 in the week
following Thursday at the Kisa and
that's old money - that was old money
and he so he went into the butter
company and he said you know I like you
guys they went sailing together bills
but I hate this business and I quit and
I'm gonna go in the fertilizer business
and he did and he built up miracle-gro
it's probably the number one recognized
brand in the world right up there with
coca-cola and Pepsi I have to add and
then he was approached by Scott said go
buy him out in a reverse buy on what
Scott's for like 315 million bucks he
told us and then he said thank you very
much and we all went up to get
autographs and I was standing in the
back and he looked up at bt100
shooting one feels I said yes he goes so
sorry I told that story about the butter
company my father and grandfather owned
the butter no kidding oh my god and we
became quite good friends as a result of
that talk he gave and he would come up
to Anchorage Alaska and sit in my
backyard my wife Judith arranged to have
10 or 15 gardeners come over one in an
hour and he would interview home and
then the ads would run on a Super Bowl
you know he would I think if he was
alive today he would definitely be an
organic gardener he would definitely see
the bad
and now I'll answer the question right
on you know that this stuff is crap
that's the scientific version scientific
version first of all let's take the
large overview you know you know that's
that that ugly map that has the that
zone down there by New Orleans and the
water and a unification isn't redness
all rainbow colors as a pollutant that
that that's nitrogen runoff everybody
always says it's the farmers but in fact
home growers gardeners but at home
growers are certainly part of it we use
four to five times more nitrogen than a
garden than a farmer does so we're
responsible for that as much as anything
you use a teeny little bit of it a teeny
little bit of it hits the root the rest
of it goes out into the war ever and it
pollutes simple as that
the plant doesn't use all that high
concentration the microbes some of which
will die because the stuff is so heavily
concentrated you know if you took any
kind of 10th grade high school course
and paid attention which most of us
didn't in science you know about osmosis
and diffusion and and what happens if
you have a high concentration of salts
on one side and a single-cell organism
on the other side and you put them
together what happens is the single cell
water leaves the single cell tries to
loop the salt salt tries to go we're
gonna steal some one dilute the the
water and you want to have an
equilibrium and you end up with son of
an equilibrium on it's always at least
one molecule I learned when I wrote in
with nutrients sois one model I feel at
least off but anyway he wind up with
this quasi equilibrium but you also know
what the dead microorganism right
because in a cell you know so so you
there either eating like crazy changing
the constant natural concentration or
they're getting killed by this stuff and
both of those are bad now once they
start to go then you have a you have the
entourage effect of bad effects
the plants ISM I don't need to do the
extra date thing it's a lot of work
making 5060 percent of my closest
photosynthetic energy to produce and she
dates I'm going to concentrate on the
flower and not worry about that stuff
but it needs to worry about that stuff
because it's not getting what it wants
what you know it's getting nitrogen sure
it's getting phosphorous NPK high
numbers of it and everything else but is
he getting the little nutrients that it
needs some micro ones you know that make
the right enzyme that does that right
it's phenomenal what you need and again
the theme of nutrients I highly
recommend because teacher we didn't need
to know but what happens inside that
cell is influenced by what goes into so
now let's go let's go a couple more
steps you could stop with whatever you
want you know if ever I have to rewrite
a or do another book it will be called
more teams with microbes one of the
things I'm going to stick in it is known
as now known as rise over fakie you know
just in passing
Rezo something I'm really really
fascinated by you know I wrote teaming
with fungi boy I mentioned all three
walks now that's amazing how that is but
it links to all the books are in the
description below so go out and buy Oh
believe me I'm not making any money my
publisher is the the fungi of course did
this wonderful symbiotic relationship
well it turns out that now they're
discovering some of the bacteria and
this is what I'm trying to figure out
how much how often does this happen some
of the bacteria do do i talked about in
teen with microbes you know they get
eaten the things that eat and poop them
out feed the plant you know the plant it
puts a charge on it it goes into the
plant
timid nutrients Lila what rifle
involves is a completely different
system the the bacteria is in the
rhizosphere it goes into the into the
root enters the route through the
meristem the area goes into the root
takes off its cell wall it is oxidized
by the plant cell that strips off the
nutrients it contains the bacteria
continues to move through the plant it
goes to the side of the wall
it creates or stimulates the plant to
form a root hair the root hair grows the
bacteria moves through the root hair and
goes out the end of the root hair puts
its cell wall back on as it does so goes
into the soil gets more nutrients and
repeats the process so it's it's it's
taking off its outer layer passing
through the not the root zone but the
literal root is that - and then comes
out the other side kind of reborn if
it's up against the plasma lemma
apparently this gives oxidized which
pulls off the nutrients and the next
thing you know it goes back out but what
happens is the root hairs form now we're
not trying to figure out and I got to
stop traveling enough to be a leg in the
telephone see if I can find a guy that
wrote the papers are these blue hairs
only formed as a result of bacteria
leaving is this what this is is this is
a system that ejects the bacteria into a
new area of the soil that's different
from where the bacteria came from so
that it can get its nutrients and go
back into the root whoa now that would
be simply amazing but in any case we
know it does exist and that it's
happening it's very analogous to what
the fungi do
they go into the plant they give them
the nutrients that are out I mean it's
an interesting coevolution I don't know
quite what they call it it's very
similar to micro risin funda it seems to
me and and I want to know a lot more
about it all right I think about how we
got into it what the question was but
those guys are going out there and
bringing food into the plant and I think
if you use in those heavy miracle-gro
type sauce that's not happening right on
thank you very much that's fabulous
you