so Ethan you know very often when you
speak you you talk about how so much of
the present cannabis market is is is
kima bars that are heavily meer scene
based that you travel down the country
and it's like mere Seng everywhere and
and I always want to ask the next
question well dr. Russo if there's too
much mere scene in all of the
commercially available cannabis what
would you like there to be so so let's
just say that we could you know pie in
the sky if you could wave your hands and
and have the existence of particular
kima bars that were heavy in particular
terpenes or terpene profiles what would
you like to see if you could just snap
your fingers sure will it be a few one
would be alpha Pi mean alpha PI means
hard to find in most modern cannabis
kima verse and it is going to be the
King Creon limiting the short term
memory impairment that THC produces how
it does this is as an
acetylcholinesterase inhibitor
acetylcholine is the memory molecule on
the brain and by preventing its
breakdown there's more of it and people
can think more clearly and so for the
patient who has to work or study while
trying to treat their pain or other
symptoms having a good bit of alpha
pining in the mix is going to be really
helpful as a sidebar if somebody if a
patient is does need to work and they
also need to be using cannabis for
relief would it help them to be to be
using their THC but also have alpha
pining in an aromatherapy diffuser in
the room would they work together like
that well sure if it were from a natural
source mm-hmm so if they were using some
kind of pine based essential oil yeah
that could help right uh but ideally
would be better to have a cannabis based
medicine that had alpha painting in it
hopefully replacing some of the Mersey
I should mention Mersin isn't all bad
I do call it the couch lock factor in
cannabis when combined with THC because
of its its mark sedative effect a sort
of narcotic effect but it is analgesic
painkiller in its own right and
certainly would help with sleep another
component there would be really helpful
to have is limonene limonene is a very
powerful antidepressant and immune
stimulant and so this brightens up the
effects of THC and produces a vibrancy
to the experience that clearly are
bigger advantage for someone with a mood
disorder another one would be Lin Ahlul
Lin Ahlul is the main component of
lavender essential oil which is well
known as an anti-anxiety agent it can
have some sedative effects but it's not
a knock you out kind of experience like
Mersin can be so this is a good one
particularly for patients with seizure
disorders because it has an
anticonvulsant effect as well fourth one
that would be really good to have more
of is carrie awfully carry off lean is a
really interesting agent it is a
terpenoid but at the same time it's a
cannabinoid because it works on the cb2
receptor teetsi also works on the cb2
receptor but actually carry off alene is
more effective on this receptor so it
provides anti-inflammatory benefits and
pain relief without psycho activity so
clearly this is a good thing to have an
additional factor with carry off Alina's
that he has an anti addictive effect so
this would be extremely helpful for the
patient might have chronic pain and be
taking opioids at the same time as their
cannabis base
Madison so let's just take these four so
having more of these individual terpenes
in terpene profiles in Kiev ours is a
great thing what if we took it to an
extreme and said that we had a keema var
that had you know a couple percentage of
each of those in it do they work as well
together or you know you've talked
before that that sometimes these these
turkeys and cannabinoids if they're by
themself they'll act as an agonist but
if they're with other things like that
an antagonist because they they they mix
and match differently is it generally
better to have more terpenes and more
variety in most cases or really do you
do you really kind of want to breed your
cannabis for particular notes and try to
stick with those well having the variety
terpenoids is going to create a more
interesting experience and probably
provide more general symptom relief
however again if I know the person's
condition what we're trying to treat
gives me an idea of what terpenoids we
might have them look for on again with
the lack of diversity in the current
market in most areas this is going to be
a hard thing to accomplish but again I'm
thinking of this in an aspirational
sense that we know that these things can
be an advantage and we want the market
to head in the direction of providing
more varied chemo VARs that can provide
the kinds of profiles that are going to
be better suited to treating these
conditions right so if you want to hear
more about this I've got two great
sources for you in the first comment
there'll be a link to Ethan's paper on
this topic
taming terpenes and then his follow-up
paper as well and then also we did about
90 minutes on two different episodes so
I three hours on this topic on the
shaping fire podcast so check out links
for both of those below thanks Ethan