so for those of you who don't know I'll
start with Jeff on the far side Jeff
Lowen fells is a you know 45 plus year a
gardening author out of Alaska but most
of us in this room know him from his
teaming with microbes teaming with fungi
and teeming with nutrients series of
books which is like essentially the Holy
Grail trilogy for people who love this
kind of stuff right and so he has also
got a new book coming out in October all
about Auto flowers and it's fantastic
I've been able to check out parts of it
as it went to the publisher and it's
very much an introduction to Auto
flowers and and because of that I see
Jeff as an evangelist for Auto flowers
and then to his right is my other good
friend Seth Crawford and some of you may
know him as a co-founder with his
brother Eric of Oregon CBD seeds near
Albany and and so they're focused on
heavy-duty non-gmo heavy analytical
breeding they're at their laboratory and
with the goal of developing particular
chemo VARs that can target particular
symptom issues for patients and so they
started with CVD they have figured out
the CBG they're on their way to the
Varens and and it's fantastic much to
the joy and chagrin of cannabis farmers
throughout the country they're their
seeds continually get outstripped
because as no as many as they produce
everyone just then goes and buys those
and then they're out again and so you
know if people vote with their wallets
people are voting for oregon CBD so
thank you gentlemen for joining us today
so i'm gonna have a sip of water here
and then off we go all right so so most
people may understand that Otto's finish
faster but that doesn't seem to be that
it doesn't mean the best application for
autos are readily apparent to everyone
so well we'd like to hear you both
starting with you Jeff how will autos
influence cannabis growing in
horticulture going forward well let me
give two different answers the book as
you indicated is really an introductory
book I like to say it's a book for your
sister and your brother it's a book for
your your Uncle Bob and Aunt Sally it's
not a book for our professional grower
I'm convinced that auto flower cannabis
is going to change the general
populations attitude about cannabis
because it's the next tomato plant once
in a lifetime I'm 70 years old it's only
happened to me once once in a lifetime a
new plant is introduced to the general
horticultural gardening public the last
time it happened it was the snap pea
they took over the pea world and every
gardener grows snap peas a couple of
times during their career and probably
every year that's what's gonna happen I
think to these Auto flowers because
they're so easy to grow their quality
has risen so high as a result of the
genetics and so that's the first answer
the second answer is this is a plant
which you can grow on a deck which you
can grow outside in a garden you can
grow it in a perennial bed you can grow
it in a pot in the ground and so it's
something that is accessible to all
growers not just people who have big
farms or a big greenhouse and because
they don't have a photo period it means
that people who live in northern
climates like Alaska where on September
21st your plant finally gets the
darkness that it needs to set flower you
also get a frost that night and then
finally for those who do professionally
grow here is a plant which you can use
to inter space between your plants as
they veg the same thing your plant says
they flower you just put them in they
don't care what the light is you can
give them 20 24 hours of light they're
gonna flower based on their genetics and
so you can use your spare space this is
a dream for the entire horticultural
world fantastic so so Seth I know you're
coming from a little different direction
Jeff and I share that we were but very
interested in home growers and patient
growers but your customers and the
people you are talking I mean I know
you're a heavy patient guy so I'm not
saying you're not into patients but but
your customers are very demanding right
and so so what are you seeing as far as
the advantages for auto flowers for
folks that are growing at a scaled level
at acreage size yeah and I would I would
say since this is gonna be on the
internet for ever this is for posterity
go back and take a look if you're very
interested about geeking out on some of
the historical background on ruderalis
it's that the technical term for auto
flowering plants ruderalis is Latin for
derived from ruderal which is rubble
from the rubble these are plants that
can grow anywhere like they can grow
where it freezes they can grow through
frost they can grow in very very crazy
situations and actually finish the the
trick at industrial scale is really
being able to get them in the ground at
the right time so whether that's a
direct seeding or transplanting before
the plant goes through stress there's
some underlying genetic mechanisms that
lead the plant to go directly into
flower when it senses a stressful
situation just to step back for a second
because of that posterity sake take a
look for that geek out moment at Ernie
smalls
Ernie smalls is a Canadian researcher
who's been working on cannabis related
issues for the last 45 years
brilliant gentleman and he is the person
that was responsible for coming up for
the industrial hemp zero-point-three THC
rule and if you go back and look at his
earlier writings that was based on
taking a leaf off at the top at the
plant rather than testing the top eight
inches of flower at 0.3% hopefully
that's going to be incorporated into the
USDA rules to say move forward at the
farm bill but in 2018 he wrote a seminal
paper and I'm sure that this is going to
go down as one of those Testaments to
auto flowering plants and in the long
term the the paper is about highlighting
the fact that these day-neutral auto
flowering plants represent really the
peak in human agriculture so in a lot of
other crops the reasons and rationales
that we have for expanding the total
productivity of each individual crop on
a per acre basis has come down to
plant breeders geneticists etc over long
periods of time being able to make the
plants more compact make them more
uniform and take wild types of plants
that tend to have seeds in varying
places on the plant and consolidate them
into a usable machine harvestable really
energy dense organism and that's been a
true for many of the other crops that
have been domesticated Ernie smalls goes
so far as to say that that is the most
profound thing that we have seen in over
thirteen thousand years of human
agriculture is this move towards he
called some semi dwarf or dwarf germ
plasm so the title of the paper is dwarf
germ plasm and essentially it's about
how to get tremendously large yields
both for food crops if you're growing
for seed hopefully in places where
they're not growing for sensimilla or a
cannabinoid products we can get into
that later but also for cannabinoid
production in general so it's it's all
about being able to maximize the space
minimize the inputs and really allow
both farmers and people who benefit from
these compounds to have more access to
them and and to benefit from this plan
and auto flowering plants are tremendous
at this yeah maybe we don't know explain
so these plants if you if you're not
familiar with Auto flowers two things
first of all they'll start to flower in
eighteen days up to three weeks they'll
just flower period which is pretty
incredible which is pretty incredible
and then the the other thing about them
is that they that you can you can you
can overdo it with them this is a plant
that grew quickly they were discovered
and and and about 1900 1903 scientists
found him in the Volga River area in
Russia he described it it had low low
THC or no THC and so they basically
forgot about him and then in the 70s
people started to say hmm maybe we could
breed these and so you know the breeding
happened and then in 2003 a guy was able
to successfully commercialize one call
lowrider and and you know these are the
ultimate heirloom kind of thing they're
not a land race really I don't think
anymore but they're their heirloom and
you can you can breed these things they
go flower and the you know 18-day third
third week by nine weeks they're
finished you harvest it Wow the breeding
potential and opportunities on these
things are just spectacular so so the
opportunity to be able to improve on
this plant like we have in theory
improved on some of the some of our
agricultural plants is absolutely
incredible
another thing that I love about them is
that if you have got a greenhouse
environment but you don't you really
want to supplement with light for for
whatever reason you can actually do two
cycles of Otto flowers without light
depth and that's crazy right
you know I'm experimenting with that
this year and the biggest thing I ran
into was trying to keep them warm
because Otto flowers don't particularly
like to start off their life with cold
feet but the idea is you know you can
you can have your you can you can start
something early spring and have it
finish 4th of July and then put put
seeds in that same no-till environment
let those pop and they're done by
October 1st
so you've run two cycles and and and you
don't have to pull any tarfu which we
all love to avoid right and so um so
that's fantastic the other thing I
wanted to hit on was it was how
appropriate these are for patients and
for people with lower mobility because
like Jeff mentioned these are very
compact plants right these pretty much
top out at around three three and a half
feet and and because of that you don't
have to do the reaching and they're not
hard to break down and and you know the
patient can stand up and look all around
them from mold instead of you know
trying to work with some of these nine
footers where they're just impossible to
work with they're beautiful and I love
them and I want to talk them right but
but they're really they're you know
they're all caged and difficult to work
with so this is something that that
folks who are living in an apartment who
are growing in a tent can grow for these
together with no sweat you don't even
need to scrub them
and and then if you're a patient they're
so easily it's easy to use and always
going to flower in a particular
timeframe you be ready to go that it
really opens up the door but let's not
leave the impression that these are
little teeny baby flowers because their
little teeny plants you know I mean
there there's there's a there are some
I've seen colors that are 80 grams Wow
unbelievable and they'll have you know
10 of these colas on a plant so so these
are not the the lowrider that you
remember these are a totally new plant
ready for primetime just to add on to
that so yes you can make them flower in
general for field production we're
looking at about 77 days from the time
that the seed emerges in a starter plug
transplanted into the field within the
week 77 days from that time of emergence
until we harvest it and what Jeff is
saying is absolutely true what we see
with regular photo period plants is the
stem in stock weight accounts for about
27 and a half percent of the total
biomass of the plants with these
day-neutral plants you're looking at
roughly nineteen percent so this is a
order of you talking about a significant
percentage of increased biomass now the
one thing that I will say it it's it's a
little bit of a little bit of a brain
bubble is try growing one of these in a
hundred gallon smart pot okay so it's
really nice for patients or someone
who's just trying to experiment with one
of these plants in a three gallon
container to have it on their deck it's
amazing it's really cool the very useful
plants they stay small they're not gonna
flip out if you'd hit them with a porch
light in the middle of the night when
you go outside but if you put one in a
much bigger container you're gonna
notice that the flowering system is
genetically determined based on stress
and stress particularly to the root zone
so you can actually grow five six seven
eight nine foot tall auto flowering
plants if they have enough root space
and they're not restricted they're
actually when we think about cannabis
one of the things that researchers
always go back to is the amazing
plasticity of that plant and its ability
to respond to the environment that it's
placed in Auto flowering plants the
state
neutrals are to me it's the epitome of
that alright so so I want to pull
together something Jeff just said and
something you just said and take it
further so Jeff loves to talk about how
these scrappy little plants from Russia
you know you can put them in in in Rocky
crappy soil and they still very much
thrive and and you have spoken to me
before just like you just did to all of
us that that this it's the stress of the
of the roots hitting the bottom of the
pot that's gonna trigger flowering and
but I've never heard you give this
example before of these large hundred
gallon pots which makes me very
interested in growing an 8 foot Otto
flower just to do it right so here's my
question is that if if if how do how do
they grow in soil then cuz like I know
you go right into the ground but there's
no eventual bottom of the pot so there
has got to be something going on
scientifically genetic so what's the
trigger yeah in part and one of the
things when you're there are many many
different soil conditions and the
Willamette Valley were blessed with a
number of things including we'll get
into this as we talk about farming at
scale but we have in certain locations
38 feet of topsoil and if it's properly
prepared you can end up with very large
plants I mean we had plants that were
averaging a pound and a half per per
plant planted very densely in in the
field just north of Corvallis last
summer for one of our indie trials it
really comes down to proper soil
preparation and the ability for those
roots to just go out and do their thing
you know now in the book I stress that
it's that from the perspective of an
amateur growing these things they they
don't really like to be repotted all the
time I mean you so I always tell people
to grow them in the original container I
started out with 3 3 gallon containers
because you know I thought the plants
were cute and everything else and
there's something they call it now super
Auto flowers they're really the same
thing but different soil structure and
different soil amounts and so now I'm
telling people I 5 gallons is good that
you know you'll pick what is Hardware
bucket but 7 gallons is even better and
you put the seed right in it I mean I
don't even start them in a because I
think if if they if they
are stressed they will flower hi and the
worst thing you can have is something
that flowers when they're not cheap
seeds although you can grow your own
season they become cheap
yeah it's disappointing when they're
five inches tall yeah and I actually I
actually did that for my first time and
I have I can admit to making that
mistake my first tray last year I still
like my idea I put them in root riot
plugs which I like because um when i
find when i propagate right into soil
it's a lot more difficult to keep the
soil or keep the seed in a moist
environment right the the top of the
soil dries out really fast whereas those
root riots while they are soil and so
i'll put the seed in there let it pop
and as soon as i've got like you know
you know firmly established coddled and
leaves then i go ahead and i put it in
before the the roots are coming out the
bottom and they do make some cute little
plants i mean you I saw a little plant
growing in a thimble with with it with a
you know yeah kind of thing you put on
Instagram
Wow and so I had a tray of these right I
had a tray of these in and I let them
sit too long in the tray before I
because you're right you said you know
that same week you know but so so I let
him sit to there and so I had a tray of
very expensive beautiful eight-inch
Otto flowers and each one had this
gorgeous big noggin top and and you know
the the yield per weight was incredible
the yield per $15 seed was not right so
so I'm growing my own still paying $15 a
gram which is like not not a win but
they made awesome gifts to people
because you give somebody a small plant
with this fully mature bud and you're
like here you go snip it off like let it
dry for a couple days and smoke it and
they're like really well and actually
you know I know we're getting getting
out of order here but but but in keeping
in my idea that this is the next tomato
I'm convinced that that in in the next
future few years you're gonna be able to
walk into you know you
Whole Foods or wherever at Christmastime
and they're gonna have a little shelf
and it's gonna have you know thirty
little Auto flower plants sitting they
look like little Christmas trees that
are decorated you know and then at
Easter Easter time you know you're gonna
have a play you know plants with a
little that little green plastic crap
you know this is these plants are
unbelievable they're so much fun to grow
I just cannot you can I'm peeing in my
pants I love this so so I wanna I want
to bring the conversation back to
medical which obviously I keep bringing
this conversation back to you because
those are the people I work with a lot
and so and we're gonna keep going with
you Jeff and then we'll jump back to
Seth so so in terms of medical Jeff I'd
like you to speak a bit to the ease of
growing and and I've heard you talk
about how you can actually do too much
right so I want to I would like to hear
that and then and then and then Seth
would you pick up since you are
analytically breeding these to help with
particular ailments I'd like to hear
from you how the the breeding of Auto
flowers are can be so targeted because
they're so they're so quick to cycle so
but Jeff let's start with you well you
know these are these are unbelievable
plants and they just just you know
compared to as a marigold you know I
read a garden column in the in the
newspaper up in Anchorage and and you
know marigolds are the one plant I say
you know you got to have you got to
plant something or you're not a real
gardener so you plant a marigold you can
have you a kid do it with you because
it's the only seat you stick the seat in
the ground it's like a sunflower seed
there's certain see you just put them in
the ground you walk away you don't do
anything and they grow well they grow
the way they're supposed to grow and
that's what happens with these plants if
you put too much fertilizer in the soil
if you put any for I don't put any
fertilizer the first time you grow it
because you may not need it ever you
know you got to watch these plants very
carefully they grow so quickly that you
know that when the whitefly or whatever
decides to hit it all of a sudden it's
gone through the stage where the where
the you know the right kind of juice
it's wait a minute what happened to my
plant it's not the same plant anymore
and the insect moves on I mean these
don't need a lot of care now you gotta
keep an eye out for mildew and the kinds
of things that you normally do but they
quo so quickly that that that if you if
you push them too much they're not gonna
grow well the only thing I do to mine to
start when I buy a seed from somebody I
don't know what you know whether it's
gonna be any good
I put the mycorrhizal fungi on it and
that is all I do
and generally I've never had to
fertilize any of my plants and they grow
so fast for those of you who grow indoor
especially in tents you don't really
have enough time to screw them up and
that's fantastic right you know I had
never heard your example Jeff about the
the plant growing through the stage of
life that appealed to any particular
pest but that makes sense the first
round I did I've got no mold issues no
pest issues and and we're you know where
I live on Vashon Island we don't have
that much pest but we always get mold
right and and it's just that their life
cycle is so short a lot of that stuff
doesn't have a time to take over and
they've been bred to get rid of the mold
so I know the good the people that grow
at new breed seeds that's what they were
looking for more let's get rid of that
mold and they did in terms of being able
to use these plants for different
medical conditions I always defer to dr.
Ethan Rousseau who is somewhere out here
so I'm not going to speak to exactly
what type of compounds are going to help
for particular ailment all we know is
that all of these different compounds
are very useful and trying to figure out
exactly how to triangulate and make use
of those compounds and get them into
plants in a way that's useful for for
patients and for people across the world
is is really our goal so when we look at
different plants from a breeding
perspective what we're really trying to
do is we need photo period plants for
very particular locations we need plants
are gonna flower early but they're still
photo period sensitive and we need auto
flowering plants so that you can deploy
these these plants in basically once
you've developed a particular chemo bar
you can deploy them anywhere in the
world and that's really what makes these
different compounds available to people
so having CBD varieties having CPG
varieties CVC rich plants more
importantly now working on CBD v cv g'v
and
cbcb along with other other minor
compounds that we don't even know how to
quantify and don't have reference
standards for all of those are
incredibly important and not just from a
from a from a patient perspective being
able to grow it at home and take care of
your own family or take care of yourself
through the joy of actually gardening a
plant there's something emancipatory
about being able to do that I think
everybody feels that but being able to
make sure that those compounds are
available at scale at a price that
individuals can actually afford to treat
themselves so it's it's pretty important
and these plants make that possible one
one good example of that is being able
to use the plasticity of auto flowering
plants for a particular ecological niche
so most most people here are probably
familiar with how much grass seed the
Willamette Valley produces so well well
I'm a ballet so them to 95 percent of
the world's grass seed production we're
able to grow grass seed in the
Willamette Valley for better for worse
due to the climate the climate that we
have so we don't normally get rain in
the Willamette Valley through the middle
of July up until the middle of August we
have a month of generally speaking very
very dry conditions and it allows a
competitive advantage of grass seed
farmers who have good irrigation and
great soil to be able to grow this
particular crop cut it down field dry it
it sits in the field for five to seven
days and then it gets combine and picked
up no other place in the world has that
steady climate that allows for that
particularly even though you know most
people like food rather than lawns but
no one else is able to really do this we
can actually do the same thing and use
this technique illogical advantage
paired with a technological and
horticultural advantage by using these
auto flowering plants to plant thousands
of acres of very rare and useful
compounds that are present in these
plants after specific breeding grow them
out and dry them in a way that doesn't
require a huge drying infrastructure
that you would you would have to have
for other crops or in other locations
it's a it's a huge I think it's a huge
step forward in terms of being able to
make these compounds available make them
an everyday thing so that you can
literally walk into any supermarket and
find something that
is useful and targeting a particular
malady we just need to figure out
exactly what those come which is which
yeah right on
I've got to follow up questions for
yourself the first one is is you know I
hear from a lot of folks when I went you
know I've become kind of an evangelist
for Auto flowers because I'm so into
them but people people come up to me and
they're like like you know we don't want
Auto flowers because we can't breed with
them and and they're they're not for
everybody and I want my nine-foot plants
and you already dispelled tonight the
short plants thing I didn't I did not
know they were a taller but um but I
like that you just said that there are
particular nature environments where you
want the photo period some that are
photo period but finish early and then
there's Auto flowers I've not heard that
analysis before so will you go a little
more in depth in there why do we still
need the other two categories oh we
don't it's just it's nice to have
diversity well we do we do need them I
mean we need them to breed with because
the land race trains our photo period
and so we need those so I mean we need
them a good example is I when we're this
is something that a lot of us living in
in a black market it was difficult to be
able to get information about the way
that people produce in other areas of
the country or other areas of the world
a great example is Kentucky and
Tennessee so Kentucky and Tennessee have
incredibly wet July August and September
and then they have the very into
September and then through October they
have perfect weather and it's it's
almost like what Oregon is like in late
August early September before the rains
hit so it's most of us know here we need
to make sure that our plants are out of
the field taking care of harvested dried
properly handled it if it's not done by
the middle of September you're really
you're really pushing yourself you
really chancing it in those areas it's
it's the opposite you want to actually
get your plants out at the end of
October so in that case a long season a
full season photo period sensitive plant
is really the way to go if you if you
have it if you have an auto flowering
plant in certain areas you can plant
your
flowers in early may go back and replant
in mid-july and end up getting to crops
and and basically double the
productivity of what you have available
to you see unless you live in Alaska
where you let have six plants three of
which are allowed to be in flower you
know so I always tell people don't treat
this like broccoli you know where you
plant it all at once you stagger it and
I don't mean you wait for the crop them
to harvest you know every two weeks or
every week you put it in a couple of
more seeds and then when the regulator
comes to your house you go now I got
three in flower
you know forget the fact that I got 50
pounds of drying weed over here but but
but they really are everything you say
again sort of emphasizes the idea that
home gardener would you know people grow
heirloom tomatoes you know you married
Mary and next-door neighbor she's famous
because she's got the Oregon summer
spring and and George next door is
famous because his are plum tomatoes
gonna make the best sauce you know and
they give them away and and that's the
same thing that's gonna happen with
these auto flours mine look at the
colors on this one look at the landscape
capabilities on this one you know
they're not they're gonna be landscape
plants they're gonna be a plant that
everybody except we've got to get rid of
that stigma but it's happening and this
is the plant that's gonna carry us over
the line I'm convinced and help the big
plants as well so I really like what you
said too about neighbors sharing right
because if if we all have got plant
limits we're limited by our variety and
you know it's just like tomatoes right
you know if you grow tomatoes at home
you're still gonna end up buying
Tomatoes at the store it's not like
commercial tomato growers are all hosed
because we're all growing at home
tomatoes you buy the ones at the store
so you get the seeds so you can grow
them yourself okay but but this is
another great idea because neighbors can
you know grow different varieties and
trade and it creates increased community
and everybody gets to try more wheat
right yeah and so that's the win as well
so last year in the a at the Alaska
State Fair they actually in Kenai they
had a cannabis entry thing and I'm
convinced every every State Fair in the
country is gonna have a Auto flower
cannabis contest you know I mean it's
just this is the best thing that ever
happened to our industry because it's
gonna get mom and
pop and uncle Bonnie and Sally who
normally would be against it into it and
that's what we really need so we can get
the taxes out of it
amen amen I will say that they are a
pain in the ass why from a breeding
perspective so we make feminized seed we
don't use males and if you can come to
me with a good argument as to what is
actually contained in the male genome
that's useful and how you can access and
figure out what those traits are I'm
open to having my mind change that's
what science is about but the way that
we operate is we make feminized seed and
we use females because it allows us to
know what the chemo type is to know what
the terpene profiles are to know what
the potency is the flower structure and
then be able to figure out how that's
inherited from generation to generation
auto flowering plants are a different
animal in the sense that when you plant
that seed that clock is ticking you
can't just go oh hey that's a great
plant well I'll just revenge it and get
some cuttings off of it and use it for
breeding it's done a great example of
this last year we were I was working
through and about 20 different CBG rich
plants trying to figure out what the the
average ratio of CBG to THC was to
identify which plants we could use or at
least what the frequency was for
developing really really high ratio
plants and one of the individuals from
that population we sent the the results
into a third party lab after we tried to
screen them in house and they came back
and said whoa 50% of your total
cannabinoid profile was a compound that
we've never seen before it's not a
terpene it looks like a cannabinoid from
its molecular weight but we don't have
any reference standards to be able to
identify what it is and this is this is
Pyxis in portland they're a very good
lab they have more cannabinoids
available to them than most labs in the
country and very good equipment very
well trained personnel and the person I
was interacting with said can you send
me another sample and I'm tearing my
hair out saying that was the only plant
that was it it's gone it's gone you you
can't get that back and so you go back
and grow hundreds of those plants out
and you never find that same plant again
so for a structured breeding program
when you're trying to isolate these
individual compounds
and turn them into useful field ready or
homegrown we're ready seeds it poses a
significant challenge because you only
have a certain amount of time we have
literal professionals now working at our
company who are trying to find other
ways of making this happen and it's this
is a it's a significant technological
challenge so there's ways around it but
it takes a ton of space a ton of time
and a lot of motivation to to really be
able to isolate them so just a they're a
different animal when it comes to the
breeding stampin that's from a
professional perspective from you know
real amateur perspective if you take two
auto flowering plants and and breed them
together you can breed them and they're
fun nine weeks holy crowing all of a
sudden you know my wife just like big
guys do you know what I mean but it's
really kind of fun and the idea that you
can get somebody's you know genetics and
now I could be careful they talk about
sorry folks I joke here you know too
soon too soon
you know you get somebody's great
genetics as an amateur can I fool around
with the stuff a little bit you know
these guys obviously but you can you can
fool around with it and and you can do
it all winter long and you know under 20
hours of light you can do it all night
long if I mean it's just this is a fun
fun plant to grow yeah it can be
difficult and it can cause some problems
and if you're a professional grower
you got to adjust yourself a little bit
but boy if you are a professional grower
you're growing medical cannabis get into
these auto flowers see what you think
see if we can't improve the ability to
get more medicine out there and it it's
it I think it's a really important point
to you you brought up the historical
reference back to the low rider
varieties from 2003 that was a shitty
plan oh but the waters are worse I grew
some of that and it just made me sick to
smoke I mean it's horrible the terpene
profile was terrible the structure was
not great but you can see the promise
you could you could see the promise and
what it took was small-time breeders who
were working under either medical
programs or in
garage surreptitiously to improve those
plants and it wasn't until 2010 that I
finally consumed something that changed
my mind about auto flowering plants
someone had taken one of DJ shorts
blueberry varieties merci and dominant
with a number of different minor terpene
different Terp minor terpenes that end
up making it a very calm anti-anxiety
experience and it's a it's a beautiful
piece of work but they finally instilled
that into an auto flowering plant that
made the effect and the flavor just as
good or better than a lot of the other
commercially available varieties at the
time and that was that was the no you're
right the early ones
interesting but they weren't any good
and that's why you know I remember I
remember there's a listserv called
auto-flowering net which we kid about
they they threw me off because I I got
on it and I say gee I'm writing this
book I need some pictures and they threw
me off so I finally thanks this angle
got back on again and Ted has but but
you know when they first started you
would be on grass city or one of those
other forms and you say oh I'm growing
OTO flowers people laughed at you they
made fun of the other you were
stigmatizing basically you were drummed
out of the community so somebody started
the auto for auto net you know and if
you go back in the way you know people
were just sort of struggling services
and around 2008/9 somewhere right in
that area they hit the sweet spot you
know and then they started laughing at
other people in the pictures oh my god
and on Instagram just yesterday I saw
one somebody had a one of these movies
where it went from seed to harvest you
know in two seconds Oh fabulous I'm
telling you folks get some seeds you are
going to love these and and you know I
love to buy feminized seeds for for my
own home growing and to help patients
right because being able to take males
out of the mix if you're not breeding
them this is this is a win but right now
there are still lots of auto flower
seeds that are being sold regs right so
you're gonna get boys and girls and so
you know if you if you really if you
just want the flowers and you
want to play with the plant as Jeff is
suggesting get yourself some like
fantastic modern you know feminized
seeds from like Mephisto genetics or
somebody who's got a good reputation and
it's all very plug and play just like
Jeff is describing but if you want to
enjoy that that extra horticultural
experience of making something that did
not exist in the world until you did it
you know find yourself a pack of auto
flour reg seeds and pop a couple of them
that you think sound interesting and
it's really easy to collect male pollen
you know you take you take a branch and
put it in a bag and you shake it a
little bit now you got a bag up on and
you walk through the other side or maybe
your friend's house and you've got a
paintbrush and you put some of that
pollen on there and yeah you paint it on
to one branch of the plant and then when
you're done next year you're gonna have
like you know 40 or 50 seeds and and
like you said you get to name it which
can be the most fun part but you don't
have to wait till next year that's the
other thing I mean you know these things
grow indoors really well you know in
Anchorage we're really excited about
about the opportunity to grow these
things because we got a photo period at
the same time we get the frost man this
is gonna just change our whole world
right on so you talk about the low rider
old kima bar you know a lot of people
nowadays still consider them cute right
but professionals are like men you know
this is this is just something on the
side that isn't gonna you know matter to
the rest of us but then you know you
meet Seth and you you walk acre upon
acre of these beautiful plants in
September and the air is filled with
terpenes and you know you're just like
oh my gosh I want to lay up and let my
content and just like live here right
and so what I'd like to hear from you
both are you know commercial
applications right or and specifically
let's let's talk about yield and quality
because it's one thing that it's all
incredibly easy and we can grow them
intense but but a lot of people are
thinking about you know
scale for commercial and also am I gonna
get enough flour for my effort for home
grow so so I'd like you both to kind of
speak to
that option well here in Oregon I mean I
would start with new breed seeds frankly
they're in there you know they're from
Oregon they were the first ones to get
their license to be able to sell seeds
and and they are growing for commercial
growers I think the last time I spoke to
them they said yeah you know selling the
seeds at the dispensaries just a pin
yeah so they want to go home and there
are lots of commercial growers that are
using these things for a couple of
reasons
all the ones we've already discussed if
you're growing indoors on racks if you
get the right size plant double racks
triple racks you know you can use the
whole stealing all the way up to the
ceiling the space on these things make
it so that you can interspace them in
between existing plants which is really
a useful thing to do you you know you've
already got the heat you've already got
the light if you're indoors and to be
able to interspace a little small plant
that's not going to detract from the
bigger plants that you're trying to grow
there's you know it doubles your ability
to get more income as a result of doing
this stuff so I so in that regard it's
important and then of course the idea
that you can get something in seven nine
you know if you want to go longer 12
weeks Wow
I mean from a commercial perspective if
the yield is good and the and and and
the power is good if that's the probably
the terpene spectrum you know you're
there why would you want to grow
anything but so so I really highly
encourage you to try these they're
really quite something and to contact
you know people like new breeze season
and get names of other commercial
breeders that are doing it go see what
they're doing we all share information
that's what we do so oh I'm glad you
reminded me of that too before you
answer I want to plug with the correct
URL Auto flower dotnet yeah and cuz this
is a Jeff story with spot on right the
these were the people who were laughed
off of other forums for using Auto
flowers and so they decided to create
their own where they could be misfit
toys together and so you know one of the
things that we've lost in our scene I
think as people God have gotten more
money focused is everybody's got I pee
now and everybody wants to hide and
protect things and you know back in the
day outside of just like not wanting to
go to jail people were real
open to sharing within the community
sharing best practices swapping seeds
all this kind of stuff which which
you're seeing less on the commercial
side but you're still seeing on this
group at Auto flower net because they
are they are all trying to learn from
each other they are sharing best
practices because they haven't mattered
for a while
and it really excites me to see some of
the leaders in that particular community
knowing what's good things are gonna be
like in three or four years when Auto
flowers just falls off people's lips so
easily and and these people will be the
new generation of superstars and and
that you know that's cool when when
people who I love an underdog story
right so so so say have some of the best
bud porn I've ever seen yeah the photos
are just incredible so so Seth going
back to you um specifically you know the
the people that you are sowing seed to
are growing at acreage size right and
and and when people are I mean you don't
have to give people pitches about your
seeds anymore but but just for the sake
of this conversation what does that
pitch sound like when they're all like
you know like really you want me to you
know plant a whole field of these what
are essentially still probably gonna be
smaller plants what's the name of the
company again which one yours
uh we don't advertise right I owe you
like five emails so we can't we can't
handle the advertising right now
honestly we we don't pitch it to people
people come to us and say hey I really
want to try this I really want to try
this and we say no you don't it's really
hard you're gonna [__] up you're not
gonna do it right it's taken us it took
us three years to figure out how to get
the plants in the field without having
flowering in trays and actually getting
a good yield this year we're moving on
to large-scale field trials for
different density of planting and we've
stepped back and we're actually putting
it into the hands of much more competent
farmers who've been farming other crops
for their entire life and how many
cultivars that's such a technically how
many different kinds of plants roughly
one okay
not really
yeah there's a number a number of
different varieties out there it all
comes down for us it's not about
cultivars ours are chemo types we look
at plants as having very particular
chemical compounds that are replicable
generation after generation should
correct it it's okay don't worry but
it's it really it comes down to trying
to figure out how you in the same way
that you're describing maximizing space
in a small area inside this is how do
you maximize the productivity on a per
acre basis over thousands of acres and
it really comes down to what we've seen
with successful farmers is either direct
seeding which is wrought with all kinds
of problems that most of you probably
don't care about but it all comes down
to the depth of the the planting of the
seed and you're talking about literally
millimeters will make or break success
down and then the other side of it is
the density of planting for both weed
suppression and to maximize lateral
minimize lateral branching and force the
plants to basically just turn into one
solid flower that's that's really what
we're looking at this year I and then I
would say for 2020 dad definitely will
be ready for you to buy autoflowering
seeds both type 3 CBD rich plants and
type 4 Pierce EBG lines so what are the
other advantages amines clearly the
short cycle is great for scaled
agriculture but when I visited your farm
you were mentioning some other things
like the fact that the plants are
uniform so they're really easy to repeat
cut on a sled cut on a slit so so what
are the what are the you know
traditional farming advantages of this
plant versus the photoperiod ones the
the main one in it again it's gonna
depend your location in certain areas
you can't cut the plant down and let it
dry in the field and a lot of people
have had questions about that we did our
our team did some amazing experiments
this last summer long hours in the field
very hot conditions harvesting about 15
acres that believe it was about 38,000
plants in the early August cutting him
down laying him down in the field to
basically cook at 100 degrees during the
day
and then grind him up and put him into
totes just to see how much CBD would be
lost and what the terpene loss was going
to be and what we found was about you're
gonna lose about two thirds of your
terpenes they're very volatile they just
they vaporize they're gone but there's
still enough to be able to get some some
efficacy from the entourage effect
depending on the type of terpenes that
you're working with and their their
volatility the heavier sesqui terpenes
tend to stick around the the really
volatile monoterpenes are always going
to be gone but the moral of the story on
that was that CBD content did not change
there was no statistical difference
between plants that were cut down and
dried in the field versus plants that
were cut down and hung up in a warehouse
so again that's a that's a great thing
if you happen to have a very dry late
very dry late July early August but if
you have a rainy period that may not
necessarily be the plant that you want
to use so it's it's really about like
any farming or any any cannabis
production it's about being able to use
the plasticity of the plant to adapt to
your own local ecosystem and climate
right on so Seth I'm gonna give you a
particular question here it's just a
sniglet off topic but but it's very it's
very important for where we are today
and and what I want to ask you is you
know you're you know you have particular
experience in the dangers of pollen
contamination right and you know since
both feminized and regular Auto seeds
exist I think this would be a good
moment for you to make your pitch for
for you know running you know not
running males outdoors I'd love you to
share the story about your valley just
to make everybody more aware of the
dangers of pollen if you if you have a
pollinated crop and you're growing
outside you're gonna lose 30 percent of
your total cannabinoids and 50% of your
biomass that the seed is a tremendous
energy-sapping creation that that ends
up taking the power away from your
plants in reducing the not only the
profit the profitability but the actual
amount of cannabinoids that you can
harvest outdoors
I know Oregon at this point we're trying
to launch
a nonprofit organization that will help
in the future in terms of creating
buffer zones between farms so that we
don't have issues of pond contamination
see Oregon cannabis pinning Association
OC PA org it's the only thing they'll
advertise today hopefully and we're
really just kind of in a we're trying to
raise awareness this year and then
actually move into a more formal pinning
system for 2020 but pollen outdoors is a
huge issue and there are a number of
people who are either growing regular
male/female seeds or trying to create
seed outdoors just because you can
produce so much it's it's a tremendously
productive way to make seed but we've
had to basically go to a lot of
small-time breeders who are saying oh
man this is the big rush I want to make
sure that I can make a bunch of seed
this year and then sell it for next year
not knowing that in doing so not only
are they not going to get a successful
crop because there's other people who
are doing that and now you have a
contaminated crop yourself with no
purity that you won't be able to sell if
you're a moral or ethical person but
you're also going to destroy all of your
surrounding neighbors ability to
actually grow a crop and have something
that's valuable at the end of the year
so it really comes down it's a it's a
touchy subject for a lot of people but
it is definitely in terms of being able
to create an environment thing that we
all can continue to produce cannabis in
in an environment that our kids can
potentially continue to produce cannabis
in Oregon is one of those really really
lucky spots we're in a sweet spot we can
grow good stuff
we have great breeders we have good
water we have good land but we really
need to make sure that we can protect
that and its pollen travels a long ways
long ways it's it's dangerous and I
think that you know these these pollen
exclusion zones which I even call Youm
do you have an actual official name for
him sounds good
yeah pollen exclusion zone yeah so
that's what I've been calling it to
people and and the first time that Seth
posted about this on their Instagram it
was ugly you know that the thread was
mostly people saying you know you know
you will not tell me what to do with my
property , dammit
you know and
Santo you want to control the seeds yeah
exactly and you know and I get where
people are coming from because I don't
like to be told what to do either but
what it is it's a it's an it's an
economic and horticultural opportunity
for right we're almost all of us live
here and so what we're seeing is that
you know just like Napa Valley right
they are growing world-class wine but
there are certain things that the
community has all agreed to do and not
do so that they don't screw up the the
you know the wineries and and their
ability to grow grapes because it brings
so much economic power to the region and
for me that's what I see for for these
beautiful valleys throughout Oregon
where they can where they can you know
they've already got hemp farmers it is a
burgeoning industry that is is
lightyears ahead of many of the rest of
the parts of the world that are going to
try to follow up and when you have a
lead even though I don't want anybody to
tell me what to do with my property
either I really hope that those people
would keep open minds because the the
the reasons for not growing pollinating
cannabis plants outdoors make a lot of
sense for the oregon community and and i
think that it is lost on a lot of people
because they aren't they haven't let
their ears be open to the argument yet i
think people think it's about control
and the the problem with this is that
it's not about trying to prevent people
from making seed i encourage people to
go go go do it like i've said before
it's emancipatory not only to grow it
but to breed it and then see the outcome
it's it's a it's a beautiful thing and
it's part of what makes us human we all
could probably agree that people have a
right to fire right you can have a fire
on your property that's cool until it
jumps your fence and burns down your
neighbor's house at that point that's
your liability it's not your fire and
that's really what we're looking at
everyone in oregon has a right to farm
but you don't have a right to exclude
other people from being able to engage
in meaningful economic activity that not
only is helping that themselves but
helping other people isn't the general
motto
your fun ends when the other guy's
displeasure begins and so you do not
have a right to plant seeds outside I
would say you don't have a right to do
it period if it's gonna impact your
neighbor you don't have that right and
also for for folks who are thinking
about doing you know three four plants
in your backyard and you're gonna bring
in a mail that's way different than
we're talking about you know growing a
KERS of regular seeds Russian next-door
to look no it's fine or we've had to
take because of that and and we don't
want to stop anybody from having that
right but to be able to protect our
interests we had to make sure that our
greenhouses are sealed we only make seed
in places that we're comfortable making
it and then once it comes out we still
have to test it just to make sure that
it is what we what we think it is and to
let you know that Seth practices what he
preaches it is really crazy to go into
their breeding warehouses or greenhouses
because they are they suck you in right
so that none of the pollen escapes would
you open it they've got they've got all
the air being pulled in this into a into
a filter so that you open the door and
then you're sucked in so that all the
pollen is kept inside and that's cool
right yeah straight hair before he went
in yeah so alright so the last thing I
want to hit because we're wrapping up
here is I want to go back you know leave
a little bit of the the the breeding
analytic stuff and talk specifically
about the smoke right because because
you know most everybody in here probably
enjoys the taste and the experience of
cannabis and and you know I've I've
smoked the stuff that you grow for
extraction right and some of the stuff
that you grow for extraction these like
like like let's tear up these flowers
right and look right and I take him home
and smoking like yeah this is this is
really good flower right and so let's
hit on just real quickly the fact that
you know it may be convenient it may be
great for the valley
it may be good for patients it may be
extractable but it's good smoke - let's
start with you Jeff because I know that
you love you know Auto flower net and
and and seeing those so so we'll give
your plug for auto flower taste
yeah so I'm a vaporizer III vaporize
flower
I haven't combusted in maybe three years
there's a wonderful web website
incidentally called FC combustion and
you can guess what the FC stands for but
these Auto flowers they taste just like
stuff and the numbers on it if you're if
you're into numbers I think it's a
fool's game you know if you can't get if
you can't get stoned cuz your number is
only six percent THC take another hit
for God's sakes you know the idea that
you gotta buy a thirty to get store
anyway
they taste delicious they have this the
aisles are phenomenal and you know I
when I do it with other people a lot of
times my for my friends up in Anchorage
they go man these things grow so fast
they don't have time to to write you
know I said what are you talking about
there's nothing bad taste you know
obviously the guy was very stoned they
are just like regular cannabis they
didn't used to be but they are now and I
would defy you to tell the difference
between vaporizing and Laurel flower and
vaporizing a regular photo period there
there is no difference whatsoever I
would agree with that and it's 65 to 70%
of them are mere scene dominant so what
we're seeing out I was fun to walk
through and take a look at the the
flowers that were entered for the
competition this year and see the
different terpene profiles and watch the
evolution of what growers and breeders
are targeting at this play go through
and count how many are mere scene
dominant this year compared to years
past versus turpin alene dominant plants
that's that's a big thing it's your your
your fuel flavor your diesel flavor
Turpin a lean beta carry awfully and
alpha pining we're seeing that now
emerge in in auto flowering plants
and it's a little bit more difficult
with auto flowering plants just because
of the the breeding that we were talking
about earlier but they definitely pack
all of the flavor and to be perfectly
honest the the potency as well out of
our type four high CBG varieties that
we've developed the individual plant
that has far in a way had the highest
overall CBG percentage was an auto
flowering plant and it came in at almost
16% CBG was over 17% CB GA before addi
carbing so it's it's definitely possible
to create absolutely terpene rich
cannabinoid heavy and diverse chemo
types with with these day neutral plants
and and i know that you're having the
analytics and you test everything
in-house do their numbers come out
comparable to photosensitive plants as
well on average they tend to be a little
bit lower but it also depends on the way
that you treat them in the light
spectrum don't they also have a little
bit more CBD yeah you can change any of
those from an amateur Rohr seems to me
that there there's always CBD in my auto
flowers but but I'm not sure there isn't
my bigger plants I don't know but yeah
we haven't seen that cbc there is a
little bit more CBC there at least there
tends to be and that that actually it
depends on the varieties that you're
looking at but it is it is definitely
present amount of flowering plants let's
just spell another rumor about taste I
know that you spend a lot of time
breeding them and a lot of people say
okay so this is a cookies Otto flower so
essentially that means that's cookies
crossed with a ruderalis plant and a lot
of people say that Rudy Rudy plants
tastes like crap right so so what do you
have to say about people saying that
there's all this like this this
ruderalis terpenes coming along for the
ride there used to be I think that used
to be a valid a valid valid distinction
one of the main things to consider as
well is normally what you're trying to
do in a breeding program is look at the
f2 so you take two parents that are very
divergent across them and then do it
either an open pollination or a targeted
selfing in the the f1 generation and
then you have f2 plants that exhibit
every possible
combination or permutation that you can
possibly imagine it's where the most
diversity is expressed if you're a plant
breeder that's where you should be
looking for amazing things if you have a
specific terpene profile that you're
trying to target you can't overlook that
f1 cross because that's that's actually
where you would identify the plants that
have the most similar profiles to
whatever it is that you're trying to
target so yeah you can you can very I
won't say very easily but you could take
a you know a gg4 across it to an auto
flowering plant and then do your initial
selection in that f1 in breed it one
more time and you can you can lock those
terpene profiles in it obviously it
takes more time for stabilization of
traits and that sort of thing but
terpenes and making them taste good we
can do that
absolutely so we're running out of time
here so I'm sure that you want to hear
more from both of these folks so for
Jeff Lowen fells you can find he at
least one episode with him on the
shaping fire podcast if you go to
shaping fire com I also have several of
Jeff's presentations for various
conferences on my youtube channel at
ford slash Shango lowe's seth has been
on my show to talk about both the
new-age CBD auto flowers that are out
there and then again with a really
insightful interview on the the Nexus of
ab CB d and and and him in the the New
Economics of CBD from em and and then of
course don't forget about Jeff's book
coming out in October can order on
Amazon today you can already pre-order
on Amazon now so thank you gentlemen for
joining us it's been very informative
thank you thanks for having us