so Kevin a lot of people are starting to
plan what they're gonna do this summer
right and a lot of people like to road
trip to California purity in California
you want to explore different parts of
the state and I know that you're moving
your operation from this location here
in Humboldt to another location in
Humboldt near the historical one log
location so I want to encourage people
to like pack all their stuff in their
car and come out to your new location
because after I've toured it today and
seen what its gonna be it's you know
it's it's a it's like almost like an
amusement park for cannabis and outdoor
people so so why don't you tell us a
little bit about what people can look
forward to when they visit this new one
log location on Highway 101
I'd love to the one log is a giant
redwood tree that was driven around the
country in the 50s and it's right in
front of our spot and it's hard one of
the most well known redwood landmarks in
all the region and you can go inside the
tree and it's a basically a little house
but it's a good sized house inside of a
treatment and it's just fascinating to
have that historic piece and what we did
is we put in a dispensary and a nursery
that one can go and tour so you can go
to the nursery and look through a window
and see what's going on inside the
nursery itself so for a lot of people
that wanted to see cannabis in a nursery
form they'll have the ability and the
storefront will allow you to be able to
purchase products from our region and
we're also putting in a museum that'll
cover what is Humboldt County from a
land point of view meaning what makes
humble humble and then the history of
Humboldt County's basically exploitation
over the years and then in 68 this
reclamation of a culture we're humble
have been hacked to pieces in gold
mining and lumber and in 68 you have a
back to land movement and from that
movement phowa got the entire cannabis
world we know now in America was built
and we want to be able to show all these
components because they've never really
been showing we always show
pharmacopoeia which is cannabis medicine
that was allowed before they I want it
and then hemp
but this is actually cannabis people
growing cannabis duck in the helicopters
the end or revolution the big plant
revolution how to fifteen really changed
the region how Prop 60 for the new
legalization has changed the region and
then from that point twenty eighteen
forward what's our future with cannabis
in Humboldt County and also really it
mirrors what what's our future was
humpin with cannabis in all small
counties like humble and that museum is
what I'm excited about because it's the
first time we've ever got to really do
something like that where you get to
cover what were pot growers but like you
said to a model in camouflage with a bag
I mean they're coming up with all these
mock-ups of what it looked like for
people in the bushes carrying soil bags
climbing up hills ducking helicopters
what did indoor growers look like that
where entire buildings that were filled
with grows what had underground bunkers
look like what was a grow dozer which is
the super trucks Witter what's the
significance in generators where so much
of the indoor revolution was created
under generator power these are all the
things that people have to understand so
they can understand this evolution of an
industry so that they don't believe that
the industry was created January 1st
2018 and this new industry that we see
today somehow happened overnight on its
own with no history behind it and it's
the history behind it that lets you see
an evolution and lets you be aware of
choices and directions and how we got to
those directions and hopefully it allows
the people who see it to be able to make
better decisions on how they purchase
cannabis and how they view cannabis and
how possibly they even produce cannabis
so they get to realize that this was
really a true homegrown movement people
didn't come to Humboldt to grow pot they
came here to escape the world in 1968
and they wanted a counterculture life
that was less violent more communal more
holistic and in the process cannabis was
cultivated and then all of a sudden it
started to be sold and it organically
through this model the history of
Humboldt County cannabis is very much
like Dennis perón's model of medical
cannabis we're friends of his were ill
he created a situation that allowed
people to get free cannabis because they
noticed that the people who were ill did
better with cannabis he creates the
first cannabis clubs he creates the
first real social network with regular
people who didn't have real connect
could come there and be treated
compassionately meaning that you and you
are not ostracized for your lack of
money or your lack of social rank or
your choices with your sexuality or
color or religion
Dennis Peron didn't care who you were if
you need a cannabis you could come in
and if you could afford it he would buy
it and if you didn't use get it free
that was the basis of Humboldt County's
culture the same thing they they're
they're they're very important to
understand because it lets you see how
the humans behave when they're allowed
to behave that way and the beautiful
things that occur and it's important I
think for people to know this so that
they realize that regular people made
this happen
regular people created compassionate
cannabis regular people created the
industrial cannabis model were in now
and it allows you to say I got you it
wasn't created by these big companies or
these these big branded firms it was by
regular small people who did this which
means you're still very valid and that
you have an ability to make change
yourself and I think that when you see
these things that empowers people to
realize that and whatever you're into in
life you may have way more impact that
you have a believed and you
see these four these iconic figures and
iconic times and iconic places to really
appreciate it and when you do that it
empowers you in a way that you can
connect with because you're like wow the
cannabis is gonna be a trillion dollar
industry globally and in the United
States which is really driving this
thing forward so hard in a in a large
financial point of view it was created
by a bunch of people who were barefoot
in the hills you know basically
hillbillies and that's a huge statement
because it wasn't created by these mega
companies that said look this is what
cannabis should be what they're doing is
they're taking what cannabis was and
they're just repackaging it and with a
nicer TV set telling you this is what it
should look like and for me I want you
to be able to go back in time and
understand what drove this situation and
that's the beauty of the museum
component and the museum lets us bring
in locals we can then advertise the
locals that do production or have a
history in cannabis we can then sell
their products at the store the location
is got a setup in the back for music and
for just basic lounging to where we
don't have any official smoking spaces
but people can pull off the road enjoy
the museum check out the shop there's a
coffee shop and a restaurant connected
to it but in the back there's a
beautiful park you can come and just
take a break in and sit down and enjoy
and realize that Apple County life was
beautiful life the cannabis fueled a
lifestyle that was really holistically
healthy and it was only later on that it
became this incredible money chase where
people there kind of little lost in the
in the pursuit but the root of it is the
most beautiful route and that's what we
want to pull back and show is that the
roots of this industry and not dirty and
they don't need to be hidden that you
don't need
shamed and it allowed the region to be
able to get a little different view and
I'm really excited about it
so for people who want to come out and
and check out the museum and see some of
the awesome rare photographs you've
gotten some of the cool models and they
want to pick up some local product at
your dispensary you know I saw the
beautiful lush field in the back um what
are a couple of the big music events
that people can focus on because if
they're gonna even come out anyway they
might as well come out for from one of
these events and really you know be able
to have a whole experience while they're
there maybe spend the weekend oh yeah no
we're really fortunate that we're right
next door to French's camp which is the
site of northern Knights the Electronic
Music Festival and subsequently we're
right next door the same Frenchy's camp
where they have reggae on the river and
so both of these events have been
historically I think northern Knights is
in its 6th year reggae might be in its
30th 30th plus year maybe even a little
longer I think I've been in like 24 25
26 of them I've been in so many Africa
and they're really awesome festivals
because they're outside on the river and
they have been purchased by larger
companies that have the ability to help
with production a lot of these smaller
festivals needed assistance because
everything's so expensive nowadays and
in producing these things and so High
Times was able to lease the reggae on
the river and then the Emerald cup crew
which was Tim Blake and I believe a red
light or the truck permit of the name of
his exact name of the guy that he works
with they're gonna take on the northern
night's crew with the existing northern
Knights crew so that what you have is
you have some combined production on
these different venues and the events
then can really succeed and shine and
they're killer so if you've ever wanted
to see an electronic music festival that
goes on for a while that's in I believe
July and then the first weekend of
August of every year's reggae so if you
make it to one of these events we're
literally right next door to them on the
drive way through so just look to your
left and you'll see the one log and come
on and visit and there's there's cabin
lodging there's camping there's even VIP
you know five-star lodging down the road
so your beautiful towels in the area the
Bimbo's down the street so you have some
really upscale stuff and you also have
some really normal stuff too so like the
old river yeah you can escape your life
from the concrete and come to Humboldt
with this very little of it and so it
allows you and it's not that far I mean
really talking about three hours from
the Bay Area and 101 is a straight pipe
line up and it's very simple you can't
get lost that that makes it relatively
convenient and when you come up here
you're in you're in a world that makes
you think you're back in time and I
think for so many people that they need
it and the festival isn't harmful to
typically QD very nonviolent very little
trouble people are trying their best to
enjoy each other as people so it makes
this beautiful type of environment
that's unique and for anyone who hasn't
had a chance to check out the stuff here
I recommend it whether we were in the
shop or not it's really the festivals
themselves have been super natural for
the region and so many people have
fallen in love with Humboldt because
they came here to see music and they met
the locals and realized wow guys we're
all right and the locals here aren't
just men it's men and women and all ages
and all colors and all sexes so Humboldt
is one of the most really diverse group
of production grids in the world where
everybody who came here was accepted as
long as you didn't want to rat out your
neighbor and you didn't you're all right
and so you get to experience this really
genuine open type of situation that you
don't really get in life too much you're
in you're on urban areas that no one
wants to talk but here you can actually
sit down and have a conversation and
feel good and it's a it's just I'm so
happy that they were able to put the the
production teams together to keep these
festivals run in and now we have a long
term stability on both of them and it
should really shine the region should
shine because of it right now so we'll
see you this summer at the one log
location on highway 101 on Bull County
alright
damn so will you turn that off the next
question I don't want to have record