foreign
[Music]
hi there friends Shango from shapingfire
here and I'm here to tell you about the
Hindi mentality of Michael hinden so
Michael's Hindi mentality was made up of
four parts as I saw it the first one was
clean information Michael had the
cleanest information in an industry full
of Bro Science like cannabis was
Michael's the guy who went and found the
original research right and it wasn't
just cannabis too it doesn't matter if
it was like talking about like you know
a cannabis breeding or or botany in
general or you know dog breeds or you
know some kind of technology or gotta
help you engineering or the planets or
anything right we all know that once you
start talking to Michael about any topic
you could end up anywhere else it was
always an adventure talking with him but
he always had clean information he
always had had you know a couple books
he had read about the topic or and he'd
gone back and found the scientific
papers behind it and and then he
provided you with links right so you
could read that stuff too so so it was
beautiful he had the cleanest
information of anybody number two he
developed those into best practices
right like like just knowing the
information wasn't enough he always
wanted to know how to apply
um this knowledge that he got and so he
would put together best practices
whether or not it was you know about
cannabis breeding or diet or exercise or
or you know you know of anti-fragility
and how he wanted to build the systems
of his life right I mean we've all heard
this from him
um he was always wanting to figure out
how to apply this how-to that he was
picking up from these these books and
documents so then three he would do this
kindness in Sharing right he was always
sharing and um he he did it in this way
that was accepting of wherever I was on
a particular topic you know he didn't he
didn't blow me out of the water with
information he would start slow and kind
of gauge where you were at as a listener
and then he would change change the
vocabulary and how deep he got based on
who you were and so he was always
connecting with people at at their level
to spread his information and
um and the best practices that he had
developed because he wanted everybody to
grow good plants you know he wanted
everybody to have a good life he wanted
everybody to have reduced suffering and
and Michael absolutely believed that
good information was at the key to you
know like decreasing suffering
um so then and then the last part was
like his Joy right his just joy in
living everything that Hindi was doing
he liked doing
um you know he put joy in everything he
got up and he lived his day with joy if
he was going to a con you know a
conference or something he was joyful
there
um you know if you're just getting tacos
with him right he was he was happy about
having tacos with you
um and and it's that approach to life
that really made Michael stand out to me
and then once we got talking all the
information stuff filled it in and
really you know became the base of a
basis of our friendship so so you know
what the Hindi mentality means to me in
that clean information beautiful best
practice is that he shared kindly with
other resulting in a joyous life that
that he lived from beginning to end so
uh yeah that's uh that's the Hindi
mentality to me