so Jeff you know a lot of people may
have respect for Verma castings or worm
castings or worm poop right yeah for
good reason and um for for most people
though they see it as a good organic
nitrogen source but you know from
reading your books I've realized that
that you know that's just the tip of the
iceberg and I think it's important that
people understand how worm castings can
really help the soil food web so we
break that out for us sure well it's
interesting
worms are phenomenal yes just well you
know all the books that people have
written about worms they don't need
another one for me but if there was a
subject I read about worms and ants
would be right there but what happens
with the worm is is that they take in
their their nutrient which is really
just a bunch of microbes they don't care
about that leaf they're pulling into
their body they just want to take a
couple of little bacteria and maybe a
little fun guys so protozoa yummy and
and the rest of it goes right right film
so what comes out of the worm is that
organic material - a few of the microbes
that the worm would adjust itself but an
amazing thing happens inside the worm
that makes it more valuable than just
nitrogen yes there's good nitrogen in
worm castings but there is also somehow
an increase in a number of the elements
that you want to have as nutrients so
phosphorus I list them in the book
teeming with microbes
I can't about five or six of them are
increased five six seven eight times in
concentration as they come out the back
end so what goes into the worm and what
comes out the back end are not the same
in terms of nutrient quality and when it
comes out it comes out in a form that
helps build soil structure and and so
both the increase in nutrients and that
that wonderful friable nature of the
material itself those castings they just
mean
terrific condominium for the soil food
web they are full of nutrients which the
soil food web needs and your plants need
and they still contain a tremendous
number of good microbes in there so for
all of those reasons one casting is
great and the reason why so many people
use worm castings as opposed to just
pure compost or Verma castings is
because of this increased concentration
in these five or six or seven nutrients
so I like that you said that it creates
a good condominium for that good white
web
so it's cuz it's gonna live there right
it creates a good living environment and
you said that it adds to soil structure
right can you break out what exactly you
mean by soil structure sure you know if
you if you look at soil depending on
where you are it has it has a different
feel a different crumble miss cetera et
cetera I mean these are soil structures
how the soil is put together and so in
the soil food web world what happens is
the bacteria they give off a glue in
order to be able to stick themselves
together and that sticks the little
pieces of little in this case it could
stick to those little teeny castings and
then those castings stick to each other
and that begins to form a conglomerate
of soil
these aren't bricks that are not flat
and so you get pore spaces where air and
water can go on little guys tonight from
the big guys so it's that soil structure
and then fungi community they weave
around those little conglomerates and
they make a bigger one and and all of a
sudden and then even if you have the
worm in there you know it goes through
it it's a tunnel a burrow all of this
stuff makes it easier for a plant to
grow the roots can grow between and
around these pore spaces and into these
pore spaces if there happened to be
worms in the Sun they can go right in
the worm hole tunnels and burrows is you
know so so having worms is really a
great thing right on so so this time of
year a lot of us are you looking to
source worm castings and there's there's
lots options we can have our own worm
boxes we can we can buy castings
from a local farmer but also you know
most of us will end up going to a grow
shop and you know they've got they've
got bags that are pure worm castings
which are much more expensive but then
we've got these like worm casting and
some kind of soil mix bags and I always
have a hard time deciding which one to
buy because I like the cheaper price
right but I don't particularly like that
I'm paying for the soil but there might
be a good reason for it so so if you
were gonna guide somebody to one one
product or another what do you think we
should look for we're looking to buy
worm castings like the pure worm
castings myself yeah I never know what
the soil is now of course the label if
it's good soil and I know the people
arts that are embedded in it it's fine
but I am I also at my own compost and so
I use them I also think you have to be
very careful that when you buy worms
yourself that you make sure you get the
right kind of worms there's this worm
that bring it in from Asia as a bait
worm it looks like the regular red
wiggler that we all you know we're
taught to buy at center etc but it's not
and it's the worm that is causing the
Duff to to disappear too quickly in
Michigan fishermen go fishing they don't
catch anything they fill the worms down
on the ground these worms eat a lot of
the duck in six months that should take
two or three years to disappear and then
the next thing you know you you have
garlic mustard move in garlic mustard is
out boy am I getting off point garlic
mustard is allopathic for the
mycorrhizal fungi that feed maple trees
oh so you want to be careful about where
you get the words let's take another
step down that rabbit hole okay so so
you said you know the red wigglers that
we were all taught to buy and the recent
feedback I've been getting for people
they've been recommending picking me
picking up nightcrawlers so so which are
the right worms and does it matter well
I don't know you know the night crawlers
you know they meet they there they're
deep they go deep and we don't have them
in Alaska so I don't have a lot of
experience with them but I know people
that are brought a mineral ask and I'm
beginning to wonder is that a good thing
first of all but all the worms basically
the United States have been imported
wait like all the worms yeah like even
the ones in the Soilers the ones ever
selling no once in the slope came in we
had worms in the United in North America
glaciation came and it destroyed the
worms except a few of them down you know
in the Arizona area there's some what
they call pot worms and they survived
but earthworms didn't and so the
pilgrims came and and worms in the
ballast of their boats rocks tonight
yeah
in Johnny Appleseed or tram blablabla
and about 20-25 years ago I started
getting phone calls from people in the
Anchorage Alaska we said what are they
little bumps of my long people had never
seen a worm wow that's hard to believe
yeah it is I grew up on the East Coast I
mean we we had the biggest compost pile
in the world that worms them that's what
you fished with it the rain anyway it's
very very interesting but worm castings
are very valuable I go for the pure and
the reason is soil structure but also
this has got a high concentration of
nutrients fantastic thank you very much
you're welcome I'll shake
you