so when I'm talking to clients you know
they often are asking me okay help me
envision what this is gonna be going on
five or ten or twenty years down because
they're putting in millions and millions
of dollars and they want to have a
long-term arc of their business and you
know first of all I tell them that
nobody's got a crystal ball and and
thinking that that anybody knows what
what this chaos is gonna look like in
ten or twenty years they're they're
they're overcharging you for their
consulting right whoever it is but at
the same time we all do need to think
about this and two things that will
radically change the oil market when it
happens will be a the allowing of
Interstate Commerce in the u.s. it's
just a matter of time before that
happens and so a lot of these states
that are becoming legal now they've got
these really nice you know oil grows and
any manufacturing setups and they're
great but their margins are there their
cost of doing business is really high
right because of where they live or
their weather or whatever but then as
soon as as soon as people are allowed to
ship over state lines suddenly you know
California and the southern part of the
country are going to be doing this
producing these same products with a
very low cost of business and then wait
until international gets involved and
and Mexico can grow you know this
beautiful flower organic certified if
they choose to process all the oil down
there with like world-class and then and
then just ship up drums of oil and
that's just gonna crush like for example
the edibles market right where where the
you know it's not artisan dab oil it's
it's more of a commoditized oil so I
know that you give good advice to
people both here in the US and around
the world so so what are you telling the
people who seek your advice about how to
think about those two barriers
interstate and then national barriers
coming down as far as setting up local
businesses to provide oil that's that's
a good question because it's economy
scale
and if they start to be able to pull
like CBD drive trips out of hemp and
then with plant infused terpene
infusions all of a sudden you're really
able to make it a very simple method to
create some of these lower quality oil
packages and the question is over the
next 20 years will you be able to
develop a new group of people new
consumers who want to consume the
products that have grown in their region
where they're more aware of locally
produced products that's basically the
hope to me the fundamental about organic
a gizze that if you're really looking at
it part of the organic nature of it is
it isn't being trucked across seven
states to get to your house so it's hard
to say you're an environmental advocate
when you're having stuff shipped in
globally into your neighborhood and so
it's trying to create the awareness that
you want to have local products local
goods because they should be cheaper
unless we're we're so inefficient in our
production and you allow the places that
do bulk oil production to do bulk oil
production and you focus on what you're
supposed to focus on and that's really
the reality of Ag so Humboldt has
problems because we don't a lot of flat
ground and so there's really not a lot
of prime soil there's not a lot of flat
ground so it doesn't allow us to do
massive Central Valley type farming
operations but what we have is a
tremendous amount of clean air and untuk
sic regions because we don't have all
these other industries contaminating and
so that's the problem that you're seeing
in all these massive agricultural areas
is cross contamination so they have to
create these positive pressure
greenhouses to expel any air that's
coming out anything's coming in is
coming into massive filtration systems
well that has to be cost and so it
starts to become so expensive to create
products in areas that were
because cannabis being regulated a
degree that no add product that we've
been regulated and so you can't really
grow cannabis in the wineries that well
because you have so much much of uterine
all applied for all the grapes you can't
use cannabis in the Central Valley to
the same degree if you take a look how
many of these failures are coming from
the Central Valley even the larger
organizations they're having to remodel
the entire greenhouse ranges once they
get all that in it's still unbelievably
expensive infrastructure to provide and
as we go forward does the consumer
become educated enough to realize that
that's industrial cannabis when they
want to buy cannabis are they gonna look
at it like wine at some point where
there's many gradients of quality right
now it's confusing it's just a price in
a store but as people start to become
more aware and I believe that the youth
that are coming in are very cognizant
about these facts because they've been
barred than Barda with a sense of
childhood they didn't get the same
advertising we did that it's a don't
worry about it
these products are good for you fluoride
is great for your teeth you shouldn't
even get as much as you can in your body
now that you know it's a neurotoxin and
it changes how you perceive these
products and I think that for a lot of
the smaller places that have such a risk
it's trying to create zones of enjoyment
where people who really are about the
culture and the quality can know to
source their products and buy them and
that's really over time of educating the
customer so that the customer education
has to
and all we've done is educate them that
cheaper more hot numbers more frosty
better pictures on Instagram or what you
want and that has absolutely nothing to
do with reality and I think it's that
it's the ability to get people to
understand the reality of that these
ugly tomatoes that they won't sell at
the store the exact ones you want to cut
up and eat on your sandwich and that's
why farmers markets sell burn and
hopefully that the new generation is
able to make these decisions and say
look if I want to consume cannabis I'd
like to consume it from craft regions
where the environmental impact is low
where the farmers are known and I'm at a
fair price so the problem is you're
trying to get people to pay higher
prices for this extra effort and you
have a population of people globally
that buy cannabis oh really aren't cash
rich so their disposable income is less
and that's gone if you look at the
global situation so the 1% can afford to
buy what they want but they're not the
cannabis consumers is everyone below
them and so it's trying to be able to
figure out how do the farmers get
themselves into very specific niches of
acknowledgment where people recognize
their products they recognize the region
they recognize the farmer and they
recognize that they're fairly priced and
that starts to allow you to be
competitive and as these products start
to move across the borders then all
other high level products small niche
products move across borders too and so
why wouldn't we be able to move our
products across these borders and allow
the cheaper products to come in to allow
people who have a less price point get
cannabis enjoyment yeah because it's not
about taxing people the death is to
create a gradient where the poorest
person can afford the product the
richest person could afford a product
and they may get different products in
terms of the fine qualities but
fundamentally the poorest person still
has an edible quality product where
there's no toxins no content
and it gives them the effect they desire
and the upper echelon of subtleties that
you have to basically develop a palate
for right to even appreciate it once we
can do that and educate it so really to
me this is a twenty year cycle and
that's the part that's so scary is that
can we survive twenty years