hey there friends
shango from shaping fire here a few
weeks ago segre
international did this webcast on the
history and future of cannabis breeding
and it was just fantastic
i knew that you'd want to check it out
so i reached out to segre international
i said hey can i have copies of the
video for my youtube channel
so that i can share with my audience
directly and they're like yeah we'd love
that it'd be an honor so they sent me
the videos
and today i'm presenting you part one
part two will be out in a few days
so the official title for the panel is
the past
the present and the future of cannabis
breeding and this is part one today
and oh my gosh does it have a top-notch
group of participants on the panel so
first off is ryan lee that you and i all
know is chimera
the famous canvas breeder then there is
rob clark who's essentially
you know the the godfather of cannabis
taxonomy and botany
and then mark lewis from napro research
whose cultivars keep on
uh you know picking up awards at emerald
cup and then
mojave richmond of uh bioeconomics group
who's new to me but adds a lot to
the to the panel as well and then it was
moderated by michael williamson of
catalyst bc
so um this part one covers cannabis
taxonomy
cannabis breeding lineage and historical
milestones in canvas breeding
and then how some of the breeding
vocabulary evolved which is particularly
interesting and how we understand these
words
um so there's also some really great
photos from the
folks um you know personal collections
that i hadn't seen before so
you know historically cool photos are
great um
so it's it's an all-around fantastic
hour and a half to check out so
so i encourage you to check it out come
back for a couple days come back in a
couple days to
see part two you might want to subscribe
to the channel while you're here
and also jump on over and subscribe to
segre international who've got the new
youtube channel
who uh who agreed to share this video
with us so here we go enjoy
i'm going to turn this now over to my
good friend michael williamson who's
going to
moderate the panel for us today michael
himself is no slouch when it comes to
cannabis
he's got a long track record ranging
from founding one of the first licensed
dispensaries in the state of colorado
to breeding some of the interesting
industry's top genetic blinds
and also designing some of the most
sophisticated cannabis grower operations
in the world with his company
catalyst bc so michael i will turn it
over to you
all right appreciate it thanks for the
uh thanks for hosting this event for all
of us we're all excited to be here
um on the panel today i'm super excited
and honored to uh
kind of moderate for uh ryan lee
co-founder of keem of our health
rob clark co-owner of bioeconomic group
mark lewis
president of knapp pro research and
mojave richardson
also co-owner and founder of
bioagronomic group
so to get started guys um i wanted to
kind of
have you guys give a little bit of
pedigree information and one of the
questions that we're looking to answer
here is
when did you guys make your first way
into the cannabis industry
and also at what point and why did you
look into breeding after you got into
cultivation and uh
we'll start with you ryan
well it seems like forever ago um
i got into the cannabis industry quite
early um
well i guess kind of when i was you know
i was a consumer in high school and then
when i got into university
i was you know had a keen interest in
genetics and
was already making seeds and crosses and
so it was really kind of a way to
understand
you know i guess it put like a a
practical side to the the theoretical
stuff i was learning
in university um
so yeah it just kind of came naturally
after that really it was all about
finding new things
and just screening plants and learning
about the plant
right thank you and uh rob
rob i think you're on mute
give rob justice yeah we've got you now
thanks for joining um i guess my first
real opportunity was after going to
university in in indiana was to go to
the netherlands and work with david
watson and do the whole
hoard of farm experience and really our
breeding aim there was to try to develop
varieties for
medicinal use and went on from there
yeah what year was that rob oh i moved
there in uh
1987.
so yeah quite a while ago yeah when i
was three
um all right thank you and uh mark
yeah i'm uh also from i grew up in
indiana
and uh i think some of the fruits of
rob's labor trickled into our
our ecosystem and it was really dr dre's
chronic album that sent me into the
cannabis industry in
the the early 90s and i just happened to
be really good at chemistry and um went
to
uh on to get a chemical engineering
degree and a
phd in in chemistry with all just like
creating a really great great skill set
for
for this industry especially when in
indiana you go to 4-h
they teach you that seeds turn into
plants and the first time you buy
a sack of cannabis to have seeds in it
you naturally make the connection
and then if you can create seed you can
always have cannabis and you don't have
to depend on the
undependable so awesome that's good
and mojave yeah i um well i guess i was
kind of born into a
cannabis community i was born in big sur
california in 1969
and there was already a kind of a
thriving
cannabis culture there
and cannabis was kind of the connective
tissue of
our community so i kind of grew up in
the cannabis scene
but um it wasn't till uh 1993 when i
moved to the netherlands that i really
started to
get into breeding and trying to develop
varieties that kind of represented the
cannabis that i
uh remembered in my youth in california
wonderful all right um for some of
people who might not be as familiar with
some of the basics
um there seems to be a lot of confusion
around the terms indica and sativa
and rob can you kind of highlight some
of that for us here
well the words began with the uh
the taxonomists of the classical age
linnaeus coined the at least popularized
the
binomial cannabis sativa referring
really to european hemp that was what
was in his uh
purview at the time and then uh
later lamarck who had seen cannabis from
india which he named cannabis syndicates
so
that's where we got the terms to begin
with of course they're used completely
differently today
they've become part of branding and
advertising and uh
and uh street understanding of of the
cannabis
plant and the variety they're in
basically
sativa these days refers to uh
more narrow leaflet drug varieties maybe
their heritage would have been
ultimately from india
and uh versus some newer introduction
the afghan
varieties and pakistani varieties that
have come to be called indica
um in reality it's a giant taxonomic
snarl and we'll go there
but uh to to people today it means uh
a number of things it the main thing
is the effect it's all gone from using
these uh
names uh taxonomic names to to
representing
what the herb does and that's uh
yeah that's that's the way popular words
come
to be and be understood um
that's it's in my mind not
a productive way to look at things that
you can talk something being indica
predominant or sativa
predominant and that has something to do
with
its effect compared to the other one but
actually everything's a hybrid it's all
in between somehow
so it seems inadequate terminology but
that's what we got
so we'll run with it for now yeah
definitely seems like there's a lot of
improvement
for retail education and you know people
thinking that they need
something based off of this
classification which as you highlighted
is
a lot of you know polyhybrids um
rob another question for you what are
the botanical basics that everyone
should know about
in the cannabis plant
well everybody should know it's uh
dioecious
that means that there's male flowers on
one plant and female flowers on another
plant
at least under uh under uh normal
conditions
the conditions the way it evolved
monica's plants are very rare
um they've been used in breeding in uh
fiberhemp varieties now used for seed
production also
for for edible seed and but they're very
rare
and uh plants that change sex
are we talk about that you can induce
this and we'll talk about it shortly
that's another subject
but basically they're dioecious it takes
a male and a female
to make seeds they're not
self-pollinated
in nature so there's always that
variable throat in there which will
weigh on the next question
um it's an annual plant yeah
we've made it a perennial plant by
cloning
um but it's it's an annual normally it
goes through a seed cycle every year
and uh it grows as an escape
in places what people call wild plants
often
um and it does very well
on the edges of human habitation but it
doesn't really thrive in nature
so that's i guess it's a basic uh
botany of it wonderful any other
complimentary comments there from the
rest of the panel
okay uh ryan this one's a little bit
more geared for you
how does cannabis breeding actually work
can you walk us through that
yeah well i think again we'll come at it
first from
you know the kind of the perspective rob
is talking about it i think it's always
important to look at
what an organism does in the wild how it
how it
really naturally breeds and then you
know what we do to it
is really a different thing um
because there's there's important
consequences to learn about the the
species and the type of
genetic variation that you're going to
be working with from how it behaves in
the wild
this condition where
rob's talking about what we have diocese
plants males separate males and females
on different plants really leads to a
whole bunch of consequences in the
breeding scheme
one of those well the main the main
thing is
that it makes cannabis an obligate
crosser which means
you have to have two different
individuals um
that come together to breed in the wild
for there to be
made seed which will be the generation
for next year
um so really i think it's a good way to
think about it for people to think about
it as cannabis is kind of more like
um a human mating system than it is
you know like a tomato mating system
like a a different type of selfing plant
um and what i mean by that is the way
that we breed
we're never really shedding genetic
uh variation um because we're always
passing on
you know males always pass on genetics
to the female egg
um you know kind of father to mother
kind of thing
and those traits are then combined in
the offspring
in in other organisms
you get this thinning down of the
population that happens as a result of
the environment and the the traits in
the environment and that leads to
a narrowing of the genetic type but as
you can see with human
genetic diversity we have all these
different genetic forms from all over
the planet
and in the last 150 or so years we're
now
bringing all these different genetic
forms together through mating
and cannabis is much the same way we end
up with a lot of genetic variation a lot
of different possibilities
but inter-family breeding to make
something uniform is
it becomes quite challenging as a result
so it's
it's just important to understand that
when we have the males that are
producing pollen
and it lands on the female plant that's
really the creation of a seed
but what the plant does from there on
and how we shape it
is really a consequence of human
selection i mean
rob talks about this in the in cannabis
evolution one of his books
but really the plant that we found when
humanity started interacting with
cannabis
was a a small camp following plant
probably a few feet high and made a few
small flowers with a little bit of oil
and
maybe a little bit of cannabinoids and
all the changes that we see in modern
cannabis have really been
created or reinforced through
the eyes of man working with the genetic
possibilities within the plant
so maybe that was a bit of a rambling
explanation
it's very similar to corn right ryan i
mean corn when they first found it as
maize it didn't produce a whole lot of
the kernel
but then after 150 years of focusing on
that kernel
now it produces biomass of
corn star or corn syrup you know the the
sugar form
and and other less thans that is mind
boggling because it's you know
30 percent of the biomass which is very
similar to
to to cannabinoids in the way that
humans have
you know stuck their hands into that
machinery somehow just by selective
breeding
and created a plant that produces 30 of
a medical analyte
it's incredible yeah it really is and i
think people
don't really maybe don't really
understand the wild relative of corn was
about the size you know the cobs were
about the size of your baby finger or
smaller maybe
you know they had a few kernels per cob
and now we have these
massive cobs that produce you know
hundreds or even a thousand kernels per
month maybe a thousand to successive but
we have many many kernels much bigger
cobs
um and that was really done through
rudimentary breeding
um you know not using science i mean
even the
the the indigenous mexican human
population they
they created you know what we call maize
which is kind of protocol
kind of what we call protocorn right
it's it's a step before that's not quite
as
big and and indestructible as the corn
that we have now
but um it shows that even with simple
breeding systems what
humans can do just by looking at a plant
and saving the seeds from
the plants that are naturally breeding
in the environment
right and and i think a good way to look
at this talk is
is kind of to consider what the
technologies that we're going to be
using
or we have used in the past and
um the technologies that we'll be using
in the future and how we can use those
to shape and refine cannabis
and you know the 30 percent thca plant i
mean
that was bred by breeders
in in their bedrooms or their closets or
their backyards not really using science
i mean they're
they're just using their their head
state right
and and pretty much selectively bred
other cannabinoids out of that the the
plants biosynthetic pathways
yeah let's talk about some of those
early breeders um rob can you highlight
kind of what the early years look like
um for plant breeding
yeah for sure that the early years were
were basically people just crossing land
races which means
they bought a lid and it had seeds
because almost all weed had seeds back
in the day
yeah they were seen samia
shipments that led to people
understanding the meaning of the word is
seedless but weed had seeds
and people were curious and as
as primates that we are and we stuck
them in the ground
in gardens and a lot of the early uh
growers or people who already had
gardens
vegetable gardens you know places where
it was natural for them to go
stick them in the ground and farmers as
well but it's really started as a garden
crop
and uh it's spread from there
but the early days where you got a bag
of mexican and you grew that
first year and then you got a bag of
colombians sometime in the interim
before the next spring
and then he planted some of those and
huh
lo and behold that sex thing came in
again and seeds were there and
he planted those and he had the first
hybrid and then
the next year somebody got some thai
stick
and then you throw that in there you
know and that became the mail because
you already had your stuff you knew
so then the next thing you have is half
thai
and and a quarter colombian and a
quarter mexican and hope that it goes on
and on
so he began with poly hybrids this is it
went from land races to
um human curiosity and basic breeding
like
like we've been talking about take over
and
that's what happened those are the
really the early days what happened
a bit later and it goes back to what
mark was just saying it's
what went on when when prohibition
suppressed cannabis so much
was that everybody hid out then the
internet came along and
i think cannabis breeding is one of the
earliest
and most poignant examples of
crowdsourcing
and this is uh this is the other end not
really early breeding sorry i kind of
jumped but
that they're tied together there and
yeah it's uh
the future we'll see what holds but so
far it's been a fantastic ride
that's for sure yeah mojave i'm
interested in
some of the um kind of input you have
you know being pretty much born into
you know a mecca for cannabis but what
were some of the early
pioneer breeders working with and how do
their breeding objectives also evolve
over time well um as rob mentioned the
early breeders
in my experience were all growing with
land raised varieties
and their objective was um
more to be to perpetuate what they had
already found you know i think it's
it's um i think most of the work was
done
before the imported cannabis reached
these modern breeders
that they they developed and they
crossed but most of the work was done if
you you know
i think um the some of the early import
cannabis was phenomenal and it was
already
kind of developed and it was more about
acclimating it to the region
and um growing it you know producing a
fresher
and more um you know healthier version
of these plants and i think it's
something to you know to
to recognize is that out of these early
land race hybrids land race-based
hybrids because once
everything once it leaves the land it's
no longer a land race
um that there was a little development
done
and then those the the product of that
those um of that breeding was then
passed on
to the netherlands for instance and then
they were utilized
for stock material to make seats but
the the bulk of the work was done you
know
before they made it to the netherlands
and they were
some some breeders um definitely did a
lot of work
and increased the potency and increased
the
various agronomic traits but if you
think of afghan one and hindu kush
and durbin these are
bag seed that came from imported
cannabis and then
was worked on a little bit and then was
used to make
um seeds for decades so there wasn't a
lot of
improvement on those original land race
varieties
um for for quite some time and some of
them are still
just a few generations away from their
original
um source material
okay we can't leave out the importance
of the hunt
that you know the the importance of that
the role of the hunt
played in this whole thing i mean we we
we tend to focus as cannabis consumers
or even
even breeders as on the the winds but
i mean there was thousands of people
trying to grow weed
from the seeds that were in their you
know in their stash like rob was saying
and they were a lot of that were
failures right i mean there's a lot of
plants especially that come out of these
land race populations that really aren't
they aren't very good we call them dogs
you know they're just plants that are
way way
sub-par and so you have to grow through
a lot of those
terrible plants to really find the ones
that are
exceeding for for drug content and often
what that was what we were doing like
mark said was
we were using our brains kind of like a
a little bit like a gc and selecting for
the compounds
of the plants that had the highest thc
content
and that was really based on how it made
us feel this kind of idea of a bio assay
right um it's the the the experience
that we get from consuming the plant
really dictates our choices in in
in selecting the plants right and of
course how it smells
and and tastes and it's like you cannot
you cannot talk about how important
bagsy
was and has been since day one i mean
that's that was like the treasure trove
and when we used to find seeds it was
like
you know finding that you know toy at
the bottom of the crackerjack box was
like awesome we get to grow one like you
know what i mean it's like awesome
yeah and also just to think that the
difference between bag seed
from a clone versus bag seed from
a pound of weed that was homogenized
from a big batch
of seeds you know most of the the
cannabis grown in the u.s was from seed
and
and when it would be distributed there
was not
you every single flower was different
from the next so you couldn't just
dip into the bag and pull out seed you
had to go and sort through
all the different flowers and then make
your selection which was really hard and
as
as you know time went on over the into
the late 80s
i started to notice that there was
definitely more consistency
among the batches but in the beginning
it was
you know sometimes it was a dog's
breakfast of
of you know different phenotypes all
sold as one variety
so it was you know it was a challenge
and that was a blessing growing up in
indiana was that
iu university had one of the two dea
permits and i'm sure rob can speak to
this but
david watson had sent over i think it
was 157
seed accessions for them to grow out at
the greenhouse there and
do chemotaxonomic analysis on it and as
you know i mean college kids growing
weed
those clones and seeds got out and like
indiana just happened to be one of these
little tiny epicenters that had kind bud
you know it was like very serendipitous
on that note too speaking of the 80s and
90s mojave how did
the isolated and clandestine nature of
modern cannabis breeders both hinder and
help the development of modern cultivars
that's a that's a big one um well for
one
what you started to see is the impact of
law enforcement
on cannabis in the late 70s into the 80s
and that became the biggest selective
pressure
for breeders was developing varieties
that could evade law enforcement
whether it was a lower stature plant
grown outdoors that could be hid under
under canopy of other plants or whether
or
just harvested early enough that law
enforcement you know
well you know camp california of either
marijuana eradication program they they
had a timing
when they would release the helic
release the hounds so to speak
and it was all based off of late
flowering narrow leaf semi-equatorial
varieties
and when we started introducing afghani
and making these earlier
crosses you could get things in before
the helicopter started descending on
your your crop and
in also you know the the hybridization
between these afghani
and narrowly varieties allowed for
plants to be grown indoors
because they weren't 15 foot tall
trees they were these squat little
bushes that you could grow under
under lights and you then at that point
you saw people growing cannabis
virtually everywhere
as opposed to just the most optimal
climates you could grow
cannabis on the moon at that point so
that inspired a lot of people to get
involved and have a hand in developing
their own varieties where they normally
wouldn't have
that opportunity and i think that did a
lot for preservation
of of cannabis that we now have these
little incubators going on all over the
world
but it also meant that the agronomic
traits became
maybe more important than the um
than the the chemo bar so it was
now the primary selection was for for
yield for size and for flowering period
where earlier cannabis was more all
about the effect
and certain varieties that had amazing
effects and and
you know positive attributes were no
longer you know
available because they just didn't make
it indoors or they just
took too long to grow
yeah we really can't understate the
influence of afghanica
being introduced in the into the drug
pool in like the what
rob mid to late 70s mid to late 80s or
sorry yeah
um because they they brought not only
the genes that you're talking about
um for small stature plants and
higher yield and higher resin content
but also some of the genes for
you know like the the source of the
hydroxylated terpenes comes from that
afghanistan too
right so we wouldn't have had those
things occurring in the
in in some of the more equatorial
populations so
um i mean we could talk about some of
the bad traits that came into right the
the lack of mold resistance um that came
along with that compact form
um yeah so it's really interesting how
the the plants that came into the pot
into the united states
predominantly um
[Music]
you know where where they were being
shipped from from when it was mexico or
thailand or colombia
in probably the late 60s and early 70s
and as these these more diverse sources
you know people
around the world looking for different
sources of cannabis to import
that's when really when the afghanica
plants kind of started flooding in
right and that's had a major impact on
the way that the
not only the cannabis community is
developed but also like how the plant
was grown
but you know the types of user
experiences that were available
hey mark this quick this next question
is for you and i don't know if you want
to comment on this picture on the right
that you've provided for us here on the
screen as well
um but what have been some of the major
milestones in the history of cannabis
breeding
in your opinion i mean
obviously david
watson's curation of land races and
um he and de meyers working to create
single cannabinoid plants that were then
you know ryan knows more about this than
i do but that was that was huge to learn
the plasticity of the plants through
demire's papers and
dave's work but then obviously
the removal of prohibition in certain
states
for medical uses open the door for
um you know for like napro research for
example to
set up a laboratory and start using
chemical markers to drive breeding
and then be able to tease apart the
different traits and then obviously now
with
the the the snip chips coming out from
eurofins and
you know groups like oregon cbd using
that technology to really drive that
single cannabinoid model
um the timelines you know it's pretty
there it's there
um but i think the true
innovative work was when you know we
started trying to create
you know some people get adverse effects
from from cannabis products and
and you know to remove adverse effects
from a product
is always a good thing to make a product
safer and still provide you with
the ability to get high or find pain
relief or whatever it may be
without paranoia anxiety or you know
different types of evers effects i mean
that's a true milestone
in in breeding similarly to you know
creating a plant that produces all cbga
in a
bud format but ryan probably has a great
perspective on this because he kind of
sits in the captain's chair
of the whole canvas breeding thing even
you know back into the into the 90s um
and i think that
picture at the bottom right there was
ryan's uh that's his grow right now in
british columbia i believe
you're on mute ryan
it's actually a picture of mark's
college uh college
closet but you know you know we're
talking about dave
dave watson's work david watson's work
in the creation of the single
cannabinoid varieties that ended up
being licensed by gw pharmaceuticals
i mean there's no better person to talk
about it than rob
i mean he was there and right in the in
the in the middle of the whole thing
um can you tell us rob about how that
came about in the pursuit of the single
cannabinoid varieties
and and the idea that you could explore
you know david's wild collection for the
plants that would become
[Music]
you know the the progenitors of what led
to all the different cannabinoid
chemistry on the market
well that got to be a big question um
back to the
gw um beginning of the question
um one thing led to another that was not
the first intent
the first intent was to produce thc
natural version of drennabinol
the registered name for delta 9 thc
and the pharmaceutical name and produce
it naturally
because marinol was based on synthetic
dernavanil
hence their easy approval as the pot
pill
um it was the answer to
people who smoked cannabis saying that
it was medicine
the government could say okay we have
medicine it's called marinol see
this little pill it's got the active
ingredient same thing you guys like
here it is that was that's why it got
fast tracked and that's why it ended up
where it was
but it was an easy uh target for a
generic equivalent
and that was originally what we were
doing um the gw thing came along later
and uh yeah that's where it all started
for a little history
um but gw came along because you guys
found all these different plants that
had different chemistries right i mean
they were
they were looking to set up a
pharmaceutical company and you guys were
the place that had the supply
right one of the only places in the
world that had this diverse chemical
supply
we did and they uh
they basically were focused on one
compound and that was thc
okay cbd was um
included in the program basically
because they wanted to um
ameliorate the naive user effect
that's when an old fart like me does it
for the first time and their heart beats
really fast and they go
you know i don't feel so good and and
that happens
in all their trials even the ones that
pass
at about around ten percent i mean
probably can give anybody a sugar pill
into is in the hospital and ten percent
don't feel good you know but that's they
were trying to ameliorate
um the effects and
through anecdotal evidence provided by
david basically um
cbd was not it kills your buzz
you know and and that's where it came
from and just that
simple user knowledge led to them
using it to ameliorate those effects and
uh
that's where we ended up and and on from
that then
cbd became a first-line um
pharmaceutical hence epidiolex all this
is a good thing
but that's the history of how cbd ended
up in the program
well and and to address your cbd kills
your buzz i would say that it attenuates
your buzz because if you have something
that's four to one thc to cbd
or 10 to one thc cbd it tends to have a
much more
indica effect like knocking you like
onto the couch hardcore whereas thc
alone has that more like you said heart
pounding effect
depending so it's it's i'd say when you
get one to one
and less it definitely kills your bus
yeah and that's something that we
learned through the napro breeding
programs was that
we could achieve cannabinoid ratios that
we we didn't find in the natural
population
right and those and some of those
stranger altered cannabinoid ratios
when you put them in a flavor profile
that's
pleasing that the market is used to you
know then you
then you really have this new types of
connect this new type of cannabinoid
experience that just doesn't exist
or hadn't existed i should say but you
know up until that point in time
and think about how one-dimensional
today's marketplace is with just
it's just thc but the vast majority of
users
of cannabis or hemp products are really
using an
enhanced or type 2 product because all
of the hemp is getting sprayed with
something
and then getting bought and sold on the
black market going
you know the other towards the east or
whatever it's really interesting to
think that these people going to
tobacco shops are essentially smoking
an enhanced product and they're one of
the biggest growth
user groups in the united states right
now just
and then when you mix in th cv or
for instance there's um cultivars that
are
out here that you know um that have that
are a type
2 which means they have thc and cbd but
they also have
a propyl so now you're talking about
four cannabinoids in the mix and if
there's a
you know one plus percent cbg that you
got five cannabinoids in the mix
those cocktails really begin to create
what is
what was truly meant by the original
entourage uh
dubbed by shulam right like the
cannabinoid entourage
let alone layering on top of that like
ryan said the
og nose or the jack nose which
also layers on another pharmacological
piece
yeah it's it's funny that we you know
these things exist and i think that the
market is
you know they understand that these
things can exist that these you know
these
types of cultivars could potentially
exist on the market but they're real
market penetrances like you said they're
not
really accepted the people that go to
the the dispensaries looking for their
cannabinoids i mean they're usually
looking for thc right um
but you know with the right consumer
education again
you have specific um you know as you
know certain combinations of
cannabinoids work great on
you know skin irritation or you know i
mean sativex
you know is is a as a medicine for a
reason and it's not
thc and when you get into a recreational
market that's looking for
functional um products i mean
consumers love holy crunch because they
can
use it in the morning get high drink
some coffee and it lasts for three hours
and then when they smoke their type one
later in the day they actually get high
again whereas
you know you smoke type 1 all day all
thc you have a tendency to kind of
taper on that getting high a little bit
it's like a refresher for your
endocannabinoid system or something
yeah that's what's it dr 80 ray
you can accomplish some dr addy ray is
about to publish some
interesting data on that that they've
collected at the uh
one of the oregon festivals cannabis
consumption events
on the different preferences chemistries
because again people are buying
you know when they go into the store
they don't really you're overwhelmed
when you go into a dispensary
of choice and and you don't really know
how to differentiate between the
different products
right and so the natural thing that
everybody goes to is what's the highest
thc
um and i think it's i've said it before
but i think it's important to say again
you know up until even the early 2000s
that's not the way that cannabis was
purchased nobody knew about
you know everybody assumed that higher
thc was better but nobody really knew
i mean thc wasn't on the bottle right it
wasn't on the label back then
um so the way that you would select the
cannabis that you'd want to buy is you'd
put your nose into the bag and see what
smelled and looked good
right and it didn't really have anything
to do with the number per se
um it was more judged based on the user
experience
and we've kind of moved into this market
where people are now buying based on a
number
on a metric because that's kind of
something that they have to grab onto
anyway i don't mean to divert our our
talk here but
no it's it's it's just great that you
mentioned some of those things and
the future is definitely a more
robust cannabinoid offering and chemical
offering right
yeah let's see let's let's shift from
the past to the present for the sake you
guys are like most
growers and breeders very ambitious with
all the information that you are trying
to accomplish today
um but yeah if we can if we can shift a
little bit this one's going to be for
ryan and for mojave
um present day what objectives drive the
thinking of today's cannabis breeders
you know what type of desired traits are
they looking to enhance or
to alter
um well i'd say that just to follow up
on what we were just talking about i
mean it's all about predicting
what the consumer's needs are you know
we're in kind of this era where cannabis
is now being marketed like other
products
with packaging and media
and um we're it's about connecting
the cultivar or a variety with the end
user
right just like what mark was saying i
think there's a cannabis variety for
everybody
but predicting what that variety is
going to be
is is the challenge and and and finding
the user that's seeking that particular
effect
is extreme extremely challenging but
cannabis does so much for so many people
that we all know that that there is a
variety for everybody
um but as a you know in terms of
selecting cultivars
and selecting in and working developing
new varieties
you have to have foresight 12 months
ahead of the market and you have to be
able to predict
where the market is moving so it always
comes back to education you know we have
the consumer needs to be educated so
the supply chain can meet their needs
right now
you know people love purple weed for
whatever reason i think purple's a
pretty color
and it sells well you know and people
are driven
by these uh you know associations with
other
um products you know we've got all these
sweet
cakes and and cookies and stuff like
that which
tap into our primal love of of uh
carbohydrates
so we got two competing fronts one is
the marketability of the product and how
you reach
your consumer and the other is actually
producing
and developing varieties that address
the needs of the consumer
and i think that those are are
challenging for
breeders and challenging for cultivation
groups in order to align those
and be able to predict what the future
cannabis varieties are going to be
um so yeah it's it's um i i talk with
with um cultivation groups all the time
who you know
stock their build up their mother blocks
based off of the trends of today
and by the time those blocks are all
established and they're making clones
and putting them into production
everything's changed
so it's it's a guessing game you know
but
yeah changeover at commercial scale a
lot of people don't realize they're
trying to stay with these trends by the
time they
identify a trend they're already midway
in the trend and by
time you get everything in a population
it's a year later and it's and it's over
um so i i can relate to that one
personally um if you had to identify
like a top three desired traits on a
breeding project uh maybe a recent one
is there something that rings out to you
there
um for me well it's it's um it's
pest and pest in um pathogen resistance
and the effect i mean that's i've effect
has always been primary for me
you know i i kind of feel like if uh
if i had to chew a bitter pill to get
the effect that i was the desired effect
i would do that way over
you know a strawberry flavored vicodin
or something like that you know
and i think that that's really hard to
um
to relay to a consumer when cannabis now
is so dynamic
and has such an amazing um aromatic
profile
but to me it's all about effects you
know and that's that's why i was drawn
to cannabis i think that's why people
you know that that's our primary concern
but
now color and and flavor seem to
predominate and
and as mentioned for thc content you
know
so yeah i i've i've always felt that
pest and
you know resistance and um effect are
the two primary
you know concerns and ryan you want to
piggyback on some of that
yeah i think i think again to look at
what we've been doing
is really you know mohave calls it
effect but truly that is
smelling and cannabinoid content really
our scent and cannabinoid scent flavor
and cannabinoid content
and that's kind of what we've been
focusing on i don't mean we but i
mean we personally but we as a as the
cannabis community has been focusing on
we haven't had the ability to run proper
breeding programs to be able to
to lock down things like resistance
right um
those things take time and they take
time to learn how to learn how to do and
that was really some of the
early work we were doing in april was
trying to understand the inheritance of
these flavor molecules or the scent
compounds so that we could learn how to
shuffle the deck
to to get the desired outcome that we
wanted
and you know that was not that was
really within the last 10 years you
could say
so the way i look at the industry is
we've got this incredible genetic
resource but
you know with corn and a lot of these
other species that all those crops were
handed over to the plant nerds
right way at the beginning of the crop
right i mean
that was those the people that naturally
gravitated to it and cannabis really
wasn't that way cannabis got harvested
and sequestered in these these disparate
and remote gardens like all
over the world and so different people
were starting with different populations
and they were kind of all cobbling
together their own car that they could
just make it run
and now we're lucky to be you know 20
years into that cycle where we can start
dipping into these different populations
that people have been
developing on their own and we're able
to bring these things back together in a
more
organized and structured way um
and i think that when you're doing that
the only real way to do that is to start
piece by piece
right and so so like i said when we were
doing that at napo
we started figuring out how to shuffle
the the
the cannabinoid and the terpene synthase
genes in such a way
that we could stabilize and lock those
traits down
and then the next step is going in and
increasing
uh you know fixing frog pro properties
like you're talking about like
resistances to mold or pester pathogens
um and improving yield and stature and
even a lot of these like basic
plant architecture traits to do with
mars
morphology and structure for for making
a plant that's ideal to grow i mean
those things kind of have to be
added back in one at a time as you're
building this
you know you get a good analogy is like
you know to
to build a plane while you're flying it
like really that's what we're doing
because we don't the cannabis industry
doesn't have the type of crops
that other industries like corn can rely
on i mean if you're you want to be a
huge corn producer you go and
sign a deal with cargill or one of the
big corn seed suppliers
and you plant their bulletproof corn
crops
right and you pay them a hefty
percentage of the crop
because they're they're providing you
with with a type of seed that is
is going to be you know allow you to
build a really robust business model
and we're only kind of i think that
we're only getting to that point in
cannabis
right now you know where we're starting
to get to that point ryan and mark i
think you brought up a good point
and i encourage everyone to google it if
you haven't seen it but they have these
images of like
every traditional commercial crop 100
years ago
or 150 years ago and what it looks like
today and it's quite a bit different so
you know from my perspective i think a
lot of people are trying to
in in their head at least breed towards
the utopian plant
and generally you know they're looking
for obviously high yield
um but they're looking for other
characteristics as well uh you know one
that i see people digging down on
is like uh calyx to leaf ratio you know
if you're in the business of growing for
trim
flower you probably don't want to grow a
cultivar that's 40 percent
you know trim in in a commercial setting
so
it seems to be pretty common from my
kind of out and abouts
but i see other people looking for like
resistance to lodging um i know
people are battling trellises uh on all
kinds of different levels so the idea of
having
um in my opinion like a turgid plant
um that's you know self-erects itself
and can handle a little bit of wind and
jostle here and there versus you know
two or three layers of trellis
would really speed up things from a
labor perspective particularly
associated with harvesting
and maybe even increase things like
better contact on sprays and things of
this nature are there any other traits
ryan
mark in the in the group here that you
really think are
kind of um not not
brought into the light yet that are
critical
i don't know about you know one of the
traits that is critical for
a lot of asexual propagators is a
clonability of a
of a variety or cultivar if it takes
root really easily
um and when you when you take clones you
have this high
frequency of stress uh stressed plants
so if you can reduce that population
through breeding a plant that's easily
asexually propagated
that works we're seeing terpenes is a
big focus
even for on the hemp side and some of
the breeding programs we oversee that
that terpene cannabis derived terpenes
from hemp
are proving to be a real market breaker
for
you know people are doing well
cultivating hemp for terpenes as long as
it's not
mir seen because all hemp is pretty much
mercy and there's a couple
lines now that are terpenoline but
there's six
terpenes that can be dominant and when
you get the
into the limonenes the piones the the
osamines and the linole
then those essential oils uh really
provide income for those hemp farmers
who are struggling who are growing for
cbd or whatever
then you have like you know some plants
we see
exhibit uh you know reduced branching or
no branching at all which could be
useful in row crop
similar to corn instead of getting
christmas tree shapes you just have
straight spindles and for fiber
but the resistance obviously those are
those are big big ones the flavor
is is huge and creating terpene profiles
that didn't exist previously
because when you looked at the cannabis
market seven years ago
you had like five terpene profiles and
that was kind of it
and with help from ryan we've been able
to assemble
terpene profiles that never exist things
that were
uh you know pining is a recessive
terpene like
any time you hybridize it with anything
the pining starts going away
you have to really focus on keeping
certain terpenes to be co-dominant when
you when you breed through them so
for example if you have something that's
limonene pinene and beta-carotelline
dominant
that really doesn't exist in the
marketplace because keratopheline and
limonene
kind of squash out the pinene the only
way to preserve some outlier
in that case is to have a clone or
if you have a seed producer who has a
parental that's pioneering dominant and
a parental that is carefully limiting
dominant
and they homozygously breed those two
terpenes to be codop those three
terpenes be co-dominant in the seed
then you have this new new way of
sharing um
homozygous uh seed crops based on flavor
and mark can you elaborate a little bit
on founder events and bottlenecking of
gene pool
you know i think that ryan is the king
of the
the the bottleneck of the gene pool
because that used to be his
uh sign off on his email was was it the
the only
was it the only crime against the
cannabis genome is itself or seed and i
don't know i can't remember
i don't know it doesn't sound like
something i would say but um
that founder of events is all about
consequences and so
like for example a good a good a good
one that people understand is og
right og's a great plant it's got a
great nose i don't know if i would call
it a great plant but it's got a great
nose and a
and a flower profile from a consumer
point of view it's
there's a lot of things going for it but
it's kind of like you said
uh michael you know it's probably a
plant that needs to be multiple
trellised and it takes a lot of support
um so think of it this way like when you
choose a plant like og
and everybody wants to have og
everything og cookies or og
whatever you know everybody like when it
became popular everybody crossed
everything to og
and and so yeah you get those hot that
high thc
and you get that nice fuely kind of
scent profile that gets added to
whatever
you're you're breeding with but you also
get to inherit all the bad traits that
come along with it
um and what happens is when the entire
world
focuses on og
you know when when darwin said you know
survival of the fittest what he meant
was survival of the
the genes the genes that will survive
are the ones that are passed on in the
most frequency so when everybody's using
og to breed with
those genes become overrepresented in
the population
okay and so all the good things that
come from og
yeah they come into the pool but you
also inherit all the bad things
and when you only have a few individuals
that are leading to
the entire like i mean think about it
like you know we're gonna go to mars
and you want you you're gonna start a
new colony on mars if you take
five people right like those five people
that
leave that will have a big imprint on
the future genetics from everything
everyone that comes from them
you're you're over emphasizing the
traits that those
that those people have right in the in
the forming population and so
it's kind of the idea that just
understanding that
when you go through a bottleneck and a
bottleneck means that you know think of
it like
all the genes in a population are in a
bottle i mean you turn the bottle upside
down
there's you know the limit of the amount
of genes that can actually get through
that
that constriction is much lower
right and so that has an impact on the
future of the species from that point of
view
um and so it's really important to
remember
when you're doing things like
everybody's breeding with og that you're
yeah you're inheriting all the good
characteristics but you're also
inheriting all the bad characteristics
and rob writes about this in a book
called um
sorry advances in hemp research palo
vernale
and rob wrote a great chapter about the
you know the plants and the and the
cultivars that really founded the drug
gene pool mostly being i don't know
northern lights afghani
afghani one skunk one and hayes
um and and it wasn't only those plants
it was that a few or those those what we
call varieties
it was a very few individuals from those
pla
from those genetic lines that were kind
of
what we say made it intersect or cross
between each of themselves amongst
themselves
and the different combinations of those
very few plants
for a long time had a big impact on the
drug
uh population the global drug population
because
everybody was growing seeds from those
crosses
right um so that's really what a founder
event is
okay yeah and and we you know we have
gone through like i said we've gone
through that a couple of times in
cannabis once with the ogs and once at
the beginning and i
and i think that we're always going
through that
um it's always nice when people come
along like dj short or
these gentlemen out of colorado i don't
know if you know them the cannabis
potency research that have this freak
show plant
um with the with the weird leaf shape
and you know
it's nice when someone pops up and
they've been doing their own thing
and crossing to their within their own
genetic program
for say 15 20 years because they kind of
become isolated from all the trends that
are going on in the day
and those are really great um what i
call
repair pools or their genetic um
collections that we can go and draw from
to kind of reinvigorate
uh some of the interbreeding again
remembering that cannabis is an
outcrosser
inbreeding is very unnatural to cannabis
and so
when we do these these inbreeding events
we have to understand that there's
genetic consequences to that
um and they went through this with corn
as well you know so it's not
it's not to be unexpected yeah i like
that terminology repair pull and save
that one
um i know one of the things that we
talked about previously as a group
was we're currently in a seed to clone
market
and i think a lot of people had some
strong opinions that we're probably
going to be shifting at some point to a
a clone to seed market and move away
from others altogether
so collectively within the panel um i'd
love to have a discussion
and get some perspective on on your
thoughts there
well like rob said this is a seed crop
i mean we don't grow corn not corn is
bad example
but we don't very few things in
agriculture do we
grow from asexual propagate if it has a
hearty seed
and when you compare the amount of
horticultural
horticultural required to produce from a
clone
versus producing from a seed there's no
comparison
you know when you grow from a clone you
have to first propagate
it which costs money a couple bucks a
clone and then you have to
skirt the plants when they get a certain
age so that you you
you know focus the the root to shoot
ratio on the top so you get good bud
formation
and they're usually susceptible to
diseases and pests
that have just come along unless you
have
seggers technology which is tissue
culture which cleans all the plants so
that they're really nice for
for production but it's really a
no-brainer when you compare a plant with
a tap root
versus a plant without a taproot it's
really remarkable you can even grow
in low-light winter conditions with no
heat and still get really great bud
formation
in good yields your pest and disease
pressure goes way down
and like i said the horticultural cost
goes down you just have to
be working with someone who has
developed seeds for the purpose
of production instead of
someone who takes a strawberry kush and
crosses it with a banana kush and causes
strawberry banana kush
if they didn't look at the chemistry
behind those two products and
or those two plants and the resulting
seed isn't going to be what they think
it is and
all the panelists can can kind of vouch
for that when you're just taking names
and hybridizing hybrids and hybridizing
hybrids
you don't really it it's it's the same
thing over and over and over again
right like even when you look across all
of the gelato cookies
wedding cake sunset sherbet they're all
beta-carotene dominant
a little bit of limonene and a little
bit of other secondaries and
they basically have a very similar
aromatic profile
and that's one of the main drivers of
what seeds are produced like ryan was
talking about og kush
well o.g kush has fallen out of favor to
the cookies family of
of hybrids right so so i think in the
future
as the hemp farmers have shifted to seed
that's a great model for the cannabis
farmers to shift to seed
and pretty much anyone growing outdoors
whether it's sonoma
or santa rosa or santa barbara they're
all growing from seed for the
bcc marketplace because it doesn't make
sense to
pay what it costs to do the clonal work
and put it in the ground
and then it'd be a crap shoot if you're
going to have a fire or a windstorm
or whatever we know that that model's
not um
completely dialed in yet but if you had
to predict a
time where you see this transition being
there at the level of like a
monsanto tomato seed as an example what
kind of timeline would you put on that
well i mean we have clients who have
products that currently
are homozygous very stable
and perform in the field but
when you're talking about a complete
catalog that's roundup ready
uh you know monsanto has to step into
the game to get roundup ready going for
us but
i would say in the next five years
you'll see a lot more products entering
the marketplace i mean
there's a couple good good
autoflower seeds that are finally
starting to get better on the nose out
there
um molecular farms has a couple great
products that are autoflower and
photopredependent um yeah probably like
five years and there'll be a lot
and i'd say i just added that that i
think that clones will
always have a place i mean we
we're the closer we get to homozygous
seeds it's obviously and it depends on
the
cultivator and where they're cultivating
and what they're cultivating
um but clones and tissue culture will
will have their place in the market um
definitely for you know maintaining
breeding parent stock
at the very least um and it just it all
depends i mean with there's a there are
you know we some plants just are so
um unstable like grapes and apples you
know that we have to grow from clone
and you know some markets are so
discerning about
what they want that we're not yet
they're not ready to take
the even limited variability that comes
from sea crops
um you know so i i think that they'll
still be relevant you know and even but
we all
we all hope to be able to produce um
better seed
it's more reliable especially for
international markets and i agree with
that
i'd like to add that broad acre is the
future for most of cannabis production
it's all cannabis whether it's hemp or
seed
or drug it's all cannabis and that will
weigh
in in a future question but
you you need to think towards what
agriculture really is
and it's broad acre agriculture it's an
australian term
basically but it means growing um
crops from seed on large acreage
and this is the way forward for
producing
cannabinoids as just cannabinoid stock
just like it is for producing cedar
or fiber um so really we need consistent
seed varieties for that
sort of production they exist for fiber
and for seed but they don't exist for
drug cannabis and
this is something that really needs to
happen to really move
the plant forward as a real crop point
that's switching gears a little bit ryan
did you have a comment i'm sorry
before i do it or switch gears yeah i
just wanted to say
you know i i think that there's a bit a
little bit of a dichotomy and i mean
like
like mojave with sand there is all these
trends there are all these trends that
happen
um and and cultivators have to be quick
to adapt but the truth is
the seed process takes time and so
you know to get homozygous seed of all
these really
variants i mean april's doing a great
job of it but i think that five years is
probably pushing the envelope a little
bit
in terms of worldwide acceptance from
most cultivation facilities i think most
cultivation
i think 10 to 15 years is probably
a more realistic number of when people
are going to start
really planting the majority of cannabis
drug crops from seed
at least those that are growing for
flour if you're going for extract
it doesn't matter as much but the flower
market kind of really depends on these
clonal productions
um yeah point
yeah so i i mean i'd like to i think
that going to seed
would be it would solve a lot of the
problems like mark was talking about
there are there are tons of advances
um advantages sorry but the truth is is
that those
you know we're like i said we're
building this plane as we're flying it
from parts that all these different
growers have cobbled together over the
last
20 30 years and
it takes time to develop those plants
that are
um you know they're what i call
bulletproof plants right like like
the corn of today where you can plant a
thousand a field of a thousand plants or
more ten thousand plants and they all
look the same
to make breeding parents that are stable
to get to that point where you can start
creating those hybrids is it takes time
um yeah just kind of pushing on a little
bit too because i know q and a is kind
of a
hot topic always on these webinars um
as the market evolves um leading
producers and brands are taking
increasingly sophisticated approaches to
curating cultivar menus
particularly in the new booming
recreational markets um
you know i've seen this time and time
again where people go spend 25 50
500 million dollars and build out a
facility and then you talk to them about
their genetic portfolio and what their
plan is there
and it's kind of like this afterthought
it's um oh we're gonna buy five or ten
thousand dollars for the seeds and kind
of hunt through some things
um so you know i guess
what should a producer's genetic
portfolio management
look like pre-operational and
operational and that's kind of open for
all of you guys but yeah
what does what makes up a ideal genetic
portfolio for
you know a modern company today well i i
would start off by saying probably just
ryan's catalog
but you know that's a big statement if
you could pull up those three fido facts
this is a great segue to kind of
yeah to just show how you can have
diversity within
a dispensary or whatnot and these are
all products that are
on the shelf in in california
but the idea is that uh in a true
in the future you'll be looking at
you're looking at phytofacts these are
report formats
for different cultivars being
grown in california and sold in the the
recreational marketplaces
and sc labs
now produces these for for cultivators
so you can have a better standard of
quality control because you have your
terpene profile that's color coded
semi-intuitively so if you if you notice
on the left you have a
the happy pineapple uh cultivar that's a
true
it smells like pineapple like pineapple
express never
really smelled like pineapple it was
just the name
but this plant has 28 plus percent
cannabinoids
it has 20 thc with like 8
cbg but the dominant terpene is osamine
and beta-carotene
with limonene pinene and it is really
bright and pineapply
and then you go to the far right which
is a space force one
it's 32 percent cannabinoids 30 percent
thc
limonene dominant has a gassy back end
but a lemony front end
and then something in the middle that
kind of smells like cookies is holy
crunch
and it's one to one thc to cbd and you
have
you know a host of consumer tools on
this
report format that dispensaries and bud
tenders can learn from
and understand how to direct a new user
like rob mentioned
or uh the the og who just wants the
30 thc but also gives the
consumer useful information about the
product and how it's going to make them
feel
how it's going to taste how it's going
to smell and then once you
begin creating a whole menu that is
based off of terpene profile because
if you create a spectrum from you know
the warm colored tones to the cool
colored tones on the phytofactory of red
orange and yellow those are warm colors
and then
the purples and blues are cool tones the
warm
kind of you know tie into those
sativa-like effects
the cool tones associate with the
indica-like effects and if you have a
mixture of the colors those are hybrid
like effects and when we look at plants
we look at them from their morphology
so if if you're looking at biotech seed
catalog
you'll have indica sativa and hybrid for
the structure of the plant
like rob was talking thin leaf fat leaf
short and squatty tall
and then you have the effects the
terpene entourage indica sativa and
hybrid
and that's what these phytofacts kind of
kind of do
and they're really great tools for
breeding so if you go to the next slide
please michael
this is a small shot of a of a seed
population
and you know there's four different sets
of bar charts
but as you can see each each individual
cultivar is numbered 14
21 22 etc and if you look at the second
bar
chart down with the orange and green
bars the orange is the absolute
terpene concentration and the green is
the absolute
cannabinoid concentration and then
the next bar chart under shows the
relative terpene profiles
and then the bar chart under that shows
minor molecules that most people don't
don't even look at but they definitely
look unlabeled
and it truly affects the nose
and it's it's really it's really neat
and this is an example of an
f2 so we're trying to get diversity in
the terpene profile
but if you look at number 19 it has like
four and a half percent terps and 20
some plus cannabinoids
so it's like one of the clear winners
you know of of this group
but it takes you it takes you a little
bit of time to look at these and
actually understand what they're looking
at but
really if people focus in on the two
middle rows
of the kind of the rainbow row and the
orange and the green one the orange
the oranges correct me if i'm wrong mark
or orange is cannabinoids and the green
is
terpenes you got exactly yeah well
oh the opposite sorry all right but
anyway
you can you can really easily look at a
population and start to see
okay you know number six for example is
obviously low in both cannabinoids and
terpenoids
but you can look at the ones with the
high peaks and start seeing the ones
that have the high levels of terpenoids
and cannabinoids and
you can even look at the ratios between
those compounds
um so it's a really informative way
to look at an entire population rather
than looking at individual
lab reports one at a time
uh the phytoefects make this possible
and you know the guys that are
growing the strawberry banana kush are
breeding that that product
they don't look they don't they don't
have access to tools like this but
we're we're planning on helping sc labs
make this a product of the future for
for cannabis breeders we can help move
the industry forward a little bit more i
mean yeah it's very cool
these tools have been awesome in helping
you know uh
molecular farms and others create truly
novel products in the marketplace
that taste great have a great experience
and it's truly tailored breeding when
you break it down to the chemicals like
this
yeah and when you go back and i mean if
you go back to this the slide before
where you're showing the hot happy
pineapple
um most people won't tell by looking at
these lab reports because you're kind of
you know when when they're new to you it
takes a little bit of time to read them
but once you've seen
you know a thousand of them those plants
that are up on the on the
or the i don't know if you can go back
to it michael but those plants that were
on the previous slide
their technical difficulties okay
they're pretty interesting plants i mean
that happy pineapple
is a is a pretty cool plant 28
cannabinoids eight percent
cbg um with that terpene profile high in
osamine and
it looks like there's a bunch of other
little miners in there yeah you got some
limonine and some pinene and some
beta-carotelline
i mean that's a cool plant that's a and
that ocean
came from bag seed of hawaiian
from 1994. that's not from the pinterest
line then
no no no no this that's from the the
this ended up getting crossed with
um a blue moonshine and then
and then flow and then back back across
to the
the hawaiian parent and yeah dj short
stuff
not the chemistry it was more the early
flower
and the structure um because dj stuff
often was really early like uh which i
which i really liked
so it's it's great to see this um you
know
the fido facts is such a powerful tool
um
and for breeders and ultimately for
consumers which is really what we you
know kind of the underlining
theme here is consumer education and the
fact that selabs is doing this
with with napo and that the emerald cup
is now
has a terpene class awards which really
you know these the cannabis awards
really drives the market in a big way
and the fact that we're going to see
people
acknowledging these different terpene
classes and hopefully eventually
the retail outlets um also
realizing that they need to have a
representational variety for
all these different terpene and minor
cannabinoids um that's great
in that yeah
2014 or 2013 i think but that's great
for finally doing it i mean it's like i
always use the example of a
um like a best a dog show right it's
like you have
what we do now is kind of like best in
show but you know they'd also
say what the best labrador you know or
the best poodle is right
and so when you can actually start
judging cannabis
amongst samples that are similar to that
type i mean that's quite interesting
yeah like like the ipa versus a porter
versus a stout
i mean it's a natural way or a merlot
versus a you know
cab cabernet um and just so so everybody
knows
sc labs did a great job on their website
if you guys want to check out the fido
facts they put together video
and all kinds of stuff so i think it's
just also interesting how you know the
cultivation classic
um awards out of oregon their terpene
class
excludes myrsin
yeah they're just like we're not even
going to try it because otherwise you
know the market is dominated with mere
seeing dominant varieties
we need to talk about other terpenes hey
mir scene's not even on the grass list
so stay away from that stuff really i
didn't know that that's hilarious
2018 they pulled it off the grass list
yeah
yeah all right guys so
i am going to push us forward a little
bit here
uh last question and then we're gonna
get into q a um what concerns should
producers have when planning for new
genetics
um and we discuss educating and
consumers through retail training and
education
and also how does geographic uh location
and regulatory climate affects some of
this
regulation is huge yes i was just going
to say it's huge especially in the
international market
i mean you look at all these new
countries that are coming online
they're uh you know they want to grow
popular varieties but they might not
have
the right climate for it they might not
have the right regulatory structure to
allow it
um yeah it's it's um it's huge
i i mean i'm i'm biased as a vendor
international vendor of seed
genetics and clone shipping around the
world
but i really feel like in order to be
successful
you have to partner with um a group that
knows what they're doing
um trying to do your whole genetic
program
on your own is crazy if you're like i
said if you're going to enter the tomato
or the farm market
you're not going to er you're not going
to and you want to be a producer you're
not going to go and collect your own
land race seeds
and start trying to put together a
breeding program and make your own
tomato
right you're going to go to a known
producer that has a reliable crop that
you can rely on to support your business
model and you're going to make a
contract with them
um and i you know
in in a lot of these companies a lot of
these these regular these
markets what what they'll do is they'll
allow a producer to have like a two or
three week window where
you know the regulator kind of looks the
other way and whatever genetics end up
in your facility
they end up your facility but once that
period is over you're locked down
and you can only trade genetics or buy
genetics from other people that operate
within your system
and that creates challenges for
producers that are always trying to
create something new and stay relevant
because you know any given producer only
has you know
a footprint of say a hundred x right and
if you have to take
25 x of that hundred and dedicate it to
veg space
you now only have three or 75 x of the
rest of that space to use for production
when we start taking away some of that
space to do r d
to try and develop that new new all the
time
right like we're saying you know a lot
of these places
might want to roll out a new cultivar
every two or three months
right so that they can stay relevant and
um
it's tough to do that all on your own
while you're trying to run a business
and i think
um you know in north america especially
is becoming quite lucky
as we envision um full legalization in
the states probably in the next five
years with the new administration
um and maybe that allows
interstate commerce and potentially
commerce within the north american block
where canada and the united states can
trade genetics
canada is already able to do
international business because we're
fully legalized
so you know segger for example just
released news that they
you know that we're shipping some
genetics over to a company in
in africa um and so the
the movement of genes is becoming more
commonplace
but really having a genetic supplier
that is going to be able to support a
diverse
menu i think is really critical
clean stock i'd add into that you know
we've talked with groups
you know some in in fully regulated um
countries they usually don't allow for
immaculate conception
so all material has to come in with the
phytosanitary certificate
and we've already heard um you know new
emerging markets that have been
completely
infected and impacted by hoplay and
thyroid
you know that they brought in seed stock
um and it's already spread throughout
their whole facility so
it's happening in canada too i mean we
you know we're not supposed to have
cross
clone cross you know cross border clone
shipments but
it happens right um and i'm seeing bro
i've seen broad mites now in a couple of
canadian facilities and for those of you
that don't know broad might start really
indigenous to canada so
that's that's a result of people
bringing up cuttings outside of the
system
and outside of the regulations not only
the cannabis act regulations but
we have regulations on the international
regulations on the movement of plants
and um
what mohave just mentioned this whole
concept of phytosanitary certification
and when people operate outside those
regulations there's consequences
so you know be careful of it's important
to be really careful of who your genetic
suppliers are because
not only on the genetic you know not
only the genetic comes in your facility
also any bugs that are on that plant
material come into your facility
and it can absolutely devastate your
business yeah
do you have the cannabis aphid up there
ryan
not yet i haven't seen it yet but i'm
sure it's on its way
i've seen about every pest in canada at
this point um
but so my takeaways there were validate
your
partners or your resources um
clean stock program is critical um and
divergent portfolio and that'll give you
enough building blocks for a good start
to
create whatever it is that's in your
vision
um go ahead rob i said well said that's
exactly all right
okay um so this is where i have to leave
you with a cliffhanger um as much as we
want to talk about
incredible things like market recessive
selection um
predictive breeding programs pan-genomes
um and and and uh that's gonna have to
be for part two
so at this point we'll transition to q
and a
uh thank you to all audience members
that provided questions ahead of time
we're able to select a few so we'll get
started there
and then we can grab some out of the
chat um
mojave ryan rob mark if there's anything
any questions in the chat that you find
particularly interesting go ahead and
just you know
um we'll pull them up after these next
couple ones so
um one of the first questions we had is
do you think hybrid seed will displace
traditional clonal propagation systems
we've already covered that um we'll see
i think we're all excited for that when
it's when it's ready
um the second one is a little bit more
for part two but i thought it would be
an interesting
little teaser if anyone's got some
experience but has anyone on the panel
performed
double haploid breeding techniques to
cannabis
you're on mute right
we we played with a bunch that's a big
that's a big thing it's not that's
not it's more than just spraying a plant
with sts
right um it's a quite involved process
and we've played around with it a little
bit
um but we don't have any products it's
really r d at this point in time
it's i would say that again is ten years
away from uh
a reliable workable system where we're
starting to see people generate
lines derived from dihapps
any other comments from the group here
no one wants to take that one okay um
speaking of sts or uh silver ethyl
sulfate
um does any of the panelists believe
that using sts
to self an individual plant will make
the seeds be more likely
to intersect is there a way to use
selfing without
creating intercept problems
does anybody else want to jump in i'll
jump in first because it's gonna need
modification by my peers
but uh basically if you start with a
female
and i can't really describe to you
exactly what a female is but an xx
female with no intersex tendencies
and then you use it to produce
male pollen then you're probably good to
go but a lot of the
varieties we have are somehow sexually
unstable
and i can't really explain that ryan's
knows more about that than i do
so there was a great paper just released
by a group in canada
that they actually sprayed sts on a
plant and looked at the kind of an
induced gene response looked at them
looked at the genes that were altered in
their expression and there's like a
whole list of
you know 120 potential candidates
um that that also seemed to make sense
as genes for possible
targets to be involved in intersexuality
people gotta be able to separate male
female-ness from intersex-ness
their different traits um and they they
overlap in the way that we experience
them in the way that we see them
but the truth is that they're separate
separate traits
um you can have male plants or female
plants that are
predisposed or not predisposed
to intersexuality and what happens is we
um when we breed those plants together
or sorry when we self plants which is
really what we're
what we're most often doing when we use
sts all we're doing is increasing the
frequency of those genes in the
offspring
and so i would argue that it's not the
sts
itself that is causing
intersex issues it's that using
sts allows us to execute
breeding programs with tighter levels of
inbreeding
and it's that inbreeding that is
exposing these traits that are buried in
the cannabis genome
like i said earlier cannabis being an
obligate outcrosser
what what that means is that plants
accumulate
genetic mutations there's no there's no
drive to push those genetic mutations
out of the population
um and so when we do
subsequently do things like use sts or
create these tight inbreeding schemes
those rare genetic mutations are more
likely to pop their head
and show us expressions that we didn't
know were already buried in the
in the cannabis genome and i think that
that's more likely the the
outcome is that we're seeing these
things occur rather than
that we're seeing these things occur as
a result of the breeding system
rather than creating these things you
know through our practices
well and just from our experience across
every chemotype and
many many latitudes and environments
the environment plays a huge role in
stress-induced stamina flower production
so even if you do great breeding
there is this opportunity for a cold
night
or a photo period disruption or
shitty root conditions that will create
a stamina flower and
once that plant produces a stamina
flower
it's hard to get that to stop expressing
so if you take a clone off of a plant
that you've stressed
then you take a clone off of that plant
and veg and
your whole clonal straw stock has this
central
came from a single plant that was
stressed one time
that stress could be enough to induce
that stamina flower production every
time you go into
flower
all right go ahead
teasing that apart is that's the
hairball
what's genetic what's epigenetic but
yeah
it it definitely can happen
again one of the benefits of seed right
it's like you you'd hope a lot of those
things were reset when you go to seed
but there are also epigenetic changes
that are passed on from generations
right um the next question um
where do you think the cannabinoid in
terpene conversation will be five years
from now will thc and cbd still be
dominant
and if so where do we think their
maximum potential for
peak restaurants are you know we've seen
a lot of 30 uh thc cannabis in the last
i don't know five years or so um but you
know
where is that limit i think we're right
up against it
um you know 35 to
35 total cannabinoids is really pushing
it that's that's a really high number
uh we see it regularly but it's a small
percentage of the cultivars and
things being bred what's more
interesting
than just absolute cannabinoid or
terpene
content is how they are not
correlated so you can have something
that has
a whole lot of cannabinoid and not a
whole lot of terpene
or a whole lot of terpene and not a
whole lot of cannabinoids
or both a whole lot of cannabinoid and a
whole lot of terpene
or not very much of either so the fact
that they're not correlated
is really cool because it means that
now that the cannabinoids you know are
up to 35 percent
and probably pretty maxed out based on
the structure of the plant unless we
create some new plant that just
basically grows a giant mushroom-shaped
trichome that fills up with 80
thc you can still drive the terpene
content
up so you can add that flavor piece to
those thirty percent thc products
yeah i have a lot of i have this this
comes up with chemists in the canadian
space
often a lot of people don't believe that
those things aren't correlated i think
that you and i know that because
again we've been looking at breeding
populations most people get their data
from the marketplace
and in the marketplace they are
correlated um
but you know i agree with you in that
there's something to be said there's
there's going to be something to be said
both in the extract category and in the
flower market
for plants that are in the lower
cannabinoid or what we call the mid-tier
cannabinoid content you know the teens
10 to 20 percent and you know higher
levels of terpenes and terpenoids
um because that's gonna like you said
it's gonna allow
people to create a space where they're
not getting whacked out on thc or
overloaded with thc too early in the day
but are still able to access that flavor
know i'd like to think that in the
future we're going to be looking at kind
of the um
the the devil and the details that some
of these compounds
the relationship with within with each
other are so critical that
you know that very small infinitesimal
amounts
of various minor cannabinoids and
terpenes are actually contributing
a huge effect to the overall ensemble
effect you know it's the
second violin and the uh the third oboe
in there
that really may be making the song what
it is
um i had a question about i guess it
really kind of comes back to holland so
i remember when i was going
to amsterdam uh as a young kid
i was considered kind of uh crazy for
rolling up a pure
pure joint a lot of stuff was mixed it
also seemed like
a lot of the general cannabinoid
profiles
i don't want to say they were low but
they were kind of lower compared to
common day
i'd say maybe with the exception of
maybe some amnesia haze or something
like that
um but most of stuff seem to be kind of
in that
mid-level cannabinoid profile um
why why was that um and what when and
where did it change where we started
seeing these really elevated spikes
of what i'll call extreme thc
well the the cultural background in the
netherlands is that they were hashish
smokers
and the way you smoked hashish
discreetly and
just you know without having a
low-volume pipe of some sort
was which is an american thing north
american thing
um you rolled them in cigarettes and
most
a lot of people smoked and the obvious
no-brainer way to do it was to mix this
sometimes not that flammable
hashish into a tobacco and dilute it
a bit and make it not so strong and
but it also the tobacco has its own
physiological effects
i mean it's uh people become
highly accustomed to smoking with
tobacco
and without it they find it difficult to
get high
even if somebody rolls a pure joint like
you were trying to do
and it's the best thing you can find but
dutchies would smoke it and really not
get high until they rolled one of their
own
or just smoked a cigarette and then
suddenly they're bombed
so it there was uh that
it was both cultural in that that's why
they did it
and it also had a certain profound
effect that north americans generally
haven't followed
um yeah that's that's the history of it
um this is a question for each one of
you
um what was the cultivar that in your
opinion
kind of changed the landscape or had the
most impact
on the cannabis uh industry and
breeding in general i'll start with you
mojave
um well the cultivar that had the most
impact for me
was haze um just because that
kind of rekindled my childhood love
affair for that particular
um cannabinoid profile interpreting
profile but
i'd say and i think that everyone else
might agree that skunk
one definitely had a profound effect on
on cannabis and that it was kind of a
backbone
variety for a lot of the dutch seed
companies and
helped to kind of rein in a lot of other
varieties like pace for instance into a
more
um you know workable um line
yeah i think that question for me is in
what era i mean i would
agree with you both hayes and and skunk
it's
pretty hard to miss the
the impact that kush has had on the kush
has had in the marketplace over the last
20 years um blueberry there's so many
and i think that
to me cannabis is kind of fashion um
and these trends will come and go and
they'll always be people looking back to
the past
you know bell bottoms come around every
10 years or so
people start wearing them again and i
think that that will
too will be true with cannabis but i see
it as a as an evolution
and there's always going to be something
new that's interesting
and that's part of the beauty of it is
really to me is not focus on whatever is
the most
highest selling thing of the day yeah
that's interesting for business reasons
but you know go out there and experience
the diversity that the cannabis plant
has to offer
um there's a lot of great flavors and
great effects that
that she has hidden within
sexy bag seed right yeah the
same same thing for for us in the in the
midwest it was
you know the purple kush was was killer
the
the super skunk came through and it was
killer
and then you know when i first moved out
to california
or early 2000s it was every
it was purple and then it went to og
and then it went to cookies and it's
just
those all are all great plants you know
mojave mentioned everybody likes purple
except for the cultivators because it
takes like twice as long to grow
you know like this doesn't seem yeah
a lot a lot of the perps lines take
forever to veg into something meaningful
especially ken's or
or or granddaddy um
or purple oracle even interesting
next question is will breeders be able
to breed
cannabis varieties with extra long
trichomes
several times larger than ones today
maybe that's possible we always felt
that the
northern lights
lineage looked sparklier than it was
because it had such long trichome stalks
the heads weren't any any larger than
than
normal and the density of trichomes on
the calyxes wasn't uh
brach's better term i apologize for that
um but the density on the bracks was
was not any higher but they look really
sparkly because those extensions of the
least surface that are the
stalks they they also glisten
but i don't
other than i'm not sure why you'd want
longer stocks
if you're a hashish maker the largest
proportion of trash you have in your dry
sift
is the bloody stalks even after you're
sophisticated enough to get rid of the
green leaf particles
you still have the stalks so i would
just like to have varieties where the
heads fall off easy who cares how long
the stocks are
that means well i think that was a
question from from david actually
um and i i think oh okay hi david i
think
i think his idea is coming from he wants
to be able to pick him straight off the
plant
and peel it like a grape and just dip it
in his in his in his dab rig
right yeah
again it comes down to you know we do
have some plants that are slightly
larger sizes and marcus
you know richardson who's here knows a
lot about this from the amount of hash
he's made
um but i think probably it comes with
um you know if you get a bigger gland
you're going to have less
of them per square millimeter right
so um like we said 35
cannabinoid content if you include oil
content in there
we're looking at upwards of like or not
maybe not upwards but we're approaching
five or forty percent by weight total
of oil of cannabinoids and terpenoids in
a plant that's a lot of oil that's a
that's a pretty oily oily plant and so
from
overall from a chemical output that's
pretty good
yeah you know i would mark was saying
earlier we're not going to push those uh
firewalls much farther and there's no
other plant the opium poppy any other
plant that produces a drug
and such proliferous amounts it's
absolutely incredible
yeah and a lot of botanists don't even
believe
it's possible they think we're all high
and all the research is weird sometimes
i really wonder
you know because that's an awful lot of
of a secondary metabolite to get out of
any
any plant it's phenomenal right and
and having said that and thinking about
the future
of being able to hack the genome and
you know there's a common a common
synthase and olivetolic acid synthase
between cannabis and streptomyces and we
actually
use streptomyces to produce you know
bleomyosin which is an anti-cancer agent
so
with the right type of funding i mean
you know
and and knowledge base i mean seth's
group is probably
light years ahead on this kind of stuff
but like you could gene edit and
very easily create different molecules
for different reasons in a very
efficient way
right well i know this is a never-ending
conversation
it's been pretty incredible uh the
people in the audience are
all pretty rock star as well and it's
been great to kind of
moderate for you guys um we are at that
point where we're gonna wrap it up and
leave you guys
um with uh kind of more to think about
um this is one of many series so we look
forward to
everyone attending um it will be
recorded
it will be put up on i think youtube and
some other channels so
if you had to leave early or if you want
to re-watch some things and learn some
stuff
again uh that'll be available and
without further ado
i will um i just want to thank everyone
on the panel first of all i really
appreciate the intel
uh and insights that you all have after
all the collective years of experience
and i want to thank segre as well for
hosting and i will now turn things over
to ian davidson to close us up
all right thanks everybody thanks for
joining us thanks panelists
we've got a bunch more of these events
coming so stay tuned please
and uh sorry if we couldn't get your
questions
get a huge amount of them and uh that's
just great to see
so you all have a great day and we'll
catch you next time for our next growth
talk thank you
thank you everyone yeah peace and love