hey there during the first shaping fire
sessions I sat down with Kevin Joe jury
of Wunderland nursery in Humboldt County
and by all accounts it was a huge
success not only did he and I have a
really good time making it for you but
tens of thousands of you have watched
the videos and so we are calling it a
success if you have not seen the Kevin
Joe jury sessions you can go ahead and
click up on the playlist above and see
all the episodes bundled together and
watch them all at once today though I am
here to launch shaping fire sessions
number two this time I sat down with dr.
Ethan Russo I'm very grateful that over
the holidays Ethan invited me over to
his house and we did a long interview on
a ride range of topics that are now cut
up into topic related snippets that
we'll be publishing over the next month
or so and as you'd expect we talked a
lot about terpenes we talked about
managing pain with terpenes how much of
a particular terpene you need for some
sort of medical efficacy we also talked
about the potential for terpene toxicity
when dabbing we hit on a couple other
non terpene topics too including for
example how mushrooms psilocybin
mushrooms work on the brain to cause
neurological healing and also this first
episode which is on what foods that you
can eat to support your endocannabinoid
system in addition to the you know can I
have it a Pathak care that you're given
your body so so we've got a whole bunch
of episodes that are gonna be coming out
this is number one thanks a lot to true
terpenes for sponsoring the YouTube
channel so we could bring you this
series and here we go
enjoy
so you can thank you so much for getting
together today you know the first
question I wanted to ask you when you do
your presentations you'll often kind of
mention in passing that you know we can
do all of this cannabinoid
supplementation of our endocannabinoids
system to help strengthen it but often
you'll mention that there may be foods
that we can eat as well which will
strengthen the endocannabinoid system
and so I filed that a little bit I found
that you have an entire paper on it and
so I hope that you would break down for
us kind of simply the foods that that
everyone and especially patients could
be eating to help support and strengthen
their endocannabinoid system in addition
to the regular cannabinoid therapies
they're working on sure well there's no
simple single food that's gonna serve
that purpose on turning up the under
cannabinoid system but in general an
anti-inflammatory diet which is very
different from what Americans typically
you know that's fried foods and emphasis
on that kind of thing is not
advantageous rather in general having a
lot of fruits and vegetables it's going
to be anti-inflammatory on much more
beneficial a lot of attention has been
paid towards things like fish oil in
other essential fatty acids and those
are great being strongly
anti-inflammatory but we don't have any
evidence that they directly increase the
endocannabinoid tone the real answer is
that to do this nutritionally you have
to be a little bit indirect and affect
the microbiome the microbiome ur that
gut bacteria and people probably been
hearing more
about this it may have heard the term
probiotics which are beneficial bacteria
like our in yogurt and in lacto
fermented foods these have a strong
anti-inflammatory effect on the gut they
help prevent diseases such as diarrhea
but beyond that we have increasing
evidence that they have a key role in
increasing the game in the
endocannabinoid system but beyond that
it's not just a matter of increasing
these bacteria but they have to have the
right food themselves and a lot of what
we might throw at them and a typical
American diet isn't going to be helpful
that way rather they like things that
are a little bit hard for humans to
digest these include certain kinds of
vegetable fibers people are not likely
familiar with things like burdock root
or acacia fiber but these are fibers
that are normally in digestibility gut
bacteria one of the simpler groups of
foods it's really helpful are the LDA CI
so that is your onions leeks garlic and
the gut bacteria really like those as
well
but there are some simple supplements
that people can use burdock can be
obtained in supplement capsules and the
acacia fiber is available online if it's
not in your store and for instance it's
a simple thing they had a tablespoon of
that two granola in the morning and if
someone's taking a good probiotic with a
wide variety of species not single-agent
chances are they're gonna see some
benefits down the road in all kinds of
things first of all the regulation of
their gut may be less pain improved
sleep even clearing
of acne in the face so these are all
things that have been tied in to the
endocannabinoid system in the gut
bacteria
what is that tie end point your first
part was all about the
anti-inflammatories is the
anti-inflammatory what happens at the
same time as supporting the
endocannabinoid system or is it through
taking is it the decrease in
inflammatory that is is the actual
benefit of the endocannabinoids is
where's the tie-in well it's it's really
both but if someone's eating a lot of
fruits and vegetables particularly
dark-colored berries blueberries for
example these have a lot of flavonoids
in them these are natural antioxidants
and there are correlations that have
been drawn between having a diet that's
rich in these kinds of foods and lower
risk of things like cancer so it all
ties together and so the old adage you
are what you eat has a lot of Merit from
when we've talked in the past about the
entourage effect and flavonoids being
part of what's important of what we're
getting out of cannabis are we
essentially saying that we're we're
getting some of the essential parts that
support the endocannabinoid system just
from another source that's not cannabis
we're getting flavonoids we're just
getting non cannabis flavonoids and it
supports the endocannabinoids system
yeah to some extent we're still looking
at those relationships but clearly
having bio flavonoids in the diet is
going to be an advantaged overall health
cool and if you want to read dr. Russo's
paper on this topic you can go ahead and
find the link in the first comment below
thank you