so Kevin you know you are an expert
consultant to big commercial grows all
over the world and so you know you know
how to grow cannabis at scale but now
all over the country the reverse is
happening right folks can home grow they
can grow four six plants or something so
they can you know get their hands in the
soil and be more self-sufficient with
their cannabis well as somebody who
helps foster these huge grows at
commercial level what kind of advice do
you have for a home grower who's gonna
grow their 4 or 6 plants so that they
can have an optimum experience based on
your depth of experience with commercial
size grows don't look at the commercial
model whatsoever because that's based
off of efficiency for sale and
production you for the individual what
you're looking for is experience part of
the experiences you actually work on it
yourself and the experience of having a
holistic healthy organic model if you
can see I don't fault anybody for
growing cannabis in their closet with a
single light using a one part chemical
because if that's the tool you have to
work with and that's what you're limited
to afford and that's the barrier that
you have to get around to be able to do
it then that's where you begin and you
look for the best genetics you can get
your hands on and you put the best
effort you can
you put the the effort in that's
required to get the result that you need
as you is you go forward on this
gradient from the least resources to the
most it's not about spending more and
more money it's the opposite it's about
trying to spend less and less money and
if you're someone who can do four to six
in California six plans you're trying to
build a situation that allows you to
develop some kind of soil situation
that's self-sustaining so that what you
have is you have a permaculture
situation where your garden is
absolutely able to give you quality
cannabis every year with almost no cost
and you want to make it as simple as
possible for you so that you have an
ability to enjoy the flowers and simple
in this case would be put a watering
system in and you build organic models
that allow you to do very little effort
on that end of it the effort is applied
to basically keeping the plant and
healthy through cleaning and inspection
and work on that nature and then what
you have is you have a very low effort
low input high quality product because
for most people that are growing for
plants they're not using it for economic
gain for six plants they're using it for
personal use consumption family use
consumption neighbor use consumption
because you can give away an ounce in
California you can share and so that
situation is a very different direction
and it allows you to be able to have a
life have a normal life you don't have
to spend twenty hours a week on your
garden you're only spending a little bit
of time on your garden to actually make
it happen and the rest of the time you
spend on your garden is not necessary
for the plant it's necessary for you
that's that's where you are spiritually
connected to a plant growth because I
think so many of us are disconnected so
I think so much of home growing is so
much more than just the end product it's
the process but once you do the process
my advice to people is once you know the
process put your hands in your pockets
that way you don't touch anything and
then then you can go and sit down in the
garden and just be around
and enjoy the terpenes that are coming
off of them that are volatize in through
the the natural sunlight hitting em and
then warming up watch the wind move them
about if it's indoor in your room smell
this beautiful smell that's lighting up
a stale indoor environment if it's if
it's even electric light experience the
way the the plant responds to the heat
of it and and how the plant moves in
tropism and you become enthralled with
this process of plants that do all these
incredible processes and never speak to
you never ask you for anything and so
you have to use all these other senses
that we don't develop typically and it
grounds you in a way that's different
and when you start to become a really
good cultivator where you're really
about what you're doing you start to
have this other awareness on what you
eat
on how the earth is treated in general
and you start to have this much more
human connection and a much more
spiritual connection to the actual
planet you're on and it allows you this
beautiful window into a world that you
haven't seen prior because our lives are
so rushed we go and we just buy product
we use cannabis to change our tone but
when you produce the cannabis you're
gonna find you changing your tone
without ever consuming it and for a lot
of people that consumption becomes
second to the production process and I
think for me it's always most important
to get lost in that process but but make
sure it fits your schedule so they don't
know are they doing it you know a lot of
people say you know that cannabis is a
gateway but cannabis is a gateway to
horticulture right because you just do
that I think it opened up organic AG I
think that use the organic aggravation
in America was funded primarily by
people who are in urban areas that had
exceptional monies or they could they
could afford to make choice and then all
of us that were in cannabis production
all over the United States because we're
like why are we feeding our plants and
building soils so well and buying
supermarket food it became this
we strange paradigm of wait a minute I
don't put anything toxic on the plants I
don't do anything bad to my stuff I'm
against all these processes with my
cannabis but I'll consume fast food and
you started to see this awareness occur
with the growers where they started to
realize wait a second I'm growing
cannabis that's far healthier than my
food supply and you start to begin to
grow your own food and then you also
start to frequent farmers market so that
you can you can support local farmers
growing the food that you know you
should eat because you're so aware the
inputs on the cannabis and how it
reflects in the the end result and so I
think that cannabis cultivation in the
United States was so big and lucrative
enough that it gave people the
disposable income to choose to go
organically when prior they couldn't
because they've made organic AG so
unbelievably expensive in its production
methodology to get to the store and sell
that it precludes regular people from
buying it and then all of a sudden is
this massive paradigm shift and what we
should consume Annie and I think the
cannabis really drove it but from a
secret level no one really knew what was
pushing this incredible consumption
because where'd the money come from
you point out that really there's only
two steps to the home growers process
one build soil so that you don't have to
buying all these bottled nutrients and
spending all these extra money and then
number two you'll be present with the
plan so that you can see their changes
and they can talk to you and tell you
anything that they'll that you need you
know they say the best fertilizer for a
plant is the growers shadow
yeah a Chinese proverb yeah so I dry
that me too no I totally do and a lot of
it is you know people say I'm working
ten hours a day in my garden and I'm
like what do you do if then I was a day
and garden lead only took an hour and a
half the other the other eight and a
half hours shouldn't be considered work
it should be considered leisure but
leisure in a positive way people believe
that if you're not constantly being
industrious you're lazy and that's not
the human condition we didn't work
non-stop until basically electric lights
came out and people who did work
non-stop called slaves and you don't
want to be a slave to yourself
constantly grinding and so when you get
into a cannabis situation with plants
there's something calming from the
release of the terpene profiles that are
just naturally zooming off of them in
vegetative state and in flower and I see
it when I have people in Gardens where I
see them relaxed and it changes their
complete demeanor I've watched this for
years and so I realize that's one of the
things that's so powerful for us is that
you can allow this process which we
normally consider work to be something
that's therapeutic and healing and most
people don't get that from their jobs
and cannabis has that ability and so you
can have people that love to grow
cannabis for the other people in their
home so you may be able to grow six
plants per parcel in California and say
I grow it but it's my it's my girl or my
other people live in my house that are
the ones who consume it I may be a small
consumer and that's not the case with me
but it is it's the reality that you have
people who love to grow and cultivate
cannabis like they do flowers like they
do all forms of horticultural flora
culture agriculture and they're not
really about the consumption on the end
of it because it's the process that
allows it to happen and it doesn't have
to be complicated the complicated part
is really to understand that living soil
is about as complicated as it could
possibly be because of this incredible
interrelationship between all these
different organisms that make a delivery
possible but you learning how to do that
over time is this incredible experience
of the human life existence so it's
something that we don't get which is
really everyday living science project
yeah right on cool thank you welcome