I sell now let's talk about actual
Island yeah okay yeah I thought you were
gonna go that way
I guess I said now there we go so so I'm
changgil oh so I'm the founder of the
Vashon Island Marijuana ignores Alliance
and the community organizing that I was
responsible for him is a little
different than what you've heard so far
I realized that back when Washington
State still had medical we had about 156
producers of various summer growers
summer value-added products like edibles
and things like that but everyone worked
independently because most of them were
prohibition-era growers and you know as
we all know prohibition-era growers
don't tend to come out of shadows very
easily and connect when they take a
little encouragement and that's what I
decided I wanted to do because all of
our growers and and edibles makers we're
working as if they had to to make the
entire change themselves they were
selling their products locally and
because everyone was selling their
products locally the prices were
incredibly low on Vashon Island but the
growers were barely making subsistence
level income and so what I did is I I
formed our first Trade Organization and
brought the growers together and said
hey listen I'm gonna go ahead and make
relationships for you with Medical
dispensaries over throughout the state
and you can pool your flower and then
we'll create a channel for them to go to
the Medical dispensaries and oh yeah
will you'll be making twice as much as
you're making now and they're all like
we like your business plan you know and
and then we realize that if we if we
bring together the growers they can bulk
purchase living soil so now living soil
is now at a price that they can afford
and that was great and then
all right we really want to do probiotic
nutrients but but they're so expensive
you know and then the you know the the
crappy salt nutrients are cheap and so
sometimes we have to use that but we
don't really want you some like well
let's get everybody together who wants
to do probiotic nutrients and that's by
the book so we did that and so what we
did is we took a community of a hundred
and fifty some producers and pulled them
into one
so they for the first time began to
speak with one voice and we were able to
start getting coverage in the newspaper
as an organization and create the
conversation that growers are people to
growers don't need to be on the fringe
being a grower and creating medicine for
people is an honourable role to play in
the community and not something that we
need to tolerate so so unfortunately you
know it's July of last year the state
dismantled the medical marijuana
industry of the state and unfortunately
you know the state really turned their
back on all of these grass roots
entrepreneurs that came out of the
shadows and decided okay we will
participate with you in this experiment
of medical marijuana in Washington and
unfortunately since very few of those
people were allowed to make the
transition to the commercial market
almost all of these businesses were
pushed out of business by the state and
I think that's a shame it put these fees
these parents in the position of I
either need to decide to keep the income
from the business
I've been doing for the last you know
five ten years and being illegal or I
need to give up the income and you know
what we've done with you know the kids
extra summer camp and all the extra
things that come with being able to have
a successful business so unfortunately
we had to pivot at that point because we
went from 156 producers on the island to
floor and wobbles for producers are
still excellent and we're proud of them
than 502 that leaves 152 other families
that had their businesses crushed so we
pivoted to becoming more of a patient
and a patient and community outreach
organization and we host fantastic
speakers meetings that bring in people
from all over where we talk about
cannabis health and technique the two
points I wanted you to make sure you get
from this is number one look for a
reason to pull people together we didn't
have an organization and the growers
didn't think they needed an organization
until we thought about why don't we pull
everybody together so that we have more
strength together and then second when
the Washington State bureaucracy killed
our market we pivoted to become patient
outreach so that we could still keep
coming together and just keep exerting
influence so those are the two things
that I want to point out Thanks