poly culture is becoming really popular
in cannabis both outdoors and even
indoors now and and the idea of poly
culture of course being planting other
plants with your cannabis and and one of
the things that I personally find really
engaging about that is that when when
plants are grown near each other they're
their roots in the rhizosphere can
interact and and if for shorthand we say
that the plants can talk to each other
right and that's certainly
anthropomorphizing and you know making
them sound like they have human
attributes but they are talking to each
other can you enlighten us and what the
what is going on
biologically below the soil which in
which we are calling talking right well
lots of different things obviously let's
start with a micro Raizel fungi we know
that a plant can share mycorrhizal fungi
with other plants and so you've got that
kind of talking where where nutrients
are going to two different plants you
know the mycorrhizal fungi itself is
feeding both of them and there's
interaction as a result we know that
carbon is transferred through that
mycorrhizal Network from plant to plant
so that a trick and the carbon goes into
the tree and then you find that same
radioactive carbon in the plants that
are nearby so we know that's happening
we know now that the plant signalling
system is very complex and and again
this is something I tried to cover and
team with
with nutrients but gets bear very
complicated and so you know if you think
of any of the pictures and teeming of
nutrients of an individual cell they're
these embedded proteins that are in the
cell some of which are outside the cell
and some of which are inside the
cytoplasm of the cell and those are used
for signaling often and so you'll get
for example calcium which is a very big
signaling molecule that the routing
element that will rub against you know I
want something on the outside of the
cell and a signal will go through the
through this into the into the cytoplasm
spread throughout the entire plant
because the all of these cells are
connected with these little holes
between them and so you get signaling in
and you get these ceilings often as a
result of things that are going on in
the soil so if the soil is low in
nitrogen that signal will be will be
sent throughout the plant but system
other plants in the area that signal
will be sent through them as well and it
may not be them sending the signal but
they're getting but they might be
carrying they're carrying so if the low
ground you get you get all of that kind
of chemical its chemical talking you get
the bacteria to talking to each other
and some of that is probably overheard
yeah every month deciding is definitely
the right word overheard by the plant
you know so so bacteria talk to each
other in terpenes this is getting cool
each other in terpenes well you don't
think the plant picks up some of those
terpenes the way the way I do the
comparison is you know you're in a big
crowd and you smell somebody and they're
crowded perfume listen let's be positive
you smell perfume woman far away that's
a signal and you're picking it up that's
a language between the two of you and so
very very interesting same thing happens
have been in the soil it also happens in
err so for example at the University of
I think it was the University of
Connecticut and a situation where they
had a greenhouse they stimulated the
plant in a way that they can get a
reaction from the plant in the
greenhouse five miles
apparently away in another greenhouse
the plants react what you know so when
an aphid hits a plant the thing goes oh
oh I can't run and go tell my my little
kids that are out there that they if it
hit me but I can send the signal out to
them and does and the other plants
realize that there's an even in the area
start preparing defenses for it so it's
a chemical talking obviously we do we
have if with amorphous eyes it that's
the right way to say and that doesn't
mean it's not going on it is right now
that's totally cool thank you yeah
you