so with more more people coming to
cannabis to try for the first time and
now so many of us are able to expand our
palates because we've got more than the
one thing that our plug had for us what
do you recommend Kevin as to how that
newcomers can can maybe like build a
flight or or try a wide range of
cannabis so that they can find out what
they like in a pretty efficient way
because you know it's expensive to
experiment with the anibus and then
similarly those of us who have been in
cannabis for years and years we're
getting access to new things so so how
would you recommend somebody who's new
to it or wants to expand their palate to
do so in a way where they can reach and
be efficient that's a good question
because there's so many choices that it
becomes almost overwhelming for the
average individual to really determine
where to begin where they like - like it
and what are what I did is I tried to
neck down 42,000 terpene so there's a
42,000 different settings we basically
had to create the smell components and
so no no one alive could remember all of
this and no one would be able to
differentiate and so I said from all the
years of distributing cannabis that
really it breaks down into four
fundamental groups earth fuel floral and
fruit and those basically are very
simple terms but it allows you to see
the different Terk profiles and I was
challenged on this by some researchers
about where did you come up with this
and I said I it's just intuition for me
and they challenged it scientifically
and really it was accurate but it
basically broke down into you have a
fruit and a fuel and underneath fuel is
earth and underneath fruitless floral so
you can basically break down 42,000
terpenes into two major groups and
cannabis fruit and fuel and then below
fuel is earth and below fruit is floral
so it was really accurate scientifically
which was interesting because for me it
was intuition but for the scientists
they
to see if his hypothesis was correct
than it was and what the importance of
it is that it allows you to be able to
break it up into four groups and they
each have some very specific type of
facts fruits basically uplifting floral
some more introspective earth is more
sedative gas is very aggressive and so
those type of sensations you experience
really are pretty dominant even if the
treatment of the cannabinoid levels
fluctuate and some of the ratios
fluctuate so that the turf doesn't
determine the entire effect and high but
it definitely is a predicator of it and
what it does is it allows individuals to
say okay I want to try things that are
introspective and you would go then
through floral categories things that
had floral smells exotics and then you
would look through those for the things
that worked for you and if you wanted
uplifting then we would go into citrus
tones lemons limes grapefruits things
that really spark up your eyes and open
you up and if we wanted to have a
radical change in effect of what we're
doing we would go into gas and that's
basically what's trendy now up to all
the oh Jesus hours where you have a very
heavy mayor scene pining base that just
and there's other subtleties that make
this gaseous effect but it's very
powerful for people who want that
that's individuals we need pain relief
primarily and a radical change its own
and then earth is stuff that was old
school bubble cush the Hindu Kush is
where the policies were around really 11
to 13 they're really run high potency
but you felt it really well because it
allowed you to have a very beautiful
relaxing body high but without too much
mental race eNOS and so you're able as a
consumer if you can take a look at this
it says hey what am i seeking and I want
to have what kind of effects and for
most people they would like to have a
couple different choices and so what we
say is then you get into the four
different categories of fuel and earth
the floral and a fruit and then you go
and consume them throughout the day in
the right sequence where you would
the things that had the most heavy
impacts when you had the least amount of
mental effort and you weren't driving
and you were using stuff that was very
open and light while you were using your
creativity so typically fruits in the
morning
floral after that so that your your
introspective as you move through you
can get into earth in the in the later
afternoon because it's relaxing but it's
not devastating and then you can get
into heavy fuels in the evening where
they just basically sit you down and
really let you change your tone
completely and in those four categories
you'll be able to start I took you to
get a notebook and you just take a look
and if you can take a look at some of
the ones that you really like and you
can look at the chemo type profiles
which is really the overall cannabinoids
and the ratios you'll start to find
certain ones that let you know hey I
like a a lot of THC because I want that
euphoria but I want enough CBD to make
it to where it's not edgy and you'll
start to see those ratios and you'll
start to see these relationships and
it'll start to let you take a look at
because it's all documented now when
you're selling cannabis all this
information is present so you could go
into a modern store and if they data
based it correctly you'd be able to say
what I'm looking for is something in
this type of basic profile with with
ratios like this and you'd be able to
get into a little subset of things that
would be within that and then you would
try those because no lab report is you
it doesn't make a difference you're your
own lab report and it every single
number could line up across the board
and still not the one you like but it
lets you exit off the list and it starts
to to make it a little simpler folks
otherwise you're looking at 400 samples
not four and you want
to make this easier and more affordable
and so for me the way I recommend it is
to break it up in this fashion and just
journal it and try to use a repeatable
process meaning the way you consume it
so you have to basically set the same
smoking situation to evaluate so if you
want to evaluate your morning smoke you
need to basically smoke it at your house
while you're drinking coffee in the
morning like that every day the same
otherwise they're comparing apples to
oranges not the other way around
and that changes how you affect the high
so if I'm in a bad mood and I consume it
and I'm in a good mood and I consume it
then it's really you're putting a huge
influence on the effect itself and so
when you're trying to find out what
works for you and and really what are
the varieties that really satisfy once
you can really put it into a clearer
context now what you have is the ability
to say that's what I like I don't need
to look anymore yes I can try new things
when it's convenient but I want to buy
an ounce of that I want to buy an ounce
of that and that'll last me the next
three weeks and hopefully when you're
talking to the people you're buying it
from you're asking them are these farms
solvent do you think they're gonna be in
business in three weeks and that way
what it does is it lets you get a
repeatability otherwise you have to keep
repeating this process but it you can
make it very simple and you don't have
to know the complexities you don't have
to be able to memorize the cannabinoids
it's not important that you know every
terpene by heart and what they do that's
wonderful but that's for fishing Otto's
on a very introspective scientific type
vision users just need to say I like it
or I don't like it
it's that simple and did it work or did
it not work was it affordable was it not
affordable and then you can get into the
emotional components of did the farm
produce it in a manner that I can agree
with meaning you know are they really
environmentally conscious do they have a
real concern for the product and all
those factors weave in but first make it
simple on what kind of effect
seeking then then log to find out what
cannabinoid levels seemed to be
comfortable for you and what ratios and
pretty soon you have a good guy booked
on what to do right on great thank you
much welcome