so Joshua thank you for taking a second
to talk with me here at Emerald cup you
know I have been really aware of your
soil cultivation science conference that
is starting to tour the country and you
know I think it's really cool that
people can finally get high-quality soil
science education you know that that is
on tour right and it's going to them so
I wanted to take a second so you could
tell us a little bit about the
conference so that people can check it
out yeah man well thanks for letting me
talk about it I mean the reason is in
the name the science of organic
regenerative cannabis cultivation
conference and it's definitely Longwood
it has definitely a tongue twister but
it's you know it's the ideas to break
through the murky waters of organic
regenerative growing and as I was
learning to do this it was very hard to
find people that could teach me the
science everyone's got their methods and
it may work on their farm but when you
translate to another farm it's a
different environment to provide biodome
so that's kind of what we're trying to
do is is bring some of these heads in
who haven't been able to talk about
cannabis because of legalization and
like say bring a mont or and and really
bring people through the process of each
step here's compost you know here's soil
structure we have dr. Elaine Ingham who
is famous soil food web lady she comes
to like open the conference up and
teaches about the players and then we
walk with ship Osborn into soil
chemistry soil diversity
and we have Layton kind of talking the
same thing soil leighton-morris and he's
my partner that actually puts this on
with me and the day two we switch into
biostimulants with chris trump who i
think you know he does came thanks great
KNF is amazing i actually took his
course this summer and I am offering
fermenting everything yeah all the time
and so he you know it's a way to create
bio students or nutrients on your
property with the stuff that's do you
know around you and then we have dr.
Faust which everybody knows bio AG humic
acid public asset like definitely a
component that's hard for us to acquire
on our properties you know a reality
kick Kevin Joel trees even flying out
isn't he that's day three and like I am
so stoked that Kevin's come in like he
brings the full package together as when
we gone day three we get to talk about
genetics and he's bringing in breeders
from each region for instance you know
we're going to Vancouver to Ann Arbor
Michigan to read way some southern
Humboldt and into Portland Maine
so he's bringin read breeders from that
region so we'll have a seat a seed swap
and a genetic swap it like I just
couldn't be so blessed to be around
these heads and learn from them and like
I'm it's it's great man so so so if
people want to find out more about it
will you give them the website slowly
cuz I've messed it up a couple times
myself so what's the website where
people can find out more I for trying to
make it easier
regenerative organic cannabis calm right
on
yeah thank you so what are the what are
the four cities again humboldt i'm
baltic and then vancouver canada yep
right and then is it Portland Maine more
than May and then Ann Arbor Michigan you
got it so so if you're anywhere drivable
from those areas make sure you check it
out it should be a good time
lots of name-brand so science folks and
and you'll get to be Joshua - yeah and
one more thing I'd like to say is this
that one thing we do different here is
we don't have any sponsors your ticket
sales pay directly for the speakers to
come and travel and be there they are
there to talk with you to communicate
with you and hang out you know it's not
so that's in an out deal it's really
like so they're there to hang and so you
can actually get like you know off class
time with these these folks
instead of them rushing off to you know
their next their next thing so we're
paying them to stay long and extra for
that and so that's you know I just I
feel like it's really important to be
authentic in that and you know not not
judging anybody for doing vendors or
sponsorships but this is your thing you
want to do it your way
right on well I wish you and Layton the
best with the program and we'll talk on
the other side and and see how when
awesome REI great to see ya right on