all right Dr seil Agarwal is a physician
scientist and medical geographer he is a
fellow of the American Academy of
physical medicine and rehabilitation
he's presently paliative medicine
physician and Associate hospice medical
director at multiair Medical Center in
Auburn Washington an NIH medical
scientist training program Fellowship
award e Dr agal received his PhD in 2008
and MD in 2010 from the University of
Washington he has published over two
dozen peer-reviewed articles and
chapters as an NSF graduate research
fellow he wrote a PhD dissertation
entitled the medical geography and
cannaboid Botanicals in Washington state
access delivery and
distress in 2009 Dr agell successfully
led the effort to get the American
Medical Association to call for a review
of the scheduling classification of
cannabis the first such statement in 72
years he serves on the editorial
Advisory Board of the National Cancer
Institute PDQ cancer Camp information
summary on cannabis and cannaboids he is
an Affiliated faculty of the MultiCare
Institute for research and Innovation
and an invited affiliate assistant
professor at the udub department of
geography and an associate member of The
Humble Institute for interdisiplinary
Mar marijuana research he is an honorary
Trustee of the medical cannabis
Foundation of India and vice president
of the Washington physicians for social
responsibility tonight he's going to
talk about the history of cannabis and
humans it is my honor to welcome
Dr so great to be here I've heard about
the vi meetings for like years uh all
the way back when I was in New York and
I've been waiting um for years to come
and I'm really really happy to finally
get a chance to be here Dominic cor
whereever he is there he is he first
started telling me about these meetings
and uh I would see pictures of this
range Hall and it just was what a scene
what a place we talk about cannabis in a
place where which is traditionally set
for people to exchange farming things
that they've grown together and and be
with others socially just it was
mindblowing and it's really is
mindblowing
In the Flesh so thank you for letting me
be here tonight and um I just wanted to
I guess uh you know Shango and I had had
a conversation about some broad Strokes
about cannabis geography and humans and
uh he said listen you should tell tell
us more about that in this session in
this setting so um that's what I that's
what I want to share with you all
tonight um I also want to give a great
homage to my mentor and friend Ethan Dr
Ethan Russo who without him I would not
have gotten that PhD in the University
of Washington because he was on my
supervisory committee so here to Ethan
and much of what I'm going to share with
you uh much of this information was
really not well put together and
collected uh until Ethan brusso sat down
and actually called it and cator
cataloged it summarized it uh for people
to read all around the world so this is
a this is has to be said so let's give
him another round of applause
it's wonderful so anyway I was very
nervous about speaking here but but I
told him please uh I don't want to get
any alternative facts tonight so
please I'm not doing
that so um geography is my spe medical
specialty or at least social science
specialty medical geography sub group in
that but in geography we've always we
studied human plant relationships as one
facet of how humans shape the
environment in planet Earth and our our
space and environment around us I was
always very interested in the concept of
questions about how cannabis came here
uh to this where this space that we all
occupy together uh and you know how
something that has was evolved on planet
Earth came to seem socially so alien uh
and so U socially you know marginalized
and and all that stuff demonized all the
things that that we've been dealing with
for all these just just actually Century
or two although if you go back in 13th
century there was there was attempts to
prohibit cannabis in in some parts of
the Muslim world at the time there world
but those didn't succeed so and it won't
succeed this time either but the
question I had was in those days nobody
ever tried to eradicate it with the
degree of f ferocity that the uh drug
enforcement Administration the United
States and their literal crop pulling
you know all that physical labor
involved in trying to eradicate
something that's wind pollinated I mean
you really have to really have a lot of
money and a lot of heart to go after
something that's spreads like that so
how did we get into that situation and
so and I'm from Oklahoma that's where
I'm born and raised um which had the
most Draconian marijuana lws in the
Western Hemisphere uh if you you know
because we aren't don't share the death
penalty uh stuff that Indonesia and
Malaysia and China and other places have
but we you know we'll put you in jaill
for life for growing one plant at least
that was on the books for a while and
life P life sentences were passed just a
few years ago signed by the current
governor for uh making
hashish so you know that's kind of hey
now they actually have their
decriminalization policies on cannabis
are actually more ahead of Washington
state in so in terms of their possession
amount that's decriminalized there still
it's still a very very different game
there and there's still a lot of ways to
go but uh still that's what I knew
growing up and um I really uh so in in
my in my body in my brain cannabis was
really really you know dangerous and
alien but anyway we know otherwise and
let's what I I want to share with you is
a little bit about what researchers uh
geograph there's a really great
geography researcher at the University
of New Mexico he was written a book
called cannabis that's it uh you know by
his name is Chris dual and he's an
associate professor the department of
geography the University of New Mexico I
cannot highly I can't more highly
recommend this book look how beautiful
some of the interior designs are it's
really it's really beautiful book
physically and I have no Financial stake
or whatever but I'm just telling you
this is of all the books that I got to
see when I was doing my research days
none that I've seen put together all the
different pieces in such a nice way and
one thing this book does that you will
not find in many other volumes on
histories and geographies of cannabis is
it talks about the use of cannabis in
Africa
uh which is widely neglected area of
research uh and study and U it's
completely unusual and surprising um and
U kind of colonialist because smoking
cannabis was invented in Africa uh and
he has unequivocal evidence towards that
fact um when drug cannabis
cultures went from India South Asia to
parts of Africa that's where the smoking
had already been developed for other
herbs and and uh this is where he
believes that Canabis smoking began
which is what we were just talking about
a few minutes ago but um anyway that's
that's something that's really worth
looking at because uh we really need to
get our brains around actually
cannabis's role in uh the global
societies internationally and
historically uh so we can actually stake
our social Commonwealth claim towards if
that's my moral two cents about the
thing because if you don't if you if you
don't claim it you're going to lose it
that's true for any of our rights in
society uh and I think at this day and
age um everybody wants to stay a claim
so um but you know what can was well
there and around well before we even
enter the scene evolutionarily speaking
so this is what's really interesting
this evolutionary story of actually how
this cannabis plant came to even evolve
in the way that we come to know and L it
uh so it all starts on um in the
primordial uh land Mass called
laasia before the Indian subcontinent
crashed into through plate tectonics
collided into with the Asian land Mach
that was a cont called laasia and that
is actually where we believe uh the
ancestral Canabis and the central part
of that where it evolved began to grow
uh and what's really interesting is that
it was really the due to the
interactions of that ancestral cannabis
with the physical environment that it
was in I elevation climate um exposure
to the sun uh this is how the different
varieties of cannabis that we know in
two major categories developed and this
is what this is what the prevailing
theories are in geology and geography of
Canabis so what happened was uh this is
kind of in between the time of the
evolution of this of nettles and hops
these are the two plants that are most
closely related on either side to this
Canabis plant and we're talking about
somewhere in a range of 30 plus million
years ago uh you know humans are I don't
know some some hominids we go couple
Mill two million you know so we're going
way back before before any of that stuff
was going on um so uh Nettles originated
about 55 million years ago and humulus
or hops distinguish itself six and a
half million years ago so somewhere in
that window is where cannabis's window
uh so in that area of Central Asia that
landscape um there was there was there
was some Highlands over there but they
weren't that high in elevation uh but
what what started to happen is that you
know due to the the movement of the
Earth's plates this Asia Indian land
mass began to collide with with the land
mass of Asia and those cannabis plants
uh became exposed to increasingly higher
elevations over a period of millions of
millions of years uh this is a very
disruptive event in the history of
planet Earth uh it it led to the
creation of the largest uh landlocked
area of land on planet Earth that whole
Central Asia area there was no there
wasi prior to that those many of those
places had exposure to Ocean but no
longer this had huge impacts on climate
uh devel led to the evolution of the
monsoon uh and um this plant uh it sort
of caused a separation of two different
varieties two different separate areas
of uh Evolution for Canabis one that was
in the area of what we now know as the
Hindu Kush mountains uh in Western
Himalayas and one that was further to
the north of I can't remember T and
Islands there's some area in that in
that part little closer to the North
further to the
north and uh what's what's really
interesting is that what we know and
what we know is that uh as cannabis uh
became more exposed to higher elevations
in lower latitudes UVB radiation becomes
more prevalent it's just a it's just a
fact of life if you're going to survive
in high Highland areas you're going to
have to be exposed to the Sun and UV
radiation can detoxic to your DNA it can
cause DNA damage which can lead to uh
mutations which can be toxic or
unhealthy and that kind of things so you
have to develop a survival mechanism and
that's one Theory as to why we think
that abundance of cannabinoids became
began to be developed the ecological
explanation to word off insects and
things like that people don't think that
that explains fully enough how much you
know what this was involved for and we
can talk separately about why this
particular class of compounds and not
other compounds tpes uh also have
interesting properties to when they are
aromatized they can seed clouds um like
Pine lemine and this cloud cover can
also help to prevent you know sun
exposure as we all know in the Northwest
so that is another thing going on but uh
this is kind of a big moment and then
the other the Cannabis stands that were
further to the north um what happened
there uh there was another like there
was different ages and shifts in the in
the glacial ages that were now the pesto
scene era and between two interglacial
periods uh people talk about cannabis
really had to become a little bit more
into the grasslands into the plains
areas to survive in that area and more
closer to rivers
uh which is different from what was
going on in the South further south
which was more into the mountainous
regions uh so this kind of created two
separate
evolutionary environmental pressures um
and nowadays I mean and it was Dr Russo
who first showed this to me uh genetics
is what we use to try to distinguish our
cannabis species to figure out you know
in dogs we can say what's a Chihuahua
and what's a Doberman just by looking at
it but but cannabis was always such a
thing where you really had to get close
up close and personal at least humans
did to find out what's what uh and that
really perplexed and Confused people for
hundreds and hundreds of years uh Bist
and everything not everyone was exposed
and people saw cannabis they would call
it one thing because they reminded them
of their cord plant you know and it
turned out to be a drug plant vice versa
so it's all confusing but Dr Carl Hill's
uh genetic analysis really tried to show
that there probably are two distinct
species and maybe this is the origin of
that distinction and I know we and we've
allten used these terms Inda sativa and
there's there's folk uses of Inda and
sativa there's technical uses of Inda
and sativa and who knows it's all very
and then of course there was a period
where there was people talked about
ruderalis um but I think all of these
things um are you really have to just
look at it from a historical Evolution
standpoint there was one ancestral
cannabis they do interbreed um but U
this is how
arose now um the other part of this
story is domestication of course so you
know cannabis was doing this thing and
then you know Along Comes um you know
Homo sapian sapiens and um you know we
we we've got some earliest evidence
abuses and I can't remember exact dates
here uh some 30,000 20,000 years is
something in that range is that righto
somewhere in that range you start seeing
polling of cannabis in uh Europe uh and
you start seeing um you know pottery
markings uh things like that of twine I
can't remember the exact years but there
are various distinct domestication
episodes that occur in Asia um which is
of course where it would naturally first
occur because that's where cannabis is
uh and the movement of cannabis across
uh from South Asia across to East Asia
into China we think was through hun
gatherers moving through this green belt
that came across all of Asia in China
and this is really interesting you know
to see how people are moving with this
um there were uses for seed uses for
fiber uh and then this the idea of using
heated cannabis greens for drug effects
uh is some is involved in primordial
relig is is the remnant of that we find
in primordial religious texts uh from
zor asrian um you know viic uh viic
societies um
those are mainly the existing written
texts that go further back but there's
current ongoing archaeologic studies of
a civilization called the haraa
civilization and there one thing called
the bactera complex which is in like a
place called tur it's now turkistan or
Turkmenistan this sort of region you can
find clay pots uh small cups and they
would have clay pots and they would have
little seves and inside those clay pots
you see remnants of E ra uh cannabis and
if I'm not mistaken opum uh those three
things in drinks that people drank and
revered uh and
uh you know uh same pot in the same pot
yeah it's it's a mix you know it's a
mixed wine mixed drink uh this
is fedra gives you stimulation opium you
know Somas and cannabis little
activation as well other kind other
sorts this ation was a possibly part of
the primordial Soma that has been sung
about for centuries or ha in other texts
in Persia so this was this was a drug
complex this was not around um you know
cannabis to starve for famine or
cannabis to make my shoes this was
Cannabis to bring me uh relief from
distress uh anxiety and closer to toity
spirituality Spiritual
Development uh so and in different parts
of Asia you saw different developments
of these types of cultures uh and
sometimes there were there was more drug
and more and less of the uh the thread
and utilization and sometimes it was the
other way around but this in these areas
indicaa was all about that European
cultures that developed around the stand
of cannabis that came from the northern
uh uh population uh you know cannabis
was more in the realm of uh cloth and
fiber this was described by Herodotus
Herodotus was the ancient Greek
historians the first references you see
uh the the very famous thing is the
whole cth I don't know if you guys know
whoever reads this stuff the cian
funeral writes of using hemp seeds
thrown on flames and people of guess
that maybe that was also psychoactive
but we don't really know for sure U but
the other thing that he mentions is that
cannabis fiber was used in thce which is
a you know that that itself tells you
that there was a development of a fiber
textile industry around H cannabis in
Ancient Ancient Greek at times uh and
then spread with the Romans and and
whatnot so cannabis was about that there
were some medical uses described for
hemp seeds and and texts of like for ear
infections I think that
right okay so the oil from ear from
seeds but uh you know they didn't know
much about anything
else so I guess uh a lot of fascinating
developments happened in South Asian
cultures around cannabis
but really we don't hear much about it
until the
1500s U because this again this is the
moment when Portuguese Sailors uh land
in in modern day South Asia and start
noticing people drinking this thing
called bang VA n they called it uh and
this was uh something that they
associated with underclasses people who
uh were doing Labor uh people who were
uh cooking cleaning um and then the
sailors started to use it too and they
said well this is this this this makes
me laugh this makes me hungry this is
this is interesting what is this stuff
um and you know there's there's actually
some nice quotes in here about the very
first sailor who came across this and he
he said it looks like the stuff we have
back home but it really
isn't I know where it is I'll I'll look
for it a little bit anyway uh this these
moments start to show Europeans that
there's this other uh type of cannabis
and um it starts to spread from there U
you start getting also more Europe
English Sailors start coming a guy named
uh I forgot his name right now he was he
was in in Sri Lanka and he had found
cannabis was being used indigenously and
he found that when he had terrible GI
upset you know from all the exposure to
different types of bacteria and water
that he's drinking there compared to
what he has in Europe uh that he could
drink used cannabis and he would still
get an appetite and you know not end up
was awayed that from diarrhea that can
would normally otherwise kill you so
that was interesting to him he brought
seed back
to the one and only Robert Hook does
anybody know who Robert Hook
is okay besid
you yes did he event we improv the mope
that's right yes he he the father of the
modern
microscope uh he is the one of the one
of the founders of you know one of the
Great scientist in the history of
Western medicine Newton's uh
Newton's competitor right you know they
they were it was there was Newton and
there was hook you know and of course we
remember remember Newton but um Hook was
really a major player on the scene in
Europe in England in the Royal Society
the first President I believe Royal
Society which still exists to this day
um so he started growing cannabis from
the seed that this other guy brought
didn't do too well apparently but uh he
also tried using some of the canns that
he had and so he was one of he is the
first Western scientist to methodically
cultivate consume and describe the
effects of K and this guy is literally
one of the most famous books in the
history of microbiology he basically
tripped out a whole lot of Europeans uh
because he showed everyone but a
protozoa looked like or am it was like a
very bizarre new thing his book was very
popular
so uh this is how cannabis becomes a
thing in you know English-speaking world
anglophone world it was through these
exposures from Colonial Sailors to South
Asia also u a lot of cross-pollination
starts happening on the ships of portug
Portuguese sailed around the world uh
often times you'd have um Africans and
South Asians and different classes of
people trying to survive on these boats
and this is one thing way that people
exp were cross exposed to use of
cannabis and I already told you about
the afan story uh and it had spread
first in the eastern part of Africa and
then it took really I think it was
somewhere in the 1600s or so that you
got to the western part of Africa kind
of in the area of South Africa and
um South Africa and Namibia but really
didn't extend beyond Sudan for a long
time so this is that this is like what
people are starting to put together when
you try to put all the different
historical records together all the U
physical evidences you see these
distinct patterns of migration of
cannabis with really really interesting
is when it starts to get out to this
part of north of the earth um you know
it was really through uh the
transatlantic slave trade
indentured uh systems of of of colonial
labor practices um cannabis was always
associated with menial
work relief people who uh did menial
jobs and uh who had didn't have a lot of
uh self saying that cannabis was
something that was used to help to deal
with monotony and this is a very this
famously entered into the popular
American discourse in the 70s when um
well if anybody was reading uh the
medical Anthropologist went to Jamaica
and studied uh the use of cannabis in
Jamaica Melanie Dre and a few other
folks I can't remember all their names
um but this was a time when people were
saying oh Canabis makes you lazy and aot
moated uh there they would find workers
that say Hey without cannabis I can't
you know it makes me motivated to work
it was very confusing to people because
we've been taught so long that it led to
this state of apathy uh and here here
you have more extent cultures that came
from those you know Caribbean um
agrarian uh work where it was just the
opposite so that um that's a little bit
of how things kind of seeped in here and
you guys have heard more of the stories
about Mexican migration or whatnot the
other part of the story I want to share
with you is kind of the history of
medicine because a lot of these things
are are forgotten people don't really um
talk about how cannabis uh made its way
into the most revered pharmaceutical
houses and in the books of the most
established and prestigious phans in the
in the history of modern medicine uh
they just think oh you know this is
something that we heard about the 1960s
and 70s when you know people were uh
people had severe symptoms of cancer and
HIV
and and then of course glaucoma those
three are really how people think that
cannabis's medicine became a thing but
really and this is a lot of work has
shown multiple uses of cannabis and and
various systems of medicine uh
traditional Chinese medicine so
traditional stuff we know about
traditional Chinese medicine unani tibbi
uh forms of Persian medicine a very
famous doctor uh Ian Senna iban Senna
also called AI in the west same guy uh
when you look at the government of
India's traditional knowledge Digital
Library where they try to catalog all
their plants so that somebody doesn't
come in Monsanto their traditional you
know crops which has been tried multiple
multiple times uh such as uh neem and U
turmeric have been attempted to be
monopolized by
Western companies uh and I believe I've
heard that cannabis was also attempted
but what they started to do is uh create
a digital library they said you know
here's traditional prior use we got this
prior use prior use prior use so there
was an entry in there for canabus and
what they site for their traditional
here's our prior use is the textbook of
abna from the 11th century and it's a
really interesting reason they cite this
book is because this book of Arabic
medicine was what they used in medieval
Europe to teach medicine when there was
no medicine besides you know leeches and
blood lining or whatever they did you
know in medieval Middle Ages and I don't
to be completely split but that's what
it was this was the Greek uh the Greeks
got it from the uh the Arabs got it from
the Greeks and the Arabs maintained it
and and expanded it and then gave it
back to the Europeans and this is a
citation they use uh but uh there is a
small reference to cannabis in Europe
but you know again it wasn't as widely
known until the 1800s or uh the 19th
century when these modern Physicians
were coming to um Kolkata and uh that's
where Dr Ran see which we all know about
everyone know about asanas asanas is the
name taken by uh for the group of
California medical cannabis doctors
since 1996 Dr Mia's group he's he was
the grandfather of medical cannabis he
also extracted all his old literature
he's now passed away 2007 I think he
passed away from liver cancer um anyway
uh he he named his group oases because
he wanted to pay homage to this Irish
physician who was so brilliant that he
actually uh you know learned cannabis
from the natives in Kolkata and used it
on his patients to treat things like uh
rabies endstage rabies where you get to
a phase where the rabies goes into your
central nervous system and you can't
drink anything you can't eat anything
you're extremely like you just like
waste away and everything you try to put
in your mouth you spit out and he would
give cannabis grains to those patients
and they would be able to start eating
oranges and have more relaxation and
fall asleep and and pass away
comfortably he gave it to patients who
had tetanus really Advanced stages of
tetanus where you were just stiff and he
could kind of relax them uh some
infantile cases and he's he writes it
all up he gives it to animals and
medical students he says this is an
amazing thing you know I'm going to make
my my name for this he actually didn't
make his name on that he made his name
on something else he laid the telegraph
lines in India uh and was kned for that
so you know he had a previous amazing
thing where he figured out how to I
hydrate people Colora victims as a
medical student people were dying of
dehydration and he said why don't we put
electrolytes in the fluids and put that
in their veins and maybe they'll survive
and he wrote those ideas down and that's
of course current day
treatment that's that's what we do so
this guy was pretty cool and uh he was a
really um interesting fellow we don't
hear about him at
all I mean why is it not taught why is
he not taught in medical schools why
because it was a cannabis thing right
because so his introduction into the
modern medicine of cannabis really
excited all sorts of people in Europe
and back in the UK and in Ohio all over
you know you'll see there was meetings
in 1850s or Ohio doctors just after he
published in 1840 something so people
were really interested in what was going
on in IND in India and they were this is
a great treatment for neurological
disorders and for pain um we were just
talking about migraines Dr beforehand U
the there was a doctor at the New York
neurological Society named segn he was a
president of the society he said it's
the most Superior treatment that he
knows for migraine headaches and Dr
Willie Mosler the father of internal
medicine who found a joh Hopkins
University and started rounding you know
you hear about white coat Dockers going
around hospitals rounding that's what uh
that's what doct Osler did came up with
and he he wrote about that in his
textbooks this is the treatment that you
got to use for Migra
hings U there was another doctor uh who
invented opalos scalpy I mean looking
into your you know when the doctor puts
up into your eye and looks into your
retina and sees if there's any illness
there what the blood vessels look like
the Doctor Who had routinely started
introducing that in medical practice uh
he was a big fan of use of cannabis uh
the one of the doctors who first started
to to distinguish the different types of
epilepsy more generalized versus related
to an injury he was a big fan of
cannabis uh the Doctor Who was one of
the early researchers of Parkinson's
disease I don't know if the poiner of
Parkinson's disease but some somebody
who did some major work uh he also
talked about canvas there was a lot of
really Advanced top Notch physicians in
the in the UK and in United States or in
Canada um who for can for them cannabis
was a very unique and important part of
the medical
pharmacopia uh there was even U Brown
there a there's a syndrome we call you
there's some things in medical school
you any medical students say hey what
what do you call a a patient who has a
spinal cord injury that's only halfway
done you know it's a one half of the
cord is cut the other half is okay
sometimes it happens in injuries motorcy
vehicle accidents it's called a brown
sequard syndrome Brown seard syndrome
where one side of the body has one
deformity the other side has another Dr
Brown secard had his own cannabis
preparation named for him cannabis and a
few other things in that so I tried to
tell this to the students and doctors I
talk to to let them know this is
actually the names Osler and all these
names are in our current textbooks and
teachings these all these doctors saw
cannabis as something that was important
part of their pharmacopia we
unfortunately lost it due to
inability to understand what it was the
rising prominence of pharmaceutical
houses the consolidation of Power by
professionals uh and Etc and the closure
of certain alternative medical practices
in the United States all these things
there was a bunch of forces not to
mention good old fashion racism and
xenophobia and all the things that we
are still dealing with in 2017 those
were probably worse back then anyway so
but it's not the science it's not
through the this is not cannabis
medicine was not a recent discovery
that's kind of it was never alien it was
never alien it was always tracking along
different groups in society that may not
may or may not have maintained a level
of Civility or
respectability but we're changing all
that now right we're we we've kind of uh
we've kind of gotten into a very new
place with cannabis and I think my
message I probably need to wind down or
take some questions or something but I
guess where I can a 15 minutes to keep
talking
yeah
H okay okay I will what what I want to
tell you about this whole where I see
that so I let me give a little bit of a
a moral or I don't
know an idea to think about so if
cannabis uh has so many fingers uh pre
of course prior to human evolution uh
and Beyond uh so many fingers so many
different civilizations throughout the
eons um and U you know who who actually
gets to say at the end of the day that
they're they get the rightful prominence
over that
species I don't think I don't think
anybody could really claim that if
anybody if one person claims it
everybody has to claim it right you
really can't choose it was never any
prior you know uh owner and that's a
that's for me a very uh important lesson
to draw from that when we talk
social policy and we're talking about
who has access to the means of
production you know to use an old term
from marks uh but it's a it's it's the
this human plant relationship is not a
imaginary or trivial or kind of a hippie
New Age concept or whatever this is a
fundamental to how we have actually
interacted with our our planet and the
things in it and that we ignore at our
Peril and I think the fact that we don't
even talk about it uh is because we have
become so commodified in our society
that we are so dis removed from uh I
mean there are variations on that that's
that things have changed but I think we
think always think about cannabis in not
already sort of process ready to go away
and the fact that we don't pay attention
to that um ground level up side of
things is why I think we never developed
a legalization of production you know
for all adults in this state uh I mean
there's other Histories on that but you
know it would have been Unthinkable if
you had imagine cannabis legalization in
other times in
history that that that didn't
fundamentally mean you know being able
to
cultivate and doing all that in your
whatever is your space or your community
space so that is a interesting kind of
thing to come out of this this uh moral
from this and I I think this issue of
monopolization or or I also like the
term
alization you guys know the these long
words but these are really ways to talk
about few people own or one person own
mono or Alo and I think that is the
whole way that cannabis diffused in
around the world was because multiple
people owned not just one or two or
three but like the most marginal person
in society stuck on a slave ship you
know uh going someplace they know not
and they bring with them a few seeds
from what their Homeland is to produced
there whether they're indentured or or
uh getting no pay at all uh these are
the kind of people that own cannabis and
that's why we have cannabis here you
know it was not because we were you know
uh had a billion dollars of extra money
sitting around and you know or had where
the son of the king or whatever it would
have been back then would be the
equivalent of privileg today and I think
that's really an interesting thing to
think about when you when you wonder
well who is going to own cannabis in
North America or in in the global
society
today uh okay I'll stop
there all right
who so I'm really interested in can
as uh Apes sexual aid for women after
menopause when they kind of lose
interest in sex I've been trying to
research that however I can and and of
course the Indian tant kind of trys they
talk about the Fang for what he should
be using which is a drink as you said so
what do you think that that's the drink
are they not smoking it then you
mentioned again sailor seeing
that so two two things first all modern
use on cannabis sexuality a really great
talk is by Dr Jordan tishler TI i h c he
gave a talk at green flower media
cannabis help Summit last year he was
there with me about a year ago I think
2016 uh in January it's probably online
someplace uh it was very good he really
summarized a lot of modern sex uh human
sexuality research around cannabis even
there's even some controlled research on
on cannabis and blood flow to organs and
and um there's like psychological stuff
and there's physiological stuff there's
a whole there's a whole world of that
that I I know very little about his talk
really put a lot of it together so
please look for that he's really into
that and um and I think that's a huge um
untapped area when we talk about you
know this whole this whole very modern
distinction we have between what's
recreational you know and what's really
medical and and then what's health that
you know I think that's both right you
can't have you're not going to be
healthy if you have no Recreation and if
you don't have access to Medicine you
also will be Healy either so it's kind
of need them both anyway so that's a
thing to to say and then I the Tantra
cannabis use of there's a a really good
paper from 1970s by a Dr Michael alich
count of cannabis using India Journal of
psychoactive drugs I think it was he was
the first one to really I thought pulled
some of these texts together a lot of
what was happening there was various
forms of violation of social Moray so
people who did not eat meat that night
they would eat some beef people who did
not use alcohol they would drink some
hard alcohol they would use you know
cannabis was also a little bit of a
always seen though it was not illegal
there was some groups in certain times
you would use it you know and if you
were't using it in off time is was like
hey you're kind of doing something that
you're not supposed to so some of that
was that to um um but yes that all the
use of cannabis in those uh uh social
religious contexts were was oral um
there is inhaled cannabis use as well in
groups there but that's not what's
described in Dr alder's book or paper
and I think that what's happening you
know is that you just get a longer
duration effect uh and there is a
there's a first path through the liver
you get this stronger 11 hydroxy
metabolite of THC as opposed to when you
get inhaled you get a much much lower
amount of that
that has more blood brain barrier
penetrability uh you have a longer
lasting effect uh and it's stronger and
you know you can go all night long I'm
just
joking that's why do like that why would
you know we're not take your
[Music]
time all right who was the
top I have a leading question for you s
uh you've talked a lot about you know
humans and the history of cannabis I
want to hear a little bit for the room
uh about the history of women and
cannabis
uh uh because obviously there's a
gendered history there uh and I know
that you could speak about but yeah and
there's a great U uh she's at University
of Southern Maine she wrote that book on
you know the Wham Community
wom BL know her name just right now now
Wendy chapus thank you yeah Dr Wendy
chapus was a sociologist who studies had
studied sex workers in in the US and and
started writing about cannabis scene and
a really great book you can check it out
called D to get high and uh she has a
really great chapter on the F the the
gendered issues around cannabis uh that
some of the Notions throughout cannabis
as a uh you know the female flowers and
some of the emotional receptivity things
that it does generate in its users uh
these are part of why it's being
maligned and she kind of ties it into
sexual um you know the feminist feminist
lens
um and there was another another uh
person who's written something out else
recently there's tremendous uh
masculinity in the U modern High Times
portrayals that historically started
High Times and Playboy join started
together you know were funded by the
same people they catered to the same
crowd you know and it was uh it was out
of that kind of a fishing a you know um
smoking your cigar in your you know what
that rope that you know the these
Notions were were popularized as if it
is a strictly masculine you know thing
High time but that's completely like
modern you know was thinking 19th
century yeah so if you go further back
you know uh I mean the historically in
uh in Europe uh the witch hunts which
were I don't know 100, women were burned
the stake or bu through through a effort
through the Royals and Catholic Church
they really eradicated traditional plant
healers um a lot of these were women and
a lot of them you think had cannabis
knowledge in in addition to other herbs
uh and uh I think that
uh is part of uh you know what we've
lost uh um the use of canvas and child
birth is also something that we know
have evidence from in the Levant like
modern Israel Palestine in actual
physical evidence of people who are
giving birth uh we've seen in their
bones and their remains have died in
child birth cannabis residue and I think
that uh use in ways to help Labor uh you
know these things have been completely
marginalized as if that doesn't matter
and then not to mention you you talked
about menopause and there's also men uh
you know menstrual dysphoria related
pain uh this this has a lot of patients
have said that cannabis is helpful for
them to have more uh when they have
severe uh symptoms also in in pregnancy
there's the nause and vomiting of
pregnancy severe problems we get
hospitalized but we have no good
treatments for that and we give very
drugs that may be more harmful to the uh
to their conceptus than than what they
are taking and that's terrible uh when
cannabis we don't have strong evidence
that it's this very dangerous thing but
we know that it can help people in that
scenario and we don't even have that
option available so there's lots of
things that we don't think about that
are specific to women's bodies around
and their traditional knowledge that
have been completely ignored as if
that's sort of like a marginal issue I'm
sure there's way more histories there I
don't I mean they don't what I was
leading to oh tell no no no you did it
you did
it this is a much more boring
question I I can't even come close to
that that was good both of those were
talking about two distinct species Inda
and then you kind of touched on ralis a
little bit is there I mean is there any
historic Route of know
yeah based on Hill's work the genetic
analysis of various libraries they
didn't find a third grouping it's just
those is actually it's a weedy version
of one of the two or a mix of the both
this is cannabis is a semi-domesticated
plant it never stays domesticated why
it's a weed right right so so some of
these stands may have been around for
Millennia uh there are still while in
that area where can evolved I was
telling you about you can still find
wild grown cannabis in the forests and
the rivers uh and so I think uh it's
came to the attention of Western
scientists uh by Soviet botanists in
sometime in the 30s or 40s I don't know
I can't remember when this is who coined
the term R RIS Soviet
biologist but I think people just didn't
really know they had no idea for
nomenclatures again they were just like
physical traits that they thought set
set it apart I'm not saying that there
might not be there's definitely a
geography to genetic distribution but if
you really want to get into the
speciation um we don't we don't find
that that's not eventually we're going
to change our the classification has
been contested for so long even the fact
that we used and named it cannabis and
that we uh had sativa for you know
something everything to do with where
lenus the botanist in Sweden where he
was at the time and what he knew about
cannabis he had no knowledge of drug
cannibis it was all the other stuff I
know so H fit in with it well yeah hemp
is the the uses what we now call hemp
the uses of cannabis that involve fiber
and uh cellulose uh cordage and Seed um
you can produce that from either of
those two classes of cannabis uh that's
for sure uh just some of them what
happened in India uh they started to
make charas and ganja which are like
more uh something that's with charas you
would actually want you you run your
body through the field and then scrape
the resin off your
bodys learn it from gos people step on
grapes and wineries all the time how
many people have oh it's so romantic to
step on the grapes that then we consume
in our wine so it's the
same except you're just you know they
would
laughing so people are laughing
Delight that's
soard it the sex
topic actually use they would often use
children this is
documented because so in order to do
this they needed shorter plants in order
to do a CH production you would you
would select for varieties that wouldn't
grow very tall so you could do that uh
when you were making other materials uh
Hong it was you didn't need to do that
Char so you could grow taller so this is
one way that some distinctions that we
kind of think about Broad Leaf and
narrow leaf and and size may have come
out of this this genetic germ plasm pool
that was down there um and then when
chus production moved into uh Lebanon
and the Middle East um people they may
not have used shorter plants they may
have used longer plants because they had
different method methods of uh making
hashish uh through you know sees and and
the more powder things that we're more
familiar with so all of these um so I
think you know it's all to do with um
just different versions of the same in
the same family which which uh species
of varials are more developed in the
area of hemping that you want whether
it's the stock or the fiber or stock or
the seed
predominantly you know and I I can tell
you the restriction that we place on
hemp today um probably like artificially
limit the variety of thick stocked High
yielding fiber oil seed uh cellulose
plants that could be potentially grown
uh so you're really not you really can't
this whole idea that okay we're only
going to have you know point less than
3% for this means that a whole potential
genetic you're chopping off the arm of
cannabis because maybe those those
varieties have gen genes and features
that'll be more helpful to uh have a
greater yield if you're trying to get
cellulose so that shouldn't be at all a
barrier for at least R&amp;D uh when it
comes to developing U good hearty hemp
string I I think you more or less
answered I was trying to sort of get to
the um genetic origins of the drug type
non-drug type uh narrowly broadly but it
sounds like the drug type was being
forced upwards over time and so had to
respond through developing new canabo
and terpenoids to protect itself whereas
the non-drug type was more having to
compete in the I'm sorry yeah the
non-drug type was having to compete in
the lowlands and you know in sort of
more in a weedy environment um but then
the broad leaf narrow Leaf sounds like
was something that was more cultivated
by humans along the way and so do we
have really kind of can you break them
into almost four distinct groups of kind
of Bas cannabinoids and terpenoids and
and and other is that one way to kind of
look at it is you've got if you were to
look at sort of the whole plan extract
of non drug type drug type broadly Nar
life would you have four distinct kind
of groupings might you have I don't know
I'll Leto answer that question it's on
my knowledge uh I'll just say briefly
there's certain terpenoids that are
associated with so-called sativa others
with so-called Indica um to me this is
sort of a false dichotomy I think people
are really hung up on these names what
you need to know is what the biochemical
composition of whatever the the Cannabis
is then you'll have an idea what it's
good for um so whether you call it one
species or four species to me is beside
the point at this time anyway my opinion
I've been on every side of this
issue yeah totally great discussion
right but um so understood about the
canono the different species but what
are your thoughts about origin of photo
period specific so photo photo period
specific so you have like your auto
flowers and then you have you know your
your
traditional
cannabis species flowering you're
talking about the daylight flowering
patterns um so I just you know recently
had my first experience with growing
some autof flowers and um it was there
was kind of an aha moment I thought well
perhaps th this expression of cannabis
was more in um areas where they had to
capture a certain growing you know
season and had to you know happen fast
so I thought well maybe this this
genetic you know expressed in the
Northern or or deep southern
hemispheres you know it was just a total
random thought right um as you know as
opposed where you know our traditional
cannabis could be um you know generating
from you know more of the Tropic region
where you would have you know the
seasonality would go on I just it's just
that's what I think the your your
thought is what I think the thought that
people have at least in this in this
text uh he talks about the day night uh
or at least the flowering pattern based
on stresses of number of days of
darkness and days of lightness has
something to do with the latitude in
which cannabis is being evolved so it
has everything to do with that it just I
think that makes the most sense we we
have different uh probably there's other
plants that are more have different
behaviors that are come from the
northern latitudes where there's much
darker periods in Winter that are still
living cannabis is is one I think the
most domesticated plant on planet Earth
it does there no other plant that grows
in so many different places so this is
this is extremely adaptable so it's got
to be a wizard adapt to different CL
different daylight Cycles I mean the
plant still has to do photosynthesis has
to have dark reactions it has to do all
that stuff to to to make it to make it
survive so that's I think you're on to
something but I I have little more to
offer than that but you I think you're
on the right
track um you talked about the the
breeding for he and for um recreational
and medicinal marijuana when did people
start talking about the different
effects of different strains of
marijana is that a 20th century thing
and I'm trying to think that's a good
question never I never um I I know that
U you know the canab stuff was being
sold in uh pharmacies in the 20s and
teens
some of it was herbal some of it was
tinctures uh they had variety of
different effects people would talk
about comparisons between this this
stuff made by grimal was different from
this stuff made by Park
Davis but I don't think people
understood much about we had no
biochemical genetic variation
understanding at least popular science
literature people actually use this
thing called a beam test to distinguish
cannabis varieties and it was a bogus
test but that's this is like it was they
thought this was testing for canab andol
it's it's a big so nobody really knew
chemically okay so but what you're
talking about is uh would be probably
something that wouldn't have been
written down maybe in the more folk
Traditions so uh I I would wonder I
would look more into that
anthropological literature if there
anything this is all like a lot of that
stuff a lot of the stuff that was sold
in the shops you know the exposure of
the United of Americans to growing
cannabis was very modern you know if you
talk about here that's going to be in
the you know post operation whatever
that Mexican operation that Nixon ran
his version of modern Trump wall thing
going on here they did the same thing
and this is what led to domestic
cultivation and uh in the US in a wide
huge explosion so maybe that's when when
people started picking that up here but
whether in there was knowledge of it and
I I mean I know that um you know the
idea of senia people think is a modern
thing actually separate this was again
South Asian cannabis farmers were
separating males from females hundreds
of years ago to produce gancha so that
is a you know they probably had a lot of
awareness of these different varieties
but I don't haven't read much about
it okay I take your point
that proliferation of Campus has been a
populist issue essentially I think
that's particularly important for us now
as we're being essentially sold a bill
of goods of legalization yet it seems
like to me and some others that
prohibition version
2.0 um are there other nuggets from
history that you might be aware of that
we can take fate from and leverage for a
better effect than an extremely reactive
prohibition this this book is crazy let
me tell you uh the relationship of
cannabis to various forms of ISM
throughout history is something worth
seriously noting uh it's really
interesting uh look the so let's talk
like you know let's say prohibition is
really just social control model or
whatever uh cannabis production was all
was all the rage for running Mercantile
systems to have your ships your cordage
and you it was backbreaking it's hard
work to turn stand of cannabis you know
not premodern societies so you really
had to incen
and you had to have people who were
willing to work for cheap and work
hard you
say yeah for sure I mean but you know
this was talking about in history but
yeah these these things certainly we
need to learn our history so we don't
repeat them but there's a lot of
interesting things this guy talks about
some of the ways in which certain forms
of transformation from slave systems to
indentured Serv ude and how cannabis
both use and and forcing people to grow
it so there was a time where we had to
force people to grow it not for you know
for for hemp and then the dismantling of
the American hemp industry after the
Civil War because Kentucky could no
longer sell to certain slave sell its
raw materials to places where slave
labor would take over the rest of the
development process these are it's
really interesting so the idea that you
know
you know you taking money off the backs
of of disempowered people and cannabis
that goes way back in various forms and
I think we can learn a lot from
understanding how that was actually done
by these different Imperial Powers
it's what you
say nothing's changed yeah it's too bad
but I think we know a lot more you know
knowledge I do believe that education
knowledge will you know and and and I
think you know you can't can't uh it's
not we can't call it alien anymore I
mean we can't in good conscience now
there's other then there's different
various ways that we're trying to
alienate cannabis now U you can look at
the I mean I I mean the government is so
recently the National Academy of
Medicine put out this report Big study
January said okay I can conclusively say
the leading scientific group in America
cannabis has effects in chronic pain it
relieves chronic pain no big surprise
this room room but you know the most
AUST scientific bodies said it but just
this morning the director of the
National Institute on drug abuse like
took issue with that so we're back to
the same you know these kind of
ridiculous back and forth you know and I
just think that what I I my view is that
cannabis is a traditional plant and
traditional plants have protections
under all forms of international law now
international law has also got its
problems with a un and who runs who who
gets to call the shots over there but a
lot of smaller countries work hard to
get those traditional plant Protections
in there and that is something that we
need to uh keep saying over and over
this is not an investigational new drug
a modern a modern thing this is a
traditional thing and if that has any
value or any weight um if you go to sty
Falls if there's a plaque there uh says
traditional cultural property of the I
forgot which tribe uh is had that so Bal
tribe yeah so it's the traditional
culture property a law under the
American federal system this is one of
the first places that got the
recognition cannabis is traditional
cultural property I think that's a very
fair way to talk about it so follow up
on that yeah sure give you a littleit um
currently in Washington the only black
letter law we have is uh thir County the
curs correct been to the Supreme Court
been vetted that's the best law we have
and that's based in good samaritanism
right so given that what does it say I
not familiar with that ruling basically
bill was growing to supply both for
himself and for other folks and I think
it involves both a commercial exchange
for expenses as well as the fact that in
a world in which there's no appropriate
product you can be a Good Samaritan and
provide at least this is what my lawyer
tells me and I rely on every day right
um
so it it sounds like there's maybe even
an older case in law to be made U my
question boiling down to do you think
we're in perhaps a more protected status
here in Washington state as many of our
States move on to more prohibitive and
narrow uh scope of access do you think
maybe we enjoy some special I'm looking
for a silver lineon compared to other
states I mean we we are special because
we are Washington tonians and we have
like a governor that's like you know
going to stand up to the the presidents
and sessions with you know cannabis push
back that's that's unique you don't hear
all the governors and all the legal
states doing that uh we have also you
know um we have a bash on
island I mean there's that's there's
something to be said for these for what
we what you create I me I'm no attorney
I don't know what what things can be
argued I I thought law would be a great
thing to go into when I was younger you
know to fight for the rights of people
but you have to really know what they'll
listen to you know and all that but I I
believe that um you know I did write
something up with Katherine Pettis who's
International Association of hospice and
pal of care activist at the
international level uh on this idea of U
the the uh International drug treaties
if you're going International similar
kind of thing if you FR it down are a
form of patent protections you know that
gave ownership of these plants to uh
governments and uh the government's
friendly pharmaceutical companies and
that's wrong and that's if you recognize
that this plant is older than the
company's ever existences then that that
can't stand where you going to argue
that probably in P or something but
maybe you know our courts would
recognize more of those things in other
courts I don't know I mean there are
always you should should talk to a
lawyer but I I would love to there's a a
lot of folks also interested in
indigenous uh indigenous rights in this
country this in this state we've got
very active native uh tribe presence uh
and they like to they follow whichever
federal law or their treaty law or their
state law depending on you know what
they're trying to achieve right and
that's really that's unique here we have
a very interesting system here that is
different from where I grew Oklahoma
that you know the tribes are told on day
one that memo will never apply to you so
forget it that wouldn't happen here we
have a stronger tribal presence so we
got to like figure out something
there a quick little sidebar uh you
talking about Bashon in Washington I was
cced on an email earlier this week from
Dr Dominic Cora who's here and he was
talking to somebody in Humble County and
CC me on it and he was describing Bashan
and he says bash's like like a liberated
Zone he says cannabis and people who
think it's just different you got to go
there
is a very high
compliment we've got time for two more
questions yes so when we think about
cannabis on a genetic level and I know
that what little resarch people talk a
lot about cannabis having these
thousands of genetic structures is
cannabis a potential for gene
therapy uh gene therapy is when you use
a vector uh to introduce new genetic
material usually a virus to to introduce
new genetic material into the subject
usually a human host that has a genetic
disorder uh and you try uh usually
they've used various forms of polio HIV
um some forms of those viruses that are
really good to get into the cells um
cannabis genome U you know as a plant
genome um its genes there are there are
remnants of uh let's see what is it
um well no I I I don't know of any
genetic overlap I was going to tell you
CB1 receptor Gene which is a you know
one of the most widespread receptors in
our brain
um there is a bit of that DNA in the in
the spirro that causes lme
disease actually some of the spyroy that
causes Lyme disease as DNA is in cv1
that's that's there
some ancient overlap of that bacteria
when it was infecting us its DNA got
transferred into the human cv1 this is
some this is in some medical journal I
found in Switzerland and there's some
interesting hypothesis about about the
seasonality of
schizophrenia uh diagnosis and and bl
who you know people like to make all
kind of theories but that there is
something overlap there and I don't know
to it but there was definitely a lot of
there's cross talk in nature between
pathogens and hosts Genetically speaking
uh when we consume cannabis we aren't
getting its DNA into our
system um but is it altering our way
that our body does gene expression
yes so that's that's that's how it's
therapeutic it can be in that way but
for something like if you if you have a
genetic disorder if you were to start
gene therapy with a host could you
multi-generations later that that's gone
is cannabis the potential for
that to start changing the way the
genetic structure of a person responds
to things so we know sometimes genetic
mutations start happening because of
outside sources so could cannabis
reverse those effects and do the
opposite
so exhibit a you have a host who has a
genetic disorder you give it to them it
kind of treats they have a Next
Generation you give the Next Generation
treatment even though they're affected
and then by the third generation you
don't have an affected
potentially we'll talk more in
your last questiona super quick have you
had any personal contact with
Dr no I have not
please I I I would I actually no I take
that back I did meet her I did meet her
in Seattle in 2006 at in Kane Hall she
was there with a talk with Sati Kumar
yes that I remember yes n she seed
saving group in U in India she started
and has argued for the rights of farmers
uh to save seeds you have a lot more to
talk about I hope you meet her again
okay well great well thank you s