so even you know you are a pretty famous
proponent of the entourage effect using
the entirety of the cannabis plant
together because all of the you know THC
the CBD all the what we call minor
cannabinoids the terpenes all these
parts they kind of play together with
our endocannabinoids system or body as a
whole kind of like a lock and key to
kind of open up you know different forms
of healing but in popular press and
where most of the studies that we're
seeing you know they're mostly on you
know THC CBD the acid forms of those you
know CVG and some of the terpenes are
cool right but um I'm curious what you
think we may find with some of the
things that we're not hearing about and
may or may not be researched yet like
like the the flavonoids the esters and
secondary secondary metabolites that are
there and you know what what do you
think that we're gonna find when we
start studying those focus li instead of
you know just turbans generally well
there's a lot of potential for other
parts of the plant from the leaves
there's an agent called canna preen
which has a really interesting
anti-inflammatory profile there's been
virtually no work done on yet another
agent of Flav owned from cannabis is
called ken flavin a again this is a very
powerful anti-inflammatory without the
side effects of the non-steroidal
anti-inflammatories that quite
frequently can produce ulcers even heart
attacks or strokes in contrast ken
flavin he has an anti-inflammatory
profile where these side effects would
not occur so that's something that it's
worth looking into additionally we've
got a totally different set of agents
from cannabis roots which historically
have been used for some of the same
things as the tops including as int
inflammatories and in treatment of
cancer we know that the roots contain
small amounts of tri terpenoids which
have very interesting
facts in these areas and even some
alkaloids which they always look for in
the tops but never found so there's a
lot to be learned yet do we know enough
yet about even how to use these that
that it would justify processing other
parts of the plants other than the
flowers just to get some of these even
though we don't know exactly what
they're doing yet being done a couple of
months ago I was in Chile in Valparaiso
on the coast and there was a man there
selling various kind of cannabis
preparations on the street and one of
them was a salve that he made out of
cannabis roots so there are a lot of
artisanal products that are employing
these other parts of the plants and dog
people are claiming good efficacy we
don't have again controlled clinical
trials but hopefully that will come and
give us the answers it's interesting too
because you know you've said before that
you know people who are processing their
Sun leaves for CBD are gonna be
disappointed because in the in the
exterior Sun leaves where trichomes are
not made they're not gonna find CBD
there and and so I tell people you know
if you want to still use your Sun leaves
that's great but you're essentially
making yourself wheatgrass shots you
know you're gonna you're getting some
with chlorophyll and aminos and good
things like that but this actually is a
whole nother level of justification for
that because while we may not know
exactly what they're doing to us in
those dosages and with a plant that
we've carried around for us for so many
thousands of years chances are it's only
going to be a win well it's not likely
to produce damage a lot of people are
juicing leaves in large amounts because
of the magnesium load from the
chlorophyll they can get intestinal
cramping and diarrhea but beyond that I
wouldn't expect any major harms great
thank you so if you're interested in the
specialty chemicals that you can find in
the cannabis rootball we actually did a
podcast on
a while back so you can find a link for
that in the first comment Thank You
Ethan