things whenever you do presentation
you're always very clear to point out
that there's a lot of active debate a
lot of these topics and I think that's
very fair and you'll often give both
sides and kind of give your opinion on
what you think is gonna end up being
right over time in the science and one
of those hot debates right now is the
bacteria to fungal ratio in soil and oh
my god like the online debates are like
a bloodsport you know it's crazy yeah
and so you know you're a nice
even-handed guy so I would appreciate if
you would give us a general overview of
what the debate looks like so people
have email contacts true and then give
us an idea where you think that it's
gonna end up being played out for Canada
specific right right right well first of
all for those who don't know anything
about fungal bacterial relation your
soil is usually dominated by either
fungus or it is dominated by bacteria
and if it's dominated by fungus then it
it likes the ammonia type back a
fertilizer or microbe where I should say
and if it's if it's got a bacterial
dominance it likes the nitrate type so
there's two kinds of nitrogen also else
have a balance of these by the way if it
has more fungi than bacteria in his
acidic in nature if it has more bacteria
than fungi it is a basic or an alkaline
and if it is bacteria it has matrix in
fixing bacteria that fixed the nitrogen
so there are those differences your
soils have one of the other or dominance
but they BA they have both of them so
there's always some fungi and bacteria
so I'll advise a person unless you at
the very far ends of the spectrum now
when we first started talking about this
dump and the concept really has been
developed by dr. Elaine Ingham who is a
goddess among mortals as far as I'm
concerned and and I never want to put
words in their mouth but dr. leading
them showed us about fungal bacterial
ratio and explained to us
that if you are in a beginning
analogical situation when I call the
beach you know when life is just
beginning as opposed to the old-growth
forest which is the other end of the
spectrum when you're in that beach end
you have bacteria there is nothing
really for the fungi to eat and as
things grow and develop you start to get
detritus and the bunch I move in and as
you move further along that spectrum or
more contact the bacteria number
basically stays the same when you get
all the way over to the old-growth
forest you've got so much stuff with a
bunch of heat that fungi dominate the
soil 50,001 I mean they really they
really go nuts so you've got those two
ends of the spectrum and in order to
know what your plant lights you figure
out where along that spectrum you get
I suspect that debate started this way
that was too difficult for me to figure
out doctor Healing is a lot smarter than
me I promise you and that was just too
difficult for me to figure out so so I
came up with this idea because I was
giving talks to regular gardeners not
intelligent highly intelligent cannabis
growers and so I had to dumb down the
system and I came up with this idea that
if you grow things for less than a year
they like bacteria dominated soil and
basically when you look at the spectrum
the doctor lien has sure that's that's
what happens if you grow things for more
than a year perennials and trees and
shrubs they tend to want finally
dominated soil and and so I've got this
slide fungal dominated it is more than a
year less than a year isn't it is
bacteria dominated what does cannabis
cannabis is less than a year cannabis
actively dominated says Jeff Lauren felt
now dr. Elena again a lot smarter than I
am I think she's done some some research
and she's decided that no really
cannabis has a little bit higher
bacterial I mean a fungal ratio than
bacteria
I'm willing to accept that then doesn't
bother me at all I wouldn't accept
anything dr. Elaine says frankly but she
really what she has done for the world
is phenomenal as far as I'm concerned
but yeah so maybe a little bit more
bacterial now last night when we talked
about all the fun yeah does a new race
car of cannabis oh they are so fast and
I it's hard for me to believe that they
want to back to have fungally dominated
soil will experiment and find it out but
versus the bacteria makes it makes sense
how do you get it bacteria like green
things they like sweet things you know
molasses straw hay you know that kind of
stuff is they grasp with all the green
mulches there's all the green folks
isn't then the bacteria the fungi like
the brown mulches and so you can you can
use those so so bifur folks are not
brown mulches we're talking things like
like wood chips and Dinny and just leave
leaves and yeah yeah yeah leaves I go
out and just pump bunch of leaves off my
yard make sure they're not oak leaves
because those are allopathic to a lot of
plants but yeah and then the more you
grind them up the more bacterially the
bacterial oriented they become so you
can take a follow food and and really
grind it up it becomes a bacterial food
so if you really wanted to do it right
you get a fungal food grind it so it's
bacterial fungal so if if if folks want
to know which side they're dominant on
is this something that you can just get
from a simple soil test no that's one
way you need a soil food with this and
or microscope with your own you can get
a grid and try to figure it all out
or you can bottle something
and how do you find the soil food web
lab you google their wall around the
world that will give you your you're
right yeah cool thanks for taking apart
that debate for us okay right on the
probably cost
[Laughter]
you