I can't believe I went the whole summer
that didn't occur me does get a bigger
pot yeah yeah you never know yeah well
sort of those things you know the reason
I like four of these plasma lights down
in Oregon there's a guy down there who's
testing them out I think the next thing
I'm reading I want one that's that big
that you lose in the tent because there
but but the root systems are twice the
size and so this guy kept insisting that
he was gonna dig it up and I don't know
he was he was pulling off the leaves
that's what he was doing I kept saying
what are you doing you know that's sort
of is it I don't know if you're filming
this or not but that's one of the
tendencies feel a lot of people pick off
the leaves and they pick off the leaves
ostensibly I think to make the bottom
nodes maybe they get a little bit more
light
I'm not quite sure why they do it but I
think that's what it what it must be
because I just tuck them under but I
kept saying you don't understand dig
your root ball is and so we dug it up
and what am i doing
you're right I mean then you pull those
leaves off ain't owned the root system
you screw the plants up yeah it's a nice
most being balanced and worked together
and and you gotta be very careful how
you pitch back in train plans I think
it's really so so where we live here in
the northwest one of our biggest issues
are is mold right right and so a lot of
folks here will pinch leaves like you
said for the for the light to get in but
also so the air can get in so that
there's there's constant fresh air in
the in the middle right is that worth is
that worth the trade-off to pinch leaves
well I don't I don't know I mean I think
if there's a way you can train the plant
by pulling it apart little bear this Oh
a the least disturbance you can do to
the physical part of the plan is the
best are the leaves really banking
nutrients for future use well I think
that yeah I think so they're there
they're certainly those nutrients get
used up the reason why you see those
bottom leaves turning
turn yellows because those blue kids are
being used and you know so you can
publish yellow ones off sure I think
people people just get a little carried
away with it yeah you know it's it's
tempting play with our plants yeah yeah
this look this will make a good addendum
to our series yes all right so the next
question here
we read these cannabis plants again uses
in the hydroponic model puppet food in
pumping food in or pumping food that's
what that's enough we really need to do
that to all plants you know or you know
and but now that we're in the soil model
I'll be taking the hydroponic model into
the soil world or have we'd sort of
altered a little bit so that now we're
using the giant pumpkin model you know
you put as much food in the slow as you
possibly can that may not grow the best
cannabis and ultimately I think that's
what we got to get back to we understand
thinking about what kind of cannabis
were growing it is not necessarily the
best big is not necessarily better you
know we're looking we're looking for
good quality and the specific kind of
quality that we as an individual might
want you're going to love medical my
creations so let's let's take just one
more step so so if on one end it is it
is powerfully interesting to grow an
auto flower in plain bagged potting soil
and not and not give it a bunch of food
so I that's just interesting to watch I
did that last year I did a last year's
my first growth you're growing autos I
did a bunch of different stuff and the
damn thing is they all grew so I'm so
it's amazing samesies all time
oh I I did with three different types of
seeds and and they were all out of
flowers all feminized and they all grew
and it was it was like bulletproof ramen
and the fact that you can you can pop
seeds April first and harvest July one
pop a second round has seeds July first
and be done October one that's two
cycles with no light depth and you know
here in the northwest that's like gold
ready for baby who's Alaska that is
platinum Yeah right so there you go so
so my question though is that let's so
let's say so now now this season and for
you know folks who are you know a couple
years into Auto flowers
we're looking to fine-tune and let's say
okay we're already impressed that
there's we don't have to use nutrients
and we know that we don't want to give
too many nutrients because that will
confuse the plant but what would you
suggest would be a couple amendments
that we might want to use to find that
happy
we're okay yeah we don't have to add a
lot but what might be the targeted few
that will supercharge your plans sure
and the way I've approached this the
second year is is to experiment in two
ways one is to experiment fertilizing
during the vegetative state and I would
use the vegetative you know the typical
vegetative fertilizers we talked about
which was the nitrogen Sosa and then I
would also experiment I would we then
let them going to flower and not
fertilize them and then I would take
some that I would fertilize only in the
flower stage and then the certain third
said of course I fertilize both to see
to see I think that that might makes a
big difference I kind of like the idea
of letting the plant grow you know if it
flowers in the two to three weeks that
it normally should flower you know
you've got a plant that's getting into
the flower stage and and and then
fooling around with the the firts
are in the the flowering stage may
produce the best result so so I'm going
to go a little bit deviant so so
certainly we all have got more
experimentation to do with this with
these autumn flowers and we got to share
it which is why that Otto flower network
is so yeah bought a flower net don't
miss it
Wow and so so where do you think it's
gonna end up though in your experience
with the soil food web and your
experience with checking out Otto
flowers outside of this testing for
people who like you know I'm very
patient focused right so so for a
patient who's using Auto flowers because
they've got low mobility low resources
and low space let's just cut them to the
ending and say this is what we think the
research is gonna go show just use these
few additives what would you tell them
to use uh soybean in molasses really
yeah and mycorrhizae fungi of course
sure I was like that's
but yeah I like so beating molasses in
myself you know if you can find GMO
soybeans kind of tough to do but I'm
sulphur molasses of course not too much
of it that's a bacterial food and the
soybeans a follow them yeah and the mix
of the two together you know the
microbes love it
so when you say soybeans do you mean
like Okara or do you meet what it would
exactly soybean meal slaving meals you
know again I always tell people you know
originally fertilizer was manure and
then I think people forget out Chia he
was just the manure it's kind of hard to
carry around why don't I use this stuff
it makes them anymore and so they bought
the food that goes anything so if you go
to a feed store you can find on Sulphur
molasses because it's a food and you can
find and you can find soybean meal also
food that makes great food great for the
lawns great for cab yeah I've never used
soybean meals so I'm excited to look
into this unbelievable if you can't burn
you know it's only youth when it's eaten
it's great stuff it's unbelievable I use
it on my mom yeah cool thank you very
much that's great
you