so Ethan we've been hearing recently
more and more talk from researchers
recommending and talking about the
healthy benefits of
psilocin uh from hallucinogenic
mushrooms on the healing and rebuilding
of neural networks after things like uh
traumatic brain injury or a severe uh
trauma um and you know most of the the
the crossover media they're just saying
cybin mushrooms isn't that crazy it's
good for you and they kind of you know
handle it at that level of
superficiality um but folks often ask me
what is going on in the brain like at
the cellular level what does the
psilocybin do that helps heal or
regulate or expand the neural network uh
would you break that out as a
neurologist I figure this is this is
right up your alley uh well you know
I've been delving into this area for
decades actually but the fact is in uh
at the end of 2018 we still don't know
exactly oh wow the conventional answer
is uh that
psilocybin and related tryptamine
psychedelic drugs work on the serotonin
2A
receptor however that is not an adequate
explanation
uh for the effects that we see with
these drugs because there are other
drugs that work on the receptor that
don't have any similar kind of activity
particularly the kinds of prolonged
benefits that we're seeing uh now in
controlled uh clinical trials uh
psilocybin has produced um great benefit
in end of life um issues for people with
um terminal illness particularly cancer
um additionally uh it's shown long-term
benefits uh treatment of intractable
depression where even things like
electroconvulsive uh therapy or shock
therapy have been
unsuccessful but that's with full
psychedelic
doses um of these agents uh we have a
phenomenon now that's become quite
popular in our society um of using very
low doses of sub therapeutic doses uh of
psychedelics what's called micro doing
so this would be a dose that doesn't
produce um uh strong alterations in
Consciousness but um has led to people
feeling like they have greater levels of
insight greater levels of
creativity um we don't have a lot of
proof of this but we have have hundreds
of anecdotes uh that support this kind
of thing um there are enough clinical
trials underway now with positive
results that support the idea that in a
not too distant future another schedule
one drug uh psilocybin is going to be an
approved
pharmaceutical um so there's a great
deal to be learned here uh in the 50s
before psychedelics were outlawed uh
there had been a lot of therapeutic
research both with psilocybin and with
LSD um but um in a manner analogous to
what happened uh to cannabis all the
biomedical research stopped in the 60s
when they were outlawed and we've seen
this slowly come around in the same way
that uh there's been a Resurgence in
therapeutic cannabis research uh so
interesting times will follow yeah for
sure and and I understand um from your
paper that um not only do you hold that
um that do using micro dosing can help
uh heal and kind of reconfigure the
brain after traumatic brain injury um
but that using it in uh in concert with
canono can actually be better than
either of them alone how do you normally
uh suggest that cannabinoids would be
paired with psilocybin for maximum
benefit well this is conjectural um we
don't have any studies of the two
together uh one of the phenomena that is
common uh with the psychedelics in high
doses is uh at least a phase of nausea
which is easily counteracted with
cannabis but um in complex psychiatric
conditions I I could see the potential
uh for combinations of say lowd do uh
psilocybin
uh in conjunction with a properly
constituted cannabis based preparation
preferably cannabid per dominant um but
we've got to get one over the finish
line of approval and then see um more in
a controlled setting of what the
combinations might really
accomplish I think it's going to be
interesting too because as you said we
don't actually know what the psilocybin
is doing in the brain we've got pretty
good ideas but the the research has been
quashed but hopefully seems to be coming
back now um but we both know that that
you know self- healers and Psychonauts
are going to be going down this path
Alone um uh before the science catches
up since the science has been held back
by regulation um would you offer any uh
cautions to people who want to uh pursue
this kind of solution on their on their
own um considering you know neither
neither mushrooms or cannabis are
dangerous but you know there you might
have some uh cautions around dosing
perhaps uh absolutely I I'd emphasize
that uh this should be done in the right
environment sa and setting are critical
uh nobody should engage in using a
psychedelic unless they're feeling
reasonably secure or in a safe and calm
environment and
absolutely um in the presence of a
respon responsble person who's not uh
engaged in the same activity in other
words a guide uh anything else is
overtly dangerous the danger of any
psychedelic is that someone is going to
have uh produce a panic experience um
and this can be really really traumatic
so I would never downplay that um but in
terms of direct toxicity no but uh
certainly psycho trauma uh is possible
and the best advice is uh to proceed
with Extreme Caution um it's much better
to use too little than too much um uh if
a person exceeds the threshold of what
they can handle they're going to have a
bad experience it's going to last some
hours and uh it's not going to be
remembered um as a good idea yeah um so
again uh they have to engage in
judicious
dosage uh in a proper setting with very
good uh supervision when you use use the
term micro doing um what are you
actually talking about because you know
people people are usually talk about
dosing in the you know the regular
citizens stre the nonscience environment
by weight right and you know whether or
not you're having getting your cybin
from cubes or cyanin they've got
different potency themselves so you
can't just approach um mushrooms by
weight so if somebody had an idea though
of how much active ingredient was in
their mushrooms how much are you looking
for to be a micro do well a threshold
dose for a psychedelic experience with
with soloc cybin is about 20 mg and this
can vary um so something well under uh
10 Mig is going to represent a micro do
and uh could be much lower than that and
as you mentioned if someone's uh doing
this directly with mushrooms it depends
on their potency there are things
written about the expected potency of
specific species uh they vary a great
deal it could be U 1% or less um psybin
in cubensis it could be as much as 4%
and solos be azer resin um but uh
without knowing what species you have or
anything else um I would always have
people if they're going to go down this
path at all and let's emphasize that um
these agents are still schedule one and
illegal in the United States um but if
they're going to go down that path uh
they should always ear on the side of
too little rather than too much mhm uh
go start low and go slow this is the
same adage that we use in relation to
cannabis doing why not excellent if you
want to hear more about this uh there's
a link in the first comment to the
podcast episode that Dr Roose and I did
together thanks a lot Ethan thank you