hey there friends shango here from
shaping fire and i'm with my good buddy
tyler marquart who's here as well
um we are here to talk about uh tyler's
bookner funnel technique and some of you
may have already seen the video that we
did i don't know almost two years ago
now
when he was here when he had just
figured out this technique and um you
know he tyler helps me with hash all the
time and so um he came up uh
to do that with me and then he brought
this get up with him and i'm all like oh
my god i am i'm always gonna use this
when i make hash from here on out and so
um so we posted that video on youtube
and i told some people about it on
instagram and the response was like
pretty significant um people were pretty
stoked to have an option um that dries
out their hash very quickly um without
the high budget tool of a freeze dryer
and like i mean i think we all want a
freeze dryer right freeze dryers are
great and and totally are useful um but
like you know a lot of us are balling on
a budget and this definitely falls in
that category so
um so i was talking with tyler and since
he was going to be up here on vashon
island this weekend helping me out i
said hey man let's go ahead and do an
update video because the first one we
did we didn't actually realize was gonna
be such like a big hit and um we did
kind of a pretty quick abbreviated
version and i'm all like well you might
we might as well do a longer version
with all of the best practices that he
has developed um you know in the last 18
months or whatever and so so here we are
with this so tyler thanks for joining me
thank you for having me all right so so
let's start with the the purpose what is
the purpose of the device so this device
will help uh
hashmakers at home dry their hash faster
so there's a reduction in any sort of
contamination through mold issues from
having too much water in your material
it's gonna allow
water to come out really quickly
and uh by doing that um you're giving
yourself a much better chance to have a
higher end quality product around so
let's let's go through the equipment
first because i'm sure there's a lot of
folks out there like me who who were not
familiar with the buckner funnel at
first so so why don't you start at the
top and work our way through to the
vacuum pump absolutely so at the top
here we're going to have
the this hairband just uh i belong here
so this works out well for me you could
use a variety of different things a
rubber band but this is just what i have
on hand
and that is going to secure the piece of
aluminium foil
which has a very small hole in it here
you can use the tip of a pen to poke
that through
this is going to create a suction device
other people on the internet who have
been using this have shown me that
they've used tupperware
tops or some sort of plastic top and
they've been burping it a little bit
there's a variety of different things
that you can use i just had this readily
available so that's what i ended up
using and it works really well
if you don't make the hole big enough it
will
pop this off into the air um and you'll
be very surprised at that when that
happens um then we have the actual uh
top piece here which is connected to um
the vacuum pump
this has a glass frit disc in it and it
has a tube on the inside
which allows a vacuum to be pulled
through the flask and so
you could use a variety of different
sizes
this is a 500 mil top and a 2000
milliliter
flask um you can
this is more
stable right very giving you the
stability i at my place i use a 1 000
milliliter flask and a 1 000 milliliter
or i'm sorry a 500 milliliter flask in a
1000 milliliter um funnel and that
allows me to put larger amounts in and
still pull a tight vacuum
then going from the tube here
into the vacuum pump
is pretty much all the parts so you have
one two three four five six parts in
total to the to the equipment right on
so a couple things i want to point out
um this uh this frit disc which is
essentially um
a filter uh it's built in so you don't
buy these separately this is one piece
which i didn't realize at first when i
was first starting to shop for it um
there you go um and
so so ty just to give people a general
idea um you know the the pumps kind of
like it's separate things so this piece
and this piece which is where um
i actually don't know if it's mostly
expense
what is what's what should people
somebody pay expect to pay for that on
like amazon or something for sure so you
can get in a variety of different sizes
but this is going to be less than 75
dollars for the two of them depending on
the type of glass the quality of glass
like everything has quality ranges right
and so depending on where you get it
from and all that it's gonna be less
than a hundred dollars wow yeah much
less than a
freeze dryer yeah absolutely all right
so so now we know we're we're using it
to take water out of the hash material
very quickly
and um and it's it's an affordable
option so so will you walk us through
the using of it yep absolutely so what
we'll do is we'll take the hash out of
the bag
when we're pulling um the the 45 bag or
the 73 or the 90 whatever you decide to
use take that material out put it onto a
screen um we we've been using these five
inch by five inch screens um that were
provided by the press club for us to use
here and that then goes on into the
funnel area and you place it down lay it
flat
i find that often
slicing the patty a little bit will help
with air getting through
and allowing it to dry a little bit
faster you don't have to do that
once that's on there you're going to
want to take the aluminum foil here
put it on the top
secure it with whatever device that you
have again you don't have to use
aluminum foil you can use a plastic lid
they probably actually make if you're
into chemistry and you work in a
chemistry lab there probably is a device
that they actually legitimately make for
this i just haven't looked for it yet
because
this works really well this is just in
my kitchen and just
one less thing to purchase on and over
um
and yeah so then you hook up the the
tubing here make sure the tubing is
attached um this has um
uh
i can't remember the name of it now but
it it it'll
attach itself without coming off it
won't the vacuum won't pull the tube off
so you don't have to secure that
to that at all
and then on this side i did secure it
with a um
a amount and so that's mounted to that
um when you purchase these pumps
something to note is that they usually
need to be filled with oil um so you
will have to buy some vacuum pump oil
you can purchase that at your local like
auto store um i think i went to like
o'reilly's or something like that and
like just they had a bottle there
but vacuum pump oil uh it needs to be
specific vacuum pump oil and uh and then
they have a max minimum line usually on
the outside and there also is like a um
a glass chamber you can see how much oil
you have in there so that helps you set
that up
once it's all hooked up uh
and everything's attached like we have
here and the hash is in there just turn
the pump on
i let it run in between the runs so uh
when i make hash i usually do a three
minute run uh depending on the quality
of the hash and and all the
standards that go around it
three minutes
allows it to pull most of the water out
it's still going to be wet it's not 100
dry um it's not like a miracle like but
you can see individual granule you know
yeah it turns it from like what is
essentially wet mud
to being
just barely damp sand correct and like
that's such i mean that saves two days
at least of oxidation
doing it with like dehumidifiers and
fans absolutely absolutely and so yeah
so once you're at that stage it just
starts pulling through
you can see in this that we've pulled
from today we've pulled out a fair
amount of water um just from what we've
we've run here um
yeah
right on so let's talk about the vacuum
pump um i know when we did our last
video um we were using um aquarium pumps
right yeah so would you compare like the
experience of using an aquarium pump
versus using this badass [ __ ] yeah yeah
absolutely this uh really moves air
faster
also having a smaller
base and a smaller top will help pull
the vacuum harder faster too um but
mostly this is a fork cfm cubic feet per
minute pump and uh the other ones we
were using were like .2 or 0.5 so um
this really just made a huge difference
and these are like less than 100 i think
this one was like 79 or it came out to
be like nine so really this is like 200
bucks all in 200
you know maybe this is a couple uh you
go to home depot and or your local
hardware store and you can find the
tubing there for you know a couple bucks
a foot or a couple uh with inflation who
knows what it is
it's not expensive for less than 200 or
250 bucks you're pretty much set and
ready to go right on and um you know if
if you want to take a look at these
parts um i'm gonna post links below uh
to these and then you know you know if
you want to get something else by all
means but you can actually see what what
we're rocking here um in the links below
so um so now tyler like like
i've been watching you all day as we've
been doing
you know these these rounds
you're you've got the hash and it's on
the mesh screen
and then you turn on it and it like
pulls down the water which is like
obvious and amazing and then you take it
off what do you do when you take it off
of um the bookner funnel yep so when we
take it out we're gonna put it on the
table we take a knife and just kind of
chop it up a little bit more break it up
so that it gets more surface area and
then you have a lot of different options
you can go from there um i've been using
a wine fridge
wine fridges are about can be set uh the
digital ones you can set to about 45
degrees so it's a good temperature to
keep the that down they also sometimes
keep the humidity low in the 50 to 60
percent range which is good
so that'll help it dry a little faster
we've also found that putting dry ice
into that or putting dry ice into a
cooler with a cookie
drying sheet or sorry the the cookie
aluminum um
like a wire rack
the wire racks uh the the cookie drying
wire racks those uh you put those down
and you uh then put the uh um
the 25 micron or 15 micron whatever size
you decide to use sheet on that with a
hash on it and then the dry ice will act
as a desiccant and pull the rest of the
water out
you can use a cooler like if you have a
cooler to go to the beach with or take a
picnic
and then put that in there with the dry
ice and that will help pull the rest of
it out
but essentially in less than 36 hours or
24 hours depending on how much material
you have obviously the more
hash you're making the
more space you need to dry and and so
forth um but once you have that figured
out within 24 to 36 hours you're pretty
much ready to go
so so you say 24 to 36 hours break that
out into how much time it's at each
place so of that time is it like
you know 24 to 36 hours but only the
first like 10 minutes is in this like
like
like um give me the location of the hash
for those 24 hours yeah it's a it's also
a nuanced thing i think to start with is
what is your relative to humidity um i
live in california near the beach so uh
we are in an area where in the mornings
it's 90 humidity easy pretty much almost
every day
it drops in the afternoon and then back
up in the evening and so you have to be
conscious of what your relative humidity
is um unless you're using a dehumidifier
in the room or the tent that you're
you're washing and stuff or you're
processing all this in um so that is
kind of your biggest mitigating factor
but um
when you pull the hash out of the bag
you put it in here i'm running it for
about three to six minutes depending on
how long i make my runs so if i'm making
a three minute run on the uh on the
machine
this will the run before that will will
be drying in here uh once uh the machine
stops and i'm draining while it's
draining i go i'll pull this out move it
set this up so that i can move the next
one in and then kind of cycle through
like that if i find that the material
isn't like the best material and i can
wash it at six minutes it dries a little
bit faster
it does seem like there's a bell curve
where like if you do have high humidity
it'll dry it out but then all of a
sudden it starts getting a little bit
more moisture back into it um but again
it's it always i think associated with
the relative humidity the in in the
immediate area that you're working in uh
once it's it's in there um three to six
minutes usually it's pretty good 10
minutes we'll get it really really
really pretty dry like we saw you're
like cutting it almost in the sand yeah
and um and then after that it's just
move it into the the dry chambers and
break it up put it in the dry chamber
and then i was taking a sieve and
putting it in there
sieving it up and then that opens up the
airflow even more i love more surface
area and and it dries it even faster
within a couple hours after that it's
pretty good to go right on
so um as we all know this has been an
evolving technique right like you're
doing it more sophisticated than we did
whatever there was 18 months ago when we
recorded the first video
um are there any uh problem points that
you are experiencing now that you are
trying to sort out at this point like
because like you know um all of us in
cannabis we trade best practices right
so so are there any solutions that
you're looking for that um that other
people could be thinking about yeah so
there's a couple things uh one uh
somebody online mentioned putting in a
vapor trap here um so that either oil
doesn't go back in or you can collect
terpenes and stuff that comes out um
that's pretty good idea you know and we
obviously don't want oil pumping back
into the the situation i haven't seen
any uh
traces of that or anything because it
would also have to go all the way back
up past the front disc past the other
micron filter so there's some other
stuff that i have to go through um let's
hit on that a second time because
as you know youtube jerk boys you know
they like leave all these stupid
comments and um
there have been like a couple people who
have left like like eye-rolling comments
about how
using this technique is gonna make your
hash taste like oil right
and like ugh
but um would you explain just like for
the back of the room why
the oil from the pump is not going to
end up in your hash yeah the the amount
of pressure coming through is so much
it's just
i mean this is what i've been using for
the last two months and there's no oil
in here at all and you can see it hasn't
been collecting any oil so um you know
having it as a preventative measure sure
would be great um it's an added cost
that maybe you know somebody can't
afford if it's a 50 unit or 100 unit
i don't think it's needed personally um
i haven't had any
uh any of the hash tastes like it's
flavored off or anything like that um
and i looked under a microscope i
haven't seen anything awkward or any
sheens or anything like that so for that
nature i i don't think that it's
particularly needed but you know for
somebody who maybe wants to
be extra careful sure or if you want to
experiment have the money and you find
out that it does make a difference and
you can do an a b run and have it tested
for petrochemicals then
that that's awesome you know we
definitely encourage people to take this
and and expand it even more and if you
have those capabilities to do sort of
that r d um let us know what what turns
out so that we can let other people know
last time we posted the video there were
like a whole bunch of comments from
people saying like you know dude you
need to monetize this why are you giving
this [ __ ] away from free some some some
chad's gonna like like bring this into
the market and make all your money and
just to kind of like pre-answer the
people who are going to comment below
the video what is your answer to this
yeah i mean i didn't really invent
anything i literally just took things
that existed and was like whoa and i'm
sure other people have already done this
i mean other people have mentioned that
they're like oh yeah i did that a few
years ago or something so it's not like
something that uh like i'm like i'm the
inventor of this put my name on it like
that's impo it's i literally just was
working i've been working in a lab and i
saw this equipment and it just
hit and i was like i was thinking about
buying a freeze dryer one day and i was
like i really don't want to spend 3 500
bucks to 5 000
on a freeze dryer like there's got to be
something other other way around it and
it just kind of clicked
and you know being a patient and having
access to high quality medicine is
always like uh important to me uh i
thought why not just get this
information out i'm not manufacturing
something that's unique like somebody
else manufactures this somebody else
might i would basically be a middleman
for like you know selling lab equipment
to somebody where you could just go buy
it off of amazon i'm not going to mark
it up 20 because i'm the guy who
invented it right right right brought it
up or something like that
and also you know one of the reasons why
tyler and i became friends early on is
we both really believe in the
self-sufficiency of patients
and um not everybody has got uh you know
the budget for a freeze dryer or a sexy
lab or all these things we're just
trying to like you know do some home
grow and process it into hash
that so that we have easy access to
medicine and we can um you know make
using licensed stores an option for us
instead of making us have to use them
right and that kind of independence i
think is really important for people who
rely on their cannabis medicine so yeah
all right so to wrap this up
um um you know this is a continually
continuing to evolve technology
so if you have ideas uh that might
improve on this by all means leave them
in the comments and then um tyler you
often talk about this technique on your
instagram and um as you come up with
like um new best practices you share
them so where can people follow you on
instagram if they want to find out more
and kind of just follow along with your
trip yep my instagram handle is just my
name tyler marquardt and uh i pushed it
on there also i'm linked in too um so if
you're on there you can find uh some
information on there as well which
basically shoots you back to my ig yeah
shoots you over to shaping fire um but
yeah those are pretty much the two spots
that i'm not on facebook so right on all
right cool well thank you for interest
in the bookner funnel technique and
thank you tyler for sharing it with
everybody appreciate it all right thanks
all right so now we're going to take the
hash which is on the screen that we've
cut out uh and we're going to place it
inside of the buckner funnel
[Music]
and make sure it sits in there then
we're going to take
our aluminium foil with a tiny little
hole in the top
we're going to place it on top
we're going to take a hair tie you can
use something else this is what i use
because i have it readily available for
my long hair
put it on
make sure it's secure
and then we're going to turn on the
vacuum pump
now you can see the water is coming out
of the buckner funnel into the bucket
flask
and it is pulling out water really
quickly
so in roughly three to six minutes it'll
be
substantially more dry than it was
before
you