hey this is Shango from shaping fire a
couple weeks ago I sat down with Kevin
Joe jury and asked him a whole bunch of
questions that I really wanted to know
his opinion on but nobody else seemed to
be asking him so this is first in a
series that you're gonna get you know
over the next couple weeks and they
cover the topics couldn't you know cover
everything from growing specifically for
pre-rolls to choosing the quality of
terpenes to use in manufacturing your
cannabis products all the way through to
like you know snitching you know what's
going on with snitching in California
and even even his mom on his Facebook
page and what's up with that so anyway
it's gonna be a good series this is
number one here we go so Kevin you know
when you were up speaking on Vashon
Island you said this great thing in your
lecture and I wanted to give you a
chance to break it out a little bit you
said that there are is a particular way
to grow for pre-rolls
right and you know pre-rolls have taken
off but but you were very clear that
there are there are types of strains
that what you want to use for pre-rolls
and definitely ones that you do not so I
want to give you an opportunity to break
that out about how to choose your
strains if they're gonna end up in
pre-rolls pre-rolls
are a unique type of cannabis delivery
system because you've taken the flowers
and you ground them and so you've
oxidized them you've exposed them to
oxygen which starts to break them down
and because they're typically consumed
in that smokeable form you end up having
a long cylinder of smoking material and
so cannabis that has a high monoterpene
very loosely molecularly bonded scent
molecules they're outstanding for flower
sales and for oil sales because the nose
can pick it up but you should look they
don't pick up those smells through the
Rowland paper and they're also very
temperature sensitive and and the
process of handling grinding exposing
the air diminishes right and so for
pre-rolls what you really want to seek
as a sesquiterpene dominant strain
and one can even take a look down with
all the trip reports and find out which
varietals have these high sesqui
terpenes and when you're doing
sifting say through a line so say we're
sifting through a Lemon Haze line we
would go through the lemon haze line and
we would look to see which one's of
these phenotypes that were selecting our
cultivars we're trying to select have a
higher sesquiterpene signature because
what that does is it has a much higher
heat resistance in its resiliency to
stay active and so as you start to
consume the pre-roll the flavor in the
front of the joint when you smoke it
should be very close to the same at the
back of the joint and with a lot of the
pre-roll of products is we get a hit
that tastes okay and then it's just
smoking and the problem is that it gives
pre-rolls a bad name and for people who
like to smoke joints they are typically
rolling a flower fresh meaning they're
breaking it up themselves they're
preparing it so they get everything in
this beautiful package and when they buy
something pre-prepared
its diminished and for me it's a lot
simpler to just find the right varietals
that have a higher sesquiterpene and a
good example would be the met the old
Mendel perps the Urkel the Barney all
those perps that was so resilient and
they were so popular because blunts at
that time was such a in vogue form of
smoking and you have this large cylinder
of cannabis that you're burning so
there's really a lot of heat the men
doper the herbal had an ability to hold
the flavor all the way to the bitter end
and so it allowed people to enjoy the
experience the entire time and when we
started to really look at pre rolls and
that's how the market accepts that I
realized that that's where we had to
focus and so if you're going to go do
pre rolls and you're trying to get into
that distribution you might find that
the varieties you sold as flower aren't
necessarily best for pre-roll and you
have to kind of Reese if your population
and then you
Turpin Alice's to give you an idea which
ones really have a much higher level
assessment syrup beans heavily more
bonded it's it's clear that you know in
the early days especially medical people
would use their their B and C stuff and
put those in the pre rolls because you
know they were gonna be chewed up and no
one would see them but now with so many
more people involved the the pre roll
game has gotten a lot better and it
makes a lot more sense to put you know
maybe not your super bag appeal a but at
least you're a - stuff that's got sesqui
terpenes in it so people can even taste
it you know tasting it down to the roach
is a rare thing well well it also opens
up another market of things that aren't
necessarily visually attractive and so
flower market has to be beautiful
because people see it but once you grind
it and turn it into a product no one has
any idea what it is and so therefore it
allows you to pick different varietals
that really would shine in a pre-roll
environment where you get a lot of
quantity the flower it has a high
sesquiterpene component it's not bag
appeal a plus but who cares so it allows
you to have some choices to work with on
your farm so you have more of a
distribution and I think that what
really happened too is the consumer got
educated and so back in the day you got
whatever you could turn that off
[Music]
it has the right idea though because it
got hot in here fast as soon as it
closed the doors the regulatory gauntlet
for a while so we get back to the topic
the customer became educated and so back
in the day you received cannabis it was
from wherever it was from then you
received cannabis from your street
dealer and it was what they could grab
and then you got into the rise of
dispensaries where you had an incredible
amount of cannabis being grown
everywhere constantly being brought into
these storefronts that allowed
tremendous numbers of people to buy
cannabis on a normal consistent level
but they could examine and an educated
them so you can't dump your low-end
cannabis into pre-rolls anymore just as
you can't dump any low in cannabis into
concentrates because people have an
expectation of flavor profile so it
doesn't work to dump quality products
that should be in a bag into a pre-roll
and it doesn't make sense to take stuff
that should be in a pre-roll into a bag
and so once you see that it allows you
to differentiate what you're working
with on the farm and things that don't
require the visual Beauty are a lot less
labor-intensive and so it gives you some
options in terms of profitability I
think well cool thanks for breaking that
out know where it's right up