welcome take a look thank you all for
having me here I but I hadn't been to
one of your meetings before so I wasn't
sure how formal it was and now that I
see how warm and Kathleen everyone's
gonna have a seat instead of standing up
and try and pontificating and um and now
I also regret not wearing shorts so I
plan for today is to just go through a a
topical understanding of how cannabis
relates to Parkinson's and to tell you a
little bit about how people here on
Vashon are already getting relief from
symptoms using very specific types of
cannabis so I want to be clear at the
outset that I am NOT a doctor I do not
have formal medical training however I
have been working with patients across
the board including Parkinson's patients
for the last five years on my podcast
called shaping fire I interview the top
doctors in the world on a range of
health issues including Parkinson's and
and I have been working one-on-one with
patients for several years now so that I
get to see and experience their
individual experiences because as we all
know Parkinson's manifests differently
for different folks so with that said if
you feel inspired by anything that
sure with you today please be sure to
not drastically change your medicine or
do anything drastic like that without
checking in with your primary doctor
don't don't make any big change just
based on what I'm saying here today the
information I'm hoping to share with you
today is to supplement the research that
you're probably already doing on your
own so that so that you have access to
nice clean information about Parkinson's
because as we all know if you look up
any information on the Internet your
your mileage may vary on its quality so
in addition to being an educator of
patients and doctors how to use cannabis
or also known as marijuana in the clinic
I also have a weekly podcast and I'm
also the founder of the Vashon Island
marijuana enthusiasts Alliance and
originally when we started the
organization the organization was going
to be a training organization for all of
the medical marijuana companies that had
started on Vashon and there were over a
hundred of them small cottage businesses
that were supplying cannabis and edibles
and oils and various products to the
Medical dispensaries across the state
but unfortunately Washington has changed
gears and dismantled the medical
marijuana program in the state and
because of that the companies that the
cottage industries that have started on
the island were no longer legal and most
of them didn't have the
it took to become a licensed company in
the state which you know most people put
between 250 and 500 thousand dollars and
so with that the organization of the
island transitioned to be primarily
patient outreach and education and we
get together about every six weeks at
the Grange Hall and we have a guest
speaker come in really world-class
speakers and then they'll come in and
teach about either cannabis medicine or
about the botany of the cannabis plant
so that's what's happening here on
Vashon and and who I am so before I get
into the specifics of both the
precursors to Parkinson's and how
cannabis can help a lot jump to the end
first so that you kind of know where
we're going what we're seeing on mash on
is very significant reduction in the
symptoms of Parkinson's patients and as
you know the most obvious health is in
symptoms that are involved with motor
skills so so tremors and and stooping
and muscle clenching you know all
different muscle sets and and people
started Parkinson's patients started
coming to the meetings at the Grange
Hall and asking questions and then one
way or another they were getting their
hands on the appropriate cannabis
medicine which I'll talk about a little
more later and the results have been
astounding much to my surprise none of
the Parkinson's patients I work with on
the island are actually here but maybe
it's because they're already familiar
with what I'm going to say today but let
me tell you about one particular patient
which I think really really
stands out so I was working with this
fella he's in his early 60s and his
Parkinson's had progressed to motor
skills issues and and he had he had
tremors in his right arm
he had muscle muscle clenching that was
causing his hand to stay closed most of
the time and the two that he really
hated he had muscle clenching in his
back which was causing him to stoop and
then caused him to shovel and he really
disliked the shuffling because he felt
that that telegraphed to other people
that he wasn't feeling 100% and and that
changed the nature of the conversation
people wanted to have with him they want
to talk to him about just stuff they
wanted to talk to him about his stooping
and that annoyed him and so his wife
came to one of the meetings and she got
some more information and then she was
able to get a t-shirt for him and took
it home and and you know sometimes I
hear back from patients and sometimes I
don't but I heard from her not three
days later and she came by my house and
she she started with giving me a big hug
and I'm like all right at least I know
this is a good meeting
and after giving me a big hug she said
I've got to tell you what happened this
morning and she said you know my husband
has just been getting worse and worse
over the last few years and you know and
with all the things that I don't already
told you about and she said this morning
while I was preparing breakfast she said
I heard the lawnmower at first time in
years and she stopped what she was doing
and she went outside and her husband was
mowing the lawn with a big smile on his
face and she went over and hugged him he
turned off the mower for a moment they
talked and and he said it was the first
time in years that he was able to stand
up straight and felt loose that his his
his tremors had entirely disappeared at
least for that moment and he was not
shuffling and he was able to actually
exert force through his human without
losing balance and was able to mow the
lawn and so even though they have a
conservative sized passive lon it was
obviously a big breakthrough for him and
and now we're almost a year and a half
after that day and except on the rare
occasion when he forgets to take his
canvas medication he is merely without
any visual symptoms that you can maybe
point him and say oh he must have
Parkinson's um except for sometimes at
the end of the day when he's tired I'll
be there at their house visiting and
he'll have a slight tremor in his hand
just from being maybe you know exhausted
from the day but for them it's been a
wild success and on Vashon I would say
that is a fair general as
of what of people's success the the the
two things that I have found that most
impede people from having a positive
experience with cannabis and their
Parkinson's is number one just like with
pharmaceuticals each person is built a
little differently and it takes a little
bit of time at the beginning of taking
cannabis to find the right dosage and
combination so there's a little
experimentation at the beginning and
some folks don't have the temperament or
just patience for that they want they
want it all right now and they don't
want to have to experiment and and gosh
when I rep you miss journaling sometimes
people just rip out right eternally at
all but so some people they get
frustrated at the very beginning say
just like a week to you know dial in the
appropriate dosage and then second of
you know as as as we all know there's
still a lot of peer pressure against
cannabis from people who know it more as
a as a taboo drug from the early years
before we realized that that actually
it's an ancient herbal medicine that's
been used for by humans for over thirty
thousand years and it's only been in the
last 50 years that we haven't been using
it and that is the extraordinary anodd
part of our experience with it we
actually have a lot more of a history of
using it everyday for a wide range of
health issues instead of seeing
as as a negative thing in our culture so
those are the two main reasons trying to
dial in the dosage and also just you
know people succumbing to peer pressure
from people around them to not use it or
occasionally people just they just don't
feel good about it themselves because of
what I've been taught you know to each
their own but I am here to offer you
some information in case your mind is
open to using cannabis medicine how you
might want to think about that and how
you could approach it for your best
results so about 25 years ago we
discovered a new system in our bodies
that up to then had not been discovered
called the endocannabinoid system and
the endocannabinoid system is
fascinating because it produces
cannabinoids very similar to the ones
that are in marijuana in cannabis
correct when our bodies produce them
they are called endogenous cannabinoids
meaning produced inside of the body and
when they're produced by the plant
they're called
phyto cannabinoids because they're made
by biosynthesis and I in a plant but
they're incredibly Simula similar to
each other
well our endocannabinoid system which up
to 25 years ago we were totally
unfamiliar with we now understand it to
be the master regulator for some two
dozen of our body's systems and it's
amazing that something that we believe a
master regulator was was unheard of for
so long the it regulates including
in the two dozen systems are your
likelihood for fight or flight your you
know your response to things that might
scare you or end you need to respond to
appetite and digestion your GI tract
sexual arousal the mix of chemicals in
your brain which also makes sense that
then it would also moderate anxiety and
depression your brain protection
maintenance systems that we'll be
talking about a lot today
and finally signaling issues for example
your toe reporting to your brain that
you stubbed it now you know when when
your endocannabinoids system gets
weakened there is now a scientifically
determined name for this called
endocannabinoid deficiency and what this
means is that you've got your
endocannabinoid system but your body is
not producing enough cannabinoids in
order to stay robust and run all of
these different vital body's systems and
you know what makes your endocannabinoid
system meat is pretty much definition of
living in the United States things that
can weaken your endocannabinoid system
include stress questionable nutrition
using pharmaceuticals not getting enough
exercise and and long term anxiety or
depression so the idea is the more the
more that your body gets taxed the more
likely it is that your body is not
producing enough
the noise inside itself to take care of
all these systems also but not part of
the conversation today but also
associated with cannabinoid deficiency
our is fibromyalgia irritable bowel
syndrome and increased migraines so
cannabis by itself is a neuro protectant
and you know for years it was says that
said that you know cannabis makes you
dumb and people who pots to focus smoke
pot are are dumb and they get more more
dumb as they smoke more and even though
we may all have you know some life
experiences that may support that
evidence because we all know someone
who's lazy and also smokes marijuana
there's also a lot of brilliant people
who are very active and productive that
smoke cannabis and the way that cannabis
is a neuro protected is because of two
two two two things number one it causes
neurogenesis when you have enough
cannabinoids in your system your brain
actually produces more brain cells when
I was a kid I was told that once you
killed a brain cell that wasn't you
didn't get a chance to replace them but
modern science is showing us that that's
actually not the case we had just never
done the studies on cannabis which is
one of the few things that caused the
creation of new brain cells additionally
of cannabis working with the
endocannabinoid system helps moderate
which what is essentially the brain's
self-cleaning and ability to take out
the trash and so what happens and this
is one of the things that gets a lot of
interest from
Alzheimer's patients is that when your
brains doesn't take out the trash
regularly plaque starts to make a
buildup on the end of the neural endings
in the neural pathway and impedes
communication between different neurons
in the brain and this is eventually what
leads to Alzheimers well when you're
using cannabis of the correct way it
kick-starts your endocannabinoid system
and then and no cannabinoid system
starts cleaning your brain and warehouse
hi MERS patients I get all this rough
response up I'm feeling brighter I'm
feeling lighter I'm remembering more
things and and similarly we'll talk
about more of this in a moment but with
Parkinson's patients you're getting a
lot of the same benefit because
Parkinson's disease is associated with
compromised motor function after about
60 to 80 percent of the
dopamine-producing neurons are damaged
and so without the dopamine that's
produced by these particular neurons
this leads to the physical attributes
that come without that we're familiar
with with Parkinson's so what we want to
do is we want to protect those
dopamine-producing neurons as much as we
can and the fact that the
endocannabinoid system is causing our
brain to clean itself it can start to
clean and repair many of these dopamine
creating cells alright so so the last
thing I want to talk about on this
aspect is that you know I've talked a
little bit about the classic motor
symptoms so far which is usually how you
can identify someone third persons that
they may have Parkinson's but the some
of the other symptoms that are
associated with Parkinson's which might
not be as visual also can be remedied
with low doses of cannabis as well
including decreased facial expressions
dementia fatigue sleep disturbances
depression constipation cognitive
changes fear anxiety and urinary
problems and what's interesting is if
you look at this list these are all
mechanisms within the body that are
moderated by the endocannabinoid system
and so so cannabis can help you on two
levels on the first level it can be a
preventative and it can also help
decrease the symptoms that a patient is
experiencing but also it can decrease
the symptoms by strengthening the
endocannabinoid system so even if you
still have Parkinson's you won't have a
degradation of your life quality so
everything I've told you so far is
strongly supported with scientific
evidence of studies that are taking
place in Europe right now because
cannabis is still a Schedule one drug in
the United States those studies are not
happening here there is a new group of
studies that are underway which are
showing a lot of hope and since you know
you all have probably you know
researched Parkinson's much more than I
have it by familiar with people starting
to tie Parkinson's
systems to what's going on in the gut in
the microbiome of your stomach and so
this new this new science of suggesting
that when you're when your gut flora is
overly acidic and your endocannabinoid
system is deficient poor signals are
sent between the gut and the brain which
can make Parkinson's even worse and so
one of the great things about using
cannabis is that your endocannabinoid
system moderates your gut the mix of
chemicals the cleaning the cleaning of
the cilia that moves your food along and
your ability to take extract nutrition
from the food and so while this is newer
science and the other aspects I've
talked about so far I wanted to mention
it because if you've been doing some
work trying to you know eat more raw
foods you know if you get rid of your
GERD or heartburn or just you know work
with the the chemistry of your gut
cannabis is a good option for you as
well because the endocannabinoid system
moderates the tummy so so at this point
what we're looking at is is the systems
that moderate the symptom the symptoms
that you're experiencing are are all
moderated by your endocannabinoid system
and so if we're if we're if most
Americans are deficient in their
internal cannabinoid
making what can we do to help and and
that is with supplementation by by
taking the final cannabinoids that are
produced within the cannabis plant and
then taking them ourselves to make up
for the fact that we're not producing as
many cannabinoids ourselves so let's
talk about typical methods of dosing so
one of the things that I get a lot of
pushback from patients upon it on
especially when they're just learning
about cannabis is that they don't want
to get high and they don't want to be
smoking weed and I and I get that right
we all spend a lot of our lives cracking
jokes about stoners and about what that
does to your life and and you know those
folks get judged a lot and none of us
like to get judged
well except for a very small group of
people who actually prefer the smoking
or the enjoyment factor of it and they
like to get high while they're getting
their medicine I don't recommend smoking
cannabis for nearly any of the symptoms
that we're looking for a relief from I
recommend that you take it orally
because when you smoke marijuana you are
inhaling it it's going into your lungs
and the cannabinoids immediately jump
from the lungs to your blood and then
goes to your brain and so you're getting
all of the medicine fast at once and the
tea
see part of the cannabis is what makes
you high and so all of that reaches your
brain at the same time and at that point
you're feeling some level of
disorientation and soon after we'll
probably want to eat everything
different and so the process is
different when you eat something though
because it goes into your body and if
you're taking a teacher some of it will
be will soak in through your mouth but
if you're eating an edible it's got to
go all the way through your GI tract and
gets filtered by your liver and then
finds its way to your blood there so any
way that you take it orally is you're
likely going to get better experience
then if your were to smoke it now I'm
not saying that smoking doesn't work
smoking can work but it's just not for
everybody and so we're going to focus on
the solution that seems to be more for
more patients so so if you're going to
take it orally then lick what are your
options well we all know the classic pot
brownie right and and a lot of people
find very good results with taking a
regular diet of brownies now I don't
usually recommend that to patients that
I work with because number one you know
they're a little better if you buy them
at the store but but if you tend to make
your own brownies at home brownie one
and six and twelve are all going to have
different strengths because it's really
hard to homogenize the medicine
throughout the baked goods and while
they're much better at this you know we
have the commercial element stories it's
still not perfect but it's certainly
much better than you know grandma mary's
brownies who used to make them in San
Francisco also you know most of the
patients that I talk to are trying to
avoid extra calories let alone
taken as often as they would need to
take something to help with their
Parkinson's so they're all like you know
I mean three brownies a day seven days a
week you know I'm going to have to start
a whole new exercise regime Justin just
to help mitigate the weight gain from
trying to deal with my Parkinson's so so
you know cookies and brownies and
candies are not always the best solution
for some people they find that they
really like lozenges because you know
there's not as much to it there's no
flour there's less sugar involved so
there's that with some of the
enlargement options so those are the
things that I would put into kind of
like a food category then the second
category are capsules so there are an
increasing number of companies that make
cannabis capsules that can be purchased
in the recreational market and I wish I
could make a generalization and say you
can't go wrong or even the say that
they're all bad but it's neither the
recipes that that are put into the
capsules vary from maker to maker which
is ass so so I'll talk more about where
to purchase capsules and the like later
but at this point I just want to say
that the the the person behind the
counter at a reputable cannabis store
should be able to guide you to their
products that are more medical than
other than others at its base all
cannabis is medicine
it's just that different people are
using different kinds of cannabis for
different conditions so if you tell them
that listen
for a capsule with you know very little
sugar that's reliable for Parkinson's
you know with a little luck the the
store clerk will guide you in the right
place so that's food capsules and then
my favorite which is tincture and we're
all familiar with teachers you know a
kadesha or marshmallow root for the
stomach there's a there's a whole range
of teachers that we can use that are
made from taking the plant and soaking
in an alcohol and then straining on the
plant what's left in the alcohol already
is the essential constituents of the
plant its oil is that same thing works
for cannabis and you know in a very
simple way that's essentially how we
make it you take the dried flowers you
so given alcohol you strain them and
then you hopefully laughs test it and
then you've got a teacher and people
have been taking teachers for hundreds
of years as a matter of fact before
cannabis was banned in the United States
it was the primary used teacher for a
whole host of human ailments and it took
up 70% of the pharmacopoeia which is
essentially the pharmacists guide to
what to give people from everything from
from migraines and hot flashes to
menstrual cramps and and a general pain
which to cross the war it was because it
helped the endocannabinoid system even
though we didn't know that then so what
I also like about the tincture is that
when you buy a tincture over-the-counter
and sometimes from neighbors they'll be
lab tested and so you know that every
time you take it it's going to be
exactly the same once you find what your
correct dose
for this for you you'll be like okay I
take 1/3 of a drama and so every time
you take that third of a dropper you
know that the dosing is always the same
the other thing that I like about
teacher is that it's variable you've got
a lot of control as the patient when
you're getting capsules it's got a set
amount of cannabinoids from from
cannabis in it but every time you take
it you have to take the same amount well
as we all know with which with lots of
times you might want less of medicine on
some days or maybe you're feeling
especially bad and you want to take some
more on other days and so teacher gives
you that kind of flexibility where once
you find out what your baseline is you
can change it a little bit based on what
you think your needs are for your day so
it just so happens that arguably the top
neurologists in the country for cannabis
and Parkinson's lives on Vashon dr.
Ethan Russo lives just above KVI beach
here and he's a friend and he's been on
my podcast a few times and he's spoken
at the Grange Hall a few times and he's
a very active member of the fruit Club
good
so dr. Russo sets dosages at after
speaking with the patient but generally
hears me this is a rule of thumb he says
that the threshold to start getting some
sort of benefit isn't is that about 2.5
milligrams of THC and that THC is the
part of cannabis which can make you feel
high if you take enough of it two point
five milligrams though is pretty much
not going to get anybody high there are
outliers say maybe one in 2,000 people
that might feel two point five
milligrams but in all of my years
with patience I've only met one person
and that is why I now have to say 2.5
because up to that point I had said that
no one will in it but then I met someone
so so two point five milligrams of THC
is where you just start to potentially
get some medicinal benefit
he also says though and this is my
experience that the sweet spot of really
starting to have a decrease in the the
motor skills symptoms is that five
milligrams now at five milligrams some
people may feel a little bit of
something some people experience it as
maybe a little bit of cloudiness some
people experience it as just feel a
little more relaxed for those of you who
have had alcohol you know a lot of
people that have that that that cocktail
at the end of their business day which
when it hits their blood they're like
alright the workday is over and now my
time is my own that feeling of relief is
how a lot of people experience five
milligrams and then other people just
experience five milligrams as oh the
shaking has decreased in my arm and I'm
not clenching as much and so they don't
experience five milligrams as something
added but more something that's taken
away in their symptoms right there are
many Parkinson's patients who will take
ten milligrams and at ten milligrams
just about everybody will feel some kind
of response to the THC more often than
not though folks will like that
experience
you're not full-on stoned and difficult
to talk to and giggling and things like
that but you're definitely feeling some
sort of sense of relief from your
symptoms and probably a release of your
days stress and and occasionally just
occasionally
what you might want to be a little more
careful going to slap off the light
switch on the wall because it might take
a little more effort to Zone into the
target but for the patients that I've
worked with the slight feelings of
different this that they get with that
low dose of cannabis is well worth
getting rid of the other symptoms that
are causing them discomfort some of you
may have looked on YouTube for videos of
Parkinson's patients trying cannabis and
if you haven't I recommend that you give
it a try because it's really remarkable
one of the most popular videos is of
this this fella sitting on his couch at
home and he has got of advanced
Parkinson's with with a range of severe
motor or symptoms that that he's
suffering through and his buddy gives
him a small amount of cannabis oil and
puts it underneath his tongue and the
patient is you know playing with it in
his mouth so it's soaking in through his
mucosal membranes in his mouth that's
tongue and it's cheeks and and they're
running a timer at the bottom of the
video and you know for the first you
know minute or so you don't notice any
difference and you're you know you're
tempted to turn off the video if you
like it nothing's happening right but by
the time you've hit
two minutes you can see him instead of
being over to the side he started to set
up more and then by three minutes
his spasticity is decreased his hand
hasn't clenched anymore and he's sitting
up and I think it's by about the four
minutes
you cannot visually tell that this
gentleman has got Parkinson's four
minutes and you know this is a best case
scenario for certain because he had the
right medicine taken sublingually with
that was easily taken up by the body
so everything was optimized in that
situation but it shows the potential in
the medicine of being able to work so
chemists a teacher is similar when you
take the teacher it's in a vehicle 190
proof grain alcohol usually and because
it's in that you don't really want to
take a teacher right into your mouth
those little bird but you take a little
bit of water you know get a juice glass
or a shot glass and you stick a little
bit out of the faucet and put your
squirt in there and you drink it and
patients tell me that they are
experiencing a lessening of their
symptoms within about ten minutes and
they're feeling pretty great by 15 and
when they take it regularly as a
preventive the symptoms just don't come
back throughout their day which is of
course the goal right the goal is not
say like you know let the symptoms get
really bad and then taking it over for
the best the goal is to get yourself on
a schedule that you know about how long
laughs in their system which is usually
about four to six hours and then and
then scheduled yourself to take small
doses during the day so it keeps your
symptoms at bay it helps your brain
clean itself so that the signaling in
your body starts to be better and so
that you can avoid the symptoms entirely
so um with cannabis one of the important
aspects of it is to take what we call
the whole plant or a whole plant
medicine there are some people who are
selling CBD extracts and you may have
heard about this from friends or seen
them on the Internet
CBD stands for cannabidiol which is one
of the cannabinoids that's in the
cannabis plant and it's easily the
second most popular after THC and it's
the one that's had probably the most
research done at this point
besides teams and because of the you
know the laws don't allow marijuana in
some state still some people are
purchasing just CBD on its own over the
internet and hoping that that will help
them with their symptoms I want to
caution you from that because for the
medicine to work you need all of the
different constituents of the plant you
need the THC as part of it you need the
CBD that can have a dial as part of it
you need the minor cannabinoids which we
don't even have them all identify
there's over a hundred of them in the
plant and then you also need the
terpenes which is the aromatherapy of
the plant over these thousands of years
that can't know that human
have been taking the planet with us
everywhere that we expand and travel
over the world we've gotten into a
synergistic relationship with it and so
the plant you know how corn has followed
humans because we take corn everywhere
we go and as we go we're selecting the
seeds for the corn that we most like so
that's the plant that we've come to know
and love especially now during the
summer same thing happens with cannabis
every time humans moved on they took the
seeds of the planets that made them feel
the most healthy and this happening
again again over tens of thousands of
years means that the plant that exists
right now is more uniquely refined to
help our endocannabinoid system than it
ever has before
so I tell you this to kind of inoculate
you against suggestions from your
friends of oh if you need canvas
medicine just get this CBD extract
online you know it's easy to do and it's
you can buy the line it's just easy than
going over town resist that temptation
because it's not the true cannabis
medicine that's made of the whole plant
yes
she said you want that it feel
guys you know I said I don't want to
feel but I just wanted to feel I mean
I've been what be hi correctly to feel
their but so so if you go to a store and
you and you buy something that you don't
deem is appropriate for you and so if
it's got THC in it and it makes you feel
high unfortunately in Washington you
can't return it and so you're kind of
stuck your best bet would just be to try
to create value in someone else by
giving it to them but you can't return
it and and my best suggestion would be
to certainly not work with that
budtender again at that shop and try to
find somebody who's more of an extra
sure yeah and unfortunately incredibly
common there are a lot of unfortunately
they've got a very coordinated
they're known as blood tenders who help
you when you go to their retail stores
and you know certainly there are bud
tenders that do their homework
they've got medically certified with the
state they work with patients on their
free time and they know what they're
doing but unfortunately the ratio is
very small to overall because you know a
lot of folks they're new to cannabis
they just wanted they just want a job in
cannabis and that's an entry-level
position and so they get the job or they
may be familiar with how to help certain
kinds of patients but not Parkinson's
patients so I recommend that you get as
much of your information in advance and
then go active asking for a specific
product for example I like to recommend
the capsules made by a company called
the sea
see and thus the CPC has been making
medicine all the way back years and
years during the Washington medical
industry days and so they are one of the
more reputable companies that
transitioned to the recreational market
and so I know the formulator for the
company Ben and he is an incredibly
knowledgeable person who puts patients
first and so when you hear that kind of
recommendation from somebody in the
field who works with patients all the
time I recommend that you you know talk
with me and others to find out what
they're using that works for them for
their Parkinson's and and then go pick
up the same product because if you go
into a store and just you know blindly
ask for something with low THC and high
CBE
for your parking sins if you get the
wrong bud tender you you you may not
have you know a good experience right
off the bat that said I encourage you
would not give up if that happens to you
because you know the medicine does exist
both in Washington and on Vashon you
just have to find the right source for
for you well if I had Parkinson's I
would actually buy locally here on the
island from an herbalist that's local
here now this is where I also need to
point out that that's technically
illegal and so since they got rid of the
medical
industry it has taken a lot of
herbalists who used to make custom
medicine for patients and put them into
the informal market and so and there's
challenges with the recreational market
which is getting better but again just
by its name it's called the recreational
market you know we're about 18 months
into having a recreational market and
mostly it's it's it's the kind of
medicine that can be used for medicine
for some people but also a lot of people
use it to party right and so the
availability of medicine that is not
made to also party on is still lacking
in the market that said I bet you that
18 months from now the market will be
flush with it because companies they
respond to market demand right and and
unfortunately the state when they with
the medical market was taking care of
tens of thousands of people enough that
we had you know over a thousand stores
just here in Washington and not only did
they get rid of they went from over a
thousand stores down to you know a
little more than three hundred but the
people in this market were were trained
and driven to help patients and some
people who were partying but patients
first and the new market has got that in
reverse where because they wanted to
establish some revenue first they went
below hanging cruge for them who has
people who party and now after they've
got that market establish
they've got some income now they're kind
of circling around the patients which
are more difficult to design products
for it takes more effort it takes more
experience and so so to circle back to
your question if you can find an
herbalist who has experience in the
medical market I would say go with
somebody that you trust locally and shop
locally right legally know that exchange
is not legal in Washington and so if
it's important to you to remain legal
then I recommend then you go to a
recreational store that has a reputation
for being more medical and luckily for
us we have one that's nearby just here
in West Seattle there's a shop called
Canada West Seattle so that's see a and
and a channel West Seattle and they are
on California Avenue and they have most
of their staff is actually has got the
state medical certification and the
owner Mary Ann Mary Ann actually used to
own a reputable medical dispensary
before they all got close so she's got
her heart in the right place and as the
medical products come out and are
released she stops them so if you want
to go somewhere close that understands
patients I can recommend Mary Ann's shop
canna West Seattle as being a place
where you're more likely to get
something a pro
than just walking in anywhere you can
also go on the state of Washington
website and find out the stores that
have received their medical
certification from the state no no
actually you don't so you can go into
stores and buy products that are deemed
medical without having a prescription
for it because cannabis is now legal in
the state and so you know because really
all cannabis is medicine it's just that
some products are really made directly
for patients versus for patients and the
partying and for example the the the the
most common of recommended dosage for
Parkinson's patients is 10 milligrams of
CBD and 5 milligrams of THC take it at
the same time and because it's whole
plant you're also getting a sprinkling
of all the other cannabinoids that are
in there as well you're getting some
terpenes and some flavonoids and some
CBN and CBG and all these lesser-known
cannabinoids but the two that that your
that would likely be written on the
package is 10 milligrams of CBD and 5
milligrams of THC now one of the reasons
why I recommend tinctures is because I
like to tell patients to buy one teacher
that's all THC and one teacher that's
all CBD that way you can play with the
ratio yourself so that you find out what
is the best ratio for you for many
Parkinson's patients 10 ratio is 2 to 1
2 parts CBD to every one part THC the
combination
sorted by studies and by a lot of
first-hand experience that I just seen
with patients but you may find that
you're more sensitive to THC and you
don't want five milligrams at once so
maybe you'd rather take it more often
during the day and and have less THC so
for you the ten milligrams of CPD might
be great but instead of taking five
milligrams you'd actually prefer to have
2.5 so getting buying two teachers one
that's THC and one that CBD you might
find out has more flexibility to you
you're definitely going to find over
time that you become more sophisticated
with how you want to dose yourself this
takes some education even though we've
been using the cannabis plant for tens
of thousands of years it's just coming
back right and so the people who are
making the medicine are relearning what
was essentially a lost craft the the
store employees are relearning not only
how to talk to patients but what to
recommend patients ourselves which I am
I had a brain injury that's how that I
got into medical cannabis
I had a brain injury and so I hadn't
learned about medical cannabis to help
with my brain injury and I had to learn
the appropriate kind of cannabis and the
dosing so if you if you can do you know
how people say about like AB and O you
know they're they were an instant
success they were instantly popular but
they don't know the band
had been gigging and traveling for ten
years it's like that it's like you know
cannabis is a pretty reliable solution
for Parkinson's symptoms and with
long-term use decreasing even the cause
but you got to go through some legwork
at the beginning to find the right
dosage of the right product but lets you
find the right dosage of the right
product it's actually quite to say it's
quite simple to moderate your your
symptoms it's one exam I'm not supposed
to say it's gonna help everybody right
because it doesn't but as far as the
people that worked on on Vashon were 11
for 12 that's pretty good results and
the one person who told me that they
didn't care for it I don't think that
they were patient with learning their
way through the dosing process and so so
yeah it's not a solution for everybody
but but you know based on the people
that I've talked with nationally and the
people that I've talked with right here
on Vashon you know some people call it
Parkinson's low-hanging fruit for
cannabis because Parkinson's is so
directly tied to the endocannabinoid
system
are they using other Parkinson's
medications also everybody I spoke to is
using other Parkinson's medicines as
well like I said at the beginning I
don't recommend that you you know get on
the cannabis and then immediately get
off of your your scripts but I know
several patients that have they have
either decreased their dosage or gotten
off them totally if they're very anti
pharmaceuticals so so at the beginning
they take both because there's no
negative interplay that we've seen the
only negative interplay that we've seen
is that with just a couple epilepsy
drugs there seems to be some interaction
with high doses of CBD but in the
Parkinson's realm I come across no kind
of negative interaction yes sir I don't
like any resident it's better than their
quick answer I have defense Ferguson I
have this building a business there's
gonna be help with that I am not as
familiar with dystonia
would you tell would you just tell me a
little bit about it so that I understand
what biological what human system it
works with appropriate messages from the
brain to the muscles
stay there okay that's a yes so the
short answer is without having read
their research much my immediate
conclusion would be yes and I'll tell
you why I actually glad that you
mentioned this because I I missed this
earlier in my notes the thickness so so
the main components of cannabis that
we've been talking about today are THC
and CBD and one of the reasons that
people love CBD and why it's used for a
variety of patients is because it
supports the body's signaling system and
our signaling system has to do with a
lot of different problems so so I'll use
pain is as an example first
so CBD is often used for pain patients
because while teeing a see is an
analgesic and so it kind of it kind of
dumbs down the pain when someone has got
endocannabinoid deficiency let's say
that you that you injure your leg when
the lay communicates to the brain that
there's a problem it sends it for the
first time full force hey god we've got
pain you should be alert to the lane and
and then after you recognize that it's
supposed to turn down the volume so that
you you continue to tell get medical
care but it shouldn't be giving you that
initial signal constantly well with pain
patients we run into all the time that
because they've got a weakened and no
cannabinoid system the leg keeps up
reporting back we're in trouble
we're in trouble very loud every
single time and so the experience of
their pain is is is severe when they
start taking CBD it turns down the the
experience of pain because the
signalling system is working more
properly belay is calling up the brain
hey we got a problem the brain says okay
we've made a note of it you can turn
down your signal and sends back and so
now while you still might feel the pain
you don't feel it as intensely similarly
with muscle sets so when when when you
when you're experiencing muscle set
clenching say say you know maybe the
hand is clenching or or the forearm is
clenching which then may be causing some
tremors
what you're experiencing is the brain
sending a signal to the muscle set to
clench and in you know he needs to be
turned off because you don't want it to
clench and and you're part of what you
relieve this experience is having a
healthy and no cannabinoid system where
the signaling between the brain and the
muscle sets becomes optimized and
rebalanced and with that causes they're
relaxing and then this is why the the
gentleman who I started my talk talking
about who who was cutting the lawn
that's what his experiences Keith Keith
Keith was he'd be all clenched up
because there's this constant signal to
to to tighten these muscles sets and you
know he would get sore from it and then
he gets on this other side of his body
instead
that side but then after he started
taking this this CVD whole plant
medicine that signaling system
rebalanced itself and so now the signal
is no longer stuck yes you're talking
now about an isolated Canada better wait
are you saying you're still saying take
it with the PRC correct because so the
long the short of it is is that there is
not as much research done on the entire
family of cannabinoids yet for us to
know what role the minor ones play what
we do know is if you give someone just
CBD they don't have the same response
and so we know that it's not the
isolated molecule and the studies that
have been done have been done with CBD
in the presence of whole plant
cannabinoids and and so it's the
interplay between them so without having
read the specific research on your
question I would say that that sounds
like a signaling disorder that would be
certainly helped by whole plan yes so in
your research
[Music]
doesn't also identify your strengths so
that the research does not focus on
particular strains it focuses on
molecular components of the plant and so
different strains will have more will
have better effects for different
patients so but knowing this strain
mostly only helps patients who are
smoking it right because people smoke a
particular strain but when people buy
products in the store they're not
usually identified by the strain so if
you were to go and buy a two to one
capsule 10 cup 10 milligrams of CBD and
5 milligrams of THC it won't say the
strain name it will identify the
ingredients as molecules it's got this
much CBD this much THC and other minor
cannabinoids right with that being said
i you were looking to source a strain
say for example you're a patient who
wanted to grow their own medicine which
is very common on fashion i would
recommend that you find a strain that is
high in the CBD and very low in THC and
then also find one and give that a try
but you're probably going to need
additional THC so then also grow another
one that's just a THC strain and then
when you mix those together that would
be the right strain there certainly are
strains that
truly come out at 2 1 for example the
Harlequins strain is a very popular
strain with Parkinson's patients that is
comes out naturally being two parts CBD
to every one part THC but I don't want
to give you the impression that you need
to go find the Harlequin strain right if
you want to grow it we can talk about
where you might be able to get plants
that naturally occur at to the one but
really as far as getting medicine goes
you're just gonna you're gonna buy it
based on what the ingredients are
molecularly
in the package versus by a strain well
the only the only negative that I have
come across for Parkinson's patients in
cannabis is if you accidentally take
more THC than you want and you can have
an over medicated experience right which
also is also known as just getting
stoked right so and that that is there's
a there's a big wide spectrum on that
right there's there's medicinal doses
for Parkinson's that youth Network and
you don't won't feel it at all some
people need a little bit more and you
might get some of the cloudy headedness
and appetite and many people just feel
like relief from stress and that's
actually a good thing but then you know
if you let's say that you're not on a
schedule and it will let's say they mess
up your schedule you normally take it
three times a day and and because you
have forgotten you take it now then you
take it again in a half-hour and
suddenly you're doubling up on your THC
and at these low doses you're probably
not going to have
overmedication experience but some
patients need to take 20 30 40
milligrams of THC which is you know
eight times what I'm recommending for
that kind of a patient if they
accidentally take it and then take it
again and a half hour they they could
have what's at the far end when you're
having an over medicated experience
which is not pleasant you may experience
paranoia you'll probably experience a
rapid heartbeat because it can lower
your blood pressure a little bit that
might cause you to have some clammy
sweats and luckily I've only had that
happened three times in my life but the
first two times I totally felt like I
maybe I should call the paramedics
because my body was doing weird things
but as I got more educated I realized
that no one has ever died from cannabis
and your mind might be telling you that
these are unfamiliar feelings and I need
medical help but if you just stick with
it you know go for a calm walk in your
yard you lay down in your bed to try to
take a nap or there's some other good
things you're doing you'd smell black
pepper black pepper tends to reduce the
experience of cannabis as well as
drinking lemonade because the citrine in
the lemonade decreases your high as well
all things that you can do and but if
you get that if you get that high and
you don't want to be and it's negative
it's a drag but it won't kill you and
you just got to wait it out for 45
minutes and then
anyway okay I need to be more careful
with my dose English saying everyone's
in our experience if you take a really
high encourage yeah if you take a really
high dosage of edibles you can if you
can have a whole day thing now if you
were to go in and ask for an edible as
it as a new patient for Parkinson's
there is no way that they should sell
you a strong enough animal to get that
high right that said if you get an
edible and let's let's say let's call it
a it's a chocolate bar right and each of
the little squares is ten milligrams and
you're only supposed to take one square
right and you eat it all right that's
good chocolate and so that maybe you're
tempted to take the second one and then
you start to get the munchies
you want to make sure you have something
else to take write more or as the
classic thing to happen I forget the
name of this senator but early in canvas
legalization she flew from some East
Coast state to Colorado and she bought a
chocolate bar that was supposed to be
eight doses and and she didn't read the
packaging she didn't do her homework as
a responsible patient and when she got
back to the van and they drove on she
aimed the chocolate bar just enjoying
the chocolate bar but she didn't realize
it was eight doses when she had an
intense experience it was a very
unpleasant she went to the hospital you
know she and and it became national news
and and one group of people are like see
marijuana medicine is dangerous and then
present marijuana patients raw like
she's being irresponsible with her
medicine you know we wouldn't say that
she was responsible she didn't read the
label in an eight-hour oxycontin either
right we would say that's a patient
error well same thing with if you're if
you're you know taking more than you're
supposed to a THC as well so so yeah if
you're if you're talking about you know
the difference between five and ten
milligrams or ten and twenty milligrams
we're talking about 45 minutes before
you're feeling you know it's at least a
little more like yourself and not
concerned but but in these type of cases
when you're trying to take five or ten
milligrams and you're taking a hundred
milligrams that's that's it that's a
difficult day you're not gonna
enjoy or maybe enjoy a whole line yes
sir yeah awesome thank you appreciate
your energy they could have glad to be
here and I love teaching about cannabis
medicine so I get enthusiastic these
financial this kind of things how much
does this teacher cost and what some
insurance companies do sure that's a
really good question
unfortunately insurance companies will
not come anywhere near this until it's
federally legal and so unfortunately
that means that we got to all pay for it
out of pocket which is a drag the the
recreational stores are presently more
expensive than they were in the old
medical days because they've got a lot
more overhead and you know they've got
to pay for advertising and things like
that that didn't really happen very much
in the medical industry so I would say
that you know a bottle of teacher in the
recreational market will probably run
you you know between 55 and 75 dollars
depending on the strength and who you
buy it from and at what store how do you
mean to let this test can you get a
picture and tell them you have a picture
no but they're all required to be tested
by the state ahead of time and so you
can rely on how much is in each one
yep even though you're not getting the
same thing for a brownie if you're
really good over a course and you're
still getting the same thing you would
but if you happen to get the brownie
that's especially high in THC and mint
and that this one's lower in THC this
one way you might feel more more high
from than you want to be because if
you're if you're trying to give yourself
10 milligrams of or 5 milligrams of THC
and for some reason when you were
started the THC ended up in this corner
you can end up with a higher amount when
you're doing it at home so the capsules
depending again on on who the producer
is and what store you're buying an app
will float between five and ten dollars
capsule which unfortunately capsules are
still pretty high priced especially if
you want to be taking 3 a day right so
that's unfortunate but but there's hope
because prices are continually coming
down in the recreational market because
there's more producers and more
competition and more people are making
capsules plus the companies are learning
to be more efficient and to save their
costs as well in contrast you know I
mentioned earlier that you know you can
also buy locally because we happen to
live on Vashon where there are you know
cannabis is historically our number one
cash problem and and it's been that way
since the 70s and love it or hate it
it's been the truth of
matter and we also have got a lot of
good herbalists on the island and you
know there are places on the island that
you can get teachers for as little as
forty dollars of all and the important
thing though is if you buy from family
or friends or even make your home
I implore you to make sure that it's
laboratory tested for its strength
because you don't want em to have an
experience where either you're making
your own tincture and the first time you
make it it's weak and then you make it
again and it's super potent and there's
this disparity and so you give yourself
a negative experience for and you want
to you know the part of Medicine is
where the repeatable results and if you
want repeatable results you need to know
what your variable a is and so if you
make your own or if you buy it and
formally on the island or from anywhere
in the country you know make sure that
the that the person who's producing it
the herbalist has had it tested and if
you're gonna make your own it's really
easy to have your products tested just
right over here on the other side of the
ferry from at analytical 360 is a lab
that will do testing for you know any
patient you don't need an authorization
just go in and give them yourself and
say you know tell me how strong it is /
/ dropper squirt right and anybody who
is any herbalist who's informally and
illegally producing it on the island
would be getting it lab tested as well
because that person cares about their
patients yes
[Music]
so it is legal to grow your own in
Washington if you have a patient
authorization card from your doctor if
your doctor fills out a form that says
that you have one of the corresponding
illnesses they check the box and they
sign it and that piece of paper gives
you the right to grow four plants
if you then choose to sign up to the
state's registry of patients that four
plants become six and if you have your
doctor right on the authorization that
you need more plants than what's allowed
and you get on the registry you can get
up to 15 plants your private your
primary care doctor may well as a matter
of fact there are I can't say all but
several of the doctors at the Batchelor
clinic give authorizations and also
there is a naturopath that I
for folks to regularly who's very
familiar with cannabis medicine and
patients who I can I can give out his
number to anybody who wants it I must I
must caution you from getting on the
state's registry though if you want to
preserve your privacy because as we know
the state is not very good with keeping
things secret and you know all the tens
of thousands of patients there are in
Washington I think we're only at 14,000
in the entire state that have signed up
for it and those are mostly people who
are doing it because they want to pay
less tax and when you buy because if you
become a patient's you don't have to pay
the sales tax no you're technically not
supposed to smoke marijuana in the sight
of other people so you're so you're
supposed to be able to enjoy it at home
or if you're out by yourself
the wilderness or you know but you're
but that's right right now you're not
even allowed to do cannabis social clubs
in Seattle where you're in a you know
because there's other people there right
now do people do it all the time sure
but but it's not legal technically
technically you're not supposed to do it
in eyesight of other folks
so so so so the information that I'm
giving you is from years of experience
and so there probably isn't a particular
place you're going to go online that's
going to have synthesized at all like I
am you can certainly find out
information you can google Tarkin sins
and cannabis and you'll get us a slew of
information a good part of it will be
accurate I like to recommend the website
project CVD org and as a matter of fact
right now now their homepage they've got
a big thing on Parkinson's in CBD for
beginners which is an excellent article
setting in is a project CBD for the
information there is the best of the
best their articles are written by
people who know about cannabis and also
if you go to their they've got a section
on the website that says conditions and
it lists 50 conditions that cannabis can
be used for if you click on Parkinson's
it will take you to a page of all of the
medical science that has been done into
cannabis and Parkinson's and you can
actually read the study that not someone
filtering the information for you which
is that's where I go to learn about
dosage for patients because I don't I
don't want to read it filtered through
somebody's article I want to I want to
be the actual scientific study that was
done in the UK right and so they have
both on projects TV news website they
have quality articles that are
synthesizing this
raishin and they also have the original
scientific papers that you can read as
well sure sir well we could get you a
piece of paper write it down when we're
done here
400 heavier newspaper looks like she's
going to give it to you so project CBD
is very reliable over the store
this sort canna West sea I'll go in
there and ask for specialized well they
can't compound
like they're like a pharmacy would but
they will know which of their products
is more most appropriate for you and I
was going to get them out at the end but
since you're leaving let me give you one
of my cars in case you want to ask a
follow-up question and also in case
you're interested in being introduced to
somebody on the island
[Music]
and I I do this all volunteer work I
make my money through my podcast and
through paid speaking engagements and I
teach patients because I think it's
important so the name of the Islander
sure out after the beating when it's a
little more one-to-one I would be happy
to tell you more about where you can get
another island and movement and who to
talk to
yeah I know I don't mind those questions
in an email just just nothing to be a
facebook because it's that's that's not
secure for any kind of healthy
discussion yeah totally so another yes
right so before the whole thing with the
whole licensing all that came I thought
I had my papers and I would buy bits of
things and so no I wanted that never got
used how is that so if if it's uh if
it's flour itself like the buds like
first money that slowly degrades over
time because you Roma therapy about the
smell of it is part of the medicine and
it degrades over time so maybe if
flowers will will stay really met
medicinal for a year oh this is more
like teachers and so things like that
teachers will be self shelf-stable you
know easily a year sometimes they add
additives that make it less shelf-stable
like like it
like raspberry flavorings or something
like that but the but it's been a very
clean medicine let's say for example a a
full can avid cannabis extract in
alcohol which what the in a dark
container kept in a dark area your home
not on the shelf that could stay good
for two or three years because it
stopped degrading things like edibles
and and capsules it depends on what
they're made out of it but but but once
the cannabis is taken out of the plant
and put an alcohol becomes very stops -
thank you so any other questions before
we wrap up it amazes me how much money
could be collected by the government if
they made marijuana not you know you'd
have to have a prescription and you have
to pay for it and you're paying an awful
lot of it even if you're making it
yourself yeah you're right about that me
then just just in our own state they tax
it 37 percent before the sales tax and
so that's a lot of money being raised at
the same time at 37 percent tax is
coming out of our pockets as patients so
that's kind of a drag too because if
they if they decrease the taxes patients
wouldn't have to pay so much
but you're right there's a lot of money
to be raised in taxes that's a festive
night they're right on well then I'll be
around for a few minutes for questions
if anybody has been kind of informally
on the side thank you very much for
having me here and for