yeah okay I'll make it much briefer this
time hi I'm Zoe thank you guys so much
for coming if you have questions please
save them for the end I tried to make
this really easy to understand there
might be questions that's okay
I talked really fast if I talk to you
last let me know
okay little history context the
endocannabinoids system it has a very
long history and we're going to shove it
into three South slice um first things
first
evolutionary history so the
endocannabinoid system is present in all
vertebrates and it's present in more
than just vertebrates in fact components
of the endocannabinoids system has been
found in everything from humans to fungi
but the endocannabinoids system as we
understand it now it exists in all
coordinates which is a specialized genus
of animals that includes vertebrates and
also things like the sea squirt which is
not a vertebrate it is very squishy but
that has none of cannabinoid system so
chordates evolved around five hundred
and thirty million years ago vertebrates
evolved around 525 million years ago our
researchers are hesitant to put a an
exact pinpoint on when the
endocannabinoids system evolved which is
fair we don't actually have any way to
tell but that's a little like taste of
how old this system is as I was reading
one of my favorite researchers dr. John
McFarlane he had this lovely quote about
the evolution of the endocannabinoids
system that I just wanted to read to you
so over evolutionary time we see
duplications and mutations of the
endocannabinoids sit receptors and
ligands the symbol for Enda can end up
cannabinoid evolution is not a
bifurcating tree but an inter waving
arabesque of Ko evolving receptors and
ligands so rate isn't that words I will
get into what all those things mean but
that just means like this system evolved
in many different species at many
different times in many different ways
for many different reasons and then we
ended up with it it's complicated all
right so moving on to slightly more
modern times the timeline
this is important in understanding of
why we understand what we do in doge
about the endocannabinoid system so 1964
rafael Chilam elucidated the structure
of THC just so you know 1963 the
structure CBD was elucidated and then
nothing for a long time scientists
thought that the vitamin a monoid like
THC worked through a nonspecific
membrane-associated action which is
about as specific as it sounds
so they didn't really know it had
something to do with lipids it did some
cool stuff and there wasn't really
funding and so they moved on um and then
80s NIDA was like marijuana is bad let's
prove that it's bad by funding it
alright find out what that about
marijuana so in 1988 in dr. Allen hall
it's lab using night of funding they
discovered the first so almost three
decades later they found the first
endocannabinoids scepter for THC and
then they were like mmm it's weird that
we have this thing in our bodies that
only interacts with a plan why could
that be and then they found the first
endocannabinoid a couple of years later
then they found the second
endocannabinoids scepter then they found
a second and Oh cannabinoid and we've
gone on from there but that's all to say
this is you know like 30 years old um
this field of research is really new and
it changes really fast which brings me
to I am NOT a scientist I'm not a
researcher I'm not a doctor this
research changes really fast I read a
lot of it all the time if you hear
something you're like that's wrong eight
tell me cuz I want know and B just know
that like it changes a lot and there are
a lot of conflicting information about
this
so if I say something that sounds wrong
let's explore um okay so moving on to
where is the under cannabinoid system
this is important because the
endocannabinoid system can do so many
different things we hear about it being
involved in all these different disease
states and a lot of that has to do with
where it is um so it is found in the
nervous system the immune system and fat
skin bone circulating cells the justice
system you've heard of reproductive
system it's found everywhere um and so I
want to start with does anyone know what
the nervous system does anyone not even
[Music]
exactly exactly
that was a description of what the
nervous system does it is the way that
our body communicates and regulating a
lot of other systems there are two parts
to their dinner to the nervous system
there's the central nervous system which
is your brain and your brainstem spinal
cord and then there's the peripheral
nervous system which is all the nerves
that run throughout the body so the
central nervous system is like the
communication hub it receives signals
from all over the body and then it sends
out other signals telling the body what
to do it organizes all that information
and regulates everything the peripheral
nervous system is responsible for
communicating that information to and
from the central nervous system this is
important because the nervous system
does things like regulate our breathing
or heart beating or us looking at our
arms being like I want to open my hand
cool I opened my hand it did it
that's awesome that's your nervous
system at work the other system that's
super important when we talk about the
endocannabinoids system is the immune
system so the immune system pretty
straightforward we all are pretty
familiar every winter where there are
game systems and what they do and it's
not just make us feel really shitty for
a while it is they are trying to protect
us from invaders and the there are a
bunch of different parts of the immune
system the parts that were particularly
interested in for the endocannabinoids
system are the B and T cells which are
like the warrior cells of the immune
system they like go around your body and
they're like you invader die which is
also bone marrow really important in the
immune system and a cannabinoid system
is also in your bone marrow cool and all
of these other systems so this is the
reason that when we talk about cannabis
and cannabis being therapeutic for a
number of different things that are
really not very closely related this is
one of the reasons it could be
therapeutic for all of those things
because there are so many places that it
could interact throughout the body in
fact the endocannabinoids system has
been expressed in every organ and in
every system that's been looked at so
far with the exception of but there's a
respiratory center go to Britain and
it's not there but it is in most parts
of our brain not all of them um okay so
much and you've all been waiting for
what is the under cannabinoid system
I'll start using ECS for
endocannabinoids system and they're just
a little bit faster um there's a lot of
words on this screen and there's also
you know it's a really good question
that's why we're here
we're gonna talk about the
endocannabinoids system as it's
classically understood there is a lot of
information about the endocannabinoid
system that is evolving really really
rapidly and we'll touch on that at the
end but for today we're going to talk
about the to classical endocannabinoids
afters you have a vaild receptor type
one
one cannabinoid receptor type 2cb to
their endogenous ligands which are the
compounds that our body creates to bind
to those receptors and then the enzymes
that synthesize and metabolize those
those ligands so those are the enzymes
that like give birth to and break down
the compounds that bind to the under
cannabinoid receptors we're gonna go
into each one of those again don't worry
there's also a lot of other parts to the
under cannabinoid system we'll touch on
all of that at the end we're gonna focus
on these three parts starting with
receptors so this question isn't urine
dear to my heart I started at a
dispensary because I needed a job mine
PhD programs in sociology and I had like
two days of training and I walked out of
my science training and I was like we
have an endocannabinoid system it's some
receptors on cells somewhere I don't
know what a receptor is like what is a
receptor what does this cell what is it
neuron and then like that's when the
rabbit hole started so I love this
question a receptor let me see what
image I put first yes okay cool this is
an image of a receptor an actual image
well an illustration never accepted I
think that this is important because
oftentimes people will just be like oh
it's like this thing but like it
actually looks like that they were
subjects of a tiny protein on the
surface of a cell that compounds engage
with that to tell the cell to do
something or to not do something they
allow compounds to have impacts on the
cell the largest family there are four
families of receptors the ones that
we're going to be talking about tonight
are g-protein coupled receptors cb1 and
cb2 are both GPCRs that all doesn't
matter it's called a cook um what does
matter is GPCRs are the target of like
40% of medicines they are really
widespread throughout your body they are
one of the oldest families of receptors
and CD 1 is one of the most common G
protein-coupled receptors in our brains
which is crazy
ok so this is a little illustration that
I made
it's not very good but it does the job
so cb1 and cb2 are widely expressed
throughout the body you can see we've
got a central nervous system the
peripheral nervous system their cb1
actually let's just go that slide all
right here we go
can I have an interceptor type 1 now
we've got a focus on it so that picture
of the receptor is a cb1 receptor
g-protein coupled receptors have 7
protein strands that go from the outside
of the settle the inside of the cell
when compounds bind to the protein or to
the receptor they bind they make the
receptor change a little bit and then a
bunch of chemistry happens and it makes
a cell go cb1 receptors are most
prevalent and most densely populated in
the brain and in many many areas of the
brain that are responsible for memory
word systems attention emotional
responses that's a lot of what we focus
on when we talk about cd1 cb1 is what
makes you feel high it is a very
important receptors the first one
discovered and it plays a major role in
pain perception um which is why THC can
help some people feel less pain it seems
to do that by altering our emotional
perception of pain which is kind of
interesting and might explain why some
people feel more pain because they start
to notice it more it's not actually
killing the pain anyway it's also
present on the olfactory bulb
reproductive system and on the skin um
moving on to cannabinoid receptor
- I'm so excited that I found a picture
of this receptor when I was looking for
a picture of this receptor a couple
years ago one wasn't available I found
one and it was through Creative Commons
so here it is it is just seven protein
strands yeah but it's actually the CVT
receptor and it has something binding in
it which is really cool that green thing
is you know where a compound binds this
is important receptors are
three-dimensional shapes and
three-dimensional shapes bind to them
and those three-dimensional shapes are
different shapes and so when those
shapes come together and change they
have different effects
cd2 what is most prevalent in our immune
system so it's found on B cells in our
immune system and it is really important
in regulating inflammation throughout
the body cb2 does not make us feel
hockey but it is of particular interest
to many many researchers who want to tap
into the benefits of cannabis without
feeling high unfortunately that's really
hard they are very closely related for a
long time and this is really
controversial
cb2 was thought to not be present in the
brain at all but there is some evidence
to suggest that it is present in the
brain and it might serve an immune
immuno protective function up there but
again very controversial this is like
where we're at with you can have an ID
system alright moving on to
Williams all right endogenous ligands
let's break it down endo means within
Liggins means a compound that binds so
these are compounds that bind to the
receptors found within our bodies
endogenous is the opposite of exogenous
so an exogenously gun would be something
from outside of your body that binds to
receptor it can have annoyed if I don't
can happen to it a cannabinoid from
plants would be an excellent example of
this so I started looking at receptors
and ligands and it was just like words
words words words words um but these are
actually really important for it and so
I made a little diagram explaining what
they are mmm a Star Wars characters
[Laughter]
receptors tell the cell cells do
specific things we don't know why they
do those things they just do the things
that they do which is cool but they
won't do those things without some
motivation and that motivation comes in
the form of compounds or in this case
Star Wars characters so in this case the
cells action restores balance to the
force urgell the whole premise of Star
Wars
I really hope everyone to see this movie
otherwise now it really doesn't work
okay so Luke Skywalker our you know hero
of the moment would be an agonist so an
agonist is a compound that binds to
receptor and that tells the cell to go
do your thing
you're awesome you're gonna go do it now
um that's Luke Skywalker he's gonna
restore balance to the forest by
activating the receptor on the cell um
the opposite of that would be an
antagonist so an antagonist binds to the
receptor still but it tells the cell
don't go and also nothing else
find here so nothing can activate you
more or less and that was a little
harder so it's like if the movies didn't
get funding like if Luke didn't get
funding if you just like stayed on his
farm with his aunt uncle forever that
would be the antagonist so like the
story just doesn't happen this can be
really important for like when a system
is overactive if you want to like calm
it down a little bit you can introduce a
net agonist to a system and make the
receptors chill heck out we also have
allosteric modulator x' so agonists and
antagonists bind to the primary binding
site on our septic which begin is
sometimes other compounds will bind to
other sites on the side of the receptor
and will change the shape of the
receptor but they won't activate it not
really but what they do when they change
the shape is they can make things that
bind to it work more or less well so
when something changes the shape of
receptor and makes it work better with
the things that find and activate it
it's called a positive allosteric
modulator so this compound is changing
the same shape of the receptor to allow
things that bind to it to work better
the opposite of that which is kind of
like Emperor Palpatine in this movie but
the kind of not including him is the
negative allosteric modulator so that's
something that binds to the side of the
receptor changes the shape and allows
and makes it harder for things to bind
to the receptor and they work less well
this is why CBD makes you feel less high
once you if you like taken too much THC
CBD is a negative allosteric modulator
at cb1 change the shape THC binds less
well you feel less high I also included
synthesizing enzymes just to like
continue on the road towards explaining
the endocannabinoid system
so if synthesizing enzyme would be an
enzyme that triggers the creation of
those ligands in the endocannabinoid
system so it's like responsible for
giving birth to the agonists or
antagonists in the system in this case
Princess Leia if she didn't send that
message Luke would have never gotten it
he never would have gone and done the
thing so she is kind of responsible for
like the whole thing being born which is
pretty cool it's not a ligand so um
alright and then as a bonus we have
Darth Vader who's an inverse agonist we
won't really get much into inverse
agonists in this particular presentation
but it is another important function
that compounds can have so if an agonist
activates the cell and tells the self do
your thing go and do it an inverse
agonist does the opposite it's exactly
the opposite it tells the cell do the
opposite thing if the cell wants to
usually go to the right an inverse
agonist will be like go to the left and
that's what happens in our bodies get in
first agonism very very weird okay
in addition to all of these things
binaries are all false including how
things bind to receptors so something
doesn't just simply bind and tell the
cell to go they can bind more or less
well which is why allosteric modulation
is a thing but compounds in and of
themselves have a binding affinity so
you have a scale from a partial agonist
to a full agonist and this is important
because THC and one of the
endocannabinoids are partial agonists at
the endocannabinoid receptors other
things are full agonists at the
cannabinoid receptors and they have
different effects this is important when
you're looking at research a lot of
research that done that's done in the US
isn't done using THC it's done using a
synthetic cannabinoid often times 155
which is a full agonist at cb1 and cb2
pretty good standing
perfect um okay so partial agonist full
agonist partial antagonist full
antagonist allosteric modulation
synthesizing enzyme lots of words we're
gonna move on to endocannabinoids okay
so endocannabinoids are compounds that
our bodies produce that bind to the
cannabinoid receptors there are over a
dozen that are named so far but we
really only know about two of them and
they were the first two discovered a
named amide or a EA and to erect a rocky
denial glycerol which I like to say
because I had to learn how to say it
lowered to AG which is what everyone
calls it I like to include the images of
the three-dimensional shape with the
molecules just to highlight again that
these are three-dimensional shapes
binding in three-dimensional pockets and
that's why they can find more or less
well they if like if there's a little
candy cane shape in the receptor and
that little candy cane goes in there
perfectly it is a full agonist life it's
like not quite a perfect candy cane it's
just a little bit of a candy cane that
still kind of goes in there and
activates it just a little bit that's a
partial agonist that's why it's
important enough um so you know how you
can go for a run some of you some of us
and after like a little while the first
mile the first 30 minutes you start to
feel really good but only for a while
that's a runner's high and they have
shown that after thirty thirty minutes
or more of running men experienced a
doubling of an and amide in their brains
so this compound and an amide is
probably responsible for the runner's
high which is pretty cool the reason
that our runner's high lasts very very
short amount of time is that when endo
be now
are released their enzymes to break them
down are also released and so there
started to be broken down like
immediately very very short effects but
still very important um an and amide is
and it's great oh man I forgot it means
to pre enjoyed so the actual name of the
molecule means what it feels like just
pretty amazing so true AG second
compound found seems to be like more
expressed in more tissues at higher
concentrations than Ananda mine and they
often play like opposing roles like when
one of them does one thing like is it
it's anti-inflammatory and this is the
case for when I pick it up I talk about
it later I think an and abide is largely
anti-inflammatory to AG and can be
pro-inflammatory and we'll talk about
why that's important we want to like put
that out there but these two compounds
are both millions of the cannabinoid
receptors they both bind and activate
the cannabinoid receptors but they can
have opposing effects which is important
when we talk about what the
endocannabinoids system does on a large
scale okay
metabolic enzymes oh no okay well
there's a whole list of compounds you
don't really need to know them the most
important are the catabolic enzymes
which are the enzymes that break these
two endocannabinoids down ba and maggle
mag lipase meg yeah they're released at
the same time as the endocannabinoids
they break them down they eat them if
you adjust the levels of those enzymes
end up adjusting the levels of
endocannabinoids and that's some of how
like this medicine works so when we are
talking about the endocannabinoids
system these three parts the receptors
the endocannabinoids and the enzymes
that synthesize them and break them down
work in concert throughout the body so
if you change one of those three parts
you will end up with changes in the
other two parts it balances itself and
so this is these are all therapeutic
targets for medicine and there are
different research projects going on
manipulating each one of these things
for different reasons okay so this is
the important question what does it do
this is a really hard question to answer
especially breaking it down in rap
generalities like we talked about
earlier the endocannabinoids system is
expressed everywhere in the body and it
does a lot of different things but in
general it seems to encourage the body
to maintain homeostasis so it regulates
systems it is like um it's like a
thermostat and I stole this metaphor
from Martin Lee my boss so the a new
cannabinoid system is like a master
thermostat it takes all the diff
information from the different systems
and it makes sure that all of the
systems are running in concert what I
was saying about the pro and
anti-inflammatory effect of the
endocannabinoids earlier that plays
directly into this so you know when you
get a fever your body is trying to kill
the germs it's really important that
like you know they don't take root in
your body and take over and then you die
it's not good um so it raises the
temperature tries to kill the germs
that's awesome but then okay it's cool
the germs die but your body can't stay
hot forever then your cells will die
which also results in death not good so
there needs to be a system to
that system down to bring the
temperature down so it's it's like that
but everywhere with every system it's
super interesting to try and research
any of this online because it's like the
endocannabinoids system and the gut the
endocannabinoid system and respiratory
system the end you can have no system in
the reproductive system and it's just
like doo doo doo doo doo doo it does
this everywhere everywhere it's really
really amazing um and in order to
illustrate this I decided to look at two
conditions and talk about what happens
with the endocannabinoids system in
those conditions
the first being pain and inflammation um
so this is one of the primary things
that it is thought that the
endocannabinoid system regulates in the
body inflammation is implicated in a lot
of different diseases there are
degenerative diseases might be related
to inflammation autoimmune diseases
might be related to inflammation and so
finding you and like novel ways to
reduce inflammation is really important
at the end of cannabinoid system
presents a really awesome therapeutic
target for that first things first
cd1 modulates pain perception what I
said earlier about it
changing your emotional perception of
pain super important but it doesn't seem
to have much of a rule the plantation
may be a little bit cb2 on the other
hand really seems to play a major role
in modulating inflammation when ananda
maya and 2ag binds to it they can have
those opposing effects and yeah one of
the things that is important to note now
as before is it's really hard to find
that activates only one of these two
things so when you get cb1 activation
you also get cb2 activation and fight
Somerset a lot of research is being done
to look for a cv2 agonist that doesn't
activate cv 1 and it's going ok you know
we're still learning once they do that
scientists are gonna lose their stuff
it's gonna be a big deal ok so one of
the reasons that we know CP 2 has an
impact in information is they designed a
mouse that didn't have cb2 receptors
which is something that researchers do
with my cell the time they delete
different receptors or systems or
whatever and we're gonna see what it
does and those mice had elevated start
elevated levels of inflammation that
they ended up like having tissue damage
and dying so CP tu seems to be very
important in regulating inflammation
throughout the body
yeah all right yes moving on to Oh
actually I wanted to touch on no that's
okay alright metabolism and energy
this was another really interesting
thing that I guess like every system is
an interesting system that the
endocannabinoid system interacts with
but this is another really interesting
one um so the underground system starts
developing in fetuses really early on by
only 14 and it seems to be responsible
endocannabinoids play a role in embryo
implantation in the uterus and then when
a baby is born endocannabinoids play a
role in supplamine there and that Amanda
mine is found in breast milk and when
you take an and my doubt of breast milk
Mouse pups in the mouse model just
didn't supple and they died so
endocannabinoids systems really
important from the very beginning for
feeding and cd1 seems to be the real
star of this whole aspect
the systems like modulates every aspect
of feeding from like finding food to the
eating of food to the processing of food
to feeling satiated cv1 is implicated
and all of that cb2 seems to oppose
those effects so this is another of
those like homeostatic things cb1 does
one thing CBT does the other thing where
the end of cowboys there's one thing the
other and you can have no it does not a
thing the opposite thing um but cd1
really seems to be important in feeding
um when we were hungry
and we look at food the endocannabinoids
in our system go way up they start going
up like slowly over the day but then we
look at something we want to eat they
just like pop up and then we eat and
then they start to go slowly down now
when the system is dysregulated if you
end up with disease namely obesity and
on the one hand or anorexia on the other
hand people who are obese will have the
same reaction they'll have a spike of
endocannabinoids when they see food that
they want to eat but it doesn't they
don't like go down as quickly or as much
as people of normal weight and so that
could mean like maybe they're not
feeling it's this sheeted they still
feel hungry even though they shouldn't
be hungry it's just not satisfying in
the same way on the other hand people
with anorexia are showing food maybe
it's even their favorite food
no spike in endocannabinoids they eat no
spike in endocannabinoids so it's just
like they obviously aren't having a
pleasure reaction to eating food so
manipulating the endocannabinoids system
could be a really good therapeutic
target unfortunately it can have
downstream effects so there was a drug
Ramana ban which blocked the cb1
receptor that was approved for treating
obesity and it was approved and then
quickly withdrawn from the market for
negative side effects like suicidality
so it's not as simple as just like
introducing something that blocks one or
the
their receptor like it's a complex
system so what you do one thing it does
that everywhere and have really negative
side effects on the other magic and have
really positive side effects what I
wanted to say that um all right this is
the last section and probably most
important to you guys what do you do
with all this information it's a lot of
letters and numbers words how do you
impact your system how do you impact
your on your cannabinoid system there's
the obvious answer let's talk a little
bit about how cannabinoids interact with
the endocannabinoids system so THC is
the most common cannabinoid found in
cannabis something that many of you
probably enjoy tonight and it is binding
to both the cb1 and cb2 receptor
throughout your body and doing some
really cool things like making you feel
high and maybe making you feel less pain
or less nauseous or like just better in
general it does some really really cool
things TBD on the other hand does not
bind to cb1 or CVT receptors it is a
negative allosteric modulator it cd1
just how it makes you feel less hi we've
had too much and it has an impact on a
lot of different receptors and channels
throughout the body which is where we
start getting into the non-classical
endocannabinoid system so cb1 and cb2
are super small part of the picture
there are probably one of the most
important ones is the trip family of
receptors trip v1 the vanillin receptor
which is what capsaicin binds to in
order to make like the heat feeling is
CBD also binds to it and it binds to and
affects a lot of different trip
receptors trip receptors modulate
temperature sensation throughout the
body and so it can be really effective
for helping with pain
just like capsaicin cream is effective
for dealing with pain but without that
burning feeling which is pretty amazing
but the trip family receptors isn't
currently considered to be part of the
under cannabinoid system though that
might be changing um yeah all right
there's also other ways to manipulate
your endocannabinoid system so there's
canola mimetic compounds this is a fun
word it just means compounds that act
like cannabinoids dr. euthanise Oh
actually wrote a paper about this there
are a bunch of compounds found in a lot
of different plants that activate one or
another of the cv receptors or affect
the enzymes that break down and open
abdomen is bethe Correia Filene is
probably the most interesting of these
compounds because it is a selective cb2
agonist so talking earlier about how
things are not selectively activating c
b1 or c b2 if they activate one they
activate the other beta carrier filings
seems to only activate c b2 which is
really cool it does that at really high
dosages the the levels they were looking
at were like 25 to 50 milligrams per
kilogram which is a lot
it's like 1,200 to 33,000 milligrams of
bethe Correia filing in order to get
that effect but that's in mice tonight
humans there's also another compound
found in black pepper that I'm not even
going to try and pronounce it's a fawn
hibbott er sofa breaks down and and
amide it's released at the same time an
antivirus possible for the runner's high
makes you feel good ba breaks down gets
rid of that feeling if you inhibit Fah
an antibody sticks around for longer
which means you feel good for longer
which is really cool so black pepper
again getting both of those compounds
which is pretty amazing um people who
looked at a bunch of different plants to
look for cannabis cannabinoids in
particular it can happen with like
compounds they found one in kava kava it
seems to activate the cb1 receptor which
makes sense if you've ever had kava kava
definitely makes you feel high but not
as high as maca Fon hibbott er does that
thing again and antibiotics around for
longer longer and actually a Tanisha one
of the compounds in it is a CB 2 agonist
which means it activates those
immunomodulatory effects throughout the
body that CB 2 is responsible for so it
could be partially responsible for why
echinacea can be effective as like an
immune booster another way that you can
affect or impact year and an AB note
system electroacupuncture which is not
the most common form of acupuncture but
still fairly common will boost levels of
endocannabinoids in your systems pretty
significantly
double stress reduces and that could
have noise in your system there is a
direct correlation between cortisol and
endocannabinoids which is awesome for
Americans so if you reverse stress you
will start to elevate your levels of
endocannabinoids again so things like
meditation and yoga could help bring
endocannabinoids back up to a level as
healthy as we're most of us probably
live which is far too stressed out
I'm also interestingly massaged doubled
the amount of an android found
circulating antibody which was pretty
cool so it's not just someone like
getting really deep into those muscles
that feels good it's actually a green
being like feel happy so you know get a
massage all right other considerations
the endocannabinoids own which really
rolls off the tongue
no cannabinoid own or as Martin likes to
say the endo can have a diode which
actually does go off the tongue is that
larger system of receptors and compounds
and enzymes that cannabinoids endo and
plant-based can happen to interact with
so not just cb1 and cb2 but the trip
family of receptors there's also the
opioid receptors new and delta opioid
receptors media interacts with them
modulates them makes the opioids either
endo or synthetic work better and keep
our there's a bunch of different
receptors also found throughout your
body responsible for a lot of different
things that cannabinoids interact with
and gpcrs there are three GPC ours that
are all claimed to be the next CC b3
receptor but we'll see which one
actually wins GPR 55 is particularly
interesting I
I think it's expressed in it regulates
bone growth so an overexpression of GPR
55 is found in people with osteoporosis
which is not good
fortunately CVD is an antagonist at GPR
55 so it can help bring that down which
is pretty amazing um and on the other
hand THC seems to be an agonist at GPR
55 so you know you win some you lose
them and then GPR 18 another really
interesting cannabinoid receptor
potentially is actually THC has a
stronger affinity for GPR 18 that it
does for CB 1 or CB 2 and it could be
responsible for the anti nausea effects
that THC is sort of famous for at least
in like the chemotherapy world and new
cannabinoid tone this term is thrown
around a lot um and basically your spot
or refers to the level of receptors
ligands and enzymes that are circulating
throughout your body it is important to
be aware that this is a term that's turn
around but it's really poorly defined in
the literature basically there is likely
like a good level for all of those
things to be yet and if things are
overexpressed or under expressed then
you get dysregulation so a dysregulated
endocannabinoids system
disease most of the time okay that was a
lot of information oh oh there okay cool
I get this question all the time like
where do I learn more and there are a
couple of resources online project CVD
is one of the only ones that's
relatively accessible for people without
a scientific background and I had that
on my presentation before I worked for
project CVD I use PubMed in ResearchGate
which are the databases of scientific
white papers a lot of those things are
open source if you actually want to dig
into the science of it highly recommend
going to PubMed and checking it out type
in a new cannabinoid system to see what
comes up see what you can read online
for free it's a really amazing resource
and your tax dollars fund a lot of those
research projects so it read about them
um some researchers to keep an eye out
for when you start reading a bunch of
research names pop up again and again um
Ethan you introduced me to the
endocannabinoids system so thank you
much appreciated
uh doctor you can russo dr. john carlin
these are sort of like in order of
accessibility to vincenzo de marzo has
written extensively about the
endocannabinoids system he's based in
italy would highly recommend Rafael
Mutulu man actually a really accessible
writer he's the guy who the Lu sedated
the structure of THC in 1964 Susie
Hillard Allen Collett both amazing
researchers who have written extensively
about the in the cannabinoid system
check them out
and with that
[Applause]
all right so we've got time for a
handful of questions cool
all right so we got time for a handful
of questions so yes I looked into your
skin there's a lot of theories about how
you're seen like thins the blood brain
barrier or makes THC work better and
that is not substantiated in the
literature which is not to say that it's
not true there's just no research to
support it do you do we know has that
research not just really been done yet
yeah a lot of the research on terpenes
is based on aromatherapy studies so
these are studies where a small amount
of atropine is distributed into the air
of a room and then people are asked how
they feel this is how we know like lynn
Elul is calming because it's the most
common Trivium in lavender there are a
couple of studies looking at out turn
Ian's interact with our bodies the
pharmacology like what they do when they
get in our bodies but they're really
rare so we don't actually know a lot
about there are a lot of mercy together
had a very specific happy giggly
I mean it's foreign system and like it's
one of those things where I agree with
you there's like definitely a
correlation I mean so see you can extend
the duration of a high for sure but I'm
not sure about the metabolism of large
amounts of THC I mean anecdotally it
would appear that somehow it's being
stored in the body and not broken down
although that I'm yeah the the enzymes
that break down THC in the liver do so
in small packets but I'm not sure what
the case if that is yeah I got one for
ya so so we're all big fans of whole
plant medicine here right and so but but
CBD is not really produced whole plant
in the market very well right either
people are manufacturing it and they're
extracting with co2 which is no longer a
whole plant really and and so there you
know THC is abundant and cheap but CBD
is less oh because everybody's growing
THC for the REC side right so so now
though we've got all the CBD coming in
from the medical
market right and so people are finding
kind of a tweener to to take their
regular THC based medicine and then
spike it with CBD from him how similar
is taking CBD and spiking your whole
plant like ethanol hash alright yeah how
close to see her two whole plant does
that get as far as efficacy goes pretty
close I mean it would depend on because
whole plant medicine changes from plan
to plan we would depend on what your
extracting it from and sort of what
compounds are of interest to you but
just like a whole plant extract like
adding CPT to a whole plant extract
still retains all of the like effects of
the whole plant extract it's just it if
it was a CBD based will plant extract
you would hope that all of those things
that are already you're already taking
are in that extract as well so it would
be pretty similar I guess right so so
it's definitely worth using yes and the
question is whether or not the does
support support supporting novel
cannabinoids of CBD are also in that
other plan exactly
yeah although it does seem like THC and
CBD have a particularly synergistic
relationship there was a study that is
being done at Harvard which is amazing
so there was this study a while ago
about public speaking and how CBD
impacted the anxiety induced by public
speaking and it was effective but the
doses were like 300 and 600 milligrams
which is a lot of CBD and so people
would always cite that study as being
like Oh CBD is an anti-anxiety compound
it's like well no one's taking 300
milligrams he but Stacy Gruber at
Harvard is in the middle of a study
where she used 30 milligrams to see me
like 0.3 milligrams of THC and found
anti-anxiety effects for both chronic
and acute anxiety so an even though it's
hard to get at them in the market so far
we've actually been doing patient
studies all summer on CB G which has a
fantastic anti-anxiety Kemp component
but specifically for social anxiety and
public speaking it makes you feel
capable like you can handle this so the
first you know real commercial CVG is
being grown this summer and everywhere
this fall yes
all other most other can have a new into
that develop in the plant develops from
CVG Canada Jarrell is what it stands for
its present in higher quantities and
immature plants although now there are
breeders who are growing plants that
will only express CBG it is a secondary
cannabinoid it's not particularly well
studied yet it seems to have I mean
anecdotally anti-anxiety effects it's
also being looked at for its antioxidant
effects so it also helps lutein there on
muscular pain we're finding and the
studies that we did on match on this
summer it's really crazy because we have
this lightning of neuromuscular pain and
an increase of the feeling of capability
like I can overcome this which somehow
also helps with the pain and they're
together so sorry again it's all
anecdotal it's just us making a methyl
hash oil handing it out with
questionnaires so it's like that but CBD
is definitely also a compound of
interest for anxiety and one that has
more substantial scientific literature
associated with although you might very
much a very minor one yeah if you really
if you use an isolate of CBD regardless
of condition you might need a much
larger dose than taking something that
has a small amount of THC or a full
spectrum thank you
stay away from something
oh okay so at one point I didn't
actually touch on all fight open avenues
our anti have been shown to be
anti-inflammatory but not
pro-inflammatory only and novena boyd's
have both effects and researchers don't
really know why phyto cannabinoids plant
basically nowadays don't have a
pro-inflammatory effect they simply they
will only have an anti-inflammatory
effect on every cell so I I wouldn't not
worry too much about that yes I tried to
write an article about that so the
theory so cannabinoids are typically no
phenolic compounds they're basically
terpenes
um which might have evolved for a number
of different races so they're all
expressed in the trichomes on the flower
trichomes have also evolved for baby a
couple of different things potentially
to protect against the Sun potentially
to protect against pests a lot of
terpenes are like bitter a lot of these
compounds cannabinoids included are in a
family of compounds that are very
commonly produced by plants to regulate
a lot of systems like growth and cell
life cycles so there's any number of
reasons that they might have
[Music]
literally no idea sorry we got time for
one more question
yes sir we love Suzy but she did already
ask one so if you're pressing we can't
otherwise we'll go to Suzy but so what's
the rate coming if we were interested in
trying to get some CG how early do you
think we could pick CVG I mean you want
to try codes to develop for sure I
haven't actually worked with you eat
early picked cultivars and I don't even
think that homeworks been done yet I've
only used plant material that has been
bred specifically to only express CBG so
I think what yeah exactly so so people
have been actually doing that in in Hema
culture right now a lot picking every
week and running analytics and I mean
Jerry one weddings by so we're gonna
know a lot no more of this about a lot
we are going to know a lot more about
this after this summer yeah so so anyway
so we are gonna move on thank you boys
you
[Applause]