all right welcome everyone to the panel
so this panel is using microbes in
cannabis cultivation harnessing the
power of nature to enhance crop
productivity we have Colin Bell who is
the co-founder and chief growth officer
at gross sentía Shango votes who is the
host of shaping fire and we have the
Nate Chevallier founder of moon time
medicinals so before we get officially
started here I just want to let everyone
know that we are going to be doing a Q&amp;A
at the end of the session the cannabis
Business Summit has an app putting
download so it's just a cannabis
Business Summit Expo app from your App
Store you just tap the schedule if the
menu once it's downloaded you find this
session you can just type in microbes
and it'll come up right away and then at
the very bottom you're gonna scroll down
to the session Q&amp;A and you can submit
your questions there so you can also you
know as you're thinking about things as
they're you know as your brain juices
are flowing if you see something pops up
right away you can submit it at that
time and then when we start the Q&amp;A I'll
try to get to as many questions as
possible
all right so Nate Chevalier founder of
mid time' decimals when Nate experienced
intensity of kind but for the first time
in Des Moines Iowa his world changed
suddenly he became aware of a new world
of herb that raised the bar for quality
and experience while making ends meet
after moving to San Francisco it was
able to make connections that ultimately
led him to move to Humboldt County in
2006 on his path towards living off the
land and growing the best cannabis
freedom medicine the cannabis culture
inspired him after youth spent in a very
conventional agricultural setting they
quickly recognized the contrast between
food produced for quantity rather than
quality versus the simple rich flavor of
food and cannabis grown in an organic
setting inspired by his desire to learn
how to live on this raw piece of land
they received a permaculture design
certification in 2004 and continued his
education at college of the Redwoods
receiving a certificate in solar PV
installation and solar thermal
installation in 2016 this education has
guided him to leading a sustainable
living on his farm he is currently
focused on implementing more water
saving techniques such as huge rubicon
surrounds that build soil producing
plastic inputs and pouring chemicals by
preparing Korean natural farming
preparations such as fermented plant and
fruit juices with local resources and
working on upgrading his rainwater
harvesting system to offset the demand
on Springs that feed the South Fork eel
river an important sound and bearing
River in Humboldt County California
his passion for growing the highest
quality product drives his efforts to
grow in love with nature
yeah an amazing bio now we have gigolos
he is a lifelong cannabis enthusiast and
business strategist he found it he's the
founder of shaping fire and host of the
popular shaping fire podcast
in 2013 he founded the veteran Island
Marijuana entrepreneurs Alliance to
organized Island medicinal cannabis
producers and launched a media campaign
to increase the prestige of cannabis
producers in the community and educate
patients about the properties of
cannabis medicine to gain relief during
this time shank was also provided
business insight and brand strategy to
medicinal cannabis companies preparing
to make the transition to licensed adult
market as soon as it became legal
jano continues to be a staunch advocate
of patient access natural growing
practices sustainable business and
heritage farms
Shango is known internationally for his
extraordinary interviews with key
cannabis thought leaders and unique
understanding of cannabis businesses and
strategy shengo's YouTube channel of
exclusive cannabis presentations and
technique videos serves order over a
quarter million minutes per month you
can now view these videos at YouTube /sh
Angello's and you can check out the
shaping fire podcast at shaken fire calm
and let us leave we have Colin Beavan
co-founder Co investor and chief chief
growth officer at growth sentía Colin
completed his PhD in soil microbial
ecology in 2009 as a research scientist
at Colorado State University columnist
published dozens of peer-reviewed
publications that work focused on
elucidating microbial
processes that enhance plant growth call
when left his academic position at the
Colorado State University in March of
2015 to launch grow sincere grow Cindy
is a young startup company the egg tech
sector that develops microbial soil
additives that sustainably increased
time yield across many crops their first
product mammoth pea is a beneficial
bacteria blooms stimulant that targets
phosphorus cycling to maximize both
quality and yield in cannabis plants
thousands of producers across the
country are currently using and
reporting overwhelmingly positive
results
mammoth pee is now being sold in over a
thousand stores worldwide Colin's
academic research including long-term
multidisciplinary studies in which
biological chemical and physical
characteristics of soils were measured
to elucidate my soil microbial and plant
response to climate variability he is
more as more recent research efforts
focused on plant microbial relationships
with her I of spheres own to identify
mechanisms that may influence soil
microbial taxonomic and functional
differences among plant species prior to
earning his PhD called merge at CH
Robinson worldwide logistics as a
Regional Sales Manager knee so we have a
very exciting panel I'm going to jump
right into the questions so in a
commercial growing operation
conservation of resources including time
and money is vital changing from
traditional cannabis growing techniques
consisting of bottle salt nutrients to
nutrients to instead using holistic
growing techniques
that brings soil alive can see
differently expends there at differently
expensive in time training and changes
to operating procedures management often
resists making a switch because they're
afraid of the risk involved in doing
something differently with so much is on
the line and focusing on building
thriving microbe communities and
commercial operations substrate be
financially beneficial in addition to
just being more natural all right I
guess I've been voted to go first so
when I'm working with my clients to to
get them into the transition a lot of
times you know you've got the farmers
who have got this interest you to move
towards living soils and microbes and
and then there's somebody else with the
purse strings whose job it is to to
judge and handle risk and so very often
what I'll see is that the growers want
to go very natural because they want to
be producing your top-shelf stuff with
really wide terpene profiles that look
good in the bag and then you've got
people who are holding the purse strings
that say we wanted to keep the risk as
low as possible and so we want you to do
it the way that it's always been done
well the problem is is that the way it's
always been done has generally been
indoor or in renegade outdoor sitting
down for situations and so a lot of the
techniques that we've done in the past
with the risk assessment has changed and
so what I tell them is that if you want
to if you want to move if you want to
make this transition
and end up with a product that works
really well that you not stay on the
Shelf very long will get you a nice
price point and will also create
customer loyalty the way to go about it
is to get your soil up and going first
because once the soil is alive and
active you can use it again and again
and so now you're starting to save money
and now you're putting less money into
mechanics and and that is how you move
towards your transition trying to say
that you're going to stop your
traditional bottle nutrients our hydro
today and then tomorrow suddenly be a
probiotic micro appositive grow that's
unrealistic and and the people who are
saying that this is too risky they're
probably right and so what I always
recommend is that you start building
your soil and some extra piece of the
property that you may have and you know
get it going started inoculating there
with mycelium started inoculating with
microbe communities it was start a
separate pile for compost that you're
going to you're going to need in
overtime and so so if you're if you're a
farm that's already going to say that
you are already 215 and now you want to
kind of up your game for for an adult
rack market start small by getting your
soil going first and then that way when
you when you make your transition your
product you won't experience a dip
because a lot of folks when they when
they make a transition
from bottled nutrients and not all
bottle nutrients I'm talking about like
like salt nutrients because balance
comes in a bottle too but it but it's a
line right so it's different so the
transition you won't get this dip as
your soil gets beefy and full of life
right what you've got is soil that's
already full of life and so when you go
to grow into it the product that you get
off of it hopefully on your first cycle
will be as good or better as as the
bottle stuff you're going at have done
in the past plus the added advantage of
all the marketing win because now you're
providing a living living product and
living soil which as we all know
connoisseurs are moving towards quickly
now
I can say as far as scaling a commercial
crow to a more regenerative practice
from from you know a typical I guess
smart pot and till a man type of
application would be to start building
the soil like Shengo says and one thing
that we have found on a smaller scale
was she coaching and building your soil
with compost from your garden with for
stuff with downed tree limbs or down
brush from around the property
bringing messed up in letting it
decompose and you're building your
microbes that way we also found that
scaling of Korea natural farming is is a
challenge as well and we have started to
go with the things that are easy to say
and most I guess able to wrap your brain
around as far as when you're when you're
making
way through there and builds confidence
it makes you want to start taking on new
new challenges that's what as far as
your for me goes so on top of building
soil with with sheet mulching we also on
my farm that have been doing a lot of
Hugo culture which is an amazing way to
build your soil as again the downed
trees and rotten firewood and you're
bringing in mycelium from that you're
bringing in all kinds of stuff from from
the forest around you take it from
different areas you've got different
different biology all over the place so
that's that's the main thing I can say
is I want to add something to since I
just interviewed named for my youtube
channel I think that he also said that I
thought was really great for my clients
is that he went through his PNL and
looked at his most expensive inputs
right because when we're scaling for
commercial I mean it was one thing at
2:15 but now that you're trying to serve
as much in the country as you can those
those input prices are suddenly much
higher and he targeted those and he's
like ok how can I make this I using
Korean natural farming techniques
whatever I was trying to buy in the
bottle how can I do that with simple you
know wild crafted or you know you know
if you're a big operation you might not
have time to send team in to the florist
again stuff but you can order things
online that you can then make your own
at a fraction of the price using a
Korean natural farming fermenting
techniques that other people just by the
bottle
yeah
so I think the perspective that I bring
to this is thinking about from a
scientific perspective understanding
knowing it's a fact that microbes and
biology and these natural inputs are
beneficial and probably needed for
agriculture the movement that we tried
to address as scientists at the
University was understanding after years
decades of studies showing how chemical
inputs are declining soil health
declining microbial diversity is so
declining soil ability to sustain plant
life and that was a huge problem so our
goal was to figure out how to scale
bridge that gap and bring nature and
natural processes back to agriculture we
think of cannabis farming as an
agriculture doing that requires a lot of
steps and it all comes down to scale the
thing on the size of a farm I think
that's one of the biggest challenges
farming cannabis farming in general has
these days I've been to some huge farms
just over the last couple of days and
all we talk about a scale yeah they're
using microbes there's no question and
even a couple years ago this might have
been different I worked with people all
over the world in the black market and
in this market and through the Americas
and Europe in Australia and it's less
known about the benefits of microbes in
some of the other countries it's new
it's really hydroponic and so I'm
writing articles and letting people
understand why you can how you can plug
microbes into these agricultural
management practices even if it is high
up life in that
so that so there's this huge education
gap don't you get beyond that it turns
into a scalability I think in a perfect
world we want to mimic nature there's no
plant in nature that can survive without
the microbes and these natural nutrient
cycling processes about about a full
slow up and living soil that is really
difficult for some facilities to do if
you have multiple acre size greenhouses
and you're pushing out hundreds of
thousands of plants and pots it's not
really the structure that nature and
living soil thrives in and so I think
it's about understanding your
limitations understanding what you are
capable of implementing and scaling that
in many cases it's a huge win for even
these larger or huge cannabis
cultivators to understand Wow microbes
were good and they're looking at the
products of the technology I plug in
with efficacy and effectiveness meaning
efficacy they work really really well in
the different soils in the different
environment they've created and
effectiveness they're actually showing
consistent results increase quality
increased yield that's what we want we
want to distinguish we want to maximize
our clients phenotypic potential we
cannot do that my opinion with just
chemical fertilizers we can take the
plants so much further if we introduce
some other additives
I heard interactions however it's not
only inputs I think that's really
important it's also about workflow it's
also about space and all these things
that have this larger scale cost a time
of capital to support and so I think
it's really is a process of where we are
now looking at all the different
verticals of benefits and understanding
over time how to plug them in that scale
where we can meet economic and in in a
lot of the big businesses I deal with
now canvas cultivation businesses
they're looking at the full spectrum all
the verticals of cost the labor cost the
intra cost the album costs and they're
measuring all those costs along with the
return how much yield am I getting how
much quality am I getting is that
quality and yield metric averaging out
for or worth all this other labor and
all these other instruments personally
I'd love to see the movement going this
way I do think that it's a balance and
that every decision we make there's
trade-offs that we make and so
incorporating what makes sense now and
having a vision of how we could make
that better is I think how agriculture
moves it's how this industry is moving
it's moving relatively fast I'll close
on this topic by saying you know the use
of microbials and microbial a stimulant
some more
the formal term is the quickest growing
agriculture input segment across every
crop globally it's because it's
necessary farmers across many many
different crops have understood that
they literally hit a wall in some way
some people tournament chemical
fertilizers of Aldus not saying that
chemical fertilizers don't work saying
that they've hit their limits and
they're looking for catalyst and
microbes and other natural solutions to
allow plants to continue to grow a
little to maximize the yield to maximize
nutrient use efficiency the nutrients we
put into the soil into the substrate
should be taken up by the plant in in
many cases some nutrients to have about
30% efficiency meaning we have a lot of
unused fertilizer that builds up from
here up here in the soil and that's why
we think biology as a solution help
balance that out
all right thank you so much of the
market for flour is based on bag appeal
and many consider frosty flowers and
intense coloration to be the best result
or to be the result of intense synthetic
nutrients so what can commercial scale
growers do to create frosty flowers with
great bang appeal while also respecting
the health of substrate microbe
communities
yeah so something for her back appeal
that we do on our farm is we have
microbes in we do compost tea we do
another microbe inoculation is called OG
bile or it's filled with all kinds of
good stuff and we also employ water
saving techniques we feel that making
the plant a little water deprived
actually makes it produce more terpenes
and more cannabinoids so we have gone to
a irrigation system that essentially
gives the plant just as much water as it
desires no more and no less and we're
finding that the the product that's
coming out of it looks amazing and some
of the stuff that we're getting ready to
take down after after this this light
death this looks better than the stuff
that we've ever ground not necessarily
the biggest flowers but definitely the
sexiest and hopefully the best-tasting
so those are some of the things I could
point to
so since I know that polish my going to
talk about inputs to I'm actually going
to go a different route about this and
say something that is generally
unpopular with my clients when I tell
them it and it's two things number one
you know especially when you're talking
to fanboys people talk about the frosty
nuts right and super frosty flowers are
the sexiest things and and if they're
all white they're perfect and this is
like being addicted to steroids where
the muscles there the muscles are better
and that's just untrue I think that the
market is going to eventually become
more educated over the next decade and
realize that just because of flowers
frosty does not make it ultra premium
and what you want I will absolutely take
something that is less frosty that has
less trichomes but has the the powerful
terpenes that come from full spectrum
sunshine and has been fed with an array
of compost teas and microbes and other
living environments you know soils and
other substrates that worms can actually
live in and that the challenge with this
of course is that it takes more labour I
was talking with the guy a couple weeks
ago and you know Expo nearby here in San
Francisco and he was talking to me he's
asking me for hints for his forty acre
hydro greenhouse in Sacramento Valley
and I'm all and think of my first self
like I'm
the guy you want to be talking to you
because all I'm gonna be telling you is
tears right you know I'm not the guy
who's me saying the things that you want
to hear but what I'm generally telling
people other than 40 acres you know
bring back the one acre cap other than
that what I continue to tell people is
spend less money on your mechanical
overhead and spend more money on actual
human staff who know how to grow and
have them be near the plants there's
nothing that is going to impact the
plants afterward you give it good inputs
then the hand of the grower and being
attentive to it all the time
and even though you know a lot of the
people they're looking at they're PL
they're all like you need to put in
watering systems there's still nothing
like and watering not only for the plant
to get the right amount of water but
more importantly to put the grower in
the proximity of the plant more often to
take care of it regularly there's a
ancient Chinese proverb that I'm gonna
probably in a poorly paraphrase that is
the best fertilizer for a plant is the
growers shadow right or the growers
footsteps so you get the idea and yet
and that is one thing about scaling and
you know this convention is clearly all
about scaling that I often recommend to
scale less spend more money on your
natural and human inputs like how humans
as an input and that is how you can
start to make this transition to a
higher quality product that will fly off
the shelves because it's so great and
bring people back for more because the
question is done would you buy this
product once the question is would you
buy it again and there's not a lot of
stuff that I would
a second time that's not growing
properly under the Sun in living soil in
in smaller matches with dedicated humans
[Applause]
I think you know I can't really relate
to the frosty buzz comment as much as
the quality I travel all over the world
I work with people all over the world
are cultivating and in the u.s. there is
that try and call me frosty but faint
but everywhere else in the world
people are asking me about the turkeys
and smell and I was talking to another
grower just yesterday we had a great
conversation he's a little partner a
little south of here and we talked about
this overall experience he can almost
relate it to maybe someone outside of
this industry to a meal you know you
have this experience that sits with you
and if you have a wonderful meal at a
restaurant this is a sign example you're
coming back because it really did it for
you and you get there you see this plate
of food that you wanted and it looks
great and it smells great and also it
tastes great and you have this effect
it's all these senses that you're
getting invoked by that experience it's
the same thing this guy was relating and
he's been around for a long time he was
talking about back in the 80s and 90s
it's like you know I would try and check
all those boxes with my customers they
would get a bag for me they look and I'd
see their eyes brighten up and look
isn't flour and kind of expected then
they would smell it then they would
actually taste it and get that nice
experience and then they experience the
results from it consuming and he said I
can tick all the boxes with that
customer I had it for life that can
really relate to that it has very little
to do honestly even with THC there's so
much THC that you could almost get now
it's about this full flavor this full
experience and I'll say these verticals
are not any one thing there's a whole
management that you can maximize what I
like to call the plants phenotypic
potential when I go into a dispensary to
talk to my friends I don't look for the
strongest flower I look for the flower
that's nice and smooth and it tastes
like it smells and I can have a nice
experience so I know what I'm looking
for it's really that quality you know
the th C's that are relevant to me I
think there's so many different levels
is just what it is
and what does that mean what are those
verticals you know plants determined by
genetics let's Eclipse base that there's
a genetics vertical that's critical to
get that plant a genotype and phenotype
for what you want and different
phenotypes have different
characteristics and that's why we
breathe phenotypes because we want
different characteristics in those
plants so we breed that there's this
whole climate variability where we have
to control their climate in the corona
environment because that strongly
dictates the health and the outcome of
that plan there's inputs which I have an
input tag more than anything else that's
what I understand that includes
nutrients in microbes and nourishing the
claim to the best of its ability if the
plane can take up all the nutrients it
needs naturally and that's the third
facilitation with biology and the
availability of nutrients are living
soil is going to be able to
sighs its health development quality and
yield it can do these things and then
there's this last vertical bit very few
people talk about now it's fascinating I
went to a facility yesterday morning and
this is a big-time deal they've build a
million-dollar curing room felt like
that's where half of the quality is
getting lost a lot by back in after the
harvest
okay you're probably right let me ask
the other people that has put things in
bags and you know I see a degree to
almost immediately I see a degree that's
not almost immediate but that's the
example it's just really an important
part of quality and it maintains not
only the THC and the CBD profiles but
the flavor and those terpene profiles
I'll tell you what I can't say enough
about these therapies I'm just obsessed
with it and everything that we test with
our product and the P is a microbial
product we're focused on quality we know
we can increase you know a lot of great
products do that but if we can't bring
quality with it or exceed quality you
know I think we're really missing the
main point and that's what we really
focus on so maximizing the plants
phenotypic potential for that flavor and
that full experience from the moment you
see it to experiencing it through smell
taste and the ultimate feeling so that's
a that's a big
picture of how I think about the clan
and how we can kind of tweak those
different verticals to maximize that the
genetics really I like that
maximizing genetic potential okay great
so I do see some questions rolling in
we're not quite there yet but I just
wanted to remind people in case they
came in a little bit later that the
cannabis Business Summit has an app you
just download it from the App Store and
then once it's downloaded each have
schedule from the menu and to find this
session type in my growth it will come
up right away for you and then just
scroll down and tap on the session Q&amp;A
and then you're able to submit your
questions right there
and then I get them on my phone right
here so we'll be absolutely as many of
those as we can any moment here when we
get to that section all right so yeah I
actually I totally agree that you know
in 10 years from now blinking flowers
people only talking about that at all
it's not even gonna be it's not even
gonna be a thing
so outdoor growing in native soils has
become increasingly popular due to
cannabis normalization what is a
regenerative practice or try tired
native soils that notes or cannabis
growers can use to reject rejuvenate
local soils instead of merely growing
indoors in bags or outdoors in bags of
shipped in soil I think this is really
really important
so I guess I'm just gonna throw my
science card out here and talk about
healthy soil and what that means to me
is the scientists and I might have to
talk about card you know in carbon but
frankly is the currency of life here on
earth all carbon-based
everything revolves around carbon
instead of soil health and if you look
at healthy Silver's is not healthy so on
you can talk about it fertility
perspective or about a diversity
perspective you can see a very strong
correlation based on the amount of
carbon that's in s so it's a cation
exchange capacity its ability to hold
soil and hold nutrients and it's all too
new harder and so if you look at that as
a metric for success or soil health you
can really dial in with a large degree
of success how successful you're going
to be in using soils to grow here
planting the why I'm bringing carbon up
is you can add carbon simply it's really
hard to manage and turn the natural soil
at the greatest loss of natural soil you
know and a growing season or any year
already been in a decade soils of all
over decades
just natural if you take pretty
extensive steps to build up the soil you
can get there a lot quicker and these
guys at the panel of experts effect and
I like to do that in at my home and
building so a lot of pretty fascinated
by that but if you're really trying to
take steps where you could manage and
work with the soil and take the right
steps to build that make it healthier
you know there are simple things like
even I call it carbon black but it's
just a burnt carbon and everyone's using
right now just to create cation exchange
capacity you can add microbes you can
add all sorts of carbon to mix in to
help sustain soil health and start
building that up
so to the carbon thing we have with the
Hyuga culture mounds we have tried to
sequester as much of the carbon on our
property that is just laying around as
possible and to the birch or the biochar
is what we're also using as well to
increase our CC and we feel that while
this year is very challenging and we
have a lot of wood underneath our Hubel
mounds that next year as the rains hit
in the fall and and moving forward that
wood is gonna break down and it's gonna
break down into beautiful rich black
soil and we're really excited about our
that goes we also are creating our own
biochar we're burning some wood and
putting it out and doing the hardwoods
and then adding it into our soil as well
so as far as those two things go I can
definitely attest to
amazing as far as doing her you're
living so illios and then the compost
tea just to get it to get it working and
moving
all right so so I'm gonna take one
position and I'm going to tell you why
it's wrong so the position that I picked
up for the first time I answered was
that I'm a probiotic person who believes
in living soil and so if you want to
regenerate your property you are going
to want to cover that sweetheart with
compost cheese grab yourself some some
cheap M seeds for fiber hem and plant
them and everywhere plant some other
companion plants and not so much for for
pests necessarily but other plants that
are targeted for the kind of soil that
you have so they can start building up
life and carbon and nitrogen in the soil
and and and and take you the take this
neglected ground make it alive again and
then plant it your next season with your
your commercial crop the problem is is
that you know I'm a probiotic guy but I
also study business plans and I also
give business advice and we're in
California and none of you have time to
leave your property fallow for a year
and let this happen right so my first
suggestion to clients is don't buy
crappy property you should be in there
ahead of time get soil tests find out
where the floodplain is talk to local
farming neighbors find out why the
people before you dump to the property
don't get stuck with a bad piece of dirt
that you can't work do your work on in
the first place
now with
said you know their margins are so tight
and everything is so hyper competitive
in California while while using these
solutions totally work and that's where
my heart is right I love a permaculture
guy at heart but I also don't want my
clients to go out of business because
they have you know birds an important
season going through their their capital
trying to regenerate the soil so so I
know it's kind of a different approach
to the question but but my goal would be
don't buy bad property to begin with and
do your homework upfront and choose
property that you can do your magic on
to begin with I think there's a balance
we can have goals and I think it's
absolutely right it's really hard to sit
on a property for a year or ten years
and say hey in ten years this is going
to be great and until then soon enough
money in the building of us will I have
no return that's not practical and it's
not realistic but if you have a goal
this is what this needs to look like you
can incorporate and scale reasonable
inputs to get your soil built a better
year after a year and you know there's a
lot of great examples where you can get
additive improvements through management
they're extra plants through cover
cropping through you know getting
leggings and they ground our clothes in
the ground we're actually fixing
nitrogen delivering nitrogen through
different plants right into soil to
enhance more loud diversity more carbon
microbes are carbon just like you know
there's a lot of different solutions
that are out there and it's about
figuring out what's practical with
scaleable and what's the now solution so
you can keep doing your business keep
growing and regenerate the way you want
to let's continue to build towards that
I think those are realistic ways to
accomplish you know everything we need
to maintain soil health and maintaining
I got another tweener idea actually
which is a good idea to sometime take a
look at things in to black and white but
the other thing you can do is you can do
your first season or two in bags or pots
of some sort
and be working on the soil while you're
doing that you know you can even have
your rows of pots and you can be hitting
the ground with companion plants and
with compost teas and different types of
can affirmance around the bags and so
maybe in two or three years when you're
feeling that now now the soil around the
bags
right now you can now you can give up
the bags and go right into the soil and
kind of like grow into where you want to
be so so that would be realistic as well
all right great
so what challenges can a farmer trying
to employ regenerative practices expect
to encounter
so the biggest thing that we found is
trying to try to scale our labor away
from the traditional I guess farming and
going into the more natural bringing in
your own inputs type thing and it's been
it's been tough we we scaling up to
Arcana we decided that we need about one
gallon of each input that we're using
currently a week and so we have scaled
up to our pickling crocks rather than
our little pint jars to make our
ferments with local plants fruits we're
doing lactic acid bacteria from a goat
farmer that's that's local to us we
could really Chico them from her and
getting these things to be ready when
we're ready for them as has been a
little bit difficult but so what we're
doing is each week we're trying to make
a new input and sourcing the the plants
has been really easy the thing that we
found challenging on our property was
sourcing fruits for the Fuhrman
fermented fruit juice so we got berries
and stuff around the property is really
good but we also had to go to just other
parts of the flowering plant and
actually just take in the flowering
we've also started fermenting horse teas
a really good one for for silica and for
your powdery mildews and your diseases
but we also started doing thistles
because it's a very very hearty plant
shows very little resistance or I'm
sorry a very high resistance to s
pathogens any of that stuff so
fermenting that we're trying to pass
that into our plants and we found really
really good results with it and it's
it's making our plants tick off as far
as the Hyuga culture and and sheep mulch
egos we have plenty of biomass around
our property the biggest problem is
getting it to where we needed we would
want to we live on a really steep
incline and
from one place to the other has been
challenging so those are a couple of the
things I can think of also we I think
Shenko mentioned earlier check out the
piano we had noticed that our piano one
of the biggest things that we had going
was earthworm castings we were spending
a ton of money every year on earth on
casting so we decided to scale up our
earthworms and we're trying to produce
as much earthworm castings as we use on
a yearly basis which is about six or
seven yards so scaling up to that has
been challenging trying to find enough
of the right material for the worms to
to eat and create a really nice rich
earthworm casting that's been a
challenge for us the list goes on and on
to be completely honest but those are a
couple of the big ones
so I'd only getting it on one because
Nate's right maybe the list of things
that can go wrong with probiotics is
long but you know they're the list of
things that can go wrong with hydro as
long as well what we are talking about
as a craft here right and so if you are
better at one side of the craft than the
other you know if you're if you're a
hydro guide and those are the things you
know you know doing the transition going
that way it's going to be harder if you
took me and put me in a hydro
environment I would probably have a
learning curve as well and that's why I
would say the primary challenge is
education and experience because all
three of us are here to tell you that
that these natural inputs will replace
thin lines on your piano that are
costing you a lot of money that you can
replace with just a little bit of effort
and a little bit of wild crafted or
purchased nutrients but you need to have
the education to know what they are and
what the processes are and they're not
hard right but something something that
might just have a six step process you
need to know what those six steps are
and when when you're your upper
management and your investors are going
like hop to it we don't see anything
going on yet and you're like we go I'm
getting educated so there are things
metals yeah you know they're pushing you
to get it done now and you're like well
listen if we want to do this right we
need to make sure that we have the
education because you know you just like
needs talking about with the crocks
right you can have a ferment going and
there are a lot of things that can go
wrong with a Furman you know the first
time I made some of these things it took
me two tries and because they take a
while to ferment you can make a mistake
that that only costs you like six bucks
and inputs but it cost you two months
and time right and so the primary
mistake or the
Challenge I think is the question it
would be education and experience and I
see that there's only really two ways
that you can get that number one hire
really well hire somebody who already
has probiotics can have living soils mic
building micro communities find somebody
who already has that under their belt so
they can hit the ground running and I
gotta tell you there's not a lot of
those people at the professional level
who can also scale out you know five
thousand plants or whatever your number
is right there's a lot of those folks
that are doing 50 plants or their
basement right there you know these
these these folks are all over the
internet however finding those same
people that can scale up to the
commercial size that you're needing to
be able to make margins in California
those people are very rare so be
prepared to pay them what they're worth
because when the cat gets out of the bag
on board this is somebody else is going
to want to steal them away from you or
the second solution is build that
education into it you know give your
give your master growers some extra time
to do continuing education just like any
professional train you don't expect
every professional to know everything
every year that's why we've got
continuing education for mental
healthcare professionals and for lawyers
and like you know so so build in
education time for the grower and make
them do it right because they're gonna
want to please you and they may choose
to like skip their education because
they're feeling under a lot of pressure
make them do
continuing education and let them make
some of this mistakes with their
ferments and build in that into it and
let them take time to to take their
staff and train them so that if staff
people see something going wrong with a
ferment or a plant or whatever is going
on you know they couldn't see something
say something right and they but but
that only works if you're if you're you
know you're your lowest person on the
chain knows what's going on has been
taught by the top person in the chain so
education and experience is clearly the
biggest challenge that I see because a
lot of this stuff is old ancient tech
that's being brought back and it doesn't
mean that anybody knows that we've all
been in doors we're going under
artificial lights of artificial
nutrients for all these years and we're
swinging back so don't just assume that
it's going to be done without challenge
yeah and I agree with all that I think
that's just continue to comment on it's
a process
since scale is key I mean an example I
was singing that one classes those guys
taught us now is you know we have a girl
you know we have a 62 acre farm we have
several 5,000 square-foot greenhouses a
10,000 square foot greenhouse mostly for
high CBD half but we do mostly
agronomics agriculture because we want
to understand plants and Kapinos and
genotypes and exactly what there
we're trying to develop and we have some
high THC farms also for research
purposes and it's the same thing it's
all agriculture research as a as a
research scientist I work with a lot of
different plants it's really hard
understand plant microbe interactions if
you don't apply to work with that's been
a challenge that's why we've got these
licenses entry' invested in one of my
growers head girl reason he's awesome he
has amassed his green hydroponics and
he's really smart they need a lot of
hydroponics and I love using microbes in
soil and living soil and that's enough
and you know he's our teammate he's on
the team is in the company and he'll
tell me straight up and then we're gonna
do that through Colin I'm not your guy
for that I don't understand it I'm like
I understand the scale and the truth is
there's this time life period where you
know the way he's doing things is really
efficient and he can bust out a lot of
productivity the way he's doing but
that's not the living soil away it's not
even a soil way there's so many
challenges and it's such a learning
curve there's not enough people that
know how it works and understand the
biology and all the interesting things
like even hydrology you think there's a
difference in hydrology between cocoa
and living soil yeah it's the level
watering regime is 100% different here
have to experiment with that along with
everything else this is all everything
changes and it takes time it's really
hard to run a business and want to
continue to produce on a cycle cycle
cycle and introduce something that
drastic and so it definitely takes the
right person it takes flying across the
board and takes that commitment probably
from will talk from the money guys down
to say hey this is who we are this is
what we're going to do and we might not
do this vertically across the world but
we're going to have a component we're
going that direction in invest money cuz
it takes time it takes money it takes
the right people and those are all big
topics to buy into so you know again
it's a process and you think about this
last point influence you know it's
pretty easy to source inputs for a
hundred points easiest source if it's
for a thousand planes well if you're
trying to knock out a hundred thousand
place
that's a whole different game until you
have those channels and you can bring
those things in ultimately that scale is
where you want to be but all the growing
pains and the scaling between then is
painful and super expensive and that's
where you're going to lose a lot of the
momentum from let's just called the
business guys they're kind of lonely see
that going they want to see profit you
know let's see all that cost if you
still agony of the things which you're
going to see you have to educate not
only internally and the practice and the
biology you have to educate everyone in
your company saying this is what this
looks like these are the expectations
and productivity expectations if we're
transitioning this way so by an
across-the-board is critical it's easier
at the home of our family farm it's hard
if you have a corporation you have a
whole bunch of people that are building
out a large large commercial cultivation
facility we need visionary leaders at
that
all right thank you so much so I'm gonna
try to there's some that are kind of
similar so I'm going to try to I'm gonna
have to select them so what do you look
for when comparing between products with
microbes what is your opinion on
products with many microbes in them do
they compete with each other you know my
perspective do you think about nature
tens of thousands of microbes interact
together with fungi and bacteria and
they do this in a very beneficial way
and that's just the natural way so
that's not necessarily a challenge I
would think what I what I think the
bigger challenge of using microbes is
understanding what they do you know I
think a lot of people think of microbes
and beneficial use those terms
beneficials but do you know what
microbes do do you understand the
functional groups do we actually
understand how many people really
understand what mycorrhizal our best of
the right mike rosa lungile
how do they work yeah so this is a great
audience for that so if you know what
they are you know the functional group
then you know how to apply them in
practice and you can use them correctly
if you don't understand how they're
functioning you don't understand their
limitations it's very hard to use them
and so I think that's the biggest
disconnect over all communities of
microbes live together again tens of
thousands of microbes in much more so
that's not the issue you all obviously
have to have that experience
there's no antagonistic group so it just
in like in my in my experience more rare
than not there's way more beneficial
microbes that wasn't the one beneficial
microbes in nature then there are any
pathogens or anything so microbes like
to work there's just part of nature you
know what are you from back yogurts do
what are differents a prophetic ones
occurs to all these questions I
understand that microbe understand micro
functional group understand their
limitations once you understand what
these groups do you can use them with
precision and confidence and that's kind
of what we're trying to do this is all
panel we're understanding educating and
supporting that movement through
deploying microbes with confidence of
precision over but not all microbes work
in every circumstance and that all
functional groups are good for all plant
health benefits different microbes do
different things to benefit plants of
different ways so I think it's again
comes down to an education camp I don't
buy a lot of products but my clients do
on my small patient grow at my home I
just make everything I make my compost
teas I make my ki inputs I just make
them and so I don't buy it but people
who rely on my opinion do spend a lot of
money on it and I tell them two things
number one if you've got your product
that you think you're going to want to
buy go to their website and almost
everybody has got a picture of their
label right so you can get a very
specific breakdown of what's in it then
go ahead and pour yourself a cocktail or
smokeable and then Google every one of
those inputs and learn what they are
you're gonna make yourself a better
person at your job you will be way more
interesting at cocktail parties and you
will know that product inside and out
and if you choose to buy it you will
know why you're gonna buy it
plus you'll notice
as you go through a couple of these
products in the same product category
you'll find that different products have
got something more than others so if
something costs a little bit more
you'd be like oh I see why it costs more
because it's got this one product in it
that I know things that we commedia what
it actually does so don't be short on
your homework and number two if you are
scaling at a commercial size the get
past the marketing people at the before
you had really commit to a product in
your farm call the company and it has to
be taught ask to talk to their Colin
right and find out what the science is
all about they want to talk to you
especially if they think that you're
gonna buy a ton of this every year
forever right then they're dying for
your money so call them up and say hey
I've got this position at this company
we are thinking about going in there
like 55-gallon barrel size of your
product and and I'd love to have you
know twenty thirty minutes of your time
to talk about it with with the
scientists right you get them on the
phone and you tell them that and you say
pitch me the science they're gonna be so
elated to talk to you it's going to be
crazy when you're done with your
internet research and after talking to
that person you will be able to buy that
product or a competitor's product with
confidence knowing that you're doing it
the right way yeah thing I could say
mainly is that I more of the better for
microbes we try to employ as many as we
can into our soil and
even the highest concentration that we
can find what I did find is trying to
use multiple micro blinds is that there
was a lot of repetition so I think
that's the number one thing to be
cautious of if you're going with
different brands is just make sure that
you have a variety and you're not going
with the same microbes over again this
is good you guys are answering some of
the questions on here without me having
to ask them so that's really helpful
we don't mind exactly but so does
implementing a thriving soil environment
pose a threat to biosecurity of an
indoor grill implementing a thriving
soil environment pose a threat to
biosecurity of an indoor grill so if
you're trying to have healthy living
soils indoors is there going to be a
threat to try to biosecurity so I only
would have one example for that and that
is if you are making your compost teas
inside and they have got some sort of
manure a compound component because when
you're making compost teas or you're
fermenting you're essentially incubating
right so you're taking your source
material and you're giving it an
environment so the life gets you know
like 2 times 3 times 100 times X right
and if you've got the e.coli in there
suddenly your compost tea is going to be
very very dangerous and so I'm not a big
fan of putting manures in my compost
teas I love worm castings but but I will
add that stuff
separately something that has not been
incubated but as far as I heard the
question that would be the only thing
that would jump for me the only thing I
could think of do is indoors and making
compost teas would just be the chlorine
dr. Walter that's the number one thing I
can think of is just making sure that
that's out of there that's gonna hurt
your biology more than anything as far
as I know indoors and just add to that I
think I think that's Drupal I'll
reiterate what I said you know most
microbes are good but there are some
pathogens out there mostly associated
with legal material that coliforms
e.coli Salmonella and we want to be
careful of those and when we're working
with microbes especially in a compost
tea I love compost teas the only
criticism I would have this is an
academic criticism it's a little bit of
an unknown we don't know what's growing
in those every time almost always get
good result but if you test them it's
gonna be different
almost every single time because there's
variability with seasonality with the
open environment I'm a microbiologist
having berlanger
a long long time and I could reliably
make the same compost every time just if
I didn't have a clothes dedicated
sterile system to do that and we just
don't do that I've seen them open so
that's just a little uncertainty and
they know we are having this consistency
and consistent in goods and defined
inputs really mitigates at risk there's
the biosafety or the bio whatever that's
that's not a challenge another person
asked me once a couple people did you
know bacteria actually in fact the roots
and go up into the flowers and some
states are actually bacterial see if you
counts that you have to test for the
flower that's a real challenge in some
of these states you have to be be aware
I wouldn't use concentrated microbial
products as all their applications
especially during bloom maybe in veg no
longer than that because your your
engineering higher bacteria on the leaf
tissue and that's gonna that's gonna
measure and that's gonna read and so
that is putting your facility in your
flower rest calendar if you can deliver
microbes in the soil or I think you know
99.99 nectar so that my group to do well
they interact with roots it's where
they've evolved it's where they lived
they were involved in plants and so if
you can get them in the soil you're
gonna have a thriving healthy
environment that the plant will respond
to very positively
you know the microbes colonize the world
back here in particular hundreds of
millions of years ago
you know they created an environment for
plants to evolve plants have always
lived
well I think it's interesting is to
provide that agriculture let's have a
healthy living microbial community or
living soil that the plants can engage
with because it does show good results
for you know by Health and you
awesome thank you so much
[Applause]
you