hey everybody shango from shaping fire
here with our friend nick reisden i'm
here visiting my folks in michigan today
and nick and i have been wanting to get
together for a long time because um as
many of you know
nick is a lime patient and he's pretty
much trail blazed
using um uh concentrated cannabis oil
that we mostly know as rso
when fighting lyme disease and so we've
been talking about this for a couple
years and i asked him i said hey man why
don't we uh
record something so that you know we can
get his best practices out to everybody
so here we are on a
beautiful fall michigan day cold so
anyway nick thanks for making time dude
absolutely good to see you brother good
to see you all right so um so let's
start at the top man um you know when
when we first started talking about it a
few years ago the reason it came up was
because you said um you know
long time cannabis guy but that you had
come across a particular rso that like
was a total game changer for you and
caused you to like go down this new path
so why don't we start there tell me tell
me about like this first time you had an
rso that told you that oh man i can use
this to treat my line
well
you know the first time was kind of the
story i told you about
going to a dispensary and all that and
raw juicing cbd
and
i never believed in
marijuana as as medicine per se but
after i got
bit by the tick and landed and i was in
icu for a month i was four years ago in
kentucky
they had up me on so many medications
that
at one point i was up to 71 medications
a day and even if one of them worked how
would you really know on that level
which wasn't the cross contaminations of
stuff and i explained to you inside like
when i first got sick four years ago i
believed
in doctors and in hospitals that you get
sick and that they're gonna treat you
but i was the first case of hwasong
virus meningococcal encephalitis
infection kentucky had ever seen i was a
75th case since 1908
and i was the first one to live through
it so they they didn't know what to do
and they experimented on me and in
kentucky there was no medical cannabis
so they would put me on prescription
drop and all you know there was 400 for
10 pills of synthetic thc
i'm on
all that medicine and
you know the seizures started hardcore
after all the iv antibiotics from you
know i was in the hospital of june and
then they had me going back to the
hospital all july for iv rocephin and
when that stopped
this seizure started and i'd never had
cedars before
i had uh
read some information about cbd oil and
i'd read some information about
this rick simpson oil stuff that and
i've been in cannabis my whole life but
i never really believed in medical
cannabis so
we come up to michigan to a dispensary
not a friend with medical card
and i remember every
part of this story with with my brain
injury the way it is but this was so
remarkable to me
that we we drove all the way up here we
got here at night we went to the
dispensary i couldn't go in because i
couldn't go into the back because i
didn't have a medical card but i said in
the front and they had a raw juice bar
and had cbd
that they would add to the raw juice
now that was my first experience ever
with cbd now at the time i shook
uncontrollably
i almost have an ms um
and i had light phobia which i still
have but not but not to that extent that
even at night watching tv i'd have to
wear sunglasses because from
encephalitis and meningitis light would
would burn
this lady gave me a raw juice cannabis
shot while we're sitting there so just
micro greens with some cbd and
i took it and a couple seconds later
shannon reached over and touched my
elbow like this and she said you're not
shaking
and when she said that i lowered my
sunglasses to look at my hands
and i wasn't shaking and the light
caught my eyes and it wasn't burning my
eyes
that was the exact moment when i'm like
oh
cannabis is medicine i
for for being in this for years and
never truly believing that cannabis was
medicine i explained this to you earlier
like you smoke a joint like to lower
stress or i believe
cancer patients smoked marijuana or
something that gave them appetite
so
uh he gets me some rso there it happened
to be bubba kush rso
well
one of the big issues with me was
sleeping you know you're in so much pain
you're hurting you're vomiting around
the clock you're having seizures
i introduced this um you know just a
0.1 milligrams of rso in the beginning
just like a little dot on the side of
the plastic capsule
[ __ ] i slept for 12 straight hours and
if you sleep you hear it allows the
antibiotics which i do believe in
to actually do their job and start to
let me heal and i was sleeping so much
in recovery
but oh i skipped over a very vital thing
there i told you this earlier inside
that after we did the raw juice shot
i'd lost 80 pounds
we left the dispensary i went to a pizza
place
and ate half half three quarters of a
pizza and hadn't done that since i got
sick and i'm like okay
i'm not shaking my eyes aren't hurting
and i just got appetite and that was
just from cbd
and then the bubba kush was the first
start that actually
uh it gave me sleep
um
and it gave me pain control that indica
and everything and
i was just
consumed with this well i'm in kentucky
and
i have seven felonies from growing in
2003.
in kentucky i have a grandma or so as a
fellow
so
you know i'm very adamant you know how i
am i talk about what i believe in and i
trained police dogs for
15 years so that kind of made it
difficult and uh
um
you know uh uh there was a politician
matt daley and the secretary of state in
kentucky alice in london grimes they
wanted to push medical cannabis four
years ago for the kentucky patients so
they used my story
and they made me uh kind of the face of
that and i fought for it in kentucky and
when it failed i'd kind of out of myself
you know again and
i moved instantly to michigan
so that i could
access our ssr so and be able to access
even then i'm looking at strain
specifics i smoke a joint of bubba kush
i feel a certain type of way i smoke a
joint a kosher kush i feel a certain
type of way different strains do
different things
kosher kush you can give me that joint
blind in a bowl of joints and if i smoke
kosher kush i'm eating in 30 minutes
there's not there's there's a handful of
strings that actually do that to me give
me an appetite
so
moving up to michigan it was about
i need to grow as many different strands
i can cook them all down to see which
ones are working the best for my
individual needs at individual times
and that's what all research went to
and i moved up here
uh three and a half years ago
and
one day i'm sitting uh i'm in my grow
room and i'm alone i mean i'm i'm born
and raised kentucky
um all my friends and family there i was
very lonely up here shannon had to stay
at our dog kennel in kentucky because we
had a lot of farm animals we couldn't
just up move everything um
so i listen to podcasts around the clock
and
you know i'm trying to learn
how to grow again to the level that i'm
doing and i'm trying to go into organics
not synthetics which i've done for my
whole life
and i came across you and i didn't know
you from adam and
that the particular podcast was uh
you and me and gene from
mendocino talking about
powdery mildew resistant strains
and then i go
i i delve down the hole more because i'm
um
i've got youtube there so i'm listening
to it non-stop you know and i'm i'm
listening different grow videos and you
find some very amateurish grow videos
and then when you find something that is
professional i'm like this kevin jones
or
you and then you're interviewing this
kevin jodrey guy and i started listening
to this kevin joder god i'm like the
smartest dude i've ever heard talk about
anything period and
you're out there uh like to take you
mentally back this is when you were like
doing your podcast like green bicycles
and some with kevin jones are you doing
those little segments where you do like
ten segments yeah the live session
yeah and
i listened to every one of the breeders
series that kevin jodrey did yeah that
was the first thing i sponsored really
yeah do you know that i grew seeds from
every single guy in that breeders series
oh that's awesome
well some of them are actually like
friends friends talk to on the phone
multiple times a week and things like
that
that changed my life like your podcast
that that well anyway let me scale back
so
jackson is talking about
the mean gene from mendocino was talking
about powdery mildew resistant strains
and i'm looking at this from a sick
person that got
lyme disease and meningitis poison
disease uh meningitis
babisia bartonella uh rocky mountains uh
rocky mountains uh
fever spotted tick fever ricketts uh
obesity bartonella just all this [ __ ]
from a tick and
that's all parasite that's all
stuff that is hosting and feeding off of
me
and i start researching the powdery
mildew and the powdery mildew
goes down and it
spores and it is sinking like an anchor
through through the meristem of the
plant and then anchoring in and hosting
off and then feeding
and i'm thinking wow if this plant is
powdery mildew resistant that means it's
resistant to this pathogen that if i
take plants
into rso that are like that
that that will help my condition more
because i'm battling parasitic infection
so you're making a a corollary that if
the plant can defend itself from powdery
mildew maybe it'll help you defend
yourself from the parasites because it's
defending itself from a parasite trying
to host off of it i've already got them
in me so
so i'm listening all these podcasts and
listen to all this [ __ ] i'm up in
michigan by myself and i'd been in
california several years ago
for six months training uh dogs on
coronado island in san diego at a
contract out there
so i got my medical card when i was out
there and it was like a three-year
california medical card it was still
valid for six months
at the time
so shannon's in kentucky i'm sick of
[ __ ] i'm not even supposed to drive the
car up here stuck in the house growing
i book a plane ticket to
san francisco from detroit i go and get
on a plane i fly to san francisco drive
up to wonderland nursery i buy the rule
7 cut ship it back to myself go to this
i research everywhere where i can find
this mean gene from mendocino guys gear
and compassion hearts and coyotes
venture the only place i could even find
the seeds three three and a half years
ago anywhere so i fly all the way there
meet
brandon from third gen family farm who
happened to be there that day he saw my
port told me
explain my story dude hooked me up with
some seeds never met me before i bought
a bunch of mean jeans gear flew back
rule seven was waiting for me on the
porch when i got there overnight to
rock it out
grow it out
um start taking it
uh it took me uh
about three months from that process
start taking this is around
end of october
um
and
i don't know how to explain how it was
changing my legs were getting stronger
the antibiotics were more efficient
i was gaining weight i was getting
muscle mass back i
um i was up here and i was thriving i
was learning how to grow i was by myself
we had to go to uh the hospital in
washington dc
for a week every month so i'd leave dc
or leave michigan shannon would leave
kentucky we'd meet up in dc i'd get
treated i'd come back and the doctor's
like what are you doing because
you're dancing faster than the other
lyme disease what sorcery do you have
yeah what else are you adding into i'm
talking to him about the cbd
i'm talking to him about which he
promoted the cbd the doctor did but i'm
talking to him about the thc he can't
wrap his head up
because he is very
medically trained like he needs no exact
milligrams exact you know everything and
i'm like it's not like that like i'm
trying to figure out which plant works
which which dose
you know at first i started off with a
drop of of rso now i'm keep building up
till i could get to a gram a day and
when i got on the rule 7 i'm doing blood
work constantly and it's showing my
blood work is doing better it's showing
that um
that the antibiotics are working so
after about two months of this the
emerald cup is coming up
i decided to fly out there and to tell
some of these people like
uh emerald mountain to tell them like yo
your royal cush is helping to tell me
gene from mendocino yo your uh
your podcast changed my life to tell you
i flew out with
the smartest lady i've i've ever met a
neurosurgical nurse
um and my doctor
and we went out there
and she was in the uh humble or the
emerald cup sessions you know like
learning as much as she could i saw you
in there and i i couldn't walk up and
say hello
um i was just you know i mean you helped
save my life and
i did stand in line i walked up and i
talked to me jean and walked up and
talked to uh uh emerald mountain bought
a bunch of seeds uh talked to capulet or
a friend of mine and gave him a bunch of
mac and uh
you know but i presented
my doctors and nurse actually showed
like like this is actually working and
from the medical standpoint we don't
understand why we're trying to figure it
out you know
and i remember when i walked up and
shared all this stuff to jackson and i
had like a doctor there and a nurse and
i've got all these medical files and
i've got a port in my chest and i'm like
your [ __ ] saved my life and there's this
whole line of people waiting to get into
his booth and his jaws like
because i'm showing him like i'm
breaking down osami and near la doll um
you know in your lines powdery mildew
resistance is battling the parasitic
stuff in because
you've done a lot of research on his
i've got all the research in front of me
and i'm breaking it down i'm not just
out there like yo this helped me like
here here's the blood work here we're
from this week to this week and you're
speaking fast because you don't want to
take up too much time
i went up my creatine levels went up my
blood pressure regulated the seizures
dropped etc etc and i was supposed to be
dead from this [ __ ] a long time ago the
fact that i'm still sitting here even
having this conversation is a medical
miracle they they don't figure it out i
mean they like to scare me with every
eight months being like hey you only got
so much more time and
i'm still here four years later
and it did come back to these strains
now i went through mean jeans pina and i
found a particular female that helped me
a lot and it has been many phenos root
wise soil dynamics had a king side chick
i lost the cut that one helped me a lot
powdery mildew resisted uh
i had a sun sunshine daydream from bodhi
that happy little tree company gave me
it was off the charts and near la doll
that stuff helped with shaking i'm
constantly looking for different plants
for different things that have a lot of
issues
um so let me clarify for a second so
what you're telling me is that you you
found that the royal kush which you went
after because of its powdery mildew
resistance
it was helping so much as well you're
like wait a minute um not only is it
helping
with powdery mildew just being a good
plant it's it's it's got some uniqueness
about it and then you you delineated
that it was the awesome and the neridol
that were the two things that you wanted
to hunt for more of am i getting it
right well awesome meaning new la doll
from
research into the nih archives the
national institute of health have
archives that anybody can access they
have
published papers that show that
marijuana was killing cancer cells in
1979. so they also have stuff on
parasitic killing you know osamine
nerolidal the tea tree oil tree you know
different stuff working on different
parasitics i was looking at stuff that
people in africa
tribes and stuff used for centuries of
malaria and parasitic and stuff like
that so awesome and nerola doll kept
coming up
awesome and near la doll don't pump out
of royal kush to that level like
sunshine daydream different things but
it was the powdery mildew just overall
resistance of rule seven and for you all
that never ran roll seven i have seen a
plant with bud rot and coated in
powdered mildew laying on the roll seven
and not a drop of it on
we had
in michigan this is i started growing in
1995 when i was 15. this is the wettest
year that i've ever grew it this year is
this year hands down i had more bud rot
than i ever dealt with this year and
even my neighbor who farms 3 000 acres
of corn around here said this the
wettest winter ever for him on corn
they've been having to cook their corn
off in ovens at night to keep the molds
and everything down
and the rule seven here not a drop not a
drop not
i mean
it's amazing what that plant can do so
you look at that did every that other
plants beside are dropping off and it's
still hardy that's what you're looking
for to to fix yourself when you're
dealing with the same things you're
doing the same parasitic infections
um
now i've tried to experiment and because
i know there's 10 000 other strains out
there i can find
but i screw myself up every time i go
off roll seven
and it's rule seven in particular that
that particular cut
so it's more than just the awesome in
the narrow there's something else in the
mix in the royal seven and you're still
trying to figure out what that is yeah
and because it doesn't always transfer
so there's another keep on talking yeah
there's another plant uh
hollywood pure kush
that
so i i i say i have two mentors in this
game now i don't think they call me
their mentoree and they have no choice
on me calling their mentors but that's
kevin gildery and mean jean from
mendocino i i love them unequivocally uh
they've just helped me so much through
through this journey and
um
you know it's not just
there are multiple plants out there
that'll help you and i hear kevin tell
the story through a
podcast maybe it was yours i can't
remember but it was about a guy that had
this disease where
he hiccuped non-stop you know now it
started off that he was at a dispensary
you know they were closing up shop it
was the end of the day somebody pulled
in there in a wheelchair or something
like that and kevin sold him some of his
personal smoke because they had already
shut down his hollywood pure kush guy
came back the next day and was like yo
that's the best i've felt and forever
with my spasticity and shaking and
things
and kevin gave me some more and then
another other couple people tried it and
the same work for them
etc etc
so
when me and you really linked up was the
michigan regenerative conference up here
three years ago and kevin's telling the
story at this point me and kevin have a
slight relationship um
just because i've flown out to
california and tracked him down and i
think he respected that like this dude
ain't just saying he's trying to get
better he's put into work and uh i
literally followed him around the
emerald cup for an hour for an hour
didn't have the nerve to say anything to
him and finally he turned around was
like yo man can i help you yeah
uh
i pulled my shirt and i was like i got a
port and instantly like uh i'm sick your
video helped me here's all the research
my doctors and nurses here they'd like
to talk to you you know and uh
so kevin tells a story about hollywood
pure kush and then this guy
that uh
hiccuped non-stop
i mean to where a business guy where he
couldn't even hold a conversation where
he'd have to drink something make
himself vomit and then he had like a 15
minutes and no hiccups you know or
something like that if i'm botching the
story i apologize
and when he tried the hollywood thrill
push it fixed that for him so
you know i get a hold of kevin
i get the hollywood pure kush i go out
to california i get it uh fly back on
and i'm sure some people seen the
pictures i flew right with it on on the
plane because it mattered like that and
i was dying
that [ __ ] helped with my shaking a lot
um but when i tried to breed the
hollywood pure kush even into the royal
to try to find either one of those
things together like the best of both
worlds i lost it both you know um
because i take royal 7r so
and i'm going to hurx and buy hurts the
easiest way is to show like i have
babisia so i take rule 7 rso
and then it's gonna it's gonna like that
is herxing this rash and everything it's
killing off the parasites inside
then i have to flush the parasites out
of me yo and that's the j herxheimer
reaction
um there's these micro parasites and
bacteria and everything inside of you
you kill them off
if you don't get them out of you
the doctor in in dc explain to me like
when a mouse dies in your house like in
a cabinet
it kind of like rots and it'll discolor
the wood and it'll stink in like ammonia
and all these chemicals come off of the
mouse
so
the parasites and stuff inside you kill
them off if you don't flush them out and
they are releasing chemicals and stuff
inside of you they're like polluting you
and they're making you hurt they're
increasing your inflammation
your joint pressure uh the bacteria the
lyme disease bacteria uh
likes to attack soft tissue eyes brain
testicles kneecaps ankles you know like
where there's a lot of fluid in that
area
so
and with my brain injury sometimes like
like i'm gonna lose myself like what we
were even talking about here but um
uh
i have no clue what we were talking
about all right well then
so you were you were talking about how
the fluid in your joints would hurt yeah
especially with the herxing yeah so
getting that out and following and
following a protocol
lemon water helps detox epsom salts
ancient minerals ancient salts are a
little bit better than just regular
epsom salts at cvs
um
as much fluids as i can drink a day all
the mushrooms that i can take um
coffee enemas doesn't sound fun but it
will detox your body out you know um
anything that you can do to help clean
out the system
from the herxing uh from the pain that's
going like before you got here this
morning my first step when i wake up in
the morning because at night i take all
mars so i'm i'm marching out in the
mornings um first step is lemon water
uh second step i mean i still got a pork
in my chest that is connected into my
heart you know we either run fluids or
i'm right in the bathtub the fluids help
flush everything out i drink a lot of
coffee in the morning and water i'm
trying to make myself urinate as much as
i can flush all this out
it's a constant trick of detox i do
ozone treatment where they take my blood
clean it put pumping it back into me the
hyperbaric chamber has been a game
changer for me an absolute game changer
uh the lyme disease called a
caused
and when i say lyme disease and all of
you always say this with me with lyme
disease my lyme disease is probably in
remission it's all the other parasites
for vco bartender which baby isn't like
it's active right now on my chest
uh
so it's sometimes trying to figure out
which which one of these things are
trying to kill me you know today
um
but everybody always tries to send me
information about lyme disease and i get
that people are trying to help and i
don't mean this rude i mean like
it's not about the lyme disease it's
what the parasites did while they were
tunneling around my body and tunneling
in and out of muscles and corkscrewing
into bones and going so we can have it
everywhere and everything
that caused
my eating bar my my stiff man's syndrome
my c5 c6 c7 vertebrae you know uh
my neurological conditions all these
weird diseases i have now that
all come from that
um like even for me to be sitting out
here to do this interview
one of my biggest issues is temperature
regulation
so
we just shift temperature in michigan
like four or five days ago i have on
two sweatshirts two t-shirts two pairs
of pants and this big jacket hood lamb
jacket shout out adam dunn this is my
favorite jacket in the world uh made out
of him
it's rated down to negative five degrees
but it's also heavy and i need that
weight and stuff for me
it's a constant game of staying ahead of
it
but what it did to me more than anything
was retail on me mental
parasites running through my brain um
the aggression the rage you all can
google this if you wanted to like there
is a symptom called lyme rage i am the
poster child for lyme rage i wasn't this
way
before i got bit by a tick
my job was to train the most
highly protective aggressive and working
line
german shepherds and milos to cap that
aggression control that self to work
through it
and to do all this through operant
conditioning through skinnerism and
theories of dog training that wasn't
based off force was based off teaching
and learning and understanding
and then all of a sudden these parasites
wreaking havoc through me and i couldn't
apply the own [ __ ] that i've always done
yeah
um
and it's been about a constant battle
you know uh this summer alone um i think
i had 11 surgery since june from brain
all the way down into the tumor removals
you know that is has been caused by lyme
disease
so keeping control the mental illness
and we've talked about this and i'm very
open about this you said even inside
like your post on social media have
really changed in the last five months
um
you're clearly you're clearly more
upbeat in the last six months
it's funny when they tell you you're
gonna die
you do everything to not die i mean you
always know it but but once they lay it
down for you and you're like not not
today you know not today and i went
through too much hell um and it's not
just me i'm not special there are
a half a million of us lyme disease
patients i mean yes i'm i'm i'm weird in
my pawason story but there are so many
of us with lyme disease and so many
people undiagnosed and i would that was
the whole purpose of us doing this to
teach people how to
try to help themselves when doctors
won't help you
um all right we're back after a little
break there so um so i want to finish up
with this nick because so far you've
been pretty clear about um you know how
you decided that you
wanted to start focusing on using rso
for your lime support and then and then
you're chasing the royal uh kush and
then and then realizing that there's so
much about that plant that's helping
your lyme disease and then you then you
started to go into some of the other
things that you were doing too right
because i think you've laid out the
cannabis stuff pretty well that we
wanted to get out but i know that you
really believe in the synergistic
combination
of the cannabis for your endocannabinoid
system with all of these other
traditional um like folk medicines
that you really believe are working with
the cannabis to better your
endocannabinoid system and then like all
of you in fighting the lyme disease so i
figure since we're here we should go
beyond just cannabis and talk about
those things so um do you want do you
want to start with the medicinal
mushrooms yeah so i mean my my major
issue um
outside of just the lyme disease is that
my brain swelled um i had a massive
brain infection uh meningitis
encephalitis which caused all kinds of
neurological issues so
you know getting into uh like with
dragonfly earth medicine we're dim pure
here and um
learning a little bit about mycology and
things from that nature and then
following paul's stamets and getting
into that to a to a massive level
uh raichi chaga lion's mane um are all
just some of i mean every day that are
mushrooms that have to go back into my
system it helps with my neurological um
helps with my speech patterns i don't
think i've stuttered much during this
interview today but there are days where
where i've even explained it to you like
i'll be like
hey what's up scissors is here to visit
me chango you know i call i call shannon
sarah or samantha or uh stacy or
whatever and and she doesn't get mad at
me because i never dated sarah
it's just word association that i get
confused with the stuff well
lion's mane rishi chaga all that stuff
um if i'm leaving something out there i
apologize i mean any
of those
medicinal mushrooms i can take i do jaw
works farm you know grows a lot of
mushrooms make some stuff for me
eclectic alchemy
a healer herbalist make some stuff for
me
so mushrooms are a very major part of it
i micro dose
0.14 grams a day
of psychedelic mushrooms to help with
the depression and the sadness for those
that know me know that i battle with um
massive rage and
suicidal ideations it's um
i'm not
i i'm not suicidal i'm not even
depressed right now let me have 10
seizures today and it's not me it just
changes all the chemicals that are going
through my my brain and
that stuff has helped me
tremendously i mean it's it's brought me
back i mean if i
uh
if if i had a seizure right now the
first thing shannon's doing is bringing
me turkey tail and chaga tinctures and
then um
cbd and
and all that other stuff yeah
and let's not and i say this to the
marijuana community
let's not downplay cbd you know just
because hemp
we kind of looked at
him as our ugly cousin and and the hemp
industry and and all and cbd flooding
the market because it was
and excuse my language but [ __ ] cbd
sold in gas stations to people who were
sick and couldn't afford it and this
goes out to everybody 500 milligrams of
cbd should not cost 69.95 you know
most people and i believe the cbd is is
misdosed people are taking way too
little i take 500 milligrams cbd a day
that's and i have went through this
stuff to find what levels like actually
help after all these seizures and i can
experiment because i go through it you
know taking a tincture of 13 milligram
cbd a day is is just not doing it for me
now
that doesn't mean that you
and your particular
cannabinoid system that 13 milligrams
wouldn't be enough of cbd to to bring
that back down we're all individuals
that's what doctors can't seem to figure
out about dosing this stuff
is
it's individual cannabinoid systems i
know people
who years later like i don't get high i
mean i just don't um
but you look at snoop dogg who've been
smoking all this weed for years he's in
a video and he's all like how the hell's
he still you know his cannabinoid system
is different he's also not taking three
to four grams or so a day
which um
i would like to increases your tolerance
but even before i was doing rso i always
smoked like crazy when i was dog
training and i just didn't get a buzz
like that
and i know dr ethan russo and different
people talk about taking you know breaks
and and resetting the endocannabinoid
system in my situation i almost can't i
do skip rso about
once every two weeks or something to
help it be more effective because like
any medication the more you take it you
build up tolerance i take three to four
grams of r so every day
that is scary to somebody out there that
is hearing me say that it takes one
single drop and feels drugged up yeah
you have to tighter that up to any
patient out there that's ever doing this
you know you take a drop and then the
next week you take two drops and then
the next week you take four drops and
then you double it you double that you
double that you don't let and yes and
and i agree for people who have never
that aren't a cannabis user you know
um
and then you have to
give your grandmother rso
and she's never had this before and
she's sleeping 18 hours a day she's like
i hate this i don't like this feeling
for somebody who's never you know had
marijuana
in
you know
drunkenness is almost what i call it
because this is different than smoking
or something it's like edibles times a
billion right
you have to remember the medical
benefits that you are getting it is okay
to sleep you need to recover if you're
going through chemo if you're going
through whatever whatever you need to
sleep and recover your body will adjust
to it it is scary in the beginning it
will get better
it is no different than the first time
doctors give you a lower tab or a pain
pill like you're really drugged up from
but you start taking them and they lose
their efficiency you will build up on
the rso and i know it's scary in the
beginning i i've had a lot of patients
talk to me that have never been candid
shoes like i really don't like the
feeling power through it gets better you
know for me i love the feeling you know
for cannabis users they don't understand
that they love the feeling but
rso can be
hard when you're already sick and now
you're kind of like if you never took
our so it's almost like doing a mushroom
tree yeah you know it's very very
psychedelic you know um power through
be prepared it's okay
um
have food on hand when you start this
stuff
um
and i know that in some places this is
still a negative taboo marijuana is
medicine but that we're losing that
number we're way bigger on states that
are than not um
i would tell you um um to research how
to make it that's all i can i can tell
you i i told shango a story inside of
the first time that i made my own r so i
cooked down a quarter pound i paid 800
for this and i cried when i was cooking
it down because i was so scared i was
gonna ruin all this material and at the
time i'm having doctors so many checks
to stay alive and i'm in kentucky not
growing
a quarter pound of marijuana is nothing
to me now it was
everything to me and and sometimes
growers
and
producers and processors need to
remember this quarter pound ain't
nothing else it's everything to somebody
in a one-bedroom apartment partiallying
out a check just to pay for their
medicine and they're disabled be
compassionate caregivers take care of
sick people you know
but it is very scary when you do it but
but it will work out it is a very simple
process um
people can help you through that process
look at the videos when you are
researching this on youtube i learned
the hard way like you've been trying to
find you all the goofy videos and i'm
not at least people are trying and
putting out content but but look at it
all all instructions are not the same
not even close
and
look at information look at how many
people have liked it look at how many
subscribers they have
um
because you have to become your own
healer because the medical system will
forget you
if you don't fit into their cookie
cutter approach
then they'll forget you and
and at that point you you've got to
remember yourself and you've got to
fight for yourself
and it's very empowering
to be run here
it's very empowering that doctors still
to this day don't understand why i still
keep staying alive even though i
constantly am having all these surgeries
and all these issues it's the rso it's
the mushrooms
um
and it's the willingness to keep
researching to try to find some
semblance of my old life
uh and it's uh
i just implore there's so many growers
and breeders out there look at your
powdered mildew resistant lines um
look at your medical lines look at your
super strong stony lines we look at that
as whoa we got really stoned off this
but you concentrate that down that may
be the lifesaver for somebody who's
battling
chemo and needs to sleep or
you know strong like that it's amazing
how many of our thc wreck growers like
who've just been like growing for you
know for smoke for years
don't even have a lot of basis in the
medical side too like like like flower
growers who don't know how to make rso
right yeah correct and it is a
um and i believe it's something
everybody needs to have in their their
tool set rso is an antibiotic
and that's something that we can make at
home um
and it's just having the research out
there i mean i've done all my research
but i was talking to you inside that i
would still like to learn more the
terpenes are the carrier for healing and
a lot of my rso we're baking it off
we're stripping it down with alcohol i'm
losing all my terpenes i mean our house
smells great though yeah
so i've got i seal it in jars and put it
in the oven and you can actually see the
oil on the jars when you bring it out
but i would you know you get ice water
hash fresh frozen you know whatever you
can smell all the terpenes in there rso
all pretty much smells the same you can
get
you know differences there
but
i'm even trying to go deeper with it on
figuring out how to decarb the ice water
hash
you know properly to be able to just eat
that
and i experiment a lot with this stuff
because the terpenes are carriers
terpenes are a big part of the healing
process
and i believe that's a big part of the
royal cush you know those are it's like
the sour diesely purpley kush afghani
mixture smell that you damn near finding
nothing else
and that terpene profile really helps
that to go over
raw juicing cannabis leaves guys from
the same powdery mildew resistant uh
strain we're all juicing flour tastes
horrible do it
healing properties come from this stuff
i'd like to get into
a little bit of even the the root tech
making medicine now the roots from the
rule seven but i i just haven't stepped
to to that level yet
um
making a sad out of rule seven for like
the the issue that i've got on my chest
or out of another powdery mildew
resistant strain
and i'm always cautious when people are
like well i've got a train that's
probably resistant is it is it really or
are you a good grower you just don't
have powdery mildew so it's like let me
see it growing right by a powdery mildew
plant i remember the first time you were
at my house
like two years ago
uh i stopped real quick and i said yo
the flower room's about to shut off i
gotta go spray everything down with
water and you were like what and i'm
like trying to create powdery mildew you
know and you're looking for this i don't
remember uh
i don't i don't know if i've ever heard
anybody trying to
create powder and mildew and i'm like
man i'm trying to find the strings that
the
that powers through that [ __ ] you know
um my the work this year
and i'll say it because i bred it
because i got my by the hydra tknl5 haze
pam did horrible outdoors with powdery
mildew the work no bud rot no powdery
mildew pushed through the cold and in
michigan we had the wettest grow season
and and the vapor pressure deficit like
we had days in in august this year that
were 50. in the next week it was eight
you know so it like the plants taking
that pressure
um so i'm
i'm gonna break down a bunch of the work
in the rso form what i have learned
though now is to not go off
royal ever i've done that a couple times
right so everything complements the
royal kush seven that you've got i went
off royal from
december to
july this year
for personal reasons i went into other
rsos different stuff i deteriorated so
bad and i still didn't just make the
pair up
and
uh got back onto the royal in july about
the time that you know things were real
bad then um
i was telling people goodbye calling
people on the phone
telling you i love you and [ __ ] like
that
um got back on the roll and lord i'm
gonna get emotional um i have came a
long way
but uh
i have came a long way and it's because
of
this podcast finding kevin jonery and me
and you from mendocino but then applying
the information i can smack you beside
the head with all kinds of information
if you don't apply it you're not going
to get anywhere how desperate are you to
get better because there is hope out
there you just gotta find it you gotta
experiment it's not gonna be quick
you know uh at all
even when i flew out to get that rule
seven you know at wonderland i knew when
i got home i had to veg it up for a few
weeks take cuts get it in the flour and
boy the hope was real and
and it and it's proved itself over and
over to me um you know mandelbrot lives
on uh thank you ros truth for creating
that strain um
shout out to emily mountain for
continuing it uh
it is a uh
it is a very medicinal medicinal plant
but just because rule seven works that
way for me
and i do believe it'll work that way for
you if you're battling lyme disease but
maybe you have a different issue um
had a brain injury from concussions
you're you're battling cancer you're
battling whatever you've got to find
strains that pair that up look at
terpene profiles look on the nih you can
research this stuff
find the strains that work for you
all marijuana is not created equal there
are some rsos i i will never take i love
smoking the flour but the rso isn't
worth it you know
um
and unfortunately to figure out that
information you got to go through trial
and error and sometimes that error can
be very costly
so it's on that point that i want to
finish up with you today and that is
this idea that you know
you have shared with us over this 40
minutes or so
what has been you know a life's work for
you and then it got way more intense you
know three and a half years ago right
and and and so you've gotten even more
intense the last three and a half years
and part of why you wanted to do this
video was because
um so many people contact you via you
know instagram and everywhere because
they hear that that you're the guy who's
using rso
to manage his lime
and and that and they want to know why
right and so we're doing this so that
you know you could just send them the
link right and they can hear your
thoughts all at once
i know that there are people who are
watching who are feeling like
so overwhelmed right because of all the
all the information all the detail
people maybe who aren't from cannabis
and so they don't even really know a lot
of the vocabulary they're using so for
these people they're to have to learn
all of that to even do what you're doing
and i'm sure that a lot of these folks
are overwhelmed so what i'd like you to
finish with
is you know real direct advice for the
lyme folks who are watching
what words of encouragement can you give
them to about about
completing this what seems like
insurmountable task because you know
you are overcoming insurmountable tasks
just staying alive every day and i know
that you've given a lot of thought to it
philosophically so so what advice can
you give folks about
just doing it
i guess uh a first thing is mental
health wise you're a warrior
and that's not just the lyme folks
that's the anybody sick you're a warrior
you're battling something that that
other people around you do not
understand and do not know so keep
worrying on i mean that's very difficult
to say but
but take pride in the fact that you are
a warrior and you're overcoming stuff
that others aren't um
i do understand this is overwhelming
start off by looking at
research rick simpson oil
um of course some of these things talk
about harsh chemicals
rso you you need to avoid that i do use
um alcohol to make rso but we don't use
naphtha anymore no no we don't do that
but
so you take that piece out but you can
go to rick simpson's actual website they
have good information at least starts
the process
um
don't be as overwhelmed with it
realizing you're taking your life in
your hands and you're creating your
medicine if you're scared when you do it
at first start with a half ounce start
with a quarter you know be a small watch
somebody can help you if you're in a
legal state um there are tons of videos
on youtube
but you have to find the right ones
um it is very overwhelming and and i get
it i've been through the whole process i
had literally
leave my home and everything i was
familiar with in kentucky to move to
michigan to do this
uh
take a deep breath
reach out to some people maybe you need
to go to dispensary and go ahead and get
some from from the right place though
i'm cautious about that how was it grown
what was in it what if it's grown
synthetically all that stuff it's gonna
compound when it's made um
see i'm even gonna make more issues um
be calm find an organic grower find a
real caregiver in your area
and there are real ones everywhere and
they will help you um
just uh
send it send people messages try to talk
that's what i did in the beginning even
with you different people like i tried
to learn more and understand i get tons
of messages i can't answer them all and
i i get overwhelmed by it but
this is a step that maybe cbd can be the
first step that at least starts building
your cannabinoid system
is what i usually have people do for
like four or five days if they've never
took cannabis it'll build the
cannabinoid system and activate it so
that the first initial boom is not just
knocking them out for 24 hours so far so
it does get better
it can get better and you have to be
your own fighter and hero and i know
that sucks i know it's scary i've told i
was talking to shingle inside that
when i got sick i truly believed in the
medical system like you went to the
hospital you're sick doctor's going to
help you it's it's not that case
especially if they don't understand
find people that can help you
there's a lady named eclectic alchemy
look her up i mean there's herbalists
and healers that can help you through
your journey
to get there they can guide you because
it's a lot from the mushroom tech to the
rso to even knowing when to take it and
i recommend
you know in the beginning for somebody
on ourselves take it right before you go
to bed because if it's negative
experience you're sleeping through most
of them and yes you're going to wake up
a little hungover in the morning coffee
is your friend during those moments you
know um
just keep powering through it
it gets better and
if i can help you i'll try but
mine and your focus always needs to be
yourself i
tried to help so many people with that
journey
and then i left my own journey you know
you have to remember that you're the
patient also you got to take care of
yourself
so um
that would be
it's overwhelming i know that that would
be where i would start
all right well yeah
one more thing all right well you just
said about overwhelming and i can't
reiterate the first time i made that
that r so i literally cried in kitchen
thinking i'm going to ruin all this and
800 i told you inside i could have been
80 million i couldn't replace that
so i also say that to growers be
compassionate you know
it's not hard to make rso and get that
to people in need um and everybody
should do that to an extent we we rode
the wave of marijuana as medicine to get
it legalized they will now put your
money where your mouth is help people
out that are sick words so that's great
i appreciate you awesome dude thank you
so much
because these uh these podcasts matter
because without it i would have never
found kevin jody or mingy and those two
continually
try to keep me alive keep me mentally
happy
keep me with right genetics
but it's important it's important and
that's what i'm saying i found him then
i found them and people were willing to
help you can do the same thing so
awesome cool
so for nick risdon from lime rising farm
i'm shane golos from shaping fire thank
you so much for being here absolutely
all right
let me walk back and show you farm real
quick