[Applause]
thanks for a mentor what makes that very
fine well I really appreciate it and I
had this wonderful speech all imperative
it's pretty much ripped it up maybe I'll
have done a little bit of it but first
thanks so much for having today and you
know where to start praying for our so I
thought about trying to do is accept
like and share with and developing last
24 hours
Pappas's focus on email sent by the
Attorney General all right get that
specifically don't you touch on us in
your reductionism I just have such
tremendous of frustrations with you to
any gentleman so not just because we
kind of disagree with you I made it
really not right I have the spirits of
people all time breaking part of my job
as a lawyer to have an adversarial
system my family said it gets six boys
when moms covering sister I mean it's a
big town in Kenya where the Christmas
table makes people we don't all agree on
anything right we don't miss that's the
way it works the big families I'm used
to that but it's hard that the Attorney
General just want to get you the first
death I think this important is number
one we had no idea this time
[ __ ] we have no idea this is coming
myself Jeff you name it
number two is the Italian kettle since
became Attorney General refused
immediately accused me of the governor
these conversations on issues of this
magnitude the legalization marijuana for
God's sakes right what that means for
our country and our state that's pretty
good right and it strikes me that face
to face conversation is hope doesn't
you're in reanimated but their health as
an example right after I call that the
Attorney General Governor James Lee was
elected governor or president wobbles
coming in Washington and they're like
marijuana careful those of you trying
down and so we have a new system we're
going to place and we think how things
were really inserted that Colorado
Washington the two states have legalized
not sure what the Obama administration
would do and why the watch the Colorado
legalized and they asked for DC right I
will have me was a pretty
straightforward
I wanted to negate care holder
respectfully Yukito very clearly then I
would defend the will voters in
Washington State but there was no in me
that did not halt Washington having
legalized marijuana from my standpoint
right though the talk about things up to
that point but that's the best giving
from my standpoint
in contrast Attorney General Sessions
you meet people meet what aggravates and
even beyond that is we got a letter from
him because if he wants to go at the
babies
get a letter from them and the letter
signed by the Attorney General to watch
to take myself the government in which
she's very critical of Washington
State's utilization of marijuana okay he
has a disagreement I understand that but
the part that's so frustrating in that
letter he literally is making things
like oh there's a problem I think that
it's great market brought together your
medical and recreational marijuana
systems he cites made reported there's
just a problem that report is a years
old and such pointed to to never record
of course the state legislature who
brought those systems together these
employees Dannette or what grow the
better for him is employees how do you
handle it i candidly it's hard to take
someone seriously the signs of erratic
unite right it's hard to take someone
seriously I want to be intellectually
understand what actually is happening in
a system that he purports to change so
that wasn't the only no me nervous
statements with Max that he just was it
was riddled balloons so the government
wrote a very very detailed letter back
builders check it out because August of
this year that you know was maybe a bit
more candid I would typically right
through the city US attorney kiddo but I
held things having said right things had
to be said so this did not only come as
a surprise it happened yesterday his
views on marijuana or very clear and I
just a couple points about what came out
so what we're surprised to is the lucky
mountainous fellow as you know it's very
very for you right now
linkie doc it's very very brief and it's
something that been crafted by numerous
team in 25 minutes it's not a
complicated document right well in fact
the : random the argument I'll talk
about the positive as well as just a
peasant
attention to this important event
marijuana front but it's it's not a
detailed work product I guess I have a
surprise once he decided to do something
that this was what he did if it wasn't
more to it basically I'm not minimizing
at all what he did deeply disappointing
deeply troubling what do you ex are
long-term remain to be seen they'll talk
about that my perspective but since it's
been a whole year a specific step at
launching state to stop watching state
moving forward right what you did for us
to say hey use all US Attorney's you've
got the discretion basically do what you
think is appropriate
the other part that surprised me but
rolling back to Pullman grant which of
course was upon administration that said
he states like Colorado Washington which
is legalized that time it's essentially
an uneasy truce basically he's
essentially they're communicating you
can move forward and just make sure
marijuana up in the hands of minors
right economy state borders reasonable
request we can work with the benefit
when we have for a number of years now
so here if you eliminated outright you
took that that that nice that were
essentially it's a low priority to the
defrost marijuana pieces but he also
foot building later has always told will
read the footnotes very carefully right
in a footnote he mentions the object at
random in 2009 which many of you
probably know is a memorandum that
applied to medical marijuana in which
the department justice said to US
attorneys it's literally two metal rivet
US Attorney's post prosecute to stuff on
the ground all around the country great
and given a lot of the port of the US
Attorney's I'll get mental the better
with the Department jezus said was
becomes a medical marijuana in states
that legalized medical marijuana
marijuana
2880 or 29 when I thank you 29 states
I'd be blessed marijuana they said
selling a cancer patient is using
medical marijuana in one of those states
that is not a priority three exact words
the member was essentially saying yeah
no we're not focusing on that someone
business state has little marijuana it's
using it that's not your party the other
things to worry about
session says mental yesterday took that
back as well which I don't think people
fully appreciate right now around
there's so much going on right I'm not
sure that was the focus as much as take
back the clothing brand but what that's
again disturbing to be on on many many
levels so you know we're gonna go from
here I guess it's all things one days
happened becoming Attorney General my
staff will close with this
aptly turn to in Colorado because we're
the two states that legalize marijuana
we met all time at the conferences or a
staff spot all the time
[ __ ] leg create a workgroup those
states that have legalized marijuana the
AG's of states that have legalized
marijuana or one nothing like marijuana
and that's been a group that's been here
helping out where I guess five years
which we discuss all sorts of issues
related to the legalization of marijuana
from the legal standpoint of defending
the will the voters rate internally
my team has been preparing for something
like this happen for five years so we're
not highest one obsessed you we're not
hot flat-footed our arguments are
prepared we have contemplated
hypothetical scenarios in which the
little voters would be ported or
attempted to be ported by the federal
government
[Music]
like I piece it over the phone all right
now with them all each piece is
obviously different but the way I do my
job is very simple
I try to stay focused on my lane of my
responsibilities I can't do anything
that was a lot of Commerce okay I can
write letters to members of Congress and
he do something tell the banking
industry when it comes to the
legalization marijuana we sent those
letters we communicate up in a DC at
militants congressional delegation to
communicate my views on that okay but
I'm not any Congress I don't have that
hope that's not my ass on my lane right
write a letter so it you write but what
I can do my role is very specific
our job is to defend this piece of
Washington state law whether it's occupy
the state legislature or adopted by the
people through the initiative process
that's very important that when it comes
to it's critical and so we take that I
take that very very seriously to thing
the whole the voters each and every time
so just so you know the folks who work
on this they are the best attorneys in
the office or working these issues they
are the best attorneys the ottoman
support on this issue
I get where you can turn them to all the
time and have three years when comes to
marijuana legalization in part because
it's so important to the people who
passed it right in London in part
because it's you do patient support the
state of Washington right or the bottom
or cannabis or we do them legal advice
it's all sorts of issues that are out
there we need to be on top of our being
that comes with this in terms of the
future what's going to happen I've been
asked that a lot lately
I don't know that anymore than use your
brain but what could happen Washington
may be different than other states
because what Attorney General Sessions
has done is essentially said to those
mobile US attorneys you have discretion
do what you think is appropriate I'm
paraphrasing but that's essentially what
the memorandum said well you know
Governor Isaac spoke about this
yesterday that press conference we
headed some at some length quite
passionately where he said basically a
nobody attorney could walk down the
streets of Washington State trying to
shut down here a lot of things the
people spoken there and what they want
we have a system is google poll right
have a lot of authority but I do think
that you know US attorneys are aware of
what they serve in many figures and they
have a lot of discretion and how what
they choose I would submit mutations out
before those attorneys ones maybe 25 in
the future is to emphasize things we
have a system okay people spent all day
right I've been when I focused on will
be like every other we haven't
understatement rate to people not every
day investing on average peasant
motivated people like they didn't
Washington state alone right there were
men old boy describe it it's a 2012 we
have a year old boys cry 2012 man woman
and child in our state alone at the 16
day supply
suddenly camp says no doesn't make any
sense
well we do something about that right
when we focus our energies on that so
that's the conversation all be having
right with the US Attorney's Eastern
District of Washington and the West
rotisserie from Washington but boldly is
up to them both should communicate to
them but they have a program to do that
right they're not elected official is
there a point but there are human beings
they're lawyers or smart people they
care about what you think
there is one ratio Hedgehog that's not
sex related before I have to get on
press your comments it is important in
Washington State setting side of the
session situation controversial one as
well as some respects less health other
states but the issue of whether not
local jurisdictions can ban and sell
marijuana can a city in a county and the
sale of marijuana and when our
initiative passed there was a lot of
questions around them because all the
jurisdictions started banning is health
care law you simply say if you ask
everyone you can't you can't do that and
so my office is asking about legal
opinion about them my legal pants are
not finding any important potentially
guidance in after or businesses but
court ultimate resolved now when we
issue a legal opinion our track records
pretty good we put a lot of fun of those
Attorney General's signed off on those
my sister general for selling me you
know there's some chart people attend
those but there are opinions for
guidance so we were asked to do that I
wanted sighs those are not policy
positions we're not massive we were not
asked to say is it a good idea if local
jurisdictions ban the sale of marijuana
that's how the question I'm asking
answering the question Hanson is legally
legally do local jurisdictions have we
how about demand axilla marijuana that's
the legal question I'm answering the
answer that question this is a few years
ago down was a yes into of the authority
of the or so so couple things without
too much of a legal side of it but at a
high level any most folks grasp
intuitively that both jurisdictions have
a lot of course granted authority by the
state pays coming
Nelson we set rules regulations as we
see a program or closest to people
that's how it works except right local
jurisdictions can be bound right or
limited by the state but only if the
state is very explicit about that in
other words the state has to say to the
legislature for the initiative process a
local jurisdictions you must do X or you
cannot do Y has to be very very explicit
Hamilton is what we call lots of cases
about this has its take pre-emptive
local jurisdictions from the usual
Boarding they have what they want
we read the initiative it's not
complicated if the initiative and had a
simple sense of saying all jurisdictions
must provide like a sailor marijuana
period that's fancy that's pinchy
initially does not say that doesn't say
that might be was I think it's a good
policy I'm saying legal aid well maybe
this assignment on that therefore local
jurisdictions retain their operated
always have now this has been important
since we started in 1990 edges around
the state have waited on that all I
haven't read my analysis both of
jurisdictions can ban the sale of
marijuana
I just Google this morning breaking down
california allows the ban and local
jurisdictions Alaska Oregon Colorado I
think every statements legalize has a
bad word there's a reason for that
two month commitment here's what is it's
important one so import local
jurisdictions are sued by a business
owner who wants to sell marijuana and
accountant ersity has placed a ban the
local jurisdiction has a too hard it's
like go to court as it's really for the
first one is let Burke's a guy who Frank
okay
the initiative doesn't preempt our usual
Authority
okay so this is what versus Eddie's
right we have our usual or whatever we
want and that's what we're doing but
they say in the alternative that's wrong
if purposing is wrong initiative does
preclude us from and silver want they
have an alternative argument the
alternate arm is
a federal law look at the federal law a
federal law on marijuana
the federal law preempts state law now
what they need to get that argument it
have no courts got that part of it yet
because they've all agreed that I'm
right
local decisions and and sell their money
so the courts haven't reached determine
whether or not federal a lot of them
state law view that wasn't ruching about
that is if it's that argument the
important things or are speak two
important things and both we this is go
to the US Supreme Court you can decide
for yourself comment will give you the
USB port designers question does federal
law and state law that would just be a
local band that's an essential thread of
legalization marijuana not just in
Washington at all across the country the
only way to avoid that conversation
before the Austrian Court is if each
state allows or bubble bands some ironic
somewhat ironically local bands actually
my new preserve the legalization
marijuana if any state those courts it's
built you've got to do it it's only a
matter of time before that issue of
whether federal law and state law ends
up squarely before the US Supreme Court
we would be you know I just put that out
there now that was not a reason for our
decision I want to be clear we're just
look at the initiative the language of
the issues at language make flavor
although jurisdictions must Anna sell
marijuana we would've said an answer but
it does not so we'll see that piece has
not got none of those pieces got our
state to be poor yet retention someone
surprised me
so this issue may end up a little fans
before speech in court but whatever they
say it's not mutual
ex-girlfriend just write articles
morning states provide that and I'm
convinced there's a reason why they
specifically provided so just to wrap up
you know it's a prison actually if you
ask what single issue I spend the most
time as Attorney General thinking about
it would have been there along in
position because it impacts so much of
state government right such importance
to people so high profile the meet
unique media's interesting it's just
it's a big big big issue right I mean
geez you're asking about it's a big big
issue and it's one of the few issues I
was saying we're a little early receive
regular memos updating me on court
actions are on the stage and issues with
state care attendant liquor and cannabis
do you get a guy here hello Trump
becoming president pasta this year has
been a big focus on our litigation with
the president but I would say the issue
of marijuana legalization you know my
team knows this is this is critical to
me personally I think to our office and
so we're going to do everything in our
power and everything in my power to pull
the wool voters a that's our job be I
think is the right thing to do
see I think women
I think part of his head I felt they
were most vulnerable the first year
about her most vulnerable to the first
year I'm thankful that President Obama
and Eric Holder held their respect
classes the first year we feel like the
marijuana instead of visiting the first
year I think thinks they're that
different man Justin cannon right so the
fact that we had those five years come
for other states at maja war that was
six on them right this is all in one
direction we have this pilots in five
years to be a lot more students in ten
years more states bill it's all about
compression and I think people
understand that and I think that worth
by the way forward too loudly will
voters to continue thanks so much for
your mission has to say a few words will
break