[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I'm delighted to be
on to this episode by it seal and
jeanclaude shakuna from cotex how are
you guys
keeping thank you all good and thanks
for having
us I'm delighted to have you both on
you're one of the the hot companies in
Europe at the moment so I thought
everybody would like to find out what it
is that you guys exactly are doing can
we first and foremost start with a t and
go through what's your area of expertise
in this industry and how did you come to
set up celotex and then we'll do the
same with Sean Claud after
that perfect so I'm coming from
technology background product Ai and
actually following a personal story from
my father getting to understand bit more
on on medical cannabis he actually got
me curious why why no one knows why
doctors refer to anour effect or it's
personalized no one actually knows the
dosage or what you should take or or
when it's all about the patient and
going through trial and error without a
real
compass this is where actually we have
thought on on celotex having more data
come into play understanding more on
what's going on with the patient what's
the actual intake
the goal is eventually to create a Clos
Loop medication by Clos Loop medication
you can actually have it much more
precise and optimized and customized
towards the patient symptoms not as a
generic one fitall as I would say
conventional medicine is doing but
something which is more personalized and
medical cannabis actually is the great
treasure which is out there waiting to
be unlocked and this is what actually
what we have
started okay thank thank you very much
and Sean Claud to
you um really and truly it's it's
something which also changes the
experience um for patients and when we
we talk about the patient experience
often patients uh in traditional medical
settings have issues accessing their
data um have issues owning their data
and most importantly um have issues
sharing this data with with the
professionals they want to
um be a doctors and and with medical
data uh it's always hard to get the
balance just right to get the balance
between um What patients can interact
with and ultimately the data and
insights that doctors need in order to
make good diagnosis to reduce errors in
diagnosis and in
prescription um so really what we're
building here is is is a as a middle
ground a sweet Middle Ground where where
this this can be shared and where this
uh can lead to better insights better
data better diagnosis and ultimately
better
care okay incredible thank you very much
I'm going to move on to the first topic
now which is AI powered precision and it
t we'll start with you when it comes to
the technology behind the AI that you
guys are building is it large language
models is it computer science to drove
through large chunks of data what is the
exact technology but that that make
makes it special to be able to give this
Precision
medicine this is a perfect question the
short answer is a bit of all of the
above what we're starting off is
obviously assessing the patient symptoms
the assessment of the patient symptoms
is not always easy we are discussing
about pain anxiety so you need a lot of
biomarkers and this is where we collect
as much biomarkers as possible both
passively and actively from the patients
who are using yeah the best example for
that would be connecting to my weall and
my were ball actually knows how am I
sleeping he knows my hard variance
different bio feedbacks which are
relevant to understand what's actually
going on with with that person obviously
capturing the medicine intake alongside
with that you're able to understand what
actually happened to the symptoms during
the following hours that was the passive
assessment active assessment can be
visual or audio or anything that can be
captured from that patient in order to
again assess the symptom and assess the
outcome so really put on the engineering
hat it's an input output problem and in
order to do that yes as you said you
need as much data as possible on that
specific patient in order to better
understand it symptoms potentially
forecast them and of course suggest to
the doctor what would be the right
course of treatment referring to the
language model which is an interesting
one what we're actually incorporating
these days on the next version of seatex
is a language model which is essentially
your digital caregiver what we have
understood from the first patients it
kind of be cumbersome because you always
need to collect also the patient
feedback how do you feel the way that
it's being done today is okay a scale 1
to 10 how is your pain where is that but
with language models you can actually
gain a lot more information from from
that patient him doing it in a much more
convenient manner which is natural to
him it can be by text or by Audio to
actually tell your doctor what's going
on instead of running through a
questionnaire so by the language model
Incorporated and empowered with the
symtoms and the medicines you actually
have almost full circle of of what you
can learn about that patient obviously
taking into account is ZR and background
information uh but bottom line here as
you have mentioned this is an AI model
and what we're doing is actually
imparing that with as much data as
possible yeah it seems to be the
opportunity as you said that the current
standard is 1 to 10 on a scale how do
you feel how is your pain being given
patients the opportunity to be able to
talk directly to whether it's a a
custombuilt applications with a
smartphone or an at home device and be
able to actually have a full
conversation and get more nuanced
information per patient would be where
some of the Holy Grail to be able to
build these targeted medicines is going
to
be exactly that so just to refer to to
one of the points that you have
mentioned our solution is at the moment
Hardware less that means that we're
tapping into existing wearables exting
mobile devices our goal is for that to
be within reach of of any patient and
and the way to go about it is is on the
software
side what we're seeing is that a lot of
the research at the moment is very
limited in terms of the number of
participants and also very
geographically focused and what celotex
and part of our goal is actually for for
that data to serve Mankind and not
specific companies or or products this
is why we're agnostic to the products
what we're are here for is actually to
to set the compass for doctors and
patients to have their personalized
Compass instead of okay medical cannabis
go ahead and and
try Okay moving to yourself M Jean claw
the next topic I wanted to bring up was
data and insights for doctors one of the
big things we see across the industry is
the lack of data for doctors to be able
to a prescribe the medicine and be then
prescribed confidently based on the
nuanced uh metrics of each individual
patients that's going to walk through
whether it's high tolerance to
cannaboids or whatever this variable may
be how important is gathering this data
and providing this insights for doctors
around the
world right well um starting off uh
medicine uh evidence-based medicine
which which we practice is increasingly
becoming data driven and this is not
simply in
cannabinoids simply looking at other
disciplines like radiology and oncology
we can appreciate that um as time goes
by uh the doctor's tool of choice will
be looking at a computer screen rather
than using a stethoscope for example um
and definitely um with with plant
medicine and cannabinoids having uh such
a complex way of of of interacting with
each other um the need for
evidence-based medicine and the need for
data driven insights is is bigger than
ever before so uh increasingly it's very
difficult for doctors to be able to
understand um what the medication is
doing in their patients bodies because
first and foremost they're not with
their their patients once they go home
and your patient is medicating we have
the term uh we sometimes refer to as
self-medicating when someone medicates
without the supervision of a doctor but
truly even when you're you're being
supervised and coming from the point of
view of uh of of my experience in in
prescription uh sometimes patients come
back and you understand that there are
communication issues you understand
there are uh nuances of both taking the
cannaboid medication or um
the time taken or certain other
activities around that and you
understand that really cannaboid
medication is not a simple um
prescription Silver Bullet it it takes
care it takes a journey with the patient
you really need uh to have a degree of
of handholding and a lot of time with
the patient and um this creates in in in
modern clinics with with the under
Staffing even in medicine we've seen
since the co pandemic uh it has created
a really huge bottleneck so the need um
to be able to convert all that data all
these insights about not simply um THC
or CBD now we have more and more doctors
being uh sometimes specialized in minor
cannabinoids and a lot of work we're
seeing with minor cannaboids and
research data uh it's a lot to keep up
with so something um we we think will
will release that bottleneck will be um
the the ability of of a solution to
Crunch the numbers uh and give the
insights for the doctors and then from
the doctor's point of view um just like
we work with Radiology we we look at um
the data and then uh do actionable
decisions based on that data um this
will give not just cannabinoid medicine
but all plant medicine a significant
boost uh a boost in The credibility
because we know that canab medicine and
and The credibility and and uh the
stigma is definitely still present um
but also and most importantly really is
a boost in the accuracy um and and in
the in the patient
outcome okay very interesting a question
for your Bo now I'll let Sean Claud you
go first with this one it seems to be
that the mass of opportunity coming in
the next let's say five to eight years
is going to be from the Blends and
formulation that are able to be created
whether it's be from fermentation
engineering or what it's extracted
individual cannaboids because the
delivery mechanism is similar across the
board it uses technology to be able to
consume H the the models that you're
going to be able to build are going to
be able to build up this patient data
but those unique formulations that
Target whether it's oncology as you said
or chronic pain or cardiovascular
inflammation or one of the things is
that the next big massive step that we
we're going to see when it comes to
medical cannabis is these unique
formulations that end up being delivered
for this exact Nuance disease mechanism
based on then body body weight
precise well I mean let's look at what
has kept this technology from being
present with us right now and and and
really it's the presence of of Big Data
Big Data pools uh which are precise
which are
accurate um and and which can be
reliable um mark ERS for for such
products to be made whether it is you
know with with um Precision growing
products or whether it is uh grown in a
lab or or or all the Technologies around
that um but but a reliable marker of how
humans interact these different strains
is is something that we have had not had
so far so um it's difficult to tell the
future but definitely
um datab backed Solutions um will be
will be a treasure throw for um not just
patients and doctors but other areas of
the industry which can grow
exponentially thanks to uh the the data
acquired amazing and to aay do you see
the a use of AI to be able to run these
tests for these potential molecule
combinations being another landmark when
it comes to muring this these
formulations to a
degree this is definitely a big hype at
the moment a lot of companies are are
going about that I would say the the
applicability of that because there is
no one formula which would fit everyone
I think conventional medicine that
thought us that looking at clinical
trials and obviously real world data the
efficacy is not always the same we are
different people different gender
different medical condition and even
different from one day to the other the
ability for those medicines to adapt to
the patient and not the patient adapted
to the medicine I guess this would be
the the big change here this is what
Precision medicine actually brings in so
a lot more molecules to work with and
the ability to understand what works for
whom when how much that would be the
next leap the way I see it in in
healthcare incredible it's been
fascinating chat to you guys what's the
thing you're looking forward to seeing
with celotex over the next 12 to 18
months are there any uh points on the
horizon that you'd like to let everybody
know but are these still uh company seek
for
now it's actually another secret we have
launched our activity in Germany already
working with compounding pharmacy we're
actually doing exactly as we have
mentioned the the compounding
specifically for those patients we're
going about observational studies
starting from Germany but will be
expanded
soon so it's definitely looking forward
to to see where in the year's time where
we will be where the industry will be
but the way I see it much more on on the
medical aspect of of cannabis not
necessarily adult use which again I can
fully appreciate but more patients
actively using it as as their medicine
to relieve the symptoms yeah it seems to
be Europe is definitely going to be
focused on the medical side of the
industry for the number of years to come
Sean Claude anything you're looking
forward to seeing in the the doctor side
of
things uh I think definitely having
having better data to treat patients
better is is something I look forward to
being able to give uh a boost in the
accuracy and credibility of the the
increasing number of doctors getting
into cannaboids uh facing stigma
sometimes from colleagues and and um
sort of being um pressured about about
data I think being able to to give that
to to a growing uh community of of
really great clinicians is is for me one
of the the highlights that I'd like to
see um and we are working with with
doctors with researchers um and really
want to make this a tool to to push uh
the entire cannabis Community um medical
community and recreational Community
forward incredible definitely want to
keep your eye on for everybody for
anybody who wants to know more about
cell taex the website is below it'll be
available in all the subscriptions where
you watch or listen to this but for now
it Jean Claud thank you very much for
your time it's very much
appreciated thank you Owen for inviting
us my pleasure have a good day guys
until next episode every
[Music]
bu