[Music]
welcome to the cannabis review everybody
we've got a great episode for you today
i'm delighted to be joined by alexi
pakovsky who's the ceo and co-founder of
alpha green group
you might have heard a lot of noise
about this company over the last while
they're making plenty of waves in the uk
alexi how are you keeping
good good doing well excited to be here
great to have you on the show mate i've
been looking forward to having you on
and learning a lot more about alpha
green group
and i'm going to take kick things off a
pretty much a simple start first topic
and give everybody an overview of how
you got here can you go tell everybody
the story of alpha green group and how
you got to here
sure um so the story starts uh actually
with me
looking into a bunch of industries bunch
of companies
as an investment banker uh at nomura and
the m a team in
2011 um and then i'm kind of spending
six years as an investor for various
family offices
and and a private equity fund and
basically seeing cannabis doing
extremely well
in canada in the us around 2019
and thinking to myself okay there is
nothing um
big or nothing in terms of high quality
companies
in the uk europe and maybe i should look
into that and so i spent a month
traveling canada and california talking
to more than 50 companies
and realized that there is a there's a
market
to have a platform in europe to offer
top brands to european and uk customers
and provide them with the top brands
beat the us brands canadian brands
or uk brands and so that was really
the background um and then yeah it was
kind of like
okay what's the team and i was really
lucky i have a super strong co-founder
and cto
and he was the cto of a copycat of etsy
in germany for many years and i
pitched him the idea and said look do
you want to join me and so
uh we we launched alpha green in october
2019.
amazing yeah i think having a good
co-founder is hugely important to the
success of your
enterprise for sure that's a a good
overview for everybody now in the the
alpha grain group
what i'd like to do is chat about the
current landscape of the cbd of cbd in
the uk
the novel food licenses that's really
gone true i see that they push back the
deadline
again there last week can you tell us
what you think the
cbd landscape looks like in the uk is it
promising are the regulations going in
your favor
or is it like the rest of uh like not
even europe but ireland
seems to be living in the stone age when
it comes to this yeah
yes it's a great question um so the uk
is making progress for sure um
with fsa pushing out the deadline
um ultimately gives some brands more
time to submit the dossier
uh for the novel food application uh
we do see that
the landscape is huge right there are
more than
500 brands um i think just on alpha
green we have more than
100 uk based uh cbd brands
um but we also know that probably
70 of them are getting their ingredients
from kind of like
five suppliers and so what you see is
that as long as these five suppliers are
getting
their noble food application validated
um the let's say 70 of brands
will be safe let's say um
at the same time of course that whole
mobile food
process um brings a lot of let's say
problems because it it then questions
the
it then basically makes it makes a
makes the process of kind of you ask
players
launching a brand suddenly in the uk
much harder because they
deficit can then argue okay well you've
not been on the market before
february wherever 2020 and you haven't
submitted your application
so you can't actually launch a brand
which obviously is kind of like against
the free market and so it will be
interesting to see
but i think the fact that there is
the novel food application and that
there is actually
some sort of clarity how you get
compliant
is already better than what's happening
in europe where
the european court decided cbd is not a
narcotic
which was great for industry but at the
same time the
european court didn't actually say well
it's a food
right so it remains somehow a gray area
and so you do
see um from time to time
certain rates on the retail market in
germany where suddenly
all the product is now illegal and then
one month later the same retailer
puts all the same products back on the
retail shelf saying actually now it's
legal again so you have this kind of
zigzag strategy in europe which
doesn't really help anybody so in that
sense i think uk is definitely
a bit ahead of europe um
and then ireland as you say right i
think
ireland uh is an interesting market it
actually is a super interesting market
from
if you look at thc habits statistics
it's it's probably the highest kind of
usage
market for thc uh like the kind of
black market thc um it's like 20
of the of the population is using that
it's a
statistic i saw it in the prohibition
partners
and newsletter so i'm not sure how
accurate it is but
ultimately you can argue that there is a
huge culture
in ireland um but around the regulations
it's probably closer to uh what europe
is doing i.e
not much clarity versus what the uk is
trying to do
yeah no i think there's a there's
definitely a little bit of lack of
enthusiasm from the politicians here in
ireland to kind of act on
what is being applied across european
law ireland seems to be just lagging
behind
but i think it's still some of the
scenarios you could pipe down to
the police are raiding places that are
selling cbd flower and the police don't
have a clue what cbd flower compared to
tac or flower looks like so to them it's
just
it's it's cannabis or it's weed and they
need to
lock down on it so i think it's more
having clarity from the government that
a bit of education and a bit of training
and being able to know the differences
or even be able to apply for a certain
license might be able to clear that up
one thing you might be able to clear up
for me and it's almost like swimming in
muddy water when you go through the
novel food license applications and
everything
the novel food for the uk does that
apply to the eu
or the eu have a completely separate
novel food license that uk companies
will have to have
as well as the uk so the novel food
obligation
right now is only uh good for the uk one
because it's under the uk fsa and the
european has
the fsa so the european food and
sundance authority
and so it's it's i guess you can kind of
submit the same application
but you need to submit it to a separate
authority
okay perfect um i'm going to now finish
on our last topic and there's some of
the success stories recently and the
listings on the london stock exchange
how excited are you guys about the
future of the
listings over there and some of the ipos
that may be happening
um well it's definitely good for the
industry that you see
a lot more capital coming into it and
can as cannabis becoming um well an
investable let's say industry
um so you obviously had cannibal
ipowing at 6.5
pence and now it's trading at
100 up so i mean i think
north of north of 25 pence or something
so
uh it's doing extremely well uh despite
actually having well a lot of sales so
let's say
back to story up right if you look at
the prospectus of that 14 000 pounds of
revenue last year
and it's trading at more than 100
million market cap now
so while it's exciting that you have
this
um you know hype and this
flow of capital i'm also very
uh let's say cautious to say okay these
are the companies
who are going to be the winners in the
future
and what i don't want is obviously a lot
of retail investors who
suddenly lose a lot of money now and
kind of like write off
cannabis when actually cannabis then
becomes
a much bigger industry uh and and should
be
a really big uh sector also for kind of
institutional investors so i think
in summary yeah you had three ipos in
the last three weeks doing extremely
well
uh cellular goods mgc pharma and
cannibal
at the same time um
i'm i'm still very cautious on how the
market will perform when they actually
see
some of the numbers okay
tell me doesn't tell me more do you
think the european cannabis industry is
going to be
pharmacy based for distribution and for
sales
and kept to a medical or can you see
full-on dispensaries like they have over
in north america
um so if you look at the north american
market it's very much
split into um yes you have
cvs pharmacy distributing some of the
cbd products but
also um some of the medical cannabis
products
you don't have medical cannabis
dispensaries
so purely medical cannabis especially in
states where there is no recreational
market and then once there is
recreational
in the state so for example let's say
new york which is about to go wreck
uh you have you see medical cannabis
dispensaries flipping
to recreational uh dispensaries reason
being that
the same customer can then still buy the
medical cannabis and show their
let's say prescription and get uh the
government to reimburse some of the
costs
but at the same time you also open up to
a much larger market which is direct
market
so i actually think a similar evolution
will happen
in in europe and the uk with the
exception that the medical
market is still tiny so you actually
don't even have
medical dispensaries neither you have
pharmacies
who are selling it of course you can
have pharmacies who can dispense it but
it's a very very little number
so instead what you have you have
already let's say vape shop cbd shops
and you have just a much more
developed online market for the cbd
products which is very different to
again to the
north american market because it's much
more thc
uh in terms of kind of like heritage and
so
online was never very big because it was
kind of
well because you needed to pick up the
product or you needed to go to the store
so
the online was much more about finding
this train
in a certain dispensary rather than
actually buying this train
and getting it delivered so the way i
see the uk evolving is
you will have still the online market
being
very very dominant when it comes to cbd
you will then gradually have
a pharmacies opening up to medical
cannabis
and then down the line you will
definitely see the cbd shops and vape
shops of today
converting to some sort of dispensary
structure but then again
that will be you know three four five
years uh in the future i think
yeah well i've started to see a lot of
even over here some of the cb stores now
call themselves cbd dispensaries
and starting to offer a flower cbd
flower under 0.2 percent
thc so i think that's a step in the
right direction for
allowing the free markets and and
dispensaries owned by
competent human beings who've gone
through a full regulatory process to
apply for a license
to be able to bring to the market as
opposed to limiting to
uh pharmacies and what we know will be
inferior cannabis if it does go that
route so
let's hopefully yeah it goes the way of
the free markets and
it all goes well for the next few years
for the industry
yeah absolutely alexi i want to thank
you very much for coming on the show i
know you're busy man so i won't keep you
too much longer hopefully we can get to
chat again in the next few months and
we'll do a catch-up and review and
there's a lot more positive news for us
to discuss
i want to thank you very much for coming
on the show anybody who wants to check
out about alpha green there's the
website
below you can go and check it out it's a
great success story and i wish you all
the best for the future lexi
cool thanks so much cheers bye thanks