foreign
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I'm delighted to
join in this episode by Nicholas Milne
who's the co-founder in CSO at Danish
based company octarine how you keeping
today Nicholas good thank you and
yourself I'm very well thank you very
much for taking your time to do this
sure
do you maybe want to give everybody an
overview of your position in your sector
and how you guys came about to found
octuring
yeah sure so uh my background is and my
co-founder's background is in yeast
fermentation and synthetic biology which
basically means we engineer the Genome
of of yeast to produce new and
interesting compounds by fermentation
and basically it's Akin I don't know if
you know but the yeast is this
microorganism that makes beer and wine
and bread and all these wonderful things
we we know and love but by playing
around with this genome you can get it
to produce other interesting compounds
basically in the same apparatus so our
fermentation process looks very very
similar to a process you'd see at a
brewery or at a drug manufacturing
facility what we do differently is we we
get that yeast to produce uh compounds
that it wouldn't natively produce
so we work within uh the psychedelics
value chain to manufacture psychedelics
we see a lot of difficulties in
extracting psychologists from their
native hosts particularly psilocybin
from mushrooms mushrooms aren't the
easiest organism to cultivate and
particularly they're very difficult to
standardize so we see fermentation as
this really nice Middle Ground where we
can get all of the sustainability
benefits of fermentation but we can
offer a much more consistent and stable
supply of of these compounds and
importantly uh cost one of the the big
advantages of yeast fermentation is the
cost that we can produce these molecules
and just as a rough input we're aiming
for to be to be able to develop or to
provide GMP grade psilocybin for dollars
per gram and even perhaps even lower
than that so the cost benefits are
really really significant
okay can we maybe break down the
difference between using fermentation
and biosynthesis for cannabinoids and
for psilocybin obviously psilocybin
let's with Starbucks first the quantity
of psilocybin per mushroom or per plant
is not replicable over and over again so
large-scale cultivation is not really a
a solution for large-scale drug
Discovery and development is that
correct well it is possible we just
argue that it's not very efficient so as
just a rough example
um psilocybin producing mushrooms they
produce psilocybin in the range of about
one percent dry Mass
um the the problem though is that on top
of producing psilocybin these mushrooms
also produce a range of structurally
related compounds so these are the
intermediates byproduct degradation
products and from a purification point
of view you have to invest a lot of
additional resources to separate your
compound which in this case is
psilocybin from the Myriad of other
structurally related compounds so it
does add a further complication step
it's also I mean and you know this if
you go to the supermarket and buy
mushrooms mushrooms are a hearty
creatures there are they have this tough
outer layer they're very difficult to
kind of
um burst open and so you have to invest
a lot of resources in order to get the
psilocybin out in contrast with our
fermentation method our yeast it grows
sensationally well in large scale
fermentation it simply secretes the
psilocybin into the surrounding media so
from a purification point of view that's
much easier and I think most importantly
our strains they only produce psilocybin
they produce nothing else that even
looks remotely similar to psilocybin so
from a purification point of view that
also makes it considerably easier
and so we can pretty much say the future
of this ingredient side about psilocybin
and rare cannabinoids is going to be
fermentation for the environmental
impact that it has the scalability it
has and as you said the dollars per gram
price do you see this over the next 10
years being the dominant player when it
comes to this out of the ingredient
Market
yeah we see it and yeast fermentation is
used to produce already a surprising
number of the ingredients in your daily
lives it's used to make vaccines
pharmaceutical drugs it's used to make
food ingredients biofuels bioplastics
that's already out there and
surprisingly large quantities I think
the area where it hasn't quite
penetrated to the to the extent as other
Industries is in small molecule
Pharmaceuticals so we see this as an
emerging application and when we looked
at psychedelics we you know psychedelic
the industry is being built mainly from
the ground up right this is not an
existing industry it's being built from
scratch and we see this as a really good
way to incorporate sustainability from
the outset instead of having to develop
an unsustainable industry and later go
in and improve it we see an opportunity
to use that from the get-go and we see
fermentation as the the most realistic
way of achieving this
and now let me move on to the
cannabinoid side of the industry
obviously everybody knows about CBD and
THC as the most prominent cannabinoids
but we all know that there's over 120
plus carnabinoids now when it comes to
those rare cannabinoids that are
available only in my new percentage is
the same process applied to psilocybin
or is there a different technique that's
used to extract these rare molecules
that that are at small scales
so in theory the story is very similar
right the the cannabis plant produces
100 different 120 different compounds
most of them an incredibly my news
amounts how do you gain access to those
but I think a key difference is that
cannabinoids are notoriously complicated
molecules and the way that the
biosynthesized is extremely complex and
far more complex than than most people
realize and so actually as a production
system the cannabis plant is in our
opinion probably the most efficient way
to get your hands on these molecules and
what we've seen in the last few years is
that we've seen in particularly breeding
techniques allowing us to gain access to
some of these these more rare
cannabinoids So in contrast to
psychedelics we we actually see
plant-derived cannabinoids as and
particularly a rare plant-derived
cannabinoids there's actually being the
major driver of the cannon bird market
where we fit into this value chain is so
we we don't have an interest in
manufacturing cannabinoids we think the
plant is doing a fantastic job it's
cheap it's readily available the problem
we see with cannabinoids is their their
properties and anybody who's worked with
cannabinoids knows that issues around
their solubility their stability and
particularly their bioavailability a
really rate limiting steps and so
actually what we're doing in this
industry is we're using fermentation and
again sustainable bio-based approaches
to convert natural cannabinoids into new
and improved compounds with these
improved properties so with this very
simple fermentation based method we
produce cannabinoids that are fully
water soluble are extremely stable and
have very high bioavailability and we
see this combination as really The Way
Forward where the cannabis plant
produces the molecules we improve them
and that's the product that makes it to
Market
we hear a lot of talk about the full
spectrum effect of all the cannabinoids
that come from a plant together is the
future of this industry if we're able to
biosynthesize molecules individually
creating new formulations that may not
necessarily already exist in the plant
but are more advantageous for whether
it's inflammation or whatever ailment it
may be
yeah so we do see this uh talked about a
lot the the the idea that multiple
cannabinoids and perhaps even
cannabinoids met with terpenes
synergistically work together to have an
improved effect and that that definitely
seems to be something that's happening I
think
when we talk about things like full
spectrum versus individual compounds I
think that's more of a reflection that
we don't fully understand how all of
these different molecules work together
and so until we really understand that
the strategy is just to to mix
everything together and assume that
they'll all work together the way that
we see it is that in the future I think
we'll understand in much more detail how
specific cannabinoids interact together
and we do see formulations where perhaps
it's a mix of two cannabinoids and maybe
a terpene that gives the over
overwhelmingly the therapeutic effect so
instead of having to mix you know a
hundred different cannabinoids together
you can just mix two or three perhaps
with the terpene and and that is your
therapeutic product
do you guys at octuring work on your own
formulations or use singly just focused
on distribution we create the molecules
and we bring them to companies who then
work on formulation is there a a big
need and a big want to get into the
formula formulation creating side of
things
so we're firmly a business to business
company so we work with um consumer
Brands but also pharmaceutical companies
or drug development companies to advance
products made by fermentation down the
value chain so in the case of something
like psychedelics we would work with uh
yeah mainly with pharmaceutical
companies to take lead candidates into
the clinic on the cannabinoid side we
work with consumer Brands who are really
looking at specific cannabinoids to get
into consumer products so for example uh
consumer facing company a might be
really interested in a water-soluble
version of CBD consumer Company B might
be really interested in CBG and we
developed the manufacturing process to
get those products into Market
how important is the Teeter amount when
it comes to the competition between
other companies in your Market is it is
a case of whoever gets the highest grams
per liter per hour is the winner of the
race or is there a scale of Purity that
can that can be more advantageous thing
going for the higher quantities
yeah so at the end of the day cost of
goods is the the most important
parameter right how much does it cost to
produce a kilogram
tiger is a really important aspect of
that but it's by far not the only
important thing to consider so we
consider yeah so tighter is a really big
thing but actually the most important
factor when it comes to costs is is the
cost to purify how much do I have to
invest to separate my molecule of
interest from the sometimes complex
fermentation broth and that I think is
is where at least in our point of view
is where most of them the r d investment
has put and how to purify
and is choosing the correct substrate a
difficult task or is it the same for
most companies
so I mean so so sugar is by far the most
commonly used bulk ingredient it's
incredibly cheap particularly compared
to the cost of the product right if
we're producing psilocybin at dollars
per gram glucose is cents per gram and
maybe even a little bit less than that
so I would say that
at least on the Psychedelic side not
many companies are thinking more
complicated than just adding sugar in
the in the case of cannabinoids I
actually think it's a little more
complicated it's as I said producing
cannabinoids is notoriously difficult
and producing it from glucose or other
sugars is is actually complicated as
well so I know that many other companies
are using sort of intermediates of the
biosynthetic pathway so things like
hexanoic acid which is more expensive
than glucose but it does make the
production process more efficient
when it comes to the biosynthesis of
cannabinoids is everybody starting with
olivetylic acid and geranophosphate and
combining those for cbga or is there an
easy entry point to start with THC or
CBD
so CBD and THC have for the most part
the end of the biosynthetic pathway so
there's not that many things you can
convert these cannabinoids and so
there's a few degradation products and
things like that the first
um sort of common intermediate is is
either hexanoic acid or in the case of
producing them the kind of big three THC
CBDs and
CBD CBG THC then all of italic acid is
is kind of the starting point wherever
you start there is a cost factor to
consider right glucose is cheapest
hexanoic acid is more expensive Olive
italic acid is more expensive again so
it really determines where your cost of
goods comes from I think the the goal of
synthetic biology is always to produce
complex molecules from very very simple
starting substrates so any synthetic
biologist always prefers to start from
glucose or something similar like that
as the starting point because that's
that's always going to be the cheapest
process but if there are difficulties
with the biosynthetic pathway like in
the case of cannabinoids then an
alternative could be something like one
of the intermediates
would we be right in saying that the
future especially in Europe at the
ingredient side of whether it's food and
beverage in cannabis or beauty and
makeup or Discovery development is going
to be led by the biotechnology companies
that the scalability and ability to just
extract extract from plant matter won't
be able to compete
I think it really has to be taken on a
case-by-case basis you know
again as a synthetic biologist we wished
we lived in a world where we could
out-compete every other process but
there are many examples where plants are
just cheaper and so I don't think you
can just apply a one-size-fits-all
approach you really have to look at the
individual compound you have to look at
the market that it's being applied to
and really holistically look at the best
way of of bringing that product to
Market in many cases the plant wins and
that that's okay we we believe that for
cannabis that the plant is going to win
over any other technique but there are
many other cases where different
molecules that makes uh Financial sense
to go for something like yeast
fermentation
it's been absolutely fascinating talking
to you Nick I wish we could have a
longer episode but we're nearly our 15
minutes time now for anybody who hasn't
ever checked out after in I highly
recommend it the website is below and
it'll be in all the descriptions but for
now Nick thank you very much for your
time it's very much appreciated
yeah thanks a lot nice to talk to you
until next episode everybody
[Music]