[Music]
welcome everybody to next episode of the
Cannabis review I'm delighted to join on
this episode by Arno valdo venos who's
the principal consultant at Canam
monitor based in Spain how you keeping
today
Arno very well thank you for having
me I'm delighted to have you on the show
um can you maybe give everybody a little
overview of you came into the industry
and your current position at caner
monitor sure so I've been involved in
the Canabis space Since U I was quite
young maybe too young even um but in a
in a professional sense um it all came
about about six years ago I started
working for a British consultancy I saw
it as an opportunity to merge my skills
in market research and consultancy with
one of my passions with which was the
the Cannabis plan and about three years
ago I started uh my own practice which
is Canam monitor working mostly with the
European clients on on Market
intelligence and and research on the on
the European
markets very good I'm going to start off
with the can of monitor report that you
guys have been working on in Spain can
you maybe give everybody an overview of
this report the sectors that it covered
is it just Spain specific and why this
would be valuable to a lot of the
European
operators yes so this is a report that
is focused on Spain we do not cover any
other markets even though it of course
they have some relevance also for the
for the Spanish Market because there are
some operators that are in both in both
cases and essentially the the goal was
to provide a comprehensive view on the
situation in Spain because now the
spanis is coming up everybody's asking
questions like uh what happens with the
clubs what happens with the uh what are
these CBD stores that I see on the
street etc etc and nobody knew exactly
how how the market is set up and what
are the uh the different segments and
The Operators and how how it all works
so essentially we cover uh pretty
comprehensively all the segments of the
industry um by by doing a a market
sizing in terms of um how many employees
there are what are the revenues
generated uh what have been the
investments in each segment of the
industry and this covers particularly
medical cannabis because it's now going
to get legalized finally in the country
but also CBD and also the hom growing uh
industry and also the the elcd market
which uh is very prevalent and growing
in in
Spain okay let's start with the Spain
and the medical cannabis industry over
there Spain has always kind of been one
of the Forefront leaders in Europe
everybody's known about the social clubs
for a long time but it's pretty
surprising that if you actually have
been checking on this territory that
there is no medical cannabis program at
all over in Spain and this new minister
of Health that's been brought in after
your general elections seems to be very
H Pro medical cannabis and bringing this
industry to the four can you maybe give
everybody a little breakdown of is flour
included is it regular pharmacies is it
specializ doctors what are the proposed
uh conditions that they're looking to
bring in for this Medical Market in
Spain yes so as we are speaking we do
not have the final version of the Royal
Decree that we legalize medical cannabis
in the country sadly uh however we know
what the ministry has said which is in
application of the conclusions of a
parliamentary commission that happened
in
2022 uh so we have some idea of of how
how it may play out
uh for now there are no mentions that
the flow are going to be included so it
seems like the regulator will choose uh
pharmaceutical forms in the form of
extracts it is not clear yet which which
of them probably oils but maybe a
different one also the list of of the
pharmaceutical forms could potentially
be expanded in the future which is also
important also how it is worded in the
sense of how easy it is to get new
formats in the in the scheme is going to
be massively important other factors are
the of course the the number of who can
prescribe which it looks like it's going
to be just Specialists and another thing
is who can dispense these products which
uh it looks like it might be only in the
hospitals but then again we do not know
how's the how the ging of this decree is
going to be therefore how easy it's it
will be to expand this dispensation also
also to community
pharmacies because obviously if you look
at at the map of Spain it's quite big
for the population it has so many
patients are going to be far away from
the from the far hospitals where they
need to get the their medicines so it
probably makes sense to allow Community
pharmacies to dispense as
well they seem to be taking a
conservative approach initially for the
first stage of this medical program but
as you said on a territory basis the the
cost and the traveling time frame for
patients who may be sick Hospital
pharmacies is a pretty a uh a reserved
strategy that they would take I would
imagine that the Pharmacy Union of Spain
are lobbying hard to be able to ensure
that their members are able to dispense
and sell these
products this is one of the advantages
of the new regulation which as you say
it's quite conservative I would say that
pretty much every country when they
first regulate medical cannabis they
tend to be pretty conservative as you
are very well aware in Ireland but also
in other uh markets in in Europe have
has had the the same the same situation
however one advantage that all the um
colleges of doctors and pharmacist are
on board with the with the new
regulation is that we're necessarily
100% on board with the regulations as
we're seeing now for instance in in
Germany with the
recreational legalization so it's quite
conservative but we certainly hope for
it to get expanded over time and sooner
rather than
later when it comes to the specialist
doctors that are allowed to prescribe is
this somebody who's a certified pain
specialist or a certified oncology
expert because I would imagine that if
teley medicine has got to be a big part
of the program in Spain due to as you
said the location of patients away from
major cities do you
see the the prescriptions being written
by a condensed small amount of
specialist doctors and if so do you
think there'll be any International
expertise that are able to take part in
the industry or would it be closed to
just Spanish
Specialists yes so sadly we do not know
yet the the specific list of specialist
that are going to be able to prescribe
however by looking at the indications
that the regulator wants to include
which are mostly pain and particularly
chronic pain which is also an important
thing to the fact that all chronic pain
patients are at least in theory going to
be able to be prescribed medical
cannabis we would assume that pain
specialists are going to are going to be
able to prescribe but uh we do not know
that uh it seems like the regulator is
uh very very worried about possible
diversion to the to the illicit Market
which is
um I mean it's probably more based on
their fears rather than than a real an
actual reality on the on the ground um
but it seems like at the beginning they
want to make sure that this is not
possible so things like uh tele medicine
and even something that is very normal
in Germany or or the UK like shipping
the products uh from the pharmacy to the
to the patient by the by the mail seems
like this is not going to be possible um
in the early stages of the new program
as it is not allowed for other medicines
in Spain
generally it also could be a positive
thing that doesn't allow one large
company to control the industry by being
able to deliver these medicines it seems
that there's going to have to be
localized clinics for each individual
territory yeah
maybe I think on the being that the the
market is going to be a magistral sector
so the pharmacist will need to prepare
each prescription according to the
indications of the doctor as it is in
Germany for instance um
in Germany we see that there are a a
relatively small number of pharmacies
that serve um the population through the
post and they can offer better price
prices and maybe better service and a
wider assortment assortment of products
than other pharmacies so I think that uh
allowing this type of things wouldn't be
bad at all for the system I think that
giving freedom to prescribe and freedom
to um to get the as as many products of
the greatest quality possible is always
the goal of a medical cannabis scheme
yeah and as you said there's no country
in the world yet that's just opened up
the gates for a medical Market it's
always been step by step and incremental
gains moving on to the next topic which
a lot of people have always been posting
about as the Social Clubs in Spain we're
a little bit detached over here in
Ireland and other parts of Europe we
kind of get headlines and the last big
headline was one of the Mayors in
Barcelona was looking to close down the
Social Clubs is this still the case and
if so are the Social Clubs so ingrained
in society that uh it is not possible
now to remove
them to be honest the landscape of
Social Clubs in Spain is highly
localized depending on the area in for
instance in in Madrid clubs have been
closed uh for for years they have been
um they have problems with the police
etc etc so one might say that Barcelona
was probably the hot bet of these clubs
and because apart from other areas but
Barcelona in particular um thanks to the
to some regulations developed by the
municipal Council so what we are seeing
now after the uh courts repealed these
Municipal regulations in the past due to
[Music]
some uh of course and the situation is
still quite uncertain there might be a
part of Simply uh populist tactics
because there's an ongoing pro security
situation in the city that the council
might want to look like they are uh
acting upon even though of course the
clubs um are are quite the harm
reduction uh initiative that actually
gets people out from the streets from uh
Street deal and so on so the the
situation could very well deteriorate if
uh the clubs were to be curtailed in in
their activities for now there have
there has been a ramp up in inspections
of these clubs um but it is not certain
at all what's what's going to happen in
the in the next few months it looks like
at least next week with the spanis uh
they are going to they are still going
to be open and to be honest as as as far
as I remember in the last few years they
have always been uh there has always
been concerns with the clubs regarding
their their
likely legal State status in the future
and this seems likely to to remain for
the time being because they are uh as
you are well aware it's not uh they are
not legal in the sense that they are
written into the legislation but rather
a loophole uh in the in the gray
area on a lighter note now you have
spannabis next week I reckon you'll be a
pretty busy man with everybody trying to
uh pull at you from all angles um are
you looking forward to spannabis have
you got a number of events lined up that
you plan on
attending yeah absolutely it's getting
better year after year it's it's no
longer only spanis but there's a a
plethora of parallel events some that
are more focused on the let's say
cannabis cups and contests others that
are more professional networking events
so yeah I'm I'm going to be attending
the Cannabis Hub which is a local entity
in Barcelona they are doing an event I'm
going to be attending the Cannabis
genomics Conference um which is a new
event created this year based on uh
genetics which just something very
interesting I will be at ICBC which is
of course B2B networking event and I
will be of course also at spanis and
looking forward to catching up with
everybody it's really nice having
everybody come to your city and uh so I
do not need to move for the networking
everybody comes to me yeah and I think
having something like spannabis and the
other uh satellite events around you is
nothing but good business for Canon
Monitor and anybody who's watching this
who's not reached out to R know yet if
you're remotely thinking about entering
into the Spanish Market or need
upto-date
uh Regulatory and Legal Information kind
of monitor the main place to be uh to be
checking out when you you go into the
Spanish Market or now I might get you to
make an introduction to the Cannabis Cup
Founders because I think that's
something that the viewers would love to
hear an in interview from the people who
managed the the Cannabis
Cup uh Cannabis Cup Founders the contest
you mean yeah the
contest okay let's Pi uh offline about
it yeah I will indeed we're just coming
up to the 15 minutes now uh again
anybody who's going into the Spanish
Market that hasn't dealt with rno or can
of monitor yet I highly recommend it
their website is going to be below in
wherever you're watching or listening to
this episode but for now our now thank
you very much for time we might even
touch Bas in a couple of weeks and you
can give us a rundown of how good the
span ofus week was and why everybody in
the global industry should be attending
that every
year amazing it's been an absolute
pleasure Owen I hope you have a great
day and great week and same to you AR
now till next episode
everybody