[Music]
another episode of the cannabis review i
am delighted to be joined by a news
desai
who is a a lawyer commercial lawyer and
a top leading cannabis has consulted
over london
and the host of one of the biggest
podcasts in the world the cannabis
conversation
he's had some of the biggest guests on
that you could uh imagine so i'm
delighted to talk to news how are you
keeping today
very good mate very good thank you for
having me on delighted to have you on i
look forward to talking to you for a
while you've
got a lot of insights i'm sure the
audience are going to love um do you
want to
get everybody just a little overview of
how you got to be a commercial lawyer
got into the campus industry quickly
just so everybody's up to speed
yeah sure sure so i my background is as
a commercial lawyer
mainly working in the media space so i
work for a variety of
uh big media companies in the uk um but
i
i kind of got a bit restless a few years
ago wanted to do something more
entrepreneurial so
uh quit my job kissed a few frogs
started my own business with a friend
um and then i kind of stumbled on
medical cannabis and at the end of 2017
i'd only known about it recreationally
before then um and
went to a few conferences and i was sort
of like wow
there's there's so much here um and it
has a real chance to
be a very positive impact on the planet
so
um i started to kind of you know read
more and and meet more
people but i couldn't really figure out
what i wanted to do so i started a
podcast
um because no one was really doing it in
europe at the time there's quite a few
american ones
um and yeah 110 episodes now in
um interviewed some great people across
the world and it's kind of ever
expanding really there's there's
more and more topics to cover so um so
yeah no that's been great
and off the back of that i i started a
commercial consultancy so
i still do a bit of lawyering but
alongside that i'm kind of helping
early stage businesses with anything
from sort of board advisor
type stuff to helping them with their
fundraising to
advising on strategic acquisitions
amazing yeah well you were one of the
inspirations for this show to start up
so
it's uh great to have you on i'm going
to kick things off get everybody up to
speeds when it comes to the regulations
that's been passed so far are we looking
at uk one eu nil
um i don't think i agree with that um
i mean it was a positive move that we
legalized uh
medical um a couple of years ago but the
reality is that
you know it hasn't really changed
anything um not not very many people
um have managed to get prescriptions on
the nhs
and it's been a real bone of contention
um
the framework and the education um
within the medical fraternity is is not
great and
so i think there's a crucial step as
well
your gp so your frontline access to to
medical
help is not able to prescribe so there's
another step that needs to go to a
consultant but those gps don't know when
to refer or who to refer to
um there's a huge amount of people
within the nhs that just didn't even
know that
the cannabis had been legalized
medically so the
you know the the knowledge just isn't
there yet so there's huge amounts of
work that needs to be done
um and in terms of you know in terms of
the wider reform um
we're we're very far behind so sadiq
khan actually the london mayor
last week announced that he would like
to open up the discussion around
decriminalization which is a you know
very positive move but
um boris johnson the next day squashed
it very quickly
saying that cannabis is a harmful
substance so
this is the level of ignorance that
you're you're dealing with um
and it shows how far we have to go um
and then you know
the tory government have never been
evidence driven when it comes to
um drug reform so i'm not hopeful
personally
but on the flip side they boris is
not averse to you turning at any moment
if it suits him
so if someone waves a bit of cash at him
who knows
he might just do that so you just don't
really know what i would say on the
eu side is i i think you know
there's a lot of positive moves on on
the eu side you know they're moving
they're allowing hemp varieties up to
point three percent thc which is sort of
bringing in line with the states
which i think is very positive and then
there's lots of the the individual
countries are doing lots of stuff so
france's new medical pro pilot program
got lots of stuff going on in the
netherlands german domestic production
switzerland raising its limit on thc to
1 so
i would argue that the eu is probably
being a bit more progressive
okay excellent because it's one of the
things you see a lot of financial
information coming out of london
and i don't know whether that's smoke
and mirrors and maybe convincing me that
it looks like it's moving quickly in the
uk compared to the european union
because
over in ireland here we've still got the
police force not enacting the european
council law that was brought
in december we've got a lady called
um veratumi has to pay 10 000
euros every two three months for a
bedrock and for her child which is
pretty much cbd
it's not as if it's some magic uh
formula they're getting so
it's good to hear that you think that
the eu are moving forward quickly i'm
going to move on to the next topic which
i swear
i should just say that i don't think
anyone's moving quick enough it's a
reality but yeah
yeah no i agree we were talking to petry
last week he's up in helsinki and cbd is
a
pharmaceutical drug in finland so again
i think this needs to be a lot of
consolidation
in the european union and hopefully this
is one of the things we're going to try
and do with the show to
reach out to as many different countries
and many different ceos and businesses
and try and get everybody on the same
page because
let's be realistic the north american
companies want a piece of europe
it's not going to be the other way
around i see europe creating the kind of
high-end
products that uh like the brandies the
champagnes the guinness i think within
time will come from european
manufacturers so
let's hope that's the case speaking
about european manufacturers
i'm very positive in terms of as much as
we've got a terrible government over
here
at the moment excuse me for this that
ireland is going to be the base for
european cannabis
the north american companies are already
positioned here with the low tax rate
that we've got we've got an
english-speaking workforce highly
skilled young workforce
would you agree with that statement or
do you see somewhere else in europe like
malta maybe
piping us to the to the number one spot
yeah i mean look it's difficult to say i
certainly think brexit has been a boost
for ireland for
some of the reasons you mentioned the uh
being english speaking
does make it very attractive for um
north americans
um to base their plus you know the tax
incentives that you mentioned
i think maybe you know ireland is very
strong in pharma
pharmaceuticals so um i was surprised to
learn that over a third of eu net
exports come out of ireland and i think
all of the major
pharma companies have a base in ireland
um
as a consequence so uh and and you know
obviously highlighted by the fact that
jazz
um pharmaceuticals bought recently
bought um gw
pharma so um i think on the medical side
of things
uh there it will certainly be an
important hub whether it would be
the the main hq for european cannabis i
don't know just because of the size
of ireland maybe maybe not but i think
it could be a very important player
um the things that you mentioned we've
had vera on the show as well
as were to sort of uh tell us about
what's happening in ireland and
um i've had leah fletcher as well on the
show and
you know ireland similarly to the uk has
quite conservative core uh you know at
its heart so
that's quite hard to to change and
modify
particularly such a thorny issue as
cannabis so
um you know i think there's a lot of
challenges for ireland but they're
certainly well placed i think
and and will benefit from brexit i think
yeah i think the one thing that's kind
of leaning ireland's way as much as
there's uh politicians in power at the
moment that mightn't
see it from what we've been told by
inside the government is that the
politicians have no problem legalizing
this it's senior civil servants that are
holding the whole thing up
so it's uh we've also got a history of a
country of having a loud voice and
i i feel sorry for the politicians at
the moment because if you go on to
twitter
they're getting hounded on the thousands
of tweets every day from all the
activists which is uh
exactly what needs to be done to help
educate and inform the guys to
bring this industry to the to the
standard that it should be there's no
reason why
the european country shouldn't be
creating our own brands and creating our
own versions
as opposed to just importing north
american products that let's face it
don't
uh are not as good a quality when it
comes to the european products on the
scale when you're manufacturing so
the next thing i wanted next thing i
wanted to talk to you about was
lots of things going on in in the uk at
the moment so
you've got the novel food and the lse
listings
that are happening do you think uk are
going to be the financial hub
for the european cannabis industry just
because the framework is already there
for
the investment and we've seen a lot of
the big investments in the llc's
listing so far uh it seemed to be a
positive move for london
um potentially i mean
again i think brexit is an issue for
this um
i mean already we're seeing on a general
level non-cannabis that um
you know london is is no longer the the
kind of financial hub
i think a lot of stuff is moving over to
amsterdam and frankfurt
um i think they're obviously being a bit
more progressive
by opening up to cannabis companies
listing um
but my concern would be around a
repetition of what happened in canada
and um you know a lot of these companies
who've
who floated in london they've got very
little meaningful revenues
and you know they're they're the market
caps are quite big
and they've they've ridden this hype
wave and
and maybe this is kind of public markets
i mean you're seeing it with crypto and
you're seeing it with
the kind of reddit uh type investors who
is
driving prices up because of kind of
putting together a groundswell of people
i don't think it's necessarily a good
thing and the retail investor often is
the one that kind of loses
out so i mean when you've got vast
valuations based on
very little revenues there's kind of
real detachment there and
you know it should really be about
building a business through your own
generating your own revenues and a bit
of private investments kind of get you a
bit bigger
and then once you're established then
you list but you know you've got
companies that are listing
before they're even doing it doing
anything and and that's very much what
happened in canada and then
in 2019 there was you know obviously a
bit of a crash there so
my my worry would be that some of things
happen in london and then what happens
is the regulators and
and the exchanges then sort of clamp
down and they don't
allow cannabis companies to list so i
think there's a risk there if it's not
handled well um i would like to see you
know genuine companies
that are listing um on the on the flip
side of that
i think it does it does get quite a lot
of headlines
and what that means is that a lot of
people it gets a lot of people's
attention so people start to see it as a
more
um grown-up industry that draws in more
talent
and hopefully some more institutional
money which
brings a bit of stability and so from
that perspective i think it could be a
good thing you've got other things going
on as well there's some m
a action as well so mc being bought by
true relief
which is a very big deal in terms of
numbers um
uh you know i think it's much more of a
signal to the market than anything else
and similarly we'll we'll create a bit
of a buzz around
um about the industry in general and i
think people will be like oh wow this is
actually something real here
um so i think it's good from that
perspective yeah well that's i think the
big numbers as much as some of them are
inflated and
not driven by real core value or
turnover anything like that is the thing
that a lot of the politicians and people
who have no clue are looking at
and they're just seeing how many jobs
can we make how much money are we going
to make and that seems to be the
deciding factor for a lot of them
tell me this your opinion on the next
two to three years europe versus the uk
who do you think comes out on top
um i don't really know i mean
it it's too difficult to tell when when
you're talking about
cannabis wider cannabis medical cannabis
i think uk is a bit behind
i think you know you've got germany's
well i mean fifty thousand
prescriptions maybe 5 000 patients um
and you've got certain other european
countries that are being more
progressive i think we're
we've got something here but it's just
it's quite hidden and i think we need
some proper reform
and i just don't think the government at
the moment is is minded to do that and
and for good reason i think kovit is
obviously
the massive priority for everyone and
then getting the economy back on board
from the latter part of that cannabis
could feature as a way to do that but
um it's by no means certain and you know
we've seen very successfully some
lobbying from the people
in this in relation to the european
super league in football
recently so i don't think that
unfortunately cannabis has the same kind
of galvanizing
across the the spectrum but um but you
could see
you know quite concerted effort to push
that thing um
i think yeah and we haven't talked about
novel foods but they're um
how that kind of pans out will be quite
interesting too um
can you tell me this is the novel food
in the uk applicable to europe
you're putting me on the spot here um
i've noticed i've been told it's not
you'd have to have a second license and
eu license now that brexit's gone true
i've been told that too but it's unclear
because i've heard
of conflicting statements on that and
it's not an area i specialize in around
licensing and regulatory so
i couldn't tell you that it's going to
be interesting you know there's a lot of
people that spent a lot of money on
getting that clearance and um but the
regulators just don't have the resources
to police it or
enforce it so we will see what happens i
think what will happen is it'll be
self-enforcing because if you've spent
100 grand on
on on all the testing you're not going
to want to see
someone down the road who hasn't done
any of that continue to sell so they'll
be dubbing each other in i think
a lot of that yeah now well i think one
of the positive things for europe that
we can look forward to because it's a
multi-state
uh that we're upping under germany is
kind of our test model at the moment
and germany have made massive the green
party have made massive gains over in
germany recently so
we could end up seeing germany with a
recreational market before a lot of the
other
countries come true and hopefully if
that's the case then the eu countries
will just replicate the model that
germany have
integrated in i think so and twins with
what's going on in the states i think
yes
i agree yeah yeah now it is it's it's an
exciting time for the industry
uh as i said we can try and keep it to a
short enough time for this i want to
thank you very much for coming on the
show
it's been very much appreciated very
informative and i hope we can talk again
towards the end of the year with some
more updates for each other absolutely i
appreciate it thank you for having me on
and keep up the great podcast mate it's
very informative and very enjoyable
cheers
cheers thank you