[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined in this episode by dr marcus
rogen who's the president and ceo of
delic labs how you keep it today marcus
um thank you very much uh cso uh ceo i
gave up that job too to a
more business-minded person so i can
focus on the science
yeah okay very good do you want to want
to give everybody a quick little
overview of how you ended up in the
cannabis industry and at dillik labs
okay uh this is a quick 15-minute talk
so that won't be the full story but in
short uh phd in chemistry and then
serendipitously while i was doing my phd
my postdoc in california i got into the
cannabis industry um it was
recreationally legal in
uh colorado at the time and medically
illegal in canada in california and so
my camera can can my chemistry skills
brought me into the field
well what is it exactly that you guys
specialize at at your laboratory
so
we are in vancouver canada so that we
can get research licenses from the
canadian government on cannabis and
psychedelic compounds and we partner
with the university of british columbia
to do fundamental research in both the
field of analytics and and
process chemistry uh of can cannabis
to help producers
and end consumers
uh
make better products
okay and do you see
i've been reading up and researching a
lot about creating your own cell line to
use precision fermentation to create uh
both psychedelic compounds and
cannabinoid compounds do you see that as
being the future of that let's say the
ingredient side of this of this industry
so i'm a chemist and therefore i will
always talk down on on a plant scientist
and say no no no uh it's it's the post
post-processing but
hear me out so yes
grow environment grow conditions
fertilizers can influence
the chemical profiles the plants express
that is that is correct so
everyone talks about the strains or the
cultivars of of of cannabis
but the grow environment is actually
more influential than the dna
so because what what people care about
is the chemical profile so the chemovar
of of the plant
and
i prefer to uh influence that in
post-production so when we
harvest the plant how do we dry the
plant how do we cure it then how do we
extract it and then package it into the
various products
and
there
currently is
done so much in extraction that there's
very little left over from the original
chemovar fingerprint of the plant
and and a lot of my research or our
research is on to optimizing these
extraction processes to better
express the chemical profile of those
plants in the extraction process and
therefore in the final product
okay so the extraction process is
basically manipulating the end product
to be as purified and exact as you want
and whatever about the initial flower
was that you get to change and alter it
so much that it's it is as clean as
the biotechnology method is it yes yes
that's correct so uh if you think about
it in its basic form the cannabis plant
produces thc or a thc asset and people
care about thc because that makes them
high so how do you get it out of the
plant and how do you put it in a vape
cartridge or final product if you only
think about a single compound then it's
relatively easy
it's extraction and the purification but
when you think that
cannabis is designed as a recreational
product because of all the flavors and
and the higher feelings one gets from
them um pure thc doesn't do it there's
the interplay of various compounds so
now we have to track multiple compounds
and they all behave slightly different
in extraction and purification and it
gets a very complicated multi-factorial
optimization problem
and
there
can be experience uh there can be
uh
chemometrics to do this work but it's
all like a single dial at a time new
experiment pro process
so we then quickly shifted in our
company to use machine learning
because these these algorithms can track
way more uh
variables at a time and optimize for all
of them
instantaneously and so we we work with
cannabis producers to take in all their
data run it through our machine learning
process and then with bayesian
optimization so if you want to look that
up on wikipedia uh we then narrow down
on on the best method and we can then
optimize for
yield cost purity or or flavor profile
yeah i actually wanted to move on to ai
and cannabis next is it's a great
transition there two things i had a
question for an ai in cannabis is
computer vision ever going to be
something that would be utilized to to
let's say monitor the health of a plant
better that the human eye could do and
is machine learning capable of
recommending what i suppose is deep
learning if you're recommending
blends and formulations of different
cannabinoids and terpenoids and
flavonoids that that may become future
ingredients or products
actually all of that is already
happening
so we have our niche of ai and machine
learning in extraction and and cannabis
analytics finding new compounds so we
we're using like language ai to
interpret
mass
fragmentation patterns to find new
cannabinoids and then track them so it's
really fun and cool for for like the
geeky chemist but but for your question
on computer vision so i've actually
worked with two startup companies that
used computer vision
to track the health of cannabis plants
so they had cameras in the in the
ceilings of grow rooms and would then
monitor the plants
and could spot
pests or diseases earlier so that a a
cultivator could then selectively treat
that one plant or remove that
diseased leaf before it spread through
the whole room
and and secondly there's a company
so so the first company was uh
deep green ai um i'm not sure if they're
still around but they they probably
folded their technology in some other
application
and then
but computer vision can also be used in
other aspects for example trimming
so the cannabis plant
is harvested and the flower buds are
then manicured with scissors to make
this to have this nice shape and
appearance
for the end consumer and that's quite
labor intensive
so um a friend uh john goa
uh had this company
um
oh sorry no
i'm missing the company i will figure it
out in a moment so uh he
built his company built robots
uh that
manicured cannabis flower buds into
these nice end products and to do that
they needed to look at the flower from
all angles understand what is flower
what is leaf what needs to be trimmed
where does it need to be cut
and so they were training
the ai the computer vision of
interpreting
what what this pla what this robot is
looking at
uh and so this his company he then sold
it on to like a a larger conglomerate in
the cannabis space so this is still
around
okay very good amazing quick question is
cryogenically frozen cannabis the best
way to treat cannabis once it's fresh
and grown
depending on what you want to do with it
okay so for me let's say we want to make
flour as the end product we want to make
vape cartridges the end product and we
want to use it as an edible is it
suitable for all three of those or is it
perfect for just one of those no so so
cryogenically frozen it basically just
means like freezing it very really
quickly yeah
so if you have to see in the bad
batman movie with mr freeze that's
carogenically frozen
but it it basically just arrests the
plant right it's still wet it's still
fresh it's just frozen in time
so if you now want to
use ice water hash or key things so to
separate the trichome heads that are
rich or that produce all the
cannabinoids from the rest of the
biomass then that is quite good because
it's fresh it's brittle and you can
easily remove them by agitation
but you can't smoke it because it's
still wet
it's just frozen but it's still wet so
you can't smoke it
you can do
cryogenic drying
so freeze drying
so you you freeze the material
cryogenically freezing material and then
you go through freeze dry cycles
and those are
potentially
really
beneficial to to remove the water and
keep more terpenes on the on the flower
but so they would potentially give you a
more
flavorful
smokable product
um
and and there are some companies in the
space that are that are working on these
aspects
linda for example um a gas supplier they
they have some technologies in the space
and
uh then lastly is it useful for
extraction no not at all because
extraction uh doesn't really want to
deal with water so you have the cannabis
plant frozen but it's still full of
water so for co2 extraction that's done
above room temperature
um it would have to thaw anyway and all
the water just really
uh throws the extraction out of whack
what is the cannabis campaign database
why did you guys set it up and what is
it so why is it so important for the
industry
sure happy too uh when i got into the
cannabis industry in like 2014
uh there were like four cannabinoids
known that people tested for you could
get basically standards for those and
that was it uh and in the academic
literature you already knew about like
50 80 compounds and then over time it
extended to like 150 different
cannabinoids that are known
uh but nowadays you can only buy 16
reference standards and testing labs
only test for like 10 cannabinoids so
you see there's a big difference between
like what information you can get on a
piece of paper from from the producer or
from the testing lab and what actually
is in the plant and then there's
research by professor dr mary
out of israel uh that really shows that
it's beyond these ten cannabinoids that
actually have biological effects uh so
he did some anti-cancer screens where he
found some really minor cannabinoids
that don't even have names yet that that
kill the tumor but thc isn't really
doing the work
and so i was always intrigued
um
what actually is in the cannabis plant
because if i want to do good extraction
or get the right product for the right
medical need i need to understand what
is in there i can't just
make a product where
eighty percent of the ingredient is
unknown to me
right i need to know what's in there so
therefore we just started scouring the
academic literature
and doing our own experiments to then
figure out what different compounds are
in the cannabis plant hence cannabis
compound database
so we just like hand curated that at the
beginning
and now that we have
better analytical tools in our lab
with our language ai to to figure out
new cannabinoids
we then start adding them as well to our
database and we hope that
this database can then use by other
people
to look at their
com their material or their spectra
their analytical runs and compare it and
then maybe we can help them through that
database figure out what they have in
their material
so that that's the basic idea
amazing yeah it seems uh how do you
useful for the the industry it's been an
absolute pleasure talking to you marcus
i hope we get to chat again in the near
future for anybody who wants to learn
more about dillik labs there's the
website below it'll be in all of the
links and all the platforms that you're
watching so thanks again for taking the
time mara because it's very much
appreciated
great thank you very much thanks
everybody until next episode
[Music]