foreign
who's the master grower at Hellenic
Dynamics how you keeping today Toby
how are you very well thanks thank you
very much for taking your time to join
us I know you're a very busy man
it's lovely to be really there's no
finer topic of conversation on the
planet this is it right so no better
person to be able to go through this for
can you maybe give everybody a quick
little overview of how you came into uh
Hellenic Dynamics and your position
there
yeah so the last four years which is
basically the the legal medical time uh
in the UK for for me uh I've designed
five different large-scale medical
cannabis cultivation facilities in
different countries in Europe uh and
coming into Hellenic I was attracted by
the idea that Greece has got a really
low cost of production uh and it's got
land labor and so on uh and it's got a
direct export route to Germany which of
course is the most exciting Market at
the moment in Europe
yeah it certainly is even with the scale
back announcement that they made I still
think there's a lot of room for growth
for uh companies it doesn't have to be a
complete waterfall and Deluge initially
at the start sometimes refining the
process and having a little bit of delay
could be good for the end consumer yeah
that's right I mean the legalization
model is a is a reflection of the
dominant political culture isn't it and
in Germany it's quite surprisingly a
little they've gone for a much less
regulated much less corporate if you
like much less if you suppose
capitalistic model and in my heart I
welcome that very much in terms of
spreading the benefits of the plant
throughout society as fast and as he and
its inequality as you can possibly hope
for
yeah agreed on to the cultivation side
of things what's the difference between
just a normal grower and a master grower
how big of a Chasm how many years of
experience and is it an extra layer of
knowledge let's say a biology or
chemistry can you explain a little bit
on that please yeah great question uh
well obviously there's there's no one
size fits all exactly but the key
differences will be around scale so uh
you're bringing a very different
approach to the HVAC and the fertigation
systems you're just doing everything
much bigger so that's pretty obvious and
fine
the other part is the regulations you're
working within a highly highly regulated
industry so you're thinking about GMP
regulations you're thinking about gacp
criteria you're thinking about all of
the pharmaceutical processes batch
Master records uh Secure Storage and a
lot of the other elements that the you
know your legacy grows if you like won't
really have to think about at all uh
then you're doing some trade-offs really
in the in the process there are some
things in the medical world of of
growing of Master growing uh that you
where there are a lot of processes that
that you can't you don't have really
free choice if you're a legacy grower
you make choices you find a line through
the various trade-offs uh about the
equipment and the process you're going
to use and you will stick to that line
I found less freedom I think to choose
for example you're really going to be
almost bound to use some substrate such
as as Rockwell an inert substrate such
as Rockwall you're probably not going to
be using living organic soil which in
some ways is a shame uh because you've
got to use that cleanliness you want to
think about the labor
um cost of of inputs whereas in the
Legacy time you're not thinking uh
you're simply aiming only for for what
pleases you and of course in that
process you've got a lot of other
hurdles stability testing uh your car
product can't just come out of your
facility and go straight to the consumer
uh it needs to go through a
pharmaceutical process of checking a
certificate of analysis uh checking on
the stability to see how long the shelf
life will be and all of those things
that are that are constraining I suppose
but and ultimately irrelevant to the
growth so a lot of those intellectual
steps and pharmaceutical steps that
you'll need to think about with the
ultimate aim of course for uniformity of
the product
um and and thinking about how you can
please a a medical pharmaceutical
audience rather than you know I suppose
your friends and and so on in in your
community
okay very interesting we recently spoke
to Professor Anna Schwab and she uses
aquaponics in 420 Organics what kind of
cultivation methods do you guys employ
that uh make the product more unique
than let's say some of the other Market
competitors yeah we try and keep it as
simple as possible we've got tables
we've got drippers we've got Rock Hall
uh
now it's really all about light intent
the three major things that I've
actually got to get right I've got to
get the genetics right I've got to get
the lights their intensity and Spectrum
right uh and I've got to get the HVAC
right so that I can control the humidity
and temperature to exactly the right
recipe for those particular genetics and
without the ability to control your
genetics to lighting and uh and your
HVAC you know that's taking those are
those if you get those right they're
taking you I'd say 70 of the way to
success and the rest of it the CO2
injection the fertilizers and everything
else are quite small increments in terms
of your success criteria
and so then it comes to post-harvest the
Mastery and scientific
Artistry that's required for that
element of the the shall we say is that
something that's gained over time
through trial and error is is again is
that kind of the last level of the
computer game type thing the ones you
master the the post-processing you can
guarantee your product is going to be
replicable yeah I think I spend more
time worrying about my post Harvest than
I do about the action cultivation the
Horticultural bit that might sound a bit
strange but a bit like for the wine guys
you grow good grapes you can only
destroy their quality as you turn them
into wine in the vinification system
it's exactly the same with cannabis
cultivation you can grow great flowers
and you can only ever lose their value
as you go through the post-harvest uh
and it's so simple we're not after the
flower itself we're after the trichome
that very fragile glossy little
mushroom-shaped thing on the outside of
that plant where all the magic is and
those are very very very delicate
components of the plant so even just
shaking the plant a little in the air
means those trichomes will detach
particularly the head of those trichomes
will detach and will float in the air
and if they if you're smelling them they
have moved in the air up your nostril
and it means they haven't then gone into
the product or into the medicine at the
end of the day
okay very interesting and
what are the kind of some of the biggest
challenges that you face as a master
grower in the UK is there are massive
hurdles compared to let's say what's
happening in Greece
um how would you compare the two areas
for the ability to cultivate yeah
interesting they're both emerging areas
in the UK you've got maybe a dozen uh
cultivation licenses probably only four
or five of which are going to go beyond
the research and development phase and
get into
um
uh you know into the market now
grief the wonderful thing about Greece
is you you've got open export routes to
the whole of Europe the real problem I
think with the UK cultivators and you've
got a higher cost of of of
um production naturally uh B you don't
have any sunlight but really crucially
you can't export so that means the
success of your business and your
cultivation regime is entirely based on
the growth of medical patient demand in
the UK and I think as any most observers
would would say that hasn't been as
Rapid or as or as solid there's a lot of
churn in the market for the patients uh
as we'd all hoped in the last four and a
half years that we've been involved
and when it comes to what's happened
around Europe It looks interesting now
that it could end up potentially be the
grown home laws get approved in most
countries for two or three plans do you
see that side of the industry like on
Research I've done already if you do
like the top 10 cannabis Industries in
America like Scott's Miracle Grow must
be two and a half billion bigger than
every other cannabis company there is
there European equivalent over here or
have they got patents and IPS and
processes in place where it's just got
to be doing the exact same as they've
done in America over in Europe
yeah all the indoor grows you it doesn't
really matter where you are in the world
you're thinking seriously about your
electricity cost and your labor cost and
those are your major determinants of
success you've got a transportable
recipe that you can implant in any
insulated space with an electricity and
water supply broadly uh more complicated
when you get to Glass House growing
where you've got to be very clear about
keeping control over the the the
temperature and humidity and I think
this is where some non-cannabis Growers
tomatoes peppers they'll be very good at
producing a very uniform crop at a very
large scale
um and I think sometimes
they they trip over the previous
experience in the they don't think
clearly enough about the post-harvest
bit that we've just talked about a
tomato gets harvested broadly it sits at
a certain temperature and humidity in a
storage area and it doesn't particularly
degrade in its quality uh so you'll see
a lot of the American Growers often have
an experienced Legacy grower working
alongside a tomato or pepper
horticulturalist and that's great but
the little question I wonder about is
the political one about who actually
really calls the shots out of those two
when it comes down to a difference of
opinion
yeah very interesting do you see uh the
Czech government doing let's say gone a
step further than what Germany have
announced do you think that's going to
be on par pretty much similar of what
they've done we saw that at the
Uruguayan similar model to Uruguay with
five grams per day do you have details
on that yeah I think that's the check is
going to be really an interesting Market
but then there's a a a a mass involved
here too you've got 10 million people in
check you've got 85 million in Germany
uh and and so you you know you would
expect that the Germans will have will
have to produce in in another way too uh
what do we really want we want
um access for all the people who want it
medical or not really uh at the end of
the day and look at the UK we're a good
probably five or ten years behind some
of those other countries you just
mentioned in Europe
a country of 68 million people with I
would say there's no data but I would
say at least 2 million regular consumers
of cannabis in the UK now that's an
attractive Market to anybody but all of
the larger companies and I talked to
many of them regularly from Australia
from Canada and so on they're all
looking at the UK
waiting for those trigger points to
enter that market and is it when GPS get
to prescribe or is it when patient
numbers reach a hundred thousand in the
UK whatever it is there are large
companies waiting to count from the UK
and I think at the moment really we're
very much in the foothills
um and I think we've had four and a half
years of experimentation and I think it
was a really long way for us to go in in
the UK in terms of matching the
regulatory framework with the huge
opportunity to build a new business here
I mean the common everyone knows the
common sense reasons for liberalizing or
destigmatizing or decriminalizing or
whatever you want to say cannabis it's
just so obvious raise some taxes
grow an industry
use skills of the people stop wasting
police time stop the stabbings all of
these social and environmental benefits
can be picked up by a sensible
Progressive liberalization model and I'm
really excited to say that the UK
government hasn't got on that at all
yeah it's from outside looking in it you
try and wonder who's worse for cannabis
curious armor or Rishi sunak the boats
seem to be charging against each other
to to have nothing but negative things
to say about the industry we've got a
Citizens assembly on drugs legalization
in Ireland happening at the moment with
all the expert politicians and a number
of advisors and one of the things that
the guards brought up is the difficulty
that would end up happening with the UK
if we went off and decriminalized a
number of different drugs so yeah it
seems we're going to be bound by each
other by the decisions what our other
makes yeah
fundamentally to the heart of society
I'm sitting here half a mile away from
Westminster apparently the seat of all
political thought or something look
we're way behind
um Kia stama has his own reasons for
being clean and getting himself and his
and his labor party
um elected without any contentious parts
of their Manifesto
um the conservative party perhaps has a
more libertar libertarian side to it but
neither party I think is is taking this
issue seriously and there's it's not
just the threat it's not just the the
stigmatization
um it's the opportunity that that it's
heartbreaking to see governments going
year after year without really grasping
this and if we're not careful the states
will liberalize federally at some point
and we won't have built an industry on
in this country that can compete with
what is to come from North America in in
that case so time is against us and the
opportunity is here and it seems a great
shame that neither of the political
parties in the UK is really thinking
about it sensitively they've set up a
framework and good on them fair enough
for if you like by exception
liberalization if you're exceptionally
ill sadly or you can have an exceptional
part of the plant CBD and quite right
four and a half years ago in the UK they
could no longer hold back the floodgates
of public demand for
cannabis based oils for childhood
epilepsy for example or the incredible
benefits of being able to manage not
cure but manage long-term illness like
multiple sclerosis or something and
perhaps end of life care too and great
it was not possible for politicians to
hold back that time but they didn't go
nearly far enough and there's a big
difference between there's no difference
in the plant medical cannabis is the
same as any or cannabis right but
there's a difference in the approach and
the market and and the ability to build
the infrastructure to serve um and to
take money away from people
um on the criminal side of things who
are not always thinking about the best
social and environmental benefits of
their production systems
here here Toby here here we've just had
our time but thank you very much for
joining us it's been an absolutely great
conversation hope we can touch base
again towards the end of this year and
have party with this conversation
lovely to talk to you thank you very
much for anybody wants to know more
about Hellenic Dynamics there's the
website below Ohio recommend checking
them out here Toby thank you very much
mate and for everybody else we shall see
on the next episode
[Music]