[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined on this episode by brian yogger
he is the founder and ceo of lemon haze
one of the hottest brands in america
over the last 12 months in the cannabis
industry brian how are you keeping
hey oman how are you thank you so much
for having me on i'm excited about this
delighted to have you on right i've been
following over the last 12 months you
guys seem to have skyrocketed with the
golf event that you had over in
america and i think a couple of other
different events that you're going to be
changing the course how people network
in the cannabis industry can you maybe
give everybody a quick overview of how
you kind of went from american football
college coach into uh founding lemon
hayes in the cannabis industry
yeah you know it's funny literally it's
almost like you take three steps
backwards and tripped over the dog and
fell into cannabis but it's been an
absolute amazing ride but yeah you hit
that nail around the head you know
growing up and coming out of college my
goal had always been to coach college
football which i did after playing uh
did that for 12 years um and as that
started you know i did that all over the
country from schools here in the big 12
to the ivy league
and as that kind of started to run its
course
i ended up actually moving back to my
hometown of austin texas
and starting my first company
back in austin that was actually a
construction company
did that for a few years when uh kind of
out of the blue
a um an opportunity came about for me to
[Music]
move to seattle and get into the
cannabis industry when at that time only
two states washington state and colorado
were legal so i got in very very early
um in washington state
uh and after the the original reason i
had moved there kind of fizzled out i
decided that i really liked the industry
and i wanted to
i wanted to
keep going so i started uh what was a
company called ted trigger it's a
precursor to lemon haze it's what is now
currently lemonade and believe it or not
we actually started as a data company we
were doing a lot of the data for the
recreational marijuana industry
in washington state
um we started putting on events to
promote our data we started doing those
events were strictly business to
business industry events
and all of a sudden we looked up and we
were having a whole lot of success with
events and the dad was kind of uh
stagnant so
we moved over full time into events and
i was in you know started in 2015 and
started 2019 started expanding uh
nationally um
started getting into oregon california
and nevada
um then this funny little thing called
covid came around you might have heard
about it um
put a put brakes on pretty much all of
our expansion plans
then you know we started looking at an
idea of how to come out of covid with
events and golf was socially distance it
was outdoors
it made sense and
we just said you know what let's just
limit it to
executives for networking like you
talked about c-suite vps and directors i
know and it just took off like a bottle
ship and before we knew it we were doing
eight tournaments around the country in
eight different states so it was just a
ton of fun and we just keep going with
it now
amazing that's kind of brings me
straight on to the first topic i wanted
to talk about lemon haze going for a
hole in one which are kind of new
networking events
i'm over in dublin and i kind of heard
about it about golf channels and to the
cannibals channel so it kind of proves
to you that the event was a roaring
success if it kind of found its way to
me without anybody kind of sending any
information i think there's definitely a
need you probably agree in the industry
there's enough events that people go to
and it's the same kind of circular thing
you go around a couple of boots and
unless you're a sociable person it's
very hard to kind of network at those
events it'll get dominated by a specific
kind of personality person wears with
golf you're stuck with a group of four
people you can get to know that person a
hell of a lot better let them know their
industry but better maybe you have a few
different questions that you'll be able
to formulate over a couple of hours time
do you see this being the cure sore for
you kind of moving into the other
territories where you're going to have
networking events outside of gulf as
much as golf will be a success for you
guys do you see
other uh other territories for growth
absolutely and it's the perfect segue to
get into new states it's perfect way to
get in to new markets um
even markets outside the united states
but yeah and so it's funny how you said
that about about the trade show and
that's really where the concept came
around and which has really always been
our basis here at lemonades is when i
just mentioned before when i got out of
coaching i started my first company down
in austin as a construction company and
i would go to the and i would do trade
shows and i would sit for three days
behind the booth and i talked to 350
people of which only eight of them were
the ones i actually wanted to talk to
because everybody else was
was you know just a random somebody from
a different area and then i found that
after three days of sitting at a booth i
was making all my business deals at the
after party so the whole concept the
lemonades is really simple
it was
kind of eliminate the actual trade show
part of it of all the of all the the
random randoms
and get the exact people you want to
network with put him put him in some
kind of a party in this case a golf
tournament and uh and at that point
you're basically putting the trade show
in the after party and that's where your
networking is and
so when you do one of our golf terms not
only are you playing with the uh
executives that you may want to that you
want to meet around the country but we
also have you know cocktail parties
before you know before the actual
scramble and then we have the cocktail
party afterwards with the awards and
everything
so you have a you have actually
at our events you have you know two
hours before the golf two hours after
the golf and four and a half to five
hours during the golf to network with
executives from all over the industry
and being able to move that around from
market to market because as you know
we're not federally legal here in the
states yet and so
we're only legal on the state on the
state level so normally if you go from
state to state not a lot changes but in
this case doing an event in california
nevada
massachusetts and florida you might as
well be doing them in france belgium
germany and you know and ireland it's
just there it's you're they're totally
different
uh they're totally different industries
from each other and there's people you
need to meet in each one of those
industries and that's what we've been
able to give people
yeah the layout of the different uh
nuances of government in each state is
going to allow for you guys to step in
and basically be a great interstate kind
of networking event it's a genius idea i
have to admit and i look forward to at
some stage i'll get over to you guys and
i'll get to have a few rounds and throw
down because i'm a pretty mean golfer i
like to think myself so i'm going to
move on to the next topic and it's
something that uh you probably agree
with me in this and a lot of people who
actually know what they're talking about
well bud tenders did he underestimated
entry point to consumers
how important do you think
both tenders are to brands and their
entry point into the consumer because
i've i've talked to a number of people
excuse me on the on this uh
series of episodes and some of the
smartest guys have been previous both
tenders in stores and in cannabis are in
canada and in colorado so what do you
think the future for the boat tenders
and some of the events and stuff and and
connection events you see happen for
these
yeah and the bud tenders in my opinion
the blood tenders are just as important
as the executives are when it comes to
this industry so we have the you know
obviously with our golf tournament where
all our golf tournaments are limited to
c-suite vp and directors
uh of those cannabis companies and
because those are the decision makers of
who's going to buy their treatment
equipment their pos their data equipment
whatever it may be however
the blood tender is as equally important
to the industry as anybody else and the
reason being the blood tender is quite
literally the sales person for every
single brand in existence to the
consumer um you know every other like we
talked about every state's different
every country is different but
at least here in the united states right
now if you walk into a dispensary or a
retailer in any state in this country
whatever product you buy is going
through the hands of a butt tender that
but you're gonna you don't you don't
walk up to the shelf here and pull
something off the shelf and walk it up
to the cashier you literally walk in you
just talk with the butt tender and you
ask them what they have or you tell them
what you want and they're and if you
know what you want they're going to grab
it for you but 90 of the time people
walk in and say
i want marijuana and the blood tender
kind of goes you know which one
and then they have to ask you know
you're looking for something for for
energy to sleep to whatever and whatever
that bud tender recommends is usually
what that consumer is going to pay for
so that bud tender is the sales person
to
to the for the entire industry to the
entire consumer base
in that market so they they're just as
important as anybody else
yeah i would agree which i think when
you have uh for federal legalization
over the states the m a's that will
happen will then uh
i think blood tenders real value will
come to market then i think it'll be
like having the high end similier in a
michelin star restaurant the guys who
really know what they're talking about
and really understand the ingredients
and like a good dj know what genetics
are coming out before they kind of hit
the market are those kind of guys will
be at a premium
value
and i'll tell you what that's going to
i'll give you one step further where i
exactly agree with you it'll be in the
same way especially when we do get into
federalization where all of a sudden
you'll probably see a lot of the growing
in the country you know uh go to certain
areas of the country similar to how
breaks are generally done in florida
you'll see a lot of the i think a lot of
the outdoor brewing go to tobacco
tobacco row or southern oregon northern
california and it's going to become like
wine where you're going to have these
huge outdoor crops that come in and you
know your you know 2023 crop is not
going to be the same as your 2024 crop
but that button is going to be just like
a somebody
at a at a great wine bar or wine shop is
going to be able to tell you the
different vintages and the different
years you're gonna start seeing the
exact same thing
in marijuana not only when it comes down
to um simple things like
i hate these but the good old-fashioned
state of indica um
a hybrid but when it comes down to
actually
your your premium products and and which
crops they come out of them which props
are better than other ones same way
advantages of one
yeah i agree
the the real cannabis consumer doesn't
really care about having a high thc
content it's more about a blend of
terpenes uh a mix of caramel noise that
are basically going to suit whatever
lifestyle they fit cannabis into for
them because i think cannabis is a
lifestyle for a lot of consumers and
they're they're long
are lifelong consumers as well when you
get them
it's been a great year for yourself for
the last 12 months what have you got
planned for 2022
so we are you know we are doubling down
on what we have so we've identified
we've identified three segments in the
industry to be the most important
segments in the industry one we just
discussed which is the blood tenders the
butt tenders are
the sales person for every brand in the
industry the second is the actual buyers
because you know those buyers that
decide decide which products are going
into those dispensaries that the butt
tenders can push and the third is the
executives that we talked about so
currently we're in 12 states doing
events with bud tenders
with bud tenders buyers and executives
going into 22 we are going to expand
that now so we're adding four more
states onto our repertoire so we have
we're going to be doing events next year
in addition to the states we're already
doing also now in colorado new jersey
missouri and missouri and ohio and
that's in the addition to the art the
states we already do of washington
colorado or excuse me washington oregon
california nevada oklahoma massachusetts
florida michigan and illinois um and
then in subsequent years we'll just keep
adding more and more states going on and
we'll just be coming back with events
specifically for those butt tenders
events specifically for those buyers and
events
you know the golf events which we
started with exclusively for those
executive c-suite vps and directors
because at the end of the day those are
the three segments of the industry those
are the decision makers the decision
makers in canvas are the executives the
buyers and the butt tenders and so we'll
do specific events targeted specifically
for people that want to talk to those
targeted groups uh to meet with them and
we're really excited we're really
excited to be in 14 states by the end of
next year and be in 20-something states
by the end of 2023.
you know as i said the more of research
the more impressed i am with lemon hayes
and what you guys have been building
over there and i think you've got
nothing but success and enough for
trajectory for 2022 and as i said i look
forward to lacing up my glove when i get
over to america sometime with you guys
we're nearly up on the time i can't
thank you enough brian for coming on the
show it's been an absolute pleasure to
talk to you for anybody who wants to
check out lemon haze there's the website
below lemonhaze.com i highly recommend
going checking them out and if you're in
the states and you're a bud tender you
need to be going to one of the events
these guys put on because they're slowly
becoming the the top of the food chain
around the state so brian thank you very
much again for coming on the show
hey owen thanks so much and let me know
whenever you're around one of our
tournaments over here you have got a
spot to play anytime happy days thank
you very much until next episode guys
[Music]