foreign
[Music]
everybody to this episode of the
Cannabis review I'm delighted to joining
this episode by George vlemis who's the
co-found cube Northern luggage New York
420 media and Farmers Choice how you
keeping Today George doing well doing
well how are you I am very well thank
you very much for taking them to do this
I know things are all busy with you over
in New York
yeah it's uh very busy over here we have
a new lawsuit that just hit so all of
the licenses are you know currently on
freeze we're hoping that clears up soon
but you know still moving forward here
that's it we're talking to John perro
one of the legal experts from New York
on that topic exactly today as well so
hopefully we get some insights from a
legal perspective yeah that'll be nice
that will be nice to see what's going on
here yeah tell me this can you maybe
give everybody a quick overview of how
you ended up in the Cannabis Indian boy
and what companies you decided to create
in that space I've been in the Cannabis
industry on the other side for many
years and then when Massachusetts
legalized I moved there and we started a
cultivation situation to learn the legal
landscape and then we waited for New
York to open and then when New York
opened we really hit the ground running
we secured several Prime real estate
locations early on before any of the
rules were even released and positioned
ourselves to really enter this space
across the state so we are positioned
now in multiple locations
from the state's capital Albany New York
all the way down to Manhattan and we
have a big presence in the Mid-Hudson
Valley so we have Cube where I'm
partners with Quan Liddell in Manhattan
then we have Northern Lights and why
where I am partners with Joe Kelly in
Albany then we have another site coming
online in Fishkill New York New Paltz
New York and Newburgh New York at the
moment so uh those are the three brands
and then we created uh Quan and I we
founded NY 420 where we put up a website
where we allow anybody in the Cannabis
space in New York that's participating
to have free advertising and showcase
their brand
um everything that they're doing a link
to where they want to drive traffic and
it's a website where people entering the
space can come and basically find every
service you need to open up a dispensary
in this state
okay very interesting I might start off
with Cube as our first topic of
discussion and this chain of
dispensaries that you're going to have
throughout New York City or New York
State and what is the purchasing process
when you're deciding what kind of flower
and what kind of products are cute
well we we have a good relationship with
a lot of the cultivators and processors
now for the last couple years since they
started coming online and we inspect
everybody's product we sit down with
them and we see you know what they have
available at the moment and what they
have coming online and we for all the
sites that I work with all the partners
that I have we really want to let the
public know that we want to push Fresh
Products so if you're coming and you're
buying flower from one of our sites it's
going to be fresh flowers not going to
be a year old
um so that's that's how we work with the
cultivators is we try to
tell them look you want you know you
want to have space on the Shelf we want
to support you we just want to have
fresh product we're not looking to take
in last year's crop and we want that to
transpire go with the customer coming in
so we're always looking to try and bring
in new and exciting products as fresh as
possible
and when it comes to the cultivation of
flour and the products that you're
accessing and is it all to recommend
from New York Farms
it has to be yeah we have to purchase
from New York cultivators and processors
and is there specific companies that are
standing in the rest when it seems to be
the cultivation in New York or uh is it
a case while we're in Canada we're going
to see the smaller operators the more
craft operators produced a better
quality flower
I mean it's very early on now so I don't
know how comfortable I feel calling
everybody out and saying who's better
than who but listen there are definitely
some companies that are much larger than
others
um and there are people who have very
small craft operations so
you're gonna have a mix of both right
you're going to have people that can
supply you know two three hundred skus
for your dispensary you're going to have
people that that specialize in two or
three that have a supremium quality
compared to everybody else so it'll be a
healthy mix still very early but you
know there are a handful of companies
that I think are going to survive
a long time
now when it comes to the current Retail
Landscape in New York we obviously have
seen a lot of illegal operations opened
up but then some
tomorrow policy work by the Cannabis
Commission in New York looking to try
and close these down what does the
current Retail Landscape look like in
Manhattan at the moment compared to the
rest of the state
I mean listen the the office of cannabis
management the governor all the powers
that may be in New York state they're
going to do the best they can to
minimize these illegal shops
you know unfortunately at the moment
Manhattan is flooded with them wherever
you go you know if you pick a spot you
pick a street you know within a couple
of feet couple of minutes you know you
you can find plenty of places to
purchase all kinds of cannabis products
24 7 here
you know that are not licensed operators
so
it is what it is right now we have we
with the licenses have to trust that the
customer
is going to want to shop
to purchase a product that New York
state has tested
and has confirmed there are no other
narcotics in the mix and it is a safe
product to consume so that is what we
have to really tell the public who's
shopping
buy from a licensed operator we have
tested product it's safe to consume the
illegal shops they're doing what they
got to do to survive I can't speak on
what they're doing I don't own one of
them you know I wish them the best of
luck in making the transition I wish New
York State the best of luck in you know
minimizing their exposure and collecting
tax revenue so
interesting interesting landscape in
Manhattan yeah for sure as I said I was
there last year and it was pretty
comical to see the explosion the
proliferation of these sort of is it a
case of it's currently just whack-a-mole
the police are closing down and they're
just finding a new retail outlet and
they're going to make the money as
quickly as they can until they get
closed down again I mean listen the show
what's going down in Manhattan you need
nothing short of the National Guard you
know you got to close the streets you
need a couple of military units and you
have to attack Manhattan for a good two
three days and shut down thousands of
stores shutting down two or three here
or there by the time you're done doing
the paperwork five more have opened so
you know you got to call in Special
Forces and really show your power here
you know shut them down in a week can't
be [ __ ] around for you know what I
mean you got to come in and do what you
got to do
um you guys are one of the card
applications when it comes to the
licensing in New York what does the
current landscape look like for the
recipients that are already opened up
has it been a big success for them and
uh are you looking forward to seeing
what it's going to bring for you go over
the next 12 to 24 months yeah listen
from what I understand the licensed
operators that have been open making
sales they're doing very well they're
excited uh the customers are loving the
stores loving the products it's a very
fun business so you know we're moving as
fast as we can to become one of them and
start sales and we think that you know
for the next three to five years New
York is going to become what everybody
thinks it is one of the largest markets
in the world and we're very excited to
see the sales and to interact with all
the people and the brands it's a very
fun space
very excited for what's coming and I can
only imagine one of the places that I
was stuck at me though when it comes to
the consumption lounges or even bars
that are now
licensed towards cannabis consumption I
spoke to Alex Alexander racing who owns
the first cannabis Hotel the Lexi in Las
Vegas and the one thing in the back of
my mind was I was if you combine the
culture and the music with a consumption
Lounge in New York surely that's going
to be the next big wave of cannabis
businesses who can marry those two
sectors together
it's going to be great I mean from what
I understand now our card license allows
for limited on-site consumption so a lot
of the sites that I have we are
preparing them to have an Indus
independent space where you can come and
consume and then we're waiting on
further regulation from the office of
cannabis management to really explain
what that entails and what limits we
have to follow here but
you know New York is going to be a very
exciting Market I mean to go into
Manhattan purchase a product and then go
into somebody's creative space where
there it was designed to entertain you
while you're consuming cannabis that's
going to be something that's going to be
developing over the next five ten years
and I think it's going to be amazing to
watch happen
yeah and I think from this side of the
pond it's one of those if New York
didn't already have enough unique
selling points that have been able to go
to Manhattan and as I said go to one of
these Lounge whatever part of the scale
that ends up being on and being able to
enjoy that product and the consumption
mixed with the media over there I think
is going to be very advantageous for for
Holiday makers and for tourism for the
sector as well a hundred percent it's
going to be a huge Market people are
going to come from all over the world to
participate
do you see no because it's legal is Tom
Dick and Harry's got sort of a name
trying to get their foot in the door of
this sector now or is it still got a
high enough barrier to entry
I mean the the barrier to entry really
is is the money that's what it comes
down to I mean you know if you're an
entrepreneur you should be able to
navigate any business you want to enter
so a lot of people want to enter the
space that haven't been in the space I
mean this is my first time in the space
but it's you know it's easy in my
opinion right the the state issues
regulation
your father [ __ ] rules if you know
how to read you can operate that's what
it comes down to you know your average
person they want to talk or even people
in the space they tell you oh it's a
hard business you've never been in
cannabis get the [ __ ] out of here this
is easy [ __ ] man you follow what the
state says you raise some money and you
open a business like it's anything else
so anybody who wants to enter the space
finds your money read the regulation
have a creative session come up with
what you're gonna do and at the end of
the day we're selling weed follow the
rules and keep your license
yeah when it comes today
the actual retail locations in Manhattan
I was reading up at a number of rules of
it has x amount of meters or distance
away from each other it is that
something that people have been very
picking the retail locations known what
the parameters were for these really
retail locations in advance what is your
input on choosing a retail location in
Manhattan I mean I think the rules are
500 feet from any school and the school
I think it's defined K through 12. uh
200 feet from any house of Warship
that's the main factors and a thousand
feet at least for Manhattan a thousand
feet from any other licensed dispensary
so you follow those parameters the state
put out a new search tool
to give you a heads up if the location
is compliant and then you can proceed
forward to go to their survey tool and
actually submit the site if you have a
license but in terms of the race for
Real Estate in Manhattan
it's expensive I mean once again it
comes down to to money I mean you know
you knock on somebody's door before you
buy a hot dog to stand across the street
and look and envision where you could be
you may need you know 200 000 to a
million dollars just for a security
deposit you know you're going to need a
high net worth individual to sign for
the real estate
and that is really the issue finding the
locations they're available they're
there
um the office issued a lot of licenses
from Manhattan so and the Manhattan has
a huge Market
so once again it comes down to finding
the right partners for your business or
just being an individual that is already
self-sufficient when it comes to the
Real Estate in Manhattan you've got to
be able to write a check if you can't
write a check whether it's your money or
someone else's money then
you know it's just a waste of time
that that that's it you've got to secure
the it's money
to cash money yeah
and Before I Let You Go um I know you're
busy man what is the thing you're
looking forward to seeing over the next
18 months in New York
I'm sorry you said the next hello
12 to 18 months 24 months I would like
to see everybody open I like to see
myself open and uh you know I'd love to
see the support we have from the
residents of New York and the
surrounding states and all the
international Travelers come and
experience the amazing brands that pop
up here I would love for all the
cultivators and processors to have an
abundance of dispensaries to sell to and
see them stabilize their situation our
Farmers need stores to sell to in order
to get back the investment and be able
to maintain their financial
responsibilities I'm looking forward to
the grower showcases that the state is
allowing where we can have these uh
independent events off-site from the
dispensary with music and and and
there's so much exciting stuff here but
I I really just want to see the market
come alive I think the office of
cannabis management
has been tasked with a crazy scenario
here to open up the largest consumption
Market on the planet they're doing the
best they can they're doing a great job
shout out to the ocm they're pivoting
every time they have to they're making
adjustments every time they have through
their battling lawsuits and they're
doing the best that they can and I
praise them for the work that they're
doing and I'm excited to see this Market
open and congratulations to everybody
who's in the space
or coming in the space and I hope to
have and invite about you know four or
five hundred people here to our rooftop
Grand open Event uh for cube in
Manhattan we have a big party plan
oh my god when is that happening I'm
hoping that sometime before Halloween
let's see what happens with this current
lawsuit might be delayed a little bit
but we have an amazing venue 25 stories
high I think we are allowed to bring
three 400 people we're gonna really
invite the industry and kind of make it
one of the Premier Gatherings and grand
openings that New York has seen for one
of these retail dispensers
incredible well I'm over in New York but
he regularly mate I look forward to
meeting up in person and if not
hopefully we can touch base once Cube
has opened up and we can get an update
on how business has gone for you guys
but for now thank you very much for your
time it's been very much appreciated all
right thank you for the interview
until next episode
[Music]