[Music]
welcome to the cannabis review i am
delighted to be joined on this episode
by dr iv evan lewis of the neurology
center in toronto
evan is a pediatric neurologist and a
clinical neurophysiologist that has an
expertise in epilepsy and epilepsy
surgery and medical cannabis for the
treatment of neurological disorders so
evan how are you keeping
i'm doing well thanks very much thanks
for having me today delighted to have
you on the show mate you're a man with a
wealth of wealth of knowledge in this
topic and it's it's great to be able to
have a come back to the article that we
had over here in ireland about some
information that may or may not be
misleading we'll leave it down to an
expert like yourselves to give us the
good information on it so i kind of
could kick things actually i might
definitely give the audience a little
brief overview of how you got to where
you are in toronto and your expertise in
the industry
yeah sure so i mean i'm originally from
toronto i'm a canadian born and grew up
in toronto but did my training in ottawa
uh in pediatric neurology and epilepsy
and did uh completed my full training in
miami a year there and a year in toronto
at the hospital for sick children
and um it was kind of following my
training that was really when medical
cannabis
was coming up from the grassroots from a
lot of the parent organizations
so this is kind of circa
2009 to 2012 2013 and around that time i
had a bit of an interest but
there was a lot of stigma around it and
most the vast majority of doctors and
neurologists were not utilizing it as
all at all and that kind of piqued my
interest i guess and after working for
about a year and a half at the hospital
for sick children i left and opened up
my center the neurology center of
toronto
in as a community neurology practice in
toronto and there i was able to kind of
be free a little bit of of i guess
hospital oversight administration could
pursue some in my own interests and
that's when i really started to move
into medical cannabis and it was around
that time that i just started collecting
a lot of patients they were coming to me
and um you know i i kind of through my
own experience my own self learning
and through my patients who i owe a huge
amount of thanks because they've taught
me so much really was able to move
forward into the medical cannabis world
and started with pediatric epilepsy
which was my area that i'm trained in
and had the most confidence and felt
that it was safe to
pursue that with medical cannabis
and subsequently evolved that into other
pediatric neurological disorders and
adults as well so that's culminated in
kind of years of experience now and
through many patients both adults and
kids as i mentioned through epilepsy and
non-epilepsy conditions
i've we've gained quite a lot of
experience here in medical cannabis
we're just reviewing all of our patients
now and we have uh we're following over
500 patients right now for various
neurological disorders
oh sorry i think i lost your urine
you're on mute
hi there i'm back again so um yeah
perfectly positioned then to be able to
assist us in this next topic that we're
talking about so you we were talking
beforehand you've read the article that
was published in the irish times where a
number of doctors came out saying they
weren't sure about the products that
were being prescribed
from your point of view and over in
canada are there a safe list of products
that are prescribed to patients over in
canada and if so are they available
available in europe
yeah that's really important uh because
you know each country tends to have its
own regulatory framework and its own
product availability so most products
that i have access to in canada are
canadian products
we have very few products coming from
elsewhere and that has to do a lot with
regulation but a lot to do with cost as
well but the products are similar in a
sense that the ratios for thc cbd um are
similar or and the the corresponding
additives whether they be terpenes or or
other components are also similar so
there is similarity between the products
uh that's that are available in canada
versus the rest of the world and um you
know but but predominantly through our
regulatory framework here we can access
those products quite readily that are
canadian and really there's no sense to
kind of import products at this point
and utilize it just because the costs
are are enormous for instance epidiolex
is one that often gets asked about in
canada
and and gw pharma has not moved into
canada as a market here so to purchase
epidiolex
is is just exorbitant for families it
doesn't make any sense at all when we
have
analogous products
such as purified cbd oils here available
in canada
okay and do you see
in your opinion the message the best
medicines are the best version of
cannabis for epilepsy is there a
specific ratio of thc
that seems to work best is is pure cbd
actually proven to have worked with
epilepsy patients where there's no thc
in it so
we obviously have a much more stricter
rules over here when it comes to thc
content so
i'm just curious as to know is there the
perfect ratio of thc to cbd for an
epilepsy medicine
yeah this is uh a question that remains
unanswered so we need to know this and
we don't know this yet because we
haven't done any real head-to-head
trials on the different invariant ratios
so we have
really good randomized control trials
with purified cbd products and those
were the main ones that came out over
the last you know decade and those that
that gives us some direction from the
purified cv point of view some outcome
data and some adverse effect data and
that's very high level evidence so it's
good to rely on that but then we also
have some studies that have come out
that have been more open label uh
related studies they don't they're not
as high level um in terms of evidence as
we have available for the purified cbd
products but they certainly show um some
some positive outcomes for cbd rich
extracts those are seed those are oils
that have a higher amount of cbd in
proportion to thc but have a significant
amount of thc
in their products as well and we have
good outcome data there and we have good
safety data there too
now when it comes to that perfect ratio
question it's often a question i get
asked a lot by patients and it kind of
doesn't really matter because if you
have experience in canvas medicine you
can design your own ratio i you know for
example i can give a purified cbd oil
and give x number of milligrams of cbd
but then i could also supplement that
with a purified thc oil and then give x
number of milligrams of tg i can make my
own ratios so i don't think there's a
perfect ratio i think that that question
is is a is a big black box and we still
have yet we really don't have an
understanding and the truth is
i think that the resultant answer is
going to come out of the certain
epilepsy conditions depending on what is
driving the epilepsy disorder that is
going to be what determines the ultimate
proportion of cbd to thc or other
cannabinoids there isn't going to be a
perfect
proportionate amount of cbd thc to all
epilepsy syndromes i think that's a bit
of a misunderstanding how epilepsy works
because epilepsy just means a tendency
to have seizures but there can be
thousands of causes for that tendency so
we have to treat the tendency and not
the actual seizures and that's the
medicine to that will be
that's coming in the future for medical
cannabis to really understand um the
proportion based on the disease entity
that's causing the epilepsy if that
makes sense
yeah no completely and i think that's
one of the things that hinders the
doctors over here is the ability to dose
a patient perfectly i think the future
of medical cannabis is a patient being
given a an option of both and it their
own individual ratio is going to be
determined but as you said you're going
to have standardized medicine based on
the different ailment that you've got or
the age group or the health uh group
that you're sitting within
do you ever see a scenario where
somewhere like over in ireland we
haven't legalized cannabis to grow yet
is there an argument for if we're going
to create a grow industry that we should
be looking at what are the ailments that
people suffer from in ireland and let's
look at the strains that work best for
these ailments so if there is going to
be a medical cannabis program that there
is strains and products that are made in
ireland they're available for irish
patients
yeah again i think that's going to be
difficult um you know where do you stop
there but i.e which varieties of
cannabis do you pick and then when you
pick those right in cannabis which
ailments do you pick i mean you can you
can individualize this forever and ever
you can reduce this down to you know
so many different levels that that's
going to be
a real complicated uh path to take and i
honestly i don't think i know the answer
there i don't know if anybody could
reliably know the answer there it sounds
like a great idea and that sounds like
where things are headed so i guess one
way to look at that is
ultimately probably what's going to be
very important here is the individual
genetics i think the the
pharmacogenetics and the understanding
of how genetics uh ex
affect the endocannabinoid system
that is all that and time is going to
help us dictate the the right treatment
approaches for patients and then in
addition to the disease state as i
mentioned before so it's the genetics
and the actual disease the genetics of
an individual and the actual disease
causing whatever ailment it is i think
the combination of that and really
understanding that and how it interplays
with the endocannabinoid system will
ultimately allow us to tailor therapies
accordingly rather than going kind of
the other approach from the other end i
think if we do that from the other end
he could do that forever and i don't
know if we would really come up with
good answers there but to um to help
with that right now because we have to
kind of work with what we have right now
um it's important for for a practitioner
like myself an experienced practitioner
to develop standardized protocols based
on the best available evidence and
that's what we do at my center and
that's what i've developed here so just
as an example for our epilepsy patients
we have a very standardized protocol
that works through successive phases and
those phases so all patients that come
in with epilepsy from a certain cause
start in a phase one uh we work them
through the phase one and then if they
fail they go to phase two if they fail
they go to phase three and as we go
through those phases the treatment
becomes more and more individualized to
the to the person and then that way at
least i know i'm standardizing myself
and then i can use those protocols to
base further treatment decisions for my
entire population but also for the
individual so that's one way that a you
know a practitioner right now can try to
approach these things but when you start
to do all these different kind of
various different approaches then you
might not really know what you're doing
and that could lead to actually causing
more harm than good
okay so that kind of leaves me on the
last topic i want to talk about is
future medicines
it seems to be after our discussion now
that the perfect scenario is purified
thc purified cbd and a ratio balance for
each individual patient
is that how you see the the medical
cannabis industry unfolding over the
next number of years
it might be that's real hard
it might be it might be and i'm not
saying that's what i do here just to
clarify i do use the oils with certain
proportions so it's not so much about
that proportion right now for me it's
more about the actual dose the actual
milligram dose because if i know that
that can stay consistent from patient to
patient so for instance coming back to
the phased protocols we have our phase
one protocol um targets reaching a dose
of 300 milligrams of cbd as as an
example in most patients so i'm just
generalizing right now um so knowing and
that's based on the available evidence
that that has been produced and there's
some again there's some other slight
changes there if anybody wants to
comment on this i'm very happy to
discuss in detail with people but um you
know that's the first target so it's
more of a milligram dose because that
can stay consistent then i can read the
literature and i can see what's being
used from a milligram based dose and not
so much these proportions to be very
honest when it comes down to how much
thc is being included or whatnot i do
have standards for that but sometimes
i'm constrained by the cost
for instance um
for instance sorry about that there
for instance the
the cost of high cbd rich extracts is
really expensive and totally
unaffordable for families and we have no
public coverage of our cannabis here so
sometimes i'm at a loss and i have to
offer a patient
a higher amount of thc proportionate to
cbd when really i really want to target
a higher cbd to thc proportion so i'm a
bit constrained by other factors and i
know that that's some of the difficulty
that we see
in other countries right now as well so
it tends to be that cost does kind of
drive where things are at so so coming
back to your question i would love a
scenario in which i could just design my
own proportions and help patients in
that sense but it's not practical due to
cost that's not practical due to
regulatory framework um so i'm stuck
with having to use the proportions that
are available and that are affordable
for patients so i try to manipulate the
protocol for those patients accordingly
okay interesting do you know of any
products in europe that you think are
worth keeping an eye out for or is
epideric seems to be the main one
um well
again i i i probably don't want to go
into mentioning specific products yeah
dialects yeah i mean epidiolex is the
reason why i have a dialects and i
mentioned it is so popular epidiolex was
the product that was used in the
randomized control trials in the us that
really uh resulted in
approval by the fda and approval in
europe um so so it's kind of a little
bit of that gold standard if you really
go back and look at the
trials that have been done but
subsequent to that there are many trials
in israel trials in canada um you know
there's work in germany that's been done
that has used cbd rich extracts from
various different companies with results
that are as good as what we saw on
epidiolex trial or sometimes better
given that there was no no these are not
just the same degree of evidence and
quality of control in those trials um
but that's at least points to you know
positive signal here that there are cbd
rich extracts from various different
companies that contain thc that are
effective in epilepsy from my personal
experience with my patients um we see
this we definitely see this and in some
cases thc is necessary so we just
actually published a paper from my
center here in conjunction with the
university of montreal my colleague dr
will um where we showed a case series of
patients who who failed cbd
but then responded to thc and
incremental doses of thc we've got a
great case study that shows a resolution
of
complete resolution of seizures uh male
development neurologically and eeg
normalization with thc not with cbd so
there is a rule here for it we have to
understand it a little bit better and i
think anybody who has some understanding
of the endocannabinoid system
can understand where and how thc
comes into play and that was one of my
you know big responses to the irish
times article um was it just speaks to
me that there's a lack of education
about thc and an overall vilification of
this substance probably embedded deeply
within our societies our international
society stigma against chc and we have
to really be a bit more open to this and
realize where we're coming from and uh
look at this more objectively like true
medical practitioners and true
scientists should
and i'm happy to share the uh the link
to that article if you've got uh
corresponding notes to this to this
podcast yeah we will indeed we'll leave
it down in the link for everybody if
you're watching the show you'll see it
down below
and evan thank you very much for coming
on the show we've that we've hit our
time but i could talk to you all day on
this topic it's been an absolute
pleasure to help you and help get you on
and we can talk again further on the
topic in the future
would love to i
i could talk forever on this as well
yes well it's been an absolute pleasure
and i know the viewers would have gotten
as much wealth and information out of
that as i did so thank you very much and
you have a great day you as well
pleasure until next time guys