so on behalf of the in CBA the
international cannabis bar sensation
which is the representative body of
lawyers who operate in the campus space
I'd like to warmly introduce to you our
next public speakers
first up is a man who is very very well
known as an authority on the area of
cannabis Mall in Europe and Beyond and
that is Kai Friedrich miemann from
Germany
Mario Sanchez also well-renowned and
including all our other speakers
throughout all superb Mari is from
France Robert joppy from London and of
course Daniel Heyman from Switzerland so
just a quick word about the Inc V8 it is
the representative Association again of
lawyers who operate in the Cannabis
space we've now I think over a thousand
lawyers uh spread across North America
and Europe and Beyond and so today's
panel of discussion is of course the
European legal and Regulatory
environment in 2023 I don't need to
introduce myself again I think most of
you are familiar with me at this point
probably sick of me but uh anyway the
format for today is we have the
presentations from our speakers and then
towards the end we have a instance and
answers session so without further ado
put your hands together I'm welcome Kai
Friedrich Neumann is our first Speaker
great to be here thanks for having me
Neil and
her own pleasure to be here and I
prepared some slides for you some
information for you we only have 15
minutes
please stop me if I'm getting too long
here and yeah let's see what we where we
know what we can do here okay I'm
talking about a little bit about ham
medical and adult use cannabis in
Germany I want to give you a little
overview in regulatory overview as you
might know my now the Germany has come
to legalize
in the uh next coming month and the
Coalition agreement of the new
government in 2021 so they agreed on
Distributing
cannabis
recreational Cannabis to adults in
licensed shops that was the goal of the
new government so we had a one year of
intense debates on how to do that but
the uh four and first and foremost goal
is Health protection it's the primary
goal so if you think the calories in
legalization in Germany you have to
think Health protection at the same time
every decision you make you have to keep
that goal in mind
as well as child and youth protection
and product quality and productive
engine and of course will be fight
against the illegal market and crime
displacement
this is the magic number we estimated
amount of 400 tons plus X of dried
flowers alone from the German Market
probably 500 tons if the tourists are
allowed to purchase the recreational
Cannabis which means we have a lot of
gram 400 million
and for
a billion dollar market plus X so it's
extreme huge Market we expect
compared to the medical Market we
imported Germany about the 25 tons of
dried flowers in 2022 so then you see
how much of the Cannabis is needed for
the German mark
uh the problem is how to secure the
supply chain for medical for
recreational cannabis in in Germany
there was one proposition by the bean
party that it is limited to Farmers not
a good idea outdoor cultivation in
Germany is it possible at all under
these climate conditions do you have the
white genetics before that you see that
this is possible in Switzerland but on a
large scale in Germany I think it's
questionable indoor cultivation on the
other hand is extremely energy intensive
climate protection aspects you have to
consider maybe a glass house production
is that a middle ground is that the
middle way how to secure production in
Germany all questions are still open or
still debating they're still debated
and yeah the Imports is another question
it's another problem
um when you want to import your
immigration cannabis to Germany you have
to deal with the single convention
one proposition is to terminate the
single convention and re-entry under
reservation of cannabis like Olivia did
for the coca leaves
or you can think about the interstate
modification procedure without the
enunciation of the single convention
and with the conclusion of trade
agreements between the states some call
it the most elegant way out but then you
have to identify of course potential
international trading partners maybe
like Canada or Uruguay uh
but the problem is these agreements take
a long time so maybe it's two years
three years four years it's very
complicated to agree on such an
international trade treaty
and this doesn't solve the problem of a
product availability in Germany
and we have the EU law just to
scratch that there is this framework
decision which obliges European member
states to prohibit and to um to prohibit
the trade of cannabis as long as it is
without authorization and now we have
legal Scholars saying if you legalize
nationally domestically it is with
authorization okay
but another point is Imports and foreign
trade agreements is that under EU
restriction this does did the member
states delegate this competence to the
EU
so everything is highly disputed in
these every every question if
determination is possible if an
interesting modification procedure is
possible because the single convention
was agreed on before this Arctic 241 and
so it's really hard to get a way through
there
so the German government came up with an
idea with this so-called interpretive
interpretative statement they issued a
key Point paper in October and
everything I tell us about the status of
October okay we have
the end of February no the major
developments coming up in March so
forgive me if my predictions are
obsolete in in three weeks
um but what is that this interpretative
statement
so legalization under strict conditions
of State regulation and Improvement of
health and use protection is compatible
with the goals of the drug conventions
from 61 72 and 88. and the government is
invoking the German legal order the case
law of the Supreme Court and particular
declaration at the time of the
ratification of the 1988 agreement
the aforementioned grounds of a legal
order are subject to change and exactly
this change has happened now in 2022 and
3 right now so
and they are not talking about
terminating the single convention or
they're not talking about right now
about Interstate multiplication
procedures or all these legs to take a
Firm Stance and say we interpret the
treaties that legalization is better for
our people is better for our community
and
can achieve further more Health
protection yeah
the consequences that the calculation
must take place in Germany No Imports
for the time being so the 400 500 tons
have to be produced have to be
cultivated in Germany as it stands right
now
the the
um this is the interpretative statement
is discussed with the EU commission
right now and they're trying to find a
solution for for that
okay
um
there's also discussed right now in Plan
B Plan B would be decriminalization of
cannabis of recreational Cannabis the
allowance of homegrown and Collective
homegraph and cannabisotic flaps this is
privileged under a year under the year
U.N treaties and under Euler but this is
not the goal of the government the goal
of the government as I explained earlier
was licensed stores and controlled
quality
and to really assure consumer protection
through tested products in a regulated
market
okay so I think these interpretation
solution is a bold step like Uruguay
invoked human rights and they still
stand they still have a Firm Stance on
these human rights
interpretation similar to Canada
the first development of course remains
to be seen it when and a new level and
the health Minister wants to have an
European expertise which is also
published with the first draft in March
to convince the other EU member states
that the German Way is the better way
and we have the federal drug
commissioner he is traveling all over
Europe and he's in talks with all the
other health ministers because
the Luxembourg Malta Czech Republic
Spain Netherlands Portugal they all
wanted another Direction in cannabis
policy they want to change and if they
get together and work on a new solution
then maybe we see also a change in the
ruler in this in this framework decision
so that all European member states can
legalize the Cannabis on a safe ground
okay sorry
so the consequence without inputs
Market at the beginning that's for sure
without products in our Cannabis stores
you won't get a license I can't imagine
when you can't prove that you have
product if you have no product you can't
get a list so the first ones we have
product in the market will have an
advantage maybe we also see and a
vertically integrated value chain if the
the ones we have the first product get
the first licenses for the stores and
yeah the production in Germany will be a
challenge in terms of logistics and
energy that's not the best solution
that's not a good solution not at all so
I hope that the German government which
is which is doing right now these
intensive talks to the EU member state
that we find another solution Imports
must be possible it's a it I can't
imagine how that should work
yeah maybe the solution would be um home
cultivation we also we all already have
a sea trade in Spain in the Czech
Republic
we have a large marked market for
equipment for home growing equipment
and um
the Cannabis Social Club model is also a
route which may make sense so that you
have in big cities like Hamburg or
Berlin Social Clubs with 500 000 members
and their own production facilities
but this is not clear right now how this
will be regulated it's all in a in a
flow right now yeah and of course low
threshold and then generous licensing of
cultivation in Germany but this must be
as the key Point paper of the government
says there must be in compliance with
the sustainability goals of the German
government which are the UN goals of the
sustainability
but what that what does that mean do you
have a do you have to have a windmill
next to your indoor production facility
or a photo will tag or whatever but you
probably won't can't meet uh a zero
carbon
facility because it's just too intensive
in terms of energy
so lots of questions
we have to solve in the next couple of
months
okay
yeah
um
the schedule is like we're expecting now
in March the first draft of the law
as I said before the the draft will be
probably in two phases so we have plan B
first decriminalization home growth and
Collective home grow and
the commercialized value chain will come
in a further step in the second step in
2024 we're expecting this plan B to be
um implemented in in
June before the summer break of
moonstack
and uh then with the further notice
period for for cultivation licenses and
Retail licenses
and we're expecting sorry
and we're expecting a Federal Supreme
Court decision also in March on the
legality of the ban of cannabis in
general so the March will be a decisive
um
a month
for the further development for the
further developments in in Germany and
for the final plan of the of the
government
okay CBD Market
um
the CBD Market the CBD hype is
definitely over in in Germany
um the enforcement of the noble food
regulations since 2019 work very well so
we only have a few products on the
market still still left and you can't
CBD oil Market to no longer as food but
mainly as a cosmetic oval care product
and you see that on the shelves of the
uh of the big truck store chains
we still see party persecution on the
ground of the narcotic act against the
CBD product still a fight going on we
still need these
clarification within you with a new law
and to really make clear that the THC is
not a problem anymore for these kind of
products the CBD flowers hemp leaf tea
we still have to proceeding chemical
proceedings against these products as
well
my office has received the for two
clients suit the German government in in
the administrative code of Braunschweig
on the grounds of the free movement of
goods principle because uh CBD flowers
are legal in Luxembourg and Belgium and
Austria and Hamley tea the same so but
this is still pending we need the final
clarification with the legalization and
the changing of the law what is
marketable is CBD cosmetics and CBD
e-liquids if no Health claims are made
so these products are on the market and
are safe on the market
we had some
important courtesy in the last year CBD
as a medicine so the the court said
um
if you have a product which exceeds 18
milligrams CBD as a daily intake it's a
medicine
okay that's not much
the FSA in in the UK says 70
um 70 and 18 with the difference
but it does conflict with the court
rulings of the ECG because you meet the
significant threshold and another core
decision was that cosmetic oval care
sprays like you see over there you see
cosmetic
moonflake spray so this is the only
route you can Market CBD oils right now
because cosmetic studies find out that
um
uh CBD has an antibacterial effect for
for carrying for for treating your mouth
the cavity
so this is the but this is also a
dispute right now if this route will
prevail will be decided this year as
well
okay A little some words to medical
cannabis market so you can export
medical cannabis to Germany in principle
from every other country in the world
you just need to have
a medical cannabis production under
State control and the state has to
establish a cannabis agency
and
yeah the product has to have this gacp
and EU GMP
properties they must met these Auto
relax for regulations and the German
monographies
there's only a deviation of 10 allowed
for the from in terms of the
specification made
and patient numbers is about 120 000
right now the exact figure is not
documented the market is uh 200 million
euros plus 30 to 60 million Euros for
the private payer market so still a very
small market in terms of numbers
we had this this is the development of
the Imports of dried flowers into
Germany you see from 2017 to 2022 the
constant constant increase
uh the mouse prescription are for pain
70 through 73
and her specificity Etc blue sterosis
um
and you see these are the import
countries for Dwight flowers Canada are
still with 38 the Netherlands 26 Denmark
and others and the left-hand side is the
dried extracts and the most of the
Dwight of the uh of the extracts are
coming from Portugal right now
yeah this is the um the the range of the
different products the green is dried
flowers
um and the blue ones are the
preparations and below that is Apple
idex kind of exact wax so this is the
market share of the different products
and yeah thank you for your attention
and maybe
[Applause]
good for left
over
this left or right sorry
I guess okay perfect okay uh good
morning everyone
um thank you nayel for the invitation
and always happy to share a panel with
my colleagues here
um so I'm gonna talk about the French
regulation in cannabis and just hearing
um Kai
um it's difficult to imagine that our
countries are so close and yes yet so
far away in terms of Regulation so
the French regulation in cannabis in a
nutshell uh therapeutic cannabis is
still not legal we're under a pilot
program that was supposed to last for
two years initially started in March
um was extended this year for another
year so legalization is now not expected
until uh 2024.
um
CBD
and wellness hemp is legal to a certain
extent and I will come back to that and
adult use cannabis I will not be talking
about it simply because it's not even
under a discussion right now and we
don't see any legalization coming soon
in this country
as far as medical cannabis is concerned
friends decided to go through a pilot
program rather than legalizing directly
so in March 2021 the they started a
pilot program
um and
um so just before I go into little
details regarding the program
as far as the legal framework is
concerned um the principle in French law
is that cannabis is illegal whatever
activity related to it is illegal there
are three exceptions that are set up by
law the first ones are cannabis based
medicines so traditional medicines
containing cannabinoids that have gone
through the four stages of clinical
trial and have obtained a marketing
authorization like any other medicinal
product
um from the company authorities the
second one that was added recently to go
through the pie and and to match with
the pilot program is
medicine like medicinal cannabis which
is like flowers and and oils that are
used for medicinal purposes but that
have not obtained a marketing
authorization and yet they are compliant
with a certain number of criterias
including eugmp and the third exception
is r d
so you can obtain licenses from the
French competent and health authorities
to to run r d programs on campus
the pilot program that started two years
ago was initially designed to enroll 3
000 patients
uh one year in we had only 1500 patients
enrolled and to date one fourth of them
has already left the the program either
due to side effects or to lack of
efficacy
uh what we need to know is that medical
cannabis under the spider program is the
last recourse prescription product so
it's for patients that I've tried any
other available therapeutic
Solution on the market and that are for
for whom nothing is working anymore
the pilot program in cannabis is
available uh under for five therapeutic
indications so neuropathic pain serious
pharmacal resistance epilepsy supportive
care in oncology palliative care and uh
central nervous system related diseases
friends decided to go with finished
products and like Germany we don't have
a magistrar preparations with cannabis
yet
and it's used in under three forms so
dried flowers for evaporizations no
smoking
oral forms like capsule gels and oils
so as you can see the requirements for
the quality and safety of cannabis to be
used under the program are pretty
stringent so of course like jacp ugmp
um the the ansm which is the French
health authority requires uh the
products to be a pharmaceutical quality
and they have to comply with all the
other guidelines that are basically
pharmaceutical guidelines and the plans
also must meet the specifications of the
European monograph
um
specific requirements also related to
France is that suppliers or All Foreign
companies since we don't have a local
production line
in place but those companies cannot
distribute directly the products to uh
the centers and health centers that are
involved in the program they had to
enter into partnership agreements with
French pharmaceutical companies that had
already the authorizations to
um to deal with
narcotic drugs
um and so this was uh pretty long to put
in place and and as Kai said about
agreements earlier those Agreements are
pretty long to put in place so even if
we are fast forwarding to legalizations
any operator that is looking to enter
the French Market in a way or another
and is Seeking a partnership with a
French company really needs to start if
they haven't started yet to seek for
partners and discuss those Partnerships
because it's not taking like one month
to to put in place obviously
um
so that's about the medical cannabis not
not much has happened and unfortunately
in the past years but if we are talking
about a legalization in 2024 there are
still a few questions that remain
unanswered uh one of them is the pricing
and the reimbursement of the medical
cannabis medicinal products and friends
have their price and reimbursement
determined as per a certain number of
criterias but medical cannabis and I'm
not talking about pharmaceutical
cannabis which are like traditional
medicines medical cannabis hasn't gone
through the traditional clinical trial
process we don't have those status like
SMR and ASMR and all those like proof
that are traditionally used by the
pricing authorities in France to to set
up the price and the reimbursement level
so we don't know yet what their
authorities are going to do to and how
they're going to determine the criterias
for that
the supply is another question because
even though since February 2022 the
French law has incorporated the
possibility to cultivate medical
cannabis on the French territory
the the implementation texts are not
published yet so it's in the law we know
it's there but it you cannot put it in
place and the reality is that no one is
ready yet to cultivate medical cannabis
in France it takes Millions to build a
facility it takes time you need
authorizations and so we know that in
case of legalization in 20 March 2024
there will not be a domestic production
line in place so the supply will rely on
foreign suppliers
again and
um so this this is definitely an
opportunity for foreign operators but it
it's also time now as I was saying
before to
um to start discussing how they're going
to supply how they're going to to win
their place on the French Market
um and and this is now at the latest and
the last question we we have which is a
major one is the number of patients that
will benefit from medicinal cannabis
because as we know before we started the
title program everybody was talking
about a tremendous number of patients
that would benefit from it and that
would and and they were
really really nervous about the fact
that 3 000 patients for the pilot
program was not enough and that a lot of
people would be left on the side of the
road the reality when you're in is that
only half of the patients that were
planned to to be enrolled in the program
entered the program and one-fourth of
them are already out so that's an
unanswered questions and and we see the
difference the the patients will benefit
from this pilot program or most of the
time people who never use cannabis
before and then you have all the people
who use cannabis
um and in the illegal way and as a
so-called recreational way and among
them you have people who use it for real
recreational purposes and you have
people who use it for medicinal purposes
whatever it is and so because everything
seems to be mixed up at the moment we
don't really see and really know how
many patients will really benefit from
what happens yes
just a few menable conditions and that
they were the inclusion verification
they live in Houston
they've increased the scope over the
first year especially in oncology they
have opened and enlarged the criterias
uh for enrollment especially in breast
cancer and pediatric cancer I think and
so um they have but it's also
complicated because the doctors that are
involved were trained it was like a few
hours training and we see doctors not
complaining but explaining the
difficulties they have with titration
for instance in the NSA okay but we we
have to adapt the product to each
patient and it's very highly monitored
and so it's it's I think it's a
combination of factors that
makes it and also one factor that
appeared is that a lot of people
left the the program because they can't
drive
and so it's it's complicated you know to
to run your daily life if you're you're
using a product and you a new contract
so that's there are a lot of factors
involved but for sure it doesn't help
with you know like navigating the
numbers and and knowing exactly the real
picture of of it yes
and then you're right and uh building
for program is being added
it cuts mad at the what maintaining
deferred he is the best program is being
advertising advertised by you can't
write uh the meaning it will be the the
Secretary of picks but adverse effect
based on that people is not going to
come even carved because of this speed
map all around the world so I think that
that that there are a possible solution
here is number one how they are as their
facing this program number two is the
earthquake more skip Mark is very
already existing as Sigma I never agree
which stations are if your aimed Limited
in this program with the say I'm really
sure if you go to the party areas of the
hospital those stations will be very
happen for Sap's treatments but it is
about how we are planning up to a
wedding thankful these programs and
again you work only executing programs
for executing programs or really what to
to attach any goal or something like
that I don't know well it's not it's not
I wouldn't say the user advertised first
of all I mean there's a program put in
place but the number of centers and
health hospitals that are involved is
listed so it's not all the centers in in
France that are involved in this program
first of all so if you're a patient and
you're not in the geographical area and
you're not already followed up by a
healthcare professional that is involved
himself in the in the pilot program you
don't have access to that so that's one
point the second point is of course like
any other medication if you're using
morphine you're not gonna drive that's
for sure
um and so it's like any other medication
that comes with a warning that you
shouldn't be driving if you're using
something that alterates your
Consciousness or whatever and depending
on the ratios and the dosages that are
used that's like any other drug then the
side effects like any other medicinal
products the doctor has to inform you
when you enter the program or you're
being prescribed a medication that there
it may come with side effects but again
the side effects and especially with
these medicinal products which is really
active on a personal level and each
patient will will actually have a
different response to it and the
adaptation of the dosage and is is going
to vary from a patient to another
um some patients will not have side
effects some will have side effects and
and and it's an ongoing curve it's a
learning curve it's you you constantly
discover new things and so I think
um it's not so much about how the
program was advertised but it's more
first of all was it available where you
live for the patient live is the
patients already has already tried all
the drugs before and all the therapeutic
solutions that were available and has is
it not working anymore for these
patients so those criterias are strict
for sure and limited limiting but
um I think it's uh we would need to to
see a little further and in time to
really gather all the different reasons
why the number of patients is remains
Limited
um so the second part is about CBD and
wellness hemp so I'm not going to go
through too deeply in that into that but
I'm going to refer to what happened in
2022 because we had a pretty active year
in France
um so after no the this is the kind of a
decision in 2020 uh France was forced to
review the regulation which was judged
too restrictive compared to your
European law and so they came up with
the umete of December 30th 2021
According to which uh the Hem plans that
can be used legally and cultivate it
um are must be listed either on the EU
strains list or on the French list of
hemp varieties the plants must contain
less than 0.3 percent of THC the
extracts and products containing the the
the extracts musk also contain less than
the 0.3 percent of THC subject to
specific rules depending on the kind of
products concerned and notably cosmetic
products and food products for which
there are like a general safety rule
um a principle applying and so but the
regulation didn't didn't come with any
further detail on what they were
expecting so basically I will mention a
case later but we go with a 0.3 percent
THC limit
um
the hemp flowers and leaves are
authorized only for industrial use but
the retail sale to consumer of rawhand
flowers and leaves whatever other form
which means including herbal tea
was prohibited by this regulation
so you can imagine that the entire
industry jumped off their chair went mad
and was like okay we're gonna Sue this
uh regulation because uh first of all
this prohibition of the retail sale of
hemp flowers to Consumer created a real
problem regarding the principle of free
movement of good Goods in Europe because
having hand flowers
illegal in the neighbor countries these
could be imported into France while the
same product manufacturing France was
illegal the second legal issue we had
about and I'll come back about this
regulation and in this prohibition was
that basically it means it that the hemp
flower you use the hemp strain you're
using and the plant is legal as long as
it's on the list one of the list and it
contains less than 0.3 percent of THC
but at the same time
the flowers and the leaves from the same
plant are considered as a narcotic go
for your why I'm still trying to
understand how they came up with this
but still that's what happened
um so this regulation on the field
created basically two main issues the
first one is the noble food regulation
so Noble food is in the EU problem
um and it's it's eu-wide and in theory
you're not supposed to put any CBD
product edible products on the market
including the French market and we have
as far as food supplement or concern the
French regulation is pretty very clear
on that you cannot use Noble food that
has not been authorized by the FSA
um
and um in in the manufacturing or food
supplements
however in practice the reality is that
we've seen very limited controls on the
French Market over the past few years
which has resulted in a num tremendous
number of products invading the French
market so you can find CBD products and
CBD oils and CBD gummies and CBD showing
chewing gum
everywhere in pharmacies in CBD shops in
supermarkets
and so if you're lucky you will not be
controlled if you're not lucky you will
get a control and depending on where you
are it can be bad timing but location so
it's it's all it creates real
discrepancy in in inequality on the on
the market
um
and what we see and and and two two
consequences we've seen so the first one
is not directly related to CBD that the
the the the second one is that a lot of
companies have started suing each other
for competition and for competition and
judges because the French authorities
have not taken real clear position and
official position regarding uh the
enforcement of the novel food regulation
even though they will say and they
rewrite somewhere you're not supposed to
place until those products on the market
until the FSA has given the marketing
authorization yet
um you still have
no real enforcement and so the courts
whenever you will have a competitor
suing another competitor for unfair
competitions claiming that said
competitor is selling his products on us
in supermarkets while he's not doing it
because he wants to remain clean
um
the judge will say will simply decide
most of the time that uh he is not the
one who has to make decision until the
competent authorities have taken a clear
position on what to do regarding notably
um the transitional measures that are
contained in the noble food regulation
um
the second issue is the hemp flower so
with the prohibition of the retail sale
of hand flowers to Consumers
um the a lot of Industry players
actually sued the government and and to
have the uh the regulation repealed or
at least the article that was setting
out the Prohibition repealed and so
um
in 2022 we had three major Court
decisions the first one was the
Constitutional Council in January 7th
2022 that reminded the definition of
Narcotics and that precise that by
narcotic we we must understand
psychotropic substances that
characterize by risk of addiction and
harmful effects on health so that was
pretty important for the CBD industry
because it kind of confirmed what had
already been set up by the the ECG in
in on January 24th 2022 the French the
Council of State suspended the provision
of the regulation that prohibited the
retail sale of hemp flowers to Consumer
so the retail sales resumed and in
December 29th
2022 the Council of States ruled on the
merits of the case and uh decided to
repeal the article one paragraph two of
the regulation and hence repealed the
prohibition of rooted sale of raw hemp
flowers and leaves to Consumers so it's
now
um the the legalization is uh
confirmed what's next further following
this decision is that the government is
supposed to review the regulation what
they will come up with it's a question
because we know they're still reluctant
and they don't want to have smoking
products on the French market so uh it's
a big question
um
T may be easier to solve because even
the European
commission has already indicated to
France that t is a food product so you
cannot rule as you know an architect but
the smoking product issue remains a real
question
um and
um we would expect more clarifications
in the regulation itself notably
regarding the safety the THC levels in
in food products in cosmetics and but we
are not sure that the legislator is
going to come up with any clarification
anytime soon so those are questions that
are still remain 2023 may be an
interesting year so we'll see what
happens thank you
[Applause]
thank you very much Marie so uh next
speaker up is Robert Jeff
all good good to go out uh
hi everyone my name is Robert jappy I'm
a regulatory lawyer um based in London I
focus on uh advising medical cannabis
and CBD companies on all this or
day-to-day Regulatory Compliance and
that's
graduated interval regulatory support
first or big corporate commercial
transactions as well
um today I'm going to be talking about
the disaster Zone that is medical
cannabis in the UK
um it's going to sound like
I'm being very negative about things
there is still huge huge growth
potential in medical cannabis in the UK
and I genuinely believe in it but
um the next two to three years is going
to be a decisive time make or break for
this sector
so um firstly medical cannabis has been
legal in the UK for more than four years
now uh patient numbers have increased
slowly last year we think there was
about twenty thousand patients in the
legal regime which are receiving
prescriptions and having them fulfilled
that's an increase from 7 000 patients
in 2021 which is positive
but we are still way short of uh the
numbers that are needed to make this a
successful and sustainable industry in
the UK so um medical cannabis is paid
for privately uh
we don't have the same position as in
Germany where medical insurance will pay
for for cannabis medications and there's
been a handful and I mean literally a
handful four or five uh prescriptions
are being paid for by the NHS at the
moment so that's obviously the end goal
is to try and get the NHS to to start
paying for more and more prescriptions
but we seem to be quite far away from
that at the moment
so this is the agenda for today so I'll
just do a brief history of how we got
medical cannabis legalized in the UK
I'll talk about the five stages of the
supply chain I'm going to go through
some of the issues uh the challenges
that the sector that is facing and that
will include things like being able to
advertise medical cannabis uh the
restrictive prescribing
um situation and also cost and quality
of of products is a real issue as well
and then
um I'm going to give you my ideas on how
we can solve things uh some of them will
probably be quite controversial
um but I don't think it's uh being
talked about enough about how we we make
an industry where businesses can
actually be profitable and successful
um so 2018 we had a a stellar media
campaign whereby mothers with uh sick
children children who had epilepsy were
going across to the Netherlands
um getting the Cannabis medications for
them bringing them back into the UK and
as they entered the UK the Border force
would seize the the medications from
them and this was on the front page of
every newspaper across the country
public opinion swung very quickly behind
medical cannabis and the home office had
to act
um and you know they did a six weeks
six-week concert consultation and then
they they legalized and it just caught
everyone by surprises you know for the
home office to act that quickly is is
unheard of in the UK so we have
cannabis-based medications
um
are now in schedule two of the misuse of
drugs regulations so it's accepted that
finished product uh cannabis medications
have a medical purpose and a medical use
um they've been placed into the specials
medicine regime for unlicensed products
there are a couple of licensed
medications in the UK so you're talking
epidial exercise the GW
um medications otherwise it's all
brought in under the specials license
regime where there is a an unmet
clinical need for certain conditions so
that's that's the current regime
um and I think a lot of the problems
that I'm going to identify today will
basically boil down to the the industry
being hampered by the the regulatory
regime
so these are the five stages of the
medical cannabis supply chain
this isn't Like official five stages
this is my made-up five stages that I
use to get it right in my head so this
is how I explain it to people so you've
got stage one is the EU GMP certified
products
pretty much all of the medical cannabis
um being prescribed in the UK is coming
from overseas we we do not have a
situation where cannabis companies are
growing medical cannabis for the the
Medical Market so it'll be coming from
Canada it'll be coming from Europe uh
there are starting to be some products
coming online from places like Colombia
and Africa
so you've got to have GMP certified
products to be able to issue it to
patients
stage two is import so you need a
license from the home office to be able
to receive the medical cannabis as it
comes into the UK stage three is
logistics and storage and so you need
another license from the home office
which is a wholesale distribution
Authority usually stage two and stage
three go together so you will have a lot
of companies in the UK that hold these
two licenses they will import the
product they'll store it and then
they'll distribute it via pharmacies and
and they will need a license from the
the mhra to allow them to to to bring in
these unlicensed medications and then
finally you've got the front line you've
got the clinics who are facing the
patients and you've got the doctors who
are issuing the prescriptions and they
have to be uh specially trained doctors
to to issue prescriptions and that's the
the restrictions on prescriptions is is
something I'll come on to uh so what
progress have we made since 2018
well uh the good news is as I said there
is an increase in patient numbers
um there are around 20 to 24 companies
running medical cannabis clinics in the
UK uh at present so you can imagine you
can do the math yourself 20 000 patients
amongst 24 clinics it is not a huge
number of patients that these clinics
are dealing with and the more I'm
hearing is that a lot of the time they
are just passing around patients between
them you know moving there's the same
number of patients around from Clinic to
clinic so we are not seeing a big
increase in patient numbers for these
clinics which will help them have a
sustainable business
so really it's only consultant doctors
that can do it there's about 30 or 40
000 doctors in the UK that are able to
prescribe medical cannabis we probably
maybe have about 100 to 150 who are
actually doing it so that's a really big
problem you know there's very few
doctors who are actually actively out
there prescribing medical cannabis and
that needs to change as well
um there's a huge problem with awareness
about medical cannabis in the UK the
majority of the population don't even
realize that medical cannabis is legal
uh so when you are trying to increase
patient numbers that is very very
difficult if people actually don't even
know that it's a it exists
um you only go to the US and you go into
a hotel and you turn on a TV and every
other advert is for a medication or a
treatment or a clinic or something like
that we don't have that in the UK so
that's a real big problem for medical
cannabis companies they cannot advertise
their services they cannot advertise
their products
um and it's driving them crazy to be
honest not being able to tell people
that they're there and the products are
available and that people can get access
you've then got the cost product cost is
is still relatively High you know a
medical cannabis patient in in the UK
will probably be looking at paying
around 200 to 250 pounds a month for
their uh to fulfill their prescription
and you know most people can't afford
that if you've got patients who are
receiving opioid medication from the NHS
for free
and you're saying you know stop using
those opioids and come and use medical
cannabis and you have to pay 200 250
pounds a month a lot of them will say
well I'll just stay with the free
medication thank you very much and the
cost uh is increased by the regulatory
burden that is is placed on the the
companies that are operating in the
supply chain
incredibly enough when you're only
dealing with such a small number of
patients it's a surprise that we still
have such problems with
um quality product and reliability of
products
um in the UK so it's one thing to get
a patient into the medical cannabis
regime it's it's even harder to keep
them in it and if you're having
patients receiving prescriptions and
having to wait two or three months
before they actually get their their
product the likelihood is they'll get
tired of waiting they'll go back to the
illicit Market if they do get their
product and it's a poor quality
you know we've had problems with mold
and seeds and all kinds of nonsense in
in the products that are being issued to
patients again they'll go back to their
dealer they won't they won't hang around
for this it's a way for a quality
product to turn up
so there's a lot of issues that need to
be addressed
um
one of the things that we really want in
the UK is for GPS to be able to
prescribe medical cannabis
um and in 2001 we had the medical
cannabis access bill
um was brought to Parliament uh I'm not
going to go into parliamentary procedure
but effectively a Bill gets bounced back
and forth between the house and Commons
and the House of Lords and then if it
gets enacted it becomes a enact a piece
of legislation
um this was a really sort of narrow
proposed legislation really had two two
key points and one was to allow GPS to
be able to prescribe it as well as these
specialist doctors and the Tory party
filibustered it and he got talked out
and it never went anywhere and the
expectation is um
that bill is probably dead and nobody's
going to try and bring it back and
initially I was surprised I thought you
know it's such a a small change that
we're asking for but in fact when you
think about it if suddenly Nationwide
all of the GPS in the UK could prescribe
medical cannabis you would probably see
patient numbers increase exponentially
and I think that's probably what the
government was worried about too much
too soon too quickly
um The Hodges review was a report that
was done recently which has called again
for GPS to prescribe but they've they've
suggested a nationwide trial and I think
this is actually potentially a really
good idea you know pick a a small area
get five or ten GPS who are Keen to be
involved and and you know let them
prescribe for six months 12 months with
the oversight of a specialist consultant
and see how it goes the difficulty with
that is GPS are already overwhelmed in
the UK right and you're going to say to
them look guys come and do some training
come and uh you know give some time to
this endeavor you're going to have to
explain to them what's in it for them
um the good thing is we've now got
countries like Australia where GPS are
prescribing regularly and I think if you
can perhaps demonstrate to GPS in the UK
that by prescribing medical cannabis in
place of some of the other treatments
that you are giving whether it be
opioids or whatever you may actually
start to see your patients coming less
and less because they're able to manage
their conditions more on their own with
the medical cannabis that would be in my
view the way you could really encourage
GPS to get involved and and make that
effort and put that time in to um
to get involved in this in this
prescribing regime we're still waiting
to see whether the NHS or or the
authorities would authorize a GP trial
but hopefully it will happen soon
because it's a really important part in
moving things forward
so advertising medical cannabis is
really really tough as I said the
medical cannabis companies are desperate
to advertise and in fact
um there was a recent well in the last
year there's been a a company in the UK
called dispensaroo which is basically a
recreational Cannabis company okay it's
a website you can go on there you can
buy your weed you can buy THC Vapes you
pay in crypto it gets delivered to your
house
obviously completely illegal and they
had quite a lot of press attention
because they did some Guerrilla
advertising whereby they made up some
tube posters to go on the train and just
slid it over the the legit posters uh it
got picked up by all the mainstream
media the guy behind it is giving
interviews to National newspapers
obviously anonymously and I thought this
guy's gonna be in jail very soon you
know nine to 12 months on is still
happening and it's getting picked up in
the Press again and I just can't cannot
believe that
um the police haven't done anything
about it they're clearly quite smart you
know to cover their tracks and make it
as hard as they can for the authorities
to um
to find them but the the point of that
story is that medical cannabis companies
would kill for that kind of exposure you
know to have articles being written
about what they are doing in The
Independent in the guardian in the in
the evening standard on a regular basis
they would love to be able to do that
but our regulations are very very strict
um
is it this one
yeah
anyway much like um
uh Silk Roads the the you know the
online platform for a listed products
the on the dark web
they caught the dread pirate Roberts in
the end you know what I mean so how long
these guys at dispensaru can get away
with it
um I don't know but the the fact of the
matter is that medical cannabis
companies are worried about
uh businesses like dispensaru
um how are they going to be able to
encourage patients to to get into the
legal Medical Market if the with these
recreational cannabis companies are
effectively setting up and are able to
to get away with it
um I suspect the police are under
pressure to try and um
I can take it from there I think yeah
spray but that's okay no worries
um but yeah it's it's a real issue for
for medical cannabis companies and what
happened recently there was an article
in some of the Cannabis Publications
like business can like um uh cannabis
wealth about an import of some medical
cannabis from by an Australian company
into the UK
um and it had come from I think their
cultivation site in Jamaica and it was
the first import of medical cannabis
from Jamaica into the UK and business
can and cannabis wealth they wrote These
amazing articles saying what a great
company what a great product what an
amazing thing and the CEO of another
medical cannabis company who I won't
name emailed the Australian company they
emailed the Jamaican company they
emailed cannabis wealth email business
can and said guys this is promotional
material if you don't take this down by
4 pm today I'm going to snitch on you to
the medicines and Healthcare regulatory
Authority so whilst this medical
cannabis company is desperate to
advertise they will absolutely make sure
that nobody else is able to do it if
they can't as well that's that's the
current state of the industry
um I know about this because the
Australian company sent the article to
me and said Robert what's our exposure
here and I was like yeah you've got this
is this is promotional material you've
gone beyond factual into the promotional
realm you're starting to you know tell
everyone it's an amazing product and you
just can't do it
um
and this is where maybe now there is a
potential crossover between the CBD
market and the medical cannabis market
now I'm not talking about CBD today and
I think the reality in the UK is that
CBD is about reaching its peak there's
not too much growth left in that that
market what cud companies do have
is they've got a huge database of CBD
consumers that they that have been
buying their products for the last four
five six years right and if you have a
CRM of 80 000 consumers who maybe are
paying between 100 and 200 pounds a
month for your products
that would be a really really useful
platform to to leverage to try and pull
those consumers into the legal Market if
you could
you know access that 80 000 you only
need a conversion rate of about three
four five percent and you're starting to
generate serious serious numbers so one
of the things that I've been thinking
about is how can
medical cannabis companies team up with
CBD companies now to leverage that
consumer base and try and pull more
people into the into the market
um whether it will happen or not I don't
know but um I think it would be a really
really good idea
so here's a really interesting one
um patient power in the UK is
substantial okay the medical cannabis
patients in the UK have a very very
powerful voice
um and this is a screenshot from a
website called Med Bud Wiki
um it is a website that is run by a chap
called Ralph Leonardo McMurray and he is
a phenomenal resource the amount of time
and effort he puts into putting this
together
um he's quite astonishing and what this
website does is it lists all of the
available medical cannabis products
currently on the market it lists the
price point it lists uh where it comes
from it has patient reviews it is an
incredibly powerful resource amongst the
patients and now it's being used by the
medical cannabis companies to see which
products the patients like which
products they are coming back for
um and a bad review on midbud Wiki for
your product is is a serious serious
deal now most medical cannabis companies
in the UK will have a patient liaison
officer who is you know dedicated to
monitoring this resource and making sure
that their products are getting good
reviews
um and and it means that these companies
have to work really really hard to get
rid of delays and poor quality products
because as I said getting a patient into
the medical cannabis Market is one thing
keeping them is is is is even harder
as I said the cost is a big problem
um
again this goes into who are you
targeting to get into the medical
cannabis market now obviously we'd love
to have all of the pain patients in
there but as I said before if they're
already receiving medication and
treatment for free from the NHS it's
going to be very hard to persuade them
to stop that and start paying 200 250
pounds a month for medical cannabis so
this is where it perhaps starts to get a
bit controversial and and in the UK for
the last four or five years every time
you go to see a talk or a panel events
on medical cannabis it's the same thing
put the patient first put the patient
first put the patient first right
um
don't get me wrong patient access and
patient experience is a vital importance
okay but if we don't start to figure out
a way
so these companies to actually make
money and be profitable I know a lot of
patients think that medical cannabis
companies are incredibly greedy and
they're making millions I promise you is
quite the opposite
um if we don't figure out a way to ease
the cost burden and the regulatory
burden on medical cannabis companies
um we're not going to have a medical
cannabis industry for patients to access
so it's really important yes you've got
to put the patient first and it is an
important factor
but we've got to start talking about
profits as well how is it that these
companies are actually going to be
profitable be successful and and still
be here in three four five years time
as I said you ignore the patient lobby
at your peril you know they are they are
they are well voiced they are they are
influential
um and and medical cannabis companies
are really taking notice
and finally look
if it fits the
if it's the regulatory burden that is
causing a lot of these problems then you
would look to the government to try and
help okay we need some sort of
intervention from the government here to
either ease the regulatory burden uh to
to boost the industry in some way
I went to an event with this CMC a few
months ago and we were told the center
for medicinal cannabis a very
influential organization in the UK very
closely linked to the Tory party you
know they were influential in getting
medical cannabis legalized in the UK and
we were told that the government doesn't
care they their their position was that
in 2018 we took action to legalize our
job is done you know we did what we had
to do it's up to you to run with it
um
the government doesn't care
then that's a really really big problem
you're going to need
governmental support to to actually make
the UK a thriving medical cannabis
industry if they don't help then it's
not going to happen
um hopefully I think we'll have a change
of government in the relatively near
future and um again and that's a meeting
when I suggested you know we need a
change of government I was told no no no
no no nothing good will come from that
well in my view what could be worse than
they don't care
you know it couldn't be any worse with a
change of government so I'm very hopeful
we'll have a change of government soon
and then hopefully we may start to get
the support that we need to move the
industry forward yes
so the United States at the retail book
the biggest cost drivers are performed
at that position costs labor and then
Federal Taxation and settled from there
there's really nothing no profitability
yeah not even for your rents or anything
about that in church of profitability in
the UK what what are the big cost
writers that's that's preventing the
profit bill so is the the licensing
obligations the actual cost and
difficulty of getting the licenses and
maintaining the licenses is substantial
um
what companies want to do is they want
to bring in just you know big bags of of
dried flour and then package it up
themselves and distribute it they can't
do that unless um in certain conditions
um so the product is having to come in
as a finished product and and obviously
every other step of the supply chain
someone is taking their margin so by the
time we then get to the doctors uh
you've got uh you know the the fee of
paying the doctors uh running the clinic
and as I understand it with a lot of
these medical cannabis clinics and that
that have physical clinics their cash
burn rate is insane right so until you
can start getting the patient numbers up
they are just losing money
um
so so this is this is where we come to
the the inflection point in the next two
or three years if the government is not
going to help what are we going to do
it's my last slide no I'm nearly
finished
um so first of all
2023 is going to be survival okay uh
most medical cannabis companies would
playing the survival game last year is
probably going to continue this year as
well
um you're going to see uh a lot of
consolidation in the market we're
already starting to see it in CBD
lovehem filed for administration
um a lot of sort of mergers as well have
have fallen away do not be surprised if
you see some of the really big players
in the medical UK medical cannabis
Market disappear either disappear or be
acquired or or be absorbed by by a
bigger player that's definitely going to
happen this year
presence no that's okay so the last
thing I'm going to say is um
my first experience of of legal cannabis
was in California in 2012 and I was
walking down Venice Beach and there was
all of these touts on this on the on the
beach saying you know come in and see
our doctor pay your forty dollars and
you'll get your prescription and it was
amazing because they had this sign of
medical conditions and you had really
serious stuff at the top cancer multiple
sclerosis that sort of thing and then
down at the bottom you had stress and
you know sleep and that sort of thing
and you go in and they say oh do you
ever get stressed at work and you say
yeah I do I do get stressed at work
there's your prescription you know and
and it was amazing and then you know I
was there with a girlfriend at the time
and one of the towels shouted after us
you know couples that blazed together
stays together you know and and the
reality of that in California in 2012
you had a wreck Market masquerading as
as a as a medical Market okay and
unfortunately this is where I'll get
lots of stick for saying this this is
what needs to happen in the UK we need
to stop thinking about just patience and
you had to start thinking about
consumers one less person buying from
the illicit Market is one more person
buying from the legal Market whether
they are a patient whether or a consumer
whatever it may be so it to my mind that
is the only way we are going to start
generating the patient numbers that we
really need
um and hopefully we'll then end up like
places like California moving to a full
adult use Market the risk of course is
if the media get hold of uh you know
evidence that we have a wreck Market
masquerading as medical then that could
be really problematic in the UK but
unfortunately
um we've got to get patient numbers up
and that means taking some fairly
radical and Innovative approaches to
putting more people into the legal
Market
thank you very much
[Applause]
how did you
a final speaker of the league of hell up
today Daniel Heyman from Switzerland
there's a lot of activity in this uh
also crap I like have you
yeah promise me so I'm sad this thing is
banged up that's okay
okay hi thank you very much my name is
Daniel Heyman I'm a corporate and life
science lawyer from Zurich I was
previously a Commodities Trader so I'm
not sure on Woody Allen's uh Stairway To
Hell whether I moved up or down I I
leave that to you I know that we don't
have too much time left so I'm gonna do
that relatively quick and dirty without
presentation
um the framework that is embraced in
Switzerland for uh legal
for the whole Market is the narcotics
Act
and in Switzerland cannabis with the THC
content up to one percent is considered
is not considered a narcotic drug and
everything above is a narcotic drug
in the law it says Delta 9 THC and its
isomers so here already the first
question thc8
and any other compounds that have the
same sum formula and molecular weight as
thc9
Delta 9 is considered a narcotic drug
and based on that framework we basically
have three different classifications the
first one is cannabis with a THC content
below one percent let's say the CBD
market and then everything that goes
above one percent is either the medical
Market or the non-medical adult use
Market or slash recreational Market
let's speak first about the CBD Market
Switzerland's relatively big on cannabis
flower
it's probably one of the biggest
producers in Europe of cannabis flour
and also one of the biggest exporters of
cannabis flour and the way CPD is
regulated really depends on how you as a
producer classify and bring the product
to Market so cannabis flour is a
smokable mostly
and as a smokable it's tobacco
substitute law that applies in
Switzerland freely marketable which
makes it relatively special in Europe
now other markets are joining Czech
Republic and so on but this Market is
still
depending on on where the flower is sold
in growth or in retraction mode but it's
cyclical
then we have other products like e
cigarettes and vaporizers that are
considered as classified as a
utility article for human contact and as
such it is also absolutely freely
marketable in Switzerland
then we have the Cosmetic products all
the Cosmetic problems I can tell you a
lot about the Cosmetics it's been quite
a ride because
cannabis oils for example either with
CBD isolate or full spectrum have been
marketed in Switzerland as chemicals
first then or even as foodstuffs first
and once all this advertisement the
government realized that doesn't work
because of Novel food regulation also
applies in Switzerland by the way as in
the EU
they moved to chemicals and then they
moved to
um
cosmetic products which is an
interesting stretch and obviously the
authorities don't like this change in
classifications because the product
themselves didn't really change
our arguments was always that as long as
the products are safe and comply with
all the regulations they should be
in the market and there should be a
valid way to be able to Market these
products so that's for the CBD Market
in general let's speak about the medical
market so ta cannabis with the THC
content of one percent and above in
Switzerland was an exception so there
was a way to market for these products
but only with the special permit from
the health Ministry and that changed
last October where the market really
opened up so cannabis with a THC content
of one percent and up for medical
purposes became a controlled substance
no longer prohibited narcotic
with limited marketability so these
products today they can go to market and
the big difference is that doctors can
prescribe them freely they no longer
have to run to the health Ministry and
ask for a special permit and also the
patient doesn't have to be half dead and
have tried everything else before you
can get access to medical cannabis
obviously we have quite a big problem in
the medical Market also just one
there's a licensing system that was
introduced it's all now transparent
there's a way to market for producers
but it's quite complex I'm not going to
go into that today
but in reality it's already been
mentioned so I'm not going to repeat
most of that there's still a problem of
awareness doctors don't have enough
education and the biggest issue is
reimbursement medical cannabis is that
person reimbursed by the health
insurance in Switzerland
you actually have to show and you have
to prepare a whole dossier and hand it
in in order to get reimbursement but
it's getting there it's there's
companies Who start and help with this
process I'm also helping the doctors
with administrative burdens so just to
go back to what Robert just said earlier
I agree we need to show medical
companies how to make money but one of
the big big issues is that we don't have
the buy-ins from the from the healthcare
professionals and we really have to find
a way to educate doctors and to
facilitate their life in order to
understand how they can easily prescribe
medical cannabis and actually have a
benefit from that also we have another
challenge that for a lot of GPS General
Practitioners in Switzerland one of the
big income streams is self-dispensation
as B and because we have like a
magisterial preparation framework in
Switzerland where you need to have a
two-tiered consultation first by the GP
and then also by the pharmacy you cannot
self-dispense cannabis in the Swiss uh
when you go to a GP so also the
financial incentive there is a bit lower
for the GPS but it's not all GPS and we
believe that there's various ways to
solve this problem but that's definitely
one of the things that's uh that that's
a problem
last
we also have a data collection
obligation for doctors they have to
collect data it's not sanctioned if they
don't do it so let's see how what's
going to happen there but
they would like to comply and it's
definitely
um a little bit of a burden for them and
it might also be one of the reasons that
many people or many doctors say well I
don't know I'm not going to page for
this additional time additional burden
I'm not going to do it
let's speak about the lastly about the
recreational markets now in Switzerland
these products are illegal
however there's been a change in the
narcotics act that allows for pilot
trials so actually the first legal
dispensation in pharmacies for the first
pilot trial just happened last month in
Basel which is a great uh precedent I
would say and these these products come
in various ways at the moment the first
products are cannabis flowers that are
packaged
the trials are always in the context of
a scientific
trial scientific research and you have
public and private organizations that
can apply at the federal Office of
Public Health the health Ministry to
conduct such a trial so usually you need
someone to finance the trial you need to
have a research institution you have to
have the buy-in from a municipality
because you can do it in one or a few
municipalities but not federal on the
federal level Nationwide and once you
have all these buy-ins and you have
prepared your project if it is approved
you can go to market you can go to
market either via Pharmacy social clubs
or coffee shops so it's quite flexible
you can even have edible so all the
product regulatory constraints that you
have for novel food and so on don't
apply in in this scheme
so you can have up to five thousand
people in in such a trial the term is
limited to five years possible to extend
another two years and you can actually
dispense up to 10 grams per page per
consumer per month of pure THC which
translates to
depending where you are the maximum THC
content is 20 in the product or 10
milligrams per serving it translates to
basically maybe 50 60 grams of
of flour which is a lot of cannabis for
one for one consumer
so that's what's happening in
Switzerland at the same time there's
also and parallel to these to these uh
trials
there's also development parliamentary
initiative that was um handed in a while
back it already passed through the
national and state Council now the
National Council has the mandate to
prepare draft legislation for full
legalization of cannabis for non-medical
use in Switzerland I'm quite involved in
the process with the industry
Association that they represent and it's
quite fun it's quite a challenge to find
the right framework on how public policy
considerations
can be aligned with uh with the goal of
of getting rid of the black market and
and also satisfy consumer the consumer
perspective so we're trying to put all
these under one hat
and um
I believe that by the end of the year
this year or beginning of next year
we're going to have the first draft for
legalization of cannabis in Switzerland
and let's see where it goes from there
that's basically for me
I think was pretty quickly
[Applause]
another q a I guess so yeah now it's to
open it to the floor for any questions
of a lot of issues uh you can see
we're dealing with Germany the largest
beverage station in the European Union
and that's movement towards regulation
France which traditionally has a very
strong domestic market for cannabis and
yet seems to be stuck in the soils
the UK well
you know formerly in the EU now outside
the EU
having made some progress towards
regulation for medical use and then
effectively the market evaporating as I
see it before uh the eyes of those are
trying to get into the industry and then
Switzerland kind of coming up with a
very interesting pilot scheme um which
is of course going to be fodder for
false for other jurisdictions who may be
considering to get down that road first
question I'm going to direct unless
there are any questions from the floor
is this case that is coming before the
federal courts in Germany on the
constitutionality of cannabis perhaps
Kai you might just a little elaborate a
little bit on that for our listeners
um
you can't really seriously right now I
think it's coming or probably all at the
same time in March so but what are the
general thrusts of what they are going
to argue in that case have you any kind
of insight in terms of what exactly do
you mean these in terms of for example
if we were taking a constitutional
challenge of an issue before a supreme
court we'd have certain grounds for
making the art human human rights of
course just on the basic Article 2 and
article three article two is the free um
free personality and article 3 is the
comparence to alcohol and the different
treatment of these two substances and in
terms of the hierarchy of law obviously
and train
um German constitutional law the
International Convention on human rights
and then the single narcotic stress
convention
in terms of the trust of the argument
are they saying well the rights of the
individual
take precedence over some International
Convention is that the gist of the
argument I'm making
yes yes but for first and foremost it's
the new scientific findings that
cannabis is not
damaging in health and
is not a Gateway at work and all these
old arguments which have we which we
have overcome so the mix of them all of
a lot of aspects the expansion of the
argument because under International no
of course we talk about you know control
drugs but cannabis is limited for
medical and scientific use so they're
really using this is the argument saying
that at the time of the framing of the
convention of 1961 and the subsequent
psychotropic conventions in 72. the
understanding of medical and scientific
was nemeshit but in the current state of
our research knowledge that it should be
expounded upon is that the just the way
they're going with us
ground spread okay Daniel
I'm very curious
um about the Swiss pile of Marvel in
fact somebody said to me recently with
Switzerland is that no jurisdiction as
of yet has managed to get regulation of
cannabis whether it's the 21 states in
the United States or some of the
jurisdictions like Uruguay
but they were very confident that the
Swiss model could be the route to go
down and I'm just kind of curious of
your perception how long is this
particular pilot scheme set to run and I
understand it correct me if I'm wrong is
this burn was the first or uh Basel yes
a Basel so how long is it supposed to
run for
supposed to run by law between five and
seven years so five is the base and then
there's a possibility to extend by
another two years but as I mentioned
earlier yes and that's going to be the
interesting question is we have a
parallel
development happening on the legislative
side where again
we are and the government is really and
the National Council is really trying to
to put a bit momentum into drafting the
first uh legislation and if that goes
through Parliament we have a semi-direct
democracy so there's a possibility that
it will end up on the ballot again and
we'll we'll see how that develops but if
that doesn't happen the fastest road to
legalization could be within two years
already two three years
um it could be also four years but
that's my estimate is that the latest in
five years we have a legal cannabis
Market in Switzerland and that would be
of course dependent on neighboring
jurisdictions as well as part of the
calculation I assume it would probably
be yes
at the same time I think Switzerland is
a bit of of
a special kid in Europe not being part
of the European Union and I could
imagine that Switzerland might actually
go its own way yes some extent
a Mary I have a question for you and
there's um there's one that probably
some of our Irish delegates here will
have questions about them obviously it's
the free movement under article 34 of
the treaty for the furthering of the
European Union and really where this
comes down to is that our classic case
of canovape back in 2019 28 years ago
the smoke one of the major problems that
we've had in this jurisdiction and it
happened uh just before Christmas was an
appeal case and I appreciate you haven't
had an opportunity to look at this in
which a judge in the Irish high court
was presented with a judicial review
application and the judicial review
application was in relation to the
seizure of CBD products that were
imported from Slovenia
the upshot of course this application
was that they wanted a declaration but
the seizures were wrong
and secondly they were seeking a
declaration that the minister for health
showed of course Define what the
appropriate limits for CBD now this all
comes down to the classic 0.2 as it was
0.3 percent but the orange course took a
very very conservative
um take on this in other words a literal
um understanding of article 7 of the
single narcotic Strokes convention by
saying that any presence of THC in a
product
that might come across you know the
Frontiers from other EU member states
Falls within the context of article 36
as the state's right to prohibit it now
my understanding of this is the Irish
courts have actually got it wrong so
perhaps maybe just for some of the
delegates here you might explain a
little bit more about the candidate
decision and The Wider context of free
movement if I haven't put you on this
far too much
no well so the the canary case was
really about so if I take the French
regulation the former one before the
cannabeb case the regulation was
limiting the legality of CBD products to
products that were made from extraction
of the hemp seeds and fibers only which
meant that basically any extract that
was made from the hemp plant in needs
entirety was considered illegal in
France the problem in the candidate case
was that the products the liturgist
product was a
e-cigarette and vaping products that was
imported from Czech Republic
where it was made legally from the
entire hemp plant and the French
authorities considered that it was an
earthquake because the the
the extract was made from the Hem plate
in this in its entirety so it ended up
in front of the ECG and the ECG
considered that a member states
domestic law that is too restrictive
compared to EU law unless the state
actually demonstrate and proves that the
the restriction and the additional
restriction is due to health public
health issues and threat or threat to
public holder
um you you can't have a more restrictive
rule or law in a member states so that's
where the the kind of a case really
really changed things in France and we
we ended up with those new regulations
and we also had further domestic
regulations because the kind of a case
was actually about extracts everybody
made it about like flowers and and raw
flowers but it was really about extracts
we then had a few months later a case a
decision in France from the spring the
administrative Supreme Court
um
judging that
it would apply also to Raw flowers that
would be imported from another EU member
state where it was legally produced and
and then you could not prevent their
sales in France
um on the basis of the free movement of
goods so I'm quite surprised actually to
see the Irish decision because it goes
against the entire principle free
movement of goods and in particular
since now the the THC level for
industrial hemp in Europe is 0.3 percent
France was actually ahead when they
published published the regulation in
late 2021 by using the 0.3 they
anticipated the the agricultural EU
regulation and so they put 0.3 percent
before all the other EU member states
but so saying that any trace of THC in
in products if even though legally
produced produced in another EU member
state is considered as an architect then
we
in my opinion there's a real problem
with this decision I think there is
definitely an arguable case now I'm
obviously very blessed to discuss uh the
Goose's case too much because I'm not
sure whether that is under appeal to the
court of appeal but I can certainly see
some reference points to the European
court of justice my understanding is
summer some approach was made and I can
only say this from just general
awareness to the European commission to
ask whether this decision was in line
with the current perception of things at
Europe but I understand nothing was
forthcoming there so the fact is as I
see it the Irish Court seems to ignore
that principle that the least
restrictive rule within another member
State should be the rule to follow but
it's taking a um this would be
interesting to policy question to Robert
to a certain extent because
they are applying the misuse of drugs
act
um the misuse of drugs act 1977 is the
gracious knockoff in terms of
legislation because it's basically the
UK equivalent
um from 1971 as transposed into the
Irish into Irish law so it's largely
based on the UK law all beers they're
taking a very strict field so becoming
curious as to the perception of
um the UK courts in relation to the
presence of any component of THC uh in
any products such as a CBD product
um uh what the UK courts would view it
at the bones
so the the misuse of drugs Act is more
than 50 years old okay it is not fit for
purpose
um it doesn't make any distinction
between high THC
flower and and low THC flour because in
1971 you know we didn't really know
about these things to to a wide extent
um the misuse of drugs act
disproportionately impacts upon uh
communities of color and and communities
um poorer communities
and you know for for a good long period
everyone the middle classes in England
have been absolutely fine with that so
it needs radical reform and overhaul
um I can't see it happening anytime soon
um
the issue therefore then is
the the the the misuse of drugs Act
implements the UK's obligations under
the UN narcotics convention into
domestic law and decisions like can a
vape have made it very very clear in my
view that
um domestic legislation should not be
used to pro uh to prohibit products
which don't have any narcotic properties
and that's the issue with things like
hemp flower CBD flower people are
consuming it but the THC content is so
low that nobody's getting high from it
so it's it's not considered to be a
narcotic
um and it's much the same with CBD
products as well you know there's the
THC content is is low enough that people
aren't actually getting high from these
products so why is the misuse of drugs
act being used to prosecute people
selling CBD flare in the UK the bizarre
thing I just didn't have to journalists
the Irish courts are taking such a
ridiculous view
of 0.2 percent which is of course which
is a 0.3 percent of that is in the plant
that they're you know kind of
complaining that this would be an attack
on public health if we read the judges
decision it's it's you know anyone with
any knowledge at cannabis would say that
is like um I suppose we used to have a
product called Club Shandy as most Irish
people would be aware of which is
lemonade and I think it's almost zero
percent one percent alcohol all in it
you know that nobody could possibly get
pissed on but this is the equivalent but
anyway Daniel was about to you know I I
just wanted to add one thing on on the
CBD
um oils for example it's really about
the ratio so you can have a CBD oil with
0.2 percent THC and 0.1 percent CBD
shoots you to the moon it's incredibly
psychoactive it's it's it's uh it's a
narcotic so in Switzerland also now when
we're discussing uh an entire framework
we're thinking about how do we deal with
these products and on top of that how we
do we deal with all these hhcs and other
cannabinoids that can also really uh be
regarded as THC equivalence but are not
specifically mentioned in law
yeah so the the public health argument
that you mentioned Nile that to my mind
I don't know Marie will agree with this
but that flies in the face of the
verdict in canovape you know the
European Court justice was quite clear
um you should not be using domestic
narcotics legislation
um to prohibit non-narcotic proper
products on the basis of Public Health
because there's no evidence to show that
there is a an issue for public health
and that's the situation in the UK the
UK authorities are deathly afraid of THC
you know they they
um
that the home officers ask the The
Advisory Council on issues of drugs to
to carry out a consultation on what
should be the illegal limit of THC in a
CBD product and we all know that the
result is going to be so low that you're
going to end up in a situation where you
only have isolate-based CBD products and
these products don't work people want
full spectrum so this is the elephant of
the room about these isolated products
yeah I could say a little bit more about
that yeah sure and um you know for
regulatory lawyers it's great because it
means there's going to be endless legal
challenges as soon as the the home
office adopts its new position on THC
that's going to get judicially reviewed
and and you know because because the
limit the limit will be so low it won't
have any evidential basis it will be a
policy decision rather than a decision
based on actual evidence
yeah and uh so so the public health
um issue and the the public order
because in France that we had both and
it's exactly what the the Council of
State ruled
um in in December last December uh it
actually
said that the French government hadn't
proved in any way whatsoever any threat
um and the the public health threat or
the the public order threat that they
were claiming to prohibit the retail
sale of hemp flowers
um to Consumer
um and that was the government's
argument all along saying uh yes but you
can't for for the the law enforcement
for instance you cannot distinguish uh
raw ham flowers from Cannabis flowers
with a high THC when everybody proved to
them because this is what any other
member state does already
um that there are tests and specific
tests that are very easy to use that
don't cost too much money that you can
put in the flower and depending on the
color that comes out it's either
cannabis THC cannabis or hemp
um so so the the French government was
really really lost the this case
um in this aspect
another aspect and issue we have is the
with the zero three percent THC and the
fact that it's not precise depending on
the the products we're talking about
um zero three percent we we we saw
fairly recently legal geniuses that
decided to convert zero three percent
into milligrams and we saw gummies
appearing on the market with five
milligrams of THC and then they came up
and say hey about five milligrams of THC
it's far below 0.3 percent so it's legal
obviously this is if it's still on the
market it's not going to stay long
because it's definitely that doesn't
fall down of the reference dosage
this is an issue that we we see often
raised by the likes of the hpra about
the amount of Tolerance in the system so
I'm very curious how they get around
that in perhaps huge reference we don't
we don't see but we we saw that popping
out and people claiming about that and
we were like yeah well you know that's
the the exact issue we see with the lack
of clarity in the regulation at some
point you have to to Define exactly what
you want what is legal what is not legal
what you mean by
um the THC level the T the CBD levels
and or any other cab you know it's level
in in this type of this type of products
because without those precisions you
will always end up with people trying to
circumvent and going through and using
the you know the weaknesses of the
regulation to place products on the
market if we're talking about consumer
protection we need to have curry in in
the regulation and and not
legislators that are dragging their feet
because they don't want to move on with
this
we are there so at some point we they we
need to take their responsibilities and
to and to work
um to have clarifications where they're
needed okay thank you very much now I
wonder instructions that were 10 minutes
15 minutes soon for two so I may have
time for one more question anyone
Bob sorry bring it
it's been said that the CPP regulation
in UK is a model for the rest of the
world and I know you didn't comment much
on it but could you just describe why
people's talk about it that way and and
what are some of those basic features
so so novel food regulation is
effectively The Benchmark globally for
food standards and quality it is it is
um akin to a pharmaceutical procedure
the amount of data and the studies that
need to be prepared in relation to
um the products is extensive
um you're effectively talking about full
toxicology studies to show the impact of
taking the product for every day for 30
years you know so you can imagine
there's a huge amount of laboratory work
that goes into that
um
so so the expectation is once you have a
novel food compliant product you should
be able to introduce it into any Market
in the world because you will have the
safest most highest quality products
that there is
um the problem is that because of the
nature of of the data and the the
information that needs to be generated
it is an expensive and lengthy process
right
um it's it's effectively using a
sledgehammer to crack a walnut so the
regulatory burden that has been placed
on UK CBD companies to achieve novel
food compliance
um has in fact stifled the market it has
stopped Innovation you cannot bring new
products to to Market you cannot uh
bring new formulations to Market until
you have a cheese nut and achieved full
marketing authorization and the
expectation is that could take it some
anything between two and six years
so whilst
the introduction of Novel foods for the
CBD sector was supposed to be a platform
for the industry to really take off and
and hit the mainstream instead it has
caused a number of operators to drop out
of the market and he has placed a
significant Regulatory and financial
burden on the existing operators and
unfortunately sales have not increased
um at the rate that is needed to sustain
the the financial success of these
companies so so that's why there is a
general feeling that novel Foods uh has
has had the opposite effect of what it
was intended to do and you know it also
reflects on medical cannabis what
they're doing in the UK is they're
shoving these industries into existing
regulatory regimes that don't suit
cannabis so you you know putting medical
cannabis into the specials licensing
regime doesn't work
um and unfortunately amongst the UK
government there doesn't seem to be any
inclination to create bespoke regulatory
environments for cannabis products which
is ultimately what is needed so so
that's the issue
thank you
yeah thank you very much ladies and
gentlemen sorry I've been running around
a little bit so that concludes uh this
morning's uh panel I'd like to thank our
speakers Kai Marie Robert and Daniel are
for their excellent contributions this
morning so if you could give them a
round for close package
[Music]
thank you
[Applause]
foreign
[Music]