[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review we had a little bite
there but we're delighted to be back now
and we're talking all things kind of as
education on this episode we're
delighted to be joined by
ryan mccreener he's the founder and ceo
of sativa learning ryan how are you
keeping mate very well and how are you
i'm fantastic thank you very much for
being a nice health summer here over in
dublin so uh
we're back into the work now with
everybody back after holidays can you
give everybody a little overview of uh
how you got to where you are with sativa
learning and your your background and
time in canada
yeah sure so i i suppose this is a
fairly brief introduction to myself so
after university i worked as a
toxicology scientist
and the company i worked for created
drug testing kits for drugs of abuse and
one of the
panels i was involved with and tested
for synthetic cannabinoids and as well
as cannabis other prescription drugs
and and designer drugs or street drugs
so
that's kind of where i got my
introduction um
to the world of toxicology
did that for a few years um
and then later went off traveling and
and ended up in vancouver and when i was
in vancouver
i worked for the government um when just
shortly after they legalized um adult
use or recreational cannabis
in 2018 so i was on the phones taking
calls from the public on everything to
do with cannabis and educating um around
cannabis and eventually moved into a
training role where i would travel to
retail stores across british columbia
and educate the cannabis
consultants and
yeah and moved home back to back to
belfast not too far away from you um
i think it was end of 2019 and that's
when i decided to set up sativa learning
um as an education platform for the
cannabis industry
okay amazing um so you've
got a fair deal of experience already
before you set up sativa learning and
knowing exactly what to teach can we
talk about the cannabis education
worldwide like we've got amsterdam over
the us legally have their own 101
version everybody seems to have that uh
that little introductory uh module for
everybody to get their grips around who
do you seen as having the best cannabis
education at the moment is it europe or
is it north america
i would say definitely north america um
as you say oaksterdam are probably one
of the the biggest leaders in the space
and green floor academy and are
also doing very well and
there's many others you know there's
cannabis training university tricom
institute there's quite a lot of these
platforms which are very successful
in north america
and i don't think that a leader is has
emerged yet here
um in the uk um even europe and beyond
you know i think even australia and new
zealand um
could do with a leader i know there is
one that started in in south africa
the name escapes me at the minute but
yes we're seeing a lot of cannabis
education platforms pop up at the minute
and i think if you look at what's
happening in north america
um colleges and universities are now
starting to offer cannabis education
programs and some of them in conjunction
with cannabis education platform so if
you look at what the future of the
cannabis industry is going to be like
it in it's my belief that it's going to
be like any other industry where you're
going to need some form of um you know
formalized credible training and
education and to secure
a position within the industry
and i think if you're unfamiliar with
the cannabis industry you might you know
you might be too sure as to why that is
but if you look at the industry as a
whole from seed to you know seed banks
genetics
cultivation and extraction purification
product formulation
and the retail side of things operating
the cannabis business cannabis policy
there's so many avenues and aspects to
the cannabis plant
um
you know and
whether it's wellness medical
recreational or even if you're looking
at the industrial hemp side which is a
whole other category as well
there is a need for um credible
formalized training in the industry so
that's
that's what we're trying to do with
sativa learning that's the reason it's
it's been set up
and when i returned home from canada i
noticed there was
um a big gap
in knowledge especially in the the cbd
industry so that's why we we released a
course on the cbd industry to provide a
comprehensive overview and for people
trying to get a better understanding
and what we're going to do is just
continue to add different courses where
we're now working on a medical cannabis
course with the medical cannabis
clinician society
and in the hopes that we can start
educating more clinicians on prescribing
cannabis based medicines
yeah well actually we'll kind of move
into the next topic now scenes that you
brought it up and it was educating
medical professionals this seems to be
the the hardest uh hurdle that a lot of
people are having to overcome is that
there is no doctors who know what
they're talking about generally and uh
nor they want to prescribe a medicine
that they don't know what they're
talking about what's going to be the
magic arrow that gets true to this is it
going to be targeting a specific
association of doctors and get them all
on board in one fell swoop is there
going to be some super celebrity doctor
that gets on board and a lot of them
start to follow what do you see
happening over the next six to 12 months
that'll help get the patients to access
to the products that they need
that's a hard one to
to
to answer you know what what's going to
be the there's so many factors involved
in why medical professionals are not
educated
on cannabis based medicines so so it's
tricky to say i mean the main reason as
you touched on is you know
there's just a lack of education for
them at the minute
um i think anybody that's familiar with
cannabis we'll we'll know a little bit
about the endocannabinoid system
so for anybody that doesn't know it was
only discovered in in the 1990s but it
has yet to make its way into
standard medical teaching whether that's
your continuing teaching as a medical
professional or when you're a student
um in university
um so i mean it's an end it's a
neurotransmitter system and doctors will
be familiar with the likes of the
serotonin system the dopamine system the
noradrenaline system
and but the vast majority of medical
professionals will have no understanding
of the endocannabinoid system
and it's vital to our our function and
i'm sure you've heard of dr ethan
rousseau
um he's a
a world-renowned cannabis researcher
and he uses the prime example that there
are more cannabinoid receptors in the
brain than there are for all other
neurotransmitters
put together
so it has a an overall role in memory
pain control sleep appetite and
temperature control
immune response and and that's the
reason why cannabis medicines can
um
you know benefit such a wide range of
medical conditions
and
it would be similar to you know a
mechanic knowing nothing about the
engine of a car that's that's how
important the endocannabinoid system is
to to our health
and and we have endocannabinoids in the
body that regulate that system and but
when that system is not functioning
optimally we can introduce cannabinoids
from cannabis and to supplement that and
and help
and
help bring about homeostasis in the body
and so so that's one of the i suppose
the main one is the lack of education on
the ecs
then there's the issue of
plant medicine and
versus you know single compound
pharmaceuticals
or more broadly i suppose people will
look at it as eastern medicine versus
western medicine
and so western doctors have been
conditioned to think about medicine in a
certain way
and usually that's as you know single
compound drugs to combat a certain
condition uh but cannabis doesn't really
fall into that that category so there
needs to be a a paradigm shift here
and cannabis contains
um hundreds of of active compounds it's
a polypharmacy in itself
and there are over 140 cannabinoids
there are over 100 terpenes and and 20
or more
flavonoids that all interact
and when ingested they interact with
each other synergistically to create an
overall effect which
is known as the entourage effect
and doctors are just not comfortable
with that at this stage they have no
training on botanical medicines
and um
a lot of that as well will be fear of
the unknown for them you know um a
doctor that's used to prescribing pills
um to a patient will be very
uncomfortable
um with a patient vaporizing dried flour
to to get relief for you know chronic
pain or whatever it happens to be
so those are a couple issues and then
when it comes to the um i suppose the
research side of things there is a lack
of randomized controlled trials um which
would be considered kind of the gold
standard for single pharmaceutical
compounds
um and there are some for cannabis and
and products like epidiolex have made it
to market through
you know
clinical trials and rcts
and but cannabis does not lend itself
very well to randomized controlled
trials again because there are
hundreds of active compounds which work
together to give an overall effect
and due to that lack of rcts and then
there are very restrictive guidelines
and so i'll use the example in the uk
because i i know a bit more about the uk
guidelines than
the ireland ones but
um nice they're the the national
institute of health care and excellence
so they provide guidelines to the nhs
for prescribing medicines
and their guidelines
for cannabis are very restrictive
and because they have not looked at
cannabis medicine as whole plant
medicine rather they've pushed it down
the the single compound route and only
looked at rcts which there are not many
of
and when really they should be looking
at real world evidence and case studies
and observational data
and so
because the guidelines are so
restrictive um even if a doctor was
educated and willing to prescribe
um
it it's not that it's frowned upon it's
it's just the the guidelines are very
restrictive for them to prescribe so
that's another issue there
okay and you might know actually there's
a couple of private clinics opened up in
manchester and london that were
prescribing cannabis to its patients how
have they fared and has that been a case
of they've literally just gone and found
a doctor and a nurse trained them up on
cannabis and then they can open up their
own practice to prescribe cannabis is it
as simple as that
i i don't know about how you know i
wouldn't know the ins and outs of
actually setting up a clinic what i do
know is that you have to be on the gmc
specialist register to prescribe
cannabis
so
the uk system is actually quite liberal
and that you can prescribe for any
condition
and it's just not within the guidelines
it's not remember recommended in the
guidelines but there's um
they don't recommend against cannabis
medicines let's say so at the minute
they have epidiolex nabalone and sativex
would be the approved prescription
cannabis based medicines so if you want
to prescribe an unlicensed cannabis
medication like dried flour or
a full spectrum oil
and
doctors will will be hesitant to do so
but at the minutes
and the latest figures
sorry to interrupt you there so if a
doctor did prescribe and say look i
recommend dried flour is that product
available to a consumer in the uk at the
moment yes at the moment it is it's just
considered an unlicensed medication so
that's why you have to be on the on the
gmc specialist register to prescribe it
so there are patients currently
receiving cannabis flower or cannabis
oil and again they are unlicensed
medications and but there are around six
thousand
um
private prescriptions so the problem is
you know private prescriptions of course
are very expensive
expensive and unaffordable for most
patients and but at the minute those
clinics have
i believe there's last time i talked to
professor barnes around 60 to 70 um
medical cannabis clinicians currently
prescribing in the uk they have
prescribed around six thousand um
unlicensed cannabis medications full
spectrum medications
and there are only three nhs
prescriptions um
in in the uk which is just shameful
really
yeah that's uh it's a bit of a drastic
ratio there and i'd love to get the
feedback in what negative connotations
have happened to any of the patients of
those six thousand i'd be uh willing to
better a large sum of money that it's
pretty much zero
yeah yeah absolutely and and the good
thing is um you know there's the likes
of project 2021 that don't know if
you've heard of that before through drug
science so they're aiming to enroll 20
cannabis patients um in
and create
one of the largest bodies of without
evidence for
for medical cannabis and that will be
you know real world evidence and that
they're providing there so
they are starting to release some of
their findings from that so it's it's
good to keep an eye on that as well to
see how cannabis
patients are getting on and they've had
some very positive results so far
amazing so great very positive to hear
unfortunately we hit our time here for
this episode i'd definitely love to have
you back on and we can get into more
detail and start talking about some cbd
reset cb receptors and
some other finer details i don't know if
you saw peter greenspoon's paper there
in the harvard medical there the other
week it was very informative and there's
lots to discuss there but thank you for
coming on the show ryan it's much
appreciated
yeah thank you and thanks for doing your
bits to spread the word and you've had
some fantastic guests on so i appreciate
the work you're doing thank you very
much man it's very much appreciated
we'll chat to everybody in the next
episode and everybody have a good day
cheers