[Music]
welcome everybody next episode of the
Cannabis review I'm delighted to be
joined in this episode by Marian Maria
tyon and he is an investor entrepreneur
and speaker in the Cannabis industry how
you keep it today Marian doing well you
and thanks for having me on your
show thank you very much for joining us
I know you're a very busy man you've had
a pretty stellar career from creating
tequila br
and being an arest across a multitude of
companies do you maybe want to start
with you entering into the Cannabis
industry in 2015 and what opportunities
you saw and how the journey has gone so
far yeah thank you for this uh chance to
kind of tell my story but yeah so as you
mentioned got into the Cannabis industry
back in 2015 there's a law firm called
viente cederberg uh really well known in
the US as they helped with the
legalization of cannabis in Colorado and
then they've been working with other
states but also private companies and um
so the three Partners I knew uh from
beforehand and they were trying to solve
you know one of the biggest hurdles as
as more licenses were being handed out
and that is the challenge of ensuring
operational compliance right because
every state in the US has different sets
of laws and even down to the
municipality level and so uh the idea
was to create some sort of software that
helped license operators streamline and
create aici icies to you know
essentially stay compliant to all those
changing regulations and so that was uh
my kind of entree into cannabis and that
was back in
2015 uh and that's you know we started
simplify it a year after that and then
having been in the space uh more
opportunities were popping up and and so
I you know turned into also an investor
and advisor and board member in
multitude of
companies yeah it's been a very
successful Journey for you so far I
wanted to kind of touch on the three big
companies that you've been a part on and
maybe we'll start with saleon Solutions
what is the offering that this company
brings to the Cannabis industry and why
has it been so successful today yeah so
San Solutions is actually one of my
oldest companies I found it back in 2005
officially in 2008 so it's a software uh
Dev company uh us-based but the
engineers are in Sri Lanka and so it you
know obvious it's been around for quite
some time helping startups but also
larger companies save costs on their on
their development software development
and when I got into the Cannabis
industry we saw a lot of need also uh
for new technologies that were being
built and so just by the fact that I'm
now the chairman of the company I don't
actively run it uh I started kind of
pointing out opportunities to the
executive team at salon and you know in
short order all of a sudden they were
developing software products for some
really big uh Brands not Brands
companies um that are well known in the
Cannabis industry and they continue to
do so today um and so that's that's
really what I think sets Salon apart
it's now in today's environment you know
when when you're whether you're a
startup or a season tech company and
you're looking to build products that
serve the Cannabis industry there's a
lot of terminology and and nuances
that's you know very different in
cannabis versus other Industries and and
so this company and and the team behind
it has a lot of experience having built
products including simplifier uh you
know the compliance company that I run
as a CEO um and so I think that's what's
made it so successful so far and we're
opening up a uh you know an office in
Barcelona this month actually so just to
expand into Europe moving on to the next
company that I want to disc which is
simplifier which is the compliance and
regulation software provider which your
expertise in computer science this
seemed to be one of the most
advantageous uh sectors within the
Cannabis industry that people could
develop unique solutions for was that an
easy step from um Sal on Solutions and
how is everything going so
far yeah so simplify I have to say so in
all the companies I've started and
founded and and and run in the past this
has been probably the most challenging
uh primarily because I think the
Cannabis industry is still very early
right even in the US it's uh you know
there's 40 States that's not legal
there's obviously no federal it's not
legal on a federal level but because
it's so early just lots of challenges in
terms of creating product that helps not
only licensed operators but you know we
now have products for banks uh for
insurance companies for law firms even
government um and those are newer
products that we have but the initial
product was very challenging just trying
to understand the needs we knew what the
needs were going to be but really how do
you price it and because the industry
was changing so much Ian we had to keep
adapting in a very rapid pace so uh all
that to say you know simplify now is the
is the leader and the largest
operational compliance company in the
space we don't have anyone that competes
with us kind of the depth and breadth of
what we do um so we've finally found
kind of our firm footing and uh we
continue to grow and uh you know the
future looks quite optimistic and
uh you know we might even be coming into
Europe and other parts of the world as
they legalize uh you know as things
go yeah now it's a incredible success
story um now moving on to the third
company I want to discat which is
leafwire it's a a global networking
platform for the Cannabis industry can
you maybe explain why you thought this
was a great opportunity and the success
that the platform has having to date for
anybody who wants to check out more the
website is below yeah so leafire is what
we call the the LinkedIn of cannabis um
now again I think Leaf fire was founded
about four years ago and one thing that
we recognize was that traditional social
networks right so even so even on
LinkedIn now you can have a profile you
can post for the most part some uh
aspects of cannabis and it's not an
issue other social media as well but we
felt like the Cannabis industry uh and
when I say we as a board member and
investor felt like there was a need for
a vertical or social network that was
dedicated purely to cannabis right
because it's constantly it's growing not
just in the US in Canada and and other
parts of the world uh we felt like
knowledge can be shared people can
connect with other people that are you
know very specific to cannabis and you
know leafar at this point I think it's
about
75,000 uh users from around the world
you know primarily a lot in North
America but uh they certainly have uh
users from uh other parts of the world
and so it
encompasses not just people within the
industry like operators but also
investors and it's it's it's been a
great ecosystem and leafire continues to
evolve and add value I think uh they've
got a conference app that they're going
to be rolling out and and you know from
jobs to marketing just all those things
that you see on social media and sites
like LinkedIn so it's been very very
proud of what they've done at Le far as
well yeah now been able to incorporate
at all those multitude of options for
the industry is definitely a great route
to be taken and definitely an
advantageous one I wanted to ask your
opinion on this proposed rescheduling to
schedule three in
America do you really think that this is
going to happen with the Biden
Administration and if so do you think
it's going to be a month or will it wait
till the end of the year when the
elections are on well that's that's the
billion doll question Ian right I think
know we've heard you know the government
and Capitol Hill say a lot of things
over the years and but I think this time
around it is very different uh for a
multitude of reasons one it's an
electioneer right and we're always
seeing a lot more activity coming out of
the White House and Capitol Hill in that
for that
matter Additionally you know the Biden
Administration asked HHS which is Health
and Human Services last year uh to take
a look at cannabis and they recommended
that cannabis be rescheduled to schedule
three
and I think if I if I recall correctly
they made the recommendation to the DEA
now of course it lies with the DEA but
historically I don't think DEA has not
ever taken a recommendation from HHS
right and so there is a lot of optimism
uh because of that and I think from all
indications you know I I hear it's going
to happen in a month I hear it's going
to happen by end of the year I suspect
it's going to be somewhere in between
right I mean no one has the crystal ball
unfortunately Ian but and I think you
know many people in the industry are a
little uh you know tired of hearing like
hey this is going to happen it's going
to happen and it hasn't but um so far
all indications are that it is on track
and it will happen this year you know
when good question I I don't even want
to take a you know guess of that
because and you can feel the palpability
with h especially if you go on to let's
say some the MSO investor platforms or
some of the retail people that you can
tell that they're beaten down over a
number of years of promises and nobody
wants to get their hopes up but
hopefully it's coming around in April
from what we can hear as well yeah and
you know I'm seeing a lot more activity
picking up even not just from investors
but uh companies that have been on the
sidelines and that have been watching
the industry waiting for the right time
and the opportunity right so uh I don't
know if you saw but uh one of the I
think like the 10th largest bank in
America called uh First Citizens they
just announced about 2 3 weeks ago that
they're uh now going to start uh getting
into the Cannabis industry and that's a
$200 billion Bank um you know we've seen
we've had inquiries from all sorts of
different uh you know companies from
alcohol to you name it that are all
kicking the tires and and really start
starting to take the Cannabis industry
more seriously I think more so because
they're seeing that there is a path to
legalization that's starting to happen
and that of course has gotten everyone
very excited and and for us that
simplifier you know some of the biggest
private Equity names you can think of
you know they've we feel we're feeling a
lot of inbounds right now just uh people
wanting to understand where we're going
and where the industry is going because
you know there's a lot of money sitting
in the sidelines trying to waiting to
get in so it should be very
exciting well to finish off I've got a
bit of a for question for you multiple
choice answer H as you're an investor
let's say we give you $50 million and
you've got a choice of Investments
you've got a biotech company that uses
fermentation engineering to be able to
produce the cannaboids as apis applied
pharmaceutical ingredients you've got a
nationwide chain of retail stores that
you could develop out you've got a
cultivation facility with Edibles and
drinks attached to it which of these
three options is getting near $50
million well I think if I had my way I
would probably Place some money in all
three of them that's probably more not
the answer you're looking for and and
here's why because I think all three of
those uh companies are touching on some
really key areas for the industry as it
continues to evolve you know I I've got
an investment uh in a CBD company out of
the UK you know that I did a few years
ago Canary um you know so I've I've
invested in in plant touching to CBD to
tech companies and and I think uh it all
comes down to execution and you know I
think all all these different areas have
to coexist to make the industry Blossom
so uh I wouldn't I'm more of a person
that kind of think Hedges the vets and
and puts it in in multiple areas so
that's how I would do it probably but
you know Smart M that's probably the
best answer because they're definitely
in different sectors going to have
different uh
launch strategies that look like they
could all be successful I know you're a
very busy man and I'm not going to keep
it too much longer I just want to say
thank you very much for your time Marian
it's very much appreciated for those who
want to check out more about leao the
social networking app I highly recommend
going over and signing up to the
platform um for now Marian thank you
very much for your time thank youan
thanks for having me on the show and and
look forward to chatting with you soon
until next episode
[Music]
everybody