[Music]
welcome to another episode of the
cannabis review i am delighted to be
joined in this episode by
nessa horgan who is the green party td
how are you keeping nessa you well i'm
well thank you for having me
i'm very delighted to have you on the
show you're the first
person from the government that we've
had an opportunity to speak and put a
few questions to yourself well thank you
very much for taking your time i know
you're very busy
in your day so first person from the
government i'm worried now
yeah yeah now as i said this is a
business show this is nothing more than
basically trying to provide some
information and education to any of the
viewers who are
looking young entrepreneurs or people
looking to pivot into this industry
would
which will be an exciting new sector
regardless of
the political party in charge it i think
it's it's an if not when now
uh or when not if it's basically the
first thing i wanted to talk to you
about
i'm going to keep you in and out in
within the time slot it's
basically the laws that the that ireland
have
are not in tandem with the eu are you
aware of the european ruling that
happened
in relation to the regulation of toc
quantities in
hemp i am and i think you know
increasingly what we're seeing
is other jurisdictions and countries
moving beyond
um ireland's understanding of the
cannabis issue and the hemp issue and
thc and cbd there's a real recognition
of
not just the medicinal qualities of
cannabis but the the therapeutic
qualities of us um and therefore i think
you know whereas we we do need to
probably reform
um do we from my point of view we
definitely need to reform domestically
i do think that there's a serious
question now around um
bringing ourselves into line with the
the european
norm because we do live within you know
a community
of of um nations and it only makes sense
that for trade and for business
um we have some similar
standards and we see that in food we see
that in medicines
and and i think that that you know we
need to make sure that we align very
well in this area too
perfect and who do you who do you think
is the person that
is responsible for enacting that is
there a series of um
people working in the background working
out there's a specific party who
is there something that can happen to be
able to enact that further and to stop
some of let's say the
the clamp downs that have happened on
some of the stores like blooms and
little collins which have kind of been
completely unnecessary and seems to be a
waste of taxpayer money just because
there hasn't been a catch up within the
european ruling is there a specific
person yeah
i i i think when we saw those kind of
incidents
it just shows you know how lacking in
clarity our own
domestic policies are and how
you know like the guardian will will
take their instruction from legislation
and when when there's a lack of clarity
there
you know they'll revert to the status
quo and so i i think those very
unfortunate incidents and i'm sure
incredibly difficult for the people
involved um really showed that
you know the the the the eu community in
which we live
has moved beyond what our domestic law
is capable of dealing with
um and i think there are it it it
straddles a number of departments
so um you know that that would be
something i think for
for the enterprise department to
consider really um
and you know certainly if you're talking
about uh the the eu region
that's something that they they should
be concerning themselves with um but
obviously a lot of the regulation would
be happening in the department of health
so it's something that we're going to
need collaboration across a number of
departments to get right
but i do think that it implies a
requirement for greater reform more
generally
yeah i agree and i don't think there's
any blame that needs to be put towards
the guards and this i think they're
following basically laws that
they're being told to enact and they
have no
ability to be able to understand the
difference between what a cbd border
flower looks like compared to a thc
board so
there's there's no well this is it
absolutely and and i would say that
more generally like i'm politicians
aren't the experts
on this because usually what you're
doing is you're trying to get the
experts in the room and the experts are
not just the professional experts or the
business experts
but all the also the people who have the
lived experience of of what the impact
of particular legislation is
um and so uh it's really important to
kind of start listening
to what people's on the ground
experience of this kind of thing is and
certainly the guardian are not expected
to be experts
you know they'll be instructed how to
deal with certain legislation or the
lack thereof
and therefore they're sometimes in a
very difficult position i i have to say
my experience with guardi is that they
are very well aware of um
you know the kind of spectrum of of
usage that's involved here
um and it's just that they don't we
don't necessarily have um the
legislative framework in place to help
them to do their job well in this area
yeah and i think one of the trends
that's going to be happening and grow
bigger and bigger that probably at the
very start now was kind of the crux of
the issue is
the ability for a cbd flower to be sold
you've never seen that on the market
before it's always been kind of
illegal illicit uh high thc content
where
that european ruling allows for a cbd
flower to be sold and said it's that
understanding
from the guards and the retailer that uh
is kind of the little like
hole in that area there one of the next
topics i want to jump onto
is the biggest fears from politicians on
a legal industry
is this it is it basically
lack of education on the topic here or
is it
uh won't somebody please think of the
children type screaming from the roof
is there is there a direct employee
there's such a hindrance against it
there's definitely a bit of that and and
i think that you know
during the government negotiations we
had it was probably one of the most
fraught conversations that we had with
our government partners
because our own policy would be
um to make it a a category four
drug and that we would we would be
promoting
the the creation of cannabis cafes um
and that there would be a legal um
pathway like a fully taxed legal
pathway to to the provision of of
cannabis substances and
um that did elicit reactions that i
would say
are kind of fear-based um and one of the
phrases i heard a lot was that it's a
gateway drug
and i think that my reaction to that is
always it is right now
it is it is a gateway drug now because
it's an illegal drug and you place
people in the realm of of
of criminal behavior and therefore if
you want to access any of these products
you often have have to have an
engagement with criminal actors
and therefore you know it's it's more
likely
that that misuse would escalate when
you're into that world
so we have through a lack of
you know moving with with the times and
moving with the
the the requirement for new legislation
we have
created a situation where um
this product can can be a gateway drug
because it moves people into an area
that they shouldn't be
and it should be something that is legal
and regulated um
so i think that my there is a definite
and genuine concern
for younger people and and i wouldn't um
discount that and i wouldn't underplay
that but my my feeling is that that is
mostly based on
not a direct experience of the issue and
i think that
um and where i know we're going to talk
later about you know the way forward and
everything but
i think it's incredibly important that
we
expose um both the general public
and politicians um to
you know the reality of what this means
for people but the reality of what a
more legal framework
would would provide for people and and
how it might safeguard them
but also the reality of what we do right
now which has placed them in contact
with you know
um gangs and an illegal and criminal um
conduct uh we also make them incredibly
unsafe because the product isn't
regulated and people can be imbibing
anything
so i think it's just more about um
educating them and making that
information available to them
i think it's an argument that you you
know or it's a discussion that
would be really useful and you could win
the argument by
simply placing all of the facts on the
table and having an honest
not fear-based discussion around it yeah
well i couldn't agree with you more i
think the simplest way to try and
explain to some of the politicians that
is
if their teenage child has gone out in
to let's say test something whether it's
alcohol or whatever it is kids are kids
they're all going to get into some sort
of mischief at some stage
at the moment if you're going to get
into cannabis your only market is to go
to a dealer who's also selling
cocaine could also sell them pills could
also sell them a myriad of other drugs
where
the option should be that there's a cafe
that sells cbd flour
that has no thc in it and if there is a
route into this
into smoking cannabis or consuming
cannabis in any way shape or form that
it's
the most temp tepid version you could
possibly get as opposed to
they're sending kids out into scenarios
that's either a gonna harden them or
b send them down the wrong path
well i i agree with you and i think that
um
you know it's there is a real spectrum
of of opinion about this and i think
that um
people's politicians particularly
are overly influenced by
an older more conservative voter because
those are the people that vote
right and that's the reality and there's
there's also there's always a framing
on all political action like that i i am
worried
that even as we kind of start to make
more progress on kind of the medicinal
side of things and we see
we start to see reform there that all of
the larger three parties are
really still at the stage of maybe
considering decriminalization
now to me decriminalization is is in
some ways the worst of all worlds
because
it's still an unregulated drug and um
and and that doesn't really protect that
young person
and and you know that's really my my
my uh concern here is that like i would
be coming from the the place where
look on balance and i'm not
under i'm not undercutting or saying
that there is no negative
um aspects to cannabis use i i of course
completely agree that
and and i and i take those very
seriously but on balance
i would prefer to trust people and help
them to make decisions in a safe way
than have a draconian criminal
legislation around the issue and put
all of the actual decision-making in the
hands of criminal gangs
yeah no i couldn't agree with you more
on that one we're going to move on to
the last topic now before i do i just
want to get clarity on
we basically talk to pretty much most of
the departments it's the minister for
health
who's responsible for any legislation
that would move forward or we're all
correct so everybody can agree
on that that is the person who does make
the decision
it's not the justice department it's not
the guards it's
the realm within the department of
health to to make this uh reform
discussion
yes that that's my understanding of it
and
because it would be um
a regulated drug um it would be it would
be in that
public health and well-being um area and
that's why
um you know i've been talking to um
minister frank feen
around pushing forward the the drugs
citizens assembly which i know we're
going to talk about now but
that he would be in the minis in the in
for health so
although i have to say um as we move
through
there absolutely would be issues around
like well how would we regulate it then
and that would be an issue for justice
and then how taxes that's a really
important part of us because
obviously we we don't want to tax it out
of existence so then it still remains in
in
uh in the waste in the way cigarettes
have become so expensive and now there's
a whole kind of criminal enterprise
around cheap cigarettes
we don't want to we maybe there's a
sliding scale of taxation around the
content
we sent in a good uh a good taxation
system to the chairman of the revenue
and got a reply from the office so again
i think you're right
it's the different departments need to
come together but somebody needs to put
on
their leadership hat and realize that
this population that's getting old
are all used to this it's not as if
they're that older population
the the 40 and 50 year olds now have
lived to nightclubs
they've lived through socializing it's
not as if it's a different mentality
mindset and they're going to want to
have a comfortable later on in life
and this is one of the products that
will be available to somebody who's 50
or 60 with arthritis
or a number of other different ailments
so i'm conscious at a time now i want to
get you out on the last topic so the way
forward
is it a citizens assembly or what do you
suggest is the best way forward for the
industry to get legalized in ireland
well as as i said we in the greens have
have for a long time been supportive of
of um
kind of reform in this area and our
policy is for
cannabis cafes and for a fully regulated
provision
uh like a pathway to supply um and
uh that you could have you know your own
personal plans and
so i i think it was very important to us
to get something into the program for
government
around this uh now we're dealing with
two parties who
really don't share our views at all and
it was a very heated
discussion and what we got in the end
was the citizens assembly now
i suppose my view on this is that
uh there genuinely is very strong
opinions on both sides
on this and some people want to see it
completely criminalized and absolutely
nothing
um and won't accept that the kind of war
on drugs meant
you know um strategy has kind of failed
and on the other hand you have people
who want
absolutely no regulation they just want
to be able it's a natural thing
let's just everybody do what they want
with it and i mean in a world where
we're starting to tax sugar because we
know it's bad i don't think that that's
reasonable either
so um i i think the best thing to do is
to get everybody in a room and then
nobody has to have the answer going into
the room but we'll come out with the
answer
afterwards and that's what a citizens
assembly does and where
there is a social issue where there's a
real and genuine
and i and i have to say even even those
who i strongly disagree with on the full
criminalization
side of things their concerns are
genuine and and need to be heard and
need to be taken seriously
where there's a genuine fear around it
and i would liken this to repeal
getting people in that room and allowing
them to
to consider all of the science and all
of the lived experience
and and come to some you know serious
conclusions around that i think that
that's
the best way forward none of the three
larger parties
finale final fall shinton support
legalization
fully and therefore there is no um
legislative route
with the larger parties to get there yet
and if we can get us in this assembly
that's based on
you know hearing testimony and and based
on those 100 people
taking the time to do it properly i
think that is a way to find that middle
ground
that works for people and i have to say
you know the irish public generally are
a little bit further along than
politicians on
on a lot of social issues i think
they're further along on this and i
think they're very mindful
that you know there's increasingly
strong
substances available out there that have
you know kind of
cannabis that's been sprayed with all
sorts of things um
you know high levels of we don't know
what and spray it onto stuff
i i think there's a real acceptance now
that we need to move ahead
i would like to see legalization um but
i don't need
i think the great thing about the
citizens assembly is i don't need to
have all of those answers
um all we need to do is create a
situation where those 100 people
can come up with some right answers that
work for for the irish context and for
irish society
yeah i couldn't agree with you more
about size that a coin need to be heard
equally and that the facts should be
able to win the argument out so
if we can ever help in reaching out and
finding people i think
the top five stories from either
argument for and against
and have five real life stories for and
against and see which ones are the most
compelling and offer the best
argument for legalization i want to
thank you very much for your time i know
you're a busy lady
i'd be remiss if i didn't say to you
would you ask stephen donnelly to talk
to vera
it's trending on twitter again the lady
is being gone months spending money that
she shouldn't have to spend on a kid
just to keep it safe when it's basically
just a simple little election of allah
over here
that could save this woman a lot of
hassle and make her life a lot easier so
get him to talk to vera i will i will i
will talk to him about that
thank you very much it's been an
absolute pleasure talking to you you're
very good for coming on the show
and you've given some great answers for
everybody to have a think about so if we
can help you in any way shape or form
when anything moving forward just reach
out to us
and you have a great day okay thank you
very much
cheers have a good day everybody