foreign
on this episode by Barry pogson who's
Global cannabis mergers and Acquisitions
consultant at Hyde advisory and
Investments and they're based in Ontario
in Canada and our trust advisors to the
global callistry industry are well known
throughout the industry how are you keep
it today party
very well thanks how are you how about
yourself
I'm fantastic Mike thank you very much
for taking the time to join us on the
show
um I've been looking forward to talking
to you now man with wealth of knowledge
and information in this industry you've
been in it for a number of years now can
you maybe give everybody a quick little
overview of how you got involved in
Canada and how you ended up at holiday
advisory Investments
sure yeah so it's it's a bit of a long
story and it comes from uh a personal
background my uh my daughter was my
reason for for entering the Cannabis
space uh she was she was born nearly 10
years ago with a condition called
Gervais syndrome
um the same as Charlotte figgy head of
Colorado
um and uh you know much like their
family we were scrambling for answers
and uh unfortunately this was kind of
just around the time uh 2012 2013 where
um the CBD industry was starting to take
shape
um we we didn't have any access to it
here in Canada we did actually a little
bit of media at the time on on Kate's
behalf but we ended up moving to
Colorado
um got Kate started on CBD and um and
kind of uh was there at the uh you know
uh Ground Zero when things uh started
picking up in Colorado ended up working
with a larger the largest uh CBD company
um at the time
um spent the last uh nine or ten years
with them in various positions
um ended up uh in the last few years
doing m a work on the Canadian side
trying to get them into Canada
um you know it as happens often in the
Cannabis space uh you know a strategy
shift uh you know regulations change
um Canada no longer became uh kind of
part of their uh long-term plan so I
looked for
um you know opportunities elsewhere and
uh David Hyde who's a big name in the
Canadian cannabis space who I'd worked
with previously I reached out to him and
he was uh pivoting himself from more of
the Securities and and Regulatory
Consulting side into the m a space and
he had room on his team for me I've been
uh with height advisory since
um pretty much the start of the year and
uh yeah we we specialize in m a work in
Canada and on the global side and um
yeah it's it's uh it's been an amazing
opportunity it's never it's never boring
and uh yeah especially on the global
side it's um
you know always exciting uh looking into
new countries with regulations changing
Industries coming online
um and uh you know working with people
that are looking for either investment
or partners and and people that are
looking to acquire or put a stake into
an up-and-coming company
yeah holiday advice you've got a great
reputation around the world for sure in
the industry and first thing I wanted to
jump on to you and talk about was
Cannabis merger Acquisitions now I've
got a couple of questions that I want to
fly through on this topic but first and
foremost do you see cannabis mergers and
Acquisitions only really start to take
place when the US federally legalized
cannabis because you have an opportunity
then for maybe the the core brand to
come to the for True mergers and
Acquisitions of small medium-sized
competitors or do you see Canada more
looking towards Europe and looking
towards M A's in Germany and Portugal
and some of the the entities that are
already set up over here
yeah well I think it's a lot about
people hedging their bets
um on on the U.S side it's you know
there's no real
um
you know transparent future where uh
it's about to come online you know it
could be next year it could be five
years it could be ten years
um whereas in the EU and the rest of the
globe there's there's real legislation
happening and real you know real
progress being made you know we know
Germany is is bringing their wreck
Market in we know southeast Asia is
starting to come on board we know
Australia is getting serious in South
America so
um until you know we see some kind of
movement in the U.S it's really just uh
still very much a pipe dream
um so in the meantime you know uh
especially Canadian companies they're
forced to look
um to the EU and to the rest of the
world
um it's not to say that Canadian
companies aren't dipping a toe into the
U.S market but it's on is still very
much on a state-by-state basis you know
nobody's looking for a nationwide uh
strategy in the U.S because we just
don't know what it's going to look like
yeah because it seems kind of nervous we
have the leg up I think on everybody
with the access to Capital I think a lot
of the the brands let's say in the
states even the likes of cookies and
some of the larger operators access to
Capital wouldn't be as free-flowing in
Canada as I'm am I writing saying that
or are these U.S companies able to
access Capital outside their territory
um it's it's
twofold really yeah
regulatory wise in Canada is very easy
to access Capital
um but they kind of Crash and Burn of
the uh the pub codes in Canada have
really left a bad taste in Canadian
investors mouths so while it's
free-flowing capital in Canada
um you know there's not as much appetite
here anymore whereas in the U.S you're
right there's regulatory hurdles
um but a lot of U.S investors are
chomping at the bit for ways to invest
in in you know new cannabis Ventures
um you know so so it is it is out there
it's just it's uh you know there's
roadblocks in their way so there's
they're they're very different animals
Canada and the US in terms of access to
Capital
very interesting and tell me this if
you're let's say a piece of advice for a
cannabis company that's growing what is
the right time to merge and what is the
right time to acquire is there a
attempted or a specific Golden Rule that
you generally tend to companies to look
for or is it on a case-by-case basis
um I mean certainly there's a
case-by-case element to it
um but uh you know and if I was thinking
on general terms in a global m a
opportunity
um if I'm somebody that's looking to be
acquired I find there's um there's a bit
of a uh you know a bit of a wave so to
speak in your in your uh in your life in
in your
in your lifespan um there's the early
startup phase where you know you're
raising capital or you have lack thereof
and you really just have you know these
big wonderful plans to build a facility
you you know you have some of the right
people in place and you know the the
groundwork for uh the licensing and a
decent relationship with the government
you know you're
um you know you're stuck between a rock
and a hard place in terms of your
financing maybe that's the opportunity
to bring somebody in uh that has some
experience that has some capital and
you're going to give away a bit more of
your company to to you know make it to
the next level but if you're able to
navigate that hurdle
um and you know get an operational
Facility have some historical Revenue
um really be at the top of your of your
game and have something that's
attractive uh you know a good example of
that right now is uh you know a facility
in the EU that can do post-harvest
processing and it's GMP certified you
know that's not easy to find it's very
attractive a lot of people want it and
and now is the perfect time to to look
to be acquired um you know a company
like Materia uh did just that
um and then there's the later stage and
you're seeing that a lot in Canada where
you know you've you've laid the
foundation you've built something
beautiful it's been operational
um but you know for whatever reason your
business model is not working the
margins aren't there or the regulatory
burden is too great and you can't make a
run of it and now you know your sales
are declining your your lease uh payment
is up for Renewal and and you have to
make an exit or else you're just gonna
have to you know put the for sale sign
up and sell it as a property and just
abandon the business so
um there's kind of three different
stages and certainly the very Middle
where you're you know your revenue is on
point and uh you have something that a
lot of people want that would be you
know the the Goldilocks time to to make
a move
interesting yeah talking about victory
of interesting to their project to put
pretty prayer over the last number of
years so do you do you see that
basically these post-harvest processing
facilities are more uh more in in
let's say in in point where everybody
compared to let's say the cultivation
facilities it's the post-harvesting
processing you think is where the demand
for Europe is going to be because the
ability to ship in low-car's products
around the world or do you think the the
shipping costs and the ability to ship
and keep a turbine and cannabinoid
profile exact over the course of let's
say two weeks shipping over the boat
over the sea is that the way to go or do
you think the cultivation in Europe is
going to end up start peeking up
um I think in the long term it will
certainly yes
um where where people are cultivating
um you know in the in the domestic
Market they're serving but you know
right now
um there's a lot of people interested in
uh you know growing cannabis uh in very
low-cost environments like South America
and Africa and shipping it to the EU
doing your post harvesting there you
know the shipping costs on top of the
low cost of production uh are still far
below what it would cost to you know
cultivate an EU GMP facility uh
somewhere in the EU so
um in the short term I think it's still
very much uh part of a lot of companies
business model but the longevity of it
yeah it's it's probably not there
um you know uh many governments are
probably going to start catching on to
this little uh you know Green wash
technique and and putting in some
regulations to block that
yeah okay next topic I wanted to jump on
to which one pretty much every
entrepreneur in the Cannabis industry
would like to get an answer to and it's
access to Capital but I'm not going to
bore you with trying to tell me where
you get access to Capital I want to give
you five different potential businesses
that were they were to come in in front
of you which one of these five would be
most uh likely to obtain funding right
so option one is a biotechnology company
biosynthesizing cannabinoids requires
double deck a million shall we say
second option would be somebody who's
got a cultivation operation they've got
their own genetics that they want to IP
the other option then is somebody who
wants to open up a chain of dispensers
start with CBD obviously in Ireland and
moving towards THC and then the other
one would be a laboratory that does the
testing facilities and those uh
governmental contracts which are those
four businesses do you think is right
that's that that's the one that I I put
my money onto or would you like to split
money across all four of them if the
phone came in from you
um yeah that's a very good question I
would also be curious you know what the
where these markets are I think that
would play into it a little bit but if
um if we wanted your we call it Europe
because the audience would be European
and we're an Irish media Enterprise
let's think of Europe in general
sure yeah
um
man I I think if it was me I would split
it between the biotech and the and the
lab testing
um you know that's not something that
everybody can do and out of Biotech
you're gonna get you know quite a bit of
Ip and and you know stuff that's not
easily duplicated
um yeah retail chains are a tough game
it's an easy answer in Canada I would
stay well away from a retail chain or
cultivation even with their own
proprietary strings to be honest but
um yeah you know I think the future is
biotech so if I'm investing for the long
term that's where you know I probably
put 80 into biotech and 20 for lab
testing lab testing the future is a
little bit
um you know I think it's a very
um important element to the Cannabis
industry
um but you're very dependent on
government regulations
um so you could be the most important uh
part of the value chain uh depending on
what the government requires of
cultivars cultivators or you could be
just one of a hundred of you know it's a
very simple uh COA that you're producing
with THC CBD and you know pesticides and
uh microbials
um so it uh it depends you know in the
UK uh lab testing is looking like it's
going to be very important for CBD with
with novel Foods in whichever direction
they go there
um so yeah I would hedge my bets and
have some form of split between the
first and the and the last option
interesting before I let you go quick
when you mentioned the UK there as
somebody who owns another business who
deals with the UK post brexit I'm fully
too aware of the looking nightmare that
involves dealing your business from the
UK to the EU now do investors in North
America see this do they realize the
extra added tax that gets involved in
the exchange between the European Union
and then the UK now or does it matter to
them they just see the UK as being a
market on its own to be able to set up
its a standalone entity in the UK
Standalone in Europe
yeah I think the I think the educated
North American company appreciates that
um their their very separate markets and
it would be beneficial to have if you
are a truly a global player to have
um an asset in the UK and a second asset
in the EU
um but um you know I I know of a few
companies that UK is there the UK is
their their end goal they don't need to
go beyond that they're happy to just set
their put their flag in the UK and and
try and make that market work
um but uh you know the intrinsics of uh
of uh transport between the UK and the
EU no I I wouldn't say your typical
North American company would understand
everything that's involved there and and
a big part not to digress too much but a
big part of a global m a play from a
North American company is to have uh not
just the asset but a team that's already
in place that either is going to do a
nice long transition so they can learn
as much as they can from them before
they leave or somebody that they can
retain that has that knowledge about the
markets that they're in
yeah we see Ireland being the footstone
into Europe for a lot of the North
American companies with an art Creator
Holly skilled Workforce and only
English-speaking entity in Europe at the
moment I think Ireland is going to play
a pivotal role over the course of the
next 10 years time and uh we'll be
championing Ireland from the Canada's
view over the next few years but thank
you very much for taking your time Barry
it's very much appreciated good talk to
you all day about access to Capital
emergers and Acquisitions but uh
hopefully maybe we can switch bases and
start it next year and have an update to
see where everybody's play is at when it
comes to Europe
absolutely it was a pleasure thanks for
having me
thanks everybody for watching see you in
the next episode
[Music]