[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined by a financial powerhouse in the
industry rob seacrest who's the
co-founder and president of polaris
equity group how are you keeping today
rob
i'm doing well thanks for having me on
thank you very much for joining us i
know you're very busy man so we'll keep
this as brief as we possibly can i just
want to give the audience an overview on
what's happening in the cannabis lending
space at the moment and can you maybe
give it everybody an overview of at the
polaris fund that you've set up to deal
with specifically with the cannabis
industry sure so poor's equity group was
the first us-based domestic lender in
the country um we
entered the space in about 2016
and since that time we've done about 69
deals for about 430 million
and we're taking that lending platform
and we're starting our initial
due diligence to look at the european
market um in other markets to bring that
same lending platform to provide gut to
cannabis use property owners across
across the country and
basically now in in europe and some
other countries as well
okay incredible so basically bringing a
state of finance to the european
industry as well can you maybe i was
reading about your java's 11.8 billion
round of funding that you recently did
what are the metrics you look for in a
good uh investment opportunity what are
the top two things that you at the
pollures fund would look for
great so regardless of what country that
we're landing in we're always going to
look for
a very experienced cannabis operator
who may or may not be the owner of the
building typically they are what we call
a owner user
the next most important thing is we want
a strong sponsor
to support that transaction
most of the transactions that we do
are uh value-add meaning that we are
providing the capital to acquire and
build the facility as a bridge loan and
then from there they're going to
refinance that loan with a lower cost
lender once it's fully built and in that
model we need an extremely strong
sponsor that has the personal balance
sheet uh income and credit to support
the size of the loan that they're
borrowing so
if it's somebody that's trying to borrow
you know like that 11.8 million dollar
transaction we need to have somebody
that can support that whether it's an
individual or a corporate guarantee um
to do that transaction so the other
thing is is that we require a commercial
piece of real estate meaning that we'll
do commercial buildings and or
greenhouses but no agricultural deals so
sometimes there is land tied up with the
commercial buildings but we're giving
our value to the buildings not to the
land
okay amazing and you guys have seen i
see you're at the icbc in berlin next
week um are you seeing germany as the
kind of first step into europe for you
guys or have you been in discussions in
malta or denmark or other territories in
this side of the world
it's
so preliminary right now and we just
returned from the icbc in london a
couple of weeks ago
and what we're trying to get comfortable
with is how does any of the european
market work
if you can import from other countries
that don't have to go through the the
same ultra high
building compliance and employee
expenses and electric expenses and all
the other expenses that are
so high in these in the european union
let's just say and you can have
countries that are able to import
we're trying to get our arms wrapped
around how this is going to work for
those uh for these countries if they're
going to
build their own facilities within their
own country or within the european union
so this is the first thing that we're
trying to really get our arms wrapped
around to make us feel comfortable if
we're going to do any lending in
the european union or in europe if you
could import at a lower cost
yeah what i think what will happen over
in europe you're obviously going to have
the low cost import options that are
going to be available but we're renowned
for farming over here and i see genetics
and different strains being created in
each different country over here that's
going to be unique to this part of the
world that'll almost be like wine to a
degree that especially special farmers
are going to be able to create specific
genetics that make their industry that
little bit better and i think we're just
a couple of years away from that you see
germany obviously at the moment it's now
a raise to who can get the cheapest
flower in like it kind of does in in a
lot of the industries but i think you're
going to start to see once the the
agriculture and farming grounds or
bodies allow this you'll start to see a
huge amount of talent flow into this
industry then
yeah we're anxious to see that um i had
the same
type i had the same
thought process as you
comparing california markets which has
the brand name and the the strains um
and for the rest of the country and
thinking that those those other states
across the country um would not be able
to compete with strains and things like
that
and i've had to evolve that that
thinking process after i've uh toured
many facilities that are in emerging
states that now already have
uh the caliber and quality of high
high end product that would compete
easily head to head with california and
so
we have to understand is this going to
happen here in uh the you know the
european union and so we have to think
about okay how long does it take to
start the importation process
when you're importing into germany or
wherever it might be from the day that
paperwork is submitted until that
product lands um in the european union
is that product going to be able to
compete directly with something that is
uh grown domestically within the
european union so these are the things
i'm i'm trying to to learn myself about
while we'll be uh well we'll be there
and we'll be touring some facilities and
looking at what's happening there and
trying to understand the pros and cons
of what might happen and when the
legislation is still not decided it's
it's difficult to start making big uh
you know making bets and and trying to
see how it's going to go
um in the united states uh nothing has
really happened for quite some time
since since our the most consequential
legislation passed there which was the
roebuck or blumen hour amendment that
defunded our department of justice for
prosecution and the hemp act which
doesn't really apply exactly to what
we're doing
yeah now i think you said at the start
of the show as well operators are one of
the things that you look for in an
investment i think that's going to be
the case over here realistically
california's got amazing flower due to
climate colombia and some of the south
american territories and portugal to a
degree can compete with that but
if you understand hvac systems
environmental control systems you really
just need an amazing operator and uh i
think you're going to be able to compete
because realistically when you're when
you're comparing 24 percent thc to 26
thc the consumer doesn't really know
that they understand that the flavonoids
and the terpenes and the flavors and
smells that they're going to get out of
the plant and what it's going to look
like compared to the strength i think
yeah um we agree um it it's a it's a
process for the consumers um typically
as new markets emerge they're willing to
take uh inferior products because
they're available um and what's
interesting about that is that typically
the illegal products are superior in
quality so eventually hopefully those uh
those legal
products will get to the same quality
that the uh domestic consumers are going
to appreciate and look for those premium
high-end brands that make sense to grow
them domestically yeah another market
i'm looking forward to seeing as new
york come on board in september now
some of the genetics that the hipsters
in brooklyn are going to be producing i
think is going to be pretty amazing
yeah um you know each of these genetics
are um it's one thing to have one that's
an amazing brand but you have to have it
to be a consistent genetic that can
continually reproduce and and that's
there's more to it than just having a
one-off product that you can say look at
this this this amazing strain if you to
produce that consistently
is a a challenge that every brand is
going goes through to to to make chairs
that they have a consistent quality of
product at all times
yeah that's why you see denmark are
probably the leaders in europe at the
moment when it comes to cannabis flare
just from their ornamental flower
industry and the fact that they have
government back in in finance as well
i'm gonna just jump on to the next topic
uh before i let you go and it's how to
value a cannabis company now everybody's
kind of seen the canadian nightmare
that's happened over the past six to
seven years with the billions of dollars
that have been wasted
what are the core metrics for evaluating
a cannabis company let's say that's a
year in business is does it have to have
iep is it an ipta rating is it what is
the core metrics for a man of your level
sure so us um unfortunately it's a
case-by-case scenario for every
transaction that we're looking at but
the first part for us is that we're not
valuing
per se the the value of the company um
for the cannabis operator that's not our
job because we're not utilizing
the cannabis company or the enterprise
value of the cannabis company
as our lending basis we're purely
evaluating the cannabis operator on
their level of experience and typically
that might shake out in their
performance of how they've done thus far
but
not always necessarily we want to see
that that cannabis operator has the
experience and capability to to they
don't they're not trying to learn how to
cultivate already they've already
figured that part out and so for us when
we're looking at a facility we're
looking at we establish our lending
basis off of the value of the facility
the tenant improvements and the
equipment that are going into that
facility so for us it's a lot more
easy to extrapolate what the value is
because we're only lending off with the
real estate basis and not off the
enterprise value of the company
okay so pretty much anybody in the
manufacturing edibles can fit into this
category because the equipment and the
the property they're going to have is
going to be
of value same way as pre-roll machines
and facilities so you kind of fit into
every facility or facet of the industry
yeah most of the time people are going
to come to us for larger builds is
what's happened in the our domestic
program
um and uh you know being that cannabis
is going to be is legal in each of these
states federally the banks will be able
to lend there and so when you have a
smaller facility that's that's
extraction or something like that
the bet you might be able to get a
traditional loan on that um we'll have
to see how that plays out too but
typically the banks are not going to
value these properties the same way you
would a commercial typical commercial
facility and so that's usually where we
become a lending advantage we understand
the cannabis market we understand how to
build these we understand how to process
the draws we've got all that
infrastructure in place and we've
competed in the in the us against banks
for 30 years and it's it's there's no
way they can compete with us on a uh
value add or construction type loan once
that facility is fully stabilized
meaning that it's cash flowing on its
own then you can start looking to uh
traditional banks to refinance that debt
okay amazing it's a wealth of
information i know you're a very busy
man so i won't take up too much more
time i look forward to seeing you at
icbc in berlin
and thank you very much for taking your
time today rob you bet thank you bye
until next time episode