foreign
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I am delighted to
join of this episode by Anna Schwab
who's the VP of orendy at 420 Organics
and also known as Dr Anubis how are you
keeping today Anna
I am absolutely fantastic even the
better for talking to you and do you
maybe want to give everybody a quick
little 60 second overview of
420 Organics and your area of expertise
uh so I have a PhD
in my research was looking at uh
genetics and phenotypic diversity in
cannabis and when after I graduated I
worked for Mile High labs for a short
time but then
um I got hired by 420 Organics here in
New Jersey a couple of years ago I've
been here for exactly two years now
um and we cultivate cannabis so both
hemp and marijuana using aquaponic
methods which is using fish to
feed the plants and the plants clean the
water for the fish and it kind of all
goes in this closed loop system and it's
a very elegant and
um green method of farming
okay incredible so is one of the first
questions I was going to actually
display in is aquaponics is the nutrient
value and the sustainability model of
this far superior than the current
method
it can be it depends so there's a couple
of different ways of doing it um if it's
done right it definitely can
um uh be comparable or Superior to other
modern methods but it is also very uh
finicky and delicate because we have bio
filters like we have the fish and we
have a bacteria culture and we have some
other things going on anything that goes
wrong in the system can just basically
wink it and everything goes wrong so
it's really
um it's it's uh nuanced and it can be
difficult because you can't just like if
the plants need something you can't just
add a bunch of nutrients into the water
because that'll hurt the fish and do
other things so it's um very nuanced
yeah it seems to be the more complicated
a process the better it can end up being
but like comparing an orchestra to a
guitar a solo there's a head a lot more
that can go wrong with an orchestra if
one person ends up going off just one
individual thing can we touch on
cannabis biology initially to first to
uh start what is biology
the study of life the study of life so
for cannabis biology it's the studio of
the life of all the various genetic
types of living plants
uh well if you're talking specifically
cannabis biology you're talking about
the life of the cannabis plant so
everything from you know seed to
consumption if you're talking about uh
consumable cannabis or you know to to
products if you're talking about
Industrial Hemp
okay so basically it allows us to
decipher the laws of cannabis and to be
able to enhance in any way shape or form
what is the the best is the is the
Emerald Triangle in America the best
place for naturally occurring cannabis
uh many would argue it is in terms of
outdoor cultivation because of
um the specific like makeup of the soil
there the sunlight the elevation it all
just seems to be a perfect
storm for cannabis cultivation not
unlike you know there's certain regions
of France that are really well known for
great cultivation
um so yeah the Emerald Triangle is
really where cannabis seems to do really
well in the United States
in regards to the latest paper that
you've put out about THC testing levels
do you want to make give everybody a
little overview of that paper and the
findings that you had from it yeah super
excited this paper was the last um sort
of publishable item from my PhD
dissertation and I just kind of stumbled
across it while I was doing another
study and we mentioned this in the paper
we were looking at uh genetic variation
and can people detect differences in the
Aromas of cannabis if there's a genetic
you know outlier for a certain strain
the answer is yes they can uh but when I
purchased those samples I noticed and
then I did the cannabinoid analysis on
those samples I noticed that the THC
levels seem to be much lower that we
tested than were on the labels like I
didn't remember buying anything that was
advertised as 12 and so I went back and
checked all the packaging and I was like
yeah these are really different numbers
so we expanded the study we did some
more shopping and found pretty much
across the board that the numbers on the
package don't match what's inside the
package
um and they're substantially different
like
um about 23 to 35 percent different
which is a big number like it's the you
know if you were to
have a beer and it says you know six
percent on the label but there was
really 12 in the bottle like that's a
big difference in alcohol and the same
sort of thing with you know that the
advertising on on cannabis it's quite a
bit different although it's lower not
higher and is it comparing basically the
lab testing art cultivation facility
compared to post uh let's say processing
where it's gone through a number of
machinery and you might have lost some
of the trichomes or is it different uh
the water moisture doesn't matter the
from the start when we tested I mean we
tested the same way that
before they put product on the Shelf
they test the finished product dried
um and all that and we tested the exact
same methods the exact same way that you
would that a Testing Lab would test
um using the same methods dried it out
completely like like a testing facility
would do I mean there was no difference
in the testing methods from testing labs
is this a case now where we already
discussed with the previous guests have
we got a number of labs that are
basically their client is the person
who's getting the results of them so it
would make sense for them to make their
client happy and alter the THC content
there's multiple
points where where people benefit from
having higher results so and it all
comes from
pricing is basically test it's basically
set on THC content and so yes the
cultivator has an incentive to get back
higher prices because then they can get
a better price when they sell it and the
labs are sort of incentivized because if
they come back with lower numbers
they're going to lose customers because
the customer wants the higher value
right
um and the cultivator you know in in in
Colorado I mean every state has their
their testing procedures that you're
supposed to follow but if you're the
cultivator and you're collecting the
samples to take into the lab you could
potentially be picking and choosing
which uh flowers you take in to get
tested so in that case the lab wouldn't
be doing anything wrong it could be the
cultivator it's taking in you know the
premium flower for testing or if they're
being genuine and taking in a
representative sample you know it could
be the lab that is incentivized to to
increase those numbers and it you know
ultimately it doesn't matter whose fault
it is
um the thing that matters is that the
thing on the outside of the box doesn't
match the inside of the box and so the
consumers need to be aware of that and
also probably should stop purchasing
cannabis based on the THC number because
that's not a really good way to buy
cannabis
yeah I think anybody who's boxing
consumes cannabis now at this stage
doesn't really pay too much attention to
it I think the terpenes and the
flavonoids are getting more attention
than a number on the side of the uh the
packaging well then we have to remember
that not everybody is at the same place
in their cannabis you know Journey so
there are still people who are just
starting out just trying it and those
people don't realize that THC is not a
good way to judge quality whereas you
know more seasoned consumers of course
they know that THC doesn't mean anything
but we have to remember not everybody's
not everybody's the same not everybody
knows the same stuff
next topic I wanted to talk about an
area you're an expert in is genetic and
phenotypic variations can you explain
what a genetic variation is and what a
phenotypic variation is for there for
anybody who doesn't understand either
so your genetic so your your phenotype
with your observable characteristics so
what you look like and so in the case of
cannabis that would be growth morphology
cannabinoids terpenes uh big uh fluffy
Buds versus dense no
um compact buds anything that you can
observe either but visually or or
through your senses is considered your
phenotype and your phenotype is dictated
by your genotype your genetic makeup so
your DNA your genes what you inherited
from your mom and your dad as well as
the environment so we don't really know
the impact how much of the how much the
environment impacts cannabis
uh that has yet to be determined but
from my research I found that it
environment has quite a bit of impact on
the final product so if a grower has
different methods uses different
watering and nutrient regimes
um you know indoor versus outdoor
um cultivating the flower at different
times so is it completely mature is it a
little bit immature and then also what
happens after cultivation so the drying
hearing time to sail all of those things
are going to alter what you what you
ultimately consume at the end of the
road
okay incredible very interesting in
terms of the the future of cultivation
that you see in New Jersey obviously we
know that in the last year so you guys
came online what is it year and a half
that New Jersey became uh yeah it was it
well it was last year on four I think it
was 21 they sort of I
uh
they didn't and I don't know if that was
like what they didn't want to open on
420 but yes it's been a year since uh
adult use cannabis as a you know in
addition to Medical has come online
however the process of getting people
licensed has been relatively slow and at
the moment most of the people who have
licenses to sell uh recreational to
adult use cannabis is limited to The
multi-state Operators who are already
here operating in the medical space
which is not at all what New Jersey set
out to do but it's what has ended up
happening and so there aren't really a
lot of mom and pop shops yet that are up
and running but uh we are one of those
um that is now building out our facility
with our conditional license that we
have
so yeah it's slow yeah it seems to be
the east coast of America seems to be
the kind of the new darling of the
industry at the moment and it's going to
be interesting it's probably going to
take a number of years before the
certain brands and the certain leaders
come to the fore and you've got a the
ability to tell the difference because
it seems to me it's one of the only
indices that anybody's got a bit of
money can just jump out into straight
away and yeah slowly realize that people
like yourself with the area of expertise
that you guys have are what you need to
make these businesses successful so it's
uh it'd be very interesting to see do
you what is your overview of the Eastern
Seaboard of America at the moment there
any companies that you think are yet
these are going to be long term around
or is it dominated by large Capital at
the moment you know I really
and I'm not a business person so I
really don't keep a lot of eyes on the
business end of the whole cannabis
industry like I'm really science focused
and you know uh doing boring things like
writing grants to try and get money and
stuff like that
has anybody ever done a trial playing
music to cannabis as it grows and seeing
the variations that comes out of it
you know I don't know that there's
anything published out there I do know
um of one really talented grower and
he's actually up in Canada but he
consistently has uh music typed into his
um plant rooms and it's always some sort
of um some form of Reggae so you know
like there's some techno reggae and
traditional reggae and he his plants are
phenomenal I can't say that it's his
music that's making the plants grow so
well or his particular method of growing
um but there's no but yeah there are
some studies that suggest that music
helps but if we and I've had I've had
discussions about this if we think about
you know plants don't have ears but they
can potentially
um
sort of gather information about the
world around them when it when a seed is
ready to germinate if there's no nothing
going on if there's no water running if
there's no animals scurrying around if
there's no trees you know rustling
blowing in the wind then it's probably
not a great place to germinate and so
maybe that's not a good place for the
big to put all its effort into growing
if there's nothing around so I feel like
the plants are responding to the
environment to the vibrations and things
like that because it indicates a healthy
environment for the plants to grow
that's my theory interesting I would
imagine that music is vibrations and
vibrations would trigger any sort of uh
uh activity in something that would be
there to sense vibrations but you'll
have to keep your ears to the ground I
mean you can let me know if you hear of
anybody who's doing any such study like
this there wasn't a MythBusters about
the base setup I think it was five
greenhouses
the plants did not
music yeah you'd like heavy metal which
was kind of surprising
um they didn't like nothing so they
didn't like the silent room but the
other kinds of me I think there's
classical they did fine with classical
music they did fine with heavy metal and
like rock and roll was fine too so I do
think it kind of matters like what the
vibrations are but you know
um don't play country and western for
your appointments they don't like it
tell me just a couple of questions
before you go what is your favorite
consumption method food inhalation or
have you got a different one I
um
I prefer
and uh but I'm not I'm not a heavy
consumer and I don't really enjoy a lot
of THC I like to
have more CBD with just a segment of TAC
or other cannabinoids I'm calling
dabbling with a thcv right now
um
which is um it's supposed to be good for
like your metabolism and stuff why not
um and then you know if if I have like I
threw my back out once and I it hurts so
bad that I just I was like I'm gonna
smoke some CBD and it kicked it and it
kicked it in the butt like right away
within a couple of minutes my back felt
fine so it I think it just depends on
you know what I'm
what I'm looking to do with my life at
that point in time do I want to go to
sleep am I looking to you know alleviate
some pain
um so but yeah normally I I I'm a I'm an
eater yeah yeah I know I love a few
Edibles myself is there a favorite place
in America that you like to consume or
is New Jersey your home and that's the
one that you you like the most
well you know I lived in Colorado for
over 30 years and I I Thought I Loved
Colorado but I did live on the plains in
a cow town called Greely you know when
people think of coloradans they think of
mountains and Aspen and you know that's
not where I lived which is really funny
because I moved to New Jersey where
everybody thinks you know New Jersey's
this armpit of America and it's you know
you know a lot of industrial like
concrete smoke smelly
um but I live in a really really
beautiful part of New Jersey I live
Between the Ocean and the forest and
it's just incredible like the wildlife
the diversity here is amazing so I
really am liking New Jersey I have not
been up state to the northern part of
New Jersey which is where I hear the
reputation comes from
um but yeah we love like exploring out
this way it's really pretty
um everything's like an airway New York
City is an hour away Atlantic City is an
hour away Philadelphia is an hour away
so we're in a really nice place yeah
excellent but it's been amazing chatting
Tiana for all those who want to check
out the paper I would highly I recommend
visiting Anna's website and subscribe
and the information is very valuable and
for 420 Organics check out their site as
well some of the top products over the
Eastern Seaboard of America for now Anna
thank you very much for taking the time
to do this it's very much appreciated
thank you so much for having me I love
talking about piano
absolute pleasure hopefully we get to
chat again towards the end of the year
and we'll have some sort of movement
happening in Europe as I'm sure you saw
the German rules of No Doubt there'll be
a a hell of a lot of cultivation the
likes of Scots Miracle growl will be the
biggest cannabis companies in Europe
all right happy days would you have a
great day and thank you very much for
the time Anna thank you
cheers until next time everybody
oh