foreign
by Alexander risk who's the CEO of
pro-hospitality group out in America how
you keeping today Alexander
how you doing sir
thank you very much for taking your time
to do this I know you're a very busy man
do you maybe want to give everybody a
little overview of your background and
how you came to the CEO Pro Hospitality
Group
yes of course um I'll make it as quick
as possible we I'm originally from
Montreal Canada so I'm Canadian
originally but moved to the United
States about 17 years ago uh Phoenix to
be precise Arizona and we and uh I
entered the hotel industry by becoming a
hotel broker so I've been a a real
estate commercial real estate agents but
that focuses only on hotels for the last
17 years and the company called
pro-hospitality group is my company we
have three different divisions we have a
hotel Brokers division that we still
active at selling and brokering hotels
for third-party investors and we also
have our own investment platform where
we own and operate 11 hotels now mostly
in Arizona Nevada and we have our first
International deal that we just bought
as well in haco Costa Rica
and the third division of the company is
a hotel brand it's mostly what
um we've been uh uh talked about for for
the last uh a couple years it's called
elevations hotels and resorts and uh
with the affiliation and membership
called elevations nation and we created
that brand for initially for our first
uh Hotel uh that we have it which is a
boutique uh fun funky Hotel Downtown
Phoenix called the Clarendon Hotel and
that hotel was the first one uh to
become cannabis friendly the first
lifestyle Boutique Hotel to be cannabis
friendly as well so I want the concept
was uh I wouldn't say complete but
um on its way we realized that we needed
more locations and uh the first one that
we tackled was Las Vegas Nevada
um and where we uh we uh we purchased in
March 2022 the yeah the art is in the
hotel at the time was the Artisan Hotel
also a boutique independent Hotel just
off the strip really great location uh
so we purchased this completely renovate
renovated the hotel uh rebranded uh and
reopened it as uh the Lexi Hotel Las
Vegas uh last June so we've only been
open for a couple of months now uh still
a lot of things to
um to fix a little bit of a Kinks to uh
to uh to a line to be fully operational
but we're getting there and uh we uh
we're uh we're happy to bring that
concept to Las Vegas as well
we we hope that we can we can provide
luxury
uh stays and amazing experiences and a
really good time Vegas is a place to go
and not necessarily go meditate but to
have to go and have fun and this is a
place that we are trying to craft those
experiences around that
incredible yeah it's definitely going to
be a huge space in the coming time I
think what's really interesting is
you're going to give everybody a quick
little history yeah on the Lexi in Las
Vegas it seems to have a great history
and a story
longevity so far
well uh it's definitely one of the um uh
landmarks in Las Vegas especially if you
consider anything that's off the strip
so it's very well known with the uh with
the the locals
um at some point and it's history I had
a really Gothic
Medieval theme to it uh it was um it was
full of art everywhere uh seating see
ceiling walls plastered with art and
small mirrors everywhere it was kind of
um uh it was great for Halloween parties
I can tell you that it looked like a
like like you were entering it to a
vampire movie sometimes but uh it was a
great Gathering Place for the locals it
became at some point uh one of the best
aftermarket After parties uh spot
especially for the locals so we're
trying to bring that back actually uh so
we're making sure because it for the
last six seven years that kind of stuff
the previous owners had a concept of
selling the whole hotel they called them
buyouts which kind of put a uh then into
the ability to be able to be open
constantly for for the local business as
well so it's been um so it's been a
little bit challenging uh but
um it was well known for crazy
uh lifestyle parties as well uh for a
while it was a lot of uh swinger club
let's call it what it is uh that rented
the hotel and we're trying to uh bring
that bring back the hotel to where it
used to be before that uh so uh we're
we're we bring our own concept uh there
although we keep it very cheeky and fun
we are one of the only three hotels in
Las Vegas now grandfather and in with a
topless pool part uh license so uh
European bathing sunbathing they call it
uh so we have uh we have this open as
well so we're we keep the the fun cheeky
sexy part of it but we're trying to
bring a little bit more class than what
the property had for the last eight
years
yeah I know a lot of Europe European
people who go to Vegas pretty regularly
and I think at your hotel be a perfect
destination for a lot of these you've
got a pretty successful industry over in
Arizona at the moment this strategy for
the hotel was obviously got tourism on
one side of the teams but the matter of
conferences and and events that happen
in Vegas we've all got MJ Biz Khan and a
number of massive massive events from
November time and around are they a key
part of the hotels plan 100 they're a
key part of the Home Market you can't
survive in in Las Vegas if you're not
playing uh the convention then group
games so we're not opposed to getting
groups we're not opposed to uh catering
to groups uh for their needs the parties
the the the
semibile if you want but
um but we also wanted to become and be
be back into the the the during the
midweek specifically uh for all the
industry people that work into those big
casinos that work into those uh tourist
industry uh we also want to be a a place
where they can come and and uh be one of
their locals favorites and from Thursday
to Sunday obviously this is Leisure and
or conference uh conference people
coming in but from Monday to Wednesday
we uh we want to reopen our doors doors
to the local uh the local uh crowd
yeah I will no doubt it'll be successful
with that crowd on those time of days
when it comes to the consumption on
property it's obviously there's no
purchasing going on in the hotel it's
just consumption friendly
correct so in Phoenix our concept works
really well
um we can legally uh as long as we are a
hotel and as long as we have a private
membership on site we and and and
there's a few
legal Maneuvers that need to happen in
order to suspend our liquor license at
in some areas of the hotel so for
example in Phoenix we have a private
membership Lounge uh the illinoisians
Nations Lounge so our members that are
paying members are allowed to come and
enjoy the hotel for the day all the
amenities of the hotel and they're
allowed to bring their own cannabis and
go into our private members smoking
lounge and enjoy the company of their
friends or or make new friends there and
enjoy the consumption of cannabis now we
also have 105 rooms only 16 of our rooms
in Phoenix are actually campus friendly
which means that if you are a guest of
the hotel and you bring your own
cannabis you're more welcome to smoke in
your room we have restrictions about
using tobacco so we're really pushing
more for anything that's tobacco Less in
terms of uh of cannabis because we can
control the smell and
the smell of cannabis once it's properly
treated it doesn't stick around tobacco
does and it's a big problem for us so we
keep tobacco out but those 16 rooms are
cannabis friendly sometimes they're
sponsors by some of our partners so the
team inside those rooms is really cool
and we have a rooftop bar where we can
suspend the liquor license and have uh
the use of cannabis there too for
specific events in Vegas this is a
little bit different we're working with
the authorities right now to change the
laws or or rewrite certain laws to allow
us to do a similar concept until that's
done uh the only thing that we can
safely do right now is that we converted
our our main fourth floor uh ask him
it's friendly we call them our 420 rooms
they're on the fourth floor they're for
428 to to Z uh but um uh these rooms are
equipped with uh Resto air equipment and
they're all hard hard surfaced they're
designed to be uh easily maintained even
with the use of cannabis
um and uh and you are allowed to consume
it onto the fourth floor and those rooms
will be also sponsored by some of our
partners so right now they're pretty
generic looking uh because they're
they're the same that any other rooms in
the hotel uh with the accession in a
couple Suites but as a sponsors Partners
come in they redesign the room and make
them their own
yeah it seems like a great branding
opportunity as you said if you've got a
lot of the big players at these big
events and walking in and there's a vape
or a cartridge on your pillow from one
of these top brands is a a very good
opportunity for these Brands and is
there a plan to take the Lexi brand
National and possibly International then
when European yeah 100 but the brand
itself is going to be elevations or
doesn't Resort the Lexi itself there's
going to be only one Lexi it's going to
be Lexi Las Vegas all of my hotels for
elevations hotels and Resort will be
soft branded so the Clarendon in Phoenix
by the by elevations hotels and Resort
Lexi Las Vegas by elevations hotels and
Resort and so on we really want to grow
into uh what I call the the the
occupancy Square for our area which is
Vegas Phoenix La Palm Springs and San
Diego most of these markets
feed each other for almost 50 in
occupancy so we our next uh annexa uh uh
Ventures are going to be San Diego La
probably two properties in L.A and Palm
Springs is on our our Target list that
doesn't mean we're not going to grow
bigger than that but that's just the
main focus right now we also have Tulsa
Oklahoma that we have uh intentions to
uh to break into and then up the coast
Colorado Oregon Washington obviously are
going to be an actual fit for us also
yeah and I would imagine New York when
the market matures that a tourism
Central I would say there's going to be
some more details yep yep New York is
part of it
um uh not Miami just yet but uh they're
working on it over there as well to
legalize uh the consumption of cannabis
so we'll see how things go there but uh
for the for the East Coast New York
would probably be the Natural Choice uh
the Carolinas uh are a good spot as well
really hot right now and um
when and if possible Florida is
obviously an easy one for us also well
that ballot is going to measure now soon
if I'm not mistaken
yeah
I was just saying that ballot in Florida
is the recreational voters coming up is
it not in the in the next couple of
months next year I believe it's next
year actually the same year in the uh in
the uh Federal elections 2024. we can
see what kind of Size Market that is
already with some of the hhc and Delta 8
products already been sold over no doubt
tourism hub for somebody IQ and I know
you're very busy Alexander so I'm not
going to take much more of your time for
everybody from Europe who's going to
Vegas to Lexi lasvegas.com website and
Below it'll be in all the various
listening and viewing spots of this
podcast but for now Alexander thank you
very much and I look forward to staying
in Alexi in Las Vegas when I get over
there soon thank you we look forward to
hosting you
until next episode everybody take care