[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
cannabis review i am delighted to be
doing this episode by pete patterson
who's the ceo of alcon medical we're
going to be talking all things danish
cannabis today pete how are you keeping
i'm doing very well thank you how are
you i'm delighted mate great to have you
on the show i've been looking forward to
getting somebody on from denmark to
discuss the overview of there we've been
going through the different countries
throughout europe kind of piecing
together the whole industry so great to
chat with you and can you kind of give
everybody an overview of how you got
into the industry and how you got to ceo
of alcohol medical real quick
sure not a problem at all um so for
myself i've been in the industry since
uh 2012 actually
got started by founding uh one of
canada's first private equity funds um
got that up and going with some capital
deployed some capital
it was still very early days when just
even talking about cannabis when you're
on restaurants or anything like that was
a taboo so
um yeah it was it was challenging but a
lot of fun in the same instance uh went
on to found a company called vitalis
extraction technology
and then uh subsequently uh sold that um
a number of years later um and then
found myself over here in europe um
making a number of investments here and
there and one of them uh is falcon
medical and so that organization was
founded in late 2018
and i've come over from canada just to
add some of that cannabis experience
and just to make sure that everybody on
the team is on the right track which
they are
amazing okay great so
my wealth of experience can you kind of
get everybody the cannabis in denmark at
the moment from what i can see of the
reading i've done so far yet the
four-year plan extended there just
recently in may and so doctors can
prescribe it there's uh patients can
have access to it companies can license
and export it and i've recently found
that there was a danish grown product
for sale in germany pharmacies is this
correct
that's correct yeah
absolutely true
and not available for danish consumers
as of yet is there a rule in regulation
that hinders this or what would be the
case to stop that
yes so you know if we when we start to
take a look at the products that are
available in denmark right now there's
four
there's three flowers that have been
introduced by uh bedrocan and then a
capsule that's introduced by aurora
as it stands right now there are no
other products that have been introduced
into denmark by danish companies um it's
not for lack of trying um and it's not
for lack of the regulatory bodies um
wanting to allow it or accept it just
takes time that's really all it is so
you look at your major cultivators such
as
like say aurora for example or you know
canopy's facility which is now owned by
little green pharma scroll medical
all of these organizations have
a flower within the um say product
approval pipeline
and just going through the the checks
and balances to make sure that it's
going to be
available and acceptable to the danish
government and then therefore to the
danish patients
i'd say just because they have market
authorization in germany um doesn't mean
that they're automatically going to get
it here in denmark the regulations or
the bars are probably
one of the one of the most or the most
stringent that we're going to see in
europe from a quality perspective
okay so again it's the kind of barrier
to entry for the products there it's
just so high and the regulations are so
strict and it was just thinking eugmp
was the the strictest of them all
yes it's not just eugmp like there's
eugmp which is going to set your
guidelines but then however
and these companies are all
cultivating at incredible quality
it's really going through the time that
it takes for the stability testing and
then along side of that making sure that
they're doing all of the microbial
potency testing throughout that time in
period
just to make sure that those products
meet the
yeah the standards that the the danish
medic medical system is going to be
requiring um on top of that
when you're taking a look at flour just
in it's in its rough warm it's a complex
product um and and the microbials um
that can be
i guess housed in this on this product
are probably of the greatest concern to
the um to the danish medicines agency so
they really are they're not taking a
look at accelerated stability or
anything along those lines they're
taking a look at you know what's
happening on a month-to-month basis um
in these true long stability studies
just to make sure that this product is
going to be safe for the um for the end
patient
yeah and i was reading up about uh
professor anna catharina uh over there
working in the danish institute medical
or technological institute doing some
work on tissue cultures and whatnot so
it seems to be the denmark as line and
itself hope to have everything all the
eyes dotted and the t's crossed
to have it this made in denmark we've
talked to the the maltese
guys already but you seem to be going
for a mate in denmark is going to be the
seal of approval you reckon from the
products coming out there as well
we're going to see a lot of
organizations yeah bringing in product
into europe from all over the world um i
think one thing that
the rest of the world can expect from
denmark as they have with it with any
other product that comes out of denmark
it's going to be um
incredibly high quality
and the consistency is going to be there
right which is
absolutely necessary for the
pharmaceutical and medicinal worlds um
we we have to make sure that we're
creating the same thing over and over
and over and over again
and that's something that's being very
very closely watched here
yeah exact dosage when it comes to the
medical industry has to be down to the
minute 0.0 milligram
um can we move on to the next part which
is the vulcan medical story you gave us
a quick overview can you explain to us
why the danish industry what the
opportunity is there and do you see
denmark having a step above
the likes of we
personally i see ireland and malta being
processing facilities for a large scale
product being turned into pharmaceutical
products and then being shipped into the
european pharmacies do you see denmark
having an upper step on the two
territories i just mentioned there
so here's where i see the um
the exciting components of denmark and
maybe taking a step back like we we
evaluated from an investment perspective
you know where should we set up a
facility um at the time denmark was one
of the first countries that were
allowing for
the
processing
and cultivation of medical cannabis
there were a number of organizations
that were getting set up to do
cultivation here and um we also looked
at the regulatory framework where there
were no caps on how much you could
cultivate there were no caps on how much
you could export
and it was a
it was very nice and
straightforward um
uh regulatory framework which we
appreciated you know coming out of the
canadian market um
i don't know how many years we spent you
know working with organizations and
watching organizations saying oh we'll
be licensed next month we'll be licensed
next month and then two years later
they're still waiting on their licensing
um uh because of the lack of
transparency um in that licensing
process unfortunately and
and the changing um of the benchmarks
you might say right versus denmark it's
been very very clear so in terms of
getting a license it's not easy to get a
license here but it's very clear on
what's required to be able to get a
license so we saw that as a major
benefit
secondarily in terms of why denmark
denmark
i'd say probably about like 30 or 40 of
their gdp comes out of the
pharmaceutical space um so there's a lot
of professionals here that are used to
working in the can
not in the cannabis space but in the
pharmaceutical space
with transferable skills to the cannabis
space
and when i've seen some of the other
other markets where they don't have that
access to that type of professional
labor pool
that can make a big impact in terms of
the reliability of the organization and
the organization's ability to be able to
produce a final product
taking a look at malta um taking a look
at ireland both great spots even from a
tax perspective both great spots to be
able to
start up production
you know we've got uh you can see
northern leaf um they're getting going
over there in jersey for example right
um you've got uh you know our friends at
uh materia that got a facility set up in
masa um all of those are places that we
took a look at even portugal
it was a regulatory framework that
really made a huge difference for us to
say look is this a very straightforward
regulatory framework and is this
something that we can act on and you
know we were founded or we founded this
organization in late 2018
so and it's taken us this long to be
able to get through you know the
fundraising processes the uh the build
out um then the licensing and validation
right it takes takes a very long time um
and denmark at the time was was great
for and still has been an exceptional
place to be able to do business
yeah a good business partner is a hugely
important thing when you're setting up
in a different territory for sure last
topic of conversation and i think you're
to have a wealth of knowledge on this
topic canadian lps
are we going to see one of them going
bust this year is is it is is as big a
show as i can see from over here in
ireland or
something that they're going to pull out
of the bag that for some reason to make
this billions of dollars of investment
worthwhile and i thought hexaware on
turn their corner and they seem to be
going the other way completely so i can
see three to four of those guys
running low on capital and who on earth
is going to keep funding unless it's a
current investor so what do you see
as the next 12 to 24 months do you see
some merger and acquisitions there where
there's left with like two players and
and kind of they're they're able to
survive on a much more leaner strategy
or what do you see the next 12 or
24 months happening over there
of course it's anybody's guess right in
terms of what's going to happen the
canadian lps have done a phenomenal job
at um driving capital into the industry
canada having um the the stock exchanges
available between the canadian x stock
exchange which has been um
i guess jokingly noted as the cannabis
stock exchange or the cse um and then on
top of that with the tsx right so um
lots of organizations going public lots
of access to capital and then that the
traditional height that brought in a ton
of capital into the market
um to bring capital into that market for
a company to say hey look we're going to
play it safe and we're going to build
out 20 000 square feet and kind of grow
with the market that doesn't drive as
much excitement as hey we're going to
build a facility that you can see from
space which we heard one of the founders
uh at one point say at a conference um
so you know uh there was definitely a
different components and different
strategies um to what the end objective
was i think what we're shouldn't even
say i think what we're seeing right now
is a lot more of a pragmatic approach
within the within the canadian cannabis
industry and also that echoing
throughout the global industry whereas
organizations are not saying hey we're
going to be everything and anything to
anybody and everybody um let's see what
we can do to try to grow this company
profitably
we are seeing you know liquidity
challenges with a number of these spaces
but not without uh you know some of
these organizations are still strong
assets on their balance sheet and
because they have that strong assets
it's really trying to commercialize
those assets and figure out okay what
can we do with these to
turn a profit you see canopy trimming
down quite dramatically aurora doing the
same thing
and really just right sizing their
business
because the industry isn't
it's growing fast like don't get me
wrong um it's growing quite fast but
it's not growing as fast as
they were maybe once previously
expecting it it'll still be a dominant
density it's going to be gigantic
but it takes time everything like it
took time in canada and it takes even
more time over here in europe
and i think i think what we're actually
going to see is yeah some more
consolidation happening but also more
specialization rather than companies
saying hey look we're going to to own
all the products and do all the testing
and all the cultivation and all the
extraction and all the everything um and
you're spreading out your dollars so
thin right
and you're spreading out your expertise
uh so thin and if you look at most
industries globally outside cannabis
industry they don't operate like that
even apple apple who said that with
everything end to end
they have groups that manufacture
products for them and and groups that
will specialize across that supply chain
and i think that we're going to start to
see more and more of that today in the
cannabis space we're gonna see that
specialization
you know we look at it over here in
europe and just doesn't make sense for a
group to go and spend you know three to
five million euros on setting up their
own extraction facility to put out maybe
four thousand five thousand bottles and
then some of the regular trade
regulatory changes might cause them to
re-pivot have to pick up some more
capital assets and then um deploy again
and when it takes you know 24 to 36
months to build out and and then even
before you bring a new product to market
just just building out and getting
qualified
that's a long time and a lot can change
during that time so i think
specialization is definitely the path to
the future
okay and last word before we go we know
medical is going to be dominant in
europe for the next few years but do you
see there being a dispensary style model
at some stage in europe to copy the kind
of american model
you know what um like the canadian
started with a male in a million medical
cannabis program right where um you
could pick up uh your orders um online
and um have them delivered to you which
was quite interesting versus europe we
already see a physical presence so i
think that step to dispensary model once
a recreational program comes into play i
don't think that's so far out of hand
um it's it's already in existence
there's a distribution platform already
in place
and so stepping into maybe something a
little bit more recreation
once it's approved
i think uh yeah i do see that happening
yeah i've started to see now a lot of
with the pass in the european commission
and you can sell cbd flair now legally
in the european union so i've seen a
huge influx of cbd flower being sold at
a good price same as cbd hash and i know
of a couple of stores open up in austria
and france where they'll be selling cbd
flour and cbd hash and i think that'll
be a quick turnaround just to be able to
add thc into their inventory model but
it's an exciting industry and a lot to
look forward to over the next couple of
years thank you very much for coming on
show peace we've got a time limit of 15
minutes so we're just coming up to that
now hopefully we'll to talk again in the
future about the danish industry and how
everything's going for you guys
i appreciate your time
thanks everybody for watching we shall
talk to you again soon