foreign
who's a PhD in pharmaceutical biology
and phytochemistry from the University
of Munster in Germany hey keeping today
sir
yeah good good server thank you very
much for having me here yeah I'm
actually
you know I'm I'm just about to go on my
vacation so it's a perfect time to
talking about candidates and women
health excellent I'm delighted to have
you on I know you're a very busy lady so
can you maybe give everybody a quick
little overview of your position in the
industry and your experience to date
uh so actually I started in cannabis
industry uh I like to research cannabis
industry for ADHD that was basically the
my starting point about like getting to
know how cannabis can be used as a
medicine and uh upon that I moved to
Berlin I started to work in a sanity
group as a medical advisor and after
that we founded a new company the name
is femcan and actually in femcan we
focusing on let's say cannabis cannabis
contain functional cosmetics and uh like
hopefully near future functional
nutritions for female health
okay very interesting and can we start
on the first topic which is I know
there's a lot of female listeners and a
lot of powerful women in the Cannabis
industry already Anonymous for Women's
Health can you maybe give everybody an
overview of how cannabis is applicable
to women's health and what the potential
benefits are
yeah actually I
mean or any living organism with
endocannabinoid system can eventually be
like cannabis can be potentially
beneficial for that organism
but for female health is especially
beneficial because uh endocannabinoid
system is ubiquitous in female
reproductive system and if you look at
many anecdotal and I have to open a
parenthesis here unfortunately
unfortunately there is very less uh good
quality uh clinical study out there to
analyze and examine the effect of
cannabis on female heads most of what we
know is that basically on old texts from
traditional herbal medicine from
different parts of the globe and uh the
anecdotes and the surveys and
observational studies
so having said that there are a lot of
like good observational studies and good
surveys that shows cannabis can help
different uh different symptoms of women
health so let's say menstruation pain
and cramps endometriosis which is a huge
topic when it's come to cannabis also it
is smooth as the transition from
pre-menopause yeah like the whole
menopausal transition and it's also very
much help with orgasm and sex so
basically clothes it's a cannabis can no
not completely close what can how do you
call it like tighten the Gap in or
orgasm like so you see that from desire
to labor cannabis can be helpful for
female Health that's like a nutshell
very interesting and are we talking
about
um targeting the endocannabinoid system
with different blends and formulations
that become products or is it a specific
Edibles or beverages what's the optimum
absorption method for a consumer
a super interesting question and again
the at the moment especially like in
Germany we don't have that much of a
diversity when it comes to different
products okay we have extracts and we
have
um the the flowers but when you look
from the female physiological
perspective what can be super helpful or
what you know suppositories I mean that
there is like one one company in Germany
where I met who put that effort to bring
that to the market so they have a pre
um let's say pre-made kits that
pharmacies can make the life of
pharmacies easier to bring that kind of
applications form into the customers and
into the patients but other than that
there is not not a huge diversity and of
course we have to look and we have to
see what kind of a cannabinoid
um ratios what kind of formulation would
be beneficial for which purpose so so
sometimes you might need a you might
need an eatable beside you might need a
topical application or you might need a
vaginal application so it really depends
which kind of symptoms you want to
Target is it are you searching for
short-term effect long-term effects and
like there are many uh there's many
variants that you have to keep in mind
when you develop a drug for female
health and female need so that that's
why there is a huge potential out there
to design and develop products specified
for female needs and uh I mean from one
so it's like that it's a two side of the
cone is from one side and like sad to
see
just banal example I mean I prefer to to
take Edibles and I prefer to take
vaginal suppositories instead of like
inhalation or instead of like uh smoking
that that's that's matches much better
to my knees and my uh physiology let's
say but yeah there is no product that I
can access to
it's sad that it's not but also it's
interesting for us as the people who as
people who are like let's say are
working in this industry to see this
potential so that's a huge the a nice
space for us to move into and to develop
product sure
yeah it seems to be that these
formulations and the specific use case
that these formulations are the big uh
advantage and the big uh exciting
opportunity that's coming over the next
five to ten years speaking of huge
opportunity can we talk a little bit
about the femcan story can you maybe
give everybody a little overview of how
you set this company up what the main
objectives are and any timelines that
consumers might need to know about Yeah
so basically we started femcan for
different reasons also so first I
shortly say something about femias or
femkin is cannabis and can as yes we can
and
the the tagline for femkin is at the
home of herbal feminism and family this
is female remedies basically so I come
with a background of traditional herbal
medicine and uh the the way that herbal
medicine is some kind of I don't want to
say suppressed or ignored but you know
herbal medicine always comes as
secondary also when you look at um
cannabis in medicine you have the the
dog when you get your cannabis
prescribed you have to show the doctors
that the doctor has to show to the
insurances that all the other ways of
treatments are done so it's like they
they uh try the second the the first and
the second uh let's say a conventional
treatment and then cannabis can be
subscribed which uh I think herbal
medicine can be super super beneficial
and why they should come at second or
third maybe they should come parallel
with the first line treatment so that
that's one part of it the second part of
it is that we want to focus on the
female health because
I mean when you look at the uh look at
the people who support cannabis I mean
women are less likely to support
cannabis women are less likely to try
cannabis if cannabis get legalized and
all of that comes from like uh
Global surveys like the the one that I'm
giving you is just published by Canadian
uh University I cannot remember the name
but it's just just publishes 20 23
publication and women also have more
negative attitude through consumption of
cannabis and that's for me as a
scientist as a person who know how uh
cannabis can be beneficial for different
uh female Health like let's say issues
and generally for like the well-being it
shouldn't be just medical it could also
be adult use and recreational just for
General well-being as a person who know
that and have experience with that that
that's a little bit hard on me because
that's negative attitude mostly come
from social cultural backgrounds like
these typical good girl bad girl if a
girl small cannabis or do cannabis or
any kind of drugs for that matter is bad
but it's more let's say acceptable and
common for men
this kind of
um how do you call it this kind of
cultural let's say pushbacks it's
something that we as a woman in cannabis
industry should try to overcome by
talking about that by just bring put
more light on this subject that yeah
okay if you use cannabis consciously and
cautiously it could be more beneficial
as harmful and uh it's not uh we should
also whether we go to some kind of like
exhibitions and trade shows you also see
that maybe like five to ten percent
maximum of the participant or woman the
rest are men especially like in Germany
and talking about here and I know that
it's like changing little by little but
uh we need more voice we need more voice
to talk about how the the benefits and
uh
how do you call it take that's a
stigmatize uh because the silver is a
stigma around this topic to take that
stigmatizing you out of it so uh
basically harm reduction uh
way of communication so so that's why as
fem can we solely want to focus on
female Health the herbs that uh how do
you call it effects or endocannabinoid
system because again not only cannabis
affect our endocannabinoid system
another example is cover cover amazing
amazing plants has also more how do you
call it
um Affinity
um let's say a stronger Affinity even to
uh CB1 receptor than like cannabis also
all of these all of that said we want to
bring
endocannabinoid system uh put light on
endocannabinoid system and work with the
plants that affect these endocannabinoid
system and also desegnatize the Cannabis
in general yeah
very very interesting and one of the big
hurdles you mentioned there is there or
indeed the actual scientific papers
aren't completed yet do you see Germany
opening up now with a larger scope
and remit to be able to do these
scientific trials hopefully over the
next coming 12 to 24 months
to be honest
12 to 20 to 24 months is a little bit
like optimistic
uh I've I I'm not sure to be honest I'm
a little bit disappointed people with
all of these delays and uh how do you
call it that they made a huge probiotic
monster around cannabis so definitely
you know that we now uh the the
government announced two pillar projects
one pillar is that self and communal
communication with some kind of a social
clubs and the second pillar is that to
uh it's a very limited pilot project to
some shops that they control the whole
supply chain okay
these stocks are good are super positive
because again it helps a lot to take
away a stigma from this topic for from
Cannabis and hopefully by how hopefully
now universities come much more on board
to do research also companies should put
more effect and put more how do you call
it um
uh put uh resources on uh r d and
clinical studies than just trying to
bring another new kind of flower which
is which is good the diversity in the
product is good but we also need some
kind of uh we need like solid clinical
and clinical studies and observational
studies to
to to be able to develop good products
so that is I mean I hope I hope because
a couple of years ago when I asked one
of my University professors say do you
want to start some project with like CBD
and ADHD and that was just cbd.com and
the reply was oh no no do you want to
ruin my reputation but now I see that
the research in this direction also in
universities get more and more so yeah
all in all is going in the right
direction
I wish for for a faster uh moves then
it's like a slow slow so yeah
yeah well that's it the entrepreneurial
mindset wants everything to move fastly
fastly so you can realize your ideas
it's been fantastic to often to you uh
shabnam for anybody who's not following
the chat room on LinkedIn I highly
recommend you go and connect them with
her and for those who want to know more
about femcam the website is below and
it'll be in all the descriptions
wherever you watch and listen to this
you go off and enjoy your holidays now
and uh hopefully we get to touch base
again next year and we can get an update
on where all the progress is definitely
definitely I would help you to do that
fantastic you have a great day and
thanks everybody for watching
foreign