[Music]
approach this from a such a different
perspectives colored by our guests our
panelists and their respective expertise
we'll try to tie this together now this
is a summit when I think of a summit
that means that people are supposed to
ask questions people are supposed to
walk away with some of the things that
are in their head at the end of this day
answered so please don't hesitate to
raise your hand if you have a question
of a particular topic let's try to
integrate those questions as we move
along
uh my name is Bob Hobart I'm an attorney
in the United States I work out of
Denver Colorado I lead the Cannabis
Industry Group for an international law
firm Colin Clark Hill Clark Hill has an
office here at Dublin my partner's uh
Sean and Sam are sitting in the audience
today and really really pleased to be
here
um really happy to be in Ireland talking
about something that's new or hopefully
going to accelerate the conversation
because it's public policy that of
course is controversial but if done
correctly it can be a change that
actually benefits society that benefits
and perhaps provides cover for
politicians and and bureaucrats and the
like
um I want to introduce to my left now
Mariana Marianne it is a life sciences
and corporate attorney from Mexico uh
she also uh she recently left a law firm
in Mexico City
um and became the director of a project
called santorio Gomez which is in taluk
outside of Tulum and on the Yucatan
Peninsula in Mexico it is a
multi-hundred unit development for
industrial hemp and Mariah will shed
some light on some of the things that
involve sourcing hemp material if you're
going to bill in this day age is there
anything else that I'd miss that you'd
like that but the uh that the audience
know is in your rapper yeah I know well
I am not Alexa Journey cannabis in
Mexico is regulated in the General
Health law so as a pharmaceutical life
science and filter attorney I started
reviewing all these matters since 2016
when in Mexico the regulations start
so the well the last year I had the
opportunity to join this beautiful
project uh that we are going to create
the first Camp living community in
Memphis and the only reason why I
quinned my my nice firm in Mexico City
and I moved to live near the sea is
because in this project we're a three
important things number one we're
educating each time we we talk about the
project people if they buy you or not
they finally think it go with your
information number two we're showing the
government a legal business in hand in
Mexico we're going to import right now
materials and the third one and the
third one is that uh we are opening the
industry right and people may be friend
between him and Kennedy's uh for uh for
adult uses or medicine uses and in times
they don't understand that when we're
opening the industry for him we are also
opening the industry for all the family
of Canada right Canada is a word that
means is the name of the family of all
the plants and this is one of the things
I want to discuss today guys about the
importance of the definitions in our
regulations and in the law because in
Mexico the problem it is not that
cannabis it is not legal it is about the
definitions that are not clear so the
authorities have no tools for for
openness industry but this is the reason
why I click the firm and now I am
leading this project and uh well I'll be
very happy to see you around italuma and
Cancun Mexico we have a beautiful place
there to show and also this is a a good
destination because it is a well-known
International destiny Asian so we're not
only going to educate and open these for
Mexicans also this is open for worldwide
for the Cannabis industry I am picturing
this place for Canada students will be
all around and instead to going and pay
a lot of uh thousand dollars in nice and
fancy hotels you'll already have your
Camp Jungkook house in a jungle of two
women right uh in a really nice resort
but that is only a little bit of the
prey thank you Robert
um and then also uh to manage that is
Mike Corral from armadino LLP armanino
is a Finance Tax Technology and
consulting firm with a top 25 in the
United States uh Mike's Mike specializes
in working in the Cannabis industry he's
worked all over the United States and
operates uh with other International
folks in the space Mike tell us a little
bit about more about yourself for for
your background involve into the campus
safely yeah I was with you know one of
the big four accounting firms and
realized that cannabis was going to be
something that was going to go state by
state and so I've moved from Texas to
California uh before it became legal
there are the props six to four uh in
2015 and then storyboarding about the
Cannabis industry eventually I wrote I
treat this as a book a research book on
multi-state cannabis taxation for talks
or borders and so I went doing each
state and how they tax this industry
whether you're a cultivator manufacturer
or distributor or retailer at each state
has their own rules their own tax system
you know to tax this industry it's very
confusing for for cannabis companies and
then most recently about two years ago
during covet I moved for California to
New Jersey as I saw this industry movie
he scored in the U.S
I would like thank you for joining us uh
and then Bo you did not miss a thing
thank you for uh I was in the same boat
I just uh I wasn't I didn't know where I
was going this morning either but with
me is as a friend he and I have quite
literally traveled the world together we
were talking uh seems like every time
we're in a car together uh people are
driving on the wrong side of the road uh
and uh that happened to get here in Iowa
uh bo worked for New Frontier data one
of the larger data companies in the
United States and in the world focusing
on the Cannabis space he left a new
frontier uh several years ago and began
Whitney economics he's regarded as one
of the top economists in the entire
cannabis space projecting uh the
Cannabis industry and I'll talk a little
bit about what I mean by the Cannabis
industry in a moment but Bo tell us uh
tell the audience a little bit more
about your background perhaps
yeah sure so
um it's nice to be here eventually
uh yeah I had I took a secure this route
5 into the account Australia really
nothing to do with it I was doing the
flight of Economics at Intel Corporation
and sizing up their supply chain and
doing Global Supply Chain work and I was
teaching economic setting University
when Oregon state of Oregon on the west
coast of the United States was just in
the on the cusp of legalizing on an
adult you site
um and so I started looking at the
market one of my students was in that
industry already and I asked them how
big the industry was he said I don't
know you're the eponymous you tell me
um and so I took that challenge quite
literally and and started looking into
it realizing uh at what point that it
was just this huge market and
was quickly picked up by a vertically
integrated company and they wanted me to
run their operations
so we eventually uh Mike from the doleus
or medical to adulties and then we were
the first company to go public on the
Canadian Securities of exchange
via with Bruce takeover at RTO
um and so we kind of paved the way for
um canvas uh you know public offerings
in Canada with U.S offices
um and with that being the chief
operations officer I got a a really good
perspective all facets of the canvas
industry in front growing to processing
and distribution retail and so then I
started using that and developing some
of my andromic theories and so I started
just trying to answer general questions
about business and the economics of
cannabis and so I started building the
foundation for others to use in the
economics Community there's had a lot of
folks in the space right now I'm not yet
and that there's a lot of interest that
not a lot of folks actually added for
anticipation Ken
um so with laid the foundation and you
know on
um you know consumer Behavior business
Behavior a labor a taxation uh
governments that influence on the market
like so try to build a body of work and
economics
and just uh focus in on that while other
people did good work in tax and in legal
and other areas so that's the end of my
story
and when you talk to people about
numbers in the Cannabis industry there
tends to be a little bit with
exaggeration
because we all want to talk about how
exciting and how successful the industry
is in some ways that's true other days
that's not true but it's very critical
it's very important when you're trying
to make your taste whether that's to
support public policy whether your
company's raising money whether you're
out there in the marketplace looking for
partners it's very important to have
accurate information real information
and information that is based in reality
particularly when you're talking about
numbers over the next hour plus we're
going to talk about some of the market
numbers we're going to talk about the
markets themselves we'll talk a little
bit about some of the regular
I just that perhaps Ireland can
participate it if not this entire region
in terms of what Commerce will look like
and as I mentioned please just read if
you have a question that we'll try to
work those in along the way uh okay
comments at the outset uh here is indeed
a global cannabis industry no make no
mistake about it sometimes those of us
that work in a particular country or in
the U.S a particular state region we
understand what's happening in our
region but everything is connect now you
say how can everything be connected when
particularly in the United States the
industry is illegal right marijuana and
by the way let me say this I'm going to
use the term marijuana to refer to the
marijuana side of the industry meaning
high THC products I'm going to use the
word hen corn and talk about not
intoxicating
compounds and Industrial uses
um all of those things in my opinion
fall under what I call the Cannabis
industry so you might hear people talk
about the Catalyst industry they just
mean marijuana but the Cannabis industry
based on what I've seen and how I've
worked in the industry for 14 years now
really has two distinct sectors hemp and
marijuana and that's less pronounced
when you travel in nationally because
they make less of a hard-line
distinction between the two but I wanted
to frame that for you so the and
abilities are not meant to be scientific
numbers but the global cannabis industry
is projected to be 75 billion dollars
within the next three to four years
those numbers could be higher or lower
depending on which uh projection sources
you use but roughly roughly half of that
number comes from North America and then
the other half of that number is the
rest of the world and the Aggregate and
this is quite significant because even
when you think about participating in
this industry some venture capitalist
funds and Equity Funds they'll say well
the Cannabis industry is very small I'm
not going to pay attention to it yet and
that's true when you compare it to some
other things but it's not a small
industry not by any stretch of the
imagination and it is indeed global
so what is the Cannabis industry the
Cannabis industry evolves as I mentioned
hemp
it involves marijuana it involves the
technologies that overlay those sectors
it's International it's domestic we're
talking about industrial uses we're
talking about pharmaceutical uses we're
talking about consumer uses for wellness
and for other non-intoxic properties of
the plant and you're talking about in
many jurisdictions recreational or adult
use the polite way perhaps to talk about
using cannabis without regulation and I
believe there are four distinct public
policy lays that already exist when
you're talking about cannabis the first
is industrial uses it kind of speaks for
itself when I talked about industrial
uses you can imagine what I mean fighter
writer plastic fuel building materials
so forth and so on these are historical
uses and by the way I'll know in the
1930s
there was a magazine article in a
magazine called Popular Mechanics that
magazine projected hint
to be the next billion fee billion
dollar industry in the 1930s they were
talking about hepting a billion dollar
industry and here we are many years
later after public policy changes and
the light actually starting to see this
occur so that first of the four lanes is
the industrially the secondly when I
call over-the-counter marijuana this is
when you go buy a flower or it foil
distill it from that flower or an
infused product which is intended to
produce a structure active effect it has
high THC they do our dispensary system
in the United States think of what
Germany's about to do think about what
Czech Republic is about to do so forth
and so on I call it over-the-counter
marijuana because there's very little
distinction between medical and adult
use in most markets except how it
qualifies the purchaser of that product
if I'm in an adult use Marketplace I
simply have to be 21 if I'm in a medical
Marketplace I simply have to have a
doctor validate that I have one of a
range of conditions it's a mere
qualifier for how he purchased the
product second of the four lanes the
other two the pharmaceutical rate this
is a different Lane than the
over-the-counter marijuana Lake and I
would question anyone that suggests that
over-the-counter marijuana is actually
medical marijuana not because there's
that efficacy there certainly is but
it's over-the-country marijuana a
pharmaceutical complex the medicinal
complex they control this third plate it
requires approval by FDA and like bonds
different jurisdictions around the world
for specific conditions we just saw it
they did the fourth Lane is what I call
Wellness or neutral thoughts think of
CBD think of protein from hip these are
compounds of a cannabis plant that don't
produce a high that are regulated as
Foods or supplements in the marketplace
and that of course is evolving as well
particularly when you throw in the fact
that there are noble Foods here in
Europe
um ultimately I believe you have to have
a balanced public policy approach where
you legalize cannabis in any
jurisdiction what do I mean by balance
look at some of the Latin American
countries that initially came out of the
box look at Colombia look at Uruguay
they looked at tech support only
mountains we can't really have an
Economy based on an export only model in
a brand new industry it doesn't work so
you have to balance that with some
sembulence of a domestic industry as
well and that's what we're seeing begin
to evolve I think Colombia is a good
example of that where they started out
with X Court only and by the way they
only allow the exportation boil
initially they changed that law
recognizing that the market dictated
that flowers needed to be exported as
well
and now they're embarking on a domestic
distribution of regulated system so for
for the for their country so my Buddhist
with that balance I think you create the
most Economic Opportunity so those of
you that Lobby or work in public policy
please think of that because you can't
have a successful industry just
participating on one side or the other
and then the last thing I'll say before
we dive into some of the numbers Bo is
um is the United Nations right let's
talk about the United States for just a
moment and it's an important thing when
you think about the U.N dimension on
narcotic drugs which effectively has
been in existence for dozens and dozens
of years now it classifies cannabis as a
highly restricted drug and all of its
membrane agents have had to enact very
strict control policies around cannabis
around marijuana
well that changed recent November of
the committee of narcotic drugs adopted
a new recognition for medicinal cannabis
for the first thought they said this is
a fail that's different and should be
controlled differently than drug type
marijuana for example as they refer to
it another thing that happened by the
Indiana Nations at that same period of
time is they began to recognize that CBD
and non-intoxicating compounds like CBD
for the HEB
fall into the industrial exception found
under the U.N convention so why couldn't
his law and regulations color all of
this but it's entrepreneurs and markets
that drive it so Bo let's talk about
some of the numbers Market wise and and
think just however you'd like it to go
with this I think it would be good at
this up level said what is the uh what
is the global economy look like I threw
my number out there that I read and then
how does that in your mind uh break down
my range yeah sure so when you when
forecasters try to predict what the
total demand is they've looked towards
conception they look towards surveys
that are being conducted by the U.N by
these various uh governmental agencies
help authorities and the like and
generally it goes like this
they call you up by the thought they say
hi I'm Tim the government do you smoke
wheat yes or not
and so in countries where it's
prohibited
everybody's going to respond uh no I
don't know anybody that
so can those surveys in the countries
that
are prohibited this the responses and
the consumption rights are recorded
that's very very low
in other countries like worldwide or
Canada or the United States when
somebody calls you up and then there
were met and says do you smoke weed when
it's normalized and when there's
distribution channels and all sorts of
stuff then the percentage of people that
admit to using cannabis in the previous
year and previous month it's relatively
high and so
um a lot of the demand is based upon
consumption and then they decide that
badly to that consumption and then the
number of consumers so it's consumers
consumption status
um
from the numbers from the unodc
um based upon these predictions the
total Global Market is between 250 and
350 million dollars and I think this is
extremely underrecorded
um because in the United States the
total Mark and elicit illegal is over a
hundred billion dollars a month
so that would mean that the U.S market
is roughly a third of the tall Global
demand
um enough just I'm just not buying that
um and so but from a consumption or a
consumer perspective the largest market
in the world is actually a nation uh
it's China it's India
um it's the Asian countries and then
effort and then then the US and Europe
and so when you look at it from a
consumer perspective those are the
largest markets in the in the world but
from a dollar or a Euro perspective the
largest market is in North America and
specifically the US uh and then the
European market from a dollar or a Euro
for stat to this is the second largest
market from a for a revited for step
um well not for Dukan was that
as the global Marketplace normalizes the
prices in these U.S market and European
market will actually fall and so
there'll be some normalization of the
market and the the that it is total
addressable Market still legal and and
legal but kind of normalize and and
shake out and then you'll start saying
uh you know the value of that Asian
market relative to the European and the
U.S markets
um and so so you can look at it from a
dollar or a Euro perspective where you
have to look at it from a consumer
perspective and I do vote
um in addition to that uh
it's often overlooked about Supply and
so where is this Supply coming from some
life firm has developed models that
looks at supplied particularly in the
United States about where the supply is
coming from and then the value of that
Supply as well
so Mike what are some of the things that
our industry or Market chillers we
talked about tax evil we were preparing
for this video comments on at least just
some other thoughts on what prevents a
new program from actually succeeding
what what Stein is more
yeah and you know this one of the buses
that I think Ireland and other countries
could learn from what's happened here in
the the U.S
what generally happens is this statement
local governments determine how much was
he they want to generate from Cannabis
taxation so let's call it a hundred
Billy and then they figure out well this
is how many and how much things sales we
have to add that we expect will generate
100 billion in tax and then they back
into it and they figure okay when is the
tax rate that I have to have times the
amount of sales that will equal 100
billion and they work backwards this way
because they want to budget you know 100
billion dollars of tax revenue the
coming from Cannabis
um but unfortunately what that does is
it creates such a high tax rate that the
legal Market just strikes because they
have no regulation they have no testing
they have no uh tax obligations and so
um they they do quite well that meant
we're seeing this right now in New York
city where the work recently of Akeem
adult used label and they've only
granted four licenses and of those four
licenses uh two uh are you know social
Mike Woody licenses that we called where
people that have been arrested or
incarcerated for
drug trafficking in the past they're
trying to make amends to them and say
hey let's you know that it's legal
let's expunge their their criminal
records let's you know make it so that
they get
etiod first opportunity into this new
business in New York
um but problem is with with only four
legal dispensaries there are
countless illegal dispensaries that are
selling Goods now and the problem is is
that when they get caught they basically
get a slime ball to wrist fine and that
said and then they turn around and next
week they have another Shuffle just
really quickly to that foot there was an
article the other day
there was a there was a store near Times
Square not licensed it was shut down
four consecutive times it just keeps
opening again to your point because
there's no repercussion there's no
nobody gets arrested maybe they get a
ticket but it's legal it's just not
licenses and regulated completely yet
and that's that perhaps that you need to
jump yeah that that you know and it's
very surprising that here in the U.S
that you know we saw this in Colorado a
California Washington or in all these
states that that came adult you sleep
years ago that now these news Stakes on
the East Coast are making the very same
mistakes uh you know even at New York
there have been attacks um cannabis not
based on the purchase price you know THC
content which is also kind of a
dangerous way of doing this because an
incentive for some of these uh testing
Labs you know to be payable much for
money and say hey just make it you know
not a hundred milligrams fake it showed
as 90 milligrams because it is a lower
cost
that's just not a good way to really the
forced a Man attack system
on the Helms so just to supplement this
a little bit uh another common estate
that's made from state to state to state
related to tax is that they expect this
huge surge attack
immediately out of the gate and they
don't realize that it takes a while
takes a couple years to deploy a legal
program and then develop the rules and
then refine the rules and throughout
that process more and more
um there was a full participate in
political system and so there's a ramp
that takes place in terms of not only
illicit to levo Consumer conversions but
the amount of tax that's generated at
the state level and so it'll ultimately
get us aware their objectives are if
they if they did things right they'd
have tests too much and distance that's
bias consumer being abroad and
conversion it'll eventually get there
but it takes a while and I think
aesthetic expectations with legislators
and with Regulators on their uh
realistic ramp is is extremely important
in the work
at that street uh that is an important
part but the renulation in all around
the world the classical series shine are
how we're going to
isolation what is THC what is CBD what
is a cannabinoid and I don't know guys
please have a question for us did it is
correct to classified in Canada's
industry regarding the person of
ndabinoids in the product you know
because that is a drawlet if you are
putting more taxes because you have a
plea tree then then the system it is not
quite cooperate the correct way in a
like Sciences as an as a pharmaceutical
journey I can tell we have if the
General Health law the definition of THC
in the classification of a controlled
substance where the log states that is a
major public health problem
products which contain more than one
percent of THC and this is a mistake so
when we're done to talk about starting
the radiation we need to be clear with
those definitions in order to not repeat
eight hour mistakes because we're here
to talk about our regulations the
mistakes we've been through and I want
to help you to do not go to the same
things as us but only was it but no no
it's great so so think about this stuff
think about
when a government decides to actually
put a law or a regulation in place and
they start to tax you on THC content
it's almost like the government's saying
hey we're doing you a favor
public we're allowing these compounds to
be introduced into society and we're
going to tax it upon how much fun you
can have or how much TNC in it when the
right approach is not that approach it's
the exact opposite it's suppose what
Beau would might describe this when a
government looks at the industry and
says what industries do for the
government not let the government be do
for the industry that's the way that
things become moved forward so if the
government can rely on the taxation the
tax dollars they can do things and you
can show that and for those of you
making an argument for talking with
public policy makers you can look no
further than pick a state in the United
States pick a country Latin America you
can show that those tax dollars have
been put to use for schools for
Education campaigns for roads for public
buildings for the public health there
are so many things that come out of
Taxation for the Cannabis industry and
it's all positive it but it's not about
the government saying we will allow you
to do this what can we do for you it
should be the other way around what can
the private sector in a new industry do
for the government which ultimately
benefits to people now around I'd like
to come back to some of the things
you've talked about uh we talked about
other markets trying to get off the
ground uh and having been off the ground
like the U.S market but of course what's
happening in Mexico Mexico of course is
135 million people as I understand it
very very large country by way of
population
its Supreme Court had issued a a finding
four years ago that says you have to
allow for and create a law for adult
news or dispensaries for lack of a
better way to put it but that hasn't
happened yet but talk about the the
three different policy Lanes medical
adult use and and the hemp and uh what's
happening in Mexico and how it relates
you think too General Global policy and
development so
um in Mexico everything starts with a
medicinal regulation we start because of
at trial individual go against the
government asking a permission for
evidence
so after this first trial daily one a
ton of Trials came right not only for
the medicinal area also for the
recreation or other ears period and uh
for a good in 2017 we had our first
amendment in the generality of law which
allowed us to grow calories for
medicinal and a clinical research Corpus
right
and that 2021 January where two years
after death the held Authority execute
the regulations for the medicinal
illness
these regulations are are really
interesting because for first time the
field Ministry execute a regulation in
which other authorities are related and
it's kind of a copy of the drugs
regulation we had before but they added
the word Candace right cannabinox THC
CBD
so uh what people pertend and is curious
is that we have a 100 percent of legal
medicinal system but we do not have
access for cannabis in medicinal
purposes right we can't go to a
drugstore we even though we do not find
the CBD oils you know in the pharmacies
you need to obtain these in maybe Easter
on Facebook in social media it either
Amazon it is not selling in Mexico CBD
so what is the problem here and the
lesson from these industries this
medicinal area internet for today
we need to understand that medicinal
academies it is not only about the
Pharma industry right we need to
understand there are other ways for
having access to amazing all panelists
that will not take us a lot of time
because for the Pharma industry the
medicinal and candidates will take a lot
of years with clinical research a lot of
investment or they will make these drugs
and by the way congratulations guide for
with all your what are you doing here
um but this takes time and takes money
and is an industry that a lot of people
is scared if or does not know enough
right example the law firm I was working
in was a really challenge to bring the
lover into into the catalase interest
because people it is afraid all the time
when they saw the Cannabis because right
so the lesson here is to understand that
the Chinese medicine the medicinal
calories it is not only aimed for the
pharmaceutical industry and that there
are other ways and systems to give
upstairs for the patients for calories
without needing to wait all this time
and all this money and all this
immersion right and investment source
then it's like a ham industrial camp in
this 2017 in this amendment uh was the
exemption and we are allowed with the
commercialized exam or products which
contain cannabbing noise that does not
uh have more than one percent of THC and
here comes I think of definition in a
lot of regulations there is a state that
if the product contains or the crop
contains
more than one percent of THC that is
recreational or menacing up but it
contains less than one percent of THC it
can this is not right hand and a
specific plot within a specific genetic
and that yes these plants uh
generates low percent of DHT but the
thing here is again the classification
what my law states is that I can
commercialize Import and Export products
which contain not not more than one
percent of THC not only in him right uh
so this part of the the technicians and
that classification uh that we're going
to start working here and there is only
important and uh well hint is little but
it is not regulated again guys it is
about regulation not over regulation
okay because when governments and
leading leader are scared about Randy
Laden they tend to over regulate and
then you over regulate a market with
taxes if you over regulate a market with
a new regulation for cannabis that says
the same thing the other one you know
can't trouble so so let's keep it simple
please and the third thing is we're
recreational is really funny in the
recreational area in Mexico in 2020 the
Supreme Court executed Crete which state
that the parts of the Articles which
means the prohibition for constitution
of calories are not more legal but the
Supreme Court only state a document they
do not amend the law so uh now what
consumers are doing they are going
reproductive automation against sanitary
risks which is a signal of MBA as
corrupt permission of transmission
they have permission but we do not have
a market
so we are then going to find the colors
in the other market right but now with
affirmation so you let me know which is
worse not regulate or have a lack in our
regulations because we are scared of the
industry that we do not know or is
instead regulating with clear rules in
my perspective these the crates of the
Supreme Court
means a lot more danger for public scale
that consumers are following a
permission with products that are not
regulated right so only a little bit
about what is happening in Mexico
just adds to that a little bit because
we've been talking about taxes when
talking about total address Walmart day
and you know like 250 to 350 million but
that's just some adult use of medical
side uh Ed when it comes to tax policy I
don't think a regulators and and policy
experts really understand the Health
Market enough to be with that and so but
for perspective
a lot of folks say that have this the
little sisters have been cannabis
when in fact with just some civil uh
market share
adjustments over to hemp substitute
products and Automotive in Plastics uh
in wellness and like the the hemp
industry globally is at a minimum 350
million but 350 billion dollars in total
addressable Market just on 10 prototypes
alone and so if you add the industrial
side of cannabis to the adult use of
medical it's a half Australian to a
trillion dollar market with the T so you
know and so it takes
um policymakers it takes some time to
understand the nuances of the market
that have this really to be more
concerned one inspired or it's graying
and it's couldadians right so people and
policymakers don't necessarily
understand that and so when you're going
into these settings when you're trying
to look at starting a business changing
policies looking at tax rejections and
light you really have to become an
educator before you can become an
influencer
yeah what what other thing about hemp by
the way who's heard of Delta a Fraser
van all right so Delta 8 is a
controversial topic right it's an
intoxicating compound derived from the
head plant
but not the Delta value THC guess what
this is the legal in the United States
there was a ninth circuit federal court
about two months ago that came out and
said Delta e quote of Hope comfortably
fits within the definition of hemp and
the farm bill definition just last week
the DEA came out and it had a chance to
say that Delta 8 was a synthetic counter
and that it was illegal it didn't do
them instead it only talked about thc0
which is a non-naturally occurring
product my point is this is a legal
product in the United States it's also
what I call Red state weed the red
States the conservative states in the
United States they probably won't adopt
the spenceries but they'll allow for
intoxicating compounds repent to be sold
in the marketplace so this is a brand
new very what they have been advised and
it's very challenging
um I want to summarize some things and
then Bo then sort of shipped to you our
part our objective is to sort of talk
about North America and the global
economy talk about some numbers but also
focus on what's happening in Europe on
the taxation piece
we talked about New York perhaps over
tax and over regulate it is an eighth of
an ounce of cannabis will cost you about
70 to 80 dollars are you gonna go buy if
you're a consumer an 80 eighth of
cannabis from a store when the guy that
you've always purchased it from will
sell it to you for 25 or 40. I don't
think so and this is the challenge so
that's one month over tax over regulate
now look at what they did in Iowa this
was years ago this was the first country
I've drafted public policy of over 30
countries around the world in this area
Uruguay was the very first and what they
did was they said we're going to set the
price point per gram below the black
market or the illicit Market Paraguay
the largest illicit marijuana producer
in Latin America sends much much of its
cannabis into Uruguay
well so they set the price at a dollar
fifty per rent
because the black market the pair of
white cannabis was sold at 175 or two
dollars per gram that's one way to
combat it whether that works or not
remains to be seen but it certainly
beats this idea of an 80 date of
cannabis
um Bo let's talk about the exciting
opportunities in Europe uh things now
are focused on an additional end of the
shop
and hold through the uh you have Czech
Republic will be covert and uh as I said
earlier I think check will probably beat
Germany but we'll see it's going to be a
great race uh a really great race the
race is uh uh but let's talk about some
of the DraStic and they have to
Enlightenment earlier
yeah so about like I mentioned earlier
uh from a revenue perspective uh in
Europe is the second largest market in
the world
um and it's split up between medicinal
and then these emerging
um I told use countries and the like
um but from a just a consumption
perspective it's interesting to know
that Italy is actually the largest
market by from a consumption perspective
there's just a lot of votes in in the
Lee that really enjoy this ugh but
what's you know what's the key to these
deployments like in Europe and the
United States and the like and I'm not
sure if we're going to talk about that
now or a little bit but
um the key to a successful regulatory
rollout is having enough Supply in
addition to decent pricing relative to
Alyssa market and access for the
consumers so if one of those three is
out of whack then it really slows down
the pace of Reform the pace of
conversion and the amount of legal
capture that the government and Country
can get
um and so in when I looked at Germany
last year they really don't have enough
domestic Supply to support their rammed
into the adult use space
um and so they're going to have to do
some favor right now they're willing to
persistent to to opening up the market
to foreign suppliers
um and so they're going to struggle and
they're not going to achieve what their
bulls that they're that they're trying
to meet uh meatball
and this uh just the thought of
legalization in Germany has uh driven
policy uh reform in a lot of the
European nations there's about
conversations and during covid for
example the the uh I'm a French police
asked that uh French government to do
more its reform and legalize and get
more supply of cannabis on the market
because it was becoming such a problem
so even the police are asking the
governments to do reform
um in Spain there's um discussions and
abortion
there's they've decriminalized it and so
there's all these oh and then in Italy
they're also looking at at legalizing as
well
um what's similar about in Europe to the
United States is that there's all these
different models for legalization
um and different strategies
um none that's been unified but yet
um in Europe and it's the same thing
that spoke not out yet in uh in the
United States so I think ultimately what
will happen is for once there's enough
momentum now keep in mind there's
sotheby countries in the world now or in
excess of 17 countries that have some
type of legal access to either
cannabinoids adult use or medical so
this is an emerging uh industry that's
accelerating in peace of Reform and I
think Europe is going to be on the
Forefront of that
and may actually
displace the United States from that uh
from a market perspective because
they'll uh they just take a different
approach to Taxation and regulation then
does have been since
the United States the way so I need you
guys need to regulate to United States
push the regulation and then Mexico
follow that right well but it's an
important point for better for worse
than any countries do look at the United
States and they're fearful of that
relationship with the United States uh
particularly Latin America that's my
experience is they don't want to step
outside of U.S policy for fear of losing
relationships business opportunities and
just you know General diplomacy and I
think that that's a major challenge even
the United Nations I was in the Indiana
Austria
four years ago for the committee on
narcotic drugs they were supposed to
make the change they made in November of
last year four years ago but they didn't
because the United States was resistant
so there seems to be this notion that
we're going to wait for the United
States to give us approval but the
United States policy is just so messed
up for lack a better way to put it on
all things cannabis but at the same time
it has the most consumers as bull points
out and perhaps the most robust
Marketplace
um you know there's also there's also oh
go ahead well I was going to say you
know in Canada is federally legal there
and we still haven't seen you know any
of the benefits of Canadian
legalization to spread around the world
and to say hey a [__] is the Canadian
model uh independent other countries and
so it's been a fortunate that it is
still the U.S that drives every and this
is because it is not about regulation
it's about industry it is about the
market you know regulation are only the
the things we need to follow but uh
Regulators need to hear and to
understand the industry in order to
create regulations in accordance for
those markets right
for sure so my
um
shipped a little bit to some of that the
consumer patterns and the markets uh
when we were talking uh you talked a
little bit about
things that don't exist in the
marketplace there's a branding for
products uh product development
um what are some of those opportunity
accounts so if there are folks
participating in the European market
what could they observe to do
differently for hacks from a market said
well yeah one of the things that's been
very successful in the US is Brandy many
of the companies that are on the west
coast you know it's becoming a saturated
Market there uh there's so many
competitors if the only way to stand out
is to have a recognizable brand and so
those companies are now will be Eastward
with their brand also going worldwide
where my client says cookies and they
now have 50 dispensaries across the US
they've opened up one at the UK I want
to be it out one in Tel Aviv and so
they're becoming a worldwide brand uh
like Coca-Cola so that they would be
renty dies no matter what country you're
in and by getting that Grandy people
that gravitate to a sugar Iran
understand that if I'm by a a product
from the I get to serve the fact I like
that fat and still those and go off that
consistency it's like a McDonald's where
he could go anywhere in the world it did
it and have a McDonald's it is going to
be the same
um that's going to be very hard video in
order to you know get confessors and
Elders excited about this company versus
competitor that nobody has heard about
the other thing is is that you know look
across this road it's it's mainly meant
everything in this room today and this
Market is really still geared towards
either 21 to 35 year old millions and
the products serving for that well the
packaging is this is you know geared for
that demographic and so there needs to
be War within in this industry more
products Go With It uh
things that appeal to women and it is
still so male dominated that's some area
that I think is very right
um in Europe and all over the world
really on to you know produce products
that that really would appeal to 50
percent of the Oculus
well from very on any comment that based
on few C markets around what do you
notice in sh's mail driven Pilots female
driven policies they're a is there a
hole in the marketplace
yes I I think it is a whole in Mexico
also we we have a call I think uh that
well for a Buddha for bad these
industrating skiing open by by length
right back then and uh
but it is by the lip and yesterday I was
talking with very that is very like
about uh women
Ming is scared to come in this industry
and that is part of our work right uh
because as I mentioned before every time
you say calories there is a stigma be
quiet and uh
if this is a market that is being
opening by men you know women were like
yes or not and I think this will with
time take the place in the moment you
know uh this is about all countries
starting to regulate and uh women were
trying to come in the industry and the
effects I I saw in other countries in
United States in Latin America I told
her yesterday it is in Mexico we we are
starting to to get together in order for
start pushing companies up but first of
all we need to identify ourselves our
roles in the industry and how we can
play this and guys this is also really
important for you to know and I am
really thank you and I am honored to be
in this panel with you guys this is
really important okay giving us space
for women because we for always we will
have at the point of view than you you
are fine with just your dates and came
with someone you here at human like okay
males we we are we are aggressive we
want to blow out we want to fight and
take money and bring it home right and
women were so careful we build planning
it we we create that the base of the
society right so those two points of
view in one industry are really
important and to make uh also if we're
starting with all these industry to to
give it a a change right
and you said something interesting other
people is where you talked about over
regulation the work over regulation and
God and and sometimes I look at the
existing system and we're looking at
when I call the dispensary system right
the sort of U.S based way of selling
cannabis over the counter which uh is
ultimately the the model that we're
seeing it's adopted verbally
I would suggest we're at the we're at
the 10-year Mark of betadavis industry
and we have to re-evaluate this
dispensory system model because it is
over text it is over regulated we see in
the United States that these companies
are dying left and right because of
being strangled by over-regulation and
over taxation how do you create an
operable Market without forward Taxation
and over
with clear definitions
the program with phc is that THC is a
classified as a controlled synthesis so
till the moment we do not have clear
regulation and not only national
International we need to go to the
Convention of the United Nations of
nurkatrix and drops we need to start
from there to to have a clear regulation
what is the problem with the
overadillation it's that the legislator
as I mentioned before is regulated with
fear and with lack of knowledge but when
you understand that the THC is a
compound that yes it is a secret propane
one but also can improve in other uses
and in other ways the cvd as an example
then you will be able to regulate with
black with no fear and we clear it we
know the statement in the lot that it
that makes me makes me nervous the
stigma in the law the law is a lot a lot
of regulations are only perming to be
following you know the attorneys we
Rizzle up we do not care if the
regulator thinks that THC or more than
what percent of THC is a major major
fully killed problem you know we're only
going to follow what the regulation is
stated so the the the the ovary
deletions came because of the lack of
knowledge and uh how you change Deeds
you need to to see first to the industry
not to regulate because regulate what
happened in Mexico with as a principle
they have been decree why because they
were regulated for regulated only and
this is not the model we need to follow
we need to change this uh I'm word I
mean when I was in Santa Monica I also
elaborate as it is a meal this is what
the first citizen Bill we submitted
reporters in nature for the relation
Federal Regulation of Canada and what do
we did we go with for interviewing each
person in the Cannabis business model
since that registry of the certified sea
heal the
um Wholesales stores that this is a
problem in Mexico the whole sales stores
is a problem because even though it is
legal for industrial pan and for the
medicinal purposes whole step Wholesale
stores and drugs stores are not allowing
these products even those are lid up and
again the problem is stigma the problem
lap of knowledge so we need to see first
the industry what do they need in
accordance for our current regulations
please do not think about a new canaries
Europe is institution and what they are
thinking about it but I am reassured
that we all have Federal Regulation for
all the products of what you need to
regulate is not a crop and eel can be
bothering the the farmers and The
Growers with the controllment of THC and
the pros you need to regulate the prayer
and who is going to use this product
because if the consumer is going to use
this product for medicinal purposes
needs to be a specific relation for that
but if this is for concerns gender like
adult use will lead another regulation
but the first thing we need to see is
the consumers the patients the industry
and then
because of those start to wreck the love
in order to not over regulate with he
that we've already got regulations for
the alpha Hall and tomato and you know
same thing or alkaline tobacco can be
hip to use just like manipus and so
packaging everything has to kind of you
know child-proof packaging you know with
under 21 could purchase the product I
mean certain basic regulations then are
in tobacco and and alcohol should be
adopted for cannabis and and everything
is already there you know so all the
regulations for for alcohol this you
know it's already there bonded where
else security of the product you know as
it moves from one place to another place
uh at the even the taxes you know do you
have a low excise tax that now hunt the
illicit Market out of business because
no one goes around leaning after you go
around and say hey I know somebody
they'll sell you a bottle of vodka
cheaper than at the store that's around
the fort Middleton back we just go to
the store we buy the vodka we pay the
tax I had nobody this is too concerned
about
so it develop some models
um
re-examining the dispensary model
and because like I said earlier it's an
up Supply it's the amount of access in
this price and so if you live at the
access through the century model they
may don't get as much legal
participation so I looked at this model
where you just open it up you tax it
either like album Hall you regulated it
kind of like tobacco or alcohol in in
the sense that you had labeling and you
check IDs but then putting it into
grocery stores and gas stations and
everything else
the the amount of conversion
um was enormous the amount of
opportunities for
products and Brands inspires into space
was enormous and it really did away with
the list work very quickly so opening it
up giving high volume access to more
consumers was really a viable model that
mapsolize tax revenue minimize the
impact of the Alyssa warranty got people
participating and didn't necessarily
have as much of the public health impact
as as has been stated by other policy
managers so there are alternative models
out there that one can use to really
maximize that the industry and give
tremendous opportunities for four people
and so babe
down
lesson nonsense
enforcement for subjury now that you
went there yourself saying compared to
aldol Capo and you know let's say it's
dirty in the baby wrote the world
everybody was also that wants to replace
it it was smart like they wouldn't
collaborate they wouldn't replace it so
um
we should look back to what prohibition
enters also polar Builder but how it was
because the high CHC is basically what
absent was an alcohol when uh I think
Molly was called whatever so alcohol
today is taxed in different
um Tears by actually alcohol percentage
so the thing that we don't want in
cannabis so we say outrageous is
actually a practice all over Europe
every European country has a 15 32
percent 30 percent of alcohol different
taxation something to keep in mind a
different point I'd love to know your
opinion on it uh branding you're only
telling half the truth about cookies
cookies is building a bread not in the
in the dispensaries cookies is building
a brand in the streets cook is this uh
pirated all over the world we have
cookies packs 10 co-packs and jungle
boys packs in the streets this is where
the brands are being made credibility is
created for recreational in the streets
not in the stores and cookies is
probably the only brand also I've been
to Toronto lately there is no brand
loyalty in Canada cookies is just
another store so I just want to question
a little bit of this and then see what
your reaction would be and um just yeah
really look real thank you
hey I think you know it it's really both
ways I mean you have to have some sort
of crazy that creates that recognition
um but hey it's way it's been successful
at least in the U.S you know in terms of
competitors because you know since it's
up right but in Market each state is the
zone of regulations you have to get your
own license and everything uh so that by
having a brand that is recognized from
East Coast the West Coast at recently be
rest it's been very successful should it
without seeing in terms of branding as
well is that they're starting to Brand
views for experiences within the brat
and so you may have a coffees I don't
know a whole lot about cookies but you
may have something that is targeted
experience to that Stalker mod and
there's a targeted experience to you
know somebody going out and and doing uh
activities sports activities and there's
other uh user experiences branding
related students just chilling out
watching a load and so I'm starting to
see this converting to where their
branding and a diffuser experience and
as long as that they have consistent
products that meet those consumer
expectations then they develop really
good and durable Grand loyalty cousin
you know out of the David
uh things they're trying to be like
Supreme is you know as this high-end you
know um
Urban brand and lifestyle and and the
the Cannabis products are just part of
that why and uh this is an important
date because before United standing in
school all the other rally regulated for
adult years they are they already have a
brat you know this is a really good
marketing strategy to start building a
brand without a regulation maybe but you
know that cookies will be related with
other use but really recreational use at
easterner program but also they are
selling T-shirts that they are creating
a brand they are creating a light stop
run and wait the recruit the the
regulation come they will be ready they
will be already there right so so why
has cookies been able to expand so
rapidly as something that's in our head
which is a very good question it's
because then use a licensing mod this
goes to Mike's corn about rib
cookies there are some exceptions to
what I'm going to say but cookies
doesn't aluminance cultivation cookies
doesn't have its own licenses cookies
doesn't own its stores cookies just
licenses that need and puts requirements
in plates and yes I get your exceptions
to that rule but that's how they've been
able to expand so rapidly so to
everyone's Point here is they've
developed a Lifestyle brand they've
developed the brand does that brand
start on the streets sure it does you
have to go to the consumers right you
have to go to the consumers and of
course the other thing about cannabis
because especially what they're looking
at intellectual property laws IP laws
whether there's a copy Mark copyrights
trademarks or other forms of patents
um a lot of those laws don't necessarily
allow protection of certain cannabis
IP be chosen the fact that it's
federally illegal in the United States
and not exactly believable or strictly
in most other the jurisdictions so it's
hard to protect those things but I do
think that this is the low-hanging fruit
so to speak the initial stages of the
industry are how do you attract existing
cannabis users away from the illicit
Market into the regulated commercial
market for tax generation otherwise
that's step one then step two becomes
how do you attract new users how do you
sub classify users and make a more
sophisticated product a more
sophisticated brand for someone who does
want to identified with the person on
the street that's the cookies culture
for example all of these things are
evolving and it's really really
interesting to watch
um not even another question
how did that
good morning
great problem just uh how to be nayser
but the the statement that both should
rest still or any file Alcatel on me how
tobacco that's their fat model issue how
to fly that's
um
that's enough research absolutely what
the copper is this number one you see in
tobacco it's hidden more and more
restricted to the point where even they
think which should not the Bible just
make me is now being you know really
anti is very attack out of the looks the
big house nicotine countries such a
prismatic bubble they didn't have a real
politically double covered from the
armpitas so and the other issue helped
them out the beauticians team carried up
want is that they regulated you for
about orbit Health Focus so to say hey
where have we got a rock but I thought
maybe we're pursue it gets too
normalized and maybe we have this
restrict alcohol too and the bottlene
grant risk and public health is around
that restriction of alcohol when you see
it across world and Hamlet is a pretty
simple where for example
destroyed by capitalist dried Collision
skit cattle they tell the scores they
hit go outer knife style around it is
versus illegal upon a camera you know
formalizations did is to be mad so this
walking very very careful around this
idea of this state regulation from other
risket clouds
and a lot of that goes on as well that
goes to this notion that the regulations
prohibit advertising and jurisdictions
are severely limited uh and they they
prevent what a they store to do as the
treats it differently than any other
store and you can't just go out and
advertise and Market it in brand
um so it was about your points are very
little to you uh does that know what
happened please feel free to keep asking
questions with yes sir
dispensaries so and we agree this is the
case in the CBD Market where there's
groupies out there your consensus having
problems which supported detained CBD in
a very little and air he's eat that to
be combated and then resolves industry
run across the the social consumer has
the balance in the products and they're
just not going to buy it
yeah I'll come and that's about to jump
in here but when I would tell you this I
would say that the uh yes in the
marijuana industry it's in your interest
to produce the highest potency product
at the lowest price point because that
is the basic marketplace right now but
one of the reasons why Delta 8 hhc these
have derived intoxicates are thriving in
the U.S and around the world is because
consumers don't want
to get this High consumers don't like
paranoia consumers don't want to walk
into a dispensary they want something
that's more like a glass of wine versus
a shot of whiskey so there's a major
difference out there in terms of
consumer behavior and you have to figure
out what your Market is but would you
care to elaborate on that a little bit
so that
it depends to find the market and the
and the rape and story structure in
terms of testing too high or testing too
little and Turks and THC content because
in the market in some states
that you get more price per pound per
ounce per gram for a higher THC the
product and so there's testing inflation
that's occurring because you know you
want your brand to have the highest
amount of CHC and then at other states
where and jurisdictions where they're
testing on the percentage of THC then
there's that incense it for those to be
lower now when you think of policy
around Taz what does tax do it either
incentivizes or subsidizes something to
do uh to do something more or it
punishes to do something less like you
hide taxes on cigarettes uh produced
less consumption so right now there's
not a really good strategy on how to tax
this because they the The Regulators and
the tax policy makers really don't know
what they want out of this they just
want the money right and so they don't
have effective strategies yet
um on you know what is the purpose of
all of this right and so they're they're
creating distortions in the market uh
and then like I said on the uh on the
CPE side
um you know that's been in the United
States at least relatively unregulated
so there hasn't been any labeling truth
and label truth and products or anything
like that so there's groups out there
that that test and rigorously test their
Fridays I'm in summons subscribers six
times throughout the process and then
there's others that barely tested at all
if that if at all and so you've got
because of the lack of Regulation and
oversight you've got this Market out
there that's kind of out of the Wild
West it's a peripheral
and so a lot of the
um the hemp deride cannabinoid producers
and suppliers and retailers they
actually want to be regulated
um but just like you said you just don't
want to be too regulated or regulated
like a schedule one truck you know so uh
so it just depends upon what the
objective is and when the market is as
to whether or not you're going to see
inflation and met testing or deflation
of the testing and the like
question
writing about regular special
take evidence
she kind of bow was going on currently
then that the church
there's a big house of lay awesome the
major three zero in with about
um
the microphone you know going to this
period in Salvation
we're going to be some you know players
that are going to drive through boothy
that is getting down during the Denver's
industry
going to come from
you think you know who's going to be the
most aggressive type players do you
think would be you know big tobacco
Pharma uh big alcohol perhaps uh Equity
firms uh what are your thoughts and and
because we're running out of time here
I'd like everybody to sort of hit this
question and we can sort of round this
out that that works
um I'll tell you that like I just wrote
an article later in a first call I wrote
an article in force where I compare the
first 10 years of the tech industry to
the first 10 years in the Cannabis
industry and IT addresses some of these
points uh but think of this when the
bubble burst at the tech and the tech
Boogle we didn't know who Google was we
nibble that is on was those things
didn't exist at that time so those
people after 10 years of the decade
usually went this is over it's all over
all of these people who's going to be
the winner or the losers the point is
you'll know the winners and the losers
are going to be in Canada because
everyone has to keep trying and it's way
too soon in my business
iron Sage she found that the wiener will
be down at Company
cool
achieves to integrate
social versions of Liberty
uh Excellence marketing strategy
this company needs to be one of the
first ones because as we think with
example cookies I argument in these
arguments but there are one of the first
ones
and uh this company needs to see
what
under what uh we're being through in
other markets in order to repeat those
mistakes right
[Music]
these needs to be arrested these
ruptique company
which is believed by
by new and German
Minds boiler all the tires listening to
the folders and uh and and learning
about the others you know but uh
Kennedy's these are these this ruptic
Market in in all our around the world
and this is the reason why we are here
so I know
I I think the ones are in Dubai to can
succeed are going to need the ones that
have been managed good you know many
people forget that astique jobs you know
started apple and built up into a
billion dollar company and then he was
fired by the board because great
Visionary but not an executed NBA you
know to run a billion dollar Enterprise
and many of these stand-up these are
being grounded by inexperienced people
and and that's going to be changing it
and we're seeing it now where Ford War
uh people from the food and beverage
industry are coming into the market
they're demanding first like Horrors to
produce data analytics for them to say
how much is this product selling Thing
Worth am I making money on this what's
my margin you know but what's my
inventory what's my uh all these things
that they need to know about their
company in order to run it you know
efficiently and I think those the ones
that are going to succeed along with the
ones that have access to council because
right now it's very difficult for
gambler's companies to obtain gecko when
you can go ahead and invest in a Fortune
500 companies right now that
down from their historic High stock
plates so I think that that's with two
things that are gonna you know outline
of this you know in the next 10 years
I've said in uh for years now that and
that redefining factors in the Canada
space will be
branding
scale and Supply Chain management and so
if you can manage your brand get your
brand out there if you can scale it out
if you can manage your costs to where
you're we're made profitable then you're
going to be successful in this case uh
with respect to the jobs and the layoffs
is to me is a natural flow
what cannabis represents as an industry
in heck of Alliance is called an
entrepreneurial events and so there's an
opportunity to achieve higher than
normal profits and when you achieve
those and everybody wants in and so
you've seen some people early on that
had the problems but then everybody
jumped in and took all the profits out
um and so what um what results from that
when everybody enters in this it drives
down a drop ability and it drives down
your margins and then dead thinks
consolidate so you know there's this you
know period of
multi-phases of of uh expansion and
consolidation expansion consolidation
and I think that we're just in the
earlier phases of this right now and
then uh I'm producing a Joshua court and
uh this and conjunction with Leafly
every year we co-author Joshua fork and
what we're seeing is that a similar to
what occurred in Canada out of early on
with this expansion and installed
capacity for production capabilities and
the light you saw that a bit with the
multi-state operators of the United
States where they wanted to go into
these new larfix between that the demand
will grow
and they installed the capacity but now
realizing that there's been a little bit
of a reset in the market
they don't mean to hire us to staff that
capacity and so they're they're just
laying in weight but meanwhile because
the market is it is starting to compress
from a margin perspective and they are
started starting to have to cut costs
and so
um we're seeing that there were jobs
added in 2022 but there was a lot they
wouldn't add it more but I did not been
for the layoffs and other downsizing
approaches as large of MSS
okay if I do some job but thank you to a
wonderful people
with me and we're going to complete this
first session