[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I'm delighted to
join in this episode by Keat bushfield
who's the CEO Rex's biotech how you
keeping today Kei good and yourself I'm
very well thank you very much thank you
for taking your time to do this can you
maybe give everybody a little overview
of your career today and how you found
yourself a rexus
biotech yeah it's you know serial
entrepreneur came out of school and
realized uh you know I didn't want to go
down a law school path I didn't want to
go down some of the things that I
thought were predetermined for me so I
really got in the entrepreneurial space
did a lot of different things and then I
started a biotech firm in
2009 and that managed to morph into
another thing and another thing
approached by a few different companies
to say what could we use our technology
or could we use our technology in
cannabis so we started to do some
experimentation um and here we are so in
2002 or sorry
2022 uh rexis was founded um and it took
multiple Technologies from different uh
entities from different people put them
together to produce what we do today so
we are a biotech firm um that really
specializes in taking hydrophobic
molecules molecules that don't
assimilate in water and having them
assimilate in water so a thing like
cannabis is a perfect example uh we can
take that hydrob molecule stick it into
our process comes out the other end in a
fine white powder and that powder is now
fully stable in water so we remove taste
smell a lot of the profiles that are
off-putting with cannabis but at the
same time keeping a lot of the
mechanisms for efficacy and so
forth so we kind of knew from the start
of the beverage side of the industry
that the cannaboid molecules were either
sticking to aluminium or were settling
in a specific part of the can so you
guys are part of this new wave of
Technology that's allowing the
cannaboids to distribute throughout the
product and give an exact kind of dosage
correct correct the biggest problem with
the I'll call it cannabis beverages 1.0
or 2.0 or three we're probably on to you
know round 20 by now but the original
companies the early companies either
just put oil into the beverage which is
just like salad dressing Salad
addressing oil in water it floats to the
top doesn't assimilate tastes terrible
all the things that are bad with that
then they got more sophisticated and
they use sonification High Shear a whole
bunch of different things that have been
in the pharmaceutical industry for years
problem is it used a surfactant so a
surfactant is basically just a chemical
some are more organic base than others
but it's still just a chemical you use
that surfactant to bond the molecule to
water so it's just an artificial way to
hold it together the problem with
surfactants they come apart so they
don't hold very well it doesn't take
long for them to separate so the other e
the other issue with those is the flavor
is very off-putting that chemical that
goes in there uh it's hard to deal with
so in the old days you would get colas
or root beer or other coffee things to
try and hide the Cannabis flavor so with
our technology we use our trade name is
fused polymorph nanofiber so we make a
co- Crystal of the Cannabis molecule so
we make multiple molecules fused
together in a permanent fuse so they
don't come apart so you can take our
ingredient put it into water put it into
a beverage or whatever you're going to
use put it into food uh and it will not
separate over time so we've got uh
pharmaceutical studies twoyear stability
in water without separation so pretty
well unheard of in the industry and
that's I think why our um path to growth
has been so fast because we have this
that's different than everybody else and
I think that's where the market needs to
go you know just like in every industry
we limp along until we make some
breakthroughs in different Industries or
different Technologies and so forth and
I think that's where we're at so we're
starting to see other companies dabble
and trying to make it better but uh you
know I the beverage space is where the
growth is happening uh the Cannabis has
been around in a bunch of different
Industries before this but it was
limited I think from technology but now
we've introduced this technology it's
growing at light
speed it seems to be the first wave of
the Canabis industry was
cultivated flour extraction equipment
and it's it doesn't seem that the first
mover Advantage is going to end up
working in this industry it seems to be
that the reluctance for a lot of big
Brands to get into this was a the
ingredient of a cannaboid where biotech
companies are now are able to use
fermentation engineering to make this
molecule stfe Sable replicable over
again and you guys are delivering the
mechanism for the distribution of the
product so would it be writing saying
that the future of the industry after
this wave is the brands the the people
who can come up at the brands tell the
stories and connect with their customer
bases uh I think you couldn't put it any
better I couldn't put in any better than
what you just said I've been preaching
this since
201617 there was this mad rush for
everybody to be cultivator oh we got a
license I spent a million dollars for
this one 10 million for that I got a
license I said from day one it's a
commodity as soon as we get economies a
scale whoever sells the best for the
cheapest amount of money will continue
to sell it and there will be zero profit
margin left I use this example take
Budweiser I have no idea who makes the
Hops or the grain or the sugar or the
canning facil I don't know any of that
but I know Budweiser and I don't care
who made all the other stuff but the
brand is what is worth the money so you
have situations like Canada where Canada
eliminated branding and that was a big
mistake for their industry because if
you can't if all the packages have to
look the same there's no branding
differentiation so branding of a product
in that scenario maybe is equal but in
the rest of the world or primarily in
the United States right now branding is
starting to become the most key place so
we're starting to see branding that
doesn't look like the old cannabis
branding where you know somebody was
high and built that now it is fullon
like you know we we make products that
look like you know full retail off the
shelf Coca-Cola made this so it's
getting away from the oldfashioned way
building a brand that has a long life
building a brand that is resonates with
people and key which I think is the
brand is not a fringe anymore I had a
discussion with someone recently about
gummies and they said oh gummies are
outpaced beverages always will and I
said well I don't think so because
gummies yes have been around for a long
time but gummies are associated with
children's vitamins or vitamins now
they're associated with cannabis and not
a lot of other things but when someone
says oh I had a gummy the first thing
comes to mind is oh I snuck a gummy and
I had cannabis with it the person that
doesn't know about cannabis and all that
has that reputation of or that image of
what cannabis and gummies are going to
be however if I give someone one of
these we've been drinking rtds ready to
drink beverages our entire lives I can
drink this this is now a transition
between between someone that's never
tried cannabis and someone that has
someone that can try 5 milligram dose
it's like drinking a beer it has a
slight intoxicating it's it's not crazy
you're not you know eating too because
the first one didn't work and looking at
purple dinosaurs 45 minutes later and
wondering what happened so we don't want
that the other thing is the old adage of
I want to get someone as high as I
possibly can we don't go by that we
don't build drinks that are more than
five or 10 milligrams it's kind of our
own company model
and the big guys that we work with the
biggest alcohol brands in the world they
have said to us why would I possibly
want someone to have a 100 milligram
drink I want them to have five so I can
sell them five in an evening instead of
selling them one it makes no sense so
we're starting to see the old cannabis
religion of you know that that get
everybody's high as possible starting to
dissipate especially when it's come to
mainstream and that mainstream brings
the brands and I can tell you I can't
tell you who but I can tell you the
biggest brands we work with and they are
coming like a freight train and people
don't realize it yet but it all those
purists that were like oh keep the
Pepsis and cokes and an heisers out of
the business forget it that's coming and
that's coming
strong yeah and I seem to think most
people are overlooking that consumer 55
60 plus that actually are looking for
alternatives to the C current uh methods
that they're taking for various
different en ailments that the people
who can tell the brands to those stories
and as you said the micro does nobody
wants at that age to be uh feeling
uncomfortable after consuming a product
in any way shape or form absolutely
without question it's uh it's
a you know if there's two things that
have changed and with our technology
that have really changed the market
speed to use the old days like I kind of
alluded there with the purple dinosaur
and you were so high you didn't know
what was going on a gummy hits 45
minutes later you know and some of these
companies are doing Nano fibers which we
have Nano in our name but that's just as
part of the process Nano 99.9% of the
time is just a bunch of BS you know it
doesn't mean anything they can't hold
that that Nano particle that size anyway
so some have come up with a better
faster way to make it work but not
really you know we did University of
Mississippi studies we did a bunch of
Trials to see how fast we could do this
we got it in the bloodstream in less
than five minutes so you feel it
very quickly and that's the big thing
how can we control offset and offset so
if I can have a drink make it work
really fast I have a lower dose that's
going to change the industry in terms of
what people believe is a realistic dose
people aren't scared to try it they can
have that dose that be accurate every
single time and that is a big reason why
also the industry hasn't exploded yet
and I think that's where it's starting
to go because now the technology will
dick that the big Brands like that don't
have to worry that they can build a
brand they can build a product or so I
should say they can build a brand around
the technology that will be long term I
want to talk a little bit about your
fuse polymorph fiber technology can you
maybe explain a little bit what was the
time frame for or&amp; D it looks like it
was reading three years and uh was that
three successful years or three roller
coaster of emotion
years uh yeah I think they're always
roller coasters um you know we had some
aha moments along the way and I'd even
argue that it's been longer than three
years if you took all the little pieces
together
um the gist of that technology is we
went at it completely different than
everybody else went at it and I think
that's just probably from some sure luck
and ignorance as to what everybody else
was doing because I think if we as a
team knew what everybody else was doing
we would try to mimic that but because
we went into a blind
we went in for from a pharmaceutical
side a biotech side that said look I
don't think that other way works there's
got to be a better way to do it so yes
you had some trials tribulations we did
have some very immediate success not to
the degree that we have now so you know
it's like going to the casino and you
won right away you're going to stick
around a little bit longer and see how
it goes and so you know three four five
six years later you know here we are so
um the nanofiber is without question a
game changer um I think people that know
us have used it have said how much
different it is the biggest issues with
an Emulsion as we talked about which is
what everybody but us uses in a beverage
it's basically just a liquid you took
cannabis and you put it in a
sonification device you made the
particles shatter a little bit you put a
surfactant with it put it with water and
you drop some of those drops in your
beverage mix it up and there you have it
within minutes it's stuck to the wall
within minutes it started degrade all of
the things that go with it and for the
entire time it tastes terrible it's hard
to hide that surfactant Flavor now I I
will go with some of our groups that are
out there we call them competitors we
don't really do what they do but you
know they've got better but they're not
there yet so ours is so much different
we take multiple molecules we fuse them
together they're permanently fused and
now they're stable you can take our
ingredient our powder stick it in a
sealed bag so the oxygen doesn't get to
it two years later it has almost 100%
the potency it had before it started if
you take a distillate and do that you're
going to lose 30 40% in a matter of 30
to 45 days so we suspend that animation
you might call it so it can sit on that
shelf and wait and then used when it's
needed and when we put it into water we
get the same we had a six-month
stability test on THC in a can and we
lost about 4% in potency over six months
in a can I I want say the name I know
two larger players that they have to
overdose their cans before they get
tested and then they have to wait three
days then get it tested then on that
third or fourth day make sure they test
it so that it all comes up with the
right levels the problem is this one
company had something go wrong with
metric system they had to enter it into
the Cannabis system they had to retest
it and only seven days later it didn't
pass because it degrades that fast F so
the consumer gets a beverage that says
it has 5
milligrams if they didn't buy that
beverage for 30 days the thing has like
maybe two milligrams in it so that's not
fair to the consumer either yeah it
passed testing when it left the lab but
that's the big thing too we don't have
those issues and I think that's what's
changing the industry too you know the
technology is starting to build the
brands that will get involved and that's
what makes that polymorph nanofiber so
different it's very exciting and I have
no doubt it's h going to be one for all
the viewers of this show to watch that
the big brands are coming to Beverages
and it's because of companies like yours
and the team that you're building at
rexus biotech so Keith I know you're a
very busy man so I won't keep it too
much longer but thank you very much for
your time and hopefully we get to touch
base in the next 12 months and we have a
few updates from you of where the
industry is heading absolutely anytime I
love talking about what we do so uh
thank you for having me on I appreciate
it thank you very much for anybody who
wants to know more about Rex's biotech
you can see the website below it'll be
in the description where you're hearing
or watching this anywhere um for now
thank you very much and see you next
[Music]
episode