foreign
by Ruth Fisher who's the principal at
quanta she's an economist with a passion
for understanding how components of
systems work together to create outcomes
how are you keeping today Ruth Oh I'm
great how are you I'm fantastic I've
been looking forward to having a chat
with you now since we announced this um
can you maybe give everybody a quick
little overview of how you came to set
up quanta and how you ended up touching
on the Cannabis industry
um so I'm an economist and I spent a lot
of time in uh I I started out doing a
supporting expert testimony as to
damages from infringement and I was
working on a lot of technology and
especially biotech and healthcare
industry uh projects
um and I left the industry to start
quanta because I was very interested in
the fact that when I was working with
firms the information that I got tended
to come in very piecemeal from different
companies so I would go in and need to
do certain analyzes and I would say okay
in order to understand the environment
here I need this information and this
information and this information and
what happened invariably is the
companies would say okay for this piece
of information talk to this guy and for
this information talk to this guy and
for that information talk to that guy
and I would put everything together and
get a much more comprehensive and to me
more uh
just a better understanding of what was
going on in the company and I figured
that if I started my own company I could
help companies kind of piece together
this information give them a more
complete vision of what was going on in
their environment and help them more
strategically Advance their uh their
projects or products or whatever it is
that they were offering so that's kind
of how quanta came to be
I came to cannabis in about 2015 because
my brother was diagnosed with multiple
sclerosis and he was having a very
difficult time
alleviating his his neuropathic induced
his neuropathic pain from Cannabis and
one of his doctors at some point said
you know I think you might be able to
benefit from Cannabis but I can't give
you any guidance so he's kind of thrown
out there he was he was excited to
finally have something new to try
because he would he had tried everything
so he's started using cannabis and at
some point he realized that he was
getting some effects but if he knew what
he was doing he would probably be
getting better effects
so given my background in in healthcare
and under in market research and
understanding how to gather information
and put it together in a helpful uh way
he turned to me and said you know I'm
using cannabis I'm getting some results
I think I could get better results if I
knew what I was doing so can you help me
figure this out
so at that point I came to cannabis and
I literally had zero understanding of
the plant the product how it worked
anything
um it was it was a very uh interesting
experience for me
I jumped in I said I'm just gonna try
and figure this out uh I just started
reading everything it's it's a very
perhaps the most complex industry I've
ever been involved with
um it took me a long time to finally
kind of understand what was going on and
it was very interesting to me because
there's so much information out there
and I know that I I talk about this
regularly and everyone seems to have the
same problem is people who are new to
cannabis they start trying to find
information and it's really hard to
understand what's going on and and what
to believe there's there's good
information there's misinformation
there's disinformation there's kind of
everything out there
um and it took me a while and I think
perhaps what helped me most to
understand the information in cannabis
in the industry
is that you have a lot of different
people who are in the industry and
they're providing information they're
providing products and services and
advice and everything from their
particular perspective
so you have you have the traditional
healthcare industry and the traditional
healthcare industry they're very
skeptical and the early literature
everyone was very anti-cannabis and
everything is focusing on the dangers of
cannabis
um and then only more recently are they
focusing on doing research on how
cannabis actually works then you have
kind of the traditional Legacy people
and they're talking about whole plant
cannabis and they're providing a really
a lot of really good information on the
plant and whole plant products which are
diametrically opposed to the isolate
model that the traditional healthcare
industry are presenting
uh you have a lot of casual users who
some of them have good information some
don't you have a lot of naysayers out
there who are trying to kind of torpedo
cannabis in any way they can so for me
one of the biggest lessons I've learned
in the industry is to try and figure out
what perspective what's the background
of that person who's providing the
information and that will help you kind
of figure out what context to put that
information in so that that was
definitely very helpful for me
um
but so once I started understanding how
cannabis was working and I was I was
giving the information to my brother and
he was using it and lo and behold it was
working and that was just really
fantastic and we decided to
um
try and and kind of put together a more
systematic view of cannabis to help
other people we started developing a
technology it didn't end up kind of
going very far
um but
um so after that I was continuing on and
became very passionate about education
and and education and promoting medical
cannabis and promoting access to people
who uh who've been kind of not able to
be served well by the traditional
Community which there are a lot of those
in cannabis unfortunately
but at the same time as an economist and
as someone very interested in market
dynamics and Technologies I've also been
looking at the industry and following
its path of evolution and in particular
it's a highly regulated industry and how
are the the regulations shaping the way
that the industry is evolving in the way
that firms are supplying products which
products are they supplying what are the
prices
um
um what type of competition is out there
and I've also been really really
fascinated by all the different
Technologies in cannabis and kind of
which ones are emerging and
[Music]
um
so that's kind of where I am right now
yeah the Cannabis industry seems to be
one of the industries that everybody has
their own personal point of view and I
think a highly accomplished people like
yourself especially in The Economist
side of things are parliament of this
industry actually getting some validity
and being able to cut you shall we say
the [ __ ] of a lot of the stuff that
you hear in the Cannabis industry around
so it's an absolute pleasure to talk to
you I'm going to move on to the first
topic which is cannabis The Mulch and
Technology can you maybe give everybody
a little overview of your recent
Publications on this technology and what
it is that you found
sure so um I I was looking reading about
how uh beverages are now perhaps one of
the fastest growing categories product
types in cannabis and and I and I
thought that was very interesting
because all of a sudden beverages are
kind of the it product and I'm like well
beverages have been out there before so
why now are they just being uh becoming
successful and so I started researching
in that and it turns out that what's
really important in beverages are the
Emulsion Technologies and again I was
kind of puzzled because I know Emulsion
Technologies are nothing new so I kind
of did some research there and I
discovered that Emulsion Technologies in
general first started becoming
commercially available in the early
1900s and they were being used primarily
in the food industry but in other
Industries as well so that's that's been
a hundred years now so you know why are
our cannabis beverages only Now new so
after the the traditional Emulsion
Technologies in around the 60s
um 50s 60s 70s you had micro Emulsion
Technologies and those were an
improvement in enhancement on on the
earlier stuff
um and those those uh did allow for very
small particle sizes and again well now
that's the 60s it's still you know 60
years so why is it new well then you
have the Nano Emulsion Technologies and
those improved upon the micro Emulsion
Technologies but those were the late 90s
so again 20 years they've been around
and it I just I kept digging and it was
more and more of a mystery and so
um it took some I went into the patent
database and I was looking at the timing
of the patents to see when the
technology started first becoming
available and so you you had the Nano
nanotech patents in the late 90s started
coming around
um and I was very baffled and um it
wasn't until I was reading some
um some papers by industrial Sono Sono
mechanics I believe is the company
um and everything became clear then and
what happened was is you had early uh
Technologies with so so no Emulsion is
basically so cannabis is is soluble in
oil not water so if you create a
beverage what you're doing is you're
taking a cannabis extract which is an
oil-based product and mixing in a
water-based beverage and so what happens
is is the canvas extract the oil stuff
was globbing in the beverage and it was
kind of sticking to the can and so that
was really problematic it wasn't mixing
up and if you take you know it didn't
taste very good the canvas extract is
very bitter
um and there's a big problem with it
because it's not homogeneous in the can
if you have say a 10 milligram uh can of
uh a beverage and you drink half the can
you're not getting half the dose
and in canvas this is a big deal uh
where you need to be able to dose kind
of in a very predictable way and so
um in a classic Emulsion technology uh
the problem is as I said so the oils
globbing in the water and generally what
you want to do is you want to break up
the oil into smaller pieces so it mixes
more homogeneously
um in in the water and they couldn't get
that in cannabis and while what you can
do is you can shake the can very
vigorously and then it kind of you know
you get a nice Emulsion but then it very
quickly separates again so it wasn't
stable and so what a good Emulsion
technology will do it will do two things
it will break the Cannabis Globs into
very very small particles
but then importantly very importantly it
will coat each of the each of the
molecules or the particles rather
in a substance called a surfactant or an
emulsifier and so by coating the small
particles then you keep them from
re-coalescing or re-separating out again
and so this is these two factors being
able to create small molecule sizes and
also coat them to keep them separate is
the challenge of the technology and the
micro Emulsion Technologies and the the
nanotech Technologies both were enabling
this but not very greatly so the earlier
Technologies what happens is they would
put the surfactant into the the Cannabis
and the beverage and it would cause the
molecules to break up but you needed a
whole lot of surfactant to do this and
you needed more surfactant than the
cannabis extract concentrate in there
which means
the the the uh surfactants don't taste
very good and so it just didn't work it
wasn't stable you could get stability
but it just it didn't taste good
um
and it was only and this is kind of the
big thing and this long-winded way of
getting there but the really big thing
is only very recently have they been
able to have these technologies that are
forcing rather than just kind of relying
on the chemical breakdown of the
particles into small sizes they're using
a technology to force
um the the breakup
of the cannabis oil into very small
particle sizes and by using the
technology to force the breakup they can
now use much much less surfactant on
there
and so now you have these very very
small particle sizes
um and much lower amounts of surfactants
and
um so the two now work together and it's
creating homogeneous beverages that are
translucent so they don't look Gloppy
um it's mixing up nicely and you're
getting
um very importantly in cannabis you're
getting not only better dosing so you
can drink half the can and get half the
content but also you're getting improved
bioavailability and traditionally in
cannabis if you use if you ingest
cannabis orally you get a really really
low bioavailability on the order of say
five percent
um but with these new technologies
you're by increasing by decreasing the
particle size you're getting it's it's
passing through your system it's not
getting destroyed in the stomach by the
acids and it's getting absorbed by your
intestines in a much better better so
um it's these technologies have only
been around for the last couple of years
and it's creating a whole new areas for
Beverages and other forms of edible uh
cannabis products which I think is just
going to cause explosive growth in the
future
yeah being able to feel the results
quicker and faster I think is the core
objective of a lot of these Brands and
it's no different that the most popular
brand that we know of is canned drinks
and they're using sources technology and
I think it seems to be that these brands
that create this Emulsion technology are
actually going to be some of the main
winners when it comes to the whole
entire industry
uh yeah I
they're
it appeals to both casual users the
whole like cocktail crowd who want to
use canvas like they use you know
alcoholic beverages but also buy the
whole medicinal group who want to you
know wrap and rate of onset wants to be
able to do very clean dosing
um and have very you know palatable
products
and before we finish up what are the
things you're looking forward to seeing
in the industry happen over the next 12
to 24 months do you think Federal
legalization is going to end up rocket
boosting the industry and the technology
into the next level
I
I was just reading this morning how
um they're talking about legalization by
the end of the year
um I don't know that it's going to
happen that quickly I think that there's
so much politics and there's so many so
many groups out there who have such a
strong interest against canvas
legalization
um so I don't want to make any
predictions but I think it's going to
take longer than uh people hope
um I also want to note there's a lot of
talk about how the industry is going to
consolidate very quickly and this is
another area that I've been looking at
and I worry about competition I think
that we need we need all the little guys
out there we need the craft cannabis and
we need all the small businesses to
promote variety because Variety in
cannabis is so important for so many
reasons and all the regulations I see
have been very problematic and that they
create they create a very difficult
environment for small business is to
thrive so I hope the legislation helps
protect small businesses and creates a
viable environment for them
um
I also the other thing I really worry
about is that
um recreational or adult use cannabis is
going to swamp medical and it's going to
squeeze it out and I think that that
when Federal legalization comes they
really need to have a very clear curve
out to promote and maintain
um products and services geared
specifically towards medical cannabis
patients uh and and so those are I don't
know where regulations are going I don't
know when it's going to come I think
it's going to come later than people
think I think it's going to take longer
for the industry to settle than people
think
um and what I really really hope for is
protections for small businesses and
medical cannabis
yet it's been highly informative chattan
chi I could wish the episodes for 30
minutes long because there's so much
more we could touch on but I couldn't
agree with you more I think that the the
entrepreneurs with a strong brand and an
exact target consumer as opposed to a
scattergun blanket approach are going to
be the ones that are hopefully around
for the long term
you know what what I think could really
do it for them is by enabling direct to
Consumer uh marketing and I've been
reading also about the wine industry and
the wine industry they do direct to
Marketing sales and that's very
important you know to to enable small
Wineries and I think that they really
need to do that and they've explicitly
prohibited at least here in California
but I think they really need to enable
it and that that would really really
help
yeah I couldn't agree with you more
um as I said I'd love to talk even
further with you but the episodes are
very short and brief to the point
hopefully we can touch base again in a
couple of months and we might have some
more information to be able to chat on
for anybody who hasn't checked out
quanta.com I highly recommend it if
you're not following our LinkedIn with
root on LinkedIn again you're missing
out on some top tier knowledge and data
so Ruth thank you very much for taking
your time to do this it's been very much
appreciated
thank you very much for having me and
and thank you for promoting good
cannabis
thank you Ruth have a great day and chat
to everybody on the next episode
[Music]