[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannas review i'm delighted to be
joined on this episode by dr adan
desalas ki
how are you keeping it down here well
very good how are you owen every time
we're delighted to have you on the show
so i know you graduated in biology
especially specializing in neurobiology
can you maybe give everybody a quick
overview of how you got into the
cannabis industry and what your
speciality is
yes so
my
so i study biology
and i
specialize in neurobiology and at some
point i joined the love of manuel
goodman who is a
a big figure in the cannabis research
field
and i carried out a phd mainly focus on
the roles
go burn by the endocannabinoid system in
the process of
brain development so i study
the
the proliferation of stem cells
neural specification newborn neuron
migration
and all these processors are tightly
controlled by the the cb1 cannon
receptor and
the endocannabinoid system but it was
interestingly a big lab in which with
different lines of research so i got a
background also in cancer research
neurodegenerative diseases
and
yeah
another potential therapeutic
possibilities of cannabis
okay incredible so you've got a wealth
of knowledge and i'm hoping you're the
demand to be able to give everybody the
information that we're looking for this
episode so the the topic of this episode
is patient access in spain can you maybe
give everybody a breakthrough of
the the legal framework that seemed to
have been passed over the last couple of
weeks the timeline the patient is
getting access and the the reality of
the timeline shall we say we understand
that it's a certain amount of months but
yeah
there are many challenges so first of
all i would like to to give a glimpse of
the actual uh context because
a lot of people actually believe that we
we have legal access to cannabis in
spain and that's not true so
most people have heard about the
the cannabis collapse no
so this is not actually uh
anything legal is something that the the
users and everybody found let's say that
the gray areas in the law
and
so all these
for the recreational uses but most
importantly for medical users they have
to go
to the black market or this collapse
which is
illegal and so they are subjected to a
possible fine or whatever
so what it took place and actually it
was june 27th
it was finally approved in the health
commission
within the spanish parliament
uh a text
that
uh
integrates the the the summary of the
com the main conclusions of a
sub-commission that was taking place for
the last the past months
and so this subcommission gather
experts physicians people from
associations and many different voices
and to evaluate to study the possibility
of cannabis medical cannabis regulation
in spain so
yes this was finally approved for with
20 votes in favor 14 against and two
abstentions
and this text
kind of
set uh
not rules but uh suggestions on the
process
and so
yeah there are many
questions
for for instance a what so we we can get
the flowers sadly are not included in
this text so
they are only status for experimental
programs
so what it is included so the what
patients could have access to
are a standardized products or
preparations
and also what it is very interesting is
this
called a
master preparation master formulas i
believe is called in english and is
something that allows for tailor-made a
medicine because the physician
taking care of this patient could
actually
change the
the
in case a patient has troubles to
swallow or has any
other medication that could interact
with
cannabis
components
or
to actually
re adjust
the
the rate of cannabinoids
to
allow for
individualized or very personalized
medicine so this is what is control
and who could be prescribing if this is
not clear in the text so they say
should be done by specialist physicians
and this depending on how
eventually the the regulation adopts
this point
it could be open to the primary care
physicians and private institutions or
only for
pain
or a neurologist or this kind of
specialist
and the patients
could get access to these products in
pharmacies
in
regular
let's say common pharmacies in the
neighborhood but also within the
hospitals
and the
pathologies that are actually
so far included because this is a
a prospective
let's say text no but so far the
indications accepted are
multiple sclerosis that we had already
sativex which was accepted already in
spain to treat this spasticity
associated with the disease
also
we have certain types of epilepsy
and nausea and vomiting derived from
chemotherapy
endometriosis
and also
oncologic and non-oncologic pain
so these are mainly the
the guidelines and then of course in the
text there are many other aspects such
as the
the
they indicate to their responsible
agency
some points in the in the regulation how
they should
ensure access to these products
and how they should
ensure the education of the medical
professionals and etc yeah
okay amazing so it's very in-depth
analysis of it so from the framework
just to maybe give everybody a rough
little breakdown it says that there's
neuropathic pain and chronic pain
allowed in that
in the dispensing of the product but it
might be only by specialist doctors so
would this be
a specific brain specialist or is it
post chemotherapy doctor specialist or
is that still open to interpretation yet
in the finalized worlds
it is still open you know to
interpretation because they say that the
what they say is
uh
the professionals allowed
are physicians with without conflict of
interests
and then they say they say
preferentially should be done by a
specialist in the areas blah blah blah
so
this we don't know as uh
so this is a um an initial let's say
proposal then
what
will be
eventually uh
implemented
this we don't know and another thing
that i have forgot to mention is that
the
in this text
they
they give a frame time work a time frame
sorry of six months to implement all
these measures to the responsible agency
which we believe
it's really very i mean being
realistic is not going to be in this in
this time but
well
let's
and
so we steal from the activists the
associations the
certain
cannabis institutions such as the
spanish observatory of medical cannabis
so we need to keep
doing some pressure
to
trying to ensure that the final adoption
of this text is as
as more
complex and sorry complete as possible
yeah
yeah because the one
nook and the cranny from an outside
perspective looking in that you can see
is right well it's not determined who
the doctors are yet but who gets the
license to prescribe the cannabis so
what what text is going to be in that
license because if it's specific it
specifies a specific type of doctor then
i think the market will have a little
bit of a shortfall when it comes to
patient access i think of course general
practitioner if it's going to be
neuropathic pain and chronic pain a
general practitioner should be able to
prescribe it but as you said
getting a licensing system built in six
months
for sure
of course and that makes a big big
difference because i mean
just talking about pain no chronic pain
so the the numbers uh
[Applause]
estimated are one in six patients in
spain are suffering from from chronic
pain
this is about eight million people in
spain
and let's let's be cautious and assume
that only one third of the patients are
really sensitive to cannabinoid
treatment which is i mean really low
number because we could assume more but
let's say one third this is more than
2.5
million people
that could already benefit and change
their lives with this treatment so of
course
this is not going to take place if only
a specialist and
and you know we need to
we need to change the the
healthcare professionals mind
because
uh
most of them have no
clue about the physiopathological basis
of the
actual potential of medical cannabis so
they barely heard about the
endocannabinoid system
and the control in physiology so and
even less they they have no clue about
the actual clinical data with of
the potential of medical cannabis
and of course they don't have a specific
training
which is something
fundamental because
cannabinoids are very
uh particular type compounds so you
cannot
establish that those
effect relationships that you usually do
with another other drugs
so this is a challenge this is another
challenge in this process yeah yeah well
that kind of leads me right on to the
next thing i want to talk about was
training the doctors and nurses because
as as we'd know that this is going to
get to a stage where as he said it's
blends and formulations of different
cannabinoids that are going to be
relative to each individual patient it's
not going to be there's a prescription
everybody one size fits all so where is
the training for the doctors and the
nurses going to come from is it going to
come from
governmental programs where they have
experts like yourself and professor
guzman or is it going to be investment
outside capital that comes in
this is a huge question mark so we don't
know and there's no specific mention in
the text so what they say is they
encourage
the spanish agent responsible agency
which is
well it doesn't matter the name
they encourage to
to ensure the medical educations of the
of the healthcare profession
so
to my opinion
there are perhaps four
ways no
one would be private
initiatives like private uh
yeah
platforms which are already
offering uh
courses of medical cannabis
then of course we could have
university linked programs
either
master degrees either
post-graduate programs
something which is called
continuous training or continuous
education which is
somehow related to university but it's
another type of
education
and
then of course
the government could
implement some programs associated
either to hospitals universities or
other type of
institutions
and
but then there is another and last a
way of training these healthcare
professionals which
is taking a actually place in other
countries as as well as this that i
already mentioned and is that the
the main companies that got these um
licenses
and of course they got the interest
because you know they have a
big niche of market and they
they want these
physicians to to be as
uh
as educated as possible so they could
actually prescribe their
products
and so
brands are actually investing a lot of
money into these
training programs
so yeah to my opinion these are the main
four ways that we could but there's
nothing clear we don't know which
yeah
yeah no it's going to be an interest in
six months over
to see how everything falls into the
place for you guys over in spain and
we'll have our fingers crossed over here
in ireland that you get a an industry up
and running that leads the way for
compliance and regulation
it's been an amazing subject
and helps a lot of patients i mean this
is something we are
pain cannot wait so yes this is
something we need to act now
yeah there as you said there's at least
a couple of million people in spain who
could be uh benefiting from access to
medical cannabis
products at the moment so i hope
everything goes amazing for you over the
next six months and hopefully we can
touch base at the end of the year or
start of 2023 and we'll get an update
and see where spain is at but for now
thank you very much for dan and have a
great day
thank you owen ciao until next time