foreign
by Andre Silva who's a field marketing
specialist in Europe working for Merck
how are you keeping today Andre
hello I'm doing very well thanks
yourself
I'm fantastic thank you very much for
taking the time to do this it's very
much appreciated if you maybe want to
give everybody a quick little overview
of your position in the sector and what
uh care and specialized in
absolutely and first of all thank you
for having me on the podcast it's a huge
pleasure to feature an episode on
quoting control from a laboratory
product provider perspective
I must say that my journey in this
industry has started back in 2019 as I
started working for Merck as a technical
sales specialist
role in which I initiated collaboration
with key customers in the European
market on the Cannabis topic so I'm
referring to pharmaceutical companies
starting production and implementing
their own quality control Labs but also
General testing Labs looking to initiate
analysis on the different cannabinoids
components and contaminants uh at the
beginning of last year I've also had the
honor to join the editorial Advisory
board for cannabis Science and
Technology magazine in the US in which
I've worked to support with scientific
articles and content review
and I'm currently performing the role of
field marketing Specialists for Western
Europe covering the the Cannabis Market
okay very interesting so a pretty big
sector that you guys are covering can
you tell me what are the main compounds
that are being tested by quality control
Labs such as yourselves at the moment
sure so we don't do the analysis
ourselves we provide products for
Laboratories to perform the analysis and
the tests and and this is a quite broad
topic so I'll try to summarize it the
best to my ability and and briefly
explain the reasoning behind it so when
we think about final products out in the
market and and this can be reflected in
pharmaceutical nutraceutical Cosmetics
food and beverage items
we as consumers expect a rigorous
quality control examination to take
place to ensure the safety reliability
but also the quality of the products
that reach us
so in cannabis as a strict regulatory
framework takes place this is of course
of extremely high importance
so now looking at Cannabis Testing
there are two key designations commonly
used by the industry depending on the
focus of the testing so on one hand we
have potency testing which looks at the
cannabinoid and terpene profile of the
plants essentially the constituents that
attracted attention due to their
therapeutical properties
and on the other hand we have purity
testing which looks at the presence of
external contaminants that could have
been introduced through the cultivation
and Manufacturing processes
so starting with potency testing
cannabinoids is for sure the loudest
sibling and everyone at this point has
heard about CBD and THC so from one
angle we have a group of psychoactive
cannabinoids that are heavily regulated
with most often clear maximum levels to
be respected therefore extremely
important to test Euro materials and
final products should not contain these
compounds above the established levels
so for instance a THC is by far the most
known here and the European commission
has set a limit of 0.3 percent in
industrial hemp crops so this has to
mandatorily be respected and and testing
is the only way to prove it
so DHC is however not alone in this
group so as his research progresses
newer cannabinoids are continuously
found some of which have even stronger
psychoactive responses than THC such as
thcp so in the in-depth studies will
then assess the potential the potency
the potential of these compounds
which will eventually dictate whether or
not maximum levels should be enforced by
the Regulatory Agencies
so it's it's currently a a very Dynamic
field of research as you can imagine
that requires close observation to
ensure for full Regulatory Compliance
so from a slightly different angle we
have the known psychoactive cannabinoids
in in some cases they've been accepted
by the European commission to be legally
used as ingredients in food products and
cosmetics and and in this area people
have heard about CBD and CBG I'm sure so
nowadays it is not surprising to come
across extracts concentrates and and
other products containing cannabinoids
and dispensaries and and some other
marketplaces so these large
non-psychoactive group also requires
testing for the identification and
quantification of the different
compounds
which should be performed by a certified
Lab in order to Showcase overall
Integrity good manufacturing practices
but also a strict quality assurance
we then have the terpenes which are a
class of compounds responsible for the
fragrance and Aroma of a wide variety of
plants and in this case cannabis strains
have terpene profiles that give them a
unique characteristic Aroma but the
individual terpenes themselves are found
in many other common plants say for
instance limonene which is found in in
citrous fruits or pining and as the name
indicates can be found in in pine trees
so some of these have also been affirmed
to promote certain therapeutic effects
both acting in isolation but also as
part of the commonly known Entourage
effect a synergistic action that is
modulated by various terpenes and
cannabinoids compounds
so hence we have companies here in this
spectrum looking at cannabis extracts
with a cocktail of cannabinoids
interpenes as opposed to isolate
specifically
so these mixture means another Target
group that requires testing
so we've now covered the two main groups
of interest for cannabis potency and
considering their varied chemical
structure and internal properties
we can already tell that they will
require different preparation techniques
analytical methods and tools in order
for the testing to be performed with
accuracy and precision
so when we dive into purity testing now
a whole new range of external
contaminants comes into place
so let's have a view of the let's have
an overview of the entire process so
during the cultivation phase pesticides
are commonly used to protect the crops
so the list here are extensive and in
the US for instance this framework
changes from state to state a few states
have guidelines in place in Europe there
still seems to be some uncertainty and
unclarity around this topic so in in the
end it matters to test not just the
pesticides that have been used during
the cultivation process
but also the ones that have been one
banned by the regulatory agencies in
place but that
could also have been somehow introduced
in the chain
on top of that
plans and in this case cannabis plants
have the capacity to extract and
bioaccumulate heavy metals from soil
so we're jumping yet into another
complex regulatory landscape here here
we have some highly regulated Metals
such as
cadmium lead arsenic Mercury
but there's an even longer list that
requires monitoring and that if it's
otherwise overlooked can possess serious
health risks to the consumers
now
so we sort of covered the interferences
that come from the cultivation phase so
the the most significant ones but
thinking about the manufacturing process
and how it affects the final product
and this is again method dependent if
it's extraction is performed with the
aid of solvents such as butane and
methanol
residual solvent testing is required to
guarantee that no dangerous levels of
these compounds are left in the end
product
additionally
um and depending on the The Matrix
that's being worked on produced we can
talk about
isolates and concentrates
extracts leaves flowers seeds on or any
other final product all present
different challenges and and the testing
methods need to be adapted so excessive
moisture in in cannabis plant parts for
instance
can lead to mold growth and degradation
which can then allow fungi micro fungi
to produce toxic component compounds
namely microtoxins and therefore this
adds additional need to perform testing
around microbial activity the presence
of mycotoxins and quantification
and and even moisture levels so I know
that was a lot of information in one go
and there are certainly areas in which I
haven't touched but these are admittedly
crucial analysis to be performed on raw
materials and final products involving
cannabis so the the Cannabis Testing
Market involves an ample range of
techniques and Equipment tools to ensure
the safety potency and quality of the
products and this is where product
providers come into place so accurate
testing is of course crucial essential
here to meet regulatory requirements
protect consumer health but also support
the development of responsive
responsible and regulated cannabis
industry
very good when it comes to the testing
of these products and the specific
molecules that are these ingredients
we've obviously got three when it comes
to cannabinoids but plan extracted
matter we've got synthetic and we've got
fermentation engineering and bio
processing to create a replical molecule
over and over again it seems to me the
future of the ingredients out of the
industry is the bioprocessing and
fermentation engineering because of the
scalability and the replica replication
that can be had and the Purity level is
this okay it comes to testing that there
is a discrepancy between the three
different separate molecules from the
three different production methods
it will of course need to be adapted and
and you've mentioned for instance uh
synthetic cannabinoids
um which product providers have already
a set of tools in place for this testing
to be performed so so testing will
overall be present
um whatever method is choose to to scale
up the production of these different
compounds that you've mentioned
okay and what are the main roadblocks in
the development of the testing Market in
EU
[Music]
um
I would say from my perspective
um regulatory restrictions seem to be
the current primary obstacle on this
road to develop the European market
if cannabis and and its components
specifically can't be handled
transported manufactured or even sold to
the consumer the need for testing also
becomes limited just as a possibility
for new research and new end products to
be developed
we are at a stage where companies have
for quite some years invested in a
market with some degree of uncertainty
and the future of their work essentially
depends on when and if any advancements
are to take place so having said that
most countries in Western Europe have
given green light to the medicinal
cannabis Market
with individual specifications and core
pilot programs in place and nowadays
more than before we we do read news
about ongoing discussions on the
recreational Market New approaches being
explored in order to forge a path to
safely introduce products to the shelves
and and to open them to the consumers
but this however in my perspective leads
to yet another challenge which is lack
of harmonization
while some European countries have
established regulations
there's still a lack of harmonization
across the region across the board which
in turn can lead to discrepancies in the
testing requirements and the product
standards so I've personally found by
speaking with a lot of
companies that operate in the field
that in our European market there seems
to be a certain knowledge Gap a need for
Guidance with end users turning to more
advanced markets such as the US to
answer common questions related to
overall manufacturing certification
processes and and regulations this will
of course support the development of the
market itself but at the same time and
up to an extent will contribute to the
lack of consistency and reliability of
the products released in our European
market
so for me outside these would be the two
main challenges that need to be tackled
in order for the market to grow
healthily and steadily in the upcoming
years
okay amazing it's been fascinating
talking to Andre and I know it might be
the most romantic check for someone
having those viable products that are
consistent and remarkable over and over
again is the only way this industry can
be taken as seriously as let's say the
chocolate industry or the fizzy drinks
industry or whatever it may be it's been
a great talking to you and hopefully
again we can catch up and have a second
part of this conversation because as I
said I think we're going to have some
movement in Europe over the next five
years that I'm sure like yourself is
going to be very busy when we get some
sort of clear regulation from one of the
countries
absolutely looking forward to see where
the market is heading and thank you
again for having me in your in your show
my absolute pleasure until the episode
everybody