[Music]
welcome everybody to the cannabis review
i'm delighted to be joined on this
episode by peter sue he's the senior
vice president at green check verified
peter how you keeping
hey thank you for having me i'm doing
great it's a rainy day in new york but
i'm excited to be on the show st
patrick's day it is indeed made a lovely
sunny day over here for saint patrick's
day so for everybody who doesn't know
who greenshad verified art they provide
uh banking solutions and expected
advisory services to financial
institutions established in 2017
you guys have brought a couple of
leaders in technology and banking and uh
to enable financial institutions to kind
of bring themselves to market in this
industry am i correct with that
that's exactly right yeah uh so so where
software and um you know in the cannabis
space
for the us anyway the the regulatory
burden for a financial institution
getting into this space can be very high
um perhaps prohibitively so
um and so in the early days that that's
kind of what lets a lot of banks jumping
in and jumping back out
and so like any good software we're a
force multiplier um
and you know the the the effects are
staggering like if you have a manual
program
you have to dedicate for every five to
eight cannabis businesses you would have
to dedicate another body to your to your
program
versus using software we have clients
with 50 60 80 accounts per fte per
full-time employee
okay amazing and i'm just going to jump
straight into the first topic here and
it's kind of capital markets and
cannabis it's something i wanted to be
talking about because it kind of brings
together a couple of different topics in
my opinion it's the capital raises that
are happening the m a activity and then
the cannabis banking sector so in terms
of the capital raises have you seen a
dramatic increase in new york in the
past 12 to 18 months since they
announced legalization last march or was
there already a lot of activity
happening for the last three to four
years with the lieu of this known people
this is gonna happen
uh yes to both uh you know the first
thing to consider is that the capital
market or just capital in general in
cannabis is probably the number one
thing
um but largely because the public
markets are not still not available yet
we have certain companies that are
actually canadian listed so canadian lps
um i mean if you look at some of the
msos that we have here that they're
essentially rollups right so they're in
their entire business is based on uh
continual m a activity
um and so in new york yeah we've seen a
lot of people for years now that have
kind of laid the groundworks of what
they knew was coming which is now a
legal you know adult use market
um that said yes uh recently of course
that that activity has significantly
ticked up
and have you guys seen is the m a
activity pretty heavy in new york at the
moment or are the investors kind of
waiting to see let's see the gate opens
up let's see who kind of gets the market
share and then
we'll make our purchases then or is
there somebody in the background as it
is kind of
combining brands that are already
established for the past few years
um definitely in the background um keep
in mind we don't have actual regs out as
yet um so technically no one can be
doing any activities um as yet
except for the original 10 ro's the
registered organization so the original
10 license holders yes
those guys have significantly ticked up
their uh
you know columbiacare just just bought a
huge property out in the hamptons
um it's it's but by square footage it's
the largest cultivation site in america
um so they're clearly you know setting
the grounds for what's coming next but
as far as actual you know capital kind
of flooding into space that's not really
happening as yet i think in the
background a lot of that a lot of the
groundwork is being laid right now um
and frankly if you hadn't if you hadn't
started if you didn't start a year ago
you're late to the game
yeah i think it's it's definitely an
industry that you want to have your uh
your feet already already in the water
for the past year or two because i think
the amount of information and the the
legal nuances and the financial nuances
to get up to speed where people are
already here hurry is going to be swift
do you see colombia care having a
dominance uh
in new york or do you see other players
that have the equivalent size and
capital to go after them
yes
again the original 10 rows have had such
a huge leg up you know they already have
operations already have the contacts um
obviously you know employment already in
place uh uh
and plus they get to keep their vertical
status uh versus everyone else that has
to kind of pick a lane
um
sorry to interrupt you there can you
explain to everybody what the 100s are
oh i apologize yeah so we uh new york
state was a medical only uh states um
and there were five and then they they
quickly added another five so so they're
collectively referred to as the ros the
register organizations
um so the original 10 from i guess 2018
roughly
those 10 organizations
which were medical only were given the
opportunity to simply you know
convert over into the new adult
market so they're guaranteed essentially
a license they just have to apply for it
so of course why wouldn't they right
um but not only that but they have a
very distinct advantage uh whereas
everyone else that's applying for a
license now needs to pick a lane you
could be a cultivator you could be a
grower you could be you know retail it
could be distribution
consumption lounges but you can only
have one you need a license whereas the
original ros the original 10
organizations
they got to keep their vertical status
so they are their own supply chain their
their own distribution and outlets
okay very interesting do you see them
being able to grow a quality
of flower that's going to be able to
take it down within the market or do you
see something happen like in canada
where the craft growers are in essence
after reading away the tilray aurora and
the kind of big companies shares up
there
that's a great question i um i'm not
sure i mean i i assume that they have
they're confident obviously they know
how to grow marijuana
the question is is it good is it quality
well is it is it craft
um
now the other question would be do the
consumers care um because you know let's
be honest for for decades despite the
fact it was illegal people have had no
problem buying you know cannabis
anywhere
uh but by and large at least in new york
um
we don't really have the connoisseurs
you know the the way the market you know
you get what you get
and so is is there a sector of the
market that will also simply carry over
like i don't care i'm just walking into
store and picking up you know a bag um i
i imagine there is that demographic and
then yes i do think there is that
demographic that has a very specific
taste of what they want and don't want
and that's probably not the mso
demographic
yeah i think what might happen in new
york is you've got such a tourist
consumer base there that it'll be that
anything goes mcdonald's type of stuff
but i think the hippies out in
williamsburg now aren't going to be
dealing with anything that hasn't been
perfectly organically grown and fed in a
specific way so i think there's a huge
opportunity there for the kind of small
cultivars themselves to come to the
market yeah yeah you know again uh um i
i think that for decades that the the
consumers that are in let's say new york
right versus like a california where
where where craft strains have has
always been a thing it's much more
ingrained into the culture
uh my belief is that uh uh the
northeastern consumers are are more like
you know you get what you get and you
don't get upset kind of people
yeah i'm gonna move on to the next topic
and it's kind of as banking so again
specifically did you guys read you guys
have created software the partnership
that you guys had with abrego there in
last september was a massive thing for
you guys can you ever give everybody an
overview of the strategic importance of
that deal
oh i think that's huge you know i i well
first of all in any situation where you
can leverage a good name alongside your
good name um you know that's certainly
symbiotic right we i think we help them
as much as they help us but to the
extent that they are in x number of
financial institutions and we're trying
to offer a solution that can run
parallel to theirs um yeah it was
definitely a good get and from a pr
perspective of course was was huge
um
that said i mean i i think uh we we have
uh arguably the largest presence in the
financial institutions um you know as is
today in america uh we have just under a
hundred that use our software um so i'd
like to think we brought as much to the
table as they did
yeah now i think it seems to be a
mutually beneficial partnership to great
countries with their complementing
technologies and talent is that is
always a win-win for everybody
absolutely yeah yeah yeah so
i just want to basically give everybody
an overview your guys software works
with what's called community banks now
over in america so they wouldn't really
exist to an
extent over here so i just want to give
everybody the demo definition between a
community bank and a commercial bank so
community bank is basically a localized
bank that's locally owned and the money
is kept locally
am i right and saying that versus
commercial bank which has a nationwide
presence
um so yes uh i wouldn't say it's a true
distinction uh uh so it's not as if you
have a license that's that that makes
you only a community bank or you have a
license you know that's only a
commercial bank the difference really is
is how you envision your bank doing
business the mandate that you have from
your investors from your board of
directors
but yes as a community bank you your
specific mandate is hey we want to bank
locally we want to take the local
businesses that exist here whether i'm
in new york long island um
and
you know if if you're mandated say we
want we're going to bank locally invest
locally be owned locally yeah like that
that is what you will look for in your
clientele
versus a commercial bank which might
have a very broad mandate hey we do uh
residential loans it really doesn't
matter you know whether that's that's
here locally or
in washington state across the country
okay
it's it's a nice industry to learn about
because it's the one thing we hear about
the most i think over here is the safe
biking acting
seems to be the biggest thing that you
guys seem to be the perfect solution to
uh to this problem
yeah you know for all the belly who
about the safe banking act um you know
the truth is i think today um
and look it's a quickly dynamic
situation right
versus even a year ago two years ago
things have changed very quickly and a
lot
but i think today where we sit
uh the barrier of entry into cannabis
banking is a decision
that's it you know granted there's work
to be done you need to do build a policy
you need to understand the market you
need to show the regulators you've done
the work but these are works that any
you know whether it be a community bank
commercial bank credit union they know
how to do the work they just have to
make the decision that they're willing
to do it um
hiring a vendor like like green check
verified is very beneficial to a program
obviously i'm bias in saying that but uh
um but that you know but again that's
something that banks financial
institutions know how to do they know
how to find a vendor that are experts in
a certain area and they can carry that
forward at the end of the day they just
have to make that decision to to get
into
you know a very lucrative space
yeah well i think if we were setting up
an industry over here in ireland now in
a week or two one of the things i'd be
pretty adamant about is that each
person applying for a license would have
to have banking solutions already in
place and i think you guys offer a
solution where it makes the politicians
decision a lot easier because you're
kind of offering their look we can get
rid of crime or we can manage crime and
and fraud to a degree and all of the
other aspects that kind of seem to be
the puzzle for people to give at the
okay
no absolutely and i i do think that the
the regulators examiners will look at a
situation and say look you you need to
put some experience on your bench i get
it you've done the homework you've done
your research but don't think you can
just get out there and bank this
high-risk vertical without some sort of
help um and hey you know when you guys
are ready we'd love to help our founder
kevin hart uh his family's from ireland
so he has roots there i hope we could be
a resource for you guys
yeah for sure and with the movement of
uh goods over in europe it's access to
the whole of europe when uh when we're
talking about this which i think the
industry over here will need a unified
answer to this because you have so many
different markets over here between
spain italy france and germany and what
not last topic i kind of wanted to jump
onto is the race for new york i we were
reading there the other day that so the
first hundred licenses is going to
people who had passed criminal
convictions so those hundred licenses
are they basically they get to choose
what section they want to be in as i
said cultivation retail consumption lens
first hundred people just get to choose
randomly from those different sectors is
it
no no uh so that first hundred license
uh you know first of all my hat's off to
the regulators here in new york i mean
um they they've seen that the social
equity movement in other states have had
largely underwhelmed um and you know i
it's funny i was talking to ruben
mcdaniel who's one of our regulators on
the ocm
and he said look you know we're not
going to make the same mistakes that
other states made we might make new ones
but we're not going to make the old ones
um and so
these first hundred licenses for the
justice involved applicants that is to
say you you've had a you know marijuana
conviction on your record in the state
of new york
the first hundred licenses will go
towards that pool of applicants
it is retail only it is meant to be
dispensaries only uh that doesn't mean
there won't be other programs other
licenses but that what you're referring
to there is specific to retail
it's great to see how debate it's
commendable to the guys in charge the
next thing for the race new york that
i'm looking about how serious is the
money that's already in the industry we
talked just off our camera that somebody
like ray galio is already present in
this century are the hedge funds really
starting to get into this space now or
is it still just angel investors and vcs
um so it is starting to tick up for from
an institutional perspective but no it
is largely smaller that the biggest
players the biggest funds are are not in
the space as yet um
uh so i i would say you know the the
bigger fun the biggest funds that we
have right now would probably be like
the the afc gammas uh the the chicago
atlantic's of the world um those are
mostly debt funds though so so they are
kind of lending to
you know existing performing players um
for pure play equity
it is still hard to find
yeah no i think that seems to be the
holy grail for the cannabis entrepreneur
at the moment is access to true capital
and i think it's only a matter of time
now somebody like new york i think is
just going to change the game completely
when we see the industry hopefully come
to fruition at the end of this year
yeah yeah no i mean it's exciting if you
think about new york new jersey
connecticut um you know the inside that
from a population perspective that is a
huge dynamic shift i mean
right after these three states more than
half of the u.s population will now live
in a legal state
yeah and i think new york did the
significance for europe how new york on
legalization can't be underestimated
it's it's such as much of not too far
it's as close to the end of america as
europe gets so generally what happens in
new york travels to europe a hell of a
lot when it happened in california in
colorado it's not that big of a deal but
new york now the amount of people that
travel there i think it's only a matter
of time before that uh infectious this
starts to spread over this side of the
pond
well maybe we will have to phrase it
that way but yeah well you know i it's
an exciting it's an exciting time to be
at the forefront of a growing industry
um honestly in my lifetime i can't think
of a scenario where
you had this type of opportunity some
people like to compare it to like the
internet for example
but to me it was a little different
because when the internet came out let's
be honest some of us didn't know what it
was it was a brand new concept whereas
here you know there's a built-in
audience built into man
and it's just a matter of capturing it
and making it legal
yeah best brands and the best products
are going to win the race at the end of
the day
yeah absolutely
it's been amazing time to be the right
to actually go on all day we've got over
time but it's been it's been great to
chat yeah hopefully we can chat again in
the towards the end of the year when
things are starting to really ramp up in
new york and we see kind of brands come
to the fore and premise is starting to
look like they're going to be open
no absolutely we'd love to follow up
again when things really start kicking
off in new york please check back
brilliant happy days well thanks
everybody for watching we will catch you
on the next episode