foreign
who's a partner at greenspoon martyr LLC
Eastern New York can you keeping today
John
I'm good greenstone martyr LLP all right
we uh we lawyers are precise about our
words and letters you know me do words
good that's how I and I we don't want to
do math that's why I ended up being a
lawyer
um but uh you know thanks for reaching
out
um and you know we're linking up right
now because of this momentous thing that
you know kind of momentous potentially
temporarily momentous thing that
happened in the um in the New York
industry right now and so the very very
quick snapshot right is that new you
know New York legalized adult use
marijuana over two years ago okay and
then New York wanted to ramp up you know
and it decriminalized there's always a
gap between when there's no longer
criminal and when an actual adult use
Mark launches and the people that
benefit the most during that period are
unlicensed illicit operators and New
York is very similar to California and
what happened was that you know uh
estimates in New York City alone 1400
unlicensed doors popped open selling
legitimate product from mature markets
like California where very difficult
frankly and the only people making money
to some extent are people selling stuff
out the back door high-end account for
products and I just heard uh from a
friend last night that some of these
stores are selling psilocybin chocolate
bars in child appealing packaging right
and so that's one big element that
happened in New York and then you know
in order to you know get sales started
soon and also to help you know uh
Upstate you know a lot of hemp Farmers
there who've been hurt by the CBD Market
they created this you know conditional
you know there's all these conditional
programs that I've opened up to kind of
accelerate the process of starting sales
and so I kind of call them like the hemp
crossover licenses so there are
conditional cultivators
um and you know processors and they were
able to start making you know uh there
was a bill past afterwards creating
conditional processors and cultivators
you know just in time I think for you
know a planting season and so all of a
sudden there are what you know the seeds
are going in for ultimately will be you
know what were and you know was an
estimated 700 million dollar Harvest
with nowhere to sell and so the
conditional retail program was created
and all of these programs okay please
keep in mind are unique to New York
there's nothing been done like this
before in the industry and any law has
unintended consequences in an incredibly
complex industry like cannabis where all
these pieces tie together those
unintended consequences you know
increase exponentially and so this you
know conditional adult use retail
dispensary program was created by The
Regulators by the office of cannabis
management right and you have to meet
these very specific criteria to qualify
being someone with a specific type of
marijuana conviction showing that you
were harmed you know by the War on Drugs
but to ensure that you know what you're
doing when you're operating a business
to also have had some history of
ownership in a profitable business and
so they get this program up and running
uh conditional retail I say we're going
to hand out 150 licenses one month to
apply 900 people apply and then after it
closes the regulators and I cover I have
a podcast we're about to relaunch where
we cover everything in the industry and
I've never seen anybody do what New York
Regulators did here in terms of after
people had applied right everything said
and done they keep on making changes
right for one thing they double to 300
licenses they're going to hand out oh
there's also this whole other idea of
we're going to have this fund 200
million dollars 50 from the state 50
from a raise of investment where we're
going to you know allocate 1.5 million
dollars or two million dollars to each
of these card conditional don't use
retail dispensary licensees that we hand
out to for the property and the buildup
we're going to help you find the sites
and lo and behold is something that
ambitious and a place as densely packed
as New York that wasn't working and no
money was being raised and so after the
application window closed you know some
of the they decided that they're going
to change the program you could use your
own property then they realize that more
people have their own property in
certain means than they thought even
though it might not have been the right
you know uh their like idea and you know
with 700 million dollars I call it Farm
to get it right people literally bet the
farm
um you know to put seeds in the ground
and transition over from the struggling
hemp and CBD Market to take a chance on
the first row and the New York cannabis
market and there's going to be no place
to sell uh and so they you know they
after the facts of ocm again right 150
licenses we're handing out you could use
your own properties we're going to
double it to 300. we got to sell all
that wheat uh and then recently they
even you know increased it I think
there's a total of 463 card licenses now
and you know the and they're also after
the fact they change and say oh we want
you to be able to sell like immediately
delivery out of the retail stores
whereas that have been intended as a
separate license
um and and then uh also
um I think it's supper license on
delivery um but I'm sorry New Jersey and
New York bounce around my head sometimes
and I'm not on Short Grass from the
Fantastic networking event uh and then
um but on-site consumption definitely
intended to be a separate
um no sorry delivery was not a separate
license sorry
um but outside consumption was always
intended to be a separate license and lo
and behold uh you know they that will
allow these cards to do on-site
consumption
um what they shifted by the way in terms
of like the intended race or full use
for card what I was referencing in terms
of delivery was the concept of you could
start sales ASAP out of a temporary
delivery location because they're just
trying to get you know to address
pharmageddon and get weed out the door
now the way that I've actually described
all this is in a way that's kind of
sympathetic to the regulators
and what I'll say is I always do the
disclaimer I don't I I thank them for
their service I think they have great
intentions of coming in and helping
people get harmed by the war drugs
especially in States like New Jersey and
New York and they certainly can't please
everyone and they're dealt you know
certain cards by the law that they're
handed and in this instance you know the
conditional processor and cultivator
loss so I've kind of portrayed all of
this a certain way and then what
inevitably happens in every single state
are lawsuits right and those throw a
wrench and everything and their losses
You can predict because you know in
every single state right they the drug
is federally illegal right can you blame
local politicians and Regulators for
trying to you know when the entire
industry is going to be inside their
state
savoring people from the state versus
what I call the Cana Carpetbaggers all
pop pawns are always intended right so
they come up with things to favor people
in their state and then there's this you
know dormant Commerce Clause issue which
is like so incredibly frustrating that
the drug is federally illegal but
according to this concept of the dormant
Commerce Clause if Regulators come up
with something that favors their own
residence to the detriments of people
outside since Commerce is supposed to be
just you know like industry
accomplishment was just supposed to be
governed by
um you know Congress they will knock out
those wrecks and there is a you know
dorm of Commerce Clause has an almost
100 percent you know track record in
multiple courts around the country so a
lawsuit comes in like that holds up the
awarding of licenses in multiple regions
but then they're what's you know what's
different and is specific to New York
and these moves that The Regulators did
in creating the entire conditional adult
use retail dispensary
that was not in the initial
um in the initial murder the law that
legalized adult use two lawsuits come in
right the first one is a lawsuit you
know nicely packaged and intelligent
packaged by some of the biggest
companies in the industry
um you know called multi-state operators
who own the medical licenses you know
the handful of medical licenses in New
York state right and these are vertical
and they're the only ones who could be
vertical and they're treated separately
in many different ways but there's a lot
of stuff in the initial proposed laws
that were not friendly towards any type
of big business and specifically these
folks and one thing was saying you're
not going to be allowed to sell and
cross over to adult use for years and so
with the card program every single
lawyer we all saw a vulnerability from
the beginning right it said in the law
itself the legalization law that the
application period for all retail
dispensaries had to be opened at the
same time right the card program created
by You Know ocm The Regulators to
address Armageddon and everything
didn't do that at first glance
theoretically anyone could apply but
they wouldn't have a shot because unless
they have the scoring the very very
specific scoring criteria uh and so
um you know what ended up
by the way I like I'm talking the entire
time
you semperaneously right this is how my
brain is piecing all this together
because I've been you know thinking this
out into different angles and I want to
get to the nitty-gritty of some of my
thoughts in terms of what's going on
right so you know this lawsuit comes in
and you know and the interesting thing
is the lawsuits in New York have
accomplished what they want to do to
some extent right the lawsuit by you
know these big companies you know one of
the things that happened was you know
the next version of the proposed
regulations was released you know by The
Regulators and lo and behold it had
changes in terms of accelerating the
timeline for them to be able to cross
over adult use and a couple other things
that were friendly to them and the
person who sued based on the Dorman
Commerce Clause because he was an
out-of-state person trying to get one of
these card licenses there's a settlement
agreement with The Regulators in which
The Regulators essentially promised to
hand them a license in the adult use
rounds if he qualifies but they settle
just so they could remove the injunction
holding up the handing out or these
licenses and opening up of the
dispensaries in well at that point you
know one region left because they hand
out the car licenses according to
Regions tied to you know population to
ensure that there's sufficient Supply so
the last lawsuit that came out and the
one that's in everyone's mind right now
is
um a couple veterans right and so in the
initial you know Murder legalization
bill you know there are specific you
know classes of you know people that
these bills are trying to help right so
we've talked about you know people hurt
by the war on drugs or whatever and
um also just say like women-owned
businesses and you know service disabled
veterans so a group of veterans came
along who you know plunked down you know
like I said it's been two years since
the bill was passed they plunk down
money for Real Estate right thinking
that things we're going to get up soon
they've taken steps they've made
investment to be there on the front
lines and have one of the first
dispensaries open and then card program
opened up and so they're suing uh on
along similar lines as you know the
Coalition of the big companies pointing
out that issue of you know the the date
right not all retail dispensary
applications open up the same date
um and they pointed out some of these
issues in terms of how you know The
Regulators keep on you know essentially
expanding the card program by worrying
more licenses by letting them you know
um do all these different things to the
detriment of all the people that are
going to participate in the full adult
use round specifically the people that
that round you know they want to hand 50
of the licenses to these you know
certain classes including service
disabled veterans and you know there's a
limited amount of dispensaries that a
state can support and that was going to
be 463 cards handed out and operating
you know presumably possibly before they
get their chance and so they came in and
you know they said they asked for a
preliminary Junction and temporary
restraining order and what that is is a
party saying we are going to be so we're
being so irreparably harmed right now
that this is untenable right and we need
you judge to stop the other party you
know in this instance ocm we need you to
freeze the card program in its tracks
it's not just adding out but sending out
more licenses it's not approving anybody
who has a license but wants to become
operational because all these folks are
scrambling in one of the densest places
that there are with location
restrictions you know tied to houses of
worship in schools you know and certain
localities that have opt-in or not to
find property right and some of them are
on the hook to pay this property and so
right now you know they you know the the
veterans the plaintiffs asked for
everything to be Frozen and what the
judge did here in this case was and this
is the same judge who you know appears
as handling both the Coalition case you
know and the veteran case and they do
that at times right because it's similar
arguments similar issues is efficient
and so what he did was he granted that
temporary restraining order he throws
the entire card program in its tracks
but it was a placeholder okay it was
just
um you know certainly interesting that
he did it but it you know this might
just end up being a placeholder until
you know and I think that the the
current deadline for the state to
respond is today and the hearing is
scheduled and this tro goes and told the
hearing uh on Friday so that's not
pushed right we may have an answer right
you know on Friday
um you know this is a function of what
will end up happening
um
uh
yeah so um so on Friday right there are
two things
um you know uh there are two things that
could happen right one thing is you know
he can deny the request for a temporary
restraining order uh in which case hard
you know unfreezes and keeps on going
um and if he grants the tro it would
extend through the point at which he
makes a decision in the Coalition case
um you know in the Coalition case
um dueling summary judgment motions in
the Coalition case both sides are saying
that they essentially have a winning
hand uh and so the judge right so the
veteran plaintiff said all right we want
to freeze hard until you judge this is
what they actually asked for so you
judge make a call on the legality of the
entire card system in that other case
with the Coalition where they made
similar arguments and you know the the
fear here right when we all saw this
vulnerability from a ways out and so
obvious is that you know talking to
other lawyers we all geek out about this
you know that there is you know an issue
here
um that you know it might not look good
it's possible that the card program was
improper from the beginning
um but you know what I want to put up on
LinkedIn today and discuss is you know
look judges know what's going on
disrupting the card program at this
point would be an incredible
stabilization in a market that's already
already really really struggling and so
I'm not you know an administrative
lawyer I always say that people need to
think of lawyers I could think of
doctors who wouldn't ask a dermatologist
to look at something up your you know
what
um just like right but you know having
read some articles around
um including a point made by an attorney
named David Holland or saying like you
know the only you know line of reasoning
that could help the state is saying
everything they did The Regulators was
due to an emergency and so I framed this
entire narrative to highlight two
emergencies that were not of The
Regulators on creating the first is
unlicensed stores selling
um you know products that are unsafe the
second is the legislature legalized
created the conditional cultivation and
processing and there were 700 million a
weed coming out of the ground that
needed some place to be sold
right and so everything they've done in
with the card program has understandably
really been for the purpose of safety of
the populace and selling the Surplus
weed so that these people aren't
economically devastated
um Upstate that they're intending to
help and the only thing I'll say is like
I want to dig deep into the chronic you
know chronology here because you're
making this argument that you're
irreparably harmed and part of the thing
that occurs to me is why couldn't the
plaintiffs have brought this earlier
what just happened that changed this and
made this completely untenable and
Justified asking for a preliminary
injunction and the only thing that was
relatively recent was the increase from
300 to 463 licenses being handed out and
so I'm wondering if the judge can dig
them on that and then ultimately maybe
right even though it doesn't look great
because they have strong arguments maybe
these emergency bases are enough that
the program continues
incredible insights and it's it's very
well summarize thank you very much for
that I'm sure everybody's going to get a
wealth of information like I just did
out of it we've run over our time now
but hopefully we can get to touch base
in maybe a week or two and see well
currently lies then do a priority to
this yeah I'm happy to do that all right
so uh thank you so much for having me
and letting me speak the entire time
next time I'm going to interview you
not at all my player until next episode
everybody
[Music]