[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I'm delighted to be
joined in this episode by Kevin Jones
who's the founder of hemp hemp Hound
based in the UK how you keeping today
Kevin I'm all good Owen and thank you
for having me on Sir delighted to have
you on mate I've been following your
LinkedIn uh post and investigative
Jerusalem journalism very closely so
it's to be able to talk to you can you
maybe give everybody a little quick
overview of how you came to found the
hemp hound and your position in the
industry yeah of course um I started off
uh with a CBD uh company in 2016 Called
Love Bud now uh that didn't quite go to
plan uh but I did discover then that I
was quite Adept at finding out
information uh understanding uh what I
needed to know and understanding who I
needed to ask if I didn't understand um
that actually sounds a bit weird but uh
that led to a job at the Cannabis trades
Association where I was member point of
contact for two and a half years where I
helped uh hundreds of companies on
various matters now that position came
to a close at the end of 2020 uh they uh
CTA evolved as an entity but what they
said that they didn't want uh I decided
to take and repackage and create
effectively the hemp pound agency which
is basically a um a signpost in an
advisory service for first and foremost
as well as uh uh now delving into the
world of investigative journalism and
Industry
commentary yeah it's it's very
interesting with the UK it seems to be
one of the territories that actually has
the most disinformation if you're
looking from the outside looking in so
it's great to be able to have somebody
of your expertise and uh Clarity to be
able to bring to these topics first
topic I wanted to start off with his CBD
in the UK again lots of reports positive
and negative that come out of the UK can
you give us us an exact overview of what
does the CBD industry look like in the
UK is it going well are the big major
retailers still purchasing after the
ruling that we saw recently based on the
the quantity of THC how does it h
currently stand as you see it well novel
Foods has been a long strangled Affair
in my point of view uh it's been filled
with vague vagueness and uh uh
regulatory updates have been um sporadic
and slow uh for example with the uh ADI
announcement recently the 10 milligram
advised daily intake that was followed
by the uh acmd recognition from the home
office in regards to control canabo
levels now one of the very interesting
things in there is that no serving size
is defined it's accepted that there
needs to be a serving size for all of
these products but in effect that leaves
us in an interesting scenario where
we've got an advised daily intake but no
serving suggestions versus um control
canabo content allowed per serving with
the home office saying yeah we need to
sort out a serving but the FSA have
never thought about doing that and if we
go back in time to the present day it
has just been that case of kicking the
can down the road in an attempt to
basically strangle the hemp and CBD
industry to uh I feel submission uh in
all honesty I don't think there's people
out there that want this industry here
and uh my fight in essence is to show
that everyone has a right to be here
whether it that be the small to
mediumsized producers or your big boys
but at the end of the day because of
that slow strangled effect it's pretty
much the same across the board we are
seeing companies close but we are seeing
companies who seem to be doing really
well in the current climate so it's a
little bit paradoxical I in that effect
but um yeah it it it is kind of holding
a steady path slightly going down but
we're hoping that basically the
regulatory authorities will be a little
bit more firm and sensible in in uh
their Direction coming on from here so
hopefully we could be at at the trough
part you know and there is that
recognition that there should be a CBD
industry here and hopefully the industry
uh the industry Regulators will provide
a sensible route forward that benefits
all companies so yeah it is low but
hopefully it's it's going to start
playing and out
now are we in a scenario and it seems to
be in a couple of countries where the
CBD industry and cannabis industry was
so new that the parameters and the rules
weren't ever set so it was kind of
free-for-all and anybody could get in
and anybody could get an ingredient from
anywhere in the world and put it onto
the shelves are we just basically seeing
now the
the grown up part of this sector where
it has to be regulated there has to be
certain licenses for ingredient
suppliers whether it's CBD or whatever
cannaboid it is that everybody now has
to obey these exact parameters otherwise
we're not going to be able to uh
comfortably allow the population to take
this is that kind of where we are do you
think in the UK that we're now getting
to the stage okay the Bad actors or the
nefarious actors or the easy supply side
of the industry is getting crushed and
the established and the more regulated
large scale commercial operators are the
ones that are going to end up being able
to thrive in this
space I I think there's there's like I
said a mixture of uh small and
mediumsized companies and big companies
that are doing well in the current
climate but when it comes to uh
regulation now there's there's always
going to be companies that are going to
try and circumvent um regulation in any
way uh for example there's wind coming
out from the FSA that they're looking to
Target um C press uh hemp producers now
part of that involves the fact that
people may or may not be using uh CBD
isolate based products misdescribed as C
press now in that sense you would think
yes something definitely does need to be
tackled there because product
misrepresentation to the
consumer you know that's obviously a big
thing in this industry um but to what
point is the regulation being a little
bit over
applied um if I go back to uh 2017 for
example when I first heard about novel
Foods I was kind of confused because in
my eyes if you had all the sensible lab
reports the canabo profile the mot toxin
the uh fungicidal herbicidal all of them
you had your um full lab reports for the
finished product traceability across the
board what's wrong with your products um
but then your flip side is
it's is more required when it comes to
the ultra refined um isolate based
products yes I believe that is the case
uh but certainly with more whole plant
products I feel that there was sensible
legislation or direction that was
available at that time um but when it
comes to uh the isolate products and
that kind of um understanding being
applied across the board then of course
where is that kind of sensible ground
you know we are we really um looking at
com uh you know comparing CBD isolates
to full spectrum products it just seems
a little bit skewed and there needs to
be that level ground where each product
Dynamic is accurately represented
without having a cloud over it that that
comes from a different Dynamic if you
know what I mean kind of overshadowing
um the CBD content you know the 10 mil
ADI that came from lab reports for
synthetic CBD and CBD isolate so should
a broad or a full spectrum product be
stuck at 10 milligram per day you you
know that it just seems a little bit
wrong so yeah there there was sensible
kind of guidance I think it's got kind
of over
complicated uh now but equally from an
FSA standpoint you can kind of
understand why they've that across the
board because it makes their life easy
but it makes the industry's life a
little bit awkward so yeah um it it is
it an easy world is is there the right
level of Regulation um or or
requirements was that there before I
think that's a little bit of a hard
question to answer because in some
aspects yes in other aspects
no yeah it's a very interesting sector
and as I said still lots more evolving
to happen there moving on now to a topic
that I know you've done a lot of
research and investigating about is the
GW Pharma and the Jazz Pharmaceuticals
relationship for everybody who doesn't
know Jazz Pharmaceuticals bought GW for
six and a half billion I think it was a
number of years ago 7.2 what have you
found out in your course of
Investigations about the proprietary
ownership of certain drugs and was the
transaction actually fully completed
based on what you can
see it's a bit of a hard question I know
there's an investigation at the moment
in the US in regards to um
misrepresentation uh on GW
Pharmaceutical side when they were sold
to uh Jazz um so there is a little bit
of a uncertainty I I don't understand
why that's not potentially being picked
up here uh if it's something that the US
authorities deem is important uh but
when it comes to Jazz and GW um I I
believe that there's an agreement in
place uh that agreement became apparent
in 1998 when the home office accepted a
22p point plan from Dr Jeffrey guia
co-founder of GW and that plan was to
regulate and control Canabis in the UK
now is GW a separate entity still I
believe it is uh you can trace them
through uh company's house if you go to
Jazz Pharmaceuticals uh canabo age it is
labeled for GW um you know there is an
indication that jazz in itself aren't
happy with the way that their canabo uh
interests have progressed and that they
are looking potentially to sell it but
if they sell it what would that be would
that be GW that they're selling or would
it be their canabo arm so there is a
little bit of uncertainty when someone
says oh oh yeah Jazz brought GW yes but
uh in what context did they buy to to
assimilate them into their business
model and work on or are they keeping as
a separate entity and why are they
keeping them as a separate entity I
believe that that's because there's a
public private partnership at play but
certainly uh since
2021 uh when Jazz did buy GW uh from
that point working up to the 30th of
November last year every patent
extension or or new patent assigned to
epids is awarded to G far GW pharmer
limited or GW research limited and GW
research limited on the 30th of November
changed their name to Jazz
Pharmaceuticals research UK limited but
at the same time they're owned by Jazz
uh sorry GW Pharmaceuticals and have
been since the six uh the 6th of the 4th
2016 this is all on on company's house
by the way um so there is UNC certainty
um are are they carrying on um you know
if the the patents are in their name um
you know is it Jazz that submitted them
or is it GW that submitted them and of
course is GW still its separate entity I
I think it's plain to see at the end of
the day um and it's quite understandable
because in a public private uh
partnership format um you've used public
funds and resources to create an entity
most likely with a monopoly right so at
some point in that contract there has to
be a return for the public so public
private Partnerships can be sold to
companies like jazz was sold to GW uh
sorry GW was sold to Jazz so that needs
to be kept separate to the point that it
can be shown that they have achieved a
certain area where the public can start
seeing a return but that's unfortunate
because that agreement comes with a 22
point to regulate and control cannabis
in the UK so petitions that get set up
that are you know buffed back because
the government have no interest in
talking about cannabis that's because
that 22o plan what we're seeing in the
CBD industry 16 lab reports uh from
epids uh unnamed but accounted for
observers in the center of toxicity uh
meetings the defined application
requirements for CBD novel Foods um you
know they have their place and their
place is to become a world leader in
medicinal CBD and canono based products
so having a conversation about cannabis
does not suit that agreement having a uh
a large and thriven CBD industry um that
does not suit that agreement but at some
point that agreement will get to a point
where the public sees a return and
that'll be an interest interes in
day yeah it definitely seems to be the
drug Discovery and development of
formulations is the the holy grail for a
lot of these big companies and anything
that they can do to ensure that they can
protect those long-term gains I think is
H is what's in place at the moment we're
nearly at our time here
now sorry there is one issue there
though when you when you to look at it
in a pharmaceutical sense in a single
molecule kind of uh product okay
but we're talking about cannabis and
cannabinoids we have an endocannabinoid
system so in essence there's a fair
argument to say that cannabis is a food
before a medicine now I believe that GW
Pharmaceuticals and Jazz know that it's
a food before a medicine but what
they're trying to do is clamp down on
that so that their profits are maximized
when your need becomes
medicinal yeah it's it's so fast to
watch this industry evolve and happen as
as we're kind of in the tick of it and
to see all these small little Splinter
things that are happening outside the
main kind of consumer platform just
before we go for anybody who hasn't ever
been to the hound. co.uk yet or doesn't
follow Kevin on LinkedIn I highly highly
recommend it one of the best sources of
investigative journalism in the UK
industry for you who are some of the
other good voices in the UK that people
should be following or listening to okay
the kind of Consultants uh definitely
without a doubt Steven Oliver and Matt
Lawson excellent excellent in what they
do as well as their interpretation on
how the industry is evolving I would
also say Kyle esplin uh from the
Scottish hemp Association he is a wealth
of knowledge and enthusiasm for the
plant as a whole without a doubt he's
definitely someone to uh keep an eye on
um as for other people I mean forgive me
it doesn't matter who I I think awesome
really people should be keeping an eye
on what's happening with the trade
associations because they should be the
ideal source of information right I I'm
of course doing my investigative
journalism um I'm not really too certain
on what they're doing uh but ultimately
they should be the ones that are
relaying current information uh out to
the industry and um I I forgive me for
saying it if if if they're not doing it
then maybe there should be someone El
about yeah I think that's the case
across a lot of countries M
unfortunately still with a lot of uh
barely good enough type of people as
opposed to people who are excelling
within this industry and can understand
the various perspective and nuances that
are going to need to be applied across
the various sectors of the Cannabis
industry as a
whole
sorry it seems like that's going to be
the case for sure yeah yeah um but you
you know
there yeah there are those people out
there certainly the cans Consultants um
Carl eslin um I would say to to an
extent there is some amazing um uh uh
academics out there there's uh Dr Ruth
fiser as well as Dr Jeff cutter they are
in the US and the and in Australia
respectively uh but they offer different
Windows into how the world is evolving
um admittedly those windows do tend to
uh kind of show uh um a a repetitive
angle as it were you know anywhere that
talks regulation tends to talk about it
with GW lab reports so uh you will see a
little a lot of that and uh obviously
alternative takes on the way that the
world is
evolving yeah um I'd definitely love to
chat to you again in the next couple of
months and hopefully we both have
updates on what's happening in Ireland
and what's happening in the UK and we
can share information but for now Kevin
thank you very much for your time it's
very much
appreciated no great for being here
thank you very much Owen not at all
until next episode
[Music]
everybody