[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i am delighted to
join this episode with owen smith owen
has two decades of experience in the
canadian cannabis industry and possesses
a wide range of subject matter expertise
based on two decades working with
everybody in industry from patients to
advocates dispensaries producers and
processors he's also one of the most
important men when it comes to edibles
in canada so owen thank you very much
for taking the time to join us today
thank you for having me owen
great to have you on mate great to have
you on so you seem to be an integral
part of one of the big sectors within
the cannabis industry in canada and
getting the
legislation and the legal process moved
forward can you maybe give everybody an
overview of how long you've been in the
industry from say your general manager
days and in in the dispensaries true to
aurora and where you're at now
well i think
i uh came in right at the um sort of
this
wave of cannabis advocacy on the west
coast that happened in the mid 90s my
family i moved here in the mid 90s from
england
and uh
they didn't have any idea they were plop
plotting me down in in such a hotbed of
of herbal medicine activism
but i started off with the university in
college as a volunteer and this man
named ted smith who owned the very first
cannabis dispensary in canada it's the
longest running it's still open it's
still operating we'll talk about that
he introduced me to medical cannabis
back in the early 2000s when i was at
college and university
and i not just stand medical but the
hemp and and really just um
opening my eyes to
sort of the
opposite view that i've been taught as a
child and many is taught during
prohibition the cannabis is bad
but
he taught how there's many positive uses
for it and i became his employee some
years later
my
my younger sister contracted cancer skin
cancer
melanoma skin cancer and
she was at the end of the options from
the doctor and ted smith in the club at
this time in the early 2000's
helped her during the last months of her
life she
did die after one year after contracting
melanoma it's very dangerous
uh deadly
condition
um but she uh she got benefited quality
of life-wise being able to restore her
abilities to to eat and have a have a
good sleep which helped her communicate
with her family during the last few
months jesus you can imagine there's an
invaluable time to be able to
communicate with your loved one who's
going to die so
i saw the value in that and i wanted to
help so i became the baker and the
product maker for ted smith i was only
one year after i started that that i got
arrested now in a local downtown uh
apartment building in victoria bc
and in response to the arrest we raised
a constitutional challenge
and this was to uh the current medical
marijuana laws which only allowed in
canada people to have dried cannabis
and
they would have to smoke it or they'd
have to chew it and swallow that down
hole which didn't make any sense to us
we extracted cannabis into vegetable
oils and butters and made food out of it
to serve people with cancer and aids and
lots of serious medical conditions you
know only only helping those who had
permanent physical diseases and ailments
and so taking it to court in 2012 we won
uh in the bc supreme court
we then took it
all the way up to the supreme court of
canada where we had a unanimous
uh victory there and instantly made
edibles oils extracts legal for anybody
in canada to make
uh that
sorry for interruptions that's the orvi
smith challenge that you're describing
there is it
that's right yes
and uh i'd be the smith but uh there's a
ted smith as well and we're not related
but uh we
we uh you know worked together all the
way through
met all the way through the
communications campaign that went along
with it we launched a newspaper called
cannabis digest
and we use that to help
publicize the the truth about the case
while the newspapers muddied it up and
got the details wrong we published 10
000 copies and distributed them across
the country just to make sure that
people knew what was really going on and
after we did win in supreme court of
canada
the government were forced to make laws
they called section 56 laws and they
introduced a new uh limits called a
three percent limit
on the strength of the edibles and oils
and this was a limit that wasn't
established in the court
but this is something that governments
can do they make laws
here in canada and courts
chop them down chop them up uh make them
null and void the parts which aren't
constitutional
and so uh the government in my opinion
is reintroduced an unconstitutional
limit an arbitrary limit on the strength
of the edibles and that has carried over
into the legal system so if you want to
buy legal recreational cannabis uh
edible otherwise you're restricted to a
very
low dose and while that's good helps
people get in uh
newbies especially
who we really cared about who we're
really working for is the most sick most
vulnerable most in need and those people
need higher doses
and so we continue to provide higher
dose cannabis against the law in
victoria bc to
or
more than that there's quite a lot of
people
who access cannabis through the victoria
cannabis buyers club
this is the longest running dispensary
in canada
and this uh club was recently charged
6.5 million dollars a fine was sent from
the provincial government
to uh
basically to shut the club down which is
not going to work
in response to that a
another constitutional challenge has
been raised a
big 700 page
document full of patient stories full of
legal arguments has been
in health canada's hands for over a year
now
and
we're pushing for an exemption to the
cannabis act so that we can continue to
provide those higher strength
cannabis products
to those who have higher needs
and uh and so that's something that we
uh
protest in the street for still these
days just last week was down in the
front of city hall in victoria bc
doing a
live trivia cannabis game show with a
crowd of people where we
showed the public that we can be a fun
uh open community of people very
knowledgeable and teach a few things
while we're out in the public
so
it's uh it's been that way
all along trying to
bring cannabis out of the shadows trying
to be as
out there as we can come out of the
closet as a cannabis community
and uh and it's a lot of fun
so it's not all serious amazing
amazing so after you guys were
successful with the orbeez smith
challenge what was the what was it like
then creating a community channels of
communication with the relevant parties
be able to ensure that what you guys
wanted got enacted
well it's
what we had uh argued with the harper
government all the way to the supreme
court of canada the harper government in
canada wanted to introduce
mandatory minimum sentencing for
what i was doing and also for growing
more than six cannabis plants these are
a new laws at the time that we protested
against
so the government in canada especially
the conservative government has been
very oppositional to cannabis and so
no no easy communications could be made
there here in bc it's a little bit
different and we've had things like the
sensible bc campaign which came before
legalization where we tried to
decriminalize cannabis um but that
didn't work we have a much higher
bar for um we have to get more votes
than washington or colorado who at that
time
their voting initiatives got them
legalized cannabis so we've had to fight
really hard in canada it's a
bit of a high bar i think for getting
this this out but uh with the liberal
government now there's since they put in
uh kind of the cows act they have a
four-year review of that act which has
been delayed thanks to covid
but
while working with aurora cannabis i
helped to
put together some suggestions and uh
some ideas that the government might uh
use to improve the system
uh including the obvious ones that i
just mentioned
but there's other there's a lot of other
ways we can improve cannabis in canada
too and a lot of fun that
could still come to what is really over
regulated hyper-regulated
industry
which you can expect because we're the
first in the world but what i'm excited
about is
tourism
we want to encourage people to come from
ireland
to enjoy a
nice farm tour from cannabis tours
enjoy our beautiful natural
environment
and
the finest cannabis that you'll ever see
or experience in your life and a touch
of the culture that's grown up here too
which is a lot of fun
so tourism is certainly certainly a part
of that
incredible yeah i think tourism it's one
thing you haven't heard come out of
canada yet is any sort of proportion or
any sort of cannabis tourism whereas we
even in ireland we hear things about
vegas and arizona where you can go over
there a lot of people go to california
you've got new york coming online now
which is gonna i think be a a huge hub
yeah i think the
the channel communication between the
canadian tourism companies who may be
operating these tours and europe don't
seem to be a
as clear as yet
it can be a lot of fun before
legalization i operated
a couple of
consumption lounges they called vapor
lounges
where you'd have
cannabis cocktails being served you come
and have a bloody mary jane
or another one of these that we made up
fun names and the dab bar laid out
so you could learn how to
dab not sure how much dabbing goes on in
in ireland
but here it's very popular on the west
coast
and i will teach you how to do these
things a little bit safely have somebody
there who can instruct new newcomers
people maybe
coming from overseas um
you need a little bit of instruction on
how to consume cannabis safely
but not a lot
and
it's something that attracts a lot of
culture so
would have musicians coming in
comedians sort of a central hub
in a way for the community
and it's so nice to be able to come out
of the woodwork and come together and
have a centralized place to consume and
and communicate and socialize
i feel like after
so much isolation social isolation in
the world we could all use sitting down
and uh having a nice cup of vape or
whatever it is we're gonna be able to do
very interesting so quickly before we go
what are you looking forward to over the
next 12 to 18 months in the canadian
cannabis industry what's the the one
thing you've got your eyes on
[Music]
well i definitely like i say the
consumption lounges is an issue which is
on the forefront of the british columbia
government
but there's a few others i mean it's
it's
slow moving in terms of development of
the industry here kovid
is part of that but we've just had
released the direct delivery
system so
finally bc producers can sell directly
to bc retailers without having to go
through the government warehouse we just
had a strike here in bc where no
retailers could purchase any cannabis
because the bc government controls
that channel but uh fortunately now that
is over
and the direct delivery is is in and the
next part of that is called farmgate
which is
having a store at your farm so that
people can come to the farm
meet you maybe go it's on a tour and go
to your gift shop and purchase some
cannabis there while they're on vacation
while they're on a tour
and
take that take that at least
while they're in canada
so these don't take it on the plane with
you
so farm gate and direct delivery are the
most exciting two things that are coming
to uh
to british columbia but consumption
lounges hot on the heels
and uh i
i look forward to the community being
able to come together more just this
year we had our first major
cannabis convention in victoria which is
the capital of british columbia
and we were able to take over the
empress hotel which is this landmark
piece of architecture in downtown
victoria and we had a vapor lounge right
in the center of town elevated
in front of everybody it really felt
like times had changed and uh
so
so i'm hoping for more of that
more uh
more of us to be able to share ideas
like this
and
develop the cannabis industry
creatively
amazing that's been great it's been
fantastic chapman to you a wealth of
information committee so far i think
everybody's going to have loved that
episode hopefully i'll be back on tv and
i'll get some suggestions for people to
talk to in the direct delivery the farm
gate and the the consumption lounge area
so we can inform everybody over in
europe what to expect the next time they
go to canada holidays
that sounds great yeah i mean if you if
you'd like any suggestions for people to
talk to over here i know some great
people
well indeed thank you very much allen
for taking part everybody we'll see on
the next episode
[Music]