[Music]
welcome to the next episode of the
cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined on this episode by lorenzo
romanesi she's the managing director of
the european industrial hemp association
how are you keeping today lorenzo
good morning good morning everybody and
thanks for the invitation i'm good a
little bit busy but uh we are very very
happy in this moment so
everything good on the show i know
you're a very busy lady so we very much
appreciate you taking the time out can
you maybe give everybody a quick little
overview of how you got to the managing
director of the eiha and we can get in
then
yes sure so um i joined a uh
in
february 2019
i was working before always in the
public affairs but in the wine sector so
i had this opportunity to to join and
growing and growing and agricultural
sectors so i was delighted to accept
this role and and i keep working with
with very with very pleasure and a lot
of motivation and passion for for this
sector
is a sector that certainly as i said is
growing uh is a sector that
is perfectly matching the society needs
as well
it's um
so it's a real it's a real pleasure to
to work for the association just to
remember to all the audience that the
association is mainly representing
companies
three
types of companies let's say three major
operators the producers of hemp the
processing companies and the traders of
hemp and its private products
okay brilliant can we maybe jump into
the first topic then straight away is
the overview of the hemp industry in
europe now i know we had a little bit of
a snails pace in terms of legislation
and movement over the last 12 months can
you give everybody a quick overview of
why everybody in the hemp industry in
europe is happy as of late and what the
future spells
yeah sure a quick overview it's
complicated because
europe is made of 27 member state and
for the moment when it comes to europe
the operator experience a fragmented
market there are member states that are
a little bit more
hemp friendly
when it comes i'm only referring sorry
to the upper part of the plants mainly
the
the hemp extract and the hemp derived
products and food products
in this case indeed we see a patchwork
of 27 different national legislation
this is why the european industrial hemp
association is is advocating for an
european framework where all the
operators can work with clear rules that
are the same from lisbon to warsaw
while today the operators are facing
different values different approaches
which complicate
which complicate the business
um
but hemp is more than only the upper
part of the plant so i'm very glad that
after what we might exchange some words
on other
sector than only food and food
supplement
nevertheless
why we are happy in this moment is
simply because
finally um one
country that is uh
great britain
uh has decided to move forward and to
regulate these products namely this hemp
derived product from the upper part of
the plants hemp extract containing cbd
and it's very complex so to sum it up um
they were fsa so the standards
authorities was looking at this product
and try to find a way how to regulate so
fsa encourage the sector to move into
the direction of
sending application and submitting
application novel food application to
measure uh the
tdi so the the the tolerable daily
intake for this product and the company
that were submitting a
toxicological studies package and they
were doing a novel food application and
they were on the market in february 2020
if they have completed all these
requirements from fsa they can trade
they can trade and they can stay on the
market with their product so
um
finally what we were asking and
advocating for that was legal certainty
it happened and it arrives even if only
in one country now the idea is that we
will apply
the same novel food application in
europe and submit this application as
well to fsa we have already submitted
some application uh based on the
preliminary results of the talk studies
that we are conducting but the studies
are not over yet um very briefly we
invested uh the member of a invested 3.5
million of euros into a toxicological
studies for both products
isolate cbd naturally derived and full
spectrum extract
on top of that we among these 3.5
million of euros 1.6 is dedicated to thc
toxicological studies on human beings
with the scope of increasing the levels
of th c
only in the final products
okay so just a quick overview that novel
feud applications are available in the
uk at the moment i think i saw the list
just like 3 500 companies got you to the
very last round but maybe 10 of them are
actually going to get approved i think
one of the irish companies chanel mccoy
was one of the first to get approval
over there as well so what we're looking
to do is take the model of the uk build
replicate it into the european food
safety authority model and how long do
you think it's going to take the
european model to enact what the uk
brought to fruition
oh well let's clarify because
when the novel food application process
started in uk
i mean the uk was still part of europe
so
it's not that uk has a special
methodology they just applied it faster
because they added a deadline well while
in europe there is no deadline but the
application is the same okay so
there were minor uh differences with
fsa
sorry but then the process is the same
so what we have been doing in uk in this
moment we did it because of the time
constraints that we had
now we simply do the rest
towards efsa
for instance efsa is different because
what we liked and what we
we are very happy that our member can
enjoy is the fact that they can stay on
the market because fsa the only slightly
difference is that they created an
intermediate step that is so clear today
in uk while is not in europe meaning the
companies that have done the three
requirements that i've stated before can
stay are waiting for evidences
while in europe if you do not have
completed your toxicological studies
this product should not be marketed
because the provision called the
temporary period has been deleted from
the novel food regulation european novel
food regulation in january 19.
this is why today we have 27 different
approaches
yeah well i think the clear science and
regulation i think is what we're all
screaming out for in the industry and i
think it's gonna
did you can see the top brands are
already kind of coming to the fore at
the moment and i think it's gonna get
rid of the cowboys and have a couple of
i think the m a action over the course
of 2023 and 2024 with the emergency
acquisitions that are going to happen in
the european industry
yes um
as i said let's wait for the
toxicological studies and the final
submission that will dramatically
clarify the status of these products in
europe every uh
when it comes to the association the
talk studies are nearly over for full
spectrum then sorry for the isolate cbd
while the food spectrum is still ongoing
then it comes the risk assessment from
fsa and fsa both they last nine months
and then the first results according to
my to our opinion might arrive in 2023
the full risk assessment
yeah well i think a lot of our fingers
crossed for that the next topic i wanted
to talk to you about was hemp and
construction now we hear a lot of food
and noise about the novel food
application but if you have your eye in
the industry you understand that the
real capital and the real
markets are going to move towards ipable
constructable products used from hemp
fiber can you maybe give everybody a
little overview of hemp and construction
and who you see with some of the leaders
and what's happening in that territory
yeah
um
let's start from an assumption the hemp
sector will be a big sector and a major
sector
only if the operators will have access
to all parts of the plant so now we are
simply focusing on the upper part of the
plants because we need to clarify to
legally clarify
the extract and the cbd
products
while hemp is much more hemp is composed
by fibers as well by seeds so
the real the real industrial hemp sector
should be an industrial sector as the
name
called us
and
that
is planted firstly in open air it has
been harvested on the field with
machineries and the best uh the best
model for for hemp according to the
association is the so-called tripolis so
we process and we collect the stalks
that contains the fibers then we
separate the biomass the green materials
namely the what is left
from fruiting top from flowering top
then we collect the seeds to produce dry
dry food or seeds oil so this is the
perfect model for hemp now let's focus
on the bottom part of the plant and as i
said at the beginning i'm very happy
to to have the chance to speak uh
to discuss with you about something else
than cbd
so indeed the construction sector has a
huge potential it's quite uh
well established or is yeah it's quite
well established in europe but
especially the interest is growing the
fact that the demands are higher than
what the sector can supply is a good
is a good signal and the good reply from
the sector is that the construction
sector
can be scaled up quite quite easily
compared to other uh to other sectors so
first of all let's clarify what we are
talking about when we are talking about
hemping construction it can be used in
the following application can be used as
an insulation material
from the corticated technical fibers it
can be used as a hemp grit made of
sheaves and lime
it looks like
blocks or bricks
or prefab walls as well we have members
that are doing these technologies as
well and as well with in restoration of
architecture architectural heritage and
the most developed country when it comes
to hemp construction is uk and france
this country are more
our most advanced market for for these
products
um
the potential of the of the hemp in
construction is is very is very high uh
as a conversion to natural material is
expected in a construction sector we
know that the european union
in when thinking about the future of the
of the construction they are integrating
uh natural and bio-based products so is
the good moment for for for hemp um
there are some
bottleneck today uh
these bottlenecks are in the
in the supply chain basically
europe is
dramatically lacking of at the
cortication lines uh there are we count
in europe less than 10 decortication
lines which is not enough to uh to
supply all the demands of these products
but nevertheless as i said before these
in
the investment needed are
not
not so important compared to fibers on
compared to to the processing of fiber
to produce long fiber so again a lot of
potential
it's good for the sector it's good for
the operator and especially we should
not forget it is extremely good for the
environment because the time is running
out but we should as well discuss about
all the good quality
of the of the hemp construction material
when it comes to
fire resistant when it comes to
antibacteric resistance so um these are
pro these are all aspects that should be
taken into account when we discuss about
the construction in help
amazing that's a great overview now for
most people i think if you if you have a
look at the industry really it's
insulation it's hem crete there are a
couple of different territories where
this fiber in this material just works
as a perfect ingredient for these end
products and i think that or d over the
next 12 months or 18 to 24 months should
be pretty exciting for the building
industry in in europe because i think
you're only starting to see some of the
big big players start to maybe have an
or a deep facility where they're working
on it or outsourcing it to other
companies and i think yeah that's the
one if you could if you're if you've got
capital to expand in the european market
that's where my money will be going
your investment could be could be
growing your investment if you invest
today in this kind of company we are
seeing members that are working with
this product joining aya because of the
the interest is certainly
increasing increasing
yeah well we're just at the time there
15 minutes i'm not going to keep you
long because as i said i know you're a
very busy lady we very much appreciate
your time and explaining giving
everybody a quick overview of these
topics and we hope you have a lovely day
and hopefully we can chat again towards
the end of the year and we're given even
more bigger smiles over more greater
news that we've heard let's hope thank
you again for inviting me here today and
i wish you all a very nice day thank you
very much lorenzo have a great day and
chat to everybody again soon bye