foreign
ER give me two seconds I'm just gonna do
that again
[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis review everybody
I'm delighted to be joined this episode
by Conor MacLeod who's the founder of
kanaman TV based in Scotland how you
keeping today Connor mate I'm doing very
well man how you doing I am fantastic
man thanks very much for taking the time
to do this thanks for the invite yeah
pretty much delighted to have you answer
I was doing I got a bit of research in
in media and cannabis and I came across
a load era series and found some of the
hilarious so I thought I'd get you on
and we can get it I have a little
discussion on cannabis media do you
maybe want to give everybody a quick
little overview of how you ended up in
the industry and and starting up Panama
TV yeah certainly essentially like most
of us
been smoking since I was about uh 14 15
kind of thing consuming the whole time
and uh as time goes on you kind of find
yourself in a position where you take a
direction there's things that you're
passionate about so uh yeah I just
decided to you know bring it into a into
something entertainment based so uh so
yeah it's been good the kind of on TV
that's really a consequence of the
forethought really so the Cannabis
industry has kind of been in this
emphasis the whole time and uh it's just
been emerging with this consuming
cannabis is aware that you know it's
it's only at the beginning stages so I
thought
apply a passionate element into it I've
always been in the drawing so at the
same time as uh consumer cannabis um I
started to make the comics uh over this
side here you see these Comics here and
instead making them and they're
developing it into an animation series
and as a consequence of trying to make
it visible to the industry uh create the
podcast and uh as a kind of like our
trajectory for the animation series and
it's taking a long time to get to a
stage where the animations is ready so
it's only in the past year one halfway
through season two so uh so yeah the
engine's running and uh yeah it's good
to see where it's going
yeah it's great to see I think once you
get into the in the content side of the
things you kind of realize that at 50
100 episodes is when you'll actually
start to get comfortable living that
it's gone a couple of cool little
questions on your episodes like how long
does each episode take to make from the
start to the idea to the end and the
production of post-production
a month so it's four weeks four four
solid weeks like essentially I'll hook
up with the idea each the other thing
I'll point out as well at the moment um
I'm working through season two so season
two um each one of the animations that's
happened at the moment from uh season
one scene one season one and season two
is essentially uh an animation adapted
from this comic book uh here that one
there essentially so there's there's 14
um original kind of man comics that's in
that book and uh that took about 14
months because each one of the comics
was a month to make
um so then that was the intention the
foundation was for the comics that have
then adapted them at the animation
series so I'm on episode 11 which is
season two episode four so this is Comic
eleven so I've got three more after this
now we've seen uh season two finished
and I'll be all the original Comics will
be done
um of from the original comic books and
uh and I'll be working on season three
um but it's a month per episode for
animation from the idea the storyboard
but essentially because of the fact that
these are adapted from the comic book
series I don't need to do a storyboard
because the storyboard comic itself so
um so one season three arrives one of
the original Comics are done that'll be
exciting because that'll be completely
new content there will be no Comics
based on it that'll be like um my
intention is to create kind of like a
format so each season is seven episodes
and uh for scene for season three the
seven episodes are going to be in
correlation with the seven principles of
the hermetic philosophy and I'm gonna
essentially intertwine the uh cannabis
rhetoric cannabis narrative contemporary
cannabis information
on top of the seven principles of the
hermetic philosophy because it would
kind of be you know eventually it'll be
fun I find both and passionate about
both and uh and yeah so it's a month per
episode and at the moment I'm on uh
comic 11 essentially episode 11 so um
but I don't know if you're aware um I've
mentioned on a couple of other podcasts
but I'm actually working on the kind of
man movie that'll be ready at the end of
August
um and that's I'm only about scene four
and uh scene four of nine and again uh
each scene takes a month and this is
what's interesting about the process of
creating the comics is that inevitably
it's been a uh each comic has been a
precursor tip episode and the episode
has been a Precast to the scenes so it's
really a domino effect
um and it's really a fascinating end
process because it's not exclusive to
even animation this is consistent it
seems to be with any craft any Endeavor
there's a whatever you do in the micro
is representing the macro you know and
the micro in this case is the the single
panel Comics then I went on to the film
comics and then the macro in this sense
is the is the movie which is uh let's
say that's going to be
that's going to be a belt on nowadays
I very much look forward to it and you
also wrote a book a case for cannabis if
I'm not mistaken correct that's right
yeah yeah okay what was the reason
behind that was that a long process was
it just trying to get your thoughts out
on paper was it a an actual specific
strategic I'm going to convince an
argument to this type of audience
essentially the the the case for
cannabis was written in 2019 2000 and
the end of 2018 2019 and the reason why
I wrote it was because uh I was putting
the the planning into doing the channel
so I was linking to myself with most
people that are cannabis orientated if
you promote any form of discussion based
on cannabis to the lame and they'll
think that you're just promoting
something that you like so inevitably
you're going to be biased so I was like
well I don't have any credentials
there's no academic background for any
form of science or chemistry or
biochemistry so I was like what can I do
to provide a foundation of
professionalism I don't have a white
coat that's no that would help and so I
was like well if I create a book and
this this academically referenced then
I'll be able to promote myself in a much
more professional manner when the
channel arrives so I was like it took me
four and a half five months to write and
the case for cannabis and that was about
three months before I started the
channel
um and the case with cannabis
essentially is a it's like 10 11
chapters each chapter is relevant to uh
main talking point in the Cannabis world
so it's essentially the best way to
describe the book is it's a broad
spectrum analysis of all the main issues
relating to cannabis so you've got a
chapter on endocannability system a
chapter on
um the terpenes a chapter on cannabis
medicinal value a chapter on
recreational Cannabis out sorry
Recreation of substance use and inside
that chapter I really enjoyed
researching for that one because what I
found was essentially compared cannabis
consumption and a recreational format to
other recreational substances but I used
alcohol but I also use caffeine and
energy drinks and the context of
caffeine and everybody's aware that
these things are kind of detriment to
your health but I had no idea I mean the
caffeinated energy drinks are
responsible for deaths you know like
energy drinks have killed people and yet
these things are rarely available on the
shop and then we've got this cannabis
this this very natural plant which is a
booster physiology which is still
prohibited it's still the information is
still being pushed underground
intentionally so um so yeah the book was
essentially a cathartic release of
information I've been collecting over
the course of years and then I've put a
really concerted effort Focus there for
over the course of four months to
complete all the Contemporary research
and put into the book and uh yeah I'm
delighted with it to be honest but the
only thing I would say is because of the
fact that I had nobody to proofread it
when going from one chapter to the next
it's kind of intense you know there's no
breathing room there's not any like side
step or we think it's just intensive
[ __ ] academically reference stuff so
so yeah but that's good and you can get
that on Amazon if anybody that's
interested
yeah definitely we've been putting up
the link to all of the plases of content
for Connor in the description on whether
it's YouTube or Spotify wherever you are
it is funny to see the hypocrisy from
some side of the things we can already
point to three and a half thousand debts
a year from alcohol in Ireland yet our
t-shock is out opening up a Distillery
for whiskey and at the same time trying
to say the Cannabis is bad uh it
resonates I think across the whole world
the hip-hop hypocrisy from one side to
the other that's bizarre I mean it's
really bizarre and I could see why
individuals who are not informed about
the the the chemical basis of the plant
and they have no knowledge of cannabis I
can see why they're kind of consumed by
the rhetoric that cannabis is a drug
it's bad for you all these kind of
things because you've essentially got a
society that promotes poisonous material
under the basis of tax really these
things I mean I don't know I'm pretty
certain alcohol the legislation behind
alcohol
um is based under a category of like
time period I think it's like 80 years
ago therefore it's still legitimate I
could be wrong
um but there's there's peculiar
legislation that's related to substances
which are poisonous and yet there is a
suppression of information for for this
plant which is beneficial actually
crucial I mean an interesting thing that
I found most explicit when I was writing
the book was that cannabis is not only
crucial to your endocannaborating system
cannabis and a consequence of
researching the plan itself
we discovered more about our own
physiology like we didn't know about the
endocannabino system we discovered parts
of our body and in a crucial uh the
master controller as a consequence of
cannabis like so we we found out more
about the human race as a consequence of
this plant and yet you're still punished
for it you've got people in prison for
it and you know people are dying because
they can't get access to it you know and
that's why let's say things like what
you're doing you know the Cannabis media
thing is so crucial to to kind of break
the stigma and uh I think personally the
the stigma and then the narrative that
cannabis is a a negative thing will
still be present long after the
legislation's passed and makes it more
favorable you know it's had a really
profound impact on the psyche of society
yeah it is guys to take the stuff like
magic mushrooms could just Breeze boy
legislation where it's kind of positions
this moral compass of wrongdoing but
that's neither here nor there as you
were staying in cannabis media is where
we kind of need to focus and that's the
next thing I wanted to talk about is the
Cannabis media and content on a global
scale I don't know about you but it
couldn't be more underwhelmed by the
content that comes out of America in
Canada from like companies that are
supposedly worth tens of millions or
hundreds of millions that they don't
have a couple of thousand to be able to
develop good content on a weekly boy
weekly or even monthly basis what are
your thoughts on the Cannabis media
content uh overview of the global
industry
very similar quite honestly I'm kind of
woefully out of touch when it comes to
really any entertainment based outside
of the UK I mean I don't even really um
pretty much attempt I spent so much time
focused on drawing and creating
animation which is kind of in concert
with your comment really because at the
same time is that there's not really a
significant presence of cannabis media
I'm trying to construct it independently
yeah yeah so even if you think as we
spoke just before a camera like there's
the the two the duo said and Mike a guy
and a girl from America I think they're
in very good work they're really
professional high-end shows some of it's
hilarious as well like that but your
your scraping that like single digit
kind of performers or YouTube channels
or whatever it may be not even
necessarily main big budget content it
just seems to be that there's not even
Brands behind content creators that are
sponsoring their channels or wherever it
may be do you think that's just a lack
of federal legislation in America and um
a lack of clarity in Europe or the
budgets aren't just even there or the
people running them just don't have a
clue how to run a cannabis business for
the Cannabis consumer industry
to be honest I think it could probably
be um a mixture of those things
legislative but I think a lot of the
time the the big mainstream cannabis
um like people that are behind these
kind of things are kind of it could be
that they're stuck in their ways so the
like High Times or or other individuals
that they've been producing content in a
particular way for so long that it's
very difficult to kind of become novel
you know it's very difficult to break
out of the the discipline in which
you've made yourself in the first place
and I think that's where
um podcasts or um Independent Media they
seems so unique and they're so necessary
because that's there that's they came
into the the kind of a space with that
is their their creative Outlet whereas
are these other creative Brands and that
are talking about cannabis they had
something different I'm thinking
predominant predominantly magazine based
really I mean it's very difficult to go
from being a predominantly magazine
orientated
um production to then going right let's
now sponsor to do a podcast let's now do
this so it could just be it could just
be aged
um production you know it could just be
that um I do also think as well that
it's kind of that there is so much
caution around how you speak about
cannabis that sometimes either not to
engage in conversation and sometimes
either not to produce that kind of
content because you could maybe make a
difference you can maybe make something
wrong or something like that so it's
like let's just we'll stick with what
we're doing and that'll be safe we've
got enough numbers and just kind of more
of a cautionary approach than one that
should be Innovative or one that should
be more focused on the fact that like
let's break the boundaries of how the
discussion has been taken place yeah it
seems to me it's just very strange if
you take something like M A for example
your lab DraftKings will sponsor 10 of
the biggest podcasts and have a blanket
let's say advertisement of all the main
consumers in that industry you'll get
the same with Coca-Cola and FIFA and a
number of other big Brands it just
doesn't seem to be that they either
haven't cut down to the opportunity
that's there because investment from
Brands will help grow a channel which
will help grow the audience and and vice
versa I think there's a massive
opportunity there for marketing officers
or content officers of companies to
people like yourself people like Martin
that we spoke about there's a number of
other uh top podcasts like the Cannabis
conversation with uh aroush and and a
couple of other guys so it'd be good to
see some of the money flown in towards
the content creation side of things and
pick up the speed in this industry
that's actually a great Point that's a
great point and I'm all for somebody to
respond to the Caravan stuff [ __ ]
right bring this bring the [ __ ] money
over it's necessary because let's be
honest we're all doing this for free
this is a this is a passion LED Endeavor
this is like you've got to try and pay
the rent at the same time as doing this
and I think that'd be a fantastic
um boost to what is everybody's doing
because you'll provide more of an
authenticity if you've been sponsored
but going back to what you mentioned
about the legislation barriers that's
potentially the reason why that's not
happened so if you're a if you're an
organization and you're sponsoring
uh private
um Independent Media that's based on our
plan or a substance that's illegal in
the region at the projection of content
that's kind of conflicting to your
marketing strategy you know it's very
difficult to make that you know and as
you know when it comes to innocent like
um Financial transactions that's based
in cannabis any form of financial
transaction with cannabis that's based
on a region that's um prohibiting it
immediately banks are [ __ ] not taken
out on board you know I mean you're
shutting it down and so I think the
amount of barriers that are in place um
could potentially be the main reason why
that's not happened and uh yeah I hope I
hope it changes I really do
yeah well I think we're one good piece
of legislation whether it be in the
Czech Republic be it in Germany be it in
federal legalization in the United
States away from a lot of M A activity
and a lot of more movement and the the
consumer being able to benefit from from
the the revenue and capital that the
companies that are selling them products
for should be able to benefit from there
should be Loyalty Rewards content
concerts there should be tons of things
that are being done for the consumer
that are actually spending the 10 euro
or ten dollars per gram on on specific
type of flower
I feel I agree and just come back to
actually what I said before about the
movie one of the things I'm hoping to
achieve is to get um legitimate sponsors
um through a cannabis businesses or
organizations for the movie itself and
to then promote it um essentially
originally through the UK but also
internationally so my intention is to
hopefully get into like the Montreal
film festival or Adelaide and I'm hoping
to get it um viewed down product airs
there's a numerous independent um
cinemas around Scotland um in northern
England as well that I'm hoping to get
viewed because essentially the basis of
the movie is going to resonate with
everybody that has any form of knowledge
of cannabis at all like the main body in
the movie people are going to know
immediately why he's the body the
fundamental story behind why caraman is
who he is immediately people are going
to be like oh [ __ ] it like this is going
to click so many things for people and
uh and interestingly as well the movie
even though it's got a very explicit
cannabis theme the bad is kind of
esteemed two bodies are kind of esteemed
actually the heroes cannabis team has
has role before he became kahneman's
cannabis themed that is on top of that
um undertone essentially underneath that
explicit um template is a story which is
based in all of our Journeys in life
where each single one of us is walking
through life with a quest of what we're
doing here why is it we're doing what
we're doing and it's essentially the
Philosopher's Journey that's what you're
dealing with
um whether you're aware of or not all of
us are walking through your life with
this existential pursuit of meaning and
that's the nature of what the kind of
man movie is it's an existential film
and with humor and a you know it's
[ __ ] swearing all the way through it
let's be honest and on top of that is
that the Cannabis
um story you know pharmaceutical basis
and all this kind of [ __ ] so that's
going to be a big deal this year that's
going to be a really exciting thing when
that's released um and it won't be
available online immediately and it will
be essentially doing a tour around the
UK Cinema wise and then after that most
likely it'll be through PayPal or
something like that like a download
subscription thing whatever you can
watch at one time and but that's going
to be
that's going to be in the same line this
is going to be the Cheech and Chong
animation and 20 years time people are
going to be talking about this this is
this is what this is May I absolutely
love it I love it they made the stuff
that you've got going on it's great to
see in here and as I said if the
Cannabis view can help in any way shape
or form promote or get the name out with
it and you just let us know we'd be
there to deal with you I appreciate that
a lot you know let's say once it's ready
a few months because I'm hoping to do
like kind of like a podcast tour and
when it's beginning when it's almost
ready so I'll be more than happy to be
delighted to come back honest with you
again you can guarantee that but uh for
now it's we're just at our time so I'm
gonna have to say goodbye we'll
definitely have a chat in a couple of
weeks or a month or so when you're
getting the tour down and I'd definitely
love to have another chance being great
off until you kind of you too man thank
you very much Happy days until next
episode everybody