[Music]
everybody today's episode of the
cannabis review i am delighted to be
joined on this show by jasmine moore
she's the founder and ceo of green
panther chef and a newly formed author
as well because her book just got
released yesterday how are you keeping
today jasmine oh i am amazing thanks for
having me i'm delighted to have you on
the show now so most people in
washington dc would know about you've
got to be the premium cannabis
connoisseur cooking up delete delights
over in that uh territory can you maybe
give everybody a little overview on
where you came into the industry and how
you're going to start a green panther
chef yeah definitely so i started green
panther chef in 2007
but i actually started cooking with
cannabis years probably like a decade
before that i had got diagnosed with
crohn's disease right after i had
graduated from culinary school and so
through the process i had dropped down
to around 84 pounds i was put on five
medications it was told this was
supposed to be my life right so i got
introduced to a doctor who introduced me
to um cannabis and just cooking with
plants in general so 13 years later i am
not on any of those pharmaceutical
medications and i exclusively use food
and cannabis for happiness
okay amazing so you had a very a firearm
journey to get to where you are now um
can you maybe give everybody a little
overview of some of the kind of events
you guys do kind of curated cannabis
events what is some of the best things
you guys have worked on over the last 12
months oh definitely so with our book as
well though we definitely do a lot of
private events
we do um a lot of catering and then
private events just for an elite
clientele in washington dc
yeah i can see infused dinner parties
being a huge thing when it comes to
europe legalization
can you maybe give the audience a little
overview of the best methods for cooking
with cannabis is it oil is a can of
butter is hash better than flour what
would be some of the top let's say three
tips that you give to the consumer who's
watching the show
definitely um know your numbers that's
number one if you want to know how to
create repeatable results you're going
to have to know your numbers that
doesn't have to go into knowing the
percentage of thc or cbd but just
knowing what's going to work with your
endocannabinoid system is that one to
five milligrams is that five to ten
milligrams and then upward um also as
well cannabis is allergic to water so
the best way to extract and get the most
out of your cannabis is in something
that is fat soluble so oils and butters
coconut oils as well but you want
something that doesn't have such a
drastic smoke point that you're going to
um
degrade your cannabis you're not going
to get the most out of your cannabis so
look for those extra virgin olive oils
look for those coconut oils look for the
the butters as well but those are the
best and something that's fat soluble so
no vegetable oil or canola oil or
anything like that to extract it
okay amazing let's move on now to your
recently uh
book that just got released can you give
everybody an overview of the story of
creating the book how you got it out and
uh some of your favorite pieces of this
oh absolutely i'm super excited we
actually just launched our pre-sale
yesterday so i'm going to share the link
with your community but it's called more
than a cannabis cookbook it took about
two years to do that or to write it and
um really it demystifies i want it to
bend perspective away from like sugary
treats you know into like a more
holistic approach of the plant i have a
lot of clientele who just want
approachable recipes and they want to
know how they can just cook for health
and happiness right so that kind of
spurred this book more than a cannabis
cookbook it has cook-offs it has
challenges over a hundred recipes as
well and it's broken into seven parts to
target the certain ailments of the
common ailments that people are dealing
with so gastrointestinal anxiety
insomnia migraines and how you can align
like your cannabis your terpenes and
your food so you can get the most out of
it
okay and can everybody expect to be able
to order that worldwide from what days
absolutely so we are actually going to
be worldwide december 15th of this year
but we definitely need your support by
clicking that link
okay
greenpantherchef.com everybody can see
the link down there to be able to go and
pre-order the book it's out in december
i'd highly recommend checking it out
we're going to move on to some of the
more uh talk about edibles in dc and
nationwide in america um who do you see
as kind of some of the premium brands
leading the way in like properly curated
uh manufactured edibles
oh definitely so there are some local
brands that are inside of maryland there
is one
it's a fruit chewy the name is drawing a
blank to me right now but it has really
great quality they're using um plant
sustainable products
like they are definitely leading the way
when it comes to light packaging and all
of that good type of stuff
but it is more on the sweet side of
things i really do like to um explore
the savory
and so using like building out your
plant pantry so a lot of the items that
we have are like the honeys the hot
sauces mayonnaises as well so you can
just like use those throughout the day
dude like in multiple uses you know and
just not like one dose and it just gets
repetitive and kind of old
okay and we have a chef jazz line of
products coming around the corner now
soon
yes absolutely
right now we do have two but we are
expanding it all out as a companion with
the book but you heard it first
okay honey taste and what's your
favorite recipe out of the book what
would you recommend if somebody was
starting off with their first recipe to
cook with cannabis what is is it a snack
in the afternoon for watching a movie is
it a brunch something with eggs what
would you maybe suggest somebody to dip
their toe into this
exact so there's two things i have one
recipe i've been cooking with this or
not even cooking i've been using the raw
cannabis flour and i've had so much
success with that um this drink is
called sexy on the inside so it has
basically using raw cannabis flour it's
a lot of green goodness inside of it but
i have that at least four times a week
you know and i've just had a lot of
success with that but one of my other
favorite recipes is our vegan seafood
paella
i love
yeah we're using oyster mushrooms in
there we're using a lot of like for the
umami flavor the capers and tomatoes and
it's just a beautiful dish
okay and dosage is a hugely important
part of this we had mara gordon on there
last week to talk about the art of
dosage how important is and how long
does it take you to kind of get the
exact dosage right for the different
consumers that are coming through your
doors yeah dosage does take a long time
that took me um in my beginning in like
my journey
i had a lot of trial and error around
that and so
you have to ask yourself if we break
down this in the book in detail but
asking yourself five questions really
and primarily just knowing your
percentage of your thc knowing your
carrier fat and the units of measurement
is going to lead you in the right
direction but in the book we actually
give you a table so you can plug and
play and you're able to create those
repeatable results so it really comes
down to like knowing those percentages
the numbers and then a calculator you
know it really isn't that difficult once
you know what to plug and play
yeah i suppose it's about sourcing the
perfect strain of flour first and
foremost for users and is there a
process that you go to if you're
creating a snack is it isolating right
this is the flour i'm going to use
because it contains this profile of
cannabinoids and terpenes and i know the
flavor is going to be x y and z out of
this is that kind of the process
absolutely and so when i am picking or
choosing a strand as well it's like what
is my outcome that's the first thing
when i'm working with a client how do i
want to feel as i always talk about
myself
when i talk because i have a
gastrointestinal issue crohn's disease
and so i really do look at strains or
cultivars that are higher in
beta-carotene you know and because the
reason being is because that interacts
with those gut receptors as well i look
for something if i'm dealing with a
little bit more pain management
something that's higher in mercy if i
need a little bit of boost i'll look for
something like limonene as well i really
pay attention to the terpene
content and then also second is like the
thc and cbd content
yeah i think terpenes are becoming a
thing with the canvas connoisseurs in
the market that they they're starting to
know their things and want those little
bit of extra bits of information on the
packaging
how are you going to see the eastern
seaboard of america
shaping up now that we've got new york
pretty much coming to market next march
what's the anticipation for there we are
definitely coming along i know it's been
a few years right we're a little bit
behind the west coast but we are coming
along um i know that there are some um
great uh i shouldn't say this online the
great consumption lounges there's some
great people that are talking to
politicians to push forward the
legislation um i am actually in
washington dc now and i've been asked to
speak
on a board just so they can kind of
navigate the language around how are we
going to introduce cannabis to the
public so i think that it's um
it's on the horizon
um federal legalization i'm not going to
give a date on that but it's definitely
on the horizon some people who need to
be in the room are finally starting to
discuss it and being taken seriously so
yeah
yeah i see consumption lounges being one
of the
focal points of the industry for
everybody to expect especially tourists
that are going to america new york vegas
these kind of territories i don't see
any reason why people are willing to pay
ten thousand let's say dollars for
bottle service and they won't pay the
exact same thing for uh premium broads
that was grown in the hills of nepal or
whatever it is they're going to come up
with so i think yeah and a music
curation combined with that environment
and that atmosphere i think could be as
big if not bigger than alcohol fueled
bars absolutely absolutely it's just
what it's going to take time it's going
to take education as well you know just
being more than a cannabis cook being
more than just like the standard so we
can break stigmas that's what it's all
about it's just more of acceptance and
you know and just opening up people just
have to learn a little bit more
yeah i think that's slowly marching on
that'll end up happening i'm gonna tilt
into something else give me the top
three songs that you listen to when
you're in the kitchen cooking
right okay so i do i love this artist
who's um named alkaline so i love a
little bit of reggae
i do love my top 40 like and then edm as
well so i love pop music i throw a
little bit of beyonce in there of course
and then i love like a little bit of edm
yeah i think it's those two worlds seem
to marry together so well the cannabis
industry and the music industry i think
there'll be uh so much more to to cover
in those two aspects um yeah i highly
recommend everybody checking out the
book you go to the greenpantherchef.com
website uh chef jazz i hope we can talk
again in the near future and we'll see
how the book has gone down absolutely so
yeah i will share the link but you will
see a big banner on the top of green
panther chef just smash that button and
you can get all the information there
you go highly recommended to be cooking
away in your own kitchen in no time
thank you very much chef jaz for joining
us thank you very much for watching
everybody we'll see you next time
[Music]