[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review we're going to be
talking all things copywriting and why
it's important in the cannabis industry
and to do that we are joined by an
expert in copywriting dave barton he's
the founder and copy chief at thermador
how are you keeping dave i'm all right i
think so in uh you know friday afternoon
here in the uk it's nice and sunny um
but yeah this is always
great when you're indoors on a lovely
sunny day you can
it makes no difference to me but no all
good thank you sir it's good to see you
in berlin where we caught up recently
yes very good to see it was a great
festival put on by alex and the guys we
might jump onto the festival stuff
towards the end of the episode but for
now you maybe want to give everybody an
overview of how you got into the
cannabis industry how you came to set up
termidor and the objectives of terminal
sure well we call ourselves a sort of
content led creative agency so i've been
a copywriter for
more years than i care to remember
probably more like sort of 17. um
started out in sort of b2b pr um my
background is very much kind of arts and
writing and drama and things like that
but in terms of finding a way into
writing his career it all became like oh
well you know what is this pr thing you
know i found myself working for an
agency doing
lots of uh
writing around obscure things like
construction equipment and uh work with
other agencies and everything from like
you know
engineering works to uh uh energy
efficient leds so really sort of sexy
stuff all food service mustn't forget
that that's mercenary if you ever get
the chance
but for me it was always okay so there's
a business objective lots of technical
jargon and how do we kind of find the
story thread through that so that's
something that's been consistent
throughout my career i set up as a
freelancer freelance copywriter about
five years ago um still her business
doing sort of tech writing and things
like that but about a year a year and a
half ago i started to see just more and
more stuff happening in the cannabis
sector and something i've always been
interested in anyway
and it was really an opportunity to take
that sort of skill set from you know
writing about complex or stigmatized
things and trying to find human stories
or find you know ways about you know
what does this mean or you know how are
things operating and the more you kind
of get into the cannabis sector the more
you find that you have to kind of do
some sort of advocacy to kind of raise
the industry uh for everyone so that's
kind of what we're trying to do trying
to work with more and more companies to
help tell those stories we're doing some
work with the cic here in the uk the
cannabis industry council um telling
everything from blogs helping with
websites
social media and we're doing our own
podcast as well the lobster pot and i'm
just trying to get different
perspectives from people all over the
world on what's happening
in their niche whether it be the niche
being a country or a particular part of
the industry i'm just trying to find
those stories so that's kind of what
we're about thermador um yeah so that's
copywriting is very much a core part of
that and like i say content driven
creativity and that really stems back to
words or anything else for me
yeah it's a great uh amount of con or
knowledge to have behind the topic that
we're talking about today because it's
the one thing i start to notice is that
for as the industry advances and gets
more mature the level of uh
let's say content or intellect in the
content needs to start upgrading towards
the likes of sportswear brands or retail
brands that are put in the amount of
effort
yeah
sorry i think it's definitely a symptom
of that i think absolutely the more
interest there is the more you need to
kind of stand out the more you need to
kind of communicate and i think there's
still a big education piece in cannabis
as well that's what i see i mean it's
very different from technology in many
respects but whereas in tech you have
kind of like taking smart people's ideas
and kind of making them palatable to a
business audience here you know there's
that stigma times 10 you know we're
talking about something that people a
lot of people regard as you know bad
drugs you know and things like that or
you know and then you've got other
people saying well actually it's
medicine like well how can same thing be
okay drugs medicine but you know there's
a lot of stigmas to overcome and a lot
of different ways that you know people
engage with cannabis and i think you
know there's that's on the job to be
done but lots of people i speak to
always have a very
touching often personal story about why
cannabis matters to them how it's
improved their lives or the lives of a
loved one
and i think that's you know it's hearing
those stories and helping that's the
anecdotal evidence that helps to educate
people and i think that's what content
is really good at doing
yeah and this is basically the first
topic i wanted to talk about now for
entrepreneurs getting into this industry
or looking to set up their own business
first and foremost start off with
everybody what is copyrighting and why
is it important for a brand regardless
whether it's cannabis or not
well i copyrighting essentially is you
know the written word and marketing so i
mean you have you know people who write
ads for tv might write scripts i mean
for me i guess more and more over the
last sort of well in my career
i sort of got into it at a time when
there was an opportunity you know there
was more and more digital communications
and as you start to see things like
websites and blogs people using content
marketing to differentiate their brand
to really you know
differentiate you know their kind of
tone of voice to kind of stand out and
then there's a whole industry around seo
i mean i'm gonna get into that but again
he's like trying to increase your
presence online as a brand
using content as a way to establish
your expertise your tone of voice how
you want to engage with your customers
and i think you always have to have that
customer in mind who's going to read
your content how are they going to find
it useful and those are a lot of
questions i think we try to ask our
clients and people we work with you know
it's not just about writing you know
something for your website it's thinking
about you know who are your customers
why they're going to find this
interesting what value does this deliver
it's not about you know our website we
do this this is great you know we do all
these wonderful things as a company you
know we sell you know zebras to you know
and things like okay well that's fine
but what's the point why do people want
to buy zebras what's important about the
zebra industry i'm just you know being
facetious um but again it's that whole
thing it's like who are you talking to
why is what you can do a solution to
their problem and there's so many
different ways you can kind of spin that
you know whether it be through web
content
and there's so many different ways that
you know
that becomes relevant through different
channels i mean you know talk about
social media as well as websites as well
as you know through i guess conventional
media as well i mean so much of it's
online and so many opportunities to use
content to your advantage that any
business isn't is really missing a trick
really um and i think they say in b2b
something like you need seven different
brand engagements
for someone to start buying products i
mean it's different from you know if
you're selling a chocolate bar or
something like that but if you're
selling something like a piece of
technology for example people gonna need
to know that they could you know you
know what you're talking about that
they're buying into something that is
interesting and will actually help them
you know do everything from you know
save them money it will increase their
efficiency all those sorts of things and
you know
that is what is at the heart of content
and similarly same with cannabis as well
you know i guess if you
uh in a kind of b2b environment if
you're selling a piece of machinery or
something like that you need to not only
talk about its features and benefits but
you know what's the impact you're gonna
have for your customer is it gonna you
know make them more money is it gonna
help them improve efficiencies and put
more you know
pre-rolls through per hour or whatever
it might be so and that was not
necessarily the interesting things the
interesting thing is that you know the
impact something like that will have and
that's where the story aspect comes in
so there's a lot of elements i see
caught up in it i mean you know it's
like journalism but it's more of a kind
of slant towards you know selling stuff
and you've got to be as authentic as you
can in order to be thought of as
credible and i think that's a big part
of well it's important for any business
to be thought of as credible
and i think content particularly in the
cannabis industry where you've got so
many restrictions around advertising and
marketing and things like that
using content to actually tell those
anecdotal stories could be a very
powerful thing
incredibly yes so do you see over in
north america any agencies that seem to
be excelling at this or is is there a
massive limit on what the company
agencies can currently do on the market
or
what do you see so far i mean it's not
something i'm hugely
you know aware of what happening in the
us in terms of their restrictions but
you look at you know the way in which
for example
in canada
sort of companies you know cannabis
companies you know you can't have a kind
of big fancy kind of uh
packaging on the shelves you know you
need to have you know you have to have
that big kind of uh has to be sort of
black it has to have a big yellow thc
sticker on or something like that so
that you know how do you build a brand
with those sort of restrictions when you
can't go on instagram for example you
can't sort of and openly advertise on
facebook how do you navigate those sort
of restrictions i think that's something
that a lot of cannabis brands in
well in north america and and beyond you
know if you're trying to build something
you're in danger of being basically shut
down from you know
to a larger part of your audience so
that puts pressure on needing to use
other channels to
you know demonstrate what your brand's
about or you know and i think again
it's trying to substantiate kind of
health claims and things like that well
that you know that's a whole different
kettle of fish but if you're talking
about that you just need to be very
mindful and i think again if you can
tell stories around it and use that kind
of anecdotal rather than cast iron
evidence that you know and again there's
there's problems around research and
things like that how can you demonstrate
statistics or demonstrate that something
has a specific impact when you you know
when there's no research happening or i
mean i'm just kind of speculating to a
large extent here i'm no expert in that
side of things but for me it comes back
to
even if you kind of think about the
wider perspective on those sorts of
restrictions from a marketing
perspective
you know you can still do more with
content than you can in
written content you know as a kind of
share of voice
uh play than using something visual and
putting on a social media post and sort
of you know because
you know like again i think you really
when you think about the broader
perspective of
a brand or marketing and things like
that it's you know it's about that full
impact the full spectrum you know i
think there's a lot of parallels in
there
in so many different sectors and i
always love how cannabis seems to be you
know 15 different sectors just coming
together and just clashing together and
you know there's a little bit of war is
it can we advertise it in the same way
as we can pharma or is it like uh
alcoholic beverages or is it like
fast-moving consumer goods or is it you
know is it medicine there's so many kind
of
thing you know ways in which people
understand it or don't understand it and
i think it's just about you know
reassuring your customers whatever it is
whether you're selling flower oils or
you know vaping devices or something
like that there has to be a way to
illustrate that
differentiate your brand and i think
through content you know i'm you know
i'm an advocate for it i think i just
think there are so many ways to leverage
it
don't have to answer the question but it
gave me a sense of feeling like i know
what i'm talking about so yes i know
indeed for sure and i actually it
incorporated what i wanted to move on to
is how to build a brand new cannabis and
as you said con copywriting is an
essential part of your brand building
book we started to see over in america
especially the west coast seem to have a
lot of golf events uh lemon haze of
their events and i've started to hear
already about new york
and where they're like the rooftop
cannabis parties uh sample parties are
already starting to happen so do you see
uh
when it happens in the uk a mix of
events like this or do you always think
the written word is gonna outdo any
in-person event that can be held
i'd you know i think you need that you
you need a kind of uh
just broader approach as possible i
think you know one of the things that
i'm always constantly thinking about is
you know
where's the kind of there needs to be
some creativity in what you're doing and
i think having restrictions sometimes
can really help to focus how
you attack something i think that's how
you can be creative in marketing
sometimes it comes from having those
restrictions here in the uk i think
because we have you know a medical
market you know it feels a long way from
having a recreational market there's
still that kind of like i say the
stigmas to overcome to convince people
that this is medicine you know people
will
have cannabis you know recreationally
illegally that that's something that's
going to happen regardless
but what in order to kind of give him
more legitimacy we need to be able to
demonstrate to to patients or potential
patients as well as doctors that this is
medicine and that there are different
ways to
you know we need to have that education
piece and i think again content is
perfect for that education piece and i
think that's the kind of first piece of
the puzzle we need to address over here
and i think you know organizations like
the mccs uh professor mike barnes hannah
deacon doing making great strides and
doing that they're going around the uk
and uh
talking to doctors directly and we've
been to one of their events and you know
they're giving these really intelligent
doctors cannabis 101 not because they
you know it's not talking down to them
it's because the knowledge just isn't
there so you know telling stories is
about you know understand you know i
think the work of you know organizations
like glee you know getting people out
there you know it's still storytelling
it's the same thing you know whether
it's you know written content
in-person events you know you need to
have those stories certain i think
that's the important thing and i think
that's something all kinds of brands can
have a
you know have a hand in and you know
like i say i feel like every
company that
engages in in the sector almost has to
do that advocacy piece and that those
storytelling aspects is is a key part of
that so i think it's it's one of the
same thing events written content social
media it's all part of the same effort
and you know there's that story aspect
that has to come through and i think
it's how do we tell those stories how do
we manifest them and what are we up
against how what again we have the
different context in which we can
do that and that varies depending on on
the country but yeah that's kind of
what's at the cross we need everything
basically i think
super stuff has been a very informative
episode so far before we finish up with
the time we've got um the election over
the uk who's going to win it and who's
going to legalize cannabis is it going
to be
you know personally i mean i think we
need to we need to change at the top for
anything meaningful to happen from
cannabis perspective but you know
politicians are in my opinion
you never know what's going to happen
next so you know maybe the tory player
will come along and say all right we
need to kind of you know get the economy
back on track let's legalize cannabis
recreationally let's tax it and let's
let's make a load of money from it
hopefully that's what is happening um
for everybody wants to check out more of
dave's work the website is below i
highly recommend checking out their
podcast as well it is very very good
indeed dave thank you very much for
taking the time to chat on this episode
and hopefully we get to talk again in
the near future very good thank you i
mean i appreciate it and uh yeah take
care
until next episode everybody