[Music]
welcome everybody to the first episode
of the new year and we're delighted to
be joined by guests i've been looking
forward to talking for a long time one
of the biggest players in the world at
the moment ilan sobel who's the ceo of a
company called bioharvest so bioharvest
basically our
bio harvest sciences inc should i say
are the first and only fully validated
industrial scale plant cell technology
platform for the production of plant
metabolites if i'm correct they've
recently created cannabis trichomes in
their proprietary reactors that have
resulted in 100 to 200 x times greater
density of trichomes than grown in a
plant so a big player in the world at
the moment ill and i'm delighted to have
you on the show today
it's an absolute pleasure owen to be
here on your first show of
but this is it maybe we have to start
with a bang last year seemed to be the
kind of
a big movement of pharma industry into
the kind of cannabis space and for all
the die-hard cannabis players out there
who are vermont in pharmacy getting into
this this is what's happening
recreational would be the genetics
growers the tenders the bud tenders it's
a separate industry now and
pharmaceuticals will create and create
bespoke medicines for bespoke diseases
that can't be replicated with a plan so
we might as well get used to it and get
talking to the biggest players in the
game at the moment alan so basically can
you maybe give everybody an overview of
how you came from coca-cola into bio
harvest sciences inc
yeah sure no problems well i i firstly
i'm i'm very uh privileged to be ceo of
bar harvest sciences
um it's been an amazing 18-month journey
in this role uh probably the best 18
months of my professional career
i
i think my experience actually set me up
beautifully
for the challenges the dynamic challenge
that i that i have ahead in in this role
with 18 years as an international
employee of the coca-cola company um
having spent that across multiple
different geographies 12 years in asia
three years in in
africa and three years three and a half
years in the us in multiple you know
general management roles um
understanding the business end-to-end so
i had a really good understanding of the
food and beverage business um and then i
moved to israel in 2014
and and went into the startup world and
together with two partners built a big
data iot and software business
um in the beer industry and after
building a business with all the major
beer players as our customers with
heineken carlsberg and halsey bush inbev
we were very fortunate to actually do a
significant exit and we sold the
business to anheuser-busch inbev
and became a major big data analytics
player
for the announcer bush in bev system so
you know with that background and
industry and knowledge in the food and
beverage industry
and also having worked at my time in
coca-cola um in really building a number
of health and wellness brands i actually
came to buy harvest sciences as an
investor
and after uh you know completing a a
very intensive due diligence on the
company i realized wow this company is
amazing it's like a gold mine it's it's
got technology uh which is like a needle
in a haystack which is you know super
unique is able to bring the power of the
plant uh to the people with a
a very unique proprietary platform
technology which has the ability
to grow any primary metabolites so any
protein or any secondary metabolite
such as a polyphenol anti antioxidant or
in fact we're going to talk about today
cannabinoids and we're able to grow any
primary metabolite or secondary
metabolite from the plant so any
essential active ingredient
that plants have we're able to grow in
cells
and then over time we grow these cells
in bioreactors to give us a an amazingly
soluble and bioavailable um end product
with with fantastic efficacy so when i
came in as an investor i thought wow
this company is really unique
and i invested and
i drove the
the existing ceo who's now the chairman
so crazy during my due diligence process
that once my check had actually passed
through the bank he called me back up
and said listen
i realized through this process you put
us through
that i need a professional ceo to come
and run this business and to bring the
the power of our technology to the
market
and i'd like i'd like you to be that
professional ceo to come and run the
business so here i am 18 months later
owen it's been amazing we've achieved so
much where we're certainly creating
history um as it relates to um
the cannabis world um at its core we're
a biotech company we are the leaders in
plant cell technology uh we're unlocking
the secrets of cellular plant biology
every single day uh bringing unique
health and wellness and therapeutic
solutions to thousands of consumers out
there
yeah amazing it seems like a very
exciting company to be a part of both uh
in both aspects now through my research
i realized you guys got started in 2008
and 2017 you got your r d license from
the israeli government 2018 is when you
do sales to grow and produce trichomes
what was the big milestone that happened
last year that all the press was about
if you could break it down simply for
the audience that uh you were able to
create strike on biomass obviously in a
reactor but what does that mean for uh
the regular consumer and industry
yeah look so there were a number of
historical milestones that happened
in the last 12 months and like i like to
say we we pretty much
climbed mount everest and back six times
just given the fact that um
we've been pioneers in in in this area
and we've gone where no person has gone
before because you know right now
there's absolutely there's no literature
out there um as it relates to actually
growing um growing cells cannabis cells
in in bioreactors um there's no academic
institution out there
that has or other business that's been
able to do what we've been able to do
and i guess the the major milestone that
we were able to demonstrate was the
ability to actually grow the trichomes
in bioreactors and as many of the
audience obviously know the trichome is
the mini factory that produces the
cannabinoids flavonoids and terpenes
and and actually stores um those
critical active ingredients and we were
able to figure out how we take the plant
once
we then grow cells from that plant and
as we actually take those cells and put
those cells into liquid media i.e
bioreactors
we were able to actually grow from each
of our cells those very unique trichomes
so this was a was a major feat
it created you know biotech history as
well as you know cannabis history
because no other company has been able
to grow trichomes in liquid media
we then
had a another
major breakthrough and obviously this is
all part of our unique ip
is that we were able to actually grow
our trichomes in a very very unique
structure
which we call a amalgamated trichome
coral structure this was a real you know
genius breakthrough from a science
perspective because as you are growing
um
as you are scaling
uh in bioreactors
and as your bioreactors get larger and
larger you have what they call shear
forces
and without amalgamated trichome coral
structures what actually landed
happening is that we were able to get
the actual trichomes to all amalgamate
closely together
to create
somewhat what you can see when you look
at it like a coral structure which
actually protects the trichome and this
was a real breakthrough because it
allows us to actually go from you know
small bioreactors to medium bioreactors
to you know really industrial scale
bioreactors in a way that protects
the unique integrity of that trichome
which is so important because it's the
the it's the mini factory so this is the
second breakthrough and with this
breakthrough we announced to the markets
um
at the end of the at the end of last
year on december 8th that we actually
have now been able to grow kilos of
final finished biomass and i think it's
important owen for you and the audience
to understand that what we are growing
is full
spectrum
non-gmo
biomass and that you know that was again
another major milestone that we
announced the marketplace that we're the
first company in the world to be able to
grow full spectrum
non-gmo cannabis biomass at specifically
at the quantities that we're able to
grow and we announced that we had
grown roughly 10 kilos of the biomass
and this is something that no other
company or institution has been able to
do and and what's important about this
is that as a result of our technology
this allows us to be able to bring a
unique grade of cannabis to the
marketplace which we will be bringing in
and the uniqueness is derived by you
know a number of different areas
the first area is it's finger brick
consistency so which is so important in
the cannabis world specifically from a
medicinal perspective
we have a level of cleanliness which is
unique to the marketplace because we we
literally we started the plant once okay
so therefore and we're growing cells so
there's no need for pesticides
there's no need for fertilizer there's
no heavy metals there are no solvents so
we have a very unique clean product and
i'll tell you now our receptors in our
bodies they understand the difference
between clean product and unclean
product
and then thirdly
sustainability is at the core of our
platform technology that we're utilizing
to grow our cannabis and as a result
obviously we're able to grow cannabis at
it with a fraction of the of the actual
amount of land that's required
even compared to
indoor indoor growing we're also able to
do it much more efficiently we're in a
perpetual flowering process
and importantly because we're not
utilizing
any pesticides there's no fertilizers uh
there's no solvent all of the water that
we use is actually biodegradable so
from an environmental perspective this
is a very unique platform technology
which gives us i would say best-in-class
credentials from a sustainability uh
perspective as it relates to the
cannabis world so some major major
milestones that obviously we're excited
now to build on as we start to scale for
well it all sounds incredible can you
tell me do you guys get to set let's say
the recipe for the cannabinoids that are
grown within the trichomes and the
secondary question do those trichomes
grow into actual flour or are they kept
in the lab and used as a as an
ingredient just to clarify for the other
so obviously we start with the plant and
based on the genetics of the plant we're
obviously growing those same genetics of
the plant from an overall cannabinoid
profile perspective
um
as it relates to the actual final you
know biomass we're growing trichomes
right so in fact it's a great question
of our biomass is trichomes and you know
i talked about the density how we're
actually able to grow um trichomes with
uh on average between 100 and 2 200
times more density than what actually
grown on a regular plant
part of that is because of the structure
that we have and just unique
confirmation but it also
drives significant overall efficiencies
for us and as a result we have you know
as part of our biomass you have roughly
a ratio of 93 trichome which is really
unique the other seven percent is the
cell which is uh the starting point to
grow the trichome and then with that
biomass we can take that and utilize
that biomass just like you can typically
utilize any type of flower we can decide
to take it and do extraction and go into
oils we can decide to actually take it
in itself and go into edibles it can be
utilized you know basically
as a regular cannabis to be consumed
from a medicinal perspective with
different types of of formats so
um it has exact same versatility that
exists in cannabis flower but obviously
what's important to understand is that
we're all all trichome or 93 trichome
and that's where all the the factory of
production of cannabinoids are happening
so in terms of synthetic versus the
methodology that you guys are using is
it chalk and cheese or is it just you
guys are far more purified when it comes
to the actual ingredient that's going
into products look i think it's
important that for your viewers they
understand that you know the differences
between a biosynthesis right which is
obviously you know but you have
synthetic you have biosynthesis which is
you know basically utilizing you know
mold or fungi to grow the kind of the
actual
singular cannabinoids versus ourselves
you know obviously you can group
synthetic and biosynthesis together
largely driven by the fact that these
are you know obviously genetically
modified okay we are non-gmo so this is
like the first like major difference the
second major difference between let's
say these two groups is you know
biosynthesis and synthetic
are always going to be using singular
isolates okay so it's you know cbd or
cbg
we are full spectrum okay and this is
really a critical component of our
technology platform is around its
ability to be able to grow
full spectrum of the different active
ingredients and this is really important
because you know
when you look at
a number of different scientific studies
the human body always reacts better to
what they call the entourage effect or
the systematic effect where you have
multiple you know multiple polyphenols
as in the case of our vineyard product
that we already where we already have
strong validation of our platform
technology
with uh selling our red grape cell
product in the cardiovascular health
space with with vineyard we actually
have pisces resveratrol with only
company in the world that actually
produces passed resveratrol from the
skin of the red grape which has
glucoside which has amazing solubility
but it works in unison together with
other critical polyphenols like catagen
coercitin anthocyanins and tannins and
it's that harmonious effect which
creates the best outcome from an overall
health and wellness perspective
similarly with cannabis there's a lot of
research on the entourage effect some
people call it the synergistic effect
which talks about the importance of the
different cannabinoids working together
with the terpenes and flavonoids in
order to give you the best possible
outcome from an overall um
effectiveness perspective and it's like
simple i like to think about it like an
orchestra you know you have multiple
different components of the orchestra
working together to give you the best
overall experience it's the same thing
in the plant world you need to have all
the different active ingredients working
together and that's the way that god
gave us the plant as well so this is a
this is a major major factor and i
actually you know you opened the
discussion talking about um the pharma
world and the farmer world you know
having woken up with pfizer you know
purchasing 6.7 billion dollars
purchasing a company that has strong you
know cannabis um
cannabis you know knowledge base this is
a major move from pharma who've gone
from the synthetic world right and
actually they're coming back full circle
now to the plant world and realizing you
know obviously the power of botanicals
in in in its full spectrum in its full
spectrum composition
in order to help solve some of the major
palliative diseases
and
and indications
that today
specific synthesized pharma drugs are
very are very challenged and that's a
very challenging helping to solve and
that's why today in the u.s you have
between 45 million people at least that
are
today
consuming medicinal cannabis
as either total substitutes or in
addition to their current you know
i guess pharma grade synthesized
medication for anything from
fibromyalgia
als
cancer medication epilepsy medication
etc so it's really really interesting
times pfizer i think took a a bold
you know
audacious decision to actually start to
kind of come back
to the original
source of where the former world started
which is the plant and back to
botanicals
yeah i think i recently saw that as they
have a medicine that specializes in
cardiovascular disease i think was the
the cherry on the cake for fish or
acquire in that company
and i could talk to you all day alone i
swear to god i'm absolutely sold on and
everything you guys are doing and it's
been an enthralling shout out and i hope
we get to chat again before the end of
the year and get an update on everything
you guys are doing for everybody wants
to know more check out the website for
bio harvest sciences below i highly
recommend doing some research on them
and thank you again mate i hope you have
a great day
thanks for the opportunity owen have a
great year thank you very much everybody
have a great day and we catch in the
next episode