foreign
to the next episode of the Cannabis view
I'm delighted to be joined with this
episode by Gianni Del Rosario macridges
how are you keeping today Gianni very
good Owen how are you fantastic me thank
you very much for taking your time to do
this I know it's late in the evening and
over there and you've got a lot of
studying ahead of you
yeah that's all right uh it's a
privilege to to be here so thanks for
having me on thank you very much for
coming on do you remember we want to
give everybody an overview in a minute
or two of what you your area of
expertise is and how you find yourself
in the Cannabis industry
yeah sure so uh I was actually quite
lucky I changed career when I was in my
late 20s so I was used to work in an
office for a freight and logistics
company and I realized that that wasn't
really what I was passionate about so I
made a big decision to just move out of
that career and I went to South America
where I lived with local people uh all
across the continent
um and uh from there I I volunteered on
farms and I did a lot of couch surfing
so it was pretty rough
but during that year I learned how they
use plant medicines over there and I
really saw the benefit and it really
intrigued me so when I came back to
Australia I decided to start studying uh
botany at Latrobe University and then
from there I got into an honors project
which is
um sort of in between an undergraduate
and a postgraduate and that was based on
plant biotechnology and I started to
realize the potential of the genetic
engineering implants and the problems
that it can solve for the world after
that I got a job with a cannabis
cultivation company here in Melbourne
Australia
and then I met some professors from
another University who said that they
had a project for me in a PhD on
medicinal cannabis and so all the stars
aligned and that's how I got into uh
studying and researching cannabis
genetics at Latrobe University
um and I focus on trichome genetics
okay incredible first topic I'm going to
start off with is cultivation in
Australia can you maybe give us who who
are the best cultivators in Australia
and who has the best genetics in
Australia
uh yeah that's kind of a dicey Topic at
the moment there's a lot of competition
and it's very secretive because of the
high competition between companies so I
no longer work in directly in the
industry
um but I do have uh four years
experience working for one of the main
major cultivators in Australia
um and uh who who are called can group
they were the first company in Australia
to get a license to manufacture cannabis
um but uh there is another company
called ACS botanics who are doing really
well in Australia right now they are
taking out all the awards
um and the main difference between
someone like can group and ECS is that
can group specialize more in indoor
cultivation and ECS uh are all about
outdoor cultivation so the outdoor
cultivation model seems to be prevailing
at the moment and
um I'm not sure if that's exactly got to
do with their genetics there's a lot of
research and development that companies
have done to get the best genetics
including importing them from overseas
like Canada
um but I think it's it's got a lot to do
more around the production it's very
expensive to run a indoor facility and
the outdoor model has been able I guess
to keep costs low
okay you mentioned genetic engineering
then in your discussions I'm sure you've
heard of bioharvest Sciences in Israel
who are able to cultivate glandular
trichomes on a mass scale and
bioreactors do you see this is the kind
of future side of the ingredient side of
the industry where we're able to make
cannabinoids and molecules 100 pure and
replicate that over and over again or do
you see that uh plant matter is always
going to have a say in the ingredient
side of things
yeah so there are definitely two sides
to the argument but I I sit more on the
whole plant uh side of things and I
think that a lot of people in the
industry like uh Dr Ethan Russo uh
believe that the same kind of model
um that the plant does it better in fact
that was uh one of the the quotes from
uh his papers that the the plant
um you know the full spectrum of
molecules produced in the cannabis plant
seem to have this Entourage effect where
they can have
um more therapeutic benefits than single
molecule drugs that's not to say that
there isn't a purpose for single
molecule drugs
um but um in terms of cultivating and um
yielding these phytocannabinoids uh in
my opinion I think it's going to be more
effective to do that within the plant
rather than
um these lab Lab situations
so for example one of the biotech
companies if they ever been able to
isolate their own cannabinoids and then
get mixtures or Blends and formulations
of terpenes and create their own recipe
do you see that as being a more
advantageous route than extracting flat
matter because surely for the
environmental the actual overall cost
and the production quantity that these
guys are going to be able to do that
there's going to have to be an
inflection point where
if the ingredient that people are buying
they don't really understand too much
about it then the Blends and formulation
seems to be
is what everybody's going after
yeah absolutely I I do think that the
Blends uh are a great
um uh Advantage
um in terms of putting different
compounds together like the cannabinoids
and the terpenes and sort of um blending
them from different sources I think that
that's something that's going to be more
futuristic right now there's not enough
clinical information to understand what
works best with what in terms of
specific illnesses so at how it stands
at the moment
um it might not be as
um
necessary right now but if you want to
sort of look to where the the puck is
heading as they say in ice hockey then
uh potentially these new ways of putting
together specific formulations for
particular illnesses or
um for to generate particular benefits
that could be a really exciting area of
of Industry
yeah because it seems to be that if you
actually move just over to the medical
side of things that if we're going to
have a cardiovascular information or a
gastrointestinal information that these
specific cannabinoids are a key
ingredient and that there's no way a
cultivation facility is going to be able
to produce the quantities that let's say
a Pfizer is going to want if they get a
good recipe for a drug in that case
yeah absolutely but the the other thing
too is you have to think about the
target market too and I don't think most
of the Cannabis Community are super
prepared to take on uh formulations like
that from Big pharmaceutical uh drug
companies
um but having said that we're talking
about patients that are not necessarily
within the Cannabis Community right the
the whole idea is we want to expand the
reach of cannabis medicine to all um
people regardless of what they do and do
not know about about cannabis so
um there is potential there but I also
see a little bit of pushback from from
the real Die Hard
medicinal cannabis fans
um yeah who might not be willing to take
that on just yet
yeah it seems to be that these big
biotech companies and Pharma companies
can see that broadening the patient
range is what their aim is I think we're
always going to have the die hards who
couldn't really tell the difference
between an independence sativa anyway
but they just have their own hard stance
and that's the way they're feeling about
a specific topic but on a global scale
if you're able to reach another 30 40
percent of patients that had no interest
in cannabis whatsoever but are going to
be happy to take a pill or a capsule or
whatever a topical formulation I think
that's where the benefits of this
genetic engineering is going to be a
dividends
absolutely absolutely and I think that
that patient
um footprint is going to grow and we're
already starting to see it grow
especially here in Australia it's really
taking off
um and we have a lot of clinics and
dispensaries that are starting to pop up
all around the country in various States
and uh they have been inundated with
calls from patients who uh who have
tried a lot of other things for their
illnesses and now they are looking into
medicinal cannabis
um at the same time you have this uh
need for homegrown cannabis being pushed
for by Advocates as well and also by
recently elected political parties here
who are introducing bills into the
parliament to allow the home growing of
of cannabis for people that don't want
to go through the clinical dispensaries
um and and prescribers
yeah you definitely start to see a split
in Europe where farm and boy attack are
going to be developing brand new novel
drugs and being able to take care of
let's say cosmetics and Beauty but then
you'll be able to placate the activists
and the the industry people who've been
around for decades with a homegirl rule
with you can have three or four plans
and this not-for-profit cannabis Social
Club model is going to pop up the next
question I wanted to ask you was how
would somebody improve their their home
growing are there any specific things
that somebody look I'm trying to grow
two or three plants at home for ex
ailments what are the two or three
things that I should be looking at to
ensure that I'm getting the best kind of
annoyed on a trichome balance
yeah absolutely so the first thing I
think is important is is the genetics
right so you want to make sure that you
have got seeds or clones from a
reputable breeder and that you're
growing the variety well we say in
science the cultivar that is suited for
your needs so you would want to know a
bit about the cannabinoid profile also
the density of trichomes Leaf uh the
flower morphology the
um the architecture of the plant so that
it fits within your growing space we
know growing at home can be quite tight
um so that's the first point of protocol
with with growing at home you want to
have a good starting point and then I
think it's just a matter of really
getting into the nitty-gritty of
cultivation and it comes back down to
light so lighting plays a big part also
nutrients plays a big part as well and
of course you're growing medium so you
need to make a decision of whether you
want to grow in soil or soil less medium
so
with that we're really um lucky these
days or a lot of information is being
published online about the best uh
cultivation tips but I think if you if
you start with those three or four
things and then um you're on a good good
path
yeah I think there's a reason if you
look at the most profitable and largest
cannabis companies around the world
Scott's miracle grower I think two
billion bigger than most of the big msos
in Canada and America and I think that
that's where it's going to Sweet Spot is
going to be the the trays the soil the
lighting the nutrients that they're
going to be given is going to be a a big
industry when it comes to Europe and no
doubt Australia as well
absolutely absolutely in fact um yeah
I'm I'm looking at ways of of trying to
uh help people out with that here in
Australia
um and and make the most of their home
go in anticipation that these laws are
going to to pass in the next six to 12
months
um and what effect that will have on the
local industry we're not quite sure yet
of course not everyone is going to want
to grow their own cannabis just like you
not everyone grows their own vegetables
but I think there is going to be a
substantial proportion of the market
that is is going to grow their own just
because of the cost but also uh because
of the enjoyment of of growing your own
medicine
yeah I think everybody initially when
they're allowed to do it are going to
put their finger and try and attempt to
do it but they're going to soon realize
how difficult it actually is and we
discussed before they came off the The
Social Club model seems to be what's
going to be the most palatable thing for
a lot of politicians to give adult
access use to places what is the the
story with that in Australia at the
moment
yeah so
at the moment like I mentioned the laws
for homegoing have not yet been been
passed but the bill that's being
proposed at the moment does have
Provisions for cannabis clubs
but I'm not sure what it's uh the
purpose mainly is in Europe but in this
field what they're proposing it for is
for people who don't have room at home
to grow their own or don't have access
to to seeds
um also for renters who who might not
um be looked up upon greatly by their
landlord to the growing cannabis at home
so you can uh allow these cannabis clubs
to grow your cannabis for you so that's
the proposition at the moment in the in
the in the legislation that's being
proposed
well hopefully now mates we in Europe
and in Australia we get these Social
Clubs up and running over the next 18 to
24 months and the people who want to
have access to a plant have access to a
plant and the people who want to create
new novel products and drugs out of the
the molecules that come from the plant
are able to do so as well and we can all
live Kumbaya happily together as we
March forward
that's right we are on the precipice of
a really exciting time in the Cannabis
industry and for the Cannabis community
and
um hopefully with Europe leading the way
Australia will will follow suit and and
make it available for for people to home
grow their own cannabis so fingers
crossed yeah big time mate Johnny it's
been great to happen to you hopefully we
get to catch up if you do oh it goes
according to plan with your PhD I'd look
forward to having another chat with you
towards the end of the year and we can
bulky joke give each other an update on
what's happening in Europe and Australia
but for now thank you very much for your
time mate
awesome thanks Owen cheers until next
episode everybody
[Music]