foreign
on this episode by Alex Popoff who's a
business intelligence Business
Development officer how are you keeping
today Alex I'm doing well how are you
today I'm fantastic mate you maybe want
to give everybody an overview of quick
30 seconds of where you are in your
business world I know you covered a
couple of different topics sure so my
name is Alex Popov I'm a U.S Air Force
veteran I'm originally got into cannabis
when I found actually just using
cannabis socially with friends I wasn't
needing pain medication as much for my
back I've had several back surgeries and
so over time in early 2018 I come to
learn about all the research and all the
amazing benefits of cannabis and how we
had been lied to for so long about the
benefits worldwide so I got involved
with advocacy work I did a bit of
digital marketing I got a Bachelor's
degree in digital marketing kind of
learned that marketing is great it's an
essential component uh it just didn't
come naturally I didn't have a passion
for it even with cannabis and the moment
that I began my uh business intelligence
master's degree
um this January I started connecting the
dots with cannabis and data I started
talking to some of the leading cannabis
data companies
um because it their their their
employees were kind enough to reach out
to me and say hey here's what we do you
know when you graduate if you're
interested in this type of work so I
kind of got a little peek inside of
what's going on at some of these
companies I've talked to some of the
license holders that are going through
an upgrade process with their data
system and seeing under the hood of it
so to speak and uh yeah I just really
love this stuff so that's about me I'm a
veteran that's found cannabis has helped
me personally I've gotten involved in
advocacy and now I'm pivoting from
marketing into the data analytics and
business intelligence okay incredible
stuff yeah I think the sector you're in
now is going to be a Cornerstone of this
industry over the next decade or so and
people like yourselves are going to be
the next big names did you start hearing
in the industry can you give me an
overview is there any big business
that's used in data analytic property
like obviously you're using whether it's
for marketing improving that whether
it's in product Improvement and research
which of the big companies like is the
cure relief green told many of the guys
that you know that have actual data
departments in there in their companies
right so I um I don't know as much about
the MSO surprisingly but I will say I
will speculate widely that they do
probably have their own data departments
I I've seen um people where it says like
data analysts and it's at one of the big
msos like you described um but I've also
seen it this is what gets me more
excited is I've seen it at like the
mid-tier level as well yeah and I say
mid-tier like you know maybe they're in
two states but they're not a cure leaf
and they're in like more than 10 or
whatever they've got so
um and these folks will they'll still
have a full data section um they may not
use like the big data tools and all the
stuff that you hear about in Academia
and with Enterprise level like forty
five hundreds or or the big msos but
they're you know they'll do they'll go
beyond using an Excel spreadsheet by all
means and I've talked to some of these
folks it's incredible the analysis
they're doing and it's everything from
um what's our best selling product you
know because your point of sale systems
most of them that I know of will give
you basic business intelligence
dashboards they'll say you know here's
your busiest time of day here's your
best-selling product here's here's the
skus that are upcoming the up and coming
they'll have all kinds of features but
the best data is your own data and you
don't really know what where they're
driving this information and it's not
granular enough because you can't
manipulate it your own way most of the
time
um so I am seeing some of these smaller
operators actually using tools they're
not just relying on uh you know what
their POS has out of the box
and is there a specific model of
gatherings the the data that they're
using themselves or is it basically
first-hand knowledge or social media
what would you think is the most
advantageous route to get a data if
you're an entrepreneur
I would say a combination right so you
always want to have this what we refer
to and I know from academics they'll
teach us is a single source of the truth
because you don't want you don't want
three different top selling products
unless it's different categories you
want you want one source of the truth
however
um what I would say is you'll see
everything from scraping like websites
and collecting the price points so a
local dispensary retailer might say okay
the average price per gram for this
strain even is four dollars or fifteen
dollars or something in that range which
can vary widely so that's why they would
want to know exactly what
um that price point is it could also be
something where they need to use
um like the the AI and language learning
models we talked about before we started
where they're going to do sentiment
evaluations where they'll scrape social
media sites and then they'll analyze
from everything to emojis to text to
determine what sentiment the community
has on their brand and on their products
and I would be surprised if like you
said purely from these other companies
aren't doing that
100 I think in this modern day and age
now you didn't you don't really need to
spend half a million on wages for data
scientists to come in and basically
analyze data I think you can have a
number of proficient people on these new
AI programs and plugins to be able to at
least get your your start in the game
but data I'm sure is going to influence
when Federal legalization comes in the
states like what every other industries
does a handful of dominant Brands and
they
Target their products and their nuanced
advertising various the sectors so kept
building that data from the ground up is
probably a parliament now to people
right like there's
um
the co-founder of uh uh pardon me I miss
so I missed out my companies there what
I meant to say was that there there are
companies out there where they're
they're taking feedback on certain
products and certain strains and using
Ai and using data analytic data
analytics and Big Data tools to
determine like how is this product
affecting people are there certain
terpenes giving certain effects I mean
and there is just dozens and dozens if
not hundreds of different apps and
companies
um approaching this I'm not an expert on
any of those that's just one like the
thing about data is when we say data we
can talk about cannabis research data we
can talk about retail data like you
mentioned the big business side of
things it just hits every facet that's
what I love is you're never going to get
bored or tired of it because you can go
in so many directions
one of the things about the data side of
things we kind of see it over in Europe
here that people cherry picking specific
data to kind of suit their own end
valuation or whatever it may be the
amount of this country's got to be worth
this amount of money boy this year uh
claims that I've seen over the last
number of years and it's one of those
ones do you see that as much in America
as well
all right
I'm trying to find the words here I
don't know how it is in Europe so I
can't make a comparison but I'll uh I'll
say it's probably worse here even
without knowing whatsoever and that's
not that's not a data-driven decision
that's just my own bias from being an
American in America uh we're terrible at
that and I I know that I can I can say
this rather than compare
um I see it with these large companies
that's why I was
um
apprehensive to be like oh yeah they're
doing great working data I'm sure
they're kicking but in data but uh but I
want to see the smaller operators and
everyone have a chance to because like
you said they can cherry picked out and
say look we're the safest cleanest
product or this but some of that just
comes from being the biggest voice and
having the most money in the room
yeah
do what you want anyone can but
especially when you have the money to
kind of shape perception around it
yeah I couldn't agree with you more I
think the only way that you can actually
really trust that is if it's been
gathered at the source itself and you
can amalgamate data then to make larger
reports but I think looking from afar
and taking a couple of people a couple
of different papers and a couple of
different numbers and translating them
into your uh let's say document that's
going to give data to somebody else it
seems to be the model that's been used
so far so is there a value and is there
a company in the US that has gone state
by state and has gathered data whether
it's via medium of music events or
consumption parties or whatever it may
be is that most to me that seems like
the smartest route for a company to do
and then translate that data back into a
software platform that like a tableau
that somebody can easily Digest
yeah exactly
um I again I'd be shocked if they're not
doing that
um that is definitely that's I learned
about this with in marketing where you
know you're doing your um your focus
groups and getting feedback from your
target audience and saying hey do the
consent you sometimes
um with with innovation in general you
don't really know what the consumer
wants and there's always competing views
like the view of oh that you need to
show the consumer what they want they
don't know maybe that works in some tech
applications but cannabis you know um
people know they like cannabis but it is
complex so I think it comes down to
um looking at things like uh
like why
um why are we collecting the data like
Define the problem and then go out and
don't just generate groups but
um like you said put it in the table
I'll put it in the power bi power bi is
the one that I'm familiar with and
there's looker and there's tons of
visualization tools that people can use
because data doesn't have I just said
this to my girlfriend before the call I
was like you know I'm gonna try to touch
on the fact that people think data is
all uh numbers and it's all quantitative
but data can be qualitative when you
take it when you can transform it and
put it into a format that the computer
programs can analyze and that's when you
drive the most value when you talk to
people and say well how is this working
for you what do you think instead of
just Mass surveys the the spray and pray
approach like is not my Approach
yeah no it's the undertale to 100 people
in 10 different cities and get their
opinion then send out 10 000 surveys
that get filled out by a much smaller
group of people the data that's
recovered on the ground I think is where
there's huge value in the Cannabis
industry over the next decade
no absolutely I keep looking to my left
over here apologize I've got my other
screen here I have a uh I'm gonna send
you this after our call so you can maybe
screenshot or or uh just for your own
viewing it's a it's an analytics
dashboard actually uh that that the
Oklahoma medical marijuana use uh agency
has commissioned a contractor to put
together and it's just beautiful because
it shows you the density of licenses Per
County it shows you the total commercial
license Trend um over time it shows you
things like total licenses uh by
category from cultivation to retail
process lab and um this is exactly the
type of stuff that I'm learning to do
and I think is so helpful because from
an investment point of view you can look
at this and see is more cannabis being
harvested month over month is there more
Harvest total like you can get very
granular and look at the specifics and
get a better idea of what's happening
and then you like we talked about then
you combine that by talking to people in
different counties and different
cultivators different license holders
and say how do you think the Market's
going that's that's business
intelligence and data analytics working
together
um and and still being a human being so
so tell me this um give me a quick
overview of what's happening in Oklahoma
how is restrictive is to sector there
and how well is it working or not
working
all right so that's a great question so
it's um it's chaotic in many ways as you
can imagine people call it the wild west
but like when we look at the data you
can see it's it's not uh it's not all
cartels and organized crime um those
those elements will exist
um most likely everywhere in the world
um at all times to some degree hopefully
to a lesser degree most of the time when
you have a new market people are going
to try to take advantage of it and
that's what's happened here and that's
what happens everywhere now since this
is the most conservative read Republican
state it's ironic that it has the most
Progressive and liberal uh program for
cannabis so what you see is you see the
state Regulators there's a disconnect
between the industry and The Regulators
like in most places as well and you'll
see that the state wants there to be
less licenses like right now I'm looking
at the dashboard and there's something
like 11 000 or 13 000 licenses there's 8
000 cultivators alone and there's no
plant limits so they can all 8 000
Growers grow as many plants as they want
and our population somewhere like 3
Point uh four uh million stores I own's
over there at the moment
part of me what would be the prize
program or price per ounce
oh that's the thing too so price per
pound per outdoor people are saying
anything from 250 to 400 uh which is
extremely low yeah and that's when you
see one thousand three thousand four
thousand even in other states but um
it's competitive so that so that's again
when we look at the data there's going
to be outliers there's still people that
can get more much much more for their
quality outdoor and for Quality indoor
and there's probably people selling for
50 bucks a pound too if it's very low
quality going right to extraction there
is um a major glut of biomass of
cannabis biomass and uh when I again I
look at the data here there's less and
less Harvest month over month and that's
not a bad thing I love The Growers I
want them to win and there needs to be
some there needs to be a balance and the
market it's not a free market because
you have Kansas and Texas Louisiana all
our bordering states that and Arkansas
even that have more restrictive or no
cannabis legal at all so so people will
produce product where it's affordable
and sell it where it's expensive
that kind of sums up the market but it's
good for patients the prices are low so
price per pound like you said is that so
as a patient I can get an eighth from
somewhere from five dollars to fifty
dollars it depends on the quality level
I can pay 170 an ounce and get very good
quality cannabis uh and that's good for
patients so so I rant a lot but I want
to give you the completion oh wait
that's brilliant yeah that's a fantastic
information and it it's been amazing
talk with you we're just coming up on
the 15 minutes here hopefully we get to
do a party with this conversation after
you've finished all the exams and
whatnot and uh we can deep dive into
this industry because as I said I think
this is going to be a Cornerstone at the
Cannabis industry and anybody who
doesn't know how to mix business
intelligence with data gathering on
their uh at source will be the losers in
this game but thank you very much Alex
for now mate
no thank you very much um you summed it
up well very more succinct than I could
but um thank you for having me I know
I'd love to come back when I'm either
employed or graduated or both hopefully
yeah sounds like a plan made you have a
great week and I will chat to you soon
until next episode everybody
[Music]