[Music]
welcome everybody to the cannabis review
i'm delighted to be joined by this
episode jp o'brien is the co-founder of
collins dispensary with a number of
locations around ireland how are you
keeping jp
g'day owen how are you very well thanks
i'm very well mate so basically we had
this episode just to kind of go over
stephen donnelly's recent backtracking
on the legislation the european
commission have brought forward so can
you give us your overview so far what
you know jp of the situation
yeah so owen what's happened here is the
the article that came out during the
week um although really poorly worded
was essentially highlighting the fact
that the current government is indeed
challenging i guess the um the european
court of justice cannavape decision
and this is to do with hemp cannabis
with 0.2 or less cbd
um and it's to do with the ongoing high
court proceedings here in ireland so
that would be our company and there
would be a number of other companies
that are going through
their own legal proceedings in order to
have the legislation sorted out
but mate what this means
sort of you know in normal language is
that
the governments believe that hemp
cannabis with 0.2 or less
i.e what our company and many other
companies have been providing the irish
people for the last three years
they believe that it is against the
public health for this product to be
supplied to
supply to people and they would like to
medicalize or pharmaceuticalize this
product um and
that's where it stands
okay so basically we've had a couple of
articles whether steven donnelly a year
or so ago said that he was open to some
sort of legislation happening now i
found some information that basically we
had um
luke flanagan asked questions in the
european council about this in april
2021 basically saying that can anybody
give an answer why the european
government are going against the
european commission ruling boy bannon's
sale of cbd goods so we found this reply
so this is from the european
commission's database themselves and it
basically is from a lady by the name of
miss stella
kiriakide so i don't want to be
butchering her name but she's basically
the commissioner for health and food and
safety
so this basically says from what we can
make all sense of that
they did say this but it's only each
individual state can then come to their
own ruling
and decide on this do you think this is
a case of lobbying from the
pharmaceutical industry have now finally
gotten to the politicians and they've
slowly started to change their mind on
the topic
well it's interesting you say that owen
because we're literally we're about four
weeks away from little collins
three-year anniversary right of actually
opening our doors three years ago this
time um in 2018 we were already selling
online and
look it's been said many times before
but um
every single arm of the government at
that at that point every single arm of
the state was totally fine with it so
what what actually happened is
in 2000 and 2018 a grassroots hemp
cannabis industry sprung up in ireland
right
via a lot of existing operators
um and some new operators like ourselves
and what the government was asleep at
the wheel this product is legal in
europe but they didn't have their act
together and suddenly then a year or two
later they've gone hang on a minute
we'd really like a piece of that
we'd really like to get that product and
take it and give it to our partners over
here how are we going to do that
no no this is against the public health
0.2 percent any thc is dangerous we need
to take this and we need to give it to
the pharmaceutical companies and start
again that's what's happening
against the public health is kind of i
mean anyone knows that this this product
is not dangerous so so what's happening
is an exercise in control it's an
exercise in um you know policy on the
run and quite frankly mate as you say
there is lobbying happening there's
lobbying happening from huge overseas
companies and um it's an exercise in
private interest dictating public policy
yeah well i think i've been doing a
number of interviews and mapping around
europe the different industries
different territories who's big and
who's not
excuse me and what i can seem to notice
is that the major players in europe at
the moment are the biggest
pharmaceutical hubs so denmark malta
these are all places with a big
pharmaceutical uh manufacturing
facilities already in place so it might
be just coming to the stage where the
pharma guys are ready to now get into
the market and they'll just start to
flex their muscles
but i mean i guess i guess what's missed
throughout all of this is um
this industry needs to be harmonized
from you know crop to shop and what's mr
at all of this is the farmers and the
ecological debate but you can't get to
that unless you can just get rid of um
the kind of confusion
and and really nonsense um that's
happening right now i mean
i've without going into the high court
proceedings i've had a a good look at um
at their argument and in my opinion it's
a house of straw you know it's a house
of cards i should say and it doesn't
stand up so
really we need to take it one step at a
time um why this issue has come up
recently is because of paul murphy td
obviously asking donnelly there in in
the door but really it's just
highlighting the duplicitous nature of
these tds i think it was martin's world
that came out during the week and
reminded everyone that donnelly himself
when he wasn't a td was he was all for
cannabis let's have a little bit of
cannabis it's all safe it's all cool i'm
cool i'm this cool guy and that was the
that was the full strength cannabis so
to speak
now that it comes to cannabis light oh
no no oh no no we can't do that we need
to uh get that off the table so look it
i mean it's at the stage for for me
where it's it that's you know i don't
want to treat it lightly but it is a bit
of a joke
um and it's a it's a it's a strategic
war at the moment it's a war of
attrition um the the daily battle to run
this business i cannot even
and
any operator would be the same running a
hemp cannabis business in this country
right now is a battle it's not a
business it's a battle
yeah and i think it might become sterner
before it gets easier let me ask you
this question if it does become let's
say medical grade regulated would you
still use this product in
your uh your own stores and your
products or do you feel that it would be
an inferior product
well we wouldn't be able to because we
we wouldn't be able to get use the royal
product the raw product would be off off
limits for anyone but you know uh you
know a licensed sort of medical
pharmaceutical operation um that's
that's the point
they want to wipe out the existing
industry and supplant it
with um a gentrified pharmaceutical
version of it
so so we we make our products from raw
hemp cannabis we import the cannabis but
we'd much prefer to be getting it from a
farm up the road but the farm up the
road the government telling to destroy
is destroy his crops but this is the
point if they win
little collins all of these businesses
they're all gone they will all be gone
and and the only businesses that will be
there selling the cbd products that you
know today will be businesses selling
these
you know
kind of generic label um products and
whether they're 0.0 or 0.2 you know it
doesn't matter
yeah and do you see uh let's say state
regulate federalization over america
being a big swing and conductor for
the the our side of the argument over
here i think with that happens you're
going to have a recreational market to
come to
come to europe whether they like it or
not and i think yeah yeah yeah i mean
absolutely and and that's sort of um
you know that's a few steps down the
line really i think that in our in our
mind mate the first battle just has to
be won here and we just have to get over
this hurdle and work out what is
happening with cbd right and
we can't we can't move on to anything
sort of bigger until we work out how the
cbd thing's gonna play and here's the
truth that that needs to be acknowledged
um not only is the defense of public
health irrelevant really and farcical
the you know the fact is they why
they're delaying it so much is they
don't have a plan for how to implement a
fair industry the only plan they have is
how to hand the industry over to their
business partners they don't have a plan
to implement
legislation around the current thriving
cbd industry they just want to wipe it
out and start again
so
they need to get a plan and they need to
get their heads out of the sand and they
need to go with the actual word of law
because the word of law in europe from
the european court of justice they are
willfully running against that and not
not just in one department in many
departments department of health
department agriculture revenue customs
the garda they're all running against
them
yeah so it's it's gonna battle going to
continue when is your court case exactly
so the viewers can uh keep supporting
tells me we're up next week we're up for
a mention next week mate and um look he
seems to think we're going to hear some
things by december i'm going to say q1
next year
but look it can't come fast enough
because customs just love taking
everyone's product on the way in and as
i say it's a it's a battle to do
business but everyone is still going
well and you know everyone's kind of
coming together in the industry but look
look out for hopefully a bit more news
next week mate
yeah excellent well everybody stay tuned
to the little collins twitter pages and
instagram pages the websites below go
order yourself some stuff and support
the battle that they've got going on
against the government and hopefully
everybody's victorious and we get to see
a thriving industry in ireland with some
proper homegrown products
that's it thank you very much mate
thanks for having me on sorry you're so
rushed
you're all good mate as i said we will
do these again in the new year and we'll
catch up and give everybody an overview
of what we know and so they can all make
their own informed decision as well so
thanks very much for your time
thanks man take care see you later guys
bye