[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
cannabis review where the final episode
of the year we are in for an end-of-year
review on this episode i am joined by
matthew o'brien of the green paper
matthew how are you keeping today
i have never been better sir i greatly
appreciate the opportunity to join you
in this occasion oh man we did it last
year so i think we're going to have to
make this an annual thing and you've had
a pretty great year with 4 p.m being
acquired and you're now on your way to
being one of the media center points of
this industry so congratulations on that
mate i think we've got a lot to cover in
the 15 minutes today
absolutely and i hope it's the the first
of many irish cannabis companies that
succeeded in this industry
yeah i have no doubt at all it'll be uh
there's a lot of good things to come in
this industry so
let's kick things off i kind of wanted
to keep it to 15 minutes so i'm going to
start up pretty simple and
straightforward we're going to do an
ender year review we're going to grade
north america and we're going to grade
europe from obviously regular grading so
i'm going to let you start if you want
me to start europe i'll give them a
grade and i'll give you my reasoning why
and then we can have a little discussion
as to see if we're both right
what are you kicking this off on just i
can get a sense as to what the format
would look like yeah cool well i'll
start off with europe so basically
we're going to give europe i think it's
a b plus to an a minus is what i'm
looking to achieve there's still a lot
of
muddy waters when it comes to the cb
industry but the leaps and bounds that
are happening are significant leaps and
bounds they're not just uh it kind of
drips and drabs and stuff germany
obviously legalizing what we'll get is
one of the biggest moments luxembourg
talking to doing it but the actual
weather coming in italy the made in
denmark products that are getting uh
licensed for sale so the acquisitions
that are happening the listings that
happened in the uk um as much as they're
not part of europe anymore we're going
to consider them part of europe for the
discussion um so yeah i think there's a
lot to be positive about in europe
there's been massive strides ahead i
think a lot of the
north american brands i saw a lot of the
finance calls and shareholder meetings
where they're adding a billion valuation
on the german market and kind of adding
this to future earnings of capital which
i think is a bit ahead of themselves
they've got a stiff battle against a
couple of the european brands that we
all know that are going to be here
fighting for this territory they're not
just going to walk in and automatically
be able to make market shares so i think
there's a a lot of positives ahead maybe
north american companies might be
getting a little bit ahead of it
themselves about the potential for
europe because as i said it's not just
an open goal they're going to have some
stiffs of competition by some highly
knowledgeable people that might be very
visual at the moment but are in the
background doing the work and putting in
the legislation uh framework for
everything that works uh
well for them so what do you think do
you agree a minus b plus
yeah i think so i i'm with you i think
there's there's certainly room for
improvement as there always is but i
think it's been a very important year
for the european cannabis industry and
i really get the sense that europe is is
really putting the foot down on the
pedal such that they can they can catch
up with our neighbors in north america
yeah no i couldn't agree with you more
as i said there's still a lot to do and
there's still a lot of uh
tape to pass and you can see over in
ireland here a lot of the cbd products
getting stopped at customs and taken off
the shelves so you can see this
happening across europe and people that
are talk to so there seems to be
something happening in the background to
allow let's say the
companies that have already got approved
let's say some of them got novel food
applications approved they're using
synthetic cannabinoids so with all due
respect to the companies that are
getting their products stopped this is
the way the free markets work the these
companies have spent the money they've
got their their foot in the door now so
it's up to you to be able to compete
against them
if there is a competition to be had
there would you agree
absolutely like like it or hate it
that's the conditions which are all
subject to and it's a free market anyone
and everyone can apply for those those
certifications and
this right this industry is going to be
regulated to death for many many more
years to come so if anyone is deterred
by the current sort of regulatory
environment i think it's a good
opportunity just to
perhaps take notice that potentially
there's another industry you want to
participate in because this is the
future of cannabis for better or worse
it's going to be regulated and
over-regulated for many many years to
come so all in all progress but a good a
good uh
a good insight for any entrepreneurs who
are potentially seeking to seeking to
get a piece of this pie that this is
just the environment you have to grow
accustomed to operating within
yeah creating the brand is going to be
secondary in europe it'll be about
regulatory framework industry nuances
how different territories uh operate
within the rules and framework so it's
not like north america where brands came
first and foremost so let's move on to
north american let's give us give me
your grade on how uh
will
do you want to do canada and america
separately or do you want to bunch them
in together
yeah certainly i'll i'll see if i can do
a bit of a separation because i think
they are quite different markets
in in the case of canada on i give
canada a b plus and i think it's
important to separate what's happening
in the cannabis stock market versus
what's actually happening in the
canadian cannabis market because
ultimately
a lot of the attention is diverted to
the larger canadian cannabis companies
whether that's a company like tilray or
aurora or canopy growth and
ultimately they've failed to meet
expectations for the last two years in
the industry they made
wildly ambitious promises to their
investors as the percentage of market
share that they could capture and a lot
of these companies are coming to the
realization that the products they're
producing are simply inferior in
comparison to craft cannabis however
ultimately if you look at the the mark
as i said as opposed to the stock market
we have seen a huge increase this year
in total sales of craft cannabis
products my understanding is that it's
nearly up 10x year-to-date now granted
that did start at a pretty low point
because craft cannabis producers were
only eligible to bring their products to
market within the last 24 months so
granted it did start at a small base
however that's been a huge success story
in the last year
that's not brought us to a point whereby
a lot of these larger companies are
really having to evaluate which
particular categories of cannabis
they're focusing on and ultimately we're
starting to see a much more
mature cannabis industry in canada
whereby producers are starting to
really focus on particular form factors
as opposed to trying to be all things to
all people so generally i'd say canada a
b plus i think they've done a great job
of the role of you know 2.0 products
whether that's beverages edibles etc i
still think there's a lot of room for
improvement in canada in certain
provinces cannabis retailers still
aren't actually able to perform
e-commerce sales in the world we live in
that is just a necessity for for any
business so that's definitely a
potential sort of room for improvement
for for canadian regulators and
hopefully in the upcoming review of the
the cannabis act that will be somewhere
on the top of their priority list
in the case of the united states i think
it's very much a mixed bag i would
generally say like maybe a c plus is
probably a fair grade for the
performance of that market this year we
have seen three bills that are currently
in place which would effectively
legalize cannabis at a federal level
and
albeit we could consider that progress
we are seeing a certain fragmentation of
the democratic party whereby you have
the majority leader of the senate chuck
schumacher who is saying that he will
literally oppose any bill which is not
his bill such that he can potentially
capture the political points of
legalizing canada so i think
right now in the states cannabis has
very much become front and center of
politics and that is that is definitely
a good sign and i think inevitably it
will result in the federal legalization
of cannabis however
and i'd like to get your perspective on
this i don't think it's a good thing
whereby
there are too many politicians in a
single party who are actively competing
against one another to sort of get the
political points associated with passing
this legislation
yeah well i think the way i look at
america is there's been sizable gains in
the the state level in terms of the
growth of the market share obviously
federal legalization is still the big
domino effect to happen but i think what
you've got happening now is the
posturing between the democrats and the
republicans they can see the capital and
the finance and the markets are moving
in this way and it's now going to be
like we want the pat on the back coming
into election you can seize and who's
going to be able to hold this cherry and
say that they got the young voter they
got the the new millennial vote out with
this uh
move so as i said i think it's a great
sign the fact that both parties are put
in in papers for an industry is an
amazing thing one of them are going to
be the other you've now got them
absolutely actively competing with each
other for the industry's benefits so
yeah i think i'd agree with you in
america it's still a lot to be done in
in that territory but uh big gains had
this year as well
uh a few other points i'll highlight in
that one so
a few really interesting statistics so
cannabis is now the fifth
largest cash crop in the united states
so of all the crops in their
agricultural uh industry cannabis is now
that the fifth most valuable crop and
that's just like determining the the
wholesale revenue like the the revenue
being generated from farmers selling it
to retailers additionally sales are
going to surpass 22 billion dollars this
year in legal cannabis sales like how
outrageous is it that you know 22
billion dollars in legal cannabis sales
despite the fact that it's federally
legal and to your point we now have two
political parties who are competing
against one another so i can only
believe that this is going to act as a
further catalyst to decrease the
timeline for which federal legalization
will occur
and ultimately when that does occur i
think we're just going to see the
floodgates truly open like what we've
seen up until this point has been
fantastic but once you have interstate
commerce and cannabis brands in
california are able to start shipping
their products you know from west coast
to east coast i think we're going to see
an enormous amount of cash flow into
this industry and i think all that we've
seen to date will really be sort of i
don't want to say insignificant but i
think it will seem a little bit
insignificant as to what will likely
follow in the the four years that will
come after that
yeah now i couldn't agree with you more
i think the biggest one of them all is
the new york legalization it's going to
jump into the second their third biggest
industry in america if not tying with
california but i think the most
significant thing is that it's so close
to europe in terms of perception by
europeans in terms of irish people and
in terms of business people in new york
a lot of them have bases over here in
europe whereas california companies and
colorado companies necessarily don't so
i think just that close proximity to a
market that's going to explode and it's
going to prove that the capital gains
and the job creations are there is
another positive for europe to be able
to watch and see and uh have the
influence come over the politicians and
decision makers over here because
whatever you can be naive as you want
capital moves everything and the capital
hasn't been able to get into these
markets yet and a lot of the capital is
situated in new york so i think it's
going to be an interesting year to say
the least from march next year when
everything kicks off kicks off over
there
absolutely and to really tie a boat on
that like right now
321 000 people have paid full-time
employment in the legal cannabis
industry in the united states like that
is the outrageous amount of employment
that industry is now providing and again
despite the fact that cannabis remains
federally illegal so very excited about
what's happening on the state level and
hopefully when we're having this
conversation next year there might be a
little bit more progress made on the
federal legislation
yeah fingers crossed now fingers crossed
so we're going to move on to the next
section we're going to pick two of the
biggest moments of 2021 each we've only
got like four or five minutes we can
stretch over maybe a minute past it um
but yeah i'm going to keep it to that
there's the kind of way gonna put there
behind me so um yeah i'll take kick
things off so two of the ones that i'm
gonna go we had a little discussion
before and i think we agreed and
everything for but the big one for me is
the jazz acquisition of gw pharma for
seven point four billion dollars it
started the hawk of it was back in
february but it was confirmed in may
when it went through the listing so i
think that's such a significant play
especially coming from a uk company that
supposedly wear a territory where it's
completely illegal they're the second
biggest manufacturer or exporter of
medic cannabis in the world and it's
just one of those funny scenarios that
you really got capital in the markets
now over this side of the water not just
in the u.s so that's going to be the big
moment for me number one what about you
for my cell phone i'd have to highlight
the fact that germany is now on course
to legalize cannabis like
having having lived in ireland for the
better part of my life and having a
decent understanding as to how how
certain legislation is crafted by
politicians in in the eu
i have to
i have to the sense that there is going
to be significant ramifications of a
nation state like germany legalizing
cannabis ultimately leap frog in the
united states were by you know colorado
first aid to legalize cannabis for
allergies purposes back in 2012 so they
had a 10-year head start despite that
the germans have caught up it looks like
they're going to be
the first sort of major european nation
to effectively embrace the adult use or
the outlet whose cannabis market so for
me that that's the top moment of 2021
and
i get the sense that that is going to
have huge ramifications for for the
european market and hopefully hopefully
our our politicians in ireland are uh
are taking note as to what our german
counterparts are putting in place
yeah well i think you agree once you've
got germany going in
everything goes according to plan there
and i've interviewed the top of the top
companies in germany some of the top
lawyers the people in that industry are
razor sharp i think that's going to be a
big big big success in germany there's
no
flesh on the bone on any of the
companies i've talked over there
everybody's very precise to know what
they're doing they're as up to date as
any territory in the world and i think
that triggers and france to happen when
you get france and germany doing
anything in europe it's pretty much a
landslide across the board everywhere
else like what we're saying in the
previous conversation the markets will
then be alive where the m a's happen
where the new territories for growth so
i think yeah a great one so my second
one then i i'm i'm chosen between two of
them and i don't know what you're going
to pick the other one so it's either
between amazon changing their cannabis
employee policy or the ufc change in
their cannabis employee policy either
way a massive sporting firm which kind
of opened the floodgates to the nfl and
a couple of orders to stop cannabis
testing for thc and not ban athletes and
also amazon uh triggering then what
allowed apple to stop banning their apps
on their app store and it was kind of
big tech and sport both aligned with uh
lifting the ban on cannabis so what are
you gonna go for your second one just
out of curiosity
i'm gonna i'm gonna piggyback on your
your suggestion regarding amazon and
apple
the fact that the two most valuable
companies in the world like literally
the two most valuable companies in the
world
both updated their policies in favor of
cannabis this year to me just speaks
volume to the progress which is being
made
as to the fact that
previously the misconceptions associated
with cannabis was i think we're now
reaching a point thankfully whereby
people are aware that cannabis is not
the the dangerous drug it was once made
out to be
and consequently you have companies like
apple and amazon who are starting to
take note of that in america there's 68
of the population are in favor of
legalization and with labor shortages
they're identifying that in order for
them to retain and attract the highest
quality people to their companies they
have to update their policies such that
they are taking a more sort of
progressive
position when it comes to cannabis so
for me that is a huge milestone for the
cannabis industry we don't have
companies that are able to actually list
apps on the app store that's a little
bit important but to me it's just the
fact that the two most valuable
companies in the world have both
simultaneously started embracing
cannabis just tells a very sort of very
interesting tale as to the progress this
industry has made in the the last number
of years
yeah i don't know if you remember from
last year one of our top five things was
jay-z getting into it so is the
celebrity world embracing cannabis so 12
months later we've got the biggest tech
companies in the world
so it's a pretty good it's a pretty good
year as much as there's been a lot of
shows and uh garbage being spewed
by a lot of people who aren't as
informed as they should be
absolutely
i think that's definitely coming to an
end thankfully i i think the the sort of
the
fear-mongering we've seen a lot less of
it this year
that's going to continue to decline as
more people have access to the
information which ultimately informs us
the fact that this is a very safe
substance
yeah well we've had some of the biggest
review and episodes on this show now
have been like dr peter grimstone from
harvard medical we've had dr anoivey
from william patterson university the
head of uh neurology in toronto medical
you know what i mean so you can you can
only refuse and have these arguments so
long before you start looking like a
crazy person in the world i think we're
really going to the other inflection
it's been an absolute pleasure talking
to you um i hope you have a great
christmas with your family and i look
forward to talking to you in the new
year but best look with the newsletter i
hope everything goes great
likewise only congrats on the success of
the cannabis review this year have been
thoroughly enjoying all the high quality
interviews should be putting out yeah
well thank you very much to all the
guests as the last episode of the year
so for every guest that we've had on
there's been maybe 40 or 50 now at this
stage thank you very much the show is
nothing without the guests coming on and
informed people like matthews giving us
their
knowledgeable opinions so thank you very
much to all the viewers as well hope
everybody's had a great 2021 i will be
blazing it up at the end of the year and
i look forward to seeing everybody at
the
start of 2022
bye