[Music]
welcome everybody to another episode of
the cannabis review thanks very much to
everybody for joining us i am delighted
to be joined on this episode by p.m
martine
she is the co-founder and ceo of
carnival ag over in germany pia how are
you keeping you well
yes i'm doing great um happy to be here
today
delighted to have you on your lady make
a lot of news in europe at the moment
uh can you maybe give the guys a little
overview of how you got to kind of them
and your journey in the industry so far
yeah sure no problem my name is pia
martin i'm the ceo and co-founder of the
konova meiji
and we want to provide patients in
germany and europe with
medical cannabis so our vision is that
every patient deserves the best
therapy and cannabis as a medicine
or cannabis in general i think is a
highly stigmatized topic here in germany
and during my studies abroad in the
netherlands for example
um i was surprised by how
different the approach from society was
there regarding cannabis
and it was much more accepted there than
it is here
so when medical cannabis got legalized
um here in germany
in 2017 i knew i wanted to
work in this industry in this field you
know and
after conducting intensive research
about medical benefits talking to
doctors and patients
i was really touched by their stories
and i always wanted to do
something meaningful um the current
state of knowledge is that
cannabis can really heal but it can
improve patients
quality of life so our federal institute
for drugs
and medical products um also called
beefarm
they're running a non-interventional
survey
for cannabis and they track indications
and improvements
and the typical patient for example is a
chronic pain patient
mostly over 50 years old and has been
in chronic pain for more than 10 years
mostly and with
medical cannabis as a as a medicine
those patients can be helped um
quality of life can be improved it can't
heal
but it can improve patients quality of
life which is really important
and um yes so what i've learned
um about cannabis as a medicine it's
it's the potential it has for patients
um hasn't been fully used yet or fully
um yeah fully developed yet so
we need to improve access to
medical cannabis for patients and we
want to provide medical
cannabis that is sunlight grown and free
of chemical pesticides
so i founded the company with my
co-founder
marius cosa in 2019
to do exactly that so
why sunlight grown and free of chemical
pesticides i
think a sustainable approach is very
important
so before i worked at kenobo i
worked in the field of renewable energy
so
therefore i see a lot of a lot of
similarity between the industries
and sustainability is very important to
me
so therefore we found canovum
with a different approach than our
competitors so we want to provide
medical cannabis that is sunlight grown
and free of chemical pesticides
because after all cannabis is a plant it
needs light and water
and i think that's the best approach
in that industry okay well i'm going to
skip to the third topic and we can come
back to the second because we kind of
led into it
and that's europe's supply chain uh
you're just
talking about sunlight ground flower and
now pesticides
we had heidi whitman on a couple of days
ago on the show
and again a similar model do you have
your flower grown in a specific part of
the world that allows for the sunlight
to be grown
or what territory is your supply coming
into europe from
um well um i can say uh exactly from
where but it's
the european union um and
we sourced probably over 50 or talked to
over 50 um cultivators worldwide
two source of products we're not
vertically integrated but we work with
the best in the industry that's our
approach
and yes and we found a partner
that is growing um
medical cannabis uh under all the
regulations
up to our quality standards so without
chemical pesticides
and in sunlight um so it's from the
european union yes
so do you see then one of the next kind
of lead-ons that
there is a certain amount of companies
that are going to focus on the price per
gram and it's going to be grown in one
of the
latin american countries or in africa do
you see the
the farming ability in europe which is
far more advanced than most territories
in the world do you see that being
a leg up for europe for him being able
to supply the whole continent of europe
with europe-grown
cannabis or do you always see that
there's going to be a balance of the
supply chain
coming into europe from far-off
countries and grown locally
well i think um there are two aspects to
it um
first of all um importing
from within the european union to
germany for example is much easier
than doing it from from third-party
countries um
so the regulatory aspect is one um but i
agree with you
um in europe we see a lot of cultivation
right now
a lot of cultivators entering the market
um with high quality product
um so i see that the european union
probably
could um satisfy
the demand here with uh within
the european union but obviously
other countries with preferable
cultivation conditions like africa south
america
will also have good products probably
with a lower price that will enter the
market
but the regulation um regarding the
certification
it's it's much more demanding um you
need to be
eugmp certified uh in order to
export to the european union or to
germany
um so not everyone is meeting the demand
yet
um covet might also be a reason during
covert
less inspections have been conducted
all over the world so this might delay
it a bit
but obviously um other cultivators from
other countries
will enter the market as well yeah
i see as well that i was reading
recently that some of the first grown
uh cannabis grown in germany has hit the
german market for your pharmacy some
grown by aurora and one of the other
concepts that's a pretty good milestone
to be able to say that we've got our own
flower on our own shelves for our own
consumers
and i i think the europe could end up
going that direction that
certain countries are going to have
certain genetics and strains
that are uh relative to maybe let's say
the diseases or the patients that
they're trying aiming to treat in each
individual country whereas i think
america is going to focus more on just
it'll be
weed to get high and weed as a
commercial adult use product
whereas i think europe you could have a
far more nuanced industry with
individual genetics and strains
kind of brings me on to the next topic i
wanted to talk to you about is germany
good for cannabis startups
do you see this being one of the homes
we've talked to the malta enterprise
board already
we've talked to we know ireland is one
of the main hubs for a lot of the big
huge global companies
do you think germany is going to be a
hub for some of the cannabis startups in
europe
um well as you mentioned um we have the
first german cannabis on the market now
so i think this is a pretty big
milestone
for the whole industry you know the
european industry in germany being the
biggest market in it
and therefore i think yes it's a good
place
for cannabis startups but i think there
are two
aspects to consider here once you have
the um
medical side you know the patients the
physicians
and we have many more patients in
germany than physicians who prescribe
cannabis as a medicine and unfortunately
cannabis
and the endo cannabinoid system are
rarely part of pharmaceutical medical
education
that's something we need to work on and
we support physicians and
pharmacists through medical education we
offer workshops
and an online platform that offers
education on that end and the other part
is the regulatory side getting all the
pharmaceutical licenses you need a
narcotics license you need a
distribution license
we also have the manufacturing license
in order
to build important steps here in germany
and yeah bring the best products to our
patients um the market is therefore
really complex with high entry barriers
um
which is obviously um good for
um the companies that are already in the
market um
but i see germany
as a really potential market
here in germany because if you look at
the german market
um it's the biggest one in europe as i
said and if you look at the numbers a
bit
in 2020 um i think more than 128 000
patients were treated
um in 2017 um when it was
legalized there were only 27 000 so
that's a lot more and according to
prohibition partners
more than one million german patients
will have access to medical cannabis
by 2024 which is it's a huge step in
development
and medical cannabis market alone i
think is expected to be worth around 7.7
billion
by 2028. so um i think
we will see great development
and the german and european market has
great potential in my opinion yeah i
agree with you i think germany is going
to be the model for europe that what
happens there is going to be distributed
across the continent
just for as i said size of market the
skilled uh
labor workforce there that you know
products coming in are going to be to
the highest of global standards so
yeah it's exciting times to be in
germany and you guys recently listened
to the burlington hamburg
stock exchanges so again congratulations
on that
what are the plans for the next 12 to 24
months that you'd like to take off your
uh
if you had a dream cannabis list of give
me two items to tick off in the next 12
months what are they going to be
oh well i mean um one big milestone was
listing
as you mentioned right now um we got
first listed in dusseldorf
that was a huge milestone we've been
working on for a while now
um but obviously we have a lot more
future plans
and we want to bring our own sustainable
brand into the market
this will be the next uh big step uh a
huge milestone for us
and obviously we see we see ourselves
not just as a
german berlin company but as a european
company
therefore we are looking into different
markets as well
and really looking closely
on the developments there and probably
will be soon in other markets as well
well we look forward to seeing your
products over in ireland for anybody
wants to learn more about
kind of them you can check out the
website down below hey it's been an
absolute pleasure to talk to you i hope
we can get to the chat before the end of
the year is out
and maybe we get to meet in person at
one of the conferences that are
happening around the world so
have a great day and thank you very much
for coming on the show
thank you very much uh thanks for your
time it was a pleasure and hope to
talk to you soon bye see you next time
[Music]