[Music]
welcome to the next episode of the
cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined in this episode by already
bernard who is the founder at newsweek
france how are you keeping the aurilian
very well thank you
great stuff mate thank you for coming on
uh i've been looking to kind of tip
around there around europe and look at
the kind of top media platforms that are
in europe and as everybody knows
newsweek friends is the top platform in
france so it's great to have you on the
show and give everybody an overview of
what is happening in your district can
you maybe get everybody up to speed and
where your career started in media and
how you ended up setting up news with
friends so we before we move into the
first topic
yes um
so newsweek was created seven years ago
uh before that i worked um in the media
industry um and i just figured out that
in france we didn't have any cannabis
news um so i'm
decided to
fulfill this empty space
and just
do what uh i was doing in in my previous
company um
that's building web platform um building
audience um and just talking about um
an empty topic in france um and when
starting
seven years ago um
i
was pretty sure i am was very aware of
all cannabis related topics and i
discovered pretty quickly that i didn't
know anything
um that
everything that i was taught in france
about cannabis was either debuts or
false um so i restarted to educate
myself on every cannabis related topic
mostly with
anglophone sources studies therapeutical
studies and
all the topics that
is cannabis related and i started to
answer my own question and in fact the
first news with article were the answer
um at my question um and
after a few months
after starting newsweek it was really
a beginner stuff at the beginning
and i gained traction i can audience and
i decided to quit my job to um just
develop news with and and build a
true cannabis media that yeah it is
today and today we are
again the the
leading um cannabis median friends and
prejudices only one to do what we do um
that is um writing daily about worldwide
legal cannabis news without advocating
um or without be uh being a
pro cannabis or poor legalization
and we try to cover all kind of stuff
from political uh subject to
therapeutical to lifestyle to culture um
not translation because we can't uh
talk about translation in france but
culture
and and and
that array of after peach and i am
got um extremely lucky for example to
work with with maps which is one of the
biggest
tech company
cannabis related in u.s um so all my
journey
was really i was very lucky to meet a
lot of companies of worldwide companies
that are very very known now
amazing yeah you guys have built up a
great reputation and the content that
you put out on a daily basis are very
impressive to say the least the first
topic i wanted to kind of jump into was
european cannabis
media the one thing i've noticed about
the media was it was a very open space
at the start you had mj biz daily and
maybe business can came to the fore over
here a little bit first and pro pro
british parkers have acquired them now
recently so i'm sure they're going to
grow their their market share as well
everything seemed directed initially at
the the kind of business people and the
ceos and there has been very few
consumer based media platforms that i've
noticed up yet even the likes of high
time seem to have lost their way to a
good degree that they're not as
reputable as they used to be
who are the kind of cannabis media
players in europe that you kind of would
respect there's obviously laura ramos in
portugal what kind of reporter is one of
the good sources is there anybody up in
switzerland or germany or denmark or
maybe even italy that you're at grc and
coming to the fore
yeah and i i look at um yeah obviously
can reporter cannabis industry in
netherlands too
uh business
in uk dolce vita
in italy kenya
um
in spain
pretty every european country has his
own um either magazine or web platform
and
when i started news with
friends didn't have any
any so
that's why i created
my media
and
they are pretty reputable some of the
oldest magazines the printed magazine
still exists today
um and in france we didn't have any um
any
media about cannabis because it's really
difficult to to talk about cannabis you
can't um uh advocate for cannabis use
for example um it's still punished with
fine and and potentially jail um so the
media
angle was a way to talk um
about cannabis without being punished uh
and i think all
the other european countries have more
facility to to talk and write
about that subject
obviously business is a big part of
all the media today
but
i try to have more
lifestyle and culture
which is important because um
all the medical
and the adult use industry is based on
what happened um 20 30 40 years before
and
we have to be aware of that to build a
sustainable industry
yeah now i agree i think a lot of the
b2b uh media platforms now they're all
just rehashing the same story somebody
puts out one story it just seems to be
copy and pasted ten times over whereas
the culture side of it and uh yeah
highlighting specific whether it's music
or food or creativity or whatever it is
that it may be there's a consumer base
out there that are consuming cannabis
not everybody's owning a business and
looking at the tax regulations and some
of the research that might be coming out
in in medical side of things um we're
actually going to be the cannabis viewer
going to be launching now in ireland as
the irish platform so we've got a lot of
lawyers going to be writing articles and
djs and people all giving in different
types of playlists and food but do you
think there's going to be a number of
mergers and acquisitions now over the
next couple of years in cannabis media
where there's a dominant player in
europe or do you see there being still
territorial publications that are
still just specific to each individual
country
yeah media is a complicated um
enterprise um as you can see in united
states or in canada a lot of media uh
felt uh
or almost disappear
for example the cannabis
who was a legacy media uh has been
bought by a local journal and then
closed i times as a lot of difficulties
to maintain
its business um
in canada um lyft was actually pretty
known and and almost disappear
they are still doing some events this
year
but as for europe um it could
um it's some major um could happen um
but
even if we are
a united 25 countries uh like big big um
uh big uh gathering um
we still have a lot of difference uh
mainly in in regular regulatory parts um
so you could have something and a lot of
language too
so it's really difficult to maintain a
wall homogeneity of news um talking
about um area and talking to everybody
in europe so i mostly see that uh with
uh
each country will have
uh its own media or medias uh with
several one and it's that doesn't avoid
um some major um
between national media to have a
european media group uh it could also
happen um but
as for um development of the development
of the media um industries should look
at it too because media is really
powerful and important um to not to to
do communication or advertising but just
to be objective and spread
um
the reality of the cannabis in the good
and the bad and the bad sides um
and industries should support the media
because they are yeah spreading
the ideas
in really important for europe i
couldn't agree with you more the media
is the tip of the sphere in this
industry and that's it's how everybody's
being informed so the more well funded
and the better content that's been put
out by media companies the better it's
going to be for everybody in the
industry because it will create more
awareness and bring that level of
professionalism that needs to be brought
to some of the media platforms i'm going
to jump on to the last topic before i
let you go and it's an overview of
french cannabis now we've talked to uh
people before comparison it was a while
ago now so can you maybe give us a quick
overview of the first cultivation
license i saw with overseed were
announced um cbd flower on sale and
dispensaries over there or is it still
illegal to sell cbd flour because i
think that's one of the
big territories that's going on our big
industries that'll happen in europe is
the sale of cbd flower been allowed i
think is gonna explode in europe once
they get all the regulations in the
place
yeah so for the medical side um we have
an experimentation with two thousand
patients for five uh illnesses um those
patients have the right to have uh thc
oil and tick flowers now um and they are
experimentating for two years
one year remaining now
um and
the country decided to
give license to go medical cannabis in
france to
once the experimentation will be
finished and
medical cannabis reinforced and
authorized in france um
to have some french medical cannabis
because you don't rely on importation
forever
so the first company had
its license of production they are doing
um research and development uh tests for
now um but could be ready to have their
first commercial grow um at the
beginning of the next year
so it's just the first we know that it
takes a lot of time um to have a
a facility that is running and ready to
um distribute to the patients that
friends finally managed to
come forward on something
medical
cannabis related
and
as you may know we are the first
cannabis user or one of the first in
europe
we are big smoker and big consumer
we also have the one of the harsher slow
in france
in europe because you can still have
some fine and some jail for cannabis
simple use just processing or smoking on
the streets for example um
and
the the
difficulty of that and
is that for example for cbd we had like
2 000 shops opened in like two years so
you have cbd shops everywhere on big
city in paris you may have like 200 cbd
shops with flowers and everywhere even
in the small city including countryside
you can
shop cbd or to the tobacco shop you find
some cbd flower so it's everywhere it's
not really legal right now
but it's not illegal
and all the other cbd products are
totally okay
but as for the flower we don't have any
low so it's a bit far west
uh for this kind of business
yeah i noticed even over new york they
don't fully legalize until i think it's
october and it was over there like a
month ago and there's like weed trucks
on every single avenue and there's just
seems to be that loophole whereas they
know it's going to be legal so what's
the point in wasting the time with all
the paperwork and and whatnot it's been
great to talk to you i could talk to you
all day earlier and uh i want to thank
you very much for taking your time to
come on the show for everybody who
hasn't checked out newsweek dot f4 the
website is below i highly recommend it's
one of the best sources of cannabis
media content in europe and i look
forward to hopefully chatting to you
again in the near future
thank you for your invitation
it was great having you on me until the
next episode everybody we'll chat you
then