[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined on this episode by real
powerhouse of the cannabis industry
george
the co-founder and ceo of jg media so
change media produces mj unpacked which
is a leading cbg consumer package goods
trade show and they also publish mj
brand insights which provides up to
minute industry intelligence and
in-depth research georgia also served as
the ceo of dope media and led its
acquisition of high time so we're
delighted to have you on the show george
thank you very much for joining us owen
thank you so much for having me today i
really appreciate it great to have you
on so i've got to basically start off
with the first kind of question that i
had you basically saw oversaw the
the
acquisition of high times what makes a
good cannabis acquisition in the media
space in your opinion
in in what makes it a good space in
europe or in just in the media space in
general in media space in general is it
consumer content is it the the
problem with this
yeah so to give a little background owen
you know i've been doing trade shows for
about 30 years mostly focused on
business to business when i came in the
cannabis space i basically took over as
the president of mj bizcon and mj biz
daily which was a b2b and became the
largest one under my
uh tenure um after i left there though i
had an opportunity to kind of step in
the consumer media space and dope
magazine had built a really phenomenal
brand um except for the fact that i
don't know if anybody had figured out
the consumer media model in the us yet
there was a lot of assets out there with
a lot of hope and promise of becoming
profitable and sustainable
um unfortunately you know when when i
stepped into the the opportunity dope
magazine um we really needed to raise
some more money and there wasn't a lot
of capital out there we had looked at a
couple of different acquisition
opportunities
had a deal done with a different company
that kind of changed their mind at last
minute and high times was a good fit for
us
and they were looking to make a number
of acquisitions and really kind of
reinvigorate the high times brand that
had a lot of legacy support in the
industry and really kind of make it um
you know probably one of the most
recognizable cannabis brands
um in the us um you know after that
acquisition i had left uh my tenure at
dope slash high times um i just i
i think that the cannabis the the
consumer media space in cannabis is
challenging um there's a lack of really
i think some meaningful events out there
that can really um you know engage with
consumers for allow them to explore the
category um you know almost every one of
these media companies has you know a
number of different channels they have
print they have digital they have events
um you know and i'm excited i i just
talked to
rama maya the other day and
you know they just held their first
green street festival out in los angeles
really as as a bridge to from the the
business to business side to the
consumer
green street owns a building in los
angeles that
hosts a kind of a shared co-working
space as well as a number of brands that
utilize that as kind of a
california outpost
and the festival is really designed to
allow people to engage the category and
kind of discover the new form factors
that are coming out it's it's such a
fast and rapidly changing category owen
um so you know in the media space so
again um you know there's there's been a
lot of consumer media assets i just
don't know if anybody's figured out the
magic formula to make it sustainable
no i i think you're dead you're right
there i think the first wave of
information had to be b2b because
everybody needed to understand the
information of how to create the laws
accounts and all the nuances that go
with the business side of thing but i
think you're starting to see
consolidation of a number of brands such
as cookies you've got a couple of uh
platforms over here and i think it's
starting to switch now towards hold on a
minute we want to start capturing the
consumer's attention now because that's
who we're actually all trying to sell
the brands to
yeah and and and this is kind of this
kind of segues really close into why we
launched mj unpacked and i want to kind
of circle back on the consumer which is
really the most important they're
they're really the hero in the journey
right
um you know we when you say that that
b2b had to be the first and and when i
took over at mj biz con
um at the time they did a 20 tabletop
trade show at a race track because there
wasn't really a lot of venues saying hey
come on in and have a cannabis event it
was kind of scary there was a lot of
stigma associated with it
um there was a lot of concern around you
know what kind of behavior would happen
at these events but they were able to
successfully hold a couple very small
conferences and i was able to come in
and help them scale but the only way
that you could do an event back then was
really to have a supply side event so as
you know the the people who are
acquiring the licenses trying to figure
out what does a retail store look like
what does a cultivation operation look
like and so you know it was extraction
equipment it was lighting technol you
know lighting it was pos technology it
was label makers and and and light bulbs
and
and and there was a number of events
that kind of all sudden popped onto the
radar and there was this huge surge of
supply-side events but at the end of the
day let's let's be real cannabis is a
consumer package goods very much like
alcohol um you know going to get a
guinness or you're going to get a
cookies right
at your local pub hopefully someday down
the road in ireland
and and they're really you know if you
look at on the business to business side
of the media space usually the most
powerful and important trade show in the
cpg industries is a brand or retail
focus show and there did one didn't
exist because we don't have a national
market here in the united states because
of the complex legal system that's kind
of bifurcated between state and federal
law
um but our goal is really is like
let's let's be honest like the brand and
the retailer the last kind of
interchange and they kind of have a
shared responsibility to win over that
consumer of creating a safe and friendly
and educational retail environment that
a consumer can come in and explore a
category many people maybe never have
used cannabis before or they maybe
haven't used it for a couple of decades
um and to reintroduce them to the
category and then the brand has to
create a product that's tested it's
trusted it's transparent
that delivers on the experience that the
consumer is expecting
um and you know we obviously saw that
you know in the early stages of the
market there was kind of this rush to
bathtub gin so to speak
uh you know 100 milligram you know candy
bars and people didn't know better and
would over consume that um fortunately
we still have a perfect track record
nobody has died from a cannabis overdose
to date um so you know there but there
is danger obviously psychologically to
somebody over consuming cannabis that
can be very traumatic for people and we
want to be mindful that we need to kind
of
really manage that consumer you know
journey through the category um to win
them over as a category consumer not
just you know have a one-and-done
experience because they got too high
yeah no i agree i think the right stuff
like the race to the high thc content is
it the complete wrong direction for what
the consumer is actually going to want
to want when they have full choice going
state from state and even over in
germany you're going to see it legalized
and i think you're going to see
a lot of north american companies
planning that they're going to have
germany all to themselves whereas we
already know of a huge amount of
european companies who are already going
to be putting up
a fight for market share i want to move
on now to your mj unpacked your consumer
package goods trade show you guys did
your inaugural event in 2020 if i'm
right just about october just before
cove would kicked in was it was actually
2021 we actually founded the company
back at the tail end of 2019 and we
raised some capital to fund it
in february of 2020 so um you know when
i kind of look back at our journey um
you know i basically you know we we got
the money in just at the buzzer because
i don't think anybody would have given
us a dime to fund this enterprise um in
march and the economy shut down we did
do a number of virtual events
um and from a trade standpoint
especially for a very tactile industry
like cannabis you want to be able to
touch taste feel you need to be able to
be in the same room with somebody that
you're going to do business with
to kind of read their body language and
build a level of trust and and virtual
events just don't fit that bill very
well for cannabis and a lot of other
industries and the tech space are great
because it's very you know kind of
technical and and and transactional but
for cannabis it's very relational and
it's important that people get together
and kind of you know celebrate the the
industry but also be in the room with
the right people
with mgm pact one of the things that we
did different than any other trade show
in the united states is we actually
qualify every single one of our
attendees to make sure that they're a
retail or a brand cpg
brand company with the title of manager
hire so we're immediately screening to
make sure that everybody in the room is
a decision maker
we also know that you know one of the
big challenges here in the united states
is access to capital and we also allow
in accredited investors who are actively
investing in cannabis because we're
looking for intent and potential not
just somebody that might have a couple
hundred shares of cure leaf in their
e-trade portfolio but somebody who could
actually write a check
you know until we have access to safe
banking and normalize you know the
financial markets for cannabis um you
know it's going to continue to be a
choke point for our industry's growth
yeah we spoke to the guys green check
verified in new york peter sue and there
seems to be a couple of solutions coming
for the banking sector just around the
corner and i think that new york
industry is going to propel the us
industry on
by a huge margin i think even myself i
was over there two weeks ago and the
cannabis was prevalent everywhere from
the vans on fifth avenue to yeah cb's
doors selling thc products i think the
consumer tourism over there
people are underestimating how many
europeans i think are going to travel to
europe for to new york for cannabis
experience sure and well you can travel
to boston right now for a cannabis
experience it's uh certainly a little
bit closer than new york for traveling
across the pond but um you know it's
interesting because
um you know it's
on one side yes in new york it's kind of
this very kind of libertarian kind of
mentality living in a big city like that
that you kind of as long as they're not
infringing on your personal space or
rights then you know let them be and and
i've been you know when we did our show
in new york just this past may i mean
people are outside smoking you can smoke
cannabis legally at any place that
you're allowed to smoke a cigarette so
restaurants you know have outdoor patios
you can go up and light up a joint and
go have your meal
you know and and i do agree with you
that new york because of its weight and
its influence in washington might
accelerate
um you know the the legal some type of
safe banking solution uh but you know
the other other side of it when you say
it's right around the corner we've been
saying that for almost 10 years now in
the cannabis space um unfortunately and
and
um you know i i know that you have a lot
of very intelligent you know listeners
to this i mean american politics have
become blood sport um we've allowed
corporate interest to influence our
politics to a a degree in a level that
is dangerous for democracy um i hope
that someday we repeal the
um citizens united we have career
politicians that are you know it's it's
i was listening to a program the other
day that
on average like 95 of our centers and
representatives will get reelected
because it's just there's that much
influence for them to be able to beef up
their campaign coffers versus a
non-incumbent thing and that's that's
problematic for democracy but um you
know hopefully we um this great
experiment will figure it out again
yeah i hope so last thing i wanted to
touch on was the mj brand and insights
that you guys do one of the things that
it's probably a pet peeve i know over in
europe here the amount of reports that i
see that europe is going to be worth 50
billion germany is going to be worth 10
billion how do you bring real truth and
insight and analysis to hypothetical
markets that may not have happened yet
do you set parameters for you guys
because over here some of the the
companies that do it don't really seem
to it seems to be all one-sided we're
just going to write all the fluffy stuff
for us i think it has to be more nuanced
than that for for real investors to have
a look
yeah absolutely and so mj brand insights
we actually just rebranded as mjbi um we
do have a strategic partnership with a
company called bdsa they are one of the
leading analytics firms in the market um
and and and going back to that i mean
everybody you know any publisher or you
know data an analyst is going to want to
come up with some hyperbolic future
number of what the market's going to be
and the bigger that number is the more
likely that they're going to get press
coverage on that number right so
um it's it it's somewhat of a function
of sensationalized news um that that
we've fallen in a trap as opposed to you
know critical thinking and you know pure
journalism um you know
what we're trying to do is again is
differentiate ourselves from the kind of
oversaturated like hey let's post news
stories that are basically pulled from
news feeds um you know about this this
happening or this company you know
launching this product but really kind
of you know have more of a
conversational approach um we also have
a strategic partnership with a company
called pioneer intelligence it's really
cool what they do they measure
um consumer activity based on three
pillars social media website traffic and
earn media and so they can kind of see
which brands are trending up they're
getting more hits on their on their
social media posts on their website and
and tie that in and so if somebody from
the company is you know can look at
saying all right we ran this marketing
promotion we saw this big uptick so
let's run that again right that worked
and if it doesn't happen it didn't work
let's do something else um so we don't
we don't do that type of market analysis
what we do do is we cover you know
brands that are creating innovation we
look at
you know um social equity owned brands
uh women-owned brands we really try to
cover the underrepresented voices in
this industry and you know while the
msos in the space get you know suck up a
lot of oxygen and news channels
it's really innovation really happens at
the kind of
small business level and when you know
you have a very serial entrepreneur
trying to differentiate themselves and
those are the stories we want to see get
lifted up get get attention um you know
going back i know that you know the
american market is very nuanced compared
to what's going to happen in europe um
but
at some point in time there's going to
be a moment where we federally legalize
cannabis
the alcohol and tobacco companies have
business plans they have operational
capital set aside they have some really
smart people and they're going to try to
steamroll this entire industry and i
think it would be a shame
if the cannabis industry lost some of
this innovation that happens at the
grassroots level and more importantly is
that we lost control of the thought
leadership of cannabis because we
deserve a better industry that's more
compassionate this is medicine this
isn't
an intoxicant and really help help
support the growth of the industry
so when europe legalizes is there a
brand in north america canada or at the
usa that you think has the best chance
of making europe
um i would say
not necessarily i think that the largest
brand in the world
might not yet have been invented
um there's certainly some powerhouses
here in the u.s like we had talked about
before the cookies purely select wanna
brands um that have some potential but
um you know i think the european
market's going to be very unique and i
think that european brands are going to
have the opportunity to really own that
market
yeah i couldn't agree it's it's very
nuanced over here when you get over here
and the the the ability to be able to
penetrate the whole of europe with one
brand and one narrative and one message
is a little bit of a misplaced idea i
think
yep we've got i mean we've got all these
bifurcated state markets here i mean in
europe you know you know regardless of
the eu you do have very you know unique
cultural kind of nuances to this and so
um yeah i'm excited to see what's going
to happen next
yeah very much so can't thank you enough
for taking your time to talk to us it's
been very much appreciated anybody wants
to check out more about jh media it is
just on the link is below it'll be
connected to the link in each platform
that you're watching around now so thank
you very much for your time george
thanks so much ellen really appreciate
your time
hopefully we get to chat again in the
near future and get an update of
everything that's happened
let's do it thanks guys see you next
episode