[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined on this episode by darwin miller
who's the chief scientific officer at
final bail i'm also an entrepreneur and
inventor how you keeping today daryl
i'm doing very well owen how are you
i'm fantastic mate as always thank you
very much for taking time out of your
busy day to chat with us and help
hopefully educate the audience on a
couple of different topics do you want
to maybe give everybody a quick overview
of how you ended up the csl final bell i
know you've been in the industry a long
time
uh sure yeah so i'm in an industry 17
years
for me you know a mechanical engineer
out of college it could have been design
slurry pumps for the fracking industry
or
joined the cannabis industry 17 years
later i've been able to with my hands-on
experience and kind of navigating the
market
teamed up with an amazing group here at
final bell and have them an opportunity
to be the chief science officer and help
with our scientific and project process
efficiencies and all sorts of different
uh research and development efforts that
we're doing
amazing yeah the photo bit looked like a
very impressive company and i can see
them changing the landscape for a lot of
the smaller brands over the next coming
years and i'm sure it's exciting to be
part of such a great group
absolutely it's an amazing team and uh i
feel super fortunate
right well let's just jump into this
topic straight away the first one i
wanted to talk about and you're pretty
an expert on this topic is extraction
techniques can you maybe explain over
here in ireland at the moment you're
only allowed to use a cold pressed
isolate so there are no supercritical
there are no co2 extraction the legality
is it has to be a cold-pressed isolator
it has to be done on the firm can you
maybe give everybody a quick overview of
what are the the best techniques what's
the most cost effective and what's the
most popular one you see
for sure well i guess um
that's an interesting question you know
obviously depending on what type of end
product you're looking to make maybe you
might choose a different extraction
method or technique based on that end
goal right so there might be
multiple different ways to get to say a
crude initial extract
and then a few different ways to refine
that but maybe only a couple of uh say
techniques for isolating and purifying
individual cannabinoids so depending on
that marketplace you're in uh if you're
not allowed to utilize certain
techniques then you're kind of
prohibited from
being able to make it there and you
might have to import those products
what do you see as being what's the best
form of extraction if you were to make
is it is it a completely different
process for let's say an edible
extraction than it would be for a
cartridge extraction
that's another great question you know
again i'm uh as a process trained design
engineer and kind of uh trying to be
agnostic about extraction techniques
don't have
one method over another that's
particularly good
again co2 ethanol extraction hydrocarbon
these all work well for
depending on what your end goal is what
you're trying to make some may be more
or less efficient based on you know
whether you're trying to make a purified
isolate or a distillate for instance
okay so when it turns to the extraction
techniques there isn't a metric let's
say
per gram per liter extracted that people
use in the industry to be able to
use a specific okay this is the
technique we're going to use because it
delivers this a b and c of our return
well i mean that's a great question too
so yield is obviously really important
and depending on whether that's weight
end to weight out or how much solvent
you're using and other things there's
lots of different ways to measure
efficiency and i think scale of
operation is one of the most important
and kind of depending on where you're at
if you're trying to get a quick and
dirty ethanol you know extraction out
and then clean that up with distillation
for instance uh ethanol really is
a
very cost-effective solution
and no reason to use you know something
like a very expensive co2 extractor
again for instance right if you're just
trying to make crew that you're going to
clean up with distillate and what would
be super critical extraction what's the
that makes that so super
great question so super critical fluid
extraction is uh you take co2 and you
know there are uh there's liquid there's
solid and there's uh gas right well
supercritical is another phase of matter
where you actually have the
properties of a gas
and a liquid so you can
extract more efficiently when you're in
those those particular phases
okay amazing and
in the two processes that get the end
product the extraction and the
distillation can you do a bad
distillation and have a good extraction
or can you do a bad extraction and have
a good distillation or do you both need
to be delivering
standards that are required
another great question uh so i mean
you can certainly have bad distillation
and bad extractions right and you could
clean up a bad extraction with good
distillation and you could ruin a good
extract with a bad distillation process
for sure so
dialing in your pro your parameters uh
you know
vacuum depth temperature et cetera that
helps you achieve
your efficient extraction and or
distillation process
okay i'm going to jump on to the next
topic and it's something that i've kind
of been curious and i think you're the
most
expert guest that i've had on you might
be able to answer this for some
pharmacological properties terpenes
versus terpenoids versus cannabinoids
now we know terpenes are basically just
a simple harm
hide carbonated structure and terpenoids
have oxygen in that exact same structure
if you were to extract a product which
one would you be advising somebody to
put into a specific let's say an
oil-based product or are they all a
combination are going to be required to
have the the desired effect
another great question so i'm actually
not the best to answer pharmacological
property questions but i do know that in
regards to classes of molecules terpenes
and trapenoids and and cannabinoids are
all terpeno terpene terpenoid phenolic
secondary metabolites and are all coming
together inside of uh in your typical
extraction process so if you know you're
going for a full spectrum or
uh a broad spectrum extract right um all
of these are coming together and they
make up that flavor profile that smell
profile everything that is really
whether it's a
solvent-less extract or a
hydrocarbon-based extract or whatever
that makes that that profile so unique
and broad spectrum versus full spectrum
is there an argument to be had here or
is it a non-conversation i hear somebody
who's it's not real unless it's full
spectrum and other people battle the
other way what's your expert opinion on
that
uh great question so for me it's
semantics whether it's full or broad
spectrum you know i guess a great uh
scientific approach to that is how can
you truly be full
if you are leaving behind like cellulose
or chlorophyll other things that might
not be necessarily of interest in your
extract
so you know whether it's full or broad i
think what the market is kind of define
that as is does it have trace amounts of
thc in it or no thc at all and that's
kind of where that has fallen
okay very interesting so full spectrum
medic is a is a non-starter for
conversation because it is an actual
full spectrum there are certain elements
left behind
okay great absolutely you got it yeah
this would be a wealth of information to
come out of you and basically i wanted
to talk about international affairs in
cannabis now we hear a lot of talk about
europe is going to be a bigger market
than north america and a lot of the
companies in canada and america talking
about how they're going to have x amount
of market share when it comes to this in
terms of the language that you see
happening in the international affairs
and cannabis how realistic do you think
american brands are going to be over in
europe selling to a recreate
recreational market and how quickly do
you think actually probably the senate
is going to okay
full legislation in america first off
ooh uh that's a good question so in
regards to
adult use products being manufactured in
say the states being shipped and sold in
europe i don't think that
uh is going to happen i think europe is
more than capable of being able to
produce its own
adult use cannabis products no problem
that said you know the more novel foods
dietary supplements and true
pharmaceuticals you know that's where
you might see more uh global commodity
manufacturing hubs coming up whether
that might be in india or south africa
or uh north america or wherever it might
more uh the climatic region makes it
more efficient right to produce these
raw materials that allow you to produce
large bulk uh ingredients for whether
that's the
food supply chain which obviously is
quite demanding on
raw ingredients or pharmaceuticals
um
when it comes so i think there's an
opportunity for say u.s manufacturers
who are uh advantageous about conforming
to
european quality control
practices to be able to sell either raw
ingredients or finished goods that they
can manufacture legally in the states
but say can't sell legally nationally
and can take advantage of the
say the european union or the uk's
marketplace that allows for novel foods
with cbd in them for instance
okay and what are your thoughts now
there's a lot of talk but we've already
talked to uh elan sobel from
bio harvest sciences and from creole
ingredients susie sarkar what are your
thoughts on the ability for bioreactor
bioreactors to be able to create kind of
a mass scale with a multiple different
uh yields per year for versus a farm do
you see that being an actual
logical uh
ingredient for people to be using due to
the price point they're going to be able
to compete with and the amount of scale
they're going to be able to deliver
i mean
precision fermentation is an amazing
science uh but to address your other
question i forgot uh within the united
states for legality where are we when is
it going to happen i'd stay still easily
three to five years out
before we see it nationally but
precision fermentation now that's an
amazing subject you know where are we
going to see that come into play in the
cannabinoid industry right
it takes place
when it comes to precision manufacturing
of enzymes and other things we see in
food like this is a known thing like
it's it's commonly done and without it
right we actually wouldn't have uh yeast
cultures that would be available right
to do it to sell commercially for bread
starts and things like that right so
precision fermentation is definitely
here to stay when does it come into play
for the cannabidoin industry that's a
great question because it's not as
simple as i just want to make thcv for
instance
well to do that you have to map out the
genetic
pathway to get from cbga the very first
cannabinoid all the way through the
cycle to get to thcv and that's not one
culture of yeast that's
multiple iterations and life cycles of
yeast to get to that one that'll take a
starter from another culture
and produce thcv so you have to have
a culture that produces cbga first and
then one that makes cbg and then one
that makes thca and then one that makes
cbga and then one
et cetera et cetera before you can
really get there so what we'll see is
these you know the master or precursor
cannabinoid cbg come around first
uh and i think you'll you know if you
kind of look around the industry you'll
already see that cbg from precision
fermentation is currently being used in
the marketplace
and then we'll see thc and cbd come
around but i think in those particular
cases
where you have
uh the e the ability to produce it so
easily from plant material it might be
harder to justify the significant
investment in that infrastructure to
precision ferment it but for some of
these novel cannabinoids that might be
more difficult to do and say that that
synthesis pathway might be easier to
genetically imprint
i think we'll start to see that come
around in the next five to ten years for
sure
yeah i think you see a lot of the
companies uh gerano flies phosphate and
the cbga are the kind of things that
they're initially uh having the let's
say the strain of yeast or visas spit
out and can do is it another case of
that cbga then just needs to have enzyme
reactions that'll turn the cbga into
another cannabinoids is that why the
process works or is it a whole new
strain of engineered use do you think
no no so you're right but it is also uh
another pers engineered strain of yeast
to do that second stage in the synthesis
pathway
i'll catch up i catch it i got you know
it's an example
i apologize one has to make the cbga
right and then the next yeast culture
then takes that cbga and turns it to cbg
i get you i gotcha it's definitely an
interesting space harley has a random
history already in in this space i'll be
so i think you you're going to see
once it gets perfected those rare
cannabinoids going into applied
pharmaceutical ingredients and gone into
food and beverage ingredients i think
it's definitely going to be a future for
the european industry for sure
tell me this what are you looking
forward to the most over the next 12 to
24 months
what's going to happen in the industry
that you're most excited about is it a
case of one of the things i'd love to
see is augmented reality being
introduced into a cultivation course or
maybe machine learning been used to
you to to to find some cannabinoids and
some properties that might not have been
already recognized
oh well that's uh interesting i like the
idea of augmented reality for training
especially remote right i i know that
it's been implemented already in like uh
facility walkthroughs you know see your
facility before it's built type of thing
right which has been interesting uh but
honestly as a member of astm
international's technical committee d37
on cannabis what i i see in the next 12
to 24 months is hopefully a
a significance and use campaign brought
on by
the committee to help inform the global
community of the existence of our 35
standards and how they can be used in
the impact and benefit to the
marketplace and regulatory authorities
that for instance have not yet set up
regulatory programs and might be
thinking about it and to help them ease
into from illicit to list
listed marketplaces so i'm excited to
see
more and more global marketplaces come
online and facilitate standards to ease
access into the marketplace and
hopefully facilitate a more diverse
uh and
i guess global community in regards to
the cannabis industry
yeah i couldn't agree with you more it
seems like little pockets at the moment
on a global scale and once those free
market and free trades are
open for this industry i think it's
going to be a very very exciting place
with people at yourself with great
interview inventions who've already got
a foothold in the industry it's been
great talking to you darwin it's been
exactly what i thought it was
informative and uh a great chat for
anybody who wants to know more about
darwin he's his own website the spock of
cannabis.com is below i highly recommend
everybody checking it out and thank you
again darwin
yeah thank you so much and live long in
process
thanks guys