foreign
the next episode of the Cannabis review
on this episode I'm delighted to welcome
D Russell who is the founder and
multiple Time author and a consultant
for some of the biggest edible companies
in the world how are you keeping today
Dee uh how are you how are you I'm doing
excellent hey depasando as what we would
say down in Puerto Rico what's happening
well thank you very much for taking your
time to do this you've designed multiple
manufacturing facilities and you have
hundreds of formulations and recipes to
your name do you want to give everybody
a brief little overview of your current
position in the industry and how you end
up getting there uh absolutely well um
I've actually been in the industry in
the industry since 2006 so
um quite a little spit not as long as
some of the people that I know and my
mentors that were in as well but I work
currently as a consultant and formulator
in the space I design and blueprint and
help other brands and other countries
open all over the world I have designed
over 17 kitchens now I have two more
that's on the way so I'm going to be
getting to 19 here by the end of this
year and I design manufacturing and
extraction Labs from uh you know
commercial kitchens to also the solvent
solvent lists uh whether you need like
ethanol extraction CO2 or
um you know hydrocarbon as well as the
commercial kitchens and then I also
license my formulations to different
brands and help with the brand
development and I have over 400 plus
skus or products of mine that are in
circulation in the CBD hemp as well as
the medical marijuana marijuana industry
uh with a multitude of Brands um some of
the ones that I can name would be like
Dr Greenthumb their partners of mine as
well as Elite Gardens CBD American green
CBD pure leaf
um just name some of the big ones my
latest one here on the island that is
the top selling edible products in the
island is rosaretta so
um yeah that's a little bit about me and
what I do uh I'm a three-time published
author of The Happy Chef expert cannabis
cookbook series it is available on
Amazon and my claim to fame was my first
cookbook that I launched was actually in
partnership with Dr Green Thumb himself
if you've heard of him his name is
b-roll of Cypress Hill he's a leading
singer rapper of the hip-hop Group
Cypress Hill that is internationally
known uh Latino hip-hop group and in
that cookbook included his album as a
free download and I was their chef uh
their edible chef and I still work with
them designing their manufacturing Labs
as well as their products so but uh long
run and I'm happy to still be here and
I'm loving the space and I can't wait
for more to get in it we need more we
need more people in it yeah a highly
accomplished career is today take me
back to the first ever balsamic
vinaigrettesh that you produced as a
young person produced in your first
product like that what were some of the
hurdles that you had to overcome
well um I go really in depth in it in my
ex in my first expert cannabis cookbook
uh there's lots of details that when it
comes to plant infusion into fats
because cannabis is not water soluble I
can make it water soluble with a
extraction method with using
maltodextrin but that's a different
topic but infusing the fat you have to
work with the different
um you know there's boiling points and
there's also flash points or smoke
points with the oil uh there's compounds
that you can lose in the plant terpenes
mainly but also you you can lose
potencies and lose one of the more like
broad spectrum uh capabilities that the
plant has when you are in the extraction
process so choosing your fat that you
want to bind it with on beforehand
before you put it into your recipe is
that utmost important uh you know we've
I've kind of strayed away from can of
butter because they're all healthy
healthier options such as you know olive
oil avocado oil the main one I like to
use is MCT coconut oil mct's uh medium
chain triglyceride which allows the
medicine to actually go through your
body faster and you and so that the
medicine actually hits you faster
instead of oh I took an edible and it's
an hour later and hasn't hit me yet and
then you know everyone makes a mistake
whoops I took it too much and you know
we've I think we've all been there
I think everybody has a bad edible story
yeah well that actually kind of brings
me on to the main kind of first topic of
the show on its edible formulations and
production methods when it comes to the
formulations type of things obviously
what are like the top two three things
that people should be looking at is to
protect an IEP is it insuring the
absorption rate and the solubility of it
what are the kind of main things when it
comes to the formulation side of things
that are a Paramount to be keeping your
eye on oh okay well uh obviously you're
you're the chef make it taste good
that's job number one but the most
important job is homogeneity
um the exactly what you said the
delivery method of it getting into the
fat that you're buying it to get it into
your system it's very important but
being able to have your formula to the
quantity of the netway or wetway
depending on if you're baking or making
Confections gummies per se
um getting the formula right so that
each dose is exactly what it's supposed
to be is of utmost importance because
that's when Edibles can get dangerous
you know we call it edible roulette if
you make a batch and it's not completely
homogenized and it doesn't pass your
homogeneity test at the lab you know you
can eat one and feel nothing and then
somebody can get an 800 milligram gummy
and you know then it's night night
Grandma she's not going to make it to
your soccer practice okay
so I would definitely say homogeneity uh
quality of your ingredients
um and uh you know every everything with
infusion is temperature time and and and
and love honestly you put you put what
you you put your energy into everything
that you do so if you love what you do
and the recipe is solid the rest is just
formulas and math and you know the you
can Master this
yeah it seems to be when you actually
dive deep into this topic that it seems
to be the beautiful uh marrying of Art
and Science together uh where you have
to kind of have to be a master of both
because it's not just about the tasting
product and the combinations and recipes
it's about the minute molecule recipes
and how this is going to be uh playing
across receptors and across different
body weight sizes and a number of
different metrics that need to be taken
into consideration exactly whey body
mass all that makes a difference as well
as your extraction process I found that
my favorite form of extractions honestly
solventless working with bubble hash
rosin and uh that and that is the more
artisanal so there's like the artisanal
form of extraction and then there's the
scientific form of extraction which
would be with solvents like hydrocarbon
and CO2 and ethanol and whatnot and you
know taking something to distillate form
you know you basically just you know you
you made it tasteless correct so if
you're working at a medical Market
that's great because you know it some
people like it being tasteless and also
you can take the potency up a lot higher
because when you work in the
distillation process you take the
potency up higher whereas I find it to
be more medically beneficial for the
patient to
um to keep it simple and work with work
with the you know the Entourage effect
of the plant work with more full
spectrum broad spectrum work with more
of the cannabinoids that are available
because at the plan in its natural form
works like that it you know it has
compounds that protect it from other
compounds so which can you know if
you're just working most of the industry
unfortunately is focused on high levels
of THC which and you know as there is
great benefits of THC there's also some
possible adverse side effects that you
can feel such as like the couch locks
the paranoia some anxiety
um you know the cheeses of the strains
they they can get up to the high 20s and
low 30s of Delta 9 potency and those are
known to give you like a little bit of
arrhythmia they can you know kind of
cause anxiety so having it paired with a
full spectrum range of like also
balancing the CBD and CBG and CBN and
the terpenes it gives you more of the
effect that like your overall body needs
and I think that's very important and I
think as more education and more science
and more research comes out
um the industry is only going to grow
and get better that's pretty amazing and
when it comes then to let's say the
future of formulations it is the most
advantageous route so let's say we get
Federal legalization European gets
legalization there's going to need to be
ingredient suppliers to this industry
when it comes to the kind of large scale
do you see the most advantageous route
the
let's say molecules via fermentation
combined with other Terrapins combined
with other molecules and these recipes
and formulations being the kind of
especially the medical side of things it
seems to be that's where the most
advantageous route for companies to get
uh patient Pacific medicine right is
going to be in those Avenues exactly
personalized medicine is in those
Avenues and that's where that's in you
know the side of the industry that I am
you know I'm blessed that I've worked
with some of the best cultivators in in
the world uh Kenji fujashima is the head
Master uh Master cultivator for Dr
greenthumbs and uh you know you're you
as the formulator are only as great as
your starting product so if you work
with a great great grower and your
starting project is amazing then you're
ending product on if if you know if you
know if you know if you've mastered your
skill in production and extraction is
going to be even better
um however you can also manipulate and
change things on the manufacturing side
and doing custom formulations with
isolated cannabinoids and make your own
custom formulation in your own full
spectrum that way so it is very much
science but it is as well as you said
art because you're working with nature
and you're working with how God how how
God made the plant you're working with
how it naturally came and personalized
medicine is going to be at utmost
important for on our side because with
us being able to play with those levels
is how we can turn it into a medicine
that is uh that is like Coca-Cola we
turn it into consistency so you know as
you can give a say a Parkinson's patient
a an edible and you do it from one
strain one whole Harvest strain batch
and you put that that oil into that
batch and that stops his tremors well
you know you might have the next Harvest
with the same strain same genetics
however it doesn't have enough lean a
little or is missed a little bit of CBG
it's missing a little bit of the
compounds that is actually what is
stopping those Tremors for that patient
so on our end we are going to be able to
manipulate with science
to make that more of a guarantee that
this medicine works and it works every
time
yeah predictable and reliable products I
think is the aim objective for a global
sized industry absolutely
some form questions now who makes the
best edibles in America
in America oh
not not just myself oh that's hard to
say
um uh there there's a few edible chefs
that I that I know and work with my
friend uh case he's worked with a lot of
a lot of great people I think he has
like over 10 companies that he uh works
with he's based out of Las Vegas
um he his handle on Instagram is call me
case he's he's excellent I probably put
him as my favorite uh besides myself
um also my my junior consultant who is
my Baker that I work with I pull her in
on when I have to do a baking consult
his Amy Robbins she's excellent as well
but I'd have to say my favorite would be
me would be me yeah you could be making
do you maybe want to give everybody an
overview of what you're doing in Puerto
Rico at the moment and who you're
working with down there and kind of what
does the industry look like in Puerto
Rico at the moment oh the industry in
Puerto Rico is medical uh and also they
don't have smoking in the regular
relation so while you can buy the flower
they you buy it too late so smoking is
still considered illegal here so pretty
much everything is in the edible topical
uh or vaping market and uh the company
that I work with right now is rosaretta
this is my latest client and I design
their
um
so and I I do a lot of regional
marketing whenever I enter a new space
so as I said I've built 17 kitchens now
one being in Columbia I've done one in
Costa Rica Canada and uh Arizona Las
Vegas about five in California and when
when I say regional marketing it's uh
you have to go with that cultures taste
buds you know because while I'm in
California and grape and watermelon and
sour apple are the most popular flavors
those flavors don't necessarily work
down here in the Caribbean so I have to
work with you know flavors like uh like
like guava you know so I did like a
guava burst this I designed to be like a
gusher if you're familiar with that or
in Puerto Rico we have like a blue is
what it's more like but I have a guava
burst um I also have uh let me see
parcha which is a passion fruit
and then mangopina which is uh I already
ate that one sorry sorry guys it's too
good but um and then of course like the
sour key lime so I have multiple flavors
there with the biscuits and I have more
flavor launches that I'm that I'm doing
for the summer
um and as well as uh my books so uh
these are these are doing absolutely
well so I actually wrote this book 10
years ago it's the Happy Chef expert
cannabis cookbook and it's in
partnership with uh be real Cypress Hill
my partner Dr Green Thumb himself and it
includes his album in there as a free
download as well as it has a multitude
of recipes uh and as as we were talking
about science I do a breakdown in my
chapter that's called trichomes Terps
and temperatures and I go into heavy
detail on which cannabinoids benefit
which ailments as well as boiling points
and flashy points to kind of help you
master your skill of binding with with
your fats and your oils that you need to
make it a better process and this book
just celebrated its 10-year anniversary
this past April 20th and so I decided to
launch as I live in Puerto Rico and work
down in South America now I decide to
launch the whole series in Spanish so
now I have it offered as La Chef police
at the cannabis so those are doing well
and um and then I have I noticed you had
on my the screen my actually this is my
psychedelic cookbook that I actually
pair uh cannabis with uh psilocybin in
these recipes and it's also this book is
a plant-based recipe book and it also
includes formulations and a lot of cfas
certificates of analysis and testing on
both psilocybin and cannabis so those
are my works that are what I'm doing
down in Puerto Rico uh with my books now
I want my book series now launching in
Spanish and my latest project that I'm
very happy to be working on that will be
launching next year is my husband and I
are launching a the first cannabis
textbook that will be uh supplied to
universities so it's called
manufacturing cannabis the art and the
Cannabis Alchemy
and we're hoping that this and you know
getting it into universities would help
people that have the passion for it to
be able to you know to Matt to to learn
and master and to get a job immediately
in the industry because that's something
I've noticed as a license holder
and a consultant that it's very
difficult to find people that have been
in the industry as long as I have uh
that you know that you're hiring people
with it with the skills uh and and also
the the passion to to do it you know
most people are coming in because they
just really have a passion for the plant
and they're we're kind of having to
teach them how I go but um having
somebody that are that is already has
that knowledge in their brain and having
somebody with a different brain that
that we can all kind of you know Talk
Nerdy to each other that that always
helps when the formulation process so
incredible but it's been amazing talking
to you hopefully we get to touch base
again over the next six to 12 months and
we can get updates on all the exciting
projects and maybe you'll be coming over
to Europe with the son of some
regulation happening over here for
anyone who wants to stay up to date with
d the website is below edibaldi.com
highly recommend following on all social
channels and go visiting the website but
D thank you very much for today thank
you thank you and I can't wait to talk
soon everybody
all right bye guys
[Music]