foreign
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I am delighted to be
joining this episode by Shane McGill
who's the senior industry manager at
Euro monitor International how are you
keeping today Shane hi um how are things
fantastic mate thank you very much for
taking your time to do this for those
who don't know about Euro modern
international they're one of the top
research companies in the world can you
maybe give everybody a quick little
overview of how you came to work with
them and how you dipped your toe into
the Cannabis industry yeah so your
honors uh what we call a strategic
research agency so that means we produce
kind of data on an annual basis and
across range of Industries we're not
like a tactical agency so we don't have
Scan data like a Nielsen Woods uh we're
not doing kind of big consumer tracker
panels Etc but we produce kind of annual
data sets on about 30 different
Industries I was started working for
your manager about a decade ago kind of
fell into it by accident it was uh doing
some legal training
um by background and kind of took a
break from that and ended up starting to
work uh temporarily where what I thought
was temporarily and then I started
working within the tobacco space
um and until about 2016 I was doing that
exclusively looking at the tobacco
industry sort of seeing kind of the
clients we have on the tobacco side
which are a mix of
kind of industry clients so the big
tobacco companies but also some of the
the public health agencies
um governments Etc
um and then in around 2016-17 I started
looking at the Cannabis industry
initially from the perspective of what
impact legalization that space was going
to have on on the tobacco space but I
very kind of quickly realized that you
know the Cannabis industry was something
that was going to be extremely
meaningful across a range of the
industries that we look at Within within
Euro monitor
um and you know a lot of the kind of
structural problems if you want to put
it that way
um that we were seeing in Industries
like tobacco but not language it's
tobacco if you look at things like
alcoholic drinks you know consumer
health
um you know all those kind of those big
monolithic Legacy Industries you know
consumers were disillusioned with what
those industries were producing what
those companies were
um we're delivering you know if you look
at you know to a certain extent tobacco
but but you know you can see it very
clearly I think the alcoholic drinks
industry some of those big alcoholic
drinks producers are really kind of an
exercise in financial engineering as
much as you know kind of delivering to
what consumers really really want and
need and we kind of very quickly
um came to the conclusion that the the
legal cannabis Industries it then was
had a lot of potential to kind of
address a lot of these kind of issues
that consumers had with existing kind of
product offerings across a range of
spaces so we kind of myself and in
particular my equivalent on on the ad
side Spirit smile and drakas kind of
started to developing the the research
we were doing on the Cannabis space
almost in our spare time really
um and started to kind of expand and
unwiden that we began to work with
clients in that space it took a lot of
persuading internally in the company
um but this was something that was kind
of serious that had commercial potential
for us Etc and we've now brought a Ford
kind of from that sort of start and
about 2016 to here where we now have a
kind of fully fledged cannabis database
that sits alongside all of the other
data sets that we have within the
company
I always tell people you know one of the
things that obviously the industry talks
about a lot and that we talk about in
the industry is the idea of normalizing
cannabis but I mean within Euro monetary
cannabis is now and quite proud and
pleased to say fully normalized it sits
alongside all of those other industries
that we research
um and we try to look at the kind of a
space as an industry in its own right
but also through the lands of those
other Industries as well very good for
somebody as big as you guys I'm sure
like cannabis after a little bit of of
niggling with the bosses I know you guys
were set up in the 70s which is a good
while ago that kind of across consumer
package Goods such as across
Pharmaceuticals Cosmetics there's a
number of different disciplines so how
quickly did you guys get into the the
Run of things have been able to create
reports was it a year or two of due
diligence or was it a a information that
is already stacked up in time for the
first report what was kind of the
process of getting the the sector a Euro
monitor off the ground yeah
um I mean the first thing for us that we
really wanted to do was kind of
understand the industry very well I mean
as I said I did a lot of the work with
Spirits as someone who uses cannabis uh
you know me not so much but we were
coming at it from different angles and
we really wanted to understand you know
the industry in terms of the regulation
around the space
um you know what companies that are
currently operating or at that time
we're currently operating in in the
industry what you know what they're set
up like what they do how they produce we
want to supply Finance all of that sort
of stuff so you turn sometimes due
diligence which is basically doing a
research I mean we're a research agency
so that's what you know we were
um we started off doing was just making
sure that we fully understood
um the industry speaking to people that
you know we reached out to all anyone
and everyone that we could find working
in the space who would speak to us
um to get a sense of what the industry
looked like and we went to some of those
early conferences
um that were often and around in London
and so on
um to get a handle on it and then after
about six months or a year or so we
started really writing some of the
briefing work that we were doing and
working more closely with clients and I
think you know as you said what sets us
apart I guess is that we have cannabis
sitting alongside all those other
Industries you know there are a lot of
very good research agencies and data
providers particularly in North America
obviously who are providing very very
granular data from this industry that's
not something we do but what we can do
um is put cannabis in the context of all
of the other kind of consumer verticals
that there are and you know consumers
are neither one thing or another
exclusively Economist consumer is not
just consuming cannabis they're
obviously consuming other areas as well
there's obviously the potential
I think most importantly or most
crucially we feel for phenomenally to
compete with products that are existing
in other areas and kind of win over
consumers who are already consuming
those spaces so we started looking you
know those adjacent Industries
um you know particularly things like
obviously tobacco alcohol consumer
health as well you know packaged Foods
those kind of spaces the soft drinks
industry and bringing all of that into
into the equation as well
yeah I've been looking at this industry
for a couple of years now and kind of
started this off as a data Gathering
exercise to see who was full of [ __ ] who
was into or The Operators who was and
and it seems to me that we're splitting
into the industry North America's got
their whole industry book the way it
looks to me is that Europe is going to
turn into biotech companies and
synthetic cannabinoids are going to
dominate Cosmetics food and beverage uh
Vapes tinctures a number of other
different projects purely because the
molecule is safe it's replicable a
million times over it has to pass the
stringent of rules and it looks now even
with Germany's uh announcement there
last week that I always read that the
social club model was where the wreck
industry was going we were never going
to have these dispensary stores all over
Europe that it seems to be that the
European industry is now splitting into
farm and biotech dominating the
ingredients side of things and then the
Social Clubs giving to the let's say the
activists and the consumers what it is
that they actually want which is right
to grow being able to buy a product at a
specific price and not being price
scheduled do you think the industry in
Europe has gone away I think it is uh I
mean I think certainly on the on the
more if you want to put a therapeutic
side or that kind of CBD in this side I
think that's definitely correct
um you know there's a lot of kind of
precedent for regulation at the EU level
if you look at kind of devices
regulation or medicines regulation
um you know for the the way that might
move
um you know certainly the initial
um kind of Regulation CBD around you
know novel foods and making sure that
there's an Evidence base there and that
there's licensing and so on I think
we'll we'll see more of that
um and in general again Europe is you
know to just broaden it out in general
Europe tends to be more restrictive I
think in terms of the way they they
regulate uh substance consumption and
somewhere like in North America so I
think that's certainly true
um it does seem like in the short term
in the rack side that the the social
club model is is the way it's it's
moving and obviously you know again
there's priests and for that in terms of
what's happening in Spain
um there are social clubs and some of
the other European markets already I do
you know somewhat Wonder ultimately
whether that's going to
um
you know kind of expand the industry in
the way that that that perhaps uh the
industry itself would want perhaps even
the way governments would want in terms
of you know being able to deliver an
excise Revenue base and all that sort of
stuff and and really develop an industry
that employs uh significant numbers of
people and so on so I'm slightly
I'm still slightly hesitant uh in terms
of the not not in terms of the social
club model itself I think as you say
that's obviously something that will
deliver to Consumers what they want you
know the the flower at the right price
and so on and strip away a lot of what I
guess you could describe as the nonsense
that goes on in North America
um but I do think there's a you know
there's a cost of the social club model
in terms of
where do you really get that investment
that maybe is needed in the industry to
develop things like format
innovation technology
um you know to develop kind of Brands
Etc that are going to bring consumers
who aren't already engaged in the in the
Legacy Industries into the space
um so it may be you know as looks like
it's going to happen in Germany maybe
that the first wave of of legalization
the rack side in Europe will be oriented
around the social club but I I do think
ultimately it may well go further than
that
um just because there there's a short
coming there in terms of of Industry
development I think
do you think the retail model in Europe
will be dominated by the North American
brands like cookies I've already seen
some transactions where people have
acquired the rights to cookie stores in
Europe already yeah do you that's going
to be the case just with the they've got
a decade of experience they'll have the
retail know-how or do you see that there
is going to be capital in the European
markets and there is going to be Brands
and let's say retail stores as big in
Europe as they are in North America and
we end up exporting over to North
America with some of the brands we
create
I I mean I I do think that there will be
North American brands that have the
potential to penetrate in Europe whether
it's going to be cookie specifically
um you know I don't know I think
obviously there's
that there there's some kind of first
move or Advantage there in terms of
brand equity and name recognition all
that sort of thing I know that for
example in the
in the medical cannabis Market in
Germany there's there's you know
patients that that are looking at
cookies and and there's already a
certain Equity there but uh you know I
think if you look at again for example
the an adjacent market like the alcohol
Market or the tobacco market there's a
number of local Brands within the
European space that there has been you
know over a number of years and
particularly if you if you think about
that sort of smaller scale Social Club
model I think that implies really more
local
um more indigenous Brands and at least
initially within the space and I think
again look at Berlin which is likely to
be you know whether there's full
legalization Germany or whether it goes
to some kind of regional pilot or or a
combination of that and Social Club
you can really imagine the kind of I
guess unique culture of of Berlin you
know developing some strong and
interesting local cannabis Brands
um out of that and again they look at
something like Frisco or whatever you
know one of the only colors in Europe
that has strong Equity that competes
with a with a big Global North American
brand coming out of Germany I think
there will be those types of of brands
in the Cannabis space in Europe so I
don't think it's going to be all North
American brands and I think you know if
I was someone who was looking at
licensing over a North American brand
right now to enter into a European
environment that we don't know what
that's actually going to look like I
think I would be probably thinking twice
about that to be quite honest
another one of the questions I want to
ask you you're based in the UK and I
have a lot of experience over there what
are the things I started to see a lot of
is the the media entities and let's say
some of the companies in the UK they
some they still seem to seem that
they're part of Europe and that the
trading between the UK and Europe and
the Cannabis industry is going to be
fine I own another company that trades
with the UK and it's the biggest [ __ ]
show I've ever dealt with since brexit
came in the Pack's getting added do you
see the UK cannabis companies being at a
disadvantage to the to the main European
entities in France and Germany and and
Spain and countries like that yeah I
think that potentially will will become
more of an issue over time I mean
obviously there isn't you know there
isn't a huge industry right now
obviously there's there's a certain
infrastructure around the Legacy space
but there isn't a huge industry right
now so maybe it's not as apparent as it
will become but I think that's certainly
the case I mean obviously traditionally
or over the last number of years I think
the UK industry has grown up as much
around
um you know while there is sort of
strong consumption of CBD and so on in
the UK Market I think the industry there
has grown up around the fact that
there's some of the capital is based in
London and and some of that is happening
in that space and industries have grown
up around that so I think they haven't
really tested that trade flow between
the UK and Europe and I think you're
right you'll find that over time you
know as that infrastructure develops
that if you want to call it isolation
will be will become kind of more
pronounced in the Cannabis space and
again there are strong
European companies increasing in the
space obviously we we notice on the
market companies that are in Germany um
you know the likes of sanity and so on
you know there's a strong for example
again in Spain and I just came back from
ICBC in Savannah as you can see like a
strong kind of industry beginning to
develop in Spain you know there are
um you know there are there are seed
companies there for example that are
amongst the biggest Employers in in the
locations in which they're based and so
on so I you know I don't think the
European industry is going to be waiting
for UK companies to come across and
and deliver to them I think there'll be
plenty of of European mainland-based
companies that will be able to do that
for themselves yeah yeah and I'd be
remiss if I didn't ask about Ireland
before we go we had a cannabis summer in
the RDS there like six weeks ago sold a
great event and it was pitched as Dublin
is going to be the the debate for Europe
for any North American company that if
you're doing cultivating in Portugal or
extraction Romania whatever it may be
that Dublin should be the main base of
Europe do you see Ireland being one of
the like biggest winners of let's say a
European cannabis industry because the
North American companies are coming here
they all seem to be geared up for it and
why would they move into a non-english
speaking territory that has a couple of
disadvantages why wouldn't they follow
the remit that Mark Zuckerberg and Tim
Cook and the CEO of Pfizer of all doing
it and setup base here do you see us
being one of the big winners of this
yeah I think that there's certainly an
argument for that and obviously there's
a there's underlying fundamentals there
that you've just kind of adverted to in
terms of what makes Ireland attractive
for any kind of company it's that um you
know time zone
language it's the tax as well we should
we'd be remiss if we didn't mention that
it's the levels of Education you know
the sort of Labor Force that's there Etc
so I don't think the Cannabis industry
is any different to that and
particularly when you talk about you
know the European market likely to be
one that is focused around biotech and
all of that kind of
um aspect of it I think that there's
certainly a strong argument for that
obviously I think you know obviously the
the drug policy or the Cannabis policy
that's in place there probably feeds
into it as well I'm interested to see
now what's going to happen with the kind
of citizens assembly I think you know
there seems to me to be you know again
coming out of uh coming out of a
historical background where obviously
you wouldn't have put Ireland as a big
candidate for for liberalization in
terms of cannabis policy I think there's
something interesting Brewing there
um you know if you look at public
perception around around what we should
be doing in the space I think that you
know there could be movements as well
from a policy point of view that
actually just enhances that overall kind
of business proposition as well so I you
know I certainly think that that's
that's an element here and that Ireland
uh probably could be an oversized player
in the European industry as well I mean
it already is to some extent you don't
have to look far for an Irish face in
the European cannabis industry so
there's there's plenty of you know
there's plenty of ours presence as it is
and I think some of that's gonna gonna
reflect are going to come back in terms
of you know actual physical presence of
companies in in in in Ireland
yeah I couldn't agree with you more
we've reached over our time I could
actually tell it to you for another hour
on this topic Shane has been very
informative hopefully we can get to have
a party to this conversation in a couple
of months time and hopefully the
citizens assembly over here have taken a
couple of steps forward yeah we can
speak after that it's been a pleasure
thanks very much Alan thank you very
much Shane until next episode everybody
[Music]