[Music]
welcome everybody to latest episode
cannabis is new i am delighted to be
joined on the second episode by jacob
sons he's the co-founder of can sativa
over in germany through a medical
cannabis company who are leading the way
in the european market how are you
keeping jacob
i'm going to thank you very much and uh
very happy to be here
delighted to have you on the show i know
you and your brother are kicking ass
with cancer tv in germany at the moment
are one of the biggest companies in the
main prominent guys in europe can you
maybe give everybody an overview on the
first topic where the can sativa story
how you guys set up and how long you
guys have been in the industry
yes so the canzativa story is uh first
of all a story about two brothers so
my brother benedict and me we founded
the company in 2017
right before
there was a significant change in law
liberalizing the cannabis market for
medical use
so this was one of the main turning
points
in the the german legal ecosystem and
this was right the beginning when
benedict and me
decided at a
family reunion at a party that we want
to engage in this market and yeah the
the company was set up uh quite quickly
um like overnight
and together with our father who's a
co-founder not an active member of the
management but still a co-founder
we elaborated
quite intense on what is the business
case this was mainly a part of
my brother who's a
business engineer
and i worked on the regulatory framework
so i have a background in law
and uh since then uh now since four
years i'm only focusing on the overall
regulation of cannabis as a controlled
substance
but both uh in the pharmaceutical and um
the um emerging recreational or to be
recreational market in germany and
europe
and uh over the the the first few months
and the first year uh 2017 and early
we built up the business rented our
first offices we did everything on our
own from cleaning the restrooms to doing
all the packaging stuff
this was like a two-man show at this
time and in early 2018 still one of the
early movers we started our distribution
in may um 2018 the first additional
cannabis products that we imported from
the netherlands
yeah were shipped to two pharmacies and
this was the point in time
in the beginning of 2018 that we decided
uh to start a fundraise um and yeah have
the the first few people join the
company and this is clearly the story of
uh 2017 and 2018 um and the end of 2018
we had our seed financing round uh which
yeah somehow uh brought the business uh
into yeah a very fast-growing um vc
funded startup company and i mean this
is like the the first uh one and a half
years of cansativa
okay yeah so like when everybody when
you set up a company you get their your
roll up your sleeves for the first
couple of years and if everything goes
according to plan then you can start
utilizing investors money one thing i'm
curious about how did you guys uh go
about getting your products in
pharmacies did you bring on
pharmaceutical sales staff or is there a
main
let's say holding company for a number
of pharmacies around germany where it
goes directly to that company and
acquire let's say 100 different
pharmacies with your products
so first of all it's important to
understand how the pharmacy ecosystem in
germany works so
pharmacies are operated by individual
pharmacists so it is only allowed to
operate up to four pharmacies um that's
why
there is no
huge pharmacy network or some kind of a
corporate uh entity that that you could
um yeah like like lobby to source
products from you so it is a individual
business that is quite intense in terms
of building relationships and building
trust
but at this time
cannabis was a very young and new market
so we could
be or we challenged the market being
best in service best in
delivery times we were not that much
into best price at this time
because we decided to build our
relationship by by customer service and
getting into a real relationship with
the individual pharmacists and what is
important is that
there are some very big full-line
wholesalers
that serve pharmacies up to three or
four times a day
so this is the route of
general pharmaceuticals towards
pharmacies
this is a kind of a close shop um you
don't really manage to get into this
niche uh just being a pharmaceutical uh
yeah wholesaler so we decided um to um
focus uh only on direct sales to
pharmacies in this special portfolio of
medicinal cannabis flowers
and if you
manage to to meet the expectations in
terms of delivery time communications
sales channels and so on at this time it
was quite easy to get into touch with
the pharmacies because they were
desperately looking for cannabis
suppliers
we see
like in the last few years a significant
change so
today it is very hard to get into touch
with the pharmacies because there are
i think 80 importers that always want to
sell just for example one product source
from the netherlands
but the pharmacies today are quite
annoyed uh they don't want to get
addressed by the 1880s or 19
importer that only wants to sell
bettercom but they want to have a single
point of contact and we developed
over time from someone who had a product
they were desperately looking for in the
beginning
towards a one-stop shop that now is
offering everything that the pharmacy
needs
and this is a transition phase where we
profited a lot from being an early mover
at this time
okay amazing that kind of leads me on to
the next topic i want to talk about and
it's the european opportunity we can
obviously anybody would have been a
sense who knows the industry it's got to
be medical for the first couple of years
but we see the the rumorings of a
recreational market happen in germany
with the recent elections there how do
you see the european uh european
opportunity do you think recreational is
going to be here within five years and
if it does happen in germany do you
think that's going to open the
floodgates for the rest of europe
uh yes so first of all i see um as he
outlined a european opportunity so we
have a harmonized european
economic zone or economic market
and that's why we see more or less in
whole europe those two dimensions the
first dimension is medical or
pharmaceutical use the other dimension
is
in the broader sense recreational use
what do we differentiate in those
segments first medical and
pharmaceutical is what we see
in germany especially as one of the
leading roles especially because we have
a cost reimbursement system
this always is a driver for for
innovation in in those
sectors or those
yeah pharmaceuticals if there's no cost
reimbursement it is always hard to bring
products in so this is why germany is
most important in the medical sphere
right now
but we
see that other jurisdictions are
important as well so especially if you
look at the production
it might be portugal or spain or
denmark which is the place to go to have
your products of pharmaceuticals grown
in a high quality
um this uh i think is in the medical
ecosystem something that is currently
developing over um different countries
in europe there is the the
the first trials in france um there are
experiments uh in other jurisdictions as
well um so in the first dimension
medical i think there is a ongoing and
and continuing development towards a
more liberalized approach over europe
towards cannabis as a pharmaceutical
substance as a medicinal product what we
see in the second dimension is clearly
recreational in the broader sense as i
said because
we observed that in whole germany we
have in three different segments the
development first is hemp especially
fiber
clothing foodstuff
we see uh the development of novel food
so there will be a decision on the novel
food status of cbd and this will be only
the beginning of a roaring and bursting
market because there is a significant
demand for cbd products even though they
are now still in the gray or black
market um so this will be the second
part this will be a holistic development
in europe that we observe and the second
or the the third
is anything relating to
thc containing products and i think
there will germany definitely be again a
leader
i would assume that if our so-called
traffic light coalition
will get
to operations and if they constitute the
government over the next few weeks
it will be quite obvious that over the
next two or three years we have
legal thc
containing cannabis in germany and this
will again be a leading role model for
europe because it will show proof that
this system works with view to uh drug
addiction policy with view to uh
protection
of miners and so on
okay kind of leads me into it the next
topic that i want to talk about is
european imports versus european
homegrown you mentioned that the place
to kind of grow with your uh your
product at the moment will be portugal
denmark denmark have the ornamental
flower industry portugal has a great
climate do you see there being a nuanced
difference between
the the warmer climates in europe grown
it and then the specialized farming
countries growing it because let's say
somebody like ireland where where i'm
from we have one of the best some of the
best farming community in the world
never mind just from europe and
the way i see it happen when the when
the regulations fall down you're going
to have the ability for each nuanced
country to have their own individual
strain with their own individual
benefits
do you see that happening or do you see
the imports from low-cost territories
like south america and africa imported
into malta place like that crate turned
into products which do you see being the
future for the european industry
um i think it always uh depends uh so as
the the whole industry is getting a bit
more liberal first in the medical
ecosystem than in the recreational
ecosystem it's uh we will see that there
is a product differentiation so it will
begin that pricing is something which is
very important to get access for the
mass market so i think for the the
low-cost products there will be a
significant need um for yeah competitive
cultivation in latin america for example
in southern africa because um you cannot
really compete with the labor cost
applied to those products there but on
the other hand especially in the
recreational ecosystem
it is more about the right brand the
right strain right product claim and
product quality and still today in the
medical ecosystem patients are very
aware of where is the product coming
from
they are very aware of is the product
for example treated with irradiation or
not so those are always topics that are
important and
the the difference between
non-eu cultivation and eo cultivation
might always be a difference between is
it indoor or auto so
producing a low-cost product is
then a huge advantage
if you are not only cultivating in an uh
climate that is that that is good for
the product not only cultivating in a
area where labor cost is is is low but
it's always about
do you need
all those extensive investments in
the greenhouses
that are closed and so on so we we see a
competitive advantage here for those
that cultivate
in in areas that have a better climate
than for example germany
if you take germany as the domestic
grown cannabis um it is still ridiculous
that that cannabis plants have to be
grown um not only uh without sunlight
but
in a safe room and this this this can't
be uh something that is here uh a
benefit uh for for the um yeah for
domestically grown cannabis um so i
would uh consider that um especially in
the recreational industry there will be
a product
need or there will be a demand for
product that that have a specific
terroir
that is more important about where is it
coming from how is the product be
made um because it is more about uh
having a product that that that is like
in the wine industry um has a a a origin
a signature uh which is not only
pertaining to a strain or genetic but
always to the origin in terms of what is
the the to
what is the the climate zone it has been
grown in and i think this will be a
story that is that is working uh when
building brands better than uh when
building a pharmaceutical product
because their product quality
standardization is more important and
this is always easier in a controlled
ecosystem controlled greenhouses where
you can control all those parameters
from
light
to water to nutrition and so on
yeah i think the medical industry are
going to be able to get that product
perfect with the amount of capital and
investment in research and development
whereas the recreational brands are
going to be the story as you said the
carbon footprint a number of different
variables that the consumer will go for
it's been an absolute pleasure talking
to you jacob i could talk to you all day
about the european cannabis industry but
i know you're a busy man and we have the
15-minute time limit anybody wants to
check out cancer tv at the website link
is below highly recommend you checking
them out hopefully we can get to talk
again in the future jacob
thank you very much it's been a pleasure
thank you very much everybody for
watching and we'll see you on the next
episode