[Music]
welcome to another episode of the
cannabis review
i am delighted to be joined in this show
by jonas simer manana how are you
keeping today
i'm good thanks how are you i'm
fantastic thank you very much so you've
been
in the news a lot over the last week or
two can you kind of give everybody a
little overview of how you got to
co-founding tech for can and your
journey in the cannabis industry
sure so i'm actually originally canadian
but i've been living in israel for over
30 years my entire career has been in
the israeli
tech ecosystem so i worked for a couple
of high-tech companies
then i ran my own agency
doing strategic marketing for israeli
tech companies i ran that for 12 years
then i got into the medical cannabis
space honestly because i was just
looking for
something interesting and you know this
was 2017 2018
and the canvas industry was everywhere
and booming so i opened a business
development company with a partner in
canada
and we were bringing over israeli
cannabis technologies to the canadian
market so we would do their
commercialization strategies
you know make sure they were able to
overcome any regulatory hurdles
and when they were ready we would
introduce them to either investors or
licensed producers or extraction
companies for
either raising capital or joint ventures
licensing agreements etc
um and then corona hit
and essentially what we're doing now is
we're setting up
europe's first medical cannabis tech
accelerator
it's headquartered and funded uh by
malta enterprise which is like the
innovation authority of the maltese
government
and we're looking to support early stage
entrepreneurs
in the cannabis industry we're talking
about ip-based technologies that
actually
solve a need in the industry
so we're not looking at brands and as i
said it's very early stage companies
so we're really looking to support them
and help them build their company
so that they can access the tremendous
you know european
market we're talking specifically about
medical cannabis
not recreational or adult use um and
like i said we're looking specifically
at
intellectual property um and companies
that have something
unique um to the industry
okay that kind of brings me on to the
first topic of conversation is
what is check for can you know you
answered a good bit of it there is there
a
is this a short medium or long term
strategy how hard was it to get the
maltese enterprise
government on board yeah so i mean the
way we saw it
is that you know 2017 2018 2019 there
was this huge
boom in the cannabis industry but all
the investment money was going to
cultivation
um and we understand that in order for
this to be uh you know
continuing to be a long-term growing
dynamic industry we have to
we have to make sure that we're
providing products and and
processes and solutions that are safe
and they're cost effective
and they're clinically validated and
they're sustainable
ultimately to that we're bringing
products to more patients
and educating both patients and
physicians that they can benefit from
these this amazing plant
um really what we're seeing is that you
know the barriers of entry
for the cannabis industry to biotech to
large pharma to the high-tech sectors
those are challenges
that we need to overcome so whether
that's
you know producing stable products at
scale or reducing operational costs
um validating biopharmaceutical products
for
specific indications digital health
solutions
across the board there is room for
improvement for the industry and that is
what tech for can is doing
so essentially what we're doing is we
are it's a short-term program it's 12
weeks
it's a 12-week cohort that during that
cohort
the companies get funding they get a
mentorship program and a curriculum
commercial services provided by leading
financial bodies
so that will help them with any legal
questions marketing financial
contractions
regulatory issues that they may have
but the real kicker here and what makes
it special and different than any other
accelerator
is that entrepreneurs who join us get to
do a validation pilot or a feasibility
study or a proof of concept
in an eu gmp licensed facility so
they're already able within the three
months of the cohort to move forward
either with proof of concept or
commercialization milestones so
essentially the
the startup just by joining the cohort
just by completing the cohort
essentially increases their valuation
and at the end of the cohort they
we we will write up like a poc report
for our investors
and then investors can then uh continue
in in ongoing rounds directly to the
startups
um so we're really i mean we use the
word accelerator and not incubator
because
it's it's short and intensive with
concrete steps to bringing these
products to market
um and then and because they're already
partnering with a licensed producer
that's eugmp that's a potential partner
or customer
so at the end of the cohort they may
even be at a position where they're
ready for a joint venture
um and obviously we chose malta
not only because of its access to
mainland europe but it already has eugmp
certified production which we don't
really have in israel
um the country had the government has
declared
that they want to be the medical
cannabis capital of europe they've
invested 110 million euro in a
designated industrial area
um they have a lot of leading canadian
companies
um are setting up in malta setting up
operations in multi in order to access
mainland europe so those are our natural
partners
and finally the whole situation with
kovid i mean
you know in israel we're 60 vaccinated
we can travel malta is a small island
that hasn't been hit hard by covid
so the expectation is that we'll be able
to have in-person cohorts
um although you know some entrepreneurs
will choose to do the curriculum
virtually that's fine but they're
guaranteed a spot
to do the pilot in the eu gmp facility
okay amazing lots of exciting things
happening in malta at the moment we were
talking to the guys
material ventures as well so i kind of
see that
malta and ireland vote with the kind of
beneficial tax rate
are going to be the kind of two dominant
spaces kind of pivoting towards
servicing the medical cannabis industry
and then further down the road the
recreational industry because
that will follow at some stage sooner or
later so
yeah it's an interesting space to be the
next topic i wanted to talk to you about
is there's
a lot of startups coming into the
industry now at the moment
everybody's looking to raise capital a
lot of the institutional investors won't
be touching it as of yet until
all the eyes are dotted and the t's are
crossed if you would set up a cannabis
startup anywhere in the world what city
would you pick
wow um
it's a good question what city would i
pick i would
um it really depends what you're doing i
think
i'll tell you what our chat the
challenges that we found um
we found that there's a lot of money in
europe right now
um people aren't looking for the early
stage
startups though so you know most
startups need you know two hundred
thousand dollars two hundred and fifty
thousand 000
in order to make their next step and
most of the investors are looking for
much larger tickets which is why the
accelerator is a good
is a good place because the
entrepreneurs get the funding that they
need but the investors are essentially
investing in this this platform this
portfolio
diversified portfolio that we're
offering them um
i would say that what we've found is
that
in the us there is huge money but a lot
of it is going to brands
um which is not what we're interested in
they're not
looking yet at the early stage
technologies um
and so there just seems to be a lot of
money
in europe right now um for the cannabis
industry and you're right that the
institutional investors are being very
careful and very wary but it's coming
it's happening
so i would say that if you're in the
real medici
medical cannabis europe's your place if
you're looking for
recreational or adult use
then yeah you're probably better off
with north american investors
do you tell me do you see a case of
where the growers and farmers in europe
are end up producing
let's say we go 10 years down the line
wreck is is illegal in europe as well as
it is in north america
do you see europe having the the more
superior let's say
brands and growers like they do with
wine or champagne or
a number of different products like
shufflers or do you see south america
then
i mean the low cost alternative that
pumps into north america
because it's all about margins and
profits at the end of the day so
yeah i think looking 10 years down the
line that's what we're looking at
so you know high quality pharmaceutical
grade cannabis will
come from whether it's south america or
africa um i absolutely see that
happening but it's
it's gonna take a while um and also some
countries you know let's say germany
or whatever are only going to allow
homegrown locally home locally grown
cannabis production so
i think ultimately it's uh it's a
decision about money and taxes
you know as long as it's worth their
while to cultivate in
france or germany or whatever then great
but once we have these
more sophisticated products and
we've a we're able to have plant
stability at scale
um then it will go commodity i believe
i mean some countries will probably keep
their own growth for like
um
really really high-end products
um but yeah
[Music]
you could have it just like liquor
you could have it like liquor whereas
again the bottle of vodka over in europe
is 80 euro
and it did you've got a similar kind of
cheaper bottle on sale in different
parts of the world so
hopefully the the premium growers and
the guys with the real knowledge of the
plant end of being the ones who
can profit from the european industry
the last thing i want to talk to you
about was
israel had become a world leader in the
r d side of medical cannabis
what were the steps that got them there
was it professor
raphael or was it a couple of other
steps do you think
yeah so israel is an interesting story i
mean we've been doing research on
medical cannabis longer than anyone else
like you said
rafael mushulum has been doing this
since like the 1960s
he's the one who isolated thc um and
he's
now 90 something years old and he still
goes to his lab and he still does work
and he's still doing research
and all the universities in israel have
um
uh like cannabis curriculums now
um and so in terms of israel look israel
made the desert bloom
for many many we we are the startup
nation specifically
in act and and other relevant
technologies
um cannabis is no different where
israel i think missed its opportunity
israel hasn't had a short opportunity
to be a leading supplier of
high quality cannabis you know we've got
350 days of sunshine a year
we've got the technology we've grown
tomatoes in the desert
and companies are now applying that to
cannabis the problem is that due to
regulatory concerns we can know we can't
expert
so ironically israel is might be growing
the best cannabis and might be having
the best technologies but we're also
right now the largest importer in the
world
because for regulatory reasons we can't
export yet now that's
that's that is happening um
and you know we've had four elections
over two years so we're looking for gov
for for political stability and then
being able to provide for the local
market and then companies will be able
to export
having said that all the largest
cannabis producers do already have
off-take agreements
to europe and north america they're just
waiting for the sort of stamp of
approval
where i do see that israel has a
tremendous opportunity is in the
uh technology sector like i said with
the start-up nation
a lot of people are applying their
incredible
knowledge and innovative spirit to the
cannabis industry
i think there's a lot to look at here a
lot of spin-offs from existing actech
technologies for the cannabis market um
and it's it's exciting it's very
exciting what's going on here i will say
however
that you know in the past weeks since
we've just we just issued a press
release on
tech for cat once and we've received
submissions from entrepreneurs around
the world from india from
africa from portugal from germany from i
mean
really incredible stuff that's going on
and these are
you know young entrepreneurs who have
their startups who are looking to get
into it
but they also have expertise that um
that will you know help us achieve
exactly what we were talking about in
terms of the stability and the safety
and
and the the wide access to this amazing
plan
yeah i couldn't agree tomorrow i think
there's a lot of entrepreneurs out there
who are going to either leave
engineering or leave architecture who've
got business ideas in their mind and
just waiting for the capital to be able
to grow their ideas so
it's been an absolute pleasure to talk
to young if anybody wants to check out
tech for can the website's down below
like highly tech eu i'm sorry to
to correct you
yeah so there's a tech4can.com website
so maybe sorry the apologies on that
mm-hmm eu is is it's fine it's just a
it's the portfolio company of my
business partner um
it's separate than the accelerator so
the accelerator is techfurcaneeurope.com
or tech4kaneu.com you there's that's the
website
okay perfect and
yeah thank you very much for coming on
the show it's much appreciated yeah
thank you for having me
okay everybody have a great day and
we'll catch on the next show
[Music]
bye-bye