foreign
to the next episode of the Cannabis
review I'm delighted to be joined with
this episode by Tom Zuber who's the
founder and managing partner at Zuber
Lawler how are you keeping today tell me
Well very good Owen great to see you uh
delighted to have you on made you're a
renowned attorney in a number of
different spaces so I'm delighted to get
to talk to you and hopefully get some
solid information out of you can you
maybe give everybody just a quick
overview of how Zuber Lawler and
yourself ended up stepping into the
Cannabis industry and the timeline and
that
sure well thanks to God we were in the
right place at the right time uh I'm
based in Los Angeles California and
super Lawler has offices across the
country
um but cannabis in one sense was born in
America legalized cannabis here in
California is the first state to
legalize at the medicinal level uh back
in the 1990s so we got into cannabis uh
this is ancient history now way back in
2006 that was to our knowledge before
any corporate law firms per se had
really entered the space and so there
were defense attorneys that started
doing contracts and Licensing but we
started getting asked to do things like
the the first
real external Rays uh the partnership
dispute IP issues uh the the heavier
regulatory issues they said well uh we'd
like a corporate law firm to do this and
would you guys help uh so I had a buddy
uh my first client was actually uh it
was a buddy uh who uh I had known uh
just uh uh uh about here in Southern
California he started a company I'll
give him a shout out my buddy Kenny
Morrison with the Venice Cookie Company
still a dear friend of mine and still a
client uh so he he said hey uh Tom can
you guys help out here we're uh about to
do this and that uh and that was back in
2006 uh we quickly became very popular
um So within five six seven years uh
thanks to God we had a long list of
clients it had to be the or one of the
longest list of cannabis clients in the
country at that point and we hadn't gone
after a single client that's literally
true we were just getting phone calls
and emails as a function of being I
guess you could say the corporate law
firm it that was embracing the subject
matter at point we realized that
cannabis was going to be his biggest
Pharma and we do work in the Pharma
industry uh and in other Industries so
we said we're all in uh at this point uh
we do as much cannabis work as any law
firm in the country uh and uh of course
we have um I want as you've noted we've
uh we we've really gotten around here uh
we represent many of the the bigger
players in the industry in respect of
our high stakes Acquisitions and finance
and IP and Regulatory and litigation
matters the international work which is
increasingly coming up uh and and that
conversation is is something we'll we'll
have on this on the zoom uh and and also
we've gotten involved I could I guess
you could say in the ecosystem we found
a global go which became a premier
cannabis consultancy we didn't really
see something like that so we decided we
needed a friend like that so we got
involved in starting one up they've now
achieved that team uh has achieved over
250 cannabis licenses I believe
throughout the world uh and and with uh
with an incredible uh success rate we're
involved in the launching of okay it was
times which is now a successful magazine
I just released their fourth issue uh
and and things like that so I guess you
could say in addition to serving the
legal industry as lawyers we're also
fans of the subject matter and we
believe I really believe in in his
potential um as human beings we believe
in this potential to lift The Human
Condition throughout the world so we're
all in uh both in terms of heart and
mind uh and and it's pleasure to be here
incredible so you're going to be
probably the perfect person who's seen
there and been there and done that and
seen all the different facets of the
industry to be able to talk about the
couple of topics I want to bring up so
the first one is globalization of
cannabis and I wanted more ask I want to
ask the question is is Europe actually
going to end up being the perfect
destination via the capital that's
already going to be ready available in
North America that'll want new markets
to expand to on investors in capital
that are already based in Europe who
will see this new Emerging Market as
something intriguing with their with
good returns is Europe going to be maybe
the center of the Cannabis industry in
10 years time or is that fanciful
thinking
well I don't think it's vegetable
thinking I don't know if I think about
it in terms of central I think it's
going to be that things are going to be
disproportionately weighted uh in the
direction of Europe uh and that that
notion of things is going to increase as
time goes on you've got an awful lot of
people there uh on the European content
with a similar standard of living and uh
so so there's just just that statement
alone you've got you've got nearly twice
as many people as we have right with the
same standard we're going to go over
there so that that that's huge uh but
also I think there are some things going
for Europe that we didn't have going for
us here in the United States and Canada
uh one of those things for example is
the example of the United States and
Canada so you get to learn from all our
mistakes so there's that um but also I I
think that there's an assuredness that
this is going to happen right here in
the United States
um there was sort of disbelief even up
until 10 years ago is this really
happening is cannabis I think Europe has
seen okay this really is going to happen
and you get to look at the United States
to see that that that that that's
probably the case for furthermore I
think that Europe is going to have an
easier time uh collaborating between
jurisdictions right here in the U.S you
can't put THC in in the trunk of your
car and drive it across the state line
from California to Nevada right you'll
get arrested uh by federal agents uh but
in Europe
um you do have the potential to move
cannabis THC across state lines and and
that's powerful that is really powerful
so yeah I think that that increasingly
the weight of the conversation is going
to move toward Europe and it's a
function of the sheer size coupled with
the the the purchasing power per per
resident uh and also I I think an
ability to move things across borders
and then finally the fact that you've
got the lesson of the United States the
mistakes we made and some of the things
made that we did well uh the United
States and Canada you get to leverage
that I think to move quicker than we did
so I think things are going to develop I
can also tell you uh just as far as it
totally we are talking about Europe over
here in the United States it's an
exceeding exceedingly great place
exciting place to focus on right now and
and it it is in terms of investment it's
in terms of how do we get product there
uh and and that that's a very exciting
conversation
yeah I think Europe's got that beautiful
relationship to whether you're going
into the consumer Focus side of things
there's a heavy consumer Pace already
here but if you decide to go to the
biosynthesis route and create your own
Blends and formulations and apis Europe
already has the infrastructure and the
industry know-how here and I think
that's a the two-pronged attack will end
up coming from Europe from the get-go
yes yeah
um there are a lot of I think oh and it
one we're here from our remote
perspective in the United States uh when
we look at Europe we're trying to say
okay how is this going to play out how
is this going to work out what's what's
what's the Cannabis industry going to
look like that the international
candidates Industries exists on the
European continent what's that going to
look like in in three years and in five
years into 10 years and and that's a fun
thing to think about
um one of the the challenges here for
instance in Germany is uh it's it's it's
accepted pretty broadly that Germany is
not going to be able to produce enough
to meet its demand there in Germany
right and so immediately from the get-go
you've got an interesting uh situation
there that really you you don't have
here in the United States where you say
Okay California doesn't have enough uh
one week we've got plenty of of product
now but two even if we didn't there's no
option to drive in that THC from
neighboring states you can't do that
right but in Europe that is possible so
it just goes to show that while there
are going to be a lot of parallels
between how things developed over here
on our side of the neighborhood and how
they develop over there oh and on your
side of the neighborhood I I think that
there's there's a lot of exciting uh
differences too uh and one of those
differences is that Germany can now plug
um its capacity needs by importing THC
so that that really is uh that really is
I think a phenomenal difference uh and
and it's those sorts of things I think
that we're so excited about here in the
United States when we look at Europe
yeah very much so and even with the
movings and happenings happening the
Czech Republic at the moment I think
you'll have these connected countries
that end up facilitating commerce
between each other and allows for Europe
to grow and a lot smoother and quicker
way than let's say North America because
UConn's kind of broke the barriers we'll
get to learn from all of the the
examples that have been set before us
very much so yes exactly and and that
that really is the the trick right is to
try and it's great to learn from your
own mistakes but you'd rather learn from
the mistakes of others that's even
better right that's free I guess in a
sense free learning
um
by looking at some of the things that
we've done wrong and you know I I will
just as long as I'm here because we do
care about our friends over there in
Europe I would take a good hard look at
some of the troubles we're having here
you know resist the the temptation just
to tax everything as much as possible
because it is self-destructive even from
the tax Authority standpoints because
you're going to kill you know the the
body that's that that that that that
lifts the hand that feeds it just
doesn't make any sense here you've got
to allow the industry to grow and and
people are getting crushed and I don't
know if this is a well-known fact in
Europe but here in California there are
over 250 million dollars and this is
tragic over 250 million dollars of taxes
are owed by California cannabis
companies I'll say that again over 250
million dollars of taxes or over by
cannabis companies here in California
now that that is really that that's
that's a depressing statistic isn't it
because that means that the burden here
that that has been placed on California
cannabis companies is really quite
extreme right and and those pressures
come from a number of areas one is is
taxation the taxation I think is is
really uh it really is is
counterproductive in many regards in
terms of the size of it in terms of the
the flippancy of the of the of the
taxation scheme
um but also uh the illicit markets here
it makes it very tough to compete the
illicit markets don't have to pay their
taxes and they don't have to pay for
compliance uh in in the same way that
that that licensed companies do and so
how do you how do you compete on price
with an illicit shop that's that's down
the street so the lack of enforcement
against those illicitors products that's
something else that I would look for
there you really want to enable your
legalized industry to thrive more than
it can if the illicit industry is
thriving at lower price points right so
that that that is a another important
thing that I would take away from from
the conversation here in the US yeah for
sure I think anybody in Europe if you're
not studying the taxation models of the
various States and understanding where
the economic went right and went wrong
and you're doing yourself a disservice
to the country you're working in because
we should be accumulating as much
knowledge and data as we can to be able
to facilitate creating the best
Industries within each individual
territory that's over here in Ireland in
Europe I wanted to move on to the final
topic Before I Let You Go I know you're
a busy man and it's facilitating
commerce between territories in a
nutshell a safe Banking Act going to
basically be the cure to all ailments or
is it going to be more complicated than
that
oh man I mean that's
now you're you know uh
it's
we we've had that dangled in front of us
for so long here it's
um it's just the thing that's coming it
never arrives right so like prohibition
itself behind that I do have a feeling
and this yeah I I this makes me naive uh
I do have I do have a notion that that
we'll see safe banking uh sometime
within the next the next few years I do
and I think it may happen sooner than
that
um but um I I don't think we're um I
don't think we'll see Prohibition end
um uh anytime soon
um but I do think we'll see safe banking
why do I think that
there are it really is as much as it's
seen as a partisan issue here and I
think in some respects you'll find
evidence for that to a degree
um but it you'll also find evidence that
that in many ways it's bipartisan there
are folks on both sides of the aisle
here that really think that it's not
sensible that we have all this Commerce
happening and you can't get a bank
account and what that does in terms of
the the government's perspective and how
that really is not in the government's
interest to have all this money floating
out around out there that that's not in
the banking system so um I I do think
we'll see something I think there's a
enough folks on both sides of the aisle
um it and that does make me naive um
because uh that's that's it out there
for quite a while but I'm happy to be in
the naive camp on that one I think
something's gonna happen yeah I'll join
you on the Youth Camp as well I think
it's something that hopefully in the
next 12 to 18 months that we see end of
coming to fruition but we shall cross
our fingers until then Tom I know you're
a very busy man so I'm not going to keep
you any longer it's been an absolute
pleasure talking to you and hopefully we
get to touch base over the next 12
months there's any movement on safe
banking
oh and it's an absolute pleasure to see
you again always and uh it's great to
have friends over there in Europe and
then we'll talk soon for sure we will
indeed thank you very much everybody
till next episode