[Music]
welcome to the next episode of the
Cannabis review I'm delighted to be
joined in this episode by Deborah
borchart who's the co-founder and
executive editor at the renowned green
marker report how you keeping today
Deborah I am doing well thank you for
having me on your show I'm absolutely
delighted to have you on uh one of the
most perfect sources of information in
the Cannabis industry is the green
market report so I'm delighted to get
the CH uh chance to talk to you can we
maybe start with giving everybody a
little overview of your position in the
industry and how you came to be there
sure so my background is actually Wall
Street um I worked on Wall Street for
over 15 years and had several Securities
licenses um but I I got really burned
out on the business and um one of the
things that I did enjoy when I was
working on Wall Street was talking about
companies and so I went to New York
University and got my master's degree in
business and economic reporting and from
there I went to work at the street with
Jim Kramer and while I was there was
really when um we started to see
cannabis stocks uh come to fruition uh
but it was really sketchy back then it
was a lot of companies that would just
put the word marijuana in the title of
the company and change the ticker make
it look like it was this cannabis
company when it when it really wasn't um
so it was great news picking lots of
drama lots of shady characters uh lots
of stock fraud uh so I started covering
cannabis back then and then I went out
on my own was freelancing but I just
wasn't the places I was working for I
wasn't really seeing the kind of
coverage that I wanted to do so I felt
like there was this opening in the
market to have a website that really
targeted financial news for the Cannabis
industry and really treated it like any
other industry um most of the stuff we
saw at that time was really cultural and
lifestyle types of Publications for
cannabis not so much business news
that was really focused on the financial
world and that's why I started Green
Market report and we've been online for
seven years uh this summer so that's
very exciting I can't believe we're
still um online for seven years just
because it's tough in media it's really
hard place to be and I always like to
joke with people like I don't know
what's harder cannabis or media and then
uh crane Communications acquired Us in
October 2021 so we're part of the crane
Communications family now and that's
they've been great partners and and
really invested in us and really wants
us to succeed in the long
term yeah you guys are definitely one of
the most uh H highly revered sources of
information in the market especially
when as you said there's amount of uh
misinformation and fibs that get told in
this industry over the last couple of
years having that North Star like green
marker report has always been
advantageous for real entrepreneurs and
business people the actual story behind
the green market report who was it that
co-founded you with it um were there the
the the first couple of years at at T
slug what's the exact trajectory for the
green marker report thank you uh so my
partners were Cynthia Sal rizada and
Vince petti and um they they left the
company when we were acquired by Crane
and so right now um our Focus has been
on events and digital advertising we've
got uh some plans to do some different
types of things uh hopefully by the end
of this year uh we really feel like
there's an opportunity to present more
information on these cannabis companies
um whereas right now it's it's kind of
broken up when you're looking for
information financial information on
these companies it's really hard to find
um there's different websites that focus
on different pieces uh maybe
Acquisitions and Deals and another one
might focus on you know something more
like uh you know the the legal news so
we're going to hopefully try to create
some kind of research center where we
can pull all these things together
uh just because we feel like it's it's
really fragmented and um thank you for
the the the comment on the journalism
because that's that's really been our uh
Northstar our our our main mission is to
deliver good journalism and you know
it's it's it's hard to do that and and
you're right there's a lot of cannabis
companies that would prefer to just have
us take the press releases and run with
it uh but we do a little bit of a deeper
dive um into the earnings we we always
go into the filings and and see what's
really there because the earnings
announcements themselves tend to be a
lot of very positive spin um which is
understandable but to your point I think
the investors and people within the
industry want to hear the truth and and
whether it's good or
bad yeah and I think one of the
cornerstones of your guys operation is
the open- source insights and Analysis
and how important that is from as I said
an investor and an entrepreneurs point
of view to be able to actually have real
and correct information because we've
seen whether it's productss being lab
tested and the THC content being
inflated or whether it's a financial
returns and people basically just trying
to pump and up the stock even to a
degree reports being generated by
so-called consultancy companies that are
given these valuations of $50 billion do
a year for this market and 20 for this
Market having you guys provide this open
source insights and Analysis is so
important was that the core objective
from the outset is to ensure okay we're
going to provide the most up toate
correct information for everybody
absolutely um you know you do take a
little bit of criticism for doing this
type of work um because you know and
when I first started doing this I was
considered negative and I wasn't an
advocate for the industry and I don't
consider myself an advocate nor do we do
advocacy reporting we just do reporting
so um and I love the Cannabis industry I
think some of the best people I've met
have been in the industry it's been one
of my favorite beats to cover
um but having said that you're still
dealing with an industry that ultimately
is federally illegal in the United
States so you do have a lot of shady
characters still roaming around the
Cannabis industry and to me that's
important um one of the things that that
struck me early on in my reporting was
how many small investors retail
investors that lost um maybe all their
savings investing in cannabis companies
because they read something that they
thought was true when it really wasn't
and I really felt for these people and
and so the thing is is that that
investor that invests $500 ,000 maybe
even
$10,000 they're just not given the same
attention by mainstream media because
they're not they're not big investors
these are penny stocks and so no one
really covers them and to me that was
something that kind of became my mission
was I want to make sure that if
companies are ripping people off that we
expose that so that they can't continue
to do this to other people and that's
been a real focus of mine and something
that you know we get emails all the time
from readers saying I'm so glad you
published that story I was about to work
with so and so and now I see they're not
paying their bills or and now I see that
they con people out of money um you know
thank you for letting me know that um so
that that's been something that makes us
feel good about what we're doing
yeah for sure the investors especially a
lot of them if you're a consumer of
cannabis you're in the culture of
cannabis it's a very distinct Market
that if you're in the culture of
cannabis you want to be part of the
success so you do see these smaller
retail investors putting a couple of
hundred Euro a couple of thousand Euro
that might be a huge chunk of their
savings and ensuring that those people
are protected is H is definitely a bonus
for everybody in the industry I think
because nobody wants to burn the small
retail retail investors I don't think
right right and and to be fair there are
some companies that are performing very
well um and and we do highlight those
too so we we try to do that we also
really focus heavily on female owned
companies you know because that's
important to me so so we try to make
sure that the female Executives and
female owned companies also get their
Fair Shake in the
media yeah well that's that having an
equal balance in any industry is very
important neveress sell the Cannabis
industry because it shouldn't be just a
select few get the profit off this
industry when the culture is so wide and
diverse and touches every demographic
and every Nuance of the the human race
absolutely moving on to the next thing I
want to talk about which is big news for
everybody it seems to be that there's
these three big things in America it's
the rescheduling it's the safe Banking
Act and the third one was the Florida
recreational ballot we heard yesterday
that this was successful and that a vote
will happen in December if I'm not
mistaken actually November it'll be in
November when we have our big
presidential election so it'll be a so
do you want to tell us all about what's
happening in Florida why there's reason
to be positive and what the
ramifications could be for the the
Nationwide industry in America sure so
Florida right now is a medical only
state so medical cannabis is legal in
the state and there's some some big
players like true leave has over 130
stores and it's it's a pretty
wellestablished Medical Market but um
they have been wanting
to transition to an adult youth legal
Market as well so fully legal and
they've really kind of struggled with
getting there and this time they have
done it uh the Supreme Court in that
state said yes it can go on the ballot
for the voters to decide the caveat
though is that they have to get 60% of
the voters to approve this and that's a
pretty big number um it'll be
interesting to see what happens um this
Market is anticipated to be a $ 6
billion Market it's already at 1.8
billion uh for medical only so three
times that puts it at about six billion
and um so it's it's considered a fairly
large market now while people think
there are quite a few stores already uh
compared to
Michigan and Massachusetts it's actually
underst stored so we could see continued
expansion in that state and maybe even a
lot of uh mergers and Acquisitions so
it's there's a lot of focus on it um
there's also a lot of focus on it not
just from the business aspect but also
the cultural aspect this is a state
that's gone heavily into conservative
politics um they have gone heavily into
culture wars and so we're curious to see
what happens here so will these mostly
Republican
voters vote for cannabis or will it
drive more democratic voters to The
Ballot Box to vote for C it's a toss-up
no one really knows so it's it that's
there's a lot of focus on this to see
what really happens with this vote I
mean obviously in addition to the
presidential
vote but uh yeah it's it's it's a it's a
big
deal yeah let's not mention the
presidential vote now we got do a whole
new discussion there's a lot of earnings
reports have been out and are still due
are we seen the upward trajectory of the
Cannabis industry now because we know a
lot of investors got in two three years
ago at the highs and those earning or
those Investments would be down
substantially they seem to be around
plateauing or getting close to what the
original values that people invested are
do you see what do you think think think
is going to be the biggest Catalyst for
cannabis stocks is it going to be
schedule three reschedule will it be
safe Banking Act is it going to be
positions that let's say North American
companies have taken Europe obviously
the likes of canopy have seen their
growth happen with Germany's news lately
what do you think is the Catalyst that
retail investors could look for I think
it will really focus on the the
descheduling so moving cannabis from a
schedule one drug which in the United
States right now um makes it as
dangerous as heroin um which is insane
and also makes it federally illegal if
it bumps down to three that takes all of
that away it opens the companies up to
uh better funding and it also takes away
the tax hit that they've had lately with
280e which means they can't take
business expenses as a deduction so it's
really hard for them to make a profit
with that um safer
banking uh is another piece of
legislation that would basically tell
the big Banks hey you can you can bank
with these companies um and and we won't
go after you for dealing in an illegal
substance um
that looked like it had a lot of promise
but we're hearing more out of Washington
that again Republicans are starting to
push back on that safer banking so
that's looking less secure than the D
scheduling um yeah I think that we are
starting to see valuations pick back up
we've been in a two-year bare market and
I think between the hope for schedule
three which which she seems much more uh
doable than the safer banking um the
hopes for that are are building so maybe
this summer we'll see something there um
we've also seen a lot of companies
really get their houses in order so
you're seeing out of this earning cycle
more companies paying down debt more
companies cutting back on expenses
really getting their house in order
versus just hinging on this whole
schedule three thing uh which is
important to see so that they're really
fixing balance sheets and making sure
that they're taking the right steps to
clean up these balance sheets so that's
that's been a really nice thing to see
to and I think that the investment
Community is starting to reward those
companies that are getting their house
in order one quick Last Thing Before I
Let You Go does schedule three mean that
we're going to see a lot of Biotech and
Pharma money come into drug Discovery
and development and actually flesh out a
range of products because that surely is
the big opport Unity for large
corporations is these formulations and
the drug Discovery and being able to
create these products that are on
through clinical trials and could be
prescribed by a doctor seems to be the
big huge opportunity in the industry for
people who aren't already established I
think for sure you'll see that I think
you'll also see a lot of interest from
beverage companies um and I think you'll
see a lot of interest from Big tobacco
so big tobacco has been losing customers
for years um um this isn't a dissimilar
product it's a leaf product that gets
often rolled into paper and smoked um
their business has been going down
they've had to stay out of it because of
the legal situation then you look at the
alcoholic beverage side of the business
in the states where cannabis has been
legalized alcoholic beverage sales drop
so they certainly would be happy to have
those that clientele or those sales so I
think you're going to see a little bit
more on that side side I think that the
biotech side yes will be interested I
also think that they've kind of got
their sight set more on the Psychedelic
side of the world at this point um while
we're still continuing to see advances
in cannabis uh medicinal cannabis for
sure um in different areas um I think
that the the excitement there is not as
strong as it once was U which is
unfortunate um but yeah it will
definitely open up that side of the
business for more research and hopefully
more um medicinal uses for
cannabis it's been phenomenal talking to
you we're just at our time for anybody
who hasn't been checking out green
market report or isn't subscribed or
doesn't read their news I don't know
what you've been doing but the website
is below you you should be adding this
to your tabs and checking this daily
because it's the most up-to-date best
source of financial information the
Cannabis industry Deborah for now thank
you very much for taking your time to do
this it's very much appreciated well
thank you so much for having me it was a
joy until next episode
[Music]
everybody