[Music]
welcome everybody to another episode of
the cannabis review i am delighted to be
joined on this show by stuart lambie
who's the secretary general of medicinal
cannabis europe how are you keeping
security well
yeah thanks owen very well thank you
excellent i'm delighted to have you on
the show now covering that
a topic that i'm sure most people talk
about but very few people have an inside
knowledge like you'll have on this so
first and foremost i just want to let
everybody if you want to inform
everybody how you're in
the cannabis industry in europe and how
you got to this stage now in a quick
brief
yeah sure on yeah thanks uh yeah well
medicinal cannabis europe was started up
about three years ago
as a pro bono project and just over a
year ago we established the association
as a non-profit
association in belgium under belgian law
i think unlike a lot of associations
we're a multi-stakeholder association so
we
welcome members from the patient and
medical community right through to the
the industry um and basically our
our objectives are to
advocate for harmonize european
regulation on medicinal cannabis
create a level playing field for the
industry to operate across all european
countries
push for funding for research and
development funding from european funds
for investigation into medicinal
cannabis
and last but not least try to educate
the public
stakeholders the medical community about
the benefits of medicinal cannabis and
try and get rid of the stigma
which is in some places still attached
to it
yeah brilliant thanks very much for that
can you give us any fresh news that's
that you've heard coming out of europe
in terms of uh council's been formed or
something you can inform the audience
about
yeah i think there's a couple of things
to pick up on uh very recent
developments
um we've been working for quite some
time now about six months together with
various members of the european
parliament um
and trying to be part of the process
of bringing together an interest group
in the medicinal cannabis
issue so the good news on that front is
that there is now an interest group
being formed within the european
parliament
um of several members of the parliament
from different political
directions different geographies around
europe
and an interest group in the european
parliament for those of your audience
who maybe
are not that familiar with the european
institutions it's a mechanism whereby
these
members of the parliament can come
together around a common issue
they can pull in input from external
stakeholders
so via associations like ourselves
industry can have access into that
process
um they can collect knowledge
information hear about people's
challenges uh
the barriers preventing trade or or the
use of
medicines and they can digest all of
that
as a as a group of members of parliament
and then they can take those issues
forward to the european commission who
are the regulators
who will be the ones uh creating any
draft regulations in the future
on this issue and they can say hey guys
you know these are the problems which
the industry which patients which the
medical community are facing
and how are you going to fix this how
are you going to start harmonizing
regulation
to make these medicines available
to european patients equally across all
european countries so i think the
formation of that interest group is a
huge step forward um and it really
indicates that
the parliamentarians are starting to
understand the need for regulation
around this
issue and that's where the process has
to begin
um it will not be a quick process it
will take time but
you know we need to start sometime so
now is as good as any
so i think that's the first fairly
significant
recent development um some
sorry no work awake um
yeah one other thing which i think is
worth mentioning is um
the well medicinal cannabis europe held
a another conference back in october
last year
and we had a member of the european
commission there from
directorate general sante that's the
directorate general which is responsible
for
public health issues and
they made it uh clear then that they
were going to start a process of
creating
a glossary of definitions which could be
used to describe
medicinal cannabis and that was in
relation to the herbal medicines
directive
and now the herbal medicines directed
might be a way
in for the medicinal cannabis
products into european regulation and
they have recently just announced that
their now their committee and the
committee looking at this will
will start work in 2021
and collecting views and information
around definitions how to define
medicinal cannabis
because that's that's an absolute
essential starting point for any
european regulation is we need a clear
definition of what is medicinal cannabis
right now there is no legal clear
definition under european
law um and without the definition you
can never start to regulate
so so that process at least is beginning
um
so those two things i think are are
quite significant
as i say quite recent developments in
brussels
yeah well i think we both agree the
rules in the framework of any industry
are paramount and ensuring that it has
longevity and there's no corruption and
a gray market as opposed to defining the
two markets individually
and one of the things that i'd like to
kind of talk to you about in this
episode is harmonizing the eu
regulations
also over in ireland at the moment it's
kind of comical the situation that's
been at the moment you've got
the enactment of the law that happened
with the european council back in
december
that hasn't been fully enacted over here
and i can understand the police point of
view when they see
a big field full of cannabis or the big
plan for the cannabis they're not to
understand which is the difference
between cbd and thc
so are you seeing a mishmash of
implementations of these regulations
across the eu
like what's happening in ireland or has
there been a cohesive action
and we're kind of the the odd one out as
per usual
well yeah i don't know if you're the odd
one i don't think so i think on this
particular issue
maybe you're the odd one out but i think
in terms of harmonized
uh view or regulation on all kinds of
aspects of medicinal cannabis
it's absolutely not harmonized across
europe and and that really is the
problem um
you know you have well nowadays we have
27 eu member states and and in each of
those member states there's a there's a
different implementation
of all kinds of aspects of the
regulation
and i mean our particular focuses are
on um the regulation allowing an
industry to
to operate so again that's very
different from one country to another at
the moment you know you have the german
model where it's
there's a relatively clear model there
and relatively clear regulation on how
to do this
and there are other member states where
it's absolutely prohibited to
have an industry operating in the middle
medicinal cannabis
sector equally for patients patient
access
to existing cannabis medicines
is radically different from one member
state to the other reimbursement
on those medicines costs is radically
different from one member state to the
other
so it's all of those aspects
and the irish cbd issue is is one of
those
although it's uh it's a cbd issue not uh
let's say not a regulated medicine
issue as such um
but yeah all of those things are in
dire need of harmonization so that
you know at least there should be a
minimum level
of harmonized regulation of how these
things are handled in all 27 member
states so a patient in
italy needing access to a drug
um for let's say epilepsy
has the same ability to access that
medicine as a patient in spain or a
patient in ireland
equally those drugs should be able to
move cross-border with the patient
in their hand baggage just like any
other medicine would move across a
border
so all those things need to be sorted
out
so that we have equal treatment for
patients
in in all countries and an industry
which
can operate on a level playing field
across all those countries and today
that just simply doesn't exist
and your irish cbd art issue is is one
example of that yeah well
hopefully the people in paris central
can form these rules and these
regulations that can the other countries
could just take it this is how it's done
as opposed to
i can understand a lot of politicians
trying to learn this as a new industry
must be a lot overwhelming for them to
the myriad of things they'd have to
learn and how fast some things are
moving
it's difficult enough when you're
already at the tip of the spirit this
industry never mind
trying to catch up on 15 years of
learning yeah no that's right and i
think that's where
um to go back to my first point about
the the interest group of members of
parliament forming an interest group you
know that interest group can
can then listen to existing experiences
on regulation in different places what
works what doesn't work
and and then hopefully channel that
through and eventually be reflected in
european uh regulation
yeah tell me this and tell me no more i
have yet to come across
a proper economist's predictions of a
european
medical cannabis i've seen this is what
the industry looks like in three years
time with a rough figure thrown out
there but there's the likes of you
whitney over in the us who's the head of
whitney economics he does them for the
hemp industry
and there is detailed a financial report
as you should be getting for an industry
have you come across
a proper financial report yet or is this
something that still is yet to be done
by an economist
yeah i mean i i think that's a little
bit outside of our
our kind of field we're more looking at
policy and regulation rather than the
economics
i mean i think would you not think that
the economics goes hand in hand with the
convincing the politicians because a lot
of them are going to see a number and
say well
we could create x amount of jobs because
all you're hearing coming out of new
york at the moment is
it's worth x amount of billion they're
doing x amount of projects to create x
amount of jobs
nobody really cares about anything else
after that and i think that should be
one of the doors for
the politicians it's it's easy it's
digestible it's something that they'd
understand as opposed to hitting them
with
all the different myriads of medical and
recreational kind of do you get to get
your best
yeah i know i think i've you know like
you i've seen the same
the same predictions of you know x
billion this this market will be worth x
billion by 2030
so those are the kind of analyses i've
picked up on
um i think what you're talking about is
something much more detailed so you
would say
you know what what jobs would how many
thousands of jobs would be created
around europe etc
and yeah you're right i think that kind
of detail
at the moment is is lacking at least i
haven't seen it
and even to put to put a figure on the
like industry at the moment like how
many jobs are currently in cbd
in each country what's the total revenue
gdp
taxation for the country so it's again i
think it's something that
when the funding and the research
development has been done i think this
is one of the things that needs to be
looked at
as carefully as this is the benefits
that the plant has for everybody
yeah no i would agree i think you know
that's that was certainly the case in
the united states i think that's what
convinced a lot of
dates in the um because of the the
potential tax revenues
which would come from it yeah now
hopefully now that's something that we
can maybe press on i would say over the
next 12 months of comprehensive
financial and economy report done for
about the hemp industry
and then subset for the cbd industry
because
i think this uh information is going to
be the key to us getting
a fully regulated eu industry yeah
sure i i think i mean just to pick up on
your cbe point again if i can um
you know i think from a medicinal point
of view um
we are we are talking much wider than
cbd obviously yeah i think cbd
you know the recent ruling on cbd is is
a kind of
it's an easy one if you like uh although
it's cause problems in ireland it's a
relatively easy one for regulators to
cope with and to
um to take on board because it has the
connection with the wellness
issues and you know it's it's relatively
soft and comfortable to deal with people
know that cbd in general is not harmful
um but when you talk about medicinal
products then you're talking about cbd
thc
and many other compounds which are found
in the cannabis plant
and that's where that's where the issue
of definitions becomes
much more important you know what do we
mean when we talk about
medicinal cannabis most likely it's a
combination of all those compounds
um maybe in terms of definitions we need
to talk about specific compounds
when we come to regulate rather than
just medicinal cannabis
as a blanket term yeah well i i think
i i think i couldn't agree with you more
i think medical cannabis is the
equivalent of saying it's jazz
genetics is it bebop isn't modern is it
slow there's maybe
a hundred different subsets of jazz and
i think meta
cannabis needs to be treated the exact
same as you said cbd is just one of
those little myriad of topics it's just
a hot topic at the moment but
yeah hopefully it's a something we get
to see more detail in each individual
component of the industry and more
financial reporting
i want to thank you very much for coming
on the show it's been an absolute
pleasure to talk to you stuart
very informative and i hope we get to
chuck to talk to you again before the
end of the year
yeah my pleasure and thanks very much
for the invitation and
good luck with your uh your efforts over
there in ireland thank you very much
have a good day