[Music]
welcome everybody to next episode of the
Cannabis review I'm delighted to be
joined on this episode by Paul Conan
who's the founder of green leaf cannabis
and Hell's Kitchen cannabis collective
in New York how you keeping today
Patrick doing very well thank you so
much for having me delighted to have you
on mate can you maybe give everybody a
quick overview of your position in the
industry on your area of
expertise yeah absolutely so I right now
um and am employed by a cultivator leny
in New York State uh to run and operate
a cannabis grower showcase which is a
temporary popup Farmers Farmers Market
style event that um occurs uh in in
either indoor or outdoor venues
throughout Upstate New York and in the
city um the state state government of
New York put out this program in in
order to um basically address the
problem that was created by the lack of
Rapid opening of stores because the uh
dispensaries were supposed to be open a
lot more soon um and unfortunately that
did not occur so they created the
Cannabis grower showcase U model and I
was able to under the license of my
employer and the farm that I work for
Green Leaf Farm um organize uh one of
those uh grower showcases actually the
first in Manhattan New York City um so
we're um up and operational um I'm
general manager running day-to-day
operations there my background in the
industry is approaching it from more of
a nonprofit advocacy side but being
interested in in how sort of the equity
side of the industry unfolds and how the
policy that uh our Regulators write um
sort of helps accelerate or or you know
make an obstruction C for those kind of
uh you know Equity questions and and
scenarios so um you know come I came
from Michigan where it there was
legalization a few years earlier than
New York and it was not a very equitable
distribution of wealth among people who
had been growing before legalization and
among people who had um you know really
sacrificed or anything to get to the
point of legalization it was really a
concentration of profits in the hands of
sort of large business business is
Corporate Consolidated um modeled
businesses so I I moved to New York with
the intention to advocate for more
Equity equity in the industry and and
sort of more tradition and and respect
to the people who had been sort of
Paving the way for this um uh this
process to to be so easy and for us to
have all of this cannabis genetic um
resources to access now that it's legal
and those genetics are worth very much
money so um I I op at them the Hell's
Kitchen cannabis Collective okay
excellent and when it comes to the
Hell's Kitchen cannabis Collective how
many members are involved is there a
limit of the amount of plants that they
all each cultivate is all of the flower
then all gathered and generated together
what are the the basic principles of the
the collective and how many people are
involved absolutely so um the the C Hell
Kitchen cannabis Collective operates a
little bit differently from what I think
people what comes to people's mind when
they hear Collective um it's a
collective of of truly uh businesses
it's it's a collective of licensed Farms
um for cannabis in New York state so um
there have been about 200 or so cannabis
cultivators who are licensed through the
state process um and and those those can
be a single person or those can be a
business entity um and basically we have
we started with nine uh cultivators and
we had three processors all of whom
basically are members in that they have
their wees at our location on
consignment um they're invited to come
operate their own uh booth in any time
they want um but we recommend Saturdays
so it's it's a kind of a their their
opportunity to participate in a retail
experience that's a lot closer to a
farmer market Market than it would be to
like Walmart or you know any type of
sort of corporate grocery store type
environment it seems to me that New York
is primed for an explosion in genetics
and some of these low or lowkey
cultivator shall we say uh like almost
what happened with beer to a degree in
New York that you had all these
individual distilleries open up with
their own unique profiles and
formulations I think New York is well
positioned with the different ethnicity
in that country to come up with some of
the most unique genetics that we're
probably going to see in the American
Market over the coming years that's what
I hope certainly I mean that is that is
absolutely a good observation I would
say what happened with craft beer though
is that you know there was decades and
Decades of of corporate consolidation
and and building massive you know multi-
uh brand uh companies before there was
kind of the the the upshoot of of craft
and the movement of craft has been kind
of a boom in the last couple years um
we're hoping to accelerate that with
cannabis so that it's not a situation
where we have to wait 20 30 40 50 years
for all of the big companies to really
be done fighting with each other and and
the last one left standing starts um
making room for small craft operations
we're hoping that that can all grow
alongside each other um at the start of
the industry in New York I do think that
New York is a special place with special
cannabis history and
culture um it's got specific genetics
that it's really focused on and and
enjoyed and liked for a long time as
well as the potential to to breed a
bunch more
so and when it comes to the offering at
the Health's kitchen cannabus Collective
is it Edibles or is it just flour is
there a range of products or is it
people just coming with the best bu that
they can cultivate themselves well yeah
it is a range of product um it is going
to be uh flow
pre-rolls gummies Vapes infused
beverages concentrates including resin
and rosin and uh Rick Simpson Oil or RSO
so which is a full spectrum cannabis
extract so we have kind of the full
Gambit of products available um on the
New York Legal market and when it comes
to the beverage side of things are these
people that are creating and developing
their own products while Outsourcing
let's say the Emulsion technology from
an established business or do you what
way do you see the beverages going
because the water solubility and the
aluminium and cannaboids being attracted
to each other do you see that being an
issue for a lot of these
Growers um you know I haven't uh delved
that deep into it I know that the first
kind of beverages on the market are
mainly collaborations between like a
laboratory like a processing licy and
between someone else who's got the idea
or it's just kind of done inhouse by the
processor so I'm pretty sure that
they're kind of a breast of these
situations cuz the cans look a little
bit different sometimes or you know
sometimes they seem like just aluminum
cans but I know that they have to do
that like Emulsion technology to get the
oil uh small enough to kind of mix with
the water so yeah that seems to be one
of the sweet spots of the industry that
it looks as if and I think New York
could potentially be well positioned for
this that if there is a dominant couple
of white label suppliers of Beverages
and Edibles it's going to be the brands
and the entrepreneurs who can create
these Brands who can connect with a
specific demographic or audience that
will uh I think grow any specific
business so you don't necessarily need
to have the most chemistry expertise or
production expertise once you can come
up with the right brand and the Right
audience I think that's where the
winners in cannabis are going to be
especially in New York in the coming
years yeah absolutely I think that those
uh this this the processors we were I've
been speaking to people in the industry
right now the processors are in a excit
I mean it's a comfortable position for
them because they control the suppli
they they have sort of extra leverage on
the supply side and the retail side so
whereas we have a lot of cultivators and
they're having difficulty getting their
product on the shelves we have a lot of
or we have very few open retail
storefronts um so they have no problem
kind of deciding what product they want
the cultivators we have the like almost
the fewest of even even the ones who are
licensed so um and by that I mean they
licensed about 250 cultivators they
licensed about 40 processors and then
they licensed about 250 stores but there
was a lawsuit preventing the stores from
opening so we're only looking at about
28 stores in the whole state um so the
processors they get to
control what kind of price they buy
their their their products at their
their raw flow for processing at and
then they also kind of get to control a
little bit about what they sell at
because their process goods are so
valuable and there's only 40 of them um
and they're in such high demand that
they they actually are in a lot less of
a dire State than a lot of the other uh
players in our industry right
now yeah hopefully with Federal
legalization we kind of get the scenario
where the processors are plentyful
because it's now an opportune uh thing
that you could go as a large company
who's not necessarily touching it right
now because if we look across the board
in every consumer package good Mars and
cabri don't grow their own Coco
McDonald's don't have their own Farms
they've managed to create a brand that
they've been able to translate this into
a large market share yeah absolutely
absolutely so yeah I think these
processors are only it's only going to
get better for them we'll see that's yes
so for now where is the best weed in New
York is it in one of the burs is it in
Manhattan in a specific territory in
Manhattan if you were recommending
somebody to go get their hands on the
best blaze in the city oh well you know
I'd probably tell you to come right down
to see us at Hell's Kitchen cannabis
Collective um we have some exceptional
Farms that we're working with who are
from all over the state of New York um
they grow between you know some of them
are full-term outdoor some of them are
mixed like Greenhouse some of them are
mixed like Greenhouse but converting to
do an indoor operation for the next
season um so there's kind of every type
of preference uh available and then also
I would say that you know there's
there's definitely some absolute um some
fire as we call it uh that you can be
found in Hell Kitchen cannabis
Collective especially I would recommend
the Hayes because Hayes is kind of a
unique um when in Rome situation with
New York I know that it's had sort of
lives outside of New York City but it's
uh found its home here and and and
become you know a favorite of many for
Generations so I would recommend trying
some hay and hopefully we get some of
the cultivators that have been working
in the shadows over the last couple of
decades now coming to award-winning
ceremonies and being praised for the
skill set that they currently have
that's why I got in this industry so
that's that's if I have anything to do
with it hopefully they will be sooner
than later excellent for everybody who's
going to New York or anybody who's from
New York helles kitchen cannabis
collective.com the website is below and
it'll be available in all good places
you're watching and listening to this
what are you hoping to see over the
coming 12 to 18 months in New York do
you want an expansion of the card
licenses and the court cases to work
themselves out do you want a multitude
of new retail licenses regardless of
what the applicant's backstory is or do
you want to see some unique cannabis
branding come to the market where you
see these homegrown billion dollar
companies coming out of New York h um I
mean know any any of the above would be
exciting and more exciting than what
we've seen in the last you know 12 to 18
months with the the kind of the all the
roadblocks and obstacles and constant
you know um doubt and and questioning
that a lot of figures have had uh with
with just the lack of clarity about
where we're headed I think that um I I
mean first and foremost I'd like the
grower showcase program to get extended
I think it's one of the most unique and
special um Creations that New York state
has um come up with in this cannabis
realm and I think that they aren't even
really realizing how special it is and
how Global of an impact it could have if
they put it in the right context and and
Amplified it a little more because it's
one of the main and only direct to
Consumer retail models for cannabis
among any legal State and it's um
frankly I believe the way cannabis
should be bought and um 's no more
fulfilling experience than you know
standing across the table from a
cultivator and actually learning from
The Source about what you're going to be
um you know enjoying later um you know
in in your flower product or your edible
or whatever it is um there's someone who
put a lot of thought and care and craft
behind that and and is excited to share
that with you so that's probably the
first uh major I hope I have for the
grow uh for New York The Grow Show
showcase program right now is slated to
end just at the end of the year but we
really think that the Market's not going
to be ready for the program to go away
and and there's no really good reason to
send it away anyways um we also would
say I mean I would say my other
preference I think that what I want to
see happen is the cards who already got
licensed I want to see them get open I
want to see um the the the law as
written helping the people that was set
out to help so those are distressed
Farmers disabled veterans people
convicted from Cannabis in New York
people from communities
disproportionately impacted by the War
on Drugs um and then and then the last
thing is is really I just want to see um
I want to see the the like just like you
said the the true kind of pioneers of
this um culture and this plant and the
people who are stewards of the plant
throughout the time when it was illegal
and still pushing along you know
breeding and genetics and and holding
these valuable clones and keeping the
lights on and paying the massive power
bill and forfeiting friendships and
family relationships and you know just
praying that they don't get incarcerated
and um taking all those risks on for so
many years I want to see them put in a
position to succeed and succeed in the
highest
degree incredible you're definitely on
the right track and in the poll position
to have a great Viewpoint of how New
York is going to explode over the next
five years hopefully I get to meet in
person and we can try some of this Haze
at the Hell's Kitchen Canabis Collective
that you tell me about that sounds
wonderful I would love to welcome you in
and show you around anytime you're in
the city excellent again for anybody who
wants to know more about Hell's Kitchen
cannabis Collective the website is below
and also about Green Leaf New York
cannabis the website is below as well
for now thank you very much for taking
your time Patrick to do this very much
appreciated thank you so much it's been
a pleasure thank you for having me until
next episode
[Music]
everybody