[Music]
welcome to another episode of the canvas
review
i am delighted to be joined on this
episode by david brown
if any of you don't know david then you
must be living in a rock in this
industry he's a regulatory affairs
specialist at stratcon at the moment but
has
an esteemed career so far in the
cannabis industry from
board mender at cfam policy advisor at
nish
editor-in-chief at lift cannabis news
and a senior policy advisor to health
canada so
you won't find a man with a better
background in the industry than david
david how are you keeping today
good on thanks for having me i'm
delighted to have you on later man who's
a
a wealth of knowledge and i'm delighted
to be able to get you on and share some
few things with the audience
um you've been in the industry pretty
long do you want to give everybody an
overview of
your time in the industry so far and
we'll kick out the topic one then after
that
sure yeah i'd say i probably started uh
in the industry here in canada
about 10 years ago now um was a
co-founder of a company called lyft
cannabis
in 2014 that started as a news and
review site for what was then the new
commercial medical cannabis program in
canada and really have just been
covering the cannabis industry
since then i spent two years when i left
lyft in
from 2018 to 2020 as a senior policy
advisor to health canada's
cannabis legalization and regulation
branch and worked with a very large
team there at both the development and
implementation of the new regulatory
regime
in 2018 and so that was a pretty
interesting time
and then when i left health canada in
2020 i got back into the media space
with a website called stratcan covering
just a different aspect of the
cannabis industry here in canada really
with a focus on a lot of the new license
holders
micro cannabis license holders for uh
especially so
okay amazing so as everybody watching be
able to understand this man has got a
a great experience in the industry and
hopefully going to be able to guide us
through the three topics for this week's
show so
first topic i want to talk about is
cannabis 3.0 in canada
is this going to be is there going to be
a cannabis 3.0 or was the release of
edibles and beverages
that's the what the market looks like in
cannabis or do you see a massive
another pivot coming sometime down the
line no no
in the sense that cannabis 2.0 was the
new uh
new products like edibles extracts and
topicals we won't really see
any you know cannabis 3.0 in that sense
where we'll see
any new products particularly when
people refer to cannabis 3.0 here in
canada i think they maybe are referring
to a couple different things
i think overall we're seeing an
evolution of the industry beyond the
sort of large
publicly traded companies to a lot more
small
private mom-and-pop uh companies so i
think in some sense that could be
cannabis 3.0 kind of a changing of the
playing field
at the same time we're also running up
on a three-year review of the cannabis
act later this year so
the cannabis act in canada was came into
force in october 17
2018 we're coming up on three years here
of october 17
2021 when the federal government will
implement a three-year review of the
regulations and we could potentially be
seeing some
some fairly major changes uh in the year
year and a half
following that review which you know you
could potentially call cannabis 3.0 as
well
but in terms of new product categories
we won't really see any anything new
um you know beyond some of the small
evolutions we're seeing now we're seeing
some
some new topicals some interesting um
strips uh i'm kind of losing my words
here for the
dissolvable strips um some things like
that in the medical space but for the
most part we're not really seeing too
many product evolutions
yeah well i definitely have noticed the
amount of craft
growers and different uh products that
are popping up out of canada then
it's great to see that it's happened to
beer already i don't see why it wouldn't
happen in cannabis across the
entire industry moving on to the second
topic which
i know a lot of people in ireland are
going to be uh pretty uh
adamant about being part of a bill
that's uh
brought to parliament over here
homegrown laws are these essential for
any bill do you see in a newly regulated
territory
personally i think it's very important
especially because you know the first
round
of regulations tend to set the stage and
so it could be very difficult to try to
ease
regulatory changes like that later on
and i really don't think there's any
good reason to not
allow home production i mean here in
canada we've got a four plant limit
uh in a few of the u.s states we've seen
up to i think six
or even eight plants and i think this is
you know a reasonable amount for a
person to produce at home
while at the same time you know creating
a clear delineation between personal
production and
illicit large-scale uh unregulated
production so i think it's very
important and i think it's also very
important
in terms of patients rights for
individuals to be able to grow their own
because when you know you're relying on
cannabis as a medicine
buying through the commercial system can
often be very costly
and so for those individuals who have
that ability and have that space to be
able to grow even just a few plants
for their own medicine i think it's very
important and i think that it's
something that should be
part of any piece of of legislation and
do you think that there should be a
license allocated to somebody who wants
to grow
or should it just be open to anybody who
decides they want to put their hand to
uh
this part of agriculture you know i
think there's a good argument
perhaps to be made on the medical side
that there need to be you know some sort
of authorization from a medical
professional or
from your physician but in terms of you
know non-medical
cannabis production i don't see any
reason for permit um you know i'm not
sure the laws
uh where you are but here in canada you
don't need to permit to you know to brew
your own alcohol or
you know to grow sunflowers in my yard
so i don't really think there's a need
for you know all of the extra regulatory
hurdles that would come with trying to
implement that kind of
permitting system and
how did canada set up their home grow
laws across the board was it strictly
illegal
uh or have have some of the different
territories
become legal yeah so canada when we
legalize cannabis uh
federally uh the federal government
allowed for up to four plants to be
grown uh per
household essentially and there's
there's some limits around it but
essentially that's that's the main limit
is for plants
um canadian law also allows uh provinces
to
uh add further restrictions to that and
so we've seen some limitations there's
one province i believe new brunswick or
nova scotia has some rules around
it having to be in a locked room here in
british columbia where i live you can't
have it in public view so you have to
have a say inside or in your backyard
we've seen two provinces now quebec and
manitoba have
both banned home production which the
federal government says is not their
right to to limit it to zero they could
limit to one but not zero
that's being fought in court uh the case
in quebec
was actually overturned in late 2019 but
the government immediately immediately
appealed it and we're waiting on that
appeal now
there's another court case in manitoba
that is challenging manitoba's ban as
well
i think the overall expectation is that
they will be successful in overturning
that but it's you know it's
it's still unknown and has not made it
to the courts yet but essentially
uh it's it's legal in canada we have a
couple provinces that are
claiming they have the right to ban it
and that's being settled in court at the
moment
and is that basically down to political
ideology in
terms of the places that are banning
versus not banning
do you see a more democratic
states or territories that have grow
laws compared to
let's say more conservative yeah i think
that's probably a fair perspective
um you know there are conservative-run
provinces that have allowed it
but quebec's uh current provincial
government tends to be uh fairly
conservative and fairly kind of
anti-cannabis they've made
some some of their politicians have made
some fairly anti-cannabis statements in
the past
they also raised their age of access to
25 it's the highest age of access
in all of canada um
manitoba the other province who has
banned it also has a very conservative
leadership
and so i think there's some sort of
anti-cannabis sentiment there
it also gets into some some issues that
go well beyond cannabis that have to do
with an ongoing push and pull between
provincial governments especially
conservative provincial governments and
the federal government in terms of
of their rights uh to to manage their
own affairs and so really i think it has
a lot more to do with that than
than even cannabis and like i say we're
seeing that uh courts
uh tend to agree that the federal
government has that sort of paramount
authority
uh to issue those rules that the
provinces can't push back on
okay perfect brings me into the last
territory that our last topic that i
wanted to talk to you about
advice to governments looking to allow a
medical or adulthood's market we've got
a couple of politicians lined up with
the show
ireland is a a new enough territory that
hasn't yet legalized it
we've got a medical cannabis program but
it's for six symptoms that
again is not reflective of the
population and even those people with
symptoms are
having to pay 10 grand a month to get
access to products so
what would be let's say the two biggest
tips if a politician was watching this
that you'd say
this is what a government should
implement if they were going to have a
cannabis industry
oh yeah that's a a big question i mean i
think stakeholder involvement really
engaging
all levels of the public um and and i
think it's important for cannabis
activists and advocates to recognize
that that you know
trying to get reach that consensus um
means engaging with people who maybe do
not agree with you and hearing from you
know
teachers and religious officials and and
public health
experts and law enforcement as well as
advocates and patient advocates and
legalization advocates so
engaging with the public and really
getting a good understanding i would
also
say data collection is very important
beforehand
so that you can build that baseline if
you want to be able to measure the the
success
of your program say five or ten years
down the road it's very important to
have that baseline data prior to
legalization so you have an
understanding of the effects of that law
have
you know has legalization increased use
uh has a decreased use that's something
that we're wrangling with here in canada
and it's still you know early days it's
still pretty difficult to
to tease that out but having that data
beforehand
has allowed us to at least have a bit of
a baseline and understanding what we're
working with
okay and tell me this we've talked to
some of the guys in colorado at the
marijuana enforcement division and the
kind of
bureau over in la did you guys have a
similar division
in canada how were license applied to
i'm sure everything went under national
license and excise
was there a department in canada that
delta is the buffer between applications
and going to excel license and excess
yeah in fact that's the branch i worked
with um at the time was the
uh health canada cannabis legalization
and regulation branch um it's now uh
it's changed its iteration a few times
but it's essentially health canada's uh
cannabis and drug branch now um they're
the the department they have several
different departments within that branch
that deal with
everything from license applications
going in and that's both on the
commercial as well as the personal and
commercial medical side
um you know review of those licenses uh
review of the regulations there's a
whole team now there that's working on
the review of those regulations that i
referred to earlier
uh so including stakeholder engagement
so it's
it's a very large department several
hundred people um in the build up to
those regulations they were engaging
with those other departments that you
you referenced as well in in different
legal states as well as
uh uruguay and countries in europe and
around the world so there's
uh constant sort of engagement with
their sister agencies
and that that department continues to
grow and i think will continue to grow
at least until
legalization maybe the industry has
matured to a place where maybe there
isn't quite a need for that that level
of oversight
okay and the last topic i kind of just
want to get a question on do you think
the canadian lps
are targeting europe as the main
customer base
for a lot of their products or do you
believe that they're going to be able to
crack america
once america legalizes statewide
investment will come in
mergers and acquisitions will happen
galore we'll have the one or two major
players in the country do you think the
canadian lps will be able to match the
use at us
companies when it's all said and done
yeah that's a good question i think up
until now um canadian lps have been
largely targeting um you know different
european countries with uh some level of
medical regulation uh australia is
another example of a country where
there's been some
some exports if you look at those
numbers honestly the export numbers are
pretty small and i think there's
probably an argument to be made that
you know that's largely uh about
stakeholder or
uh investor uh relations and trying to
show their footprint in a lot of other
countries even if it's not particularly
significant
uh the us is obviously you know the
golden goose
so to speak everyone would like to be
operating there it really depends on
what uh the u.s regulations end up
looking like is still a big unknown
will uh canadian companies be able to to
ship
product to us will they be able to set
up in the us it's still really unknown
and frankly i think we're probably
several years away from any kind of
functional federal even a medical system
much less a non-medical system in the
u.s but
that's certainly where the big companies
are looking and in terms of
of keeping investor hopes up
uh pointing to a new emerging markets
like that is you know kind of an ongoing
uh tactic
for the battle of the entrepreneur the
sun's up there on the hill i promise the
sun's up there in the hill
yes um david thank you very much for
joining the show it's been
actually a great conversation you've
been a wealth of information i hope we
can get to chat again in the future for
anybody wants to check out any david's
work
stratcom.com on the screen there i
highly recommend it
one of the best sources of information
in the global canadian cannabis industry
never mind just canada so
thank you again david for coming out
it's very much appreciated
thank you owen thanks for having me
cheers guys see you next episode