foreign
Jesse Redmond who's the founder and
management partner higher calling LLC
how are you keeping today Jesse okay
thanks how are you I'm fantastic thank
you very much for coming on I've been
following your Twitter landscape for a
number of years or a number of time now
so can you maybe give everybody a quick
overview in under 60 seconds of what
your position is and how you came to be
in the Cannabis industry yeah so I've
heard a bit of a strange career where I
spent 20 years on the investment
management side I worked at Fisher
Investments and Franklin Templeton in
San Francisco and then I co-managed a
couple of hedge funds in Santa Barbara
in 2016 I put aside the investment stuff
and started focusing on cannabis and
founded a dispensary outside of Santa
Barbara I did that for about three years
and then for the last couple of years
I've been focused on focusing on
bulleting that cannabis and investing
knowledge
okay great it's been a interesting to to
watch the Twitter uh MSO investment and
Community shall we say tether over the
last year and the positions everybody
seems to be taking do you maybe want to
give every a brief little overview of
the higher calling LLC what is the
objective with your uh with your firm
and what you guys do
yeah so that's an investment Consulting
business that I started in 2020 and the
idea there was just to help investors
find the best and most appropriate
cannabis Investments for them and so for
some people that may be a portfolio of
individual stocks so things like green
thumb Industries and Care leaf and
Verano and truly individual names like
that or for other folks it could be a
venture capital fund there's a number of
good Venture Capital funds out there
that invest in earlier stage businesses
there's also some great hedge funds out
there for people that are qualified and
interested in uh in vehicles like that
and there's also some excellent ETFs as
well and so I think there isn't you know
like a lot of investing things it's not
about there being one best solution it's
about understanding somebody's needs and
objectives and then fitting the right
solution for them so that's what I try
to do with uh with higher calling that
got started with some larger family
offices that I worked with on the hedge
fund side that were interested in
getting cannabis exposure but didn't
want to do all the work themselves as
you probably know it's a bit of a
complex and nuanced space due to the
state-by-state regulations and that
doesn't even account for the differences
between Canada and Europe and everything
else so you know cannabis is a bit of a
difficult space to navigate so some
people want to Outsource that
responsibility that's how that got
started and they've just been able to
get out building it out from there
amazing yeah it's great to see the
position you're taking and the audience
of influence that you're guttering in
the industry the topic of this episode
is basically how to invest in cannabis
and I just want to kind of maybe give
everybody a quick little overview of a
couple of different ways and models and
methods that regular people can get into
investment in cannabis stocks because it
is definitely a medium to long term play
that everybody should look at it if
they're if you're interested in this
industry so first and foremost what
platform would you use to invest in kind
of the stocks or to purchase kind of the
stocks is there a specific cannabis
based one or is just a regular platform
that investors use yeah so it's a little
bit tricky
um there's a Nuance where the U.S
cannabis the plant touching businesses
can't trade on things like the New York
Stock Exchange and the NASDAQ and so the
U.S companies go public in Canada that
have dual listings on the OTC exchange
so if you want to invest in U.S plant
touching operators names like I
mentioned earlier Green Thumb Industries
are care Leaf which I think are some of
the most compelling opportunities you
need to have a brokerage account that
allows you to a allow access to access
OTC names or B or and B allows you to
access cannabis stocks and so one easy
solution for that is Fidelity and that's
what I use for a lot of things that I do
there are other platforms out there like
Robinhood which is a big retail platform
in the US and they don't allow purchase
of these OTC cannabis stocks so it's
really a broker by broker decision I
think partially based of what they see
is the demand and partially some still
see some regulatory risk you know we
hope to get safe banking last fall that
didn't happen and I think until we get
safe banking or descheduling or
rescheduling some of these brokerage
platforms and custody platforms are
still going to be a little bit nervous
about cannabis stocks
on top of that you could buy the OTC
names like I mentioned but there's also
great options for ETFs what we hear a
lot about is like the msos ETF which is
the largest ETF in the industry that
provides access to U.S uh it basically
broad access almost indexed like it's
not an index but it's index index like
exposure to U.S cannabis stocks I also
personally invest the ETF the Poseidon
Dynamic opportunities ETF which has to
Ticker psdn and I like that one because
I think it has a little bit more
experience team on the Cannabis side and
a more focused portfolio and the ETFs
use swaps to get access to the OTC names
so because they don't actually hold
those underlying names they can be
listed on the higher exchanges so things
like the ticker msos and the ticker psdn
you are able to buy on more platforms
than you can the actual underlying
individual names like a GTI or tier leaf
okay amazing great information so let's
say somebody realizes that they found
the platform that they want to be able
to invest in how do you specifically
pick your strategy towards acquiring
specific stocks is it cash balance sheet
is it assets that they own is it future
earnings that you think that's going to
come in the door is there is there a
couple of different parameters that you
would set that all investors should be
using these one or two different or one
or two three different parameters to
judge what to uh purchase or is it
basically just research research
research yeah it's a little bit of all
of the above but I always think of
cannabis first and foremost it's a
state-led growth story and when I say
that I mean we have 21 adult use States
today so that leaves us 29 more to go
and each state has its own regulations
which can be complicated and pretty
specific to that environment so you have
States like New Jersey which are
excellent States for The multi-state
Operators High margins limited number of
stores limited number of licenses cure
Leaf as a store in Belmar New Jersey
that's on track to do 72 million dollars
in sales this year so there are huge
stores in New Jersey New Jersey is a
great environment so you want to get as
much exposure to those limited license
States especially ones that just moved
from medical to adult use you contrast
that with where I live which is in
California and California is a very
challenging state for for cannabis
operators we don't have enough stores we
have too many cultivation licenses
there's a mismatch between supply and
demand we have about a thousand stores
here today we need closer to five but
ten thousand to be healthy and so when
you're looking at investing
you could have a great big great
business and a great idea like glass
house Brands however if you put them in
the most challenging environment in the
US it still is going to be difficult for
that stock on the flip side you want so
you have States like California which I
don't make dedicated investments in but
usually with these multi-state operators
you know let's keep talking about you
know Green Thumb for example if you want
to get exposure to New Jersey which they
have you have to take some other states
along the way so those bigger Blue Chip
names are offered in five or ten
different states and if you want New
Jersey maybe you have to take in Arizona
with it which is more challenging or
Massachusetts which is more challenging
or Michigan which is more challenging or
California which is more challenging so
it's about understanding where those
exposures are at a state-by-state basis
and investing on what you think are
going to be the best environments so
that's number one is focus on the states
number two is you have to understand the
climate that we're in today if we got
safe and lending opened up an investment
opened up then I would say it may make
sense to dip into some of the smaller
operators with more debt late and
balance sheets however we didn't get get
safe we're probably in a recession in
the U.S and interest rates are really
high
so under those conditions I always think
back to a conversation I had with the
CEO of Ascend Wellness Abner Curtin who
said it's not about finding the stocks
right now that'll go up 200 percent
rather than 150 percent it's about
avoiding the ones that are going to go
to zero and I I think about that almost
every day because in this environment
there's so much opportunity in cannabis
because the prices are so depressed and
we have this series of catalysts ahead
of us but you need to be in the ones
that can survive today and Thrive
tomorrow so on top of that
state-by-state component I would focus
on stocks that have scale I would be
focused on stocks that have strong
balance sheets without too much debt I
would be mindful of near-term maturities
because it may be hard to refinance
those in an environment like 2023 and I
would look for look for businesses or
multi-state operators that have exposure
to expanding markets so Connecticut's
just turning on New York is just turning
on Rhode Island is just turning on we
have Maryland and Missouri turning on
later this year so in today's
environment I think it makes more sense
to be a bit more conservative focus on
the more Blue Chip names with the more
sound balance sheets but do that being
mindful of what states you're in and
also trying to get exposure to new
states that are opening because newer
States typically have greater margins
and more Revenue per store when they
first open
okay incredible wealth of information
there do you see a market at the moment
do you actually first and foremost do
you think that New York is ever going to
catch up with California in terms of
size of Mark of course California always
going to be the state's leading state in
America
um I think that demand wise it could be
right there you know New York is a big
state has a lot of uh you know cannabis
consultant culture and consumption over
the years so I think New York will be a
strong State I think from a cultivation
perspective California's climate is just
so much better that you know people will
argue about this California I think will
still be the leader in terms of
innovation and quality in cannabis and
maybe one day we ex we export stuff to
New York you know if we ever get into
interstate commerce I think that's
probably going to be a big thing because
if you go to these illegal bodegas in
New York they all feature California
products because that that's ultimately
what consumers want
um so I think New York is a good
opportunity the initial regulations
don't look super favorable tooth
multi-fit operators in that they can't
open their first adult use store until
three years after any adult use store is
open so they're essentially giving the
social Equity operators a big head start
there probably a decent cultivation and
wholesale opportunity to feed those
social Equity stores but I think that
broadly speaking that's the initial
regulations have not been real favorable
for the msos and so I think that the
people that have assets there like your
Crest goes like your care Leafs
um I think they've been a little bit
disappointed in the initial drafts but
maybe those things will change otherwise
it just may take a few years for that to
be a real profitable Market
okay very interesting do you see a
market for things like distressed assets
because with the uncertainty in America
do you think that there's actually a
position to to to acquire distress
assets and and uh and for that to be a
workable option
I think it is but you have to think
about why is it distressed and so if
you're in a state like Michigan with too
much cultivation and you have and you
are a grower in Michigan and you're
losing money and it's really cheap to
buy it well you might just buy it and
keep losing money and so I think you
need to be careful about which
distressed assets that you're buying I
think that cultivation in and of itself
is not a very interesting thing to buy
these days I think retail is more
interesting or even better is vertical
integration where you pair the retail
with the manufacturing and distribution
and the cultivation because they have
higher margins and that gives you
greater control the supply chain so I
think there are select distress
opportunities but you also ask have to
ask who has the money these days right
um in this environment where you don't
want to do an equity raise because their
share prices are so low and the cost of
capital has got so high like glass house
Brands did a race a preferred deal that
was 20 to 25 interest rates with a
couple of warrants so need to be a
borrow money at 20 to acquire distressed
stuff 80 that's a high cost of capital
and B I think you want to be real
selective that uh in terms of which
Assets in which you would invest
yeah very good one of the things I
wanted to mention was green Giants and I
had come across and I think it's been a
great wealth of uh knowledge and
information you want to give maybe a
quick little overview of green joints
yeah that's a website I started um I
guess about a year and a half ago and
initially it had a it had a feature
where you could uh there was a premium
service we could pay for portfolio
positions and trade updates
ultimately the payment provider canceled
that option because they didn't want
people paying for cannabis related
content which makes no sense right I'm
not selling cannabis I was selling
information about cannabis stocks but
that's the world we live in with
cannabis so that that feature went away
and now I just treat it as a place to
share things that I write and share
interviews that I do so there's about 60
different articles there and lately I've
been doing a bunch of uh interviews with
different investment managers in the
space and different operators in the
space and so it's free to subscribe
people can check it out and if you want
to you'll learn about the inductive
cannabis that's really what it's for
highly recommend everybody checking it
out and going to visit at the website
the last thing I wanted to touch on
Before I Let You Go is do you see as a
North American investor value in
European cannabis stocks at the moment
are you still a number of years away
from taking a position
yeah I think Europe is definitely
interesting especially as the
diversifier
um I think expectations may be a little
bit High because the one thing I've seen
over and over in cannabis is things take
longer than we expect and so there's a
lot of optimism around Germany I
recently sat in on the call with a
couple of German experts and they were
50 50 at whether we would see sales in
24. so if not 24 for sure 25 so if
Germany turns on in the next year or two
I think that sounds like a pretty
interesting opportunity and just like we
see in the U.S when one state turns on
offing the neighboring states do as well
so I think we could see that uh in
Europe as well if Germany Falls then you
know we we might see other you know uh
countries across Europe turn on as well
so yes I think Germany is definitely an
interesting opportunity in and of itself
but also a great way to to complement a
us-based portfolio so if you own some of
the big msos or a few of the single
state operators go ahead and add some
European exposure to diversify just like
in normal stocks a global portfolio is
often better than just the us only
portfolio higher risk adjusted returns
more opportunity less volatility I think
those same conditions apply to cannabis
stocks and so I've mentioned Cura Leaf
earlier and they're one of the few U.S
msos that's really dedicating themselves
to Europe they do have a German business
that they Acquired and so you could get
that through someone like your Leaf
otherwise if you want to hunt around for
specific opportunities in Europe I think
that's definitely a good idea
yeah for sure I think Europe is going to
lead more biotechnology and biosynthesis
cannabinoids than actual cultivation
because the industry is just set up
completely over here for that to be able
to be facilitated it's been phenomenal
talking to you I couldn't recommend
everybody checking out green Giants and
following uh Jesse on Twitter at Jesse
Redmond and very much appreciate it
Jesse thank you very much and hope that
we can touch base towards the middle of
the end of the year and get an update
and see where the stock positions are
that sounds great this was fun thank you
for having me thank you very much guys
until next episode