foreign
thanks for having me Owen how are you
I'm very well thank you very much for
taking your time to do this I know
you're a very busy lady do you maybe
want to give everybody a quick little
overview of how you ended up at flower
higher and your position in the sector
at the moment
absolutely so I actually this is my kind
of my my act two of my career um I spent
a lot of time as an education executive
in the beauty and wellness industry and
you know really felt like that was going
to be my career full stop and then
during the pandemic when everything kind
of changed around and I lost that career
I was laid off from um the job that I
thought that I was going to have forever
it was a moment for me to really think
about what I wanted to do with the
second half of my career and really do
something that was doing good for people
and also to be part of something that
was growing and dynamic and full of
potential and
what's in Innovation so automatically I
thought about going into cannabis I have
a lot of respect for the plant and
actually came to flowerhire as a
candidate to see if they would help me
find the job and you know as I was
speaking to the recruiters you know we
really clicked and they said hey why
don't you be a recruiter and so you know
the rest as they say is history it
wasn't something that I set out looking
to do but you know the the Stars aligned
and I met the right people and now you
know I've never looked back it was the
best choice I ever made
I'm delighted to hear that's the world
words it was in mysterious ways
and jumping on to the first topic of
conversation is how to recruit talent in
cannabis obviously if people are looking
for jobs There's jobs boards and
companies out there but if you've got a
specific Talent uh that works in an
overall business first of all how do you
guys find the talent and second of all
how did the companies reach you guys
looking for the talent
great question Owen so I think first if
we talk about the candidate side if we
talk about people who are looking to
work in the industry there's two camps
right there are people who have worked
in the industry before and who are now
looking for their second or third
um home within the industry because as
the market is growing and shifting and
all of those things you know we do see a
lot of movement from within uh different
cannabis operators
um and then you've also got people who
like myself two years ago are making
that initial pivot into cannabis so if
we're talking about the second group
right so someone who has never worked in
cannabis before and who now wants to get
into the industry
um there's a lot of things that you know
we always say for job seekers in general
right you know activate your network
make sure that your LinkedIn looks good
all of those things but specifically if
you're trying to get into the industry
um I suggest that people really take a
look and create a a resume that is
specifically tailored toward cannabis
and I say that because sometimes the
transferable skills that are really
going to stand out to cannabis companies
are different than what they're used to
putting on their resume
so um for example um anything that has
to do with working in regular regulated
environments anything has to do with a
lot of dealing with compliance that is
something that is really heavily valued
in cannabis and you should probably
highlight on your resume and if you have
experience in startup organizations or
any type of startup industry that is
also really highly valued because it
shows your ability to be adaptable and
Nimble in a work environment that's
super Dynamic and sometimes can be
unpredictable
um so yes I would say you know do create
a cannabis facing uh resume one of the
tools I like to tell people to use is
there is a website called careers
incannabis.com and there's actually a
free Resume Builder on there that is
catered to the Cannabis industry and
highlights those specific skills that
the hiring managers are looking for it's
a great starting place for anyone who
kind of doesn't know where to start so
that's a that's the first place that
they can go to
okay interesting and when it comes to
looking for the talent at the moment is
it
what is the most sought after Talent is
it economical expertise obviously the
wave of llms and AI technology that's
out there that is at python coders is it
Executives who've already worked in
business development and are not
matching over or is it legal expertise
where do you see the most sought after
Talent being in the Cannabis industry at
the moment it is all of the above and
more and you know that's what I think is
so exciting about recruiting within
cannabis if you think about these
vertically integrated organizations you
are not going to see the breadth and the
diversity of talent that these companies
need in any other industry right if you
think about a a vertically integrated
multi-state operator they are hiring
anyone from plant Tremors you know
hourly workers who are working in the
grow to directors of marketing to heads
of Finance to c-suite I mean they they
literally are building everything from
scratch so I think any type of talent is
always going to be applicable in term
terms of coming into the industry at the
moment you know with the state of the
market as it is it's a very it's an
employer's market right because there's
more
um there's probably right now more
experienced cannabis professionals on
the market looking for new jobs than
ever before so if you are you know
looking to build a team Now is really
the time to do it because there's a lot
of folks who are looking for work and
you're going to have you know a range of
really great people to choose from as
opposed to in other times when you know
you go out you're trying to hire people
and everyone's already
um in a job you know so right now I
would say the the most demand that we're
seeing is uh Finance and Accounting I
think that those roles are always things
that um will always be we have a need
for specifically people who have
experience in manufacturing cost
accounting and Retail Finance and
planning and Analysis those are always
really hot jobs and then of course
anything that's touching the production
side so manufacturing operations
managers
um inventory procurement all of those
things I think are always going to be
very much in in demand
is there a specific state or territory
that's the hot spot for a job at the
moment in the industry obviously we
don't have Federal legalization yet but
I would imagine New York has a a thirst
for a lot of the top kind of talent in
the industry is the ice
it's funny you say that because like
literally on my other screen I have a
big spreadsheet of like all my New York
talent because yes absolutely there's a
lot of um a lot of movement in New York
and we are starting to see
um the demand for hiring Talent there
especially on the retail and revenue
side because in New York they're they're
opening up a lot of new dispensaries so
they're looking for people who have
really strong retail sales marketing
experience to drive Revenue in those uh
you know retail dispensary outlets now
at the same time you're also seeing a
lot of demand in the Emerging Markets of
the southeast United States which is
super interesting because even a year a
year and a half ago like those states
were not even on our radar so I'm
talking about Arkansas Louisiana
Mississippi Missouri has has really done
well and and that market has really
blown up in a big way so the southeast
quadrant of the United States being
these emerging newly
um you know newly open markets there
they have a lot of demand for talent as
well
and moving on to the next topic now I
wanted to talk about was what makes a
good candidate obviously from hot people
myself or other companies that I own it
it try to find the right candidate never
mind in cannabis is is difficult to know
if we add in the Cannabis factor it's do
you know about the plant are you happy
with that they're more business
orientated do you find the odd unicorns
who you can marry both of those skills
oh man when we find a unicorn
yeah
it's a great question I think of course
with every client we work with with
every hiring company they have their you
know their idiosyncrasies and their
specific things that they look for but
that being said I think across the board
people who do well in cannabis tend to
be a combination of a few things number
one we're always looking for people who
have a good cannabis story right I think
cannabis right now because it is so
um it's it's it's highly
um
it's portrayed in the media as a very
fast-growing industry and a place where
you can make money yes absolutely true
so we want to make sure that the people
who want to get into the industry are
entering for the right reasons because
if you apply in cannabis thinking you're
going to get rich quick and that's the
only motivation you have guess what
that's not going to cut it because
you're going to come in here and see
like how hard the work is and say this
is not what I signed up for right so as
cannabis recruiters what we always look
for is try to dig down and find out what
is the motivation for this person
entering the com entering the industry
is it because they themselves are
consumers and they have felt like the
plant has made a positive impact in
their lives and they want to give back
that's something we hear a lot but it's
not you know required not everyone is a
consumer
um maybe it's someone who had had
someone close to them had who that
benefited from the plant from a medical
or Wellness standpoint
um and then there's also people who are
just really love startup you know maybe
they went through the.com thing and they
want that that kind of excitement again
and they know that they can find that in
cannabis so you know there's there's a
range of things but having a good
cannabis story is probably one of the
most important beyond that and of course
like I mentioned before people who are
Nimble people who are ready to kind of
work in this very hectic
um environment there's also some
personality things that we find tend to
be common denominators right with people
who are successful in cannabis so I'm
talking about people who are inquisitive
you know when you work in this industry
you can't just put yourself in a box and
only want to know about your specific
work because everything is connected and
so if you are a person who is naturally
curious about learning the other aspects
of the industry you will do better in in
cannabis another thing is
we look for people who are
um resilient right because sometimes you
go through changes and you know crazy
challenges that
we're at a person who was not cut out
for this work they would throw in the
towel they would say oh man this place
is crazy I'm out of here right but a
resilient person will say hey this is a
challenge how can we work around it and
how can we get better so that's a big
thing too and then we also like to say
a little bit crazy you know I think
sometimes people who have that little
touch of uh wackiness in them tend to do
well in this industry as well because
you have to really be prepared to
interact with all walks of life every
kind of person you can think of from the
most you know white collar corporate
person to you know someone who spent
half of their life in prison you know
due to the plants so literally someone
who has that you know that personality
that can really get along with just
about everyone is is also very helpful
yeah I've noticed in over two years of
dude this podcast has started out
originally is just Gathering data about
the various sectors in the industry
because if you're investing or being an
entrepreneur you need to know all the
facets and over 200 episodes and two
years later there's a new sector that's
popping up for a new law that's popping
up and I think got a degree in chemistry
biology cultivation the the lab testing
there's so many facets of this industry
that one actually has to be a breath
with you can just necessarily have a
narrow focus on trying to find those
people is to is the job that people like
yourselves are on the home to do
it's hard work but we're happy to do it
and tell me this what are your forecasts
for the next 12 to 24 months in the U.S
do you see safe banking or federal
legalization open up because um I would
imagine that's going to create a wave of
M A activity which in then will drive
skill sets from current sectors that
aren't necessarily in cannabis at the
moment but one bedroom realization comes
I would imagine the pool of talent
that's going to come into cannabis has
gone a pretty significant
well I believe that everyone is kind of
holding their breath and waiting for
that you know kind of like golden moment
right when when safe banking is passed
and and federal legalization but
honestly I don't know if that's
something that's right around the corner
I think there's still a lot of back and
forth on that and we'll get close and
then it won't happen and then it's like
two steps forward and three steps back
it's it's frustrating but you know we
all knew that that's what we signed up
for right so some of the things that we
are predicting is number one you are
going to see a migration of talent
across the United States you know you're
thinking about those mature markets like
California Colorado you know where they
have had a bustling industry for many
years the those emerging markets that I
talked about are going to be importing
Talent from those States because they
need the people with expertise and in
the local markets those people don't
exist so number one you're definitely
going to see a lot of people physically
moving cross-country to uh go to these
new markets
um I think also you mentioned New York
earlier I think New York will be a game
changer in terms of what the future of
the industry looks like you know New
York is the the financial center and the
cultural center of the United States if
not you know most of the western world
so I think the way that they handle
their market and legalization will be
um kind of like an example of what it
could look like for other states because
it's so different from California in
terms of the way that they do business
and the way that they're creating
businesses they have a a heavier focus
on social Equity programs which is also
great to benefit communities that have
been disproportionately negative
affected by the War on Drugs so that's
one thing definitely to keep an eye on
you know keep an eye on New York
um and then also I think we're also
going to see a maturing of the Cannabis
industry and turbos of from a corporate
standpoint I mean this is not this is a
very not sexy thing to talk about but as
a a recruiter it's something that we
think about a lot
um as these companies are growing and
maturing you're going to see them have
more of a robust HR infrastructure which
means when you come into the industry
you're not going to be working with like
some ragtag group and you know working
with the bare minimum you're going to
see more recent resources available to
you when it comes to benefits and
insurance and Health Plan you know all
of these things that you need resources
to offer we're starting to see more of
that in companies offering as well so
that's great news
yeah the maturity of the industry is
going to bring in all the regulation
benefits at the Banking and Financial
sector and other many other big sectors
do employ for our time now it's been
absolutely fantastic talking to you for
anybody looking for more information
flower hire their website is below and
it'll be in the description of where
you're watching or listening to this but
for now Aisha thank you very much for
your time today it's very much
appreciated
thank you very much it's been an
absolute pleasure and yeah happy to hear
from anyone if you are looking for a job
in cannabis or if you're looking to
build a team in cannabis myself and my
team at flowerhire are here and ready
until next episode everybody thanks
[Music]