[Music]
welcome to another episode of the
cannabis review
i am delighted to be joined on this show
by dr emmanuel
o'ninevy he is a professor at a william
patterson university
in new jersey how are you keeping them
manuel
fine we discovered coveted life that we
are all getting used to
i got my two vaccines already okay
you're one of the lucky ones now you'll
be on a
foreign holiday some sunshine for
yourself soon in fact i'm giving a
seminar
in puerto vallarta in mexico on the
international
behavioral neuroscience society and of
course my symposium would follow that
from japan from mexico and from spain
we are all going to be talking about the
advances in
the especially the exhibit to receptor
research
well that's i'm delighted to have you on
the show to talk about these topics
do you want to give people briefly uh a
little overview on your work in the
cannabis industry so far
and how you ended up in william
patterson university
it's a long story but i'll try to cut it
short so i finished my phd from the
university of bradford in england in
neuropharmacology
i moved directly to the united states to
do my postdoctoral fellowship
in that in the laboratory of the very
prominent scientist his name is dr
billy martin of unfortunately he's
diseased
and we worked especially on the
cannabinoid system
and for 30 years now i've been hooked on
this cannabinoid system research
and it has led to a number of numerous
discoveries not just by my group
but by others i've worked with in the
past including
the cloning of the cb1 receptors the
identification
of different systems that are involved
in the effect of cannabis that has shed
a lot of light
in the mechanism of action of cannabis
and the fact that the body the human
body makes its own natural
marijuana-like substances that are
called endocannabinoids
and i would um and um
i would and during this presentation i
will make more
addition to this endocannabinoid system
brilliant i'm delighted to have you on
the show as i said i've done research on
your work so far and as i said you're
one of the gentlemen that i've been
looking forward to chatting to
uh by having the show so i'm basically
gonna get i just wanna ask you a quick
question before we kick off
over in ireland we had this uh lobbying
group who are
anti-um cannabis who basically came out
saying that cannabis is the biggest
danger
to children's mental health of the next
10 years do you think this is a rubbish
statement
somebody with the level of education
that you have
it's a very good question because yes
why marijuana
the science as you are going to hear me
talk about today
and has exploded and we have significant
new knowledge
and some of these myths and stigma that
still revolve around marijuana because
of prejudice and prohibition
that cautionary statement is correct
and that is children should not be
exposed or pregnant women should not be
exposed to cannabis
why because the brain is still
developing but for adult use
the current explosion of cannabis use
across the globe
and it is very important for those
advocates to know that no one
anymore can stop the use of cannabis as
medicine
and as recreational use however
you must also add that this is not for
children
because their brain is still developing
this is not for pregnant women
at this time but but paradoxically i
will show you
that even in the the the marijuana
system
or the cannabis system called
endocannabinoids is
intricately involved in reproduction is
intricately involved in growth of the
newborn
and therefore this current knowledge new
knowledge
allows there's no medicine without side
effect so it allows the use
of cannabis but with stipulation that
this is not for
for children and this is not for
pregnant women
okay brilliant thank you very much for
clearing that up can you tell the
audience a little bit about the
advantages in cannabis research
things seem to be going on leaps and
bounds as new or indeed happens
in the industry so as somebody's at the
tip of the sphere of this sector
what would you see is the new advances
that we can look forward to seeing
there's a lot of advances in fact is
explosive
the reason for this is that this
advances in cannabis research had lagged
behind
other natural abuse drugs like morphine
like cocaine like tobacco
because of years years of prejudice and
prohibition
now there has been an explosion as we
said earlier
of new knowledge on cannabis research
and it has been transformed
into mainstream science not just
mainstream science but also in main
street
and the stigma is being shared as i
mentioned earlier at breathtaking speed
this new knowledge these new advances
include one
the decoding of the cannabis plant
genome with
the coding of the cannabis plant genome
what that means is that you can now be
able to
to to cultivate cannabis depending on
what you want to use it for
of course i'll talk a little bit about
cbd also
the second major discovery apart from
the human genome that is also been
decoded and mapped
the next major discovery which is almost
10 years old now or more
is the discovery of that the human body
makes its own
natural cannabis-like substances that
are referred to as
endocannabinoids first discovered in
israel
and undermined was first of these
substances discovered
and undermined is a sanskrit word
meaning eternal beliefs
and furthermore two ag two arachidonic
glycerol another
cannabis-like substance was also
discovered in the human body
and it became very clear that there is
no cell in your body
there is no system in the human biology
that does not
involve this natural endocannabinoid
system
even um even you and me
so let me give you the first example one
during fertilization
for the sperm to fertilize the egg you
require this
natural endocannabinoid to pierce
through the egg
and fertilize the egg once that egg is
fertilized
that egg travels through the fallopian
tube and anchors in the uterus
and the cell starts to divide in biology
for that cell to implant an
anchor in the uterus you require this
natural
marijuana-like substances this
endocannabinoids okay
at that critical time as i mentioned
already during implantation
if a woman smokes marijuana there might
be
the propensity for miscarriage so what
i'm telling you right now is that an
appropriate level a balanced level a
homeostatic level of this natural
marijuana-like substances
is very important for appropriate
pregnancy for you to be born or for me
to be born
and when that baby is finally born guess
what
the breast milk is now loaded
with this natural cannabis-like
substances to do what
to give the baby appetite appetite to
feed and grow
in summary what i just told you is that
this new discovery of this
endocannabinoids that is
important and involving all types of
cellular components is very very
important
yes please continue
do you want more the cloning cannot be
no receptors you can go
to that next yeah hit us up
right so the next one in terms of
cannabinoid receptors is the cloning
and the characterizations of cannabinoid
receptors this is another significant
advancement because
it became clear that the receptors that
are activated that are turned on by this
cannabis-like substances and the
exogenous the marijuana-like substances
because the marijuana-like substances
include
i mean cannabis-like substance you can
exchange exchange the two the
cannabinoid
the cannabis plant contains over
a hundred let's just put it over a
hundred chemicals including the terpenes
including the flavonoids and this has
been
now well studied because the major
psychoactive
component of cannabis is called thc they
are called cannabinoids
and that is why the one made by the
human body is called endocannabinoids
and then many of these compounds have
been characterized and classified
including cbd
cbd is referred to as cannabidiol which
is now gaining a lot of attention across
the globe
however these receptors the major ones
that have been characterized so fast
referred to as cb1
cannabinol receptors it turned out that
the cb1 cannabinoid receptors is the
most
abundant binding site the most
abundant protein producing the human
brain and testis and the uterus
and therefore they play very significant
physiological role
what has been controversial was the
discovery of the cb2 where i became very
prominent
the cb2 receptor was pre previously
cloned
by monroe in england and when they
cloned the cb2 cannabinoid receptors
it was not found in the brain and
therefore
it for many years it was thought that it
was not in neurons
neurons in the brain but here was my
major discovery that yes
this cb2 receptors is also in neurons
and it's also in microglial cells the
immune cells of the brain
and therefore this has changed now that
controversy that cannot be not
controversy
and this is why i'm very happy to be
involved in any type of controversy at
all in the globe especially if you
consider that you are correct otherwise
one more point about cannabinoid
receptors because there are many now
that we are discovering they are called
them
putative cannabinoid receptors perhaps
there will be cb3c4 cb5
but between the cb1 and cb2 they are
subtypes
subtypes of cannabinoid receptor one a
one b one c
one d depending on the species depending
on which animal
and the cp2 also in mice and humans that
we use for
studies is also cb1a and cb1d
and for that characterization one more
advancement that is surprising to me is
that you know yeast
right yeast is used to make bread right
yeast is used to make beer that a lot of
people like to consume
guess what now years can be used to make
to genetically engineer cannabinoids for
cannabis based medicine for the future
that's another significant advancement
an exciting science actually
wow amazing wealth full of information
so far yeah we're meant to do 15 minutes
of a funny feeling we'll be going longer
than this with you
i think we'll move on to the next topic
is basically something that i'm sure a
lot of people think they know about
but how does cannabis affect our bodies
this is a very good and this is this is
one of the significant
advances that has led for cannabis now
that has unraveled
our eyes for cannabis to be used not
just for medicine
but also for recreation medically
as i said there's no part of the human
biology and physiology that does not
have this cannabis system
this endocannabinoid system and
therefore when the level is too high
or too low especially in psychiatric
issues you can see the involvement of
this system
whether it is too low or too high that
the it needs to be
brought to a homeostatic level and
therefore you can see that there's a lot
a lot of application in the way it
affects the human body for medicinal use
whether it is for anxiety whether it is
for
depression for example and one of the
other
major issues and the discovery is the
what we call mix
and stigma that surrounds the use of
cannabis
one prominent one is the fact that men
that who use marijuana or who use
cannabis bound to stick with cannabis
they have low sperm count what we now
know
anecdotally and from many other
scientific research in the united states
is that actually sperm count is
increased
in men that use cannabis and i just went
over also how
fundamentally it is very involved in
reproduction in our bodies reproduction
between the sperm
is called acrosome reaction in the body
when the sperm fertilizes the egg as i
said
earlier it is called acrosome reaction
the head of the sperm
the sperm is carrying like a helmet and
then when it pierces through the egg
it's faster like it it delivers the
genetic material
from the sperm to the egg
and then that fusion that fertilization
when it occurs
indicates the the undeniable
use of canna of cannabis for
reproduction by the human body
and that is why when there is some
homostatic imbalance homeostatic
imbalance
then there could be miscarriage there
are other
uses including bone for example in bone
health
including um skin and now as you're
going to see
in the future the recreational use is
beyond anyone to stop
especially i think maybe this is the
most important component
in the legalization for recreational use
as well as
as well as medicinal use one
there will be a quality control
in canada the whole of canada marijuana
is now legal
even in in the in supermarkets
where you can go to get whatever type of
cannabis because there are different
types right there are different types of
cannabis
it cannot be sativa they cannot be
syndica and they are subspecies
so so the care that is important is that
when there is quality control
then you cannot just be using cannabis
that is illegal
because if you go out to the streets to
just get any type of cannabis now
you don't know what is left with it what
is accompanying that cannabis
so that means the regulation and the
quality control is very important
for the medicinal as well as
recreational use
one other example is that there's
something called epileptic cesius in
children
in epileptic cesius there's the dravet
syndrome
the linux dash test syndrome and in this
syndrome in children two years old
the united states of america the fda has
approved epidiolex
or the cbd in particular for the use in
childhood epileptic seizures
yet the federal government of the united
states it is still illegal
to use cannabis and for anything
but different states now have now
legalized the use of cannabis
and recreationally about 33 or 36
and maybe about 11 or 12 inclusive
for recreational use so yes
cannabis is very very promiscuous
cannabis-like substances in the human
body is very promiscuous
mexico just also approved that
netherlands has been used in netherlands
for different purposes for many many
years over 40 years
and yet the whole world is now waking up
that this is real good medicine this
natural medicine
is important in all of our daily
function yeah
well i couldn't agree with you more it's
going to be a green wave that just
sweeps the globe over the course of time
so
i can't thank you enough for coming on
the show and sharing your knowledge and
wisdom with us
i'm sure everybody got a huge amount of
knowledge from that show as much
as i did i hope you have a great day
emmanuel and hopefully we can chat again
in the future and
uh see how things have progressed you
let me see this right
i will indeed of course okay thank you
very much thank you for having me on
your show
thank you very much emmanuel thanks
everybody until next time