[Music]
welcome to the cannabis review we've got
a great episode for you today i am
delighted to be joined by anand shahid
the president and the
chief investment officer for bar capital
how are you keeping today land
i'm doing really well thank you for
having me on it's a real pleasure
no absolutely pleasure to have you on
i'm hope you're gonna shine some great
insights into the few of the questions
that i've got for you do you want to
basically give everybody a little
background on
what bar capital are doing in the
industry and how you got into the
cannabis sector
sure absolutely so i'll start with my
background i'm a finance person to the
bone
i've worked in various different
companies
uh in the financial industry here in the
us uh based out of new york
i've worked at firms like merrill lynch
morgan stanley i've done everything from
managing assets for high net worth
individuals to managing risk
uh for uh for morgan stanley um and
and in that period um as i was doing my
corporate career i was also in parallel
investing in
startups uh and small and micro cap
companies
in certain uh sectors what i realized as
i was doing
that is there's a lot of value when you
have a specialty
uh and you have a deep dive into a
vertical and
uh what what started to happen was i
realized that cannabis
was all of those things with a
completely
new and nascent industry where it could
be shaped
and you know knowing the right people
and connecting with the right folks and
investing in the right companies could
literally make an impact on people's
daily lives
and as a as a personal purpose you know
i made sure that
everybody who joins bar capital knows
that our purpose is to
make cannabis as culturally accepted
and common as aspirin or alcohol or
paracetamol and alcohol i guess in this
case uh and uh
and so that purpose drives me every
morning
i get up early i go to bed late night i
talk to people in europe
u.s china mexico i am very much looked
into what's happening
behind the scenes in particular and um
and so that's how var capital has come
around and we have been doing outreach
to europe
and i'm very glad to meet folks like
yourself
and and your program uh because we think
it's a global industry
uh that's going to only get bigger and
bigger as the years come by
right now okay perfect that kind of
gives everybody a little overview i'm
going to jump straight into the first
topic and i think it's
i'd love to get somebody like you to be
able to maybe clear some of the muddy
water so far
in terms of the overview of the kermit
the current investment landscape of the
world you've got
north america let's say the us have
state by state
only investment you can't invest across
or have companies compete across states
the the canadian companies seem to have
burned through so much money now that
it's
almost a fool's errand and
buyer beware when it comes to a canadian
llp an investment
europe seems to be technically leading
towards the medical side first and
foremost
how are you looking at in terms of
investment strategies for bar capital do
you have a separate
uh strategy for europe that you do for
north america or do you see it all
assimilating into one industry over time
that's a great question you know there
this this industry is so fractured you
know
if you're in new jersey uh as a company
involved in cannabis or massachusetts
here in the united states or any of
these individual states
you might as well be in europe if you're
trying to interact with another company
right you can't cross the border
and so what that creates is um some
unique
investment opportunities that are
interstate plays or in you know
geographical
plays but what we focus on is the
scalable businesses and the brands
so we wrote a short white paper and a
year ago actually when covid was hitting
and the cannabis industry was in a lot
of trouble and you know
a lot of stocks have kind of crashed and
we had other issues from before that but
we wrote a paper called the bold shall
conquer cannabis
and what we argued for was that you you
want to focus on businesses that can
be effective in new jersey or ireland or
uk or wherever
and be able to scale at a very fast
level
and become a global presence and so that
involves a few key aspects number one is
you have to have the
right kind of management and the right
kind of uh vision
uh number two is you need connectivity
in relationships that's where bar
capital comes in you know we we do
help uh uh we invest in we advise and we
do help raise funding for
startups and and companies that are
growing in the cannabis space
but our consulting side and our
strategic advisory side
which is connected with players in the
in the uk as well and in europe as well
is all about supply chain and um and off
take agreements and connecting the right
kind of companies to each other
so that they can scale together and and
they can scale up into
uh geographies that uh you know they
haven't entered before
that's going to be pertinent in north
america especially in the u.s
it's going to be pertinent for
transatlantic um communications and
deals
uh and so we're we're really
differentiating ourselves on that front
because this
like i was saying before this is a
global story and people are not
understanding that
this is going to be ubiquitous in our
lives people are going to be taking
different cannabinoids uh different
formulations both for
medicinal purposes and for recreational
purposes and i'll give one quick example
you had a
relative who had surgery and was
prescribed opioids
and uh and i i suggested they get a
medicinal
uh cannabis license and use that instead
and then so they did they were able to
get that uh prior to the surgery they
used it
afterwards and potentially avoided an
addiction to opioids you know and then
that's the kind of
difference that's already been made in
in places where
it is legalized okay that's a
a very concise and informative piece to
that uh
question the next one is a pretty
straightforward question but a difficult
answer i'm sure how do you spot a good
investment opportunity in the cannabis
industry
bearing in mind that there are so many
rules and regulations in different
territories and
everything is so much different in every
different uh territory that you're going
to want
or what's the best way for you to spot
an investment that's a great question
you know
it's um spotting a great investment is
like finding your future
partner right it's uh there's a first
date
and depending on how that goes you might
get a second date but
you you start to get a sense right away
if there is a click and the click comes
with management
and and how passionate they are about
what they're doing and sometimes it's
easy to tell because
their lives have been changed you know
their child might have had epileptic
epileptic fits all day long uh prior and
all medication had been tried and
nothing had worked and then cannabis
came along and made a difference in that
executive's life
and was able to shape how they wanted to
participate in the space
that's one example now there's other key
things we look for in management
which is can they handle the hockey
stick moment
can they handle a pivot in the business
because they were trying to build
a big capex project and instead now the
the market has shifted and they should
instead focus on on their brand and
launching products
that uh make more sense in the current
market what you'll see and you mentioned
this earlier in the canadian story is
a lot of companies went public too soon
because that was the only way
for them to get funded they weren't able
to create brands because the canadian
government is overly involved
and therefore they're going to suffer
and they're going to be you know
there's going to we're kind of shorting
that market uh
and looking at managers that short that
market
the u.s story is just beginning i mean
the multi-state operators are
very very attractively valued even today
we think legislation is going to change
and really change the landscape
but going back to the company and
spotting investments you you have to do
a set of due diligence you know getting
to know the family part of the dating
scenario
analogy i was giving you uh you know
making sure the values line
up making sure you know all of those
things check out and their backgrounds
are solid
but also getting a real sense for do
these folks have
legitimate backgrounds uh early days in
cannabis
there was a lot of black market
participants that you know moved the the
cannabis space to what it is today and
and helped it get legalized in a number
of geographies but they weren't
management they weren't you know quality
operators in the space
but what's shifted now is veterans from
other industries have entered and so we
also look for
uh folks that you know utilize that
talent pool that's coming in from pharma
from finance from the uh legal world and
that's
that that kind of dream team situation
is what we look for where
the pieces are lined up the messaging
the vision the mission
is is being talked about by each of
those members of the executive team
and when that happens it's it's you know
it's a it's a magical moment and then we
usually
then proceed with with getting to know
the company even deeper and making an
investment
okay brilliant i think it's definitely a
very exciting time at the us for sure i
think you've got a couple of the brands
we all know that at some stage you're
going to have a burger king and a
coca-cola
come out of the cannabis industry and
it's who gets to those investments now
is such i think
a great place to be in as as a us
investor as you are
which of the brands in the us do you see
being some of the dominant ones we all
know about cookies and
we know about the bangs and kill cliffs
who do you see kind of
rising to the top of the market when it
comes to the us and then maybe being a
global brand within time
so there's two parts of that you know
one part is
um the u.s is often laid to the story
and then buys its way in
and then tries to become a leader so in
that interaction
uh between the different geographies
right now
europe has the medicinal program and
it's got great um you know r
d and i p and um other talent and other
uh valuable assets uh even on the
cultivation front
um so so the us is going to continue
looking to do that i know of several of
the people
you're mentioning and other big names
that are actively doing that and then we
all of course see
you know deals like the cure leaf emac
deal uh recently
so there's certainly folks that are well
capitalized and they're going out
and laying out the footprint that they
need to to continue scaling
their brands however it's such a nascent
market
new entrants that find the right
connections and find the right capital
flow
and really have that brand focus can do
very very well
so i can't predict uh coca-cola or or
the burger king of the of the space yet
um certainly i think
several of the people who are already
doing quite well are going to continue
to
but uh i wouldn't i wouldn't be
surprised if a european brand emerges or
an asian brand emerges eventually
as we uh mature more and can then start
you know capitalizing going public and
getting a lot of capital behind their
own growth
uh for for the next three to five years
i see it being a very
us-dominate
world in terms of the brand if you have
a focus on california and germany for
example
and now mexico you're in very good shape
so i think those
key geographies will continue to play a
big role in brand development
but it's anybody's game still
okay brilliant that kind of leads me on
to the last topic that i wanted to talk
about and you're saying
one of the european brands are going to
do it we're betting on that ireland
is going to be one of the countries that
delivers one of these global brands
and i'd like to maybe in this little
segment convince you as to why
ireland is going to be the european hub
for global cannabis companies
um i'm sure you'd agree that a lot of
the investment opportunities and the m
a's that are happening some of the
london stock exchange stuff is exciting
industry so
i think a lot of the north american
companies are definitely going to
position themselves for a european entry
at some stage would you agree
absolutely you know i have a a special
place in my
heart for ireland um i i was born in
india when i was eight
i actually moved to ireland my parents
are doctors and they they worked there
and i lived there for six years
uh and and you know i was educated
partly in ireland and then came to the
us
um and i can say you know given where
ireland has positioned itself the only
english-speaking member right now
of the eu being known for its tax
benefits to
large corporations that have already
from other industries
utilize it as such it's a natural
natural
landing pad for the larger companies for
innovation
around this area for brand creation for
interaction with between the u.s and
eu um so i'm very excited i you know i
plan on making a business trip out there
and really getting a detailed sense of
of what the opportunities are but i
think you've already got a brand in that
space ireland already has a brand in
that space and so it's all about how do
you convert that
and how do you convince the regulators
to open up
more business around the cannabis space
and that by the way
is just a snowball effect happening
right now if you look at the us
and and you have any kind of doubt about
legalization in the u.s
just think of the fact that canada and
mexico are going to be legal federally
and the u.s is going to be sitting there
missing out on tax revenue dollars
in post covid everybody wants to address
deficits and
any kind of new source of revenue
generation is golden
so i i always you know people in the
industry complain that we get taxed too
much
i think it's a beautiful thing to get
taxed too much right now because
eventually
the as a lobbying continues as we go
towards legalization and beyond
everybody's then going to start looking
at tax efficiency and
ireland's going to be very much at the
nexus of that
yeah i couldn't agree with you more i
think there's going to be a lot of this
services will be based in ireland a lot
of the
kind of b2b business operations will be
based in ireland
granted there might be genetics in north
america but i'd still think it'll make
sense over time to have
greenhouses set up in ireland extraction
facility set up in ireland
logistic companies set up in ireland so
i think it's exciting future ahead for
ireland and north america and europe in
the next five to ten years and
hopefully we get to chat about this
again in the next few months and we've
got things to progress about
absolutely i hope your regulators in
ireland are watching
and they make a move in the right
direction and uh you know part of bar
capitals uh work is to promote and and
educate
people and and help find the right um uh
the right
ways to open up this market
perfect it's been an absolute pleasure
talking to you now and thank you very
much for coming on the show and i hope
you get to chat again very soon
thank you and thanks for having me it
was a pleasure here as well