[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined in this episode by john hudak who
who's the deputy director of the center
for effective public management and a
senior fellow in government studies at
the brookings institute how are you
keeping today john i'm doing well thank
you
thank you very much for joining us it's
very much appreciated
my pleasure
so a couple of topics i wanted to talk
to you about and maybe first and
foremost we'll get the audience up to
speed how did you get involved at the
brookings institute and what was your
first initial uh start in the cannabis
industry or covering the cannabis
industry should i say to be honest i
after i got out of graduate school or as
i was nearing the end of graduate school
i was expecting to go into a teaching
job at a university um and i got uh
someone reached out to me from brookings
uh they had an opening to see if i was
interested in applying um it uh
everything moved sort of quickly i i
didn't expect to be working at a think
tank ultimately uh but that was uh ten
years ago and and here i am still uh
still uh churning stuff out at brookings
uh in terms of how i started in cannabis
that was very accidental i actually had
a colleague who who recommended i um
take a look at some work that was being
done around polling in colorado and
washington before those two states
legalized cannabis and he said you know
you ask a lot of questions in your
research that might be applicable to
cannabis and i sort of laughed him out
of my office truth be told and uh
eventually i took a look at some of the
things he was sending me and i found the
topic really interesting and
launched a project in 2014 evaluating
colorado's implementation of their legal
cannabis system and and just kept
building it into a broader part of my
research
portfolio yeah for those who don't know
the brooking institute is one of the
most revered uh think tanks in the world
and when they release a paper on a topic
it generally moves the needle far more
than let's say some of the industry
experts so it was a great review of it
and then your book that you released in
2016 what was the reasoning behind that
you just developed a huge amount of
knowledge
yeah there was a there was a lot of uh
research going on if it wasn't being
tied together i think in a concise way
there were there were some books on on
cannabis that were very laser focused on
specific topics there were other ones
that were hundreds and hundreds of pages
long uh and brookings was actually
interested in uh putting together a
series of books that explained
short histories on a variety of policy
topics and they asked me if i'd be
interested in writing one on cannabis
and and i of course was uh and so what i
ended up putting together was a policy
history largely in the 1900s and 2000s
although some earlier
uh earlier dates appear in the book as
well
to explain the policy and political
history of cannabis largely in the
united states although there's a little
bit in there
about nations abroad that have dealt
with the issue uh and it and it serves
more as uh uh almost like a four dummies
book catch you up to speed on what's
gone on in cannabis policy over you know
150 year period uh and it's a light read
an easy read it's a beach read people
tell me um and so
obviously i recommend it
yeah everybody the link for the book
will be posted in the description below
you'll be able to click on it and buy it
directly and so the reason i wanted john
i wanted to kind of focus as much as i
can in ireland with your skill set
because you guys obviously no federal
legalization yet but there's some way
forward as to what an industry would
look like over in ireland we're still
stuck with a medical cannabis program
where even if a doctor prescribes it it
has to be okayed by a secondary
consultant who generally is over the age
of 65 70 and doesn't really understand
uh what they might be even remotely
talking about so what first up i wanted
to talk about was how cannabis emerged
from the shadows one of the types of
parts of your book so how did cannabis
emerge from the shadows in america what
was the first initial uh
pillar that got the industry out of the
open for everybody
you know over during the 1970s and 1980s
early 1980s in the united states
views on cannabis began to shift some
and you saw some states stepping up
to decriminalize cannabis that is to
make a cannabis crime the equivalent of
a speeding ticket or a parking ticket um
a few states moved forward with that
approach and
it was seen as a re-prior prioritization
of police dollars that is that there
were more important things for police
departments to deal with than low-level
cannabis offenses this was during a
period of um fairly high crime rates uh
in the united states particularly
violent crime rates um we went back into
a period of shadows when ronald reagan
became president and really began to um
re-uh reiterate the war on drugs uh in
the united states but ultimately the
years of
racial strife um police power
a real focus on on criminalization of a
lot of things including low-level drug
offenses
began to get displaced oddly enough by
the aids epidemic in the united states
and what you found was in some big
cities particularly in san francisco uh
but also in l.a in new york and
elsewhere
uh doctors and nurses and most
importantly patients were recognizing
that uh cannabis helped
with uh some of the side effects of the
pharmaceuticals early pharmaceuticals uh
being used to treat hiv and aids and uh
that began to put cracks in this system
where people were looking at cannabis as
something not as terrible as the
government was telling them it was and
something that might actually under
certain circumstances have medical
benefits uh and so began the path toward
reform starting really in the mid 1990s
in the united states and really
skyrocketing forward to today
okay so great little breakdown there so
what do you think of being the let's say
the two biggest benefits of cannabis
coming out into the main industry market
has it been revenue for the government
social equity programs patient access
what do you think if a politician from
ireland is looking at this wondering why
would we legalize it what are the kind
of two pillars that people would be
looking at going okay it's worth a room
so when i advise uh state and local
governments on on cannabis reform one of
the things i always tell them is to
discount the revenue that comes in um
it's never as much as people imagine
it's going to be it's a significant
amount of money no doubt
but it's important to set citizen
expectations about how much money that
will mean how much money it means
relative to the larger
municipal or state budget uh and and
certainly
uh
what that money will actually end up
doing in terms of dealing with budget
deficits or the ability to fund certain
programs the two areas that i think
though uh it is most impactful cannabis
reform
first is for patient care there are a
lot of patients in the united states who
will tell you that they benefit
significantly from the use of cannabis
whether it's for pain management whether
it's to deal with seizure disorders uh
whether it's to deal with a lack of
appetite for a variety of reasons for
most commonly associated with hiv aids
or chemotherapy treatments for cancer
etc
for some people it helps them sleep for
some people it helps them focus there's
a lot of
benefits either demonstrated through
government
regulatory processes or just anecdotally
from patients uh that they are getting
those types of benefits without
traditional pharmaceuticals some of
which particularly for pain management
come with significant risks uh and and
obviously uh risks for addiction
independence as well
the second uh area in which i think it
has a major impact in the united states
is in the criminal justice space uh the
idea that states are no longer arresting
individuals for low-level cannabis
offenses in mass numbers
is huge now one of the problems we've
had in the united states is that while
the number of arrests in a lot of states
that have legalized cannabis have
plummeted the racial disparities and the
remaining arrests remain
and so there's a lot of work to do in
the criminal justice space with regard
to
cannabis law enforcement
but ultimately we are arresting hundreds
of thousands of fewer people in states
that have legalized and that means a
different life trajectory for those
individuals who have been spared what
you know five ten fifteen years ago
would have landed them in jail
okay so two very good points for uh
we've got a a national day of action
over here in ireland on the 23rd of
august where
patients for safe access everybody's
joining at the department of health so
there seems to be a lot of steam coming
in the irish industry at the moment do
you guys look at the european sector at
all or do you just focus strictly on the
american uh industry
um there's a there's a pretty large
focus on uh the american uh industry and
advocacy space uh in policy space
there's so much going on here and
changing all the time it takes up a lot
of our time but you know i do think that
there are lessons to be learned
from the the european model
in particular especially with regard to
medical cannabis research medical
cannabis research has been stymied in
the united states because of ideological
reasons because of bureaucratic reasons
um and really for nonsensical reasons in
general um
research into
medical cannabis and and the efficacy of
medical cannabis for a variety of
conditions and diseases
has really uh
grown significantly in places like the
eu in israel and elsewhere where those
types of bureaucratic barriers are
reduced relative to the american model
and what i often tell uh policymakers in
the u.s is that europe is having our
lunch um we could be doing this type of
cutting-edge research but europe is
doing it for us and
it's it's a real problem but it
demonstrates that even in a
a peer government like the eu uh the u.s
doesn't have to be afraid of at least
allowing the freedom to uh conduct
research into this into the substance
and better understand what it will mean
for prospective patients
yeah and i think that's where europe at
the moment seems to be a little all over
the place when it comes to patient
access so we've got spain is legalized
in a medical cannabis program in the end
of december but it's still up in the air
as to is it specialists allowed to
prescribe it are they allowed to flower
whereas over in ireland you've got maybe
seven
like neuroplasticity and post chemo
nausea that are allowed on this but
again a consultant who has nothing to do
with the patient that the doctor has to
be the one to sign off and it creates
that extra barrier that how would you uh
when you you did your paper the report
on the medical marijuana mess um what
was that was that paper targeted at
health officials or was it a targeted on
a broader
consumer basis yeah it was targeted at
policy makers who work in the public
health sector as well as health uh
health care professionals as well um you
know you had mentioned at the outset of
the podcast that uh the secondary
consultants in ireland who need to sign
off on uh dr
doctor's prescriptions for cannabis are
oftentimes older practitioners that's a
problem we face in the united states as
well um you have entire classes of
doctors who went through medical school
being taught that cannabis is bad in all
circumstances it's hard to break people
out of that particularly older
practitioners who are more set in their
ways who have rigid ideologies about
these substances that's certainly not a
problem
uh that exists simply in ireland or uh
in europe but in uh but in the united
states and elsewhere around the world
particularly latin america as well
and so uh you know what i oftentimes uh
tell
individuals who are working to change
laws around medical cannabis is that yes
it's important to change the law that's
an important first step but you also
have to change the culture within uh
allied health professions to understand
the newest and latest
research on cannabis both in terms of
medical efficacy
but also in terms of the risks and side
effects of it or the lack thereof in
many cases
and to better understand what patient
needs are and what the risks of
alternative therapies therapy's
alternative to cannabis would mean and
that's particularly important in the
pain management space as i uh mentioned
where addiction and dependence issues
are significant
as well as overdose issues but it's true
in a variety of areas of medicine under
if you have a doctor coming to the table
who's not read up well on on medical
cannabis that doctor's not doing his or
her job and so part of
the reform around medical cannabis is
not just law and policy but it's in
medical education
at medical schools but also continuing
medical education for practicing uh
doctors and nurses
yeah there's a lot of talk about the
north american companies taking a
foothold in the european industry but
the one thing i actually see them
dominating hands down and having no
competition is the expertise coming over
here to educate the doctors on mass the
peter grimspoons of the world and coming
over here and and spreading their
knowledge and expertise i think is one
of the biggest monetization points for
the north american industry at the
moment as opposed to them all thinking
they can sell tons of flour in a market
that doesn't even have a solidified base
yet
yeah i think that's right and and what's
most important i think uh it's it's true
in the united states it's true abroad as
well um is that
individuals who are let's say new to
cannabis or or or considering thinking
differently about cannabis the messenger
for the information is critically
important they want to hear from doctors
they want to hear from nurses they want
to hear from phds they want to hear from
people in suits they're going to believe
people who look differently than their
imagined stereotype of a cannabis user
or a cannabis advocate
and here in the united states we have a
sort of mixed bag when it comes to the
way the individuals present themselves
while lobbying or advocating in other
settings
for medical cannabis or adult use
cannabis and what you see is that the
more professionalized that movement is
and the more professionalized that
movement appears the more likely
individuals will be receptive to that
message and so that's critical doctors
hearing from doctors uh and nurses about
their own experience uh clinically uh
can not be uh overmatched by you know uh
papers that they're reading in academic
journals or uh advocacy messages that
they're hearing that are more uh let's
say stereotypical in nature
yeah i couldn't agree with you anymore
and when i was doing my research i came
across myself saying this is one of the
most influential voices in american
cannabis and you haven't disappointed
her knowledge on it's been absolutely
amazing talking to you and hopefully we
get to talk again in 12 months time and
we can give you an update on what's
happening over here in europe but thank
you very much for now
thank you see you on our next episode
everybody