foreign
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review we're going to be
talking all things the world's best weed
on this episode and I'm delighted to be
joined in this episode by Nate Lando
who's a co-founder at snow till Inc
snotil uh that developed a unique
cultivation method that we're going to
discuss here in the show so Nate thank
you very much for joining us thank you
for having me delighted to have you on
mate I was doing my research and as I
kept coming across more in photos and
videos of your products I was salivating
at the mouth looking at how beautiful
and amazing they look so I said I had to
get you guys on to discuss exactly what
the key to the secrets are and maybe
help educate the audience can you maybe
give everybody a quick in under 60
seconds how you guys came to to create
snow till and what are the main
objectives of the company uh absolutely
so no tell in general was created by
mesos for Coco uh Japanese scientist in
the 50s and it's the next generation of
Organics it's called natural farming so
we build our our own soil once it lasts
for 13 or 14 Cycles it's a whole
ecosystem where everything's alive and
this has three main benefits it allows
the plants to maximize the genetic
potential because they take what it
wants when it wants it the second one is
it's very sustainable it's close to zero
waste so all our leaves stems everything
goes right back on the soil and the
third thing is
it cuts out a lot of the production
startup costs and production costs and
really simplifies it you pretty much
give our plants plain water okay amazing
that's great so I'm going to move
straight on to the first topic and it's
a unique cultivation methods can you
explain to everybody maybe what what is
no till farming and the method that you
guys use so most modern agriculture
people till their soil in between each
cycle and that breaks up the soil food
web in the soil so what we do is we
Harvest our plants and all the plant
material gets put back on top of it and
then the roots get to decompose in the
soil and it's already created the
mycelium Pathways so when we put in the
next plants they get to follow the plant
where the root system that was already
there and as you know most of the
nutrients are in The Roots itself
so you know what we do uniquely is most
of it's done Outdoors or greenhouses and
we do it indoors
because within because quality is really
really important and the control you get
indoors you just can't get we've grown
in every single methodology possible and
doing uh no-till living soil indoors is
the way that we found this produces the
highest quality product
okay amazing so in terms of cover crops
sterility required let's say for outdoor
cultivation that indoor cultivation it's
more about the essence of the soil is
what's going to give you the best
product
yeah and we do have a rice hay as our
mulch that is kind that's the main
source of nutrients for the soil so
we're not feeding the plants directly
we're feeding the microbial life that's
in the soil and the microbial life has a
symbiotic relationship with the plant
okay amazing and next topic I want to
jump on to is cultivating with aesthetic
now for anybody who hasn't seen any of
the snow till products the website is
just down below there I highly recommend
you go and watch the videos and the
products that they've got what are let's
say the top two
parameters that you guys set when it
comes to the end the static of the
flower that you're going to sell to the
consumer
so as you know the devil's in the detail
uh high-end handbags are still sewn by
hand and not by machine and we treat
every single bud with love and it is
important the reason why it looks we
call snow too because it looks like our
buds are snowy is again that's to do
with the cultivation method and we make
sure we do the property leafing and the
right training and pruning to the plant
so every single bite gets the right
amount to light so every single one
looks amazing we have grading systems
under flowers so everything that leaves
our facility has to be grade A
okay interesting so when it comes to the
aesthetic of the plant you obviously are
using land race uh previous strains who
finds your let's say your genetics that
you mix together and uh what is the main
uh objective that you look for when
you're searching for a land race
so there's Trends come and go and by the
time you chase a trend it's already on
the new one so we
stick to Classics like our motor SOG
there's a certain stuff that might drop
in popularity temporarily but always
comes back because there's this certain
uh effects that people are looking for
at the end of the day with all the names
and the hives and the brand
when people consume cannabis that are
looking for a certain effect whatever
that is we work with a handful of
breeders and for us there it has to
obviously have a unique theraping
profile it has to look a certain way and
of course we're a for-profit business so
it has to have a certain yield so I
would say that would be the three things
we're looking for when we test out new
genetics
okay very interesting so you mentioned
that you guys are cultivating with an
indoor facility which is basically the
model that can be clarified as medical
grade cannabis over in Europe we're
starting to see the industry mature and
Germany are going to legalize hopefully
2023 2024 timeline what would be the
number one tip that you'd give to indoor
cultivars in Europe that are looking at
getting into this industry and maybe uh
potential cultivars down the line
themselves so first of all the way you
design your facility
is crucial and you got to make sure you
can't cut Corners especially on your
HVAC it is very expensive especially
today with the supply chain issues but
that can make or break your facility if
you don't have the proper HVAC and you
can have full control over your
environment then there's no point of
doing indoors
okay so for everybody HVAC is humidity
ventilation and air conditioning so is
that basically a a pest deterrent is
that the best way of doing it or is it
giving more life to the plan to your
HVAC system is that on a parsed ECS
system then a a closed second behind in
terms of things people need to keep
their eye on yeah it has a bunch of
things uh and you want to maximize its
health so nature is cruel you know at
the end of the season most puns die and
everything here we're doing the opposite
we're like vaping them like what is the
perfect optimal you know point of a
percent of uh humidity and temperature
you want at different stages of it and
that would really actually fight uh
exemplifies the plant as well
yes you're right it definitely helps
with bugs if stuff if the humidity gets
too high you're inviting a whole host of
pathogens and different past thrive in
different climates so if you don't have
control over that then you have just
created a perfect thing let's say for
spider mites and that's the last thing
you want the problem with indoors is
it's a zero-sum game there's nowhere for
them to go once you do get a pest in
your facility they don't really want to
go there and if you provided the
environment they thrive in then they are
going to win
okay very interesting tell me this do
California grow the best cannabis in the
world
at the moment yes we this is the
birthplace of all almost all modern
genetics have come from the Emerald
Triangle I would say also Southern
Oregon is definitely up there they
decriminalized all the way back in the
70s so it was a lot easier for them to
get around the law then and I would say
Southern Oregon and Northern California
through all the genetics
there's definitely up and coming uh
Rivals but right now the best cannabis
in the world is still in California
okay amazing then the last topic I
wanted to touch on is the future of
cannabis flower it gonna be in craft
budgets
so yeah there's this like you can go to
a store and buy a three dollar bottle of
wine and buy a hundred dollar bottle of
wine and they both sell really well it's
different clientele
you're gonna have to have a very huge
budget if you want to compete on a
quantity level and it's like Bud Light
is the most popular beer in in the U.S
but craft breweries are cutting into
their profits into the market share
every year the same thing is going to
happen here and you have to decide
there's not going to be a lot of room
for mid grade there's going to either be
mass produced are there's going to be
crafting and you cannot compromise or
cut any corners and don't grow too fast
that's one of the problems a lot of
people that produced a really amazing
product when they were small scale and
then they jump from 5 000 square feet to
a hundred thousand square feet and it's
their quality we've seen unfortunately
even here in California with amazing
brands that they lose their quality so
you'll still you'll always be able like
in Colorado the most mature Market in
the world they still go for 50 60 Ace
which is three and a half grams and that
price point has never changed all the
other price points have gone down so you
have to stay true to your principles if
you're a craft grower and never expand
too fast no matter what Market pressures
or investor pressures you're getting
yeah I think cannabis is one of the few
Industries worldwide where there doesn't
seem to be really a budget Market
everybody if they've got an opportunity
to play the best weed will sooner have
less of the best weed that a lot of the
shittersweed and when it comes to the
the craft patches and basically you guys
being in California do you see the
Eastern Seaboard of the United States
being an attractive Market to open up a
facility or do you think that there's
still a number of years away before it's
on a par with the West Coast
so because uh the U.S is unique where we
have every state is completely different
and there's a hodgepodge rules
New York is definitely showing some
promise of being a good Market at the
end of the day most of the TVs produce
their the financial markets there
there's a lot of reasons why New York
will be good uh just like everything
rollout is really slow and the
regulations change constantly and
confusing so I would say we will see a
fully open developed Market in New York
which is Epic Center for the east coast
in two years from now so there are there
is still a little bit of time but yes
absolutely I'm from New York
and we are definitely going to have a
branch there sooner or later
incredible stuff and I look forward to
seeing the battle for uh the best flower
in America he healed over the next
couple of years because I think
somewhere like New York has so much
small little potential uh small grow
Farmers that can work on genetics over a
couple of years and perfect a plan to
the specific way and it's going to be
very interesting to see what happens and
not to mine then Europe with the history
of farming that we've already got over
here when regulations allow people to
advance and do some research and
development about cultivation it's going
to be an exciting Global industry over
the next five to ten years
yeah I'm really looking forward to it
where we countries legalize the country
so there can be cross-border like right
now we still don't have interstate
commerce so even though the border is
really tiny in the between states and
there really isn't the Border you can't
do it because that borders Federal
jurisdiction so can't wait till we have
interstate commerce and international
where we can just be treated like any
other industry where you have to compete
on quality price and service
I'd love to hear it it's we've reached
up our time now but thank you very much
Nate for coming on the show it's very
much appreciated for anybody who wants
to see what I was talking about it's a
hotel I highly recommend go visit their
website and if you're over the west
coast of America I highly recommend
trying their flower when you guys come
to the east coast I'll be one of your
first customers so I look forward to
keeping an eye on everything with snow
till and hopefully getting to chat with
you guys over the next year and see your
expansion plans and how everything's
going all right thank you thanks for
having me thanks for coming late until
next episode everybody