foreign
episode of the Cannabis view I am
delighted to be joining this episode by
Alex Rogers who's the founder and the
executive producer at the international
cannabis business conference how are you
keeping today Alex
I'm good Owen thanks for having me man
delighted to have you on mace you're at
the man who runs the best events in
Europe in the Cannabis industry so great
to chat you with Berlin coming around
the corner
hey man it's coming right up we're
working like dogs and uh that's uh you
know all that glitter's not gold behind
the scenes which it's not as glorious as
those few days of the conference that's
for sure uh but we got to make it we got
to make it seem seamless that's the
point
yeah and you seem to have a great team
behind you the guys who run the social
media and and all of the other people in
the team seem to be a top tier people so
the credit here for fun
thanks bro even the blind hog finds
irocorn every once in a while you know
what I mean
yeah exactly you just jump into ICBC
Barcelona in March how did cucumber
berries happen to Barcelona event and
partnering with spanavus was that an
ongoing conversation which is a pretty
easy deal to get done when you started
just
it was the easy deal I had this kind of
uh I when I first came into Europe I
think this was around 217 I made the uh
partnership with spanibus
you know honestly I don't even remember
if I think I contacted
them I although I it it it's so long ago
and so much has happened in between I'm
not sure but basically I think I
contacted them
and uh we basically I basically said hey
I want to do this B2B event with you
guys and I they were enough to
understand that
B2B was a important element that was
going to come to Europe because they'd
everybody had seen it already happen in
the states and we did the we we just I
don't know it was like it was a totally
seamless uh uh uh partnership and uh you
know with Carlos and with uh Jose uh
we've always had a wonderful
relationship and it just kind of we just
really just just just hit the ground
running with them and we didn't look
back so I'm really
I was really happy then when I did it
because I was I wanted to associate with
other big brands in Europe because I was
the the Newbie they saw the value and
now and then it was really uh incumbent
upon me to be like okay I'm gonna show
you the value of this B2B and make it a
success and they they loved it because
they see it as a as a compliment uh uh
to what they do and to just make that
whole span of this week have that much
more fervor
incredible so what part of what Berlin
coming just around the corner now is
there a process that you guys go to when
you're choosing the panel speakers do
you sit down and start right well we
want industry leaders first or we want
our keynote speaker first what is the
kind of first piece of the jigsaw when
you're putting together the panels
experts we we have a meeting we come
together and I mean this is actually one
of the bane of my existence the
discourage putting this uh putting these
these curating these uh
all these panels and and finding what
what is uh what's the most germane and
relevant topics you need for that
particular time I mean you could come up
we got to come up schedule right but
cannabis is dog years right so if we
come up with a schedule three months
ahead four months ahead
we we pretty much have to stick to it
but I like to be a little malleable
um and flexible because things change so
so quickly a case in point with what's
happening in in Germany right now but
basically I sit down with my with my
content team
and my most trusted uh confidence and uh
uh experts and then we just we just say
what you know what's the most germane
and relevant topics that maybe talked
about right now in this in whatever uh
respective jurisdiction we're having the
event in
for young entrepreneurs or entrepreneurs
who might not have visited the icpcs
what is the main reason that they should
be attending Berlin they're similar for
it's it's networking you know I mean we
there's no networking like the ICBC in
the entirety of Europe everybody pays
500 a ticket or more
people come from over 80 countries so
it's not just okay we're having an event
in Germany and you're going to meet all
these Germans no I'd say maybe 25 of the
people are German in at the Berlin event
and then we have Americans in Canadians
and South Africans and Australians and
Russians and Finnish and Czech and Dutch
and Spanish and and uh uruguayans and
it's it's truly an international uh
Affair and I think that's what network
if you want to just take two days out of
your life and you want to get the most
done you don't have to travel all these
countries they all come to Berlin and
it's a One-Stop shop a trefpunt as they
would say in uh German and so any
entrepreneur okay you're going to get
information from the panels there's
going to be stuff stuff here you're
you're you're you'll you'll glean and
that that'll soak in but there's no more
there's no bigger value than actually
coming face to face with your potential
uh
uh partners and helpers in this industry
and to be able to just have that
one-on-one uh time with them it's
invaluable
yeah I couldn't agree more the ability
to network at these events and
especially the caliber of guests that
you have make it definitely one of the
most sought after if not sought after
events of the year on the calendar
Germany's recent uh announcement that
made where they kind of rolled back or
did a diet version of what the
legalization was going to be there is an
argument that it could potentially be a
good thing because it allows the medical
side of the industry to get more
validation and to have a bigger range of
products and it also gives home grow to
a lot of let's say the activist side of
the industry do you see any positive
with the step back that they've done or
is it all well it should have pushed on
further we don't look at it as a step
back I see it as a completely positive I
mean it's so funny I think people had
certain it's kind of like buy the rumor
sell the fact and so everyone we were
telling people for six months that this
is what's going to happen they're good
there's a good chance that it's going to
be a decrimp thing first with these
Social Clubs and then we didn't know
exactly how the social we're going to
look we'll know that very soon I think
that's actually going through Parliament
the bundis uh top right right now as we
speak and uh uh and then we we didn't
know if what the pot if there's gonna if
they were even gonna talk about
excuse me pilot projects and um so so so
what I mean as an act there's a few
problems of this as an activist the
first thing I said in 217 when I when I
was uh uh when I when I let let off the
the first uh Berlin event was that The
Regulators are going to [ __ ] [ __ ] up and
the what you need the most is a home
garden and decrim of cannabis because
that just takes the wind out of out of
uh the constant the constabulary sale
right
and then as a legalizer and as someone
who feels that cannabis is uh is the
people's plan and it's a human right to
to grow it to use it that's a good thing
for me but on a business side I found it
funny when people like oh they didn't
just go for well guess what we've seen
them go for license and regulations in
certain areas like you said that were
medical before and we've seen medical
getting destroyed right so to do a slow
roll out like this and uh uh hopefully
methodical uh rollout
it's the best for business actually
because all people like all the VCS not
the money's not there now good we don't
want you money right we want to create a
a a a a device verse batch of
entrepreneurs and not have this limited
just to Rich Venture capitalists right
that's not how I ever made any of my
businesses that's not how I didn't rely
on those business those big
multi-billion dollar businesses to build
the ICBC the ICBC was built on mom and
pop businesses and of course we have
some bigger businesses too you know like
the 100 200 million dollar range and the
private Equity side but really we don't
we if the money's not going to pour in
great because look what happened when
the money poured in to the Canadian
companies you had pump and dumps you had
it really [ __ ] up the industry in a
lot of ways and was a real bad bad look
so that all being said there's plenty of
business that can be done with this even
with the social club model and we're
going to be talking about that in Berlin
and then the pilot project model is
where we see a uh it turning into which
they'll basically introduce around
December
uh which will basically a de facto end
around legalization because of the the
eu's uh resistance to to license and
regulation so we knew that the EU wasn't
going to go for it we knew Germany was
thinking about uh this decrim notion
um and we'll see how the social club
aspect plays out we'll see how the pilot
project uh plays out because as far as I
understand though they will limit the
amount of patients that could or people
or participants that can be part of the
pilot project specifically they won't
limit how many pilot projects there are
and we can look in Switzerland to start
to get an idea of how this might look in
Germany but basically there could be one
2 000 pilot projects within two three
years uh all around Germany which is
very exciting and in some ways we've
seen when it's kind of gray area which
you know we would rather have them just
do like you know let's get it going
let's rock it but because they didn't it
actually it actually really helps the
people the average person is going to
have a bigger Advantage now in the
market now if you're a big cat and you
want to be the Walmart a weed and blah
blah blah [ __ ] off anyway because we
don't we don't we don't we don't need
that [ __ ] we want we we're here to have
every the most amount of people have
their slice of their little slice or
bigger depending on how smart they are
how much risk they take how hard they
work piece of the pie but we want an
even playing field and so for me
personally I see this as a
um just the movement in itself is good
no matter what just to see Germany do
something like that the movement's great
but to really then how does that
translate into business
and business is thriving it it does and
it will
and do you see we've just mentioned
Switzerland there we're off to Prague
now at the end of the month you see that
little Trifecta of country is having a
massive influence on Europe or out of
those three who do you think is going to
have the most success for let's say
adult use Market
Germany by far I mean there's just no
question they're already there by far by
far it's I don't even I don't even I
mean
who I mean Germany has the size they
have the movement going they have
everything uh and you see with
Switzerland they're just
if they're very you know it can be
bureaucratic and you can get caught up
with a lot of things in Switzerland and
things go slow in general even though
Switzerland's been really cool on weed
you know for for since I used to live
there when it was quasi-legal in the
late 90s right it was amazing but uh so
Switzerland is always a fun country but
in terms of business no we Switzerland
just got decimated their their CBD
market right they banked it all on CBD
and it's now these pilot okay cool but
there's not how many pilot projects are
there and who's really doing it and What
needs what what has to happen for things
to get done there the real process
Germany I don't see that I don't see
it's going to be as cumbersome in in uh
to start these pilot projects but
certainly not these Social Clubs and so
if you're an ancillary business and you
make trim machines or you make uh
extract machines you're golden in the
German Market because that's what that
because all these because what we want
is more if more cannabis is being grown
then
and more uh and used that all these
ancillary products are going to be
needed so it's uh it's wonderful uh it's
it's wonderful to see this happen in
Germany and I I think there's no
question that we're going to see in just
a few months or all these opportunities
about abounding
yeah I think some of the big Winners had
at the German announcement there are
companies like Scott's Miracle Grow or
companies that actually sell products
for people to grow at home I think
there's got to be a massive massive
Market just in regular consumers wanting
to go there a couple of plants every
year
right and then but you have to know that
that all people now can be get a
surrogate to grow it and there will be
these big grows starting just under the
social club auspices right now you're
ready in your mind your auntie all have
two or three fronts you're you're
looking at 1500 plant Gardens because if
there could be 500 people for the Social
Club and three plants allotted per 1500
plant Gardens well I don't know about
what they're doing
you know in in in in in America a fit
team playing Garden let me tell you
something right now that that those
those folks know how to grow so we're
going to see a lot of American Master
Growers come over to Europe right now
and start getting these grows on and
then uh we'll see how how the creative
lawyering how they how they'll how
they'll uh uh set up and and structure
these entities you know it's it's uh we
saw you know we saw under this kind of
gray area in Oregon we saw gray area in
Canada and we've got those multi-billion
dollar businesses in Canada evaluated
under medical auspices right which no
one even thought would be possible a few
years ago and then you certain things
happen
in the market and so many people are
like
it's like who thinks that you're not a
real entrepreneur if something happens
if movement goes forward and you're like
oh no it's kind of a soft soft way of
thinking and a a champion way of
thinking is we've had this movement
1500 plant Gardens pilot projects and
that's just the start
let's get in let's roll let's see what's
let's see what's going on and where we
can get in where we fit in and that's
those are the folks that are gonna I
think that's gonna be an obvious thing
though in it by by the end of the year I
think all these things I'm saying now
are gonna be like oh Alex was right I
can't yeah and now people are a little
bit nay saying it but there's no there's
I've just seen it happen in too many
markets too many jurisdictions and I
know exactly what's going to happen the
people are going to figure it out man I
think it's a huge boon not only for the
German Market but it's going to resonate
all around Europe
yeah I couldn't agree more amazing we've
just finished the time I know you're a
very very busy man so I'm not going to
keep you too much longer for everybody
who wants to check out ICBC Berlin the
website for international cannabis
business conference is below would it be
posted in all the comments couldn't
recommend attending this event more Alex
thank you very much for your time today
man it's very much appreciated
thanks Owen appreciate you brother
another tell me man have a good day
everybody until next episode