[Music]
welcome to the cannabis review i'm
delighted to be joined on this episode
by
heidi whitman she's the global strategy
director for
adida global heidi how are you kevin
very well thank you owen
and you i'm fantastic thank you very
much for being on the show
those who don't know heidi she's got an
esteemed career so far in the industry
and has now moved on to one of the top
companies in the global sphere so
why did you want to give everybody a
little overview of how you got to where
you are in the video at the moment
yes absolutely back in 2017
my husband and i started researching
going into natural health holistic means
medicines
and fell into the cbd world while
visiting
america i am american but i do live here
in the uk so we spent seven months doing
due diligence
in the states looking to see what was
working what wasn't understanding the
market as best as we could
with the mindset to bring something back
to the uk
and our desire was to provide a product
for people and for pets because that is
part of my background technically was in
veterinary medicine
so we we created a brand called the
naked leaf um brought it back to the uk
and successfully started trading for
people over here as well as for pets and
people
in america back in america and our
product
and our brand and our company was
acquired by a different
group that was looking for a vertical
operation so we
um spent our time doing all of that type
of transitional work which led me
into a wonderful um experiential
education in the marketplace
in the cbd realm and also started
getting my passion for
medical marijuana which was the next
phase that i wanted to enter
and that's when i met the group at avita
global who are
producing the highest quality medicinal
cannabis and that was something i really
was excited about
and we melded forces and joined together
just this past june
oh i think
you are a mute sorry i'm still muted
there so
yeah so that's that's great it's uh you
you kind of have the expertise from the
veterinary side
coming in to talk about the subject it's
not somebody just come in and said it
set up a
a cbd company can you tell me what
attracted to you to aveda global
what's their story like can you give
maybe the viewer an overview of who
vito global are and what their purpose
is yes absolutely well
part partially because i have been a
cannabis medical cannabis patient myself
in the past it is really important to
understand where your product comes from
and i think that is something that the
consumer and the patients don't have a
lot of access
to knowing because there's so much out
there and what i liked about avita
global was their transparency and their
traceability to product
so um what's really unique about evita
is this is a group that
had an idea to create this high medical
um high quality medical cannabis with
three factors in mind the location
the people in the process around it and
so what they have done
uniquely is they've set up um in
colombia
an area called la jolla la jolla de
americo in cesar which is northeast
columbia
it's at the foot of the andes mountains
so they're looking at doing a
sustainable
natural growing method by being um
environmentally sound and carbon neutral
along the way
so this was a three year process and
i've joined in at a very critical time
where everything is now moving
and what was nice about this is that the
being that cannabis plants are like a
sponge
whatever the environment is grows into
them so they grow hydroponically
and purpose-built greenhouses so it's
akin to laboratory conditions
and i found that to be really unique
being that it's outdoors hydroponically
grown but covered
and with the optimum 13 hours of
daylight consistent temperatures of 26
to 34 degrees
they can actually harvest about five to
six crops a year
and when there's a limitation for
patient access due to supply
this to me was incredibly interesting
because now
we can produce a medicinal cannabis that
can actually reach those who need it
because of our ability to harvest
and these conditions so although they
have these six harvests per year they
micro harvest every three days
and watching these controlled batches
making sure that the epigenetics are
being taken into consideration
that all the data that's being collected
is shared with our bio diligence team in
israel
everything they're doing has such
concise and precise measures
that the quality consistency will then
follow and it has
it's proven to be and um so i think all
of the efforts that they have made so
far has been
have been unbelievably exciting um they
are in an eu gmp
track and that should be coming in at
the end of this
quarter and that will give us the
ability to
um focus on all of the markets including
not only just colombia but also the um
neighboring south american countries
like brazil uruguay chile mexico
and of course europe so that is part of
um
why why i wasn't fascinated with their
process but the other part is the locals
um impact that they have so they they
harness
almost all of the local skill sets that
they can so they work really carefully
with the ministry of justice for
security
on site but they also work with the um
the
national training service which is
called cena down at colombia and they
have
60 employees and recent grads that work
on the agricultural medicinal side link
joined joining evita and 60 of them are
now but we hope to actually employ
about 600 people when it's all the 40
hectares are filled with our
facility and i love the fact that they
also have three quarters of their
employees are female because they're
trying to keep on this ratio to give
opportunities to the local women
who are usually disadvantaged in terms
of employment opportunities in the
region
and i felt that was something that was
really close to my heart so there's a
lot of ethics behind this company
as well as the um the careful genetics
being
followed you know with the group of
people that are involved we have the top
agronomists some of the best cultivators
a lot of people that used to work in
pharma
um so the skill sets are there and then
of course we do have a bio diligence
team in israel that monitors all of the
genetics
all of the data and keeps us on track to
making sure that we're ever evolving
and that whatever strains we are growing
can complement the necessary
medical conditions that could benefit
from these strains
um and then one other little point if i
don't if you don't mind me saying is
that
they also have a foundation where coming
from a background where i worked in a
lot of non-profit as a volunteer
um avito global set up a foundation to
bring back some um to give back to the
the local country with a focus on
education
local enterprise environment and arts
and culture
so they've been working well um past
this past year a lot with the pandemic
and assisting those in the area
that were suffering from food shortages
and
job shortages of course but they also
are looking to promote um
transportation options for the local
children who tend to walk 5k to work
every day i mean to school every day so
i found that to be a really
nice component of what avita does
so that's basically the guys have got
the model in place where
the price per gram grown in colombia is
going to be
a specific attractive part of the
company you've got the medical research
side of israel which are the world
leaders and this is the other
attractive side so the components for
that company seem to be put in position
and then
the final piece for me is always equity
partners who stands to make from the
company if the companies in the
territory are they giving back to the
people in that environment so
you seem to be doing all three of the
right things for a company to do
to to make it on a global scale and i
think what you're going to see over time
now is
the acquisitions and mergers of a lot of
companies and you're going to be left
with
let's say the top five to 10 companies
who if they haven't got that price point
for gram
they're going to be blown out of the
water if they haven't got the medical
research and the top kind of
tier research that goes along with it
which kind of brings me on to my next
topic which is
fostering relationships with
universities for research and
development
you guys seem to be pretty good at this
is there something that you'd
give any information to the audience on
this side of the industry
absolutely well one of our chief medical
officer happens to be dr
francis francisco cabal and he was one
of the leading
colombian trauma doctors and what he's
doing right now in colombia he has
started a three-phase
clinical trial and he's working on four
aspects which is
trauma post-traumatic stress and anxiety
combined cancer as well as multiple
sclerosis which is very close to a lot
of
our hearts because we've had several
different family members suffering from
it as well as dr cabal so
that trial is underway that is based out
of his eye care clinics which are in
colombia so it gives us patient access
doctor access and he can keep his finger
on the pulse of all of the processes
once again this began the beginning of
this year so it's a three-phase
three-year trial
um but we also have fostered very close
relationships with universities and
academies
um locally in colombia but also in
israel as i mentioned we have
a form of bio-diligence group
over there that is keeping an eye on
everything we're doing and it's been
advising from the very beginning
so they also are looking at all the
genetic aspects and
pharmaceutical aspects of each strain
that we are working with
making sure that we have the proper
delivery systems also creating new
delivery systems that are unique to the
um marketplace which um will be released
once we we
finalize everything with them um we have
multiple just um the multi-disciplinary
center at hebrew university in jerusalem
and the techyon are two of those
locations that we're working with
um and also the um you know
understanding the new
cannabis molecules and how the
combination of these molecules and the
entourage effect
can work with different medical
conditions so these all keep us up to
date with the latest developments um
we are working hard to make sure that
we've got as much clinical background on
our strains to be able to provide to
prescribers to give them the confidence
the insurance that everything we're
doing
is um copacetic with what they are
looking to prescribe for their patients
very amazing the last topic that i want
to touch on
and it's something i know you're going
to be an expert on i know about a good
few people kind of ask me about this
we've heard of a lot of companies doing
dvds for different pets
can you talk about cbds or horses the
benefits that it does or does not blame
and how it should be administered and
maybe what the
recommended dosage for a horse would
yes absolutely i have a lot to say on
this subject it's something that's close
to my heart i'm an equestrian i have
been my entire life
um and working with horses has been
something that's been not only a passion
but creating
a hemp-based product for horses was
something that i wanted to set out to do
and i did
um that was with the naked leaf company
right now
in the uk cbd for pets and animals in
general is not permitted however and i'm
disclosing all of this information not
being a veterinarian i can give you some
information on how i have seen it work
well um in the united states
and what i hope to see is the acceptance
leading across europe and the uk um
other countries are starting to look at
it as well i think it's becoming a hot
topic
and there's a lot of owner of horses
equestrian demand for their equine
partners
to have ability to recover while in
motion
and that is what cbd does for horses
just like us they have our mammals they
have an endocannabinoid system
when you give a horse cbd they are all
sensitive creatures as large as they are
i always deem them like butterflies
and so when you give anything to a horse
it can affect them quite quickly
and cbd is no different however um
there's different types of
administration i will give some examples
just of my own
product that we created it was a pellet
form so it was an ingestible
um each pellet had a one percent content
of cbd in it so therefore
um a scoops you know that we had which
was equivalent to about a tablespoon was
about 75 milligrams and it was a
for an average size horse 500 kilos 550
kilos it was about a 300
milligram dose that seemed to work best
you're also dealing with a very long gut
so when you're dealing with anything
ingestible you've got to remember a
horse is built a little differently than
a dog
so i have had um amazing anecdotal
real world evidence showing that with
this type of dosage of 300 milligrams of
cbd product
for a 500 550 kilo horse
there was a reduction in anxiety a
reduction in arthritic
or you know a range of motion that was
increased the arthritis pain
subsided and when pain subsides a horse
will eat better like any of us if you're
in pain you don't want to eat
and forest doesn't eat they can also
result have gi
issues so it was very important that if
you have an animal you want to
treat them like a horse with something
to reduce their pain it will help them
create the regular um system functions
as well as eating and defecating etc
which is really important in the horse
world
i've also had great success with topical
products so if there
is a horse with swelling in the leg
there's no need for that edema to go
down the leg there's a way to actually
um reduce that swelling with a cbd
topical solution
and i personally loved our liniment gel
that is something that
was something we created and it worked a
long time to get that
um water-soluble nano-molecular
cbd liniment gel and it's helped horses
like i said with my own experience as
well as our customers in the past
and i think if it's in every
equestrian's toolbox
you don't have to aim for those um
butte-type drugs
you know drugs that can actually on a
long-term basis affect the animal's
well-being
the other aspect of cbd for horses it is
not permitted in competition animals so
there is a withdrawal period for
everything be sure if you're going to be
using cbd for horses that whatever
product you're buying
has that withdrawal period noted on the
product
or contact the company itself so that
you are not competing
unknowingly having cannabinoids in your
horse's body so that you get
disqualified
um so that's just i just asked a
question there so
cbd is illegal for any racehorse
um in well it would if they're racing
yes that is true and i believe the only
horses that are allowed to take cbd and
i could be wrong here are polo horses
but for the most part
um racing fei usef show jumping and and
the racing associations do not permit
cannabinoids and horses
however if there's a withdrawal period
using them while not racing
and monitoring them is very important so
you would want to make sure that you
know exactly what you're doing there's
no cross-contamination within your yard
and that your horses are getting exactly
what they should you need almost a groom
proof
system so that any sensitive tests that
they provide
these horses at times you make sure that
there's nobody touching cbd and then
touching another horse
you just never know and some of these
animals have been you know training for
so long you wouldn't want someone to be
disqualified accidentally
so i do believe though these are the
athletes why
should we prevent athletes from not
getting the chance to recover
naturally while in motion when we
personally as athletes get to recover
while we're in motion
they're doing the same and if anything
they're then put in a box and told to
stand still which isn't always very good
so
i believe that it should be necessary
i've spoken in washington dc about this
to the heads of the
olympic committees as well as ucef and
fei um
this was back in 2018 and even then they
were skeptical but interested and they
agreed with me that it does work
it's just a matter of rewriting rules
and sometimes it takes a lot of effort
and so therefore
it's a matter of uh of us those are
passionate those equestrians the
trainers
to push the veterinary medical
directorate to maybe think differently
about this
and hopefully we can allow um animals to
receive what they should receive
just as much as we can here in the uk
amazing it's been hugely informed of
chat heidi i hope we can
get you back on again before the end of
the year and go over a lot more topics
because we've got so much more to
discuss but
unfortunately we keep the show to 15
minutes thank you so much for coming on
being a great show and i hope we can get
to chat again very soon
yes absolutely and thank you so very
much for having me i really appreciate
it
see you to the next show guys bye