foreign
at the world renowned Warner Brands how
are you coming today Mike
doing fantastic and thank you how are
you today I am absolutely fantastic as
well thank you very much for taking your
time to come on do you maybe want to
give everybody a little run through
between 30 and 60 seconds of how you
ended up becoming into the Cannabis
industry and your position at wanna
Brands yeah so I got involved in the
industry in 2013.
um I had a roommate in college I I
obviously was consuming cannabis for
personal use back then and found it
beneficial I never felt like it should
be something that was illegal but my
roommate had epilepsy and I was able to
realize what medical benefits it had for
him and that it was really able to
prevent his seizures and it really just
inspired something in me and catalyzed
me to want to get involved in the
industry so I moved out to Colorado in
2012 got involved in the industry in
2013 and then started working with Wana
Brands early in 2014.
okay incredible and water brands have
become one of the stable uh top tier
brands in the in the North American
cannabis industry then what I wanted to
talk to you about and I'm sure you're
going to have a lot of information for
the audience is innovation and Edibles
at the moment there's a couple of
different things that I'd like to touch
on and that are under that umbrella of
innovation and Edibles because over in
Europe we see a lot of the only thing
that you'll see in media is going to be
a synthetic edible that comes from a
drug dealer that's done some sort of
damage so I'd love to be able to explain
to the audience how advanced this
industry is and uh what exactly are you
guys are up to so first and foremost the
technology involved in making Edibles
for everybody who doesn't understand
what is this simplified process without
giving too much away
yeah
no process
the the simple processing Edibles is um
taking taking the plant
um generally the the flower the buds the
influences and extracting it and with
cannabinoids and terpenes being
lipophilic you're usually using solvents
like butane CO2 or ethanol
to create an extract and then you can
purify and post-process it with
processes like distillation and then
that extract is then infused into
products like chocolates gummies other
edible forms
um so it's generally taking the plant
using extraction methods cleaning it up
and then introducing it into an edible
and the introduction of it into any
product per se is through specific
technology and equipment that gets used
for let's say obviously it's probably
going to be easy to be done by hand but
if they're a large company like
yourselves is there certain technology
that is given the exact dosage per exact
government every single time or what
does the manufacturing line look like at
a company of your scale
you know the interesting thing with
cannabis in the United States is how
state by state specific regulations and
Market sizes are
um so at wanna we have multiple
different
methodologies on how to do the infusion
from something as small as using lab
kits and measuring devices into things
like pots you can literally cook in in
pots at very small scales all the way up
to full automated equipment and with the
full automated equipment side there are
API dosing devices that can
accurately measure inline dosing for for
the Cannabis products
um but it really just depends on the
methodology of cooking
okay incredible and the product range
you guys got is pretty extensive and
some very Advanced uh Innovations in
your plans and form is for example the
new quick product you guys brought out
can you maybe give an example of the
technology behind uh bringing that
product to Market
yeah you know in the early days cannabis
uh Edibles really just were extracts of
a specific strain or a specific scheme
of our of canvas
um these days we are looking to make
more effect specific products we
understand that this plant has a
multitude of benefits and a multitude of
different effects it can elicit
depending upon that team of our chemical
variety of compounds in there so what is
the formulation of cannabinoids and
terpenes that elicit different effects
we know that people use cannabis for
effects like
relieving anxiety calming effects sleep
so our newest formulation called
quickcom uses a functional blend of just
one milligram of THC so it's not a very
intoxicating dose very low dose of THC
but combines that with 10 milligrams of
CBD 10 milligram CBG and also
Additionally the formulation is 50
milligrams of l-theanine normally found
in green tea this is all enhanced with
30 other Botanical terpenes for a
calming relaxing effect and it's all
fast acting so it takes it through five
to fifteen minutes
I really think the future of a lot of
cannabis products are going to be these
highly formative products
um where instead of guessing what the
stream might feel or affect we are
formulating them so consumers
can rely on the marketing and say I know
this product's going to work for me for
the effect I want
okay so that kind of leads me perfectly
to the next topic I want to discuss and
that's the research and development that
happens in Edibles you just mentioned
there your own unique blend and
formulation of ingredients that created
the quickcom do you see is this one of
the most Innovative part or the most
Cutting Edge part of the edible industry
is their big money being pumped into r d
and the creation of Blends and
formulations as a unique iepable a
component for any organization
I think there is and there isn't um the
industry is a little bifurcated in the
way that it's doing r d I think there
are a lot of brands that are sticking
towards
very simplistic r d which is throwing
whatever the new hot cannabinoid is
taking some
you know phrasing off of
places like Leafly and and spitting that
out then there are companies like wanna
and others that are actually doing
consumer research on the effects they're
doing surveys they're doing clinical
trials we're trying to understand how
these uh products make people feel how
the different formulations work
and then you also have a third piece
which is Pharma is getting into this in
actually new synthetic cannabinoids that
they're formulating
um Raphael mushroom and his team in
Israel have started to formulate a
variety of CBD uh like molecules they're
not found in the plant but they are
cannabinoids they'll do activated
cannabinoid receptors and are being
formulated for very specific treatments
and four effects
um so there's there's a bit of a
different approaches from very
unscientific to very scientific
and that do you see the biotechnology
companies now that are now able to buy
or synthesize these molecules in
large-scale batches completely clean
precise replicable over and over do you
see them taking a market share of the
ingredient side of things let's say from
a plant extraction model
it depends on where you're located so
when we're talking about synthesis of
cannabinoids there's a few different
approaches
um one that we've seen growing a lot in
Canada has been fermentation you're
utilizing bacteria and yeast to produce
you actually genetically modify these
organisms
add ingredients and in their metabolic
processes are able to convert raw
ingredients and molecules into
cannabinoids because they're genetically
modified
so we're seeing that for things like CBG
in Canada I've also seen ways to take
the actual biomechanical Machinery of
trichomes where terpenes and
cannabinoids are made in the plant and
you can isolate those and put them into
reactors and these these reactors are
able to
replicate the environment that tricoms
would live in and have them produce
cannabinoids
um and then there's always just
synthetic production in Labs where
you're taking raw hydrocarbons
synthesizing them with reagents and
producing them in labs
all of these processes end up producing
very pure very isolated forms of
cannabinoids
it's going to take
for that process to work in each market
the working with governments and other
institutions to prove that the method is
safe reliable and producing very pure
isolates
in the long term these will likely be
more environmentally friendly less cost
and providing purer ingredients so I do
see a path forward for them in the
United States right now without FDA
regulation I don't know that there's
going to be a path forward for those
soon whereas in other markets
particularly in Europe I think
governments are working to
start to regulate understand these
processes and provide a supply chain for
them
yeah it's got to be an interesting few
years ahead for the Edibles Market both
in Europe and in North America to see
how both markets evolve and the
different ingredients suppliers whether
they're one size fits all or whether we
have one company has to have two
different manufacturing outputs to be
able to suit the two different markets
you know the the one the one area that
we need to understand better when we're
talking about
um these isolated products is what
Raphael mushroom and Ethan Russo and
others have been suggesting is the idea
that there's an Entourage effect that
canvas plants produce that THC alone or
CBD alone are less effective than the
two combined or combined with CBG or CBC
or other other cannabinoids and terpenes
so while we're looking at isolating and
purifying single molecules we need to
understand that there are other
components that likely synergize
together so when we strip everything
apart and have isolated compounds we
need to be looking at how the plants are
naturally producing these compounds and
seeing if we can mimic and learn from
strains that are known for pain relief
or anxiety relief or or benefits for
sleep I'm trying to replicate those
Blends when we get to a pure Pharma
model where it's one molecule one
receptor we start to lose some of the
benefits of the plant so while I do
think that a lot of the future will be
driven by these
new synthetic isolated forms of cannabis
I think that they also need to be
combined in structured ways that are
formulated based off of the plant and
also shown in tested and research for
efficacy and validated in that way
yeah I think the Holy Grail is that if
they can isolate the different molecules
and as I said create their own recipe
that is almost replicable to an actual
plant but they can repeat it a billion
times over in a safe and conductive
manner might be the the opportunity
that's out there for the ingredients as
far as one last thing I want to touch on
before you go is the distribution battle
how do you guys see distribution in the
states I know it's it's state by state
at the moment but compared to Canada
what what is the distribution like for a
large-scale brand such as yourself
well the distribution paddle is a really
outside of even the industry itself it's
in the United States that
fact that there's no
really ability to ship across state
lines with it being federally illegal
still what it is is a patchwork of
different markets that are all regulated
differently utilizing different seed to
sale tracking systems using different
distribution models
um and you know what you can do in one
state is very different than what you
can do in another
um so that means that there is no real
model for how this works in the United
States and it has to be
figured out within each market some
markets are I think better regulated and
better set up than others
and when we're talking about
distribution I think one of the really
big red flags used to be looking at is
what's happening in California
where there are distribution centers
that are pushing out and diverting
product into the black market
um and and it's actually a significant
portion of what's being produced in
California is going through distribution
centers being sent to lesser unregulated
markets like New York
um so there's there's a lot of work to
be done on the distribution model in the
US for sure
um unlike Canada that has a more
regulated system
yeah when we were over New York they're
um about 10 months ago there was every
California brand Under person was in all
the illegal dispensaries and one would
wonder whether uh no cross state
competition or transactions how these
are getting there do you ever see a
scenario where
before Federal legalization let's say
two states that cross-border with each
other come to an agreement to come to a
deal that they're going to be allowed
trying to cross-border Commerce that's a
great question you know California's
actually already floated that idea of
partnering with States like Oregon uh
that is neighboring also has a legal
regulated system in setting up their own
state-by-state interstate commerce
um I haven't seen that move forward yet
and it raises really interesting
questions on how the federal government
would view that
um
I do not see a situation where States
like California and New York set up a
system for interstate commerce there's
too many states in between that haven't
legalized yet and I think that's going
to be a hard path forward
um I I do think that the real Holy Grail
that we're aiming for is federal
regulations
yes well let's hope fingers crossed that
2023 is the year where we get a little
bit of gain on the ground because yeah
if we've all got our fingers crossed and
it seems to be the logical thing but
like with things in life the logical
thing doesn't normally get the most
attention Mike thank you very much for
taking your time to do this it's very
much appreciated
thank you so much it's been fun today
hopefully we get to chat you towards the
end of the year and there's more good
news but for anybody who wants to check
out one of Brown's collection I highly
recommend going to the website they are
literally a a phenomenal brand and
they're one of the best product ranges
that I've ever come across so
warnerbrands.com Mike thank you again
for your time and uh until next week
everybody
[Music]
foreign