foreign
to the next episode of the Cannabis
review I am delighted to be joined on
this episode by Felix sunstrum who's the
co-founder and CEO at Spectrum Leaf how
are you keeping today Felix
very good thank you how are you
I'm very well mate thank you very much
for coming on the show and we're looking
forward to talking to you you've got
some of the most Innovative products on
the market and so we hope to give all
the audience an overview can you maybe
give everybody a quick brief of the
spectrum Leaf story how you found
yourself in the Cannabis industry and
how you've found yourself setting up
Spectrum relief
yeah so so my background is from tobacco
I've been working with uh with snooze
product and oral nicotine products for
for 15 years by to coming on board here
uh so and and uh we came across
um a brand called candidates which we
found very interesting uh it's a humble
based uh brand uh and and uh my mission
was then to as with my background from
the smokeless tobacco in in the
Scandinavian European markets to to to
to bring that product into into Europe
so we founded Spectrum leaf
and and on on that note we we also
launched candidates we started with uh
uh with some uh some markets the main
markets for for smokeless tobacco
products news products which are
Scandinavia but also uh Germany
Switzerland Austria
try to build a distribution Network and
which yeah has grown ever since so we
have 15 markets from from uh as of today
we're selling the products in and then
we try to extend the portfolio but the
main mission for for spectrum Leaf is is
really to bring in new novel type
products with a functional Focus so
we're focusing on on functional uh
delivery mechanism especially uh within
uh oral absorption
yeah so and then from there we we
launched a brand called elabor and then
and then boom it's our latest brand
okay so you've got a couple of Brands
Under the Umbrella I was reading about
the Voom uh Innovation lab can you maybe
give everybody that's the r d function
of the company and that's where you're
coming up with the most Innovative
products is that correct yeah so so that
is a brand or actually an r d company
that was founded between myself and
Spectrum leaf and uh and and uh um a
team of Swedish news entrepreneurs uh
Frank s London who's the CEO he has a
quite a substantial
experience from both the production
sales and also sell uh Distributing
nicotine pouches but together we found
it then the Boon Innovation which is an
r d company based in southern Sweden
which really focusing on how to increase
and uh make the the absorption in the
oral cavity uh more effectively
okay interesting because it's great to
see a lot of the time you see um people
setting up businesses who are just kind
of as focused I think some of the most
successful brands that are going to come
to from this industry of people who have
already been established in other areas
as you said like tobacco and they're
able to translate either the the
consumer want and need into the Cannabis
industry or utilize the innovation in
the Cannabis industry for a new product
creation are you saying that yourself
yeah for sure for sure and uh my as I
said my background is with the oral
pouches and we're always seeing that on
my view has always been that that is a
it's a very effective way of of
providing consumers with a smokeless
alternative uh
um the the oral cavity is it's a
fantastic place to to absorb different
very various different types of
uh Collective substances not only
nicotine but in this case uh different
cannabinoids and other other types of
active substances
okay can you maybe give everybody a
preview for what is and why is it going
to be effective in the cannabinoid
industry
uh so snooze is basically uh tobacco
moist tobacco which you put on your lip
and instead of hailing the tobacco or
the nicotine uh you you absorbed it in
the oral cavity uh so it goes through
the mucous membrane and then directly
into your bloodstream uh and and you can
apply that technology to to other types
of substances in our case we believe
that you know with by providing a
a a pouch type product we we can we
don't have to eat and swallow and digest
the the substance that you that you
that you that you take uh it doesn't
have to go through the liver and and and
then it gets more effective with the
absorption in the in in the in the in
the in the in the lower cavity but it
also it's a very safe and better
alternative to smoking because smoking
of today everyone knows how dangerous it
is and and the downsides that comes with
it
excellent do you see for stuff like snow
snow obviously CBD is the big
cannabinoid that everybody uses on the
market but do you see companies starting
to blend and formulate different
cannabinoids and terpenes to bring new
ingredients shall we say because I think
that's where a lot of the big innovation
will come over the next five to ten
years who's built the perfect recipe for
the perfect consumption method I I for
sure and Rooney Innovation is looking at
it every day we have a team that is
that's very well dedicated to to not
only at look at CBD as you mentioned the
terpene profiles are of course super
important but but more than that
different markets across the globe has
different uh regulatory you know
opportunities so to speak uh so for the
US for example you can look at a various
different range of cannabinoids to add
to the formulation but also looking at
Europe
with uh with many big markets opening up
for recreational use and medical use so
so I I think this is only the beginning
for sure
yeah I think a lot of the future will be
biosynthesized companies being able to
create large-scale clean pure
ingredients that will be utilized in the
cpg and the API side of the industries
and tell me this the novel food
application that you guys have managed
to get on the list and be approved how
uh tiresome and painstaking was that
process and is it over now that you're
on the list or is it just one hurdle has
been completed and there's still a bit
of the Journey To Go
uh I wish I could say that it's over but
it's of course not uh and this is of
course only for the UK Market uh uh but
uh but but it's also very promising to
see uh how the FSA has approached this
although it's taken a lot of time we're
still making some progress uh you can
say uh you know because in the European
or in the EU it's quite different uh but
but so this is as I would view with the
first step for us uh we're on the list
uh but we're still not fully approved
but but I think this um could at least
guide guy the consumer in terms of of
these products or are being reviewed and
also uh are uh are hopefully when they
are approved will be you know
safer to use from a consumer perspective
yeah and I think you're you're right
there it all boils back again to the
biotechnology companies been able to get
up to speed and make these ingredients
because I think they'll get approved so
quickly because the the technology
involved behind it where at the moment
the ingredients that people are using
the people who are giving the license
are still not crystal clear on the uh
the exact Purity and strength of each
individual uh motion
attaching
so with another food application as I
said that's just the UK we see a lot of
people getting carried away thinking
that the novel food gives them the geek
get the key to the Golden Gate or
whatever it may be so the UK Market you
guys see has been a a home for for uh
your products or you guys a global
company where this is just the first
step in the stage for you guys uh this
is for sure the first step uh this is
also a UK the FSA who has been uh
pushing this agenda
and and also uh been very clear on
towards us as a company what to do and
what is required of us uh EU has not
really reached that point yet uh but we
are will of course be looking into to or
we have submitted an application for the
EU but but still no feedback and and now
no results so far uh but but we would of
course like to to get our product uh
registered and and tested
as much as possible in order to to avoid
the consumers that are safe to use
okay and speaking of testing there do
you see there is an ample amount of
testing facilities in the UK or in
Europe or do you think that's where
there's still a lack of real capital and
real technology is in the the labs that
are able to actually test products at a
pretty high speed uh compared to let's
say the government agencies and Labs
that are currently doing it
yeah for sure and and and
what one of course could wish for is
it's a universal standard the SOP for
all the labs so we always get the same
results because as of today
uh the bigger more established labs they
don't have that much experience in
testing cannabinoids and also then you
have the in parallel you have smaller
more cannabis driven labs and they they
maybe don't in all cases have the same
Sops and testing in the same ways and if
you don't pass in the same ways you will
not be able to compare the results so so
I think this is something that is very
very important for the future
not only for the consumer safety but
also from a regulatory perspective
because when you're looking at TC levels
you need to ensure that there's no teach
in the products
yeah well I think that's it that THC
trade seems to be the the Handcuff
that's holding a lot of Brands back and
I think that comes from as you said
different labs are testing at different
capabilities and that doesn't give
Clarity to the brands and products do
you see the election over in Great
Britain having any sway on the end
result of the novel food we see your man
rushy sonak coming out and saying he's
against all drugs he's got to punish
everybody used them but your own lives
trust seems to be more open to a
cannabis industry grown in the UK
yeah I do think though that that the UK
has shown until now that they are
progressive liberal Market uh and open
to to have safe and regulated products
but uh but when it comes to politics
it's of course impossible to to foresee
and we we just have to to to to to to
monitor the situation and see what comes
out and then we have to to apply by by
the the guidelines that are are for the
future
do you see uh brexit as a hindrance to
the UK Market grout or do you think it's
been a good thing for them that the the
cannabis companies in Britain will
actually be able to supply the British
industry that there won't be much
competition because if you own companies
that deal business with the UK at the
moment in Europe it's a
nightmare things take like twice as long
the tax on top of all the the orders
that come with it do you think that's
going to end up hindering the industry
long term or do you think it's going to
cocoon us and allow the UK companies to
be able to dominate their own home
territory
to be honest I'm not an expert in this
field but but but but but but my view
would be that because what we saw when
brexit happened uh is that it created a
lot of issues and and you know many
companies had to basically cut down or
wasn't able to to sell to the UK at all
because of the complexity and also that
you didn't really know what rules
applied but I think we have seen at
least an improvement over the last years
and then over a long time
of course the UK will be a huge business
partner to the EU so I think they will
find ways to to smoothen this out but of
course it would be much easier if if
broad brexit wouldn't have occurred to
be honest yeah and a quick jump around
Europe now obviously you're from the
Nordic area of Europe do you see the
Nordic still being pretty severe on CBD
we talked to a couple of guys from
Finland and different areas where it's
it almost seems like CBD is considered a
class a narcotic do you see that uh
loosening over degree or is there a
separate strategy in all the different
states in that part of Europe
yeah I I I think we will see a different
regulatory Frameworks for different from
the different countries Finland Norway
uh but also Sweden to some extent they
have had a fairly The View has been that
simply is maybe not a narcotic but more
a medical type product and it should be
regulated on the from the medical side
uh there's been a few
um
uh verdicts also from from the from the
from the courts in Sweden for example uh
but uh but I think over time when we see
markets like Germany uh and and bigger
trademark trade trade
um
and countries uh for for the
Scandinavian markets opening up an EU
also being very open and the same you
know with the same similar type of
regulatory framework so so I think over
time this will change but I think
Scandinavia is more conservative for
sure than than the southern um European
market so
um it will take time to get a clear uh
framework in place but but long term uh
cannabis and CBD for sure is here to
stay
yeah I think we all got our fingers
crossed that Germany executes their new
industry perfectly and that the capital
generated from tax and whatnot is
actually an example to the rest of the
European countries and that we can
hopefully ride in the jet stream of how
the German industry takes off
I agree fully uh and uh and but but it
will take time we all need to be patient
yeah well this is it it's not a it's not
a Sprint by any stretchy the imagination
you want to have thick skin uh the
ability to learn all sorts of topics in
this industry if you got into kind of
mistake and it's got to be fun you'll
end up with a degree in biotechnology or
in physics or in chemistry or something
to do with uh some special tag that you
didn't even think about Felix it's been
great haven't you we just had our time
there is that and you're looking forward
to over the next 12 months in the
European cannabis industry uh that the
audience should know about
uh you mean for us specifically or in
general you know specifically yeah
no but we're very excited about uh the
laws of the Moon products we're doing
some new things with candidates uh we're
launching a little few new products
there as well but but also for for our
brand elavar with all strips that we're
going to extend the pipeline so so we
have a lot of things coming on and then
we're also looking to some exciting
products for the U.S market as well so
it's it's a it is it is an exciting
times for sure excellent well we look
forward to keeping a track at the
Spectrum Leaf story if everybody wants
to know more about the products on
Spectrum leave the website is there
below highly recommend go and checking
them out they've got some of the most
Innovative products on the market at the
moment so Felix thank you very much for
taking the time today it's been an
absolute pleasure thank you very much
for having me until next episode
everybody