[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined on this episode by greg cooney
who's a co-founder of cannabis
technology house over in israel and tel
aviv greg how are you keeping today
i'm doing great how are you i'm very
well thank you very much mate thank you
very much for taking your time to come
on so you've already had a wealth of
experience in the industry from bringing
a product direct per product at altria
already can you maybe give everybody a
quick little overview of how you got to
where you are with
the company you're in at the mobile
cannabis technology house
for sure i
joined a company in israeli company that
was called green smoke
they were in the e-cigarette space
that company later on got acquired by
altria which is the largest tobacco
company in the united states
and we really focused on innovation
creating new products ways to help
people convert from
combustible cigarettes that are the most
harmful to parts that are reduced harm
and a few years ago
me and a few colleagues so what's
happening in the cannabis space and we
decided that we want to be
entrepreneurs for this opportunity not
employees
so we basically took all the knowledge
we got in terms of how you create
innovation for regulated space what how
do you balance out the consumer the
regulator and the business side
and we wanted to apply it to the
cannabis space
and that's basically how we
came up with our product it's named kube
it's a heat not burn product
um we want it to go to heat not burn
where basically you heat up the flour
instead of burning it but you're still
using authentic flour you're not using
artificial liquids or something like
that because we've seen that that
platform is the most successful in terms
of converting people from combustion
products to something that's less
harmful
so we have these little cubes
inside there's about 0.2 grams
of cannabis flower
and all the user needs to do is put them
in this device
give it a little press
and they're ready to go
so the device is ready to use
and it switches off automatically once
the session is completed there's no wait
there's nothing involved in that
um
and when they finish they just
dispose of the capsule
they can pop
another one right in so there's no
cleaning no hassle involved um and we're
planning to commercialize this in the
united states this year
okay sounds amazing some real innovation
in the space of consumption inhalation
so you're telling me there is this going
to be like espresso pods where i can
just clip in a cartridge boom i don't
have to clean it i don't have to get rid
of any of the the nastiness that
normally comes with putting flour flour
into a vaporizer
you nailed it like the nespresso model
is exactly what we're going for
i acknowledge it there's a lot of people
who are officianados they like the
hassle they like dealing with the big
vaporizers
but we think there's a large audience
that just want the experience and when
we saw that there's this huge innovation
in terms of strain you can now find a
strain that at least claims that they
can solve every problem
but really in terms of how to consume it
half of the markets are still
joints and dried flour in jars
and we're mostly focused on the
recreational space but even in the
medical space it doesn't make a lot of
sense you go to the doctor and you say
well
i have a health problem and he goes okay
here is cannabis it can help you but
your way to consume it is going to
long-term create another big health
problem for you
yeah okay so you guys have this
consumption method inhalation method can
you explain the heat not burn parts that
uh that is a core component of the
product
um
is it the fact that it's just the
capsule that's being connected to it is
allowing some of the heat to happen or
what is the exact engineering behind the
process
for sure so i'll speak a little bit
about the technology itself so heat now
burn is a technology that's already
being applied in the
tobacco space mostly by
icos that was developed by philip morris
international i think it was the one of
the first products that were approved by
the fda is a reduced risk product and
was authorized to uh be on the u.s
market and the idea in heat not burn is
okay we want to get the sensory
experience right because if the
experience is now right people are not
going to shift to our product so it
doesn't matter how
less harmful it is people are just not
going to use it
so
basically the idea is saying let's take
real authentic tobacco but instead of
burning it
we'll just heat it up to the point where
all the components all the oil is
released and a person can inhale it but
we never bring it to the point of
combustion
where all the main harm is created the
mean harm from smoking
is uh not necessarily nicotine it's
mostly the people are inhaling something
that was combusting something that is
burned
so our logic was we wanted to apply the
same technology in the cannabis space
but in a smarter way because it has been
applied
through vaporizers like pax and mighty
and crafty and the main issue we saw
there is um
really for the consumer you spend a lot
of money they're not cheap the devices
and then basically you work
uh for the device the device doesn't
work for you
you work cleaning it all the time and
then you get to a point where it doesn't
matter how much you clean it
you know the experience is not the same
as it was in the beginning
also not great for regulation we saw
that in nicotine
the open tanks that are defined by the
fda's open systems they basically told
um retailers that if you sell this
you'll need to apply by the same
standard as a manufacturing and we saw a
lot of kind of vape stores go out of
business because they just couldn't
comply
and also bottom line it's not good
business because
you spend all these efforts selling
people this expensive device but then
you can really uh offer them your own
flower
so we wanted to solve a couple of issues
one
what we did we moved the heater from the
device
so what you would see a lot and packs
and crafty you have a very large device
and there'll be like an oven inside we
moved it to the consumable so each one
of these capsules have their own little
heater
that allows us to significantly reduce
the size of the device and also the
consumer is getting a fresh experience
every time because it's a fresh heater
every time
and it also took away everything that
has to do with cleaning
so really we wanted to create something
that's 100 focus on the consumer
uh he doesn't have to clean anything all
he needs to do is charge the device pop
in a capsule
um good for business because it's very
kind of classic razer and blades model
and it also good for regulation because
we know exactly what goes inside every
capsule
we control it it's very easy to measure
how many were sold
and so on and so on
yeah i know the more you kind of picture
in your mind the more genius it is and
you can see a future where instead of
going into boy 20 cigarettes you're
going in and selecting from cartridges
that have different flower and different
various cannabinoid and terpene profiles
in them so if you're a silk or blue
smoker at the moment or a jam player
book or to be a relevant
strain and application to pop into your
own individual consumption
exactly and it's very similar to what
you said with the nespresso association
you look at the capsules and you know
that you know the brown one is stronger
and the green one is decaf so long term
that's where we want to get so another
big component we integrated inside this
it's a technology called topography
basically
um
allows us to know when did the consumer
took above how long was the puff and
create kind of the ideal
temperature profile for each strain so
later down the line what we want to do
is basically let's say you buy a red
capsule and that's a certain strain of
thc
and you know what the effect is the
device would recognize the capsule
and automatically adjust the performance
setting of the device so again really
going taking as far as we can the
strategy of the consumer doesn't need to
do anything this is the experience for
the consumer
while at the same time obviously making
sure that it's something that can pass
for future regulations and something you
can build a scalable business on
yeah because i think you've got
regardless of what consumer bracket you
fit into as a canvas consumer
you're going to have your at home
smoking profile your traveling smoking
profile your profile with your friends
so i think that the voice can fit into a
number different scenarios
not trying to overtake one or the other
they all have a place in the ecosystem
uh absolutely and there's always a i i s
a story i tell when people try to better
understand the useless scenarios and i
say
every person who have kids
they know that there's a time and it's
right after your um kids go to sleep and
it's right before you collapse because
you're exhausted and then that point of
time you would like to relax
but not to the extent that if your kids
wake up you're not really able to deal
with that so that's how the idea of
really you know working in cubes
that have a very small 0.2 gram inside
of them uh came to mind so how do you
decide if your tea or coffee is sweet
enough you put a sugar cube inside and
you taste it and here we basically took
the traditional
joint and just broke it down to five
cubes and you can decide if you want a
fifth of a joint two-fifths or you won
the entire experience so this is another
layer of kind of intuitive control for
the consumer
instead of you know letting them
study on on their own how to adjust
resistance and what's the right
temperature
we just felt it's a more intuitive way
yeah now what i think a big part of
getting this to be a global uh
consumer industry will having the dosage
right for people who don't know or have
no education in the industry that they
can feel safe knowing that they got here
making me jealous taking a hit off that
thing yeah we can organize shipments to
ireland talking regulation we we had to
experience some issues with the pact act
in the united states but europe luckily
is is a much more understanding market
so then let me move on to the last topic
the regulatory process that you guys got
to go to is it the equivalent of fda
approval eu approval you're getting
certain territory or is it individual
countries that you have to get approval
from for the device
so really it's one big mess right now
because even the united states it's one
country but it's different regulations
in every state
what we did we basically took everything
we know from uh regulation of
the fda defines electron nicotine
delivery systems
and there's a process of pre-market
approval for that
so we basically took that as our
blueprint for what we need to take into
consideration
so we knew that
it needs to be a closed system where the
consumer can just put anything inside
we knew that there are certain tests we
need to do we know that we need to show
uh that this is not going to appeal to
the wrong audiences
so we just proactively kind of did an
exercise at the early days of saying
okay let's just replace
the fda regulation of electronic
nicotine delivery system let's just
replace the word nicotine with cannabis
and see where we land and that really
what drove our regulatory strategy from
day one so yes at the moment there are
you know regulations in every market but
usually what happens is the fda will
eventually regulate this once it becomes
federally in the united states
and then there'll be kind of standard
regulation and usually other countries
would follow whatever the fda does so
right now in the united states there's
nuances to each market
but the most important thing
it's not to you know sit down and read
every law it's to understand the logic
and what the regulator is trying to
prevent and the regulator's trying to
prevent
a few things one and the most important
thing is that this is used by the target
audience that you don't end up in
situations where
some um
e-cigarette company landed where you
know the marketing basically kind of
jeopardized the entire business because
they intentionally or unintentionally
reached the wrong audience so that's one
the second one you need to make sure
that you know what's inside and that
that's consistent
and then um
[Music]
most most importantly
is that people are really going to move
from a harmful product which is
combustion
and it's no different from cannabis but
basically for nicotine the fda has a
spectrum of harm where not smoking is
obviously the best and a combustible
cigarette is the worst you need to show
that you're actually your product is
gonna help people move from something
that is more harmful to something that
is less harmful and not just gonna you
know
for an example uh have them use both
joints and reduce harm products so the
idea is to really show conversion which
was also one of the reasons we felt heat
not burn is the best way to go
amazing excuse me can you add cbd flower
or hash is is to
what you put into these things relevant
or is it coming specifically from your
own
anything you can put in a joint
i'll clarify not everything you could
put android anything you should put in a
joint
you could put into the system so we we
operate as a technology company so we
partner up with cannabis companies that
have cultivation uh that have that and
we work with them to identify kind of
the perfect settings for their blends
amazing and and then we just set it up
um
yeah theoretically even in the earlier
days we we even tested it with tobacco
just you know as a startup
also as a category you can't really
taste cannabis and stay focused for too
long so tobacco is a good alternative so
even worse with tobacco not that we have
any plans to go into this space
but yeah essentially um
any type of flower springs whether it's
cbd or thc works well with the device
amazing it seems like one of the proper
innovations that i've seen over the last
few years in the industry and i wish you
guys the best of luck we've come to our
time now but thank you very much for
coming on the show mate it's very much
appreciated
thank you it was great to be here thank
you guys if you want to check out the
device and everything about cannabis
technology house you can see the website
down below there it'll be in all the
links whether you're listening to it or
watching it you'll see it below so
thanks again for watching and greg chat
to you again next time hopefully we get
to get an update off your buddy in the
year abs absolutely take care
thanks guys