[Music]
welcome to the cannabis review i'm
delighted to be joined on this episode
by mark
reinders he's the ceo of hem flex group
in europe mark how you keeping today
well yeah i'm very well thank you very
much
excellent delighted to have you on the
show i know you're a busy man so i'm not
going to take up too much of your time
um temflax group seemed to be doing huge
business as of late last two years
seemed to be great
in terms of turnover for you guys what's
the secret to the success that you've
had at hempflex is it the diversion of
diversity of products
or have it been the the timing that you
guys have been able to grow
grow at such a rate now i think it's
both
first of all we have 26 years history in
the industry so we have a lot of
know-how and experience and that's good
of course
especially if you look at the newcomers
and
it's hemp it's uh you need a lot of
experience to grow it to harvest it to
process it so we have this first mover
advantage over there
on the second hand as well our dive
first portfolio of products as we do a
total crop valuation
so actually we're using the crop from
the from the seeds
up to the roots and we bring everything
to market and that makes you
less dependent on specific market
developments
especially what's doing quite well now
besides cbd of course
uh also the animal bedding uh with the
woody court stalk we use for animal
bedding
uh during cove a lot of people took an
animal
and took a pet at home and any bedding
for the cages they refresh decades a bit
more than normally because spend quite a
lot of time at home
and the product is easy to be sold over
the internet so
our diverse portfolio products really
helped us
ramping up the results amazing
it's uh anybody who knows anything about
the industry in europe knows that
i've been reading a couple of the
articles and laughing at some of the
titles like hemp baron and whatnot but
everybody knows that you're one of the
market leaders in europe when it comes
to this industry
can you tell me about some of the
innovations that are happening in hemp
what are let's say the two biggest
things that you see coming because
i can only imagine you guys are grown at
a certain stage now there's just going
to be new products
created for the same type of ingredient
what would you be uh
most likely to show from the roof about
no i see a couple of death elements
going on of course if you look at the
neutral circles
i see developments in cbd
where everybody first focused in the new
market on getting extracts mixing the
extracts to an oil
and sell as a tincture or a capsule um
i think that the the i always call them
the first generation cbd products and
we are now in the second generation
maybe already starting the third
generation
cbd products where cbd is becoming more
an ingredient in functional food or
becoming more
an ingredient with other ingredients uh
like vitamin
or or um uh
um other additives like herbs or or kirk
mean and that kind of stuff
so it it's really getting a development
on the other hand
for the fibers we see a massive increase
interest for textile
where hemp can replace cotton cotton is
from an environmental point of view
[Music]
very polluting fiber and what are use
pesticide use
fertilizer use and that's all those
kinds hemp
doesn't have we don't use pesticides we
don't use artificial fertilizers we
don't use
a lot of water to grow the hemp and
modifying the hemp fiber into
a spinal fiber on cotton lines could
change the industry massively
the same is valid we see in non-woven
industries for disposables where hemp
can
replace micro plastics so textiles
disposables are very interesting trends
to follow
okay amazing ireland is known as a
construction
uh country we've got a lot of kind of
global companies that play a role in
this industry
the prices recently went up for
construction how do you see the prices
comparing for using hemp pre compared to
the
the regular overheads for uh building
structures with regular concrete
yeah it depends a little bit on how well
introduced
the product already is in the country in
the market um if i think if you're
asking a
traditional construction company to use
this kind of materials they are not
familiar with they
tend to calculate extra costs for the
risk or finding out what works or
they're just afraid for it i know there
are now already specialized companies in
europe working quite a long time with
the materials
and they can build houses for very
competitive prices
other hand you also have to ask yourself
the question does an hemp house
needs to be as cheap as a traditional
house
in the end is the cost of the total cost
of ownership not the cost of
construction but the total cost of
ownership so
if you have an improved insulation value
you earn back the higher cost during the
lifetime of the house
because of the insulation or keeping
your house cooler in the summer like
what's ham doing perfectly you save a
lot of energy cost
on on on the climate control of your
house
uh and in the end at the end of life
cycle and i agree
not so many people are thinking about
the end of life cycle of the house if
you build a house
but to dispose all these materials again
uh the recyclability of hemp is much
better and and and you will save quite a
lot of money there so
the total ownership cost will be much
lower
um on another one let's say on the food
and novel act that we were talking about
is basically this going to be the next
big gateway you do see all the big
companies sitting
sitting at the side waiting for a couple
of companies to get approved novel food
license and then they will be the main
ingredient supplier
and are you guys in the mix to be one of
those main companies
yeah we are part of the the novel food
consortium of the european international
hemp presentation
where we technically pass the validation
it's not published yet
but it's uh awaiting the talk studies
the stock studies
have been started they are designed and
they're about to start
you know talk study takes quite a long
time to
complete and i have to say the fsa took
their very
pragmatic standpoint is okay we will
accept a
null food application even without a tax
study as long as the tax studies being
initiated
um i i think they've really realized
very well
that that the process of an old food
application
takes very long on the other hand it's
also being realized if you're taking the
products from the shelf you can take
away
the supply but you will never take away
the demand
so and that means the demand goes
underground and then you lose two
complete control so i think the ffa did
a very well job there
in regulating the market in order to try
to safeguard the consumer safety because
consumer safety is the most important
thing
there is and and we have to be sure that
the brands are in the market are
produced
in a food safe and correct way
okay interesting and do you consider now
to
is the hemp industry the same as the
cannabis industry to you in europe
are they completely separate in your
eyes
uh to my opinion the separate you know
if you mentioned with cannabis uh the
medical
uh marijuana and recreational marijuana
activities and with hemp you mean
industrial hemp because in the end both
are
related in the cannabis family but uh
if i speak about hemp i speak about
industrial hemp i speak about hand below
0.2 percent tsc
there are two different industries
medical and recreational are growing
mostly indoors indoor operation
have other distribution lines and full
focus on
on on on the cannabinoids psychoactive
or not
industrial hand for me is really the
total crop valuation so you can take the
leaves for for
extracting cannabinoids for the food
supplements
but you also take the seeds for food oil
protein powder and and the fiber for
many applications so
for me hemp is is it really different to
them than cannabis
okay and you guys have three different
uh
facilities for the agriculture of the
crop do you guys see yourself expanding
into different territories or do you
prefer the territories that you're in at
the moment
they facilitate the different processes
that the plant comes through
we have currently indeed three
facilities uh two decades
decortication facilities uh one in the
netherlands and one in romania
that's where the first step takes place
growing the hemp and
processing it into fiber and chives
that's we always do the growing we
always do 50 kilometers
around the factory in order to reduce
transportation
distances and costs and emissions
and marketing the fiber and the end
products we do around six seven hundred
kilometers around the facility so by
doing like that
you get like a telephone network you're
trying to cover the european market
so with having a plant in the
netherlands and one in romania currently
we have very good
coverage of the european market and the
part of the turkish market
the third facility is in the southern
part of germany
where we produce insulation material um
so the fiber is being transported to
to that place and they're being
transferred into insulation material but
insulation material is very
light it's only 35 kilos
per cubic meter and most of the seals
are in southern germany
and austria as being part of the
the the building systems they have there
it's more wood-based building
a prefabricated wood-based building
where a
natural fiber insulation product like
hemp
fits much better than any other
synthetic or mineral
insulation but we see
that as soon as factory has reached its
maximum capacity
and transportation distances to our
clients are increasing
we always look for opportunities to to
set up a facility there
as well to serve the market there but uh
for us always
important develop the market first
before you start growing and building a
factory smart business strategy
last thing before i let you go i know
you're a very busy man what's the big uh
trajectory upwards for hemp industry
over the next two three years what's the
one thing that you think is the most
exciting thing that's going to come
happening
uh i think what i see happening is that
the the hype and i also almost sometimes
tend to think it's more craziness around
cbd will come down a little bit i don't
think that
that hemp uh growing for cbd only will
will survive or continue to grow
i think the switch will be made to the
total crop valuation more and more
and therefore you need the
infrastructure so you can't
practice total crop valuation if you do
not have a
professional decodecation facility in
your area so and
what i i said before but i i see
more and more initiatives coming up uh
trying also to capture the other revenue
streams so
um i think uh hemp
was a big crop in the past till the
prohibition came after prohibition it
was a lot of pioneering but i feel we
we are leaving the pioneering phase and
we are really entering into the majority
growing up phase and that in a couple of
years i think the area
of industrial hemp grown in europe and
other countries
will only increase more and more
especially as the positive effect hemp
can bring
on fighting the climate change and cold
fit
caused a lot of trouble for us i i do
realize that but i think also it helped
us
the people realizing that we have to
change the world and
let's say let us pick up this
opportunity we have for changing the
the the climate in a positive way and
getting a green recovery with hemp
that's a great way to end the show
having a low carbon footprint shall be
the main principle for every company i
think now in this modern day and age
mark you're a busy man i'm going to let
you get out of here thank you very much
for taking part in the show it's very
much appreciated and have a great day
and hopefully chats again soon
absolutely thank you very much