foreign
to the next episode of the Cannabis
review I'm delighted to join this
episode by Jeff Ross and who's the
founder and president of the Institute
of karma science over in the U.S how are
you keeping today Jeff doing great how
are you I'm fantastic thank you very
much for taking the time to do this I
know you're a busy man at the moment
everybody coming at the left Writing
Center
a lot of interest right now in this
subject yeah there most certainly is can
you maybe give everybody in like under
60 seconds an overview of how you've
decided to set up the Institute of
cannabis science and what the main
objective that you're looking to achieve
is
yeah so the Institute of cannabis
science exists to do research that
benefits consumers in particular my
concern that led me to found the
Institute was the misinformation in
cannabis markets that is many products
are not labeled accurately and sometimes
safety tests haven't even been performed
properly and um all of this comes down
to the fact that third-party Labs
provide the testing for the cultivators
and producers who then sell the products
but sometimes these third-party Labs
themselves can be dishonest and the
producers will shop for the lab that
gives them the best answer the producer
wants so that problem is called lab
shopping it's a common challenge in
regulatory science and we need
non-profits and other engagement in
order to get Regulators to fix the
problems and in order to bring the
scrutiny necessary so that we all have
honest data about weed
okay very interesting so can we give
everybody a quick little overview what
is science science is the measurement of
different elements in the universe is
that correct
yeah yeah I think that I agree science
always starts with a measurement yep so
science is about making measurements and
understanding a given property usually
we examine some physical property or
something that we notice around us in
the universe and then
um typically we try to measure it or
quantify it in some way that usually
involves making a number right and once
we figure out how to measure it and
observe it like say the brightness of
light in a room and put a number to it
um then we can use that information and
try to draw some insights that's really
the goal is to start with making a
measurement
interpret the information maybe make a
range of measurements over some space
and then come away with an Insight or
real understanding
amazing so what is the main way of
measuring cannabis
so the main way of measuring cannabis
and usually when we're measuring
cannabis what we're asking about is what
are the main compounds that are in there
I think a lot of us know that
tetrahydrocannabinol THC is sort of the
main drug-like compounding cannabis
although there are a lot of other active
compounds so
um if I want to know how much THC is in
my cannabis flour well I can't just look
at it right I need to actually take that
cannabis flower and soak it in some
liquid until all the THC comes out into
the liquid and then I take up that
liquid and I measure it very carefully
to see exactly how much THC is dissolved
then if I know the mass of the flower
that I started with I know how much THC
was in that given mass and that's a
useful thing that usually comes out as a
percent
okay and some of the stuff that we're
seeing obviously in the moment is
basically the certain THC levels being
stated at a certain number and it being
actually is a different number by the
time it gets to the shelves is the issue
happening at their testing the minute
it's cultivated and it then has to go
through a number of processes like
Machinery that's could devalue the THC
or the cannabinoid content or is it just
uh lazy management at a cultivation
level
that's a really good question because
actually
um you know this this one buzzword THC
inflation
is probably a couple of different
regulatory problems I believe that one
thing that does happen is that some Labs
find they have an economic incentive to
provide numbers that are a little bit
larger than their competitors and so I
do believe that sometimes there is
deliberate fraud but also a lot of the
problem that we have specifically in
Massachusetts and this is also true in
other states but the regulations are
different in each one so the exact
nature of the problems vary but in
Massachusetts we have poor definitions
for what counts as cured flour or dried
flour and the reporting basis for
cannabinoid compounds and whether that's
by dry weight basis so what that comes
down to is
the amount of water in the Cannabis
flower at the time of testing is not
specified by the regulations and a
significant amount of the weight of the
Cannabis flower comes from water so if
the if if the flower could be wetter or
drier but the rules don't say exactly
what moisture content I'm testing at
then I actually don't I don't really
know what the concentration means
because I don't know the total weight of
the flower that was tested and how to
compare that with the flower I buy
so some of the problem is bad
definitions another challenge is that
the THC in cannabis flower is not mostly
actually the compound THC it's mostly
present as a precursor compound called
tetrahydrocannabinolic acid thca and
it's upon heating that compound that it
gets converted into THC in the process
of smoking so the differences in
definitions of compounds make or the
differences in the actual compounds that
are present make it difficult to say
clearly what are the contents and if I
look at a label that tells me a THC
percent I need more information to know
what that number really signifies
so there are several problems I do
believe that also sometimes degradation
of cannabinoids can happen after
packaging but I don't believe that
that's often a big problem because most
packages of cannabis flower don't sit
around for years before they get sold
and it generally generally the flower
once it's packaged is in the darkness so
it's not exposed to light which tends to
catalyze these reactions and it's also
kept pretty cool like at room
temperature
so
um if there were significant
decomposition of cannabinoid compounds
we would see that in our testing because
we would see elevated levels of
cannabinol but we don't
yeah so despite in CBN would be able to
tell if the degradation has happened at
that level it tell me this in the
compliance side of things that
third-party testing is this stuff in
force or are they more incentivized to
have the big client yes there are no sir
three bags full so we'll be able to get
the the level that you want or is there
strict rules in any of the states where
it's legalized where the lab testing in
the protocol is actually very regimented
and you can let's say boost it up by an
extra five percent to THC just because
you're going to get a 24 month contract
question um
um a better better structured
regulations are definitely more
enforceable
um that's definitely true but to some
degree the problem that we have really
comes from dishonest Behavior right and
it's a behavior problem and a problem of
incentives right as you said right this
yes or no sir three bags full I mean
that lab that that lab is serving the
cultivator
and the cultivator is their client their
customer and in America at least we
always say the customer is always right
so the lab is doing good business if
they give their customer exactly what
their customer asks for and if their
customer calls up the lab every time
they get a number they don't like and
say could you please retest that I know
there's more THC in my weed
then the lab has to do that retest right
so I understand the pressures that
people are under but we find that only
you know there's only there's usually
like two out of ten labs
that everyone knows in a given state are
producing bad results
um those Labs usually do pretty well
okay and is it okay so basically there's
no federal legalization so therefore
there's no standard testing agency like
an FDA or something like that that's
going around to everything or do they
already exist in the relative States
they just can't cope with the quality
yeah each state has been tasked with
coming up with its own Regulatory and
enforcement scheme and so that's why the
results are so different in each state I
do agree with you if there was a more
standardized approach usually the
federal government and federal agencies
are much more proactive with stuff like
this
um and definitely in the state of
Massachusetts our regulatory agency has
struggled to figure out what constitutes
an effective action so
um definitely improvements in the rules
and regulations
that's why I founded the Institute of
cannabis science is because
um
a non-profit that what we do is we're a
non-profit and we we test products off
the shelves ourselves
and then provide information to people
about what happens so
um in a way we kind of short-circuit the
whole usual process that you would wait
for
and provide answers right away
um and fill some of that Gap that's left
by a lack of federal enforcement
okay moving on to the medical side of
the Cannabis industry is the future of
the over in Europe I think we have a lot
stricter rules the farmer companies are
ingrained in a lot of the kind of
cosmetic ingredients in food and
beverage type ingredients do you see in
within 10 years time that like 60 or 70
percent of this industry from Cosmetics
to food and beverage those molecule
ingredients are going to come from let's
say three or four major companies that
have either perfect biosynthesis or do
you always think that there's going to
be room for a cultivated flower and the
environmental impact and the capital
extensive outlay that goes with that
that is that is very interesting
um I I have a couple of different
thoughts about that actually so
um
in terms of Edibles and beverages right
those kinds of cannabis products are
they fit a lot closer with standard
consumer package goods and um
and the production of those it's
companies are finding pretty good
success at
at being national leaders so um in fact
you know there are now like a lot of
Beverage companies for cannabis that are
pretty new within the last couple of
years that are actually they're all
buying their cannabinoid
um their cannabinoid Emulsion right
because cannabinoid compounds actually
have terrible solubility in water so
just making an Emulsion that's dissolved
in water is a lot of work right well
there's a company called vertosa
that makes cannabinoid Emulsion in many
states and they sell their cannabinoid
Emulsion to many different beverage
makers so we're already seeing that some
parts of the supply chain the commodity
parts of the supply chain are firming up
and being dominated by individual brands
in some cases and I believe that that
will continue to happen with Beverages
and edibles but there is a large part of
the Cannabis consuming community that is
very partial to smoking flour and we're
not going to stop anytime soon and
growing flour is a totally different
process it's not like making Coca-Cola
it's not a not really as much of a
chemical process and there's more art
so I believe that there will continue to
be a robust sector
producing craft cannabis and I believe
that there will also be a few big
companies producing kind of commodity
cannabis flower mids you know I mean a
lot of people will probably dis as the
McDonald's of cannabis but like some
people will like it and it'll be
affordable
um but probably eventually most of that
you know eventually with Federal
legalization the other development that
will happen is interstate commerce and
then what you will find is that the most
economical place in the world to produce
these mid-grade like this mid-grade
pretty decent commodity cannabis that's
not Super Craft all of it will come from
California
and it'll all be sun grown and that'll
be by far the best like the most cost
effective way to produce modestly decent
weed that's not absolute like top grade
right for a large consume for a large
Market the same way we produce all our
other produce in America
yeah it's going to be very interesting
to see how different the European and
the North American markets end up coming
over the next 10 to 20 years because I'm
sure you saw the news of Germany opening
up for the Social Clubs and a trial
period of five years so it's a diluted
version of what they were going to do
but in my opinion it was always
basically what was going to happen the
Pharma biotech companies are so strong
and powerful over here they see the
market of as value owners have been an
ingredient supplier and they're happy to
let the non-for-profit flower activist
side of the industry have at it right
now but they want to protect and ring
fence that uh that big chunk of them at
the ingredient side industry it's going
to be interesting to see how those two
models end up coalescing because when
Federal legalization comes is comes we
all know how capitalism works and it's
the bigger and the stronger eat the
smaller and the little and then the
bigger the stronger one to expand their
words and it's going to be interesting
to see whether that model is available
in Europe yet for the North American
companies yeah I think that there's in a
little bit of a difference because
um our um our Banking and business
environment makes it our has made it
extremely difficult for any established
company to dip its toe into this
industry
right so um that's really prevented a
lot of the
let's prevented a lot of tobacco
companies and pharmaceutical companies
from immediately launching a bunch of
cannabis products
um but you're right
um and some the you know some of the
market
analysis that you point to in Europe
also it stands to reason will be
replicated here
um people people aren't like Farmers
aren't famous for getting rich right so
the people growing cannabis like it's
not going to be such a ridiculous cash
crop as some people seem to have hoped
and
um if if the predictions come true and
10 years from now a really large
percentage of the Cannabis in America is
consumed in beverages then it is it's
going to be more like you said right
that's a chemical product it's going to
be made like Coca-Cola again right they
ship bags of concentrate to every to
different bottling plants in different
states right and then they assemble
their product in bottling plants adding
carbonated water and it's going to be a
similar process of distribution right
that's a model that that's already been
scaled up so
um that will definitely be a big part of
the production and then yeah there will
be spaces for craft producers and some
of them will be like fine wineries right
they'll make plenty of money and they'll
be plenty famous but that'll be a
competitive thing to get into and it'll
be a different kind of art than
what we see right now yeah well would
you believe I'm talking next to Anna
Schwab who basically we're going to
break down genetics and a few little
bits and pieces so uh I'm very lucky to
get to two two experts such as
yourselves you know back to back and see
both sides of this oh that's awesome
that's awesome yeah yeah say hi to her
well most certainly will work just over
our time now jf7 fortune we've got to
wrap it up but I could talk to you well
David the chemical process in cannabis
hopefully we maybe get to touch base
again towards the end of the year and we
can give each other an update on the
various territories and the medical
advancements and scientific advancements
that would be great
excellent super strong thank you for
your time thanks everybody for watching
we'll see you the next episode
[Music]