[Music]
welcome
to the cannabis review we've got a great
show for you today this man has been in
the news a hell of a lot over the last
couple of weeks and has been granting
great momentum in the irish cannabis
industry and getting some good backing
after some
horrendous actions by the guards in some
of the stores i'd like to welcome jp
o'brien the owner of little collins how
you doing jp
good day owen how are you mate thanks
for having us on
i'm sure everybody's been looking to
talk to you over the last couple of
weeks with all the stuff that's kind of
happened here in ireland
um before we get into all of that kind
of stuff do you want to basically give
everybody just a little overview of the
story of little collins
how you guys started and how you got to
where you are now
yes certainly um so basically little
collins is a
it's a family company formed by myself
and my wife eda
um we're both health-driven people
we're non-drinkers we're sort of vegans
we
we really um ultimately our store is
pretty simple we we moved from australia
to
ireland to start up this business um you
know that's 17 and a half thousand
kilometers and
my wife's irish i'm australian and um
we just believe in providing people a
choice so a choice between
you know a pharmaceutical product which
is great that everyone can get from the
chemist and
and and that's perfect um or a natural
product a natural alternative and that's
what we're here for
that wraps in nicely to our overall sort
of life ethos
and um here we are we've been open since
november 22
2018 and we're into the start of 21
we've got the two stores in the online
business so
it's great to be here excellent so
that's kind of gets everybody up to
speed to where we are at the moment
um can you kind of give what has it been
like for you guys over the last couple
of weeks dealing with all this nonsense
for those who don't understand the
situation that's happening at the moment
it's because of
legislation difference between ireland
and the eu
little collins are selling cbd flair
which is completely
legal under eu law that was passed last
december
irish law just hasn't caught up with it
what's it been like dealing with this
kind of nonsense now when you're in the
right
yeah well owen it's um excuse me one
second
that's fine it's frustrating um it's
simply frustrating because we
we wouldn't have you know we did do our
research and we did touch bases with all
the
the relevant authorities before opening
the business and
i think our solicitor actually summed it
up quite well when i first met him after
the first raids i said sean you know
what's going on
it seems like the goal posts have shift
shifted i should say
um and now just to catch people up
the product that we sell is herbal
cannabis okay
now excuse my dodgy hand um i injured it
last week it's herbal cannabis
now it has 0.2 or less thc the
psychotropic
molecule compound in the plant to make
it legal in europe
now we provide that as a you know a
natural supplement
um we believe in the natural products it
is legal throughout
europe irish ireland is the only member
state
continuing with their kind of aggressive
action towards the hemp industry
but the the frustrating thing is that
two and a half years ago for all intents
and purposes this stuff was legal in
ireland as well because i had
conversations and emails with a number
of authorities and
as the solicitor said you'd hardly be a
criminal
if a you moved 17 and a half thousand
kilometers off across the wheel to start
your criminal
organization but then b you decided to
tell the police before you did it
because you know that just doesn't make
sense and you know after verbal
conversations and
and this you know we were assured at the
beginning that that it was legal in
ireland but there is still legislation
to be amended to get
ireland in tune with the european law
european law does sit above irish law in
this case there's no doubt in the world
so
um the fact of that matter is yeah
there's a bit to work out but
um yeah that's kind of where it sits at
the moment and it's unfortunate because
there's so much potential in the
industry
but the irish government does is just
lagging behind a little bit in terms of
legislation
yeah it seems a whole ah a whole lot of
pointless exercise for something
that uh everybody knows you're in the
right any lawyer who looks at this
legislation property would be able to in
a second or judge
on your side it's just about these guys
catching up with
what they're doing and in some ways you
can understand to a degree if this is a
one solve whereas a police just saw a
flower
and they don't know the difference
between 0.2 but consistently for it to
be
done when they know they're being proved
to be wrong seems to be just a fool's
errand at this stage
and oh and um i'll just actually go on
there because the the flower itself a
lot of people don't know
it's it's hemp but um and in the first
six twelve months we still explain this
to a lot of people and it was very
confusing for us to begin with but
let's just remember that hemp and
cannabis are the same thing
they they really are but it's the
difference between
a non-alcoholic beer and an alcoholic
beer if you want to really generalize
simple analogy there and hemp the hemp
that is legal in europe is cannabis
sativa l and the whole plant is legal
and that's that's what we sell we have a
whole plant philosophy and
we would to be honest mate if it was a
situation where over the last two years
we were receiving public health
complaints
and you know we weren't busy as a
company we weren't growing exponentially
the irish public wasn't accepting hemp
cannabis into their lives with
with glee quite frankly if if that
wasn't the situation we'd probably walk
away
because we'd be like look the products
are you know a bit iffy and uh the
people don't want it and the law's a bit
iffy anyway so we'll just leave it alone
but quite the opposite is true the irish
public are screening out for natural
alternatives
the the product market fit of cannabis
to ireland is
100 symbiotic and um
yeah we just feel like the government
aren't being quite
transparent let's say in their
communications
and it's unfortunate that smaller
retailers like ourselves and a bunch of
other retailers who i'm sure you're
about to
you've mentioned before you might even
mention here have been targeted to
essentially try and crush the the
grassroots industry that sprung up in
the last two and a half years
that's not fair because the grassroots
industry has only one thing in mind
and that is to create a cannabis
industry in ireland that's good for
everyone
we're not trying to send this stuff
overseas we're not trying to siphon
profits overseas we're not doing a b
and c we just want hemp and cannabis to
grow in ireland we want
local retailers selling the stuff we
want local farmers growing it
it's as simple as that and we want adult
conversations not
opaque government that does raids and
then won't even comment it's
absolutely ridiculous it's not a
democracy and
quite frankly they don't even say
anything i mean
where's stephen donnelly does steven
donald talk
accepted a few tweets every now and
again like where is the guy
we sent in 100 copies of the proposal
for
how an industry would look in ireland
and we received replies of pretty much
everybody was entered into
and every single one of them directed it
back to stephen donnelly and he's the
only person that we haven't received a
reply from yet so
i don't know whether it's lack of
education on his behalf or
what it is putting against me
it's yeah like whatever it's a lack of
it's certainly
um it's certainly a lack of speech
that's for sure
yeah come here tell me there's a
question on the delta
8 and delta 9. have you seen the huge
increase in sales of delta 8 over in the
states where the territories where hemp
is legal because they're getting around
the laws
i haven't i haven't actually looked into
that mate okay have a look at that so
they're basically
delta 8 is basically a synthetic version
of delta 9 thc which is illegal
so delta h has now been copied and
they're selling it in any territory
where hemp is legal they're allowed cell
delta eight
and it's psychoactive because it's
synthetic yeah
so yeah it was just one of those ones i
thought you might have come across just
tell me this and tell me tomorrow the
industry in 10 years in ireland
how do you see it do you see in 10 years
time full dispensaries on the corners
like in california
or do you see it always staying as a
medical and pharmaceutical grade
industry i'll tell you one thing i'll
tell you one thing that will happen
and it'll happen to a degree i don't
know what degree but it'll happen to a
degree ireland will follow other
countries
right ireland will follow other
countries but we are here and the
cannabis community is here in ireland to
make sure that we set our own path to a
degree as well
because there's no point just following
in other countries because let's face it
the world's not perfect so let's do our
own thing
how do i see it in 10 years is a very
good question and i told you before the
show that i think of an answer and i
still haven't thought of an answer but
um
mates it's really hard to say in a
decade from now but
but i will tell you how i'd hope to see
it in 10 years we would hope to see
a let's say a flourishing and growing
irish cannabis industry that is
fully regulated retail for adult use
cannabis so
over 18s can purchase thc products
there is no reason why in 10 years we
can't have
a large manufacture manufacturing sector
sector in terms of hemp cannabis and
cannabis in this country both large
growers and small growers
we'd like to see micro markets in
ireland in terms of
not sure if you've seen with the the
breweries you have the large breweries
that
you know that pump out a lot of beer
like guinness for example and then
you've got a micro brewery scene where
they use
select ingredients and you know uh
sort of high quality practices this sort
of thing to create a really high quality
quality
product now in australia where i come
from
the micro brewery industry has grown
larger
than the you know the main industry
because everyone loves the micro beers
right
because they're tasty they're made with
good ingredients and etc
the same thing can happen with cannabis
the same thing can definitely happen
with cannabis there's
blue sky horizons with cannabis and
ireland there's no reason why island
can't have
the next guinness on its hand in ten on
its hands in ten years time but that
guinness
is a cannabis bud and it's a strain it's
an irish strain
and this country can stamp its place on
the international scene
but we need people in charge who are
brave enough and clever enough to
to to lead this kind of new frontier
because any frontier is a new frontier
and
it's the wild west and although cannabis
was
was very legal on this planet just a few
hundred years ago and although cannabis
grows freely on the side of the road in
places like bhutan and the pigs eat it
there we do live in a state of
prohibition and so there is a lot of
um there's a lot of bushes to sort of
whack through to get to this sort of
10-year goal but we can do
it but we need the right people in
charge and we need to all be on the same
page we need to all be
um trying to achieve the same thing if
we're not trying to achieve the same
thing
um what what will end up being achieved
will be
um just a mix and match of everything
and it won't be any good we all need to
be on the same page page and first of
all mate the first thing we need to do
is the government
need to start communicating with the
industry on the ground it's as simple as
that
we're we are now a large company we have
two stores we're opening a store in the
heart of dublin this year
so that's three cannabis dispensaries in
ireland
before hopefully before the government
can even get the legislators legislation
sorted out make a simple amendment to
the 1977 misuse of drugs
that's not that hard pick up the pen get
it done
and we can move forward but obviously
there's a few roadblocks in the way
we feel like we're at a critical
juncture right now at the start of 2021
in terms of ireland
and um and cannabis and we urge everyone
to continue pushing
and to continue speaking and educating
about this plant because
the future is bright if we hold them to
account
that's what i'm going to say okay very
nice yeah
i think that's it it's all about keeping
up the pressure now for everybody in the
industry and realizing that we're very
close to being able to have somewhat of
a
an assembled legalized industry over
here without going too overboard with
full high thc products there's no need
to go in no it's not
just yeah absolutely not you the thc
yeah
so thc there would need to be a cap in
our opinion there should be a capture at
the beginning at the very least and um
yeah we actually set out a few thoughts
there on twitter and it's something we
should get on
on paper but we've got great people like
yourselves of course working hard on all
that sort of thing and geno so um
yeah 100 if it's done safely and um
correctly there's no reason why everyone
can't win but um
but yeah let's let's see yeah no i
couldn't agree with you more
i want to thank you very much for taking
your time to chat with us today i want
to get you off i know you're a busy man
today so it's much appreciated you're
coming on and hopefully we can talk to
you again another few months and we've
got a good
happy progress update and maybe steve
and donnelly might have stuck his head
and replied to somebody's email at some
stage
that would be brilliant that would be
green if he does and lock in another
chat um when the
judicial review is a bit a bit further
down the track oh and we'll have a chat
then
yeah brilliant to bring eid which is
well the next time i exactly
change it about all right yeah thanks a
lot and we appreciate it
have a good day bye