[Music]
welcome everybody to another episode of
cannabis review thanks so much for
joining us i'm delighted to be joined by
nick pateras who's the managing director
of materia europe how you keeping nick
very well thanks thanks for having me
today i'm delighted to talk to you today
there's going to be lots of exciting
things happen in europe over the next
couple of years so
get to here good to hear some inside
information from one of the leading
companies out there so
do you basically want to give everybody
a little quick overview of how you got
into the cannabis into yourself and how
you found yourself material and we'll
move into our first topic then
yeah sure so so my personal background
is actually in the more traditional
pharma space
um and healthcare space so i spent most
of my career actually working for
johnston johnson when i was based in
toronto
so um i helped with helped run some of
their
otc businesses and some of their rx
businesses as well
it's more on the commercial strategy
side and then um after a few years there
was looking for something more um
something probably
something smaller where i could make
more of an impact the cannabis space
wasn't something that i thought about
uh too early but around 2016 it started
to
attract my attention and i joined a
small tech company called lift
co which was well known in the canadian
industry for the expos that it put on
every year attracted thousands tens of
thousands of consumers
um every year to its two shows um and i
joined as an early stage employee i
think
employee number seven and uh we had a
great uh
we had a great series of three years
together uh where we scaled the company
up to 70 employees
there was a go public in the middle
there and added a few businesses to
it by way of a retail training program a
data analytics business as well
and then coming to the end of that time
i i felt as though i wanted to be closer
to the plant and i was also really keen
on what was happening in the european
market
that timed well with when the material
project was being put together
by deepak and michael garba the other
co-founder
and so they asked me to join the
management team and in doing so i
relocated
back to london which is my my place of
birth and so i'm now based in london
overseeing our european operations here
amazing brilliant and well get straight
into the topics because there's a lot of
things that i'd love to have a
more than 15 minutes with you because i
think there's a lot of exciting things
happen in europe and you guys seem to be
at one of the forefronts of it
can you tell me the strategy that
material have for the cannabis industry
in europe what exactly is your position
here in this
yeah so we've got two two business units
and the primary one is really focused on
medical cannabis
so on the medical cannabis side we do
processing and distribution
so our cornerstone asset is a facility
that we have been building out in malta
just to be clear we don't do cultivation
we never will we think it's a very
technical um
skill set to actually get agriculture of
agricultural operations
of a plant like cannabis right
especially
in an eugmp environment and of course
that
vertical we think is going to become
increasingly more competitive as all the
uh the sunnier more tropical climates
actually come online too
so right from the get-go right from the
initial architecture of the company we
decided that we didn't want to do
cultivation
so in malta what we're actually doing is
processing a flower into
eugmp and extraction as well
so that allows us to actually develop
and release qp release products into the
european market
from outside of europe that's where the
cornerstone
asset uh we've been working on it for
about two years now
and it's quite close to um it's quite
close to finalization and licensure so
we're excited about that
and then we stitched that processing
ability together with our distribution
asset in germany
so about a year ago we acquired a
company that
was almost fully licensed for
distribution we got it to the final
stage of licensing
and then actually um have been trading
in third party products
since then and so uh those are the two
pieces that we actually stitched
together on the medical cannabis site
yeah i was doing upon my research i saw
that acquisition last year that you guys
had in the eu gmp certification coming
through in january
so it seems to be things are moving in
the right direction with the right
amount of energy behind them
the next topic i want to talk about is
the mergers and acquisitions that we're
having so far this year do you see 2021
being the year that
the consolidation happens in europe or
do you still think we're way off from
that we're just kind of having our
first initial tease of these big deals
um i definitely think it's going to be
the first
wave of m a for sure i think you'll see
like like we've
seen in the canadian market and to an
extent in the u.s market these things
don't concentrate in a single 12-month
period
but i think the first semblance of
consolidation will definitely happen in
europe now
partly because the european market is
i'm
starting to become more understood
globally
the opportunity size is being
appreciated and i think now
when the first few players actually
start to engage in m a activity
um that really queues a lot more energy
and interest in other types of m a so
when we saw the cura leaf
mac deal recently i think that spawned a
whole bunch of energy and excitement
about what europe represents
yeah i think it's whether you're missing
your friends going to the club or
whether it's the investors missing out
in the big opportunities that fear are
missing out gently drives a lot of
footfall towards big deals
yeah i think it also reflects um you
know the general investment thesis on
just
broadening an addressable market
broadening a market that is going to at
some point
in the future not positing as to when
but eventually have recreational
access open up as we we know a couple of
countries are already working on either
recreational bills or recreational uh
pilot programs
so for a big company like cure leave uh
which has you know
us opening up in in terms of whether
it's
banking access or whatever in the us and
they're actually looking beyond the us
i think it's a strong signal for what
europe actually represents as a
whole other market to tap into yeah no i
couldn't agree with you more
and do you see basically the amount of
people i've talked and like from the
bureau of cannabis in california or the
department of marijuana enforcement to
colorado everybody says that medical is
just a
conduit for recreational and that seems
to be where the money is and where
the best regulation can happen when it
gets to that level
because in in essence a lot of consumers
could be paying a specific price for a
product that they could have a multitude
range from when it becomes recreational
do you see the the model of pharmacies
and
the sales true pharmacies being the
model for the next few years or do you
see that turning into dispensaries and
let's say independent independent craft
growers like with wine let's say
you're going to have a specific strain
for each country your master grows in
each country and then it's who owns
the distribution rights to these
genetics will be the model
yeah it's an interesting question i
definitely think anytime
adult uses legalize where there's a
pre-existing medical framework there's
always a clash between the two
we saw it in canada um where prices and
certain products
might not be available or might not be
at eq at equal levels
between the two frameworks in europe you
have an interesting uh position because
everything is sold through pharmacies
which is not the case in north america
the canadian lps who
sell medically sell directly to
consumers or patients sorry
um on the medical side in the us
obviously there are medical cannabis
specific dispensaries and we're in where
europe everything is dispensed through a
pharmacy
so i think what the potential is as
europe tiptoes towards recreational
access
is actually governments will probably
have adult use cannabis dispensed
through pharmacies as well to begin with
which is the model that they actually
employ in uruguay
that allows them to kind of uh
grandfather in a legacy framework it's
probably a system that
raises less eyebrows and raises less
concern over
diversion of products the other thing
too of course to remember
is recreational cannabis unless there's
a change
uh at the un treaty level then there's
never going to be able to have
um cannabis that actually flows across
national borders
so any adult use cannabis was going to
have to be grown and produced
in country whereas medical cannabis can
cross national borders so you also have
what's probably going to be a bit of a
patchwork of mini markets established
once europe is fully recreational just
like you have in the u.s right now
where it's basically a system of
different states with slightly different
frameworks
and tell me this one of the things that
i'm kind of predicting that being an
irish man
it's i i like to think that the industry
is going to be the exact same as we have
the heads of ibm here heads of facebook
google
everybody has their global headquarters
here i understand you guys are a malted
the two corporate tax rates are
obviously a big influence in the company
taking a position somewhere so i think
ireland could end up being the country
that services the european cannabis
industry through
the service companies we might not have
the hugest grow operations or
the best extraction facilities but we
have a highly intelligent young
workforce
we're the only english-speaking country
left in the eu now
i think there's going to be a lot of
advantages to the positions of companies
taken over here
what was the decision making between
malta and any other country was it just
a corporate
tax rate which is a completely uh uh
perfect reason to choose that it's
something that i'd probably do myself if
i was setting up in europe and not from
europe
yeah i mean the corporate tax rate was
obviously uh a part of our decision for
sure as a so for viewers who aren't
familiar
as a foreign health entity you can
actually reduce your your effective
corporate tax rate down to
five percent which is a massive decline
from the usual 30-35
um so that's there's massive tax savings
there but
uh outside of that we were also really
attracted to the way the maltese
government has been approaching the
cannabis file
for the last number of years so in terms
of the
the medical legislation and subsequent
regulation they
they implemented they're very
progressive and we've also found
since coming in because they were
obviously doing work to attract foreign
investment
into the country that they have really
been as supportive
and uh as incredible as we would have
hoped they would have been by way of
addressing any questions that we have
working through the licensing process
with us
almost as a partner rather than just as
solely as a regular that shows up at the
very end
um of the journey so we've been very
happy with that
and of course the other piece with malta
that's um that's on a
on a commercial basis but allows us to
do things that a lot of other european
countries do not
is basically processing non-eu gmp
certified flour
into eu gmp certified flower that's a
really important nuance
that not many uh countries actually
permit for right now
um and so for us what that does it
diversifies our supply chain
of course we have to do a full audit
process of the supplier to make sure
they're still up to certain
specifications
but they don't actually have to have
been inspected and certified by
a european regulator for us to import
their biomass
as starting raw material that's a huge
differentiator for us
and it kind of changes and distinguishes
our business model from most other
operators in europe
okay brilliant yet this has been highly
informative so far i'll leave you with
one last thing if you could predict how
europe is going to go over the next
five years do you see recreation within
five years or do you see a dominant
pharmaceutical distribution model within
five years
i see most european countries enabling
or broadening the medical cannabis laws
that they have today
and i hope that we can get to a place
where within five years the entire
european bloc
and the uk have full medical access
programs where any patient in need of a
cannabis medicine
is able to get it i don't see much
movement in the next five years
on the adult use side outside of the the
experiments the trials that we already
know of so
we know the dutch are putting a system
in place uh we know switzerland is
putting a system in place
for for effectively on an experimental
basis
i think those will go well those will
start in the next 12 months
um and then we'll probably while we
won't have implementation of auto use
programs in the next five years i do
expect that you've got some
bigger economies debating it sincerely
and on the cusp of implementing adult
use i would hope
yeah i think italy might be one of those
and we are you've everybody's heard the
rumblings of luxembourg it's
where how quickly that gets through
their parliament is another thing i
think what you highlighted malta's
government being open
to the capital investment coming in and
having a strategic plan to
to lure that investment in is a great
model that any country i wish our
government
would be able to be as uh have as much
foresight and intelligence as malta
seems to have had so
thanks a million for calling on the show
nick we'll be keeping a close eye on it
here i hope everything goes brilliantly
for you this year and
uh lots more mergers and acquisitions
for you ahead
thank you very much appreciate it
thanks everybody for watching we'll be
back again with another episode