[Music]
welcome to another episode of companions
review i'm delighted to be joined today
by clifton he's the co-founder of
scitec cannabis
how you keep drake lifting me well i'm
doing good
i'm thinking how are you doing excellent
thank you very much thank you very much
for the show and helping share a little
bit of wisdom for the audience that are
watching
i'd like to maybe if you want to start
well maybe i think the first topic is
going to basically bring the start of
your uh career in the industry into it
so we'll just start off
can you give us a start our guidance on
how you got into cannabis and
your relation to israeli cannabis sure
um so first of all thank you for having
me on very exciting and
good things moving forward in ireland
and my background
i mean i'm from born and brought up in
england and actually moved to israel
about 15 years ago
my professional backgrounds marketing
marketing and entrepreneurship
and i found myself involved in cannabis
it was about
six years ago now and as a medical
cannabis was kind of
beginning to to explode in in israel
um and what we saw back then was uh i
think we're gonna talk about it soon but
one of the things we saw back then was a
big
delta big lack of entrepreneurs um
not enough companies not enough young
people with innovative ideas or business
plans or technologies
to drive the industry forward and still
back then
and there was very much it was it was a
taboo you know the entrepreneurs that we
would meet
many times hadn't told their family and
friends what they were doing because
there was still this stigma
around around cannabis so what we did
was you know we we
began by launching an event called
canatec and the idea of canada tech was
to bring together entrepreneurs and
investors and
try and create discussion around the
industry and so my first couple of years
was really based around that kind of
building ecosystems
and raising awareness and some
government lobbying
to try and move everything forward um
then about four years ago i i came to a
painful conclusion
that the medical cannabis side of things
or the thc
or the doctor prescribed cannabis which
having recalled it
um is fraught with so many obstacles so
many problems
um what they can and are being overcome
in the short term it's it's consumers
that are missing out
uh whether it be regulatory or
entrepreneurs or product availability
um so i moved from the thc side of
things to the cbd side because
in 2016 the uk began to recognize the
mhra
recognize that cbd has medicinal
benefits and then from there
you know the awareness and the education
of what cbd is and what it can do
just began to blossom and that's why i
said the business offices scitec was
formed four years ago
the idea is to bring medical cannabis
quality products to the cbd market
and that's what we did we launched
profican and proficans are flagship
brands we launched that four years ago
and we now won the market leaders in the
uk and and it's exactly that it's
there's no cannabis leaf there's no
green coloring it looks like
it's something the doctor would
prescribe but your pharmacist would
dispense um
in short it's something that as a
consumer that when you look at the
products
feel it and use it that it immediately
elicits trust
and it's going to work and trust in the
company just a little bit about how i
came to where we are today
okay excellent and could you give a
little bit of a
background on your products are
developed in israel with the leading
scientists that they've got over there
can you explain to the audience how long
israel have been in the research and
development part of the cannabis
industry and why they're considered the
world leaders at this
sure um well i think we've been in the
research and science side since day one
and actually professor rafael muschilan
who's often referred to as the the
grandfather of of cannabis medicine
and it was him in the late 1950s that
began to research cannabis and he and
his team
throughout the 60s um discovered an
isolated thc
and they coined the phrase the entourage
effect and the whole
plethora of other cannabinoids were
discovered by them and they began to
research and
really uncover um the medicinal benefits
of the plants because up until that
point
and all we knew about the plant was it
gets you high and it's and it's illegal
and on top of that was built the
propaganda of everything we've known in
the last 40 50 years
so really is in the 60s that we began to
kind of break through those molds
it wasn't really until about the late
1990s
california was already beginning to move
towards medical cannabis
and we'd reached a point where we were
not just researching you know from the
scientific side but we're going to move
that
investigatory intuition into the
medical so into the clinical study world
of things so
by the late 1990s we're already
beginning to research
and understand and uncover what it can
do everything from you know epilepsy to
autism
ptsd um there's a number of indications
that
wouldn't have been known about had it
not been for um hospitals and
indeed patients over here in israel and
we've continued that path so we
we we do we do have this this amazing
perception
um and it is true and there's more
clinical studies here for cannabis
that's going on in this country than
um all of the world combined um there's
hundreds of studies going on right now
everything from pre-clinicals in in
little petri dishes
through to fill on uh human studies
double-blind placebos
almost every hospital in the country has
some kind of
cannabis clinical study going on um and
and to the point that you know even
in the last two or three years um the
stigma
the stigma of cannabis has all but
disappeared
um the final stretch will be when we
actually legalize
in in government and we hope that's
going to happen in the next year or two
or 18 months
but certainly um it's very rare now that
you would find anyone that would speak
out against
cannabis because almost everybody knows
someone who's benefited from it
and so we're in a good position over
here yeah now and i think that leads me
perfectly on to the next topic which i
hope we're both was there we're going to
start to see more of which is incur
encouraging more startups what do you
see being the hinder block here is it
the actual fact that
it's still illegal and a lot of people
frown upon it and their floodgates of
entrepreneurs creating startups will
happen once there's that kind of full
open legalization do you see that
happening
um unfortunately yes um
i mean there is there is some innovation
there is some entrepreneurs going on it
has been for a number of years but
certainly um it's the regulatory you
know
the doors that are closed because thc is
psychoactive and in almost every country
it's still
illegal it's still a a controlled
substance
so yeah you know from everything from
you know just getting a license to
research the product let alone you know
use
data or any kind of you know innovative
technology
where you need to touch the plant to
develop it it becomes a problem
um now we we've all thought we all hoped
that just the medical cannabis
regulations that have been rolling out
would open up the market enough to allow
entrepreneurs
in um unfortunately that hasn't been the
case and
i mean i believe that's mostly down sir
until the banks until the financial
institutions can involve themselves in
the in the industry
then everything gets blocked um
entrepreneurs
need investors and investors while
investment
is growing significantly it still lags
way behind other industries
at this stage in their growth by now we
should be looking at you know there
should be
vc funds and family offices and
all manner of investment coming in in
the uk i mean even i think this week
there's two companies that are
listing on the stock market in the uk
this week it's fantastic news
um two or three years behind where it
should be
um but we're hoping now that you know
now that's happening the floodgates will
open and over the next
i hope over the next year there will be
a lot more investment coming in which is
going to encourage
startups um there's nothing more
disparaging
i know this myself nothing more
disparaging for an entrepreneur than
knowing that there's nowhere to raise
money from yeah banks aren't giving the
loans because it's still illegal
um so really yes this is what we need to
do a free market's required to develop
the industry we know the exciting
products come from
creative minds and this is what we need
so we need to push this through and it's
coming
it's coming slowly but it's coming yeah
now i agree totally with you what do you
think of the headlines of the sale of gw
pharma there recently
is uh is that a good thing for the
industry or a bad thing
um well look it can only it can only be
a good thing anytime that cannabis
is is normalized i use this word a lot
that the sooner we can normalize
cannabis
the sooner that all normal things will
happen you know including
entrepreneurs and good products and good
regulation and we we need that to happen
um and i said again as i say i i think
it's i think it's happening now
yeah no i agree with you as well kind of
leads me on to the last thing i wanted
to talk to you about here a man who
knows how to build a brand between the
stuff you've got with james haskell and
the various other
products that you've got out what are
the three tips that you'd give to
somebody who's starting in the cannabis
industry on how to build their brand up
um three tips um i'll give you one tip
because i think it all starts with one
thing um
and that's trust um how do you then
you know dismantle and deconstruct the
word trust
but you know i mean so my background's
marketing i'm not a science or a medical
professional
and so i come at the industry from that
marketing and brands building side and i
know from
my years in the industry and other
industries in brands building
you've got one target your bullseye the
target
every single time is to build trust
because you know when you've got
consumers
who are choosing between different
brands it's
again what's the one thing that makes
them decide one over the other it's
which one they
trust is going to work better they trust
is going to be more than the branding
the brand language
is affiliated to them they trust that
when they tell other people about it
that they're gonna get a good reception
it's it's
it's trust trust trust um and that
in the cbd or cannabis industry is is
not an easy task
and we're talking about fundamentally um
healthcare products something that
people are using either as
um in replacement of regular medicines
or alongside
regular medicines this is not something
that's for fun
so to build trust in something that
people are using for their health is not
easy
um what we did um i guess this is this
is that my
my single biggest takeaway is we we
identified
where the trust is right or wrong the
trust is in medical cannabis
over cbd and certainly if you look at
the the markets in america
and actually over here in israel there
is a perception in the marketplace and
again
it's wrong but it's how it's evolved but
if you want
um if you want efficacy from cannabis
then you need medical cannabis you need
thc
and the cbd doesn't do a good enough job
now we know that's not right because
arguably it's the other way around cbd
is the anti-inflammatory
cbd is the anti-anxiety cbd does so many
good things
um thc does some good things but from a
therapeutic perspective it really is the
cbd and
so what we did is now we have to ask
ourselves how do we
how do we bring the credibility of
medical cannabis
into a cbd product into a wellness
product because again
medical cannabis you'll see it's being
sold in a specific strain is good for
autism or a strain is good for cancer
there's a very close indication specific
strains which
without the clinical studies you know
it's it's not it's not
it's not a legal position to take and
certainly in the cbd world
we do not make claims we sell it as a
food supplement there's no doctors so
there's no
we cannot say that our cbd is good for
ptsd although this one is good for pain
all we can say is our cbd is good so to
build that
trust is is quite complex um what we did
is from day one uh alongside the
development of the products that we do
over here in israel
and we began investing in and working
with a lot of
universities and hospitals on the
clinical studies
so we've involved us and we funded a
number of them but we've involved
ourselves in
cannabis studies to look at potential to
treat asthma
the potential to treat fatty liver
disease diabetes
and we've partnered with the medical
cannabis nurses association in israel to
share knowledge because you know we've
got tens of thousands of customers
who feedback you know what they use what
they use it for how they use it
and we can't use that for marketing
because there'll be a claim
but we can feed that back to our to the
nurses that we work with and they feed
us
information we can kind of work with our
customers
so it's kind of a symbiotic relationship
so if you look at
our company scitec yeah the background
is you know we're positioned as
a a biotech or a an r d company that
just happens to produce
good quality cbd products as opposed
to what we see in the marketplace which
is companies that begin
as a cbd brand with not much behind them
and then move on to try and establish
trust and establish credibility
we took it that that's first and
foremost first and foremost
you can have an ugly brand you can have
a very ugly logo
you can do all those things wrong but as
long as the essence behind the brand
is strong then in the healthcare world
that's going to work
because people will people will forgive
a bad tasting product
people will forgive a badly packaged
product
if it works if they can sleep if their
pain is gone
if their anxiety is gone they'll forgive
all these things
as long as they trust it works so that's
what we did we built trust based on
involving ourselves in the science and
the medicine
and it's also a very interesting side of
the industry it's very exciting
okay yeah that's a great little note to
finish on trust out there everybody for
acceptable business that's the
fundamental
pillar that you need to put in place
actually as you're speaking i could
think of a ton of cbd companies that are
let you know trying to pivot in to make
every pharmaceutical thing and become
lab testers and all this kind of stuff
whereas uh
yeah as i said if you get all those
pillars in in the place
in the right place at the first time is
where the aim should be
clifton thank you very much for coming
on the show it's very much appreciated
uh i wish you all the best for this year
and hopefully we get you on again
maybe after this novel food license
deadline to get your thoughts on that
over in the uk
absolutely thank you very much look
forward to it have a good day have a
good day guys