[Music]
welcome everybody to the latest episode
of cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined on this episode by a man of
renowned intellect in this industry it's
alex roger who's the founder of the
international cannabis business
conference alex how are you keeping
i'm good owen thanks for having me man
i'm delighted mate i've been chasing you
for a long time to try and get you on
the show so i'm delighted i know you're
going to have a wealth of information
for the audience and i'm going to kick
things off so with something that i know
probably everybody are going to like a
lot of people already know you're part
of the industry but the first topic is
jack herrera i know you've got a lot of
stories with this in your your early
days can you give everybody an overview
of the character of jack herrera who
hawaii was called the emperor
yeah yeah i'd love to uh
jack was
basically my mentor my original mentor
in the cannabis industry the cannabis
industry you know it was a lot different
uh 30 years ago i met jack in 93
in santa cruz california
and he was touring around california and
america and he was just promoting
legalization um he's called the emperor
because he wrote a book called the
emperor awares no clothes
and i think i think the book first came
out in like 84 or 85
and
it was basically about why hemp was made
illegal
and it was pretty it was a succinct and
concise uh kind of overview of
why we're dealing in a time of
prohibition for cannabis and hemp
and
he was uh he was
insanely passionate about the movement
uh he didn't smoke weed until he was 30
and got out of the army and then when he
did smoke weed he was like damn they've
been lying to me the whole time this is
this is pretty benign stuff here and
they said it was like the devil's weed
and something just lit up in him and he
became the uh the
there's nobody that i could even think
of that came close to pushing uh uh
cannabis reform
more than
jack hare and he was a he was a gruffled
son of a buck and he took no prisoners
and he was just
very direct
uh
and
you know he if you weren't into cannabis
being legalized like tomatoes as he
would say then he wasn't a why he wasn't
he wasn't into
your model of over regulation he thought
it to be a very benign thing and that
that everybody should have uh access to
it and he fought until his dying day
to make that happen
that's amazing he was a very thick skin
in the early days i'm sure there was a
lot of shade thrown his way
i mean for sure it's like we you know we
were out on the
being out on haight ashbury or telegraph
avenue with jack or down
at the la coliseum in the parking lot
even in the parking lot of the dead
shows you know it's like you never know
who would be like
more like when it was on the street
though and people would come up whenever
our signs with legalizing weed and they
would admonish us and chastise us or
laugh
and uh i always say nobody's laughing
now
yeah exactly that's for sure i've got to
move on to the next topic because it's
it's a pretty huge and popular
conference that happens in the three
major cities can you give everybody an
overview of how you set up the icbc its
history and what the plans are for the
future
uh yeah yeah basically i've been
producing events my whole life uh mostly
music events
and then about 10 years ago i run i own
a big medical marijuana clinic in oregon
and about 10 years ago we're getting all
these questions that were asked to us
about these this this new burger
burgeoning industry in america
two and two equal four to me and i was
like well let's put this conference
together and so we we created the
biggest b2b conference in oregon and
since i had lived in europe for eight
years and uh was very
uh
very euro euro savvy and euro passionate
i wanted to
do events over there and all around the
world and
i just saw a niche in international
cannabis business in
2014 basically is when i came up with
the idea for the icbc
and we just pushed forward and i went to
uh basically i went to germany i went to
berlin and and the germans were like oh
alex we are so worried for you we do not
know if an event like this will happen
five hundred dollars a ticket there's a
lot of money and you know and i was like
well i'm working for me too
and uh we just took a big chance and i
just went for it and berlin now has
become the biggest b2b event in europe
and we're scaling that event next year
it's going to be almost 5 000 people and
about 350 companies uh with over 75
countries represented so we are scaling
that model big time um
and i just knew germany is kind of the
center of
continental europe and whatever they do
goes to europe so i figured they're
going to eventually go they did with
medical they are now with cbd
uh legalization looks on the horizon uh
and looks like it's on the horizon and
then uh and otherwise i do these other
satellite events i teamed up with
spannabis the biggest uh consumer event
in europe and uh we do the one day b2b
before then and then we do a series of
uh investment events in zurich
switzerland and we're going to be in uh
croatia next year i'm going to do a i'm
starting to do a series on a
mediterranean retreat series all small
really intimate events everything's
about 250 people barcelona with spanish
that's about a thousand people but
berlin is the event we we're scaling and
then we're keeping our other events
really intimate and uh
just smaller
and not scaling them
okay amazing some more niche marketed
events for targeted exact industries and
then the main scalable
uh event i i'd highly recommend anybody
who hasn't been to the one of berlin
should definitely book their ticket for
uh next year there was three just
previously happened in august if i'm not
mistaken yeah we we pulled it off in
august it was
miracles do happen on yeah yeah the
challenges around those events i'm sure
will be uh less hindered next year will
there be more more freedom and
accessibility for people to come so
book your tickets for next year before
it sells out i'd highly recommend it
gonna move on to the last topic which is
an overview of european cannabis you've
got just a deep understanding yourself
of the various different territories the
recent elections in germany bode well
for a legalized industry over there what
do you know on the ground
you might be able to inform the viewers
yeah well we've been following this for
a long time they've called it the
jamaica coalition and the spd which are
basically the conservatives
excuse me the cdu which are basically
the conservatives have been in power for
now what is it 16 years and although we
even saw a little bit of movement with
the cdu we had a member of
the cdu speak at the last icbc which was
which was historical
uh however
what we see now in germany is a huge
shake-up and they're going to form the
coalition will probably be
with the greens uh and the uh
the uh ftp party and so
with the with the social democrats so it
looks like the cdu the conservative
government will not be part of this new
coalition
and so two of the three members of the
coalition have clearance succinct plans
for
uh
legalization
and even when i ask my most pessimistic
uh
cynical german friends of how they feel
about legalization a year ago they would
have been like we're not sure
now everyone seems to think that
legalization is on the horizon just
since the last few months when we could
see that this this when we could see
what the polling numbers were for
for the new the the election uh
everything's completely shaken up in
europe and a lot of people think that
legalization is uh
it'll be it'll be uh
on the forefront of the new coalition's
agenda
yeah i think the the legal experts in
the cannabis industry in germany are
gonna do well over the next 12 to 24
months with the applications of licenses
yeah we are we are very happy about the
the election results when it comes to
to cannabis
specifically i should say yeah exactly
what other territories we saw luxembourg
recede a little bit basically on their
big announcement that they're going to
have an industry but i don't know
whether that was just one outlier of a
politician
speaking out of turn or did you hear
more about it look here's what i here's
what i think i think after all this
everyone thinks it could be luxembourg
or sweden or or portugal or they have
ideas excuse me switzerland
luxembourg or portugal i think those are
going to be the places that will
legalize first
and i actually think it's going to be
germany now and i think germany will be
the first country to legalize in like a
robust real legalization not a decrim
but uh but a recreational full market
yeah and i think that was the case with
medical and i think that you know i
wouldn't have predicted this a year ago
but now i think that germany will
actually have the first clear
legalization laws
in europe before luxembourg before
switzerland and luxembourg and
switzerland are really important but or
switzerland is even more important but
uh
but when germany legalizes then that you
know europe goes where germany goes
generally and so it's it'll it'll be a
seminal moment but that's my big bold
prediction
yeah no i think that's if you get
germany going and then france goes hand
in hand i think you'll have a european
flip within 12 to 18 months it could be
that close uh we really actually think
that it might be
within 12 to 18 months yeah
and have you see obviously the medical
industry is
leading the way at the moment in europe
that's pretty much where all the talk is
at the moment you've got a lot of
territories with denmark up there made
in denmark brand coming in the
pharmaceutical industry strong presence
in pharma malta same strong presence in
pharma they've started processing
product coming into there turning it
into goods with the major multisign do
you see those two territories having a
leg up on everywhere else or do you see
somewhere like the uk or ireland which
is already got the home base for a lot
of the major uh global headquarters for
companies here anyway i don't see it's a
reason why cannabis might not be the
same
yeah i mean i don't think i don't think
the emphasis the previous infrastructure
uh
matters necessarily of of where
someone's poised in terms of a
farmer perspective because this is kind
of uh you know it's though it is pharma
and though big that infrastructure could
be used and one day
uh might be used uh right now you see i
think denmark is pretty much the
i mean malta has its niche right uh uh
no doubt but it's so small denmark is is
uh
they're they're i think they're next to
bedrock and from holland
uh denmark is putting the most cannabis
into the medical market in germany and
they're doing it in a way that's uh
efficient smart a good price a decent
product there's no i'm from the west
coast so all of the medical it doesn't
compare no it's it's
it doesn't
i think denmark with their with their
past and ornamental flower growing and
the kind of strong tissue culture
departments that they've got up there
they seem to be growing as premium
product as they've gotten within a
couple of years totally they've done a
great job and basically they did what
holland should have done and what we
expected maybe holland or the
netherlands to do right and then denmark
just kind of stepped in and took it to
the next level when holland was was they
never they never had the the advocacy or
the organization to to to push something
like this to a to the next degree like
like denmark did they just kind of
monopoly with bedrock and then they have
their coffee shop scene so it was like
so i was surprised holland didn't do it
you know
but denmark did it and they took the
reigns
yeah and do you see the fact that europe
is an agricultural heavy uh society and
civilization once legalization comes do
you see
ireland having its own strain france
having its own strains spain having its
own dominant strain and it
kind of nuanced almost like wine or
something like that first for sure i
mean
i i i think that that's just
what cannabis is and what cannabis does
and
i i think the region will help obviously
the southern regions are are better but
because it is so in america we grow a
lot of outdoor cannabis right but in um
but in europe because it's a little more
clinical a lot of it's going to be at
least at the beginning uh mandated
hydroponics yeah yeah and it's it's not
something i like i like soil grown sun
grown uh cannabis that's what i use it's
a it's just a more
uh
chill profile uh not as big up and down
a little more consistent i have the
luxury of that because i live on the
west coast but um
of that option but uh
yeah no i think that uh
i think every you know the sooner people
whatever countries legalize first or get
into the game they're going to be able
to have this like branding advantage
also of saying oh that's some slovenian
weed or that's some the man the irish
boys lads know what they're doing and
they've got it all dialed up and
and you know so so now is the time to
to to put these ideas together
and really brand uh start branding uh
not only the weed but then added value
products from that area also
yeah i think the the the customer will
buy into specific uh culture like they
do with every other brand whether it's
the taste of freshness or ireland or
whether it's the cool chilledness of
spain or portugal or whatever it may be
before i let you go i'd be remiss to ask
you a man who lives in the west coast
what's the best frame that you've ever
found or consumed
well you know i mean we like the og kush
out here everything has og kush in it
when you get that pure og kush it's uh
it's awesome i mean the cookies the girl
scout cookies the train wreck here in
southern oregon is popular
uh all these all these strains are great
you know i will say this though for me
my personal strength was i lived in
amsterdam 20 years ago and there was a
coffee shop called the katsu and it
specialized in uh sativa
and right when you walked in this coffee
shop you could smell the distinct smell
it's like the opposite of kush right
cushions the hardcore indica and then
the hazes were the hardcore sativas
um and now so on the west coast we have
everything we have the best weed the
best options the best everything but
what we don't have still is someone will
say oh that's part haze or that's that's
a hybrid sativa dominant or whatever
there's no more pure sativas like when i
walked into the katsu in amsterdam years
ago and smoked neville's haze or the
silver pearl or the super silver um
these don't exist on the west coast and
and if i could ever get some like
old-school haze like that uh it it would
be uh
it'd be amazing so so you so as green as
the grass is here we don't have that
one of my favorite strains which is
which is the haze it's a total sativa
and otherwise we like to cush out here
man
yeah okay amazing it's been amazing
talking to could talk to you all day
you're an absolute gentleman take your
time out for me and the viewers and for
everybody check out the website below
internationalcbc.com
highly recommend booking your tickets
for next year it's it's an amazing event
and thank you very much for your time
alex thanks owen i appreciate it thanks
everybody see you next time