foreign
welcome everybody to the Cannabis review
I am delighted to be joined on this
episode by Dario sabagi Dario's a
renowned uh journalist he's interested
in international news human rights and
cannabis and he's written for a lot of
the world's top media Publications like
Forbes High Times routing stones and
Middle East die to name just a few how
are you keeping Dario
everything is fine thank you I'm
delighted to have you on the show you've
been uh putting out some amazing content
across the various uh multitude of
Publications so I thought it'd be great
to have you on and help introduce the
audience to some of the big stories that
are happening at the moment can you
maybe give everybody a quick little
overview of how you got into covering
cannabis as a journalist and what
brought you into this place
yeah basically I started covering
cameras like two or three years ago and
uh working with uh uh English
publication
with work I started covering uh cannabis
from Italy about some stories from Italy
because it's the country where I come
from and then I started to collaborate
with all their news media organizations
including High Times on uh Forbes
but at the same time I I cover a Middle
East News from the Middle East regarding
politics and economics
and regarding cannabis I
I I also be an editor-in-chief of the
Italian edition of uh with word it was
called Woodward Italy for a one year and
a half and then now I'm working as a
freelance journalist both uh covering
both cannabis and international news
with the focus on the Middle East
okay amazing yeah for I've subscribed to
your middle eastern newsletter and I
highly suggest anybody who hasn't
subscribed and is interested to learn
about that territory of the world check
it out on his website you can subscribe
to everything there but moving on to the
first story for this uh podcast that I
wanted to talk about it's the juicy
field story it seems to be a big news at
the moment in the Cannabis industry how
a group of guys created an investment
platform that turned into a Ponzi scheme
and ran away with everybody's money can
you maybe give everybody your expert
overview of that scenario in that case
so we can get people up to speed on it
well yes I started to cover uh Jessica's
story just a few days ago actually other
Publications such as uh El Diario and uh
Spin and zero covered this topic for
months because of this alleged scheme
images about basketballs uh crowdfunding
cannabis platform where people could
invest to buy a plant to be cultivated
uh uh Harvest and sold and but uh at the
same time it was discovered it could be
uh on uh quantity scheme yeah in the
sense that the the website is not
working uh it's not working more
actually and uh people uh just uh cannot
withdraw their their deposits and uh now
there are uh some private investigation
about what's going on there on a
juicital platform and uh actually there
are some lawyers working uh only at best
clip it seems that
um the owners of the platform belong to
three people with a Russian uh passports
and uh they just they just disappeared
even the CEOs of the the pharmacy of the
uh juicy juicy food uh said he didn't
know anything about that but of course
the investigation are ongoing there are
no
official news schedules of the
developing story and uh basically upon
the scheme uh it's based on the fact
that the early investor uh get the money
from a newer investors
so on that in this way the contest came
uh is a functioning for uh for the
owners to collect all morning possible a
disappeared suddenly
and uh Jessica was uh mainly focused on
cannabis cultivation
but investors most of them were from
Latin America Spain and Europe with some
users also from Asia and North America
but uh as the the coverage suggests me
uh that most users were from Germany uh
Spain and uh Latin America and um but
they were also like uh Italian or uh
uh British uh British uses so it was a
very uh huge platform in terms of
cannabis industry because it counted
about 500 500 000 users according to uh
Joseph official records
um but at the same time you know the
Cannabis industry is a very new industry
it's a very volatile and scums can
happen we um like in any other new
Industries
yeah no I agree there's I think this
won't be the last uh opportunistic
um company that we see praying on
people's investment and people's money
because as you said it's still
unregulated there's still a lot of black
holes to the to the industry the latest
article you wrote We reposted on the
Cannabis review was about Switzerland uh
legalized medical cannabis and and and
and imports and exports do you see those
that uh we know Spain legalized and
they're saying within six months they're
gonna have a medical cannabis program up
and running do you think Switzerland are
going to be within that time frame or
within 12 months or is it still too uh
too early to tell
well uh can we uh can it be this
business around was really legal for a
specific uh uh disease uh conditions and
but now from a from my first of August
it will be uh fully legalized which
means uh passion won't uh have us for me
uh authorization to the agency but
simply a physician could prescribe
cannabis for them
and also cannabis would be with a high
level of that uh CBD I'll do uh
THC should be kept at the one percent
but probably it could be uh it could be
more we have to see about that about the
implementation of the law and uh of
course could be a very good news for
European countries which are lacking up
supplies uh for example in Italy uh most
of the supplies come from the
Netherlands and other parts of Europe of
Canada through Aurora cannabis
company and but also all their state
lots of uh cannabis supplies so there
are many patients that depends what kind
of conditions the uh the legislation
allowed to use a medical cannabis and
also for Spain which has apparently uh
recently legalized cannabis although uh
have interviewed some some experts in
the field of a Spanish cannabis industry
which have written is a very limited
legislation which won't
um solve the problem at the moment
yeah we had Dr adanda Celeste Kyogre on
the episode recently and he was
basically outlining that six months is a
little bit ambitious for Spain to think
and even the the the language used in
the ruling is still unclear which uh
whether it's a specialized physician or
he he was even saying that it's a doctor
with no conflict of interest is the one
who has to prescribe but as I said
trying to figure out that web of uh
of knowledge will be a tough one for the
Spanish regulator is I want to basically
move on now to Middle East North African
cannabis and the various territories in
there basically there's a lot of
countries and I wanted to try and cover
them all so I've got a list of all the
top countries in this space and I
basically want to run through them and I
want to give you get you to give them an
A or an F depending on how good their
cannabis industry is okay so that sounds
fair sure right so first one is Algeria
where does Algeria stand arf
well except if we talk about uh
regulation of cannabis or all the of the
recreational Cannabis all the Middle
East countries are at which means not
badly legalized cannabis for
recreational use
and uh so Algeria is included on that
although there are some illegal
cultivation some uh legal trafficking
okay perfectly Bahrain
Bahrain the same the same
uh also even uh CBD is considered
illegal because it's a part of the
uh of the cannabis plant which is
considered the legal there as well yeah
that's what we think parents one of the
strictest ones Egypt anything happening
in Egypt
Egypt has a long history of a cannabis
culture uh uh since the 18 uh um yeah
the 18th century they were or even uh
even before there was largely consumed
by population which is the uh most
populated Arab country and but still is
uh illegal there are trafficking between
the upper Sydney
and I would uh with a border with a Gaza
Strip and uh but it's illegal as well
so Iran and Iraq I'm pretty much going
to put together I presume it's highly
illegal there as it is in Bahrain that
there's not even a CBD Market yeah I
mean Iran is a even
um I mean drug trafficking could be
punished with a deaf parents as well
Iraq uh I'm not sure about that penalty
but of course it's illegal yeah yeah
some of the countries seem to be now
Israel we know of obviously has a
thriving medical uh industry at the
moment and Export industry yeah is there
is a different story uh Israel uh we can
if uh has no legalized the rec National
candidate
medical cannabis could be used for
certain uh usage but a very entrepreneur
but at the same time wasn't interesting
about Israel is the research we don't
have to forget uh uh
that THC was isolated there in in 1964
by micholam
in 1964 it was isolated there so it's a
long history with a
with the research and also recently is
one of the largest import of cannabis uh
I think even more than Germany actually
and uh it started to export uh seats to
the U.S recently in a couple of months
ago
okay so Jordan is there any movement
Jordan there seem to have uh for
thinking King no no uh Jordan as well
same legislation on what this country is
predicted and uh it's illegal and Kuwait
illegal as well Lebanon
Lebanon was the first country to
legalize medical cannabis in 2020
to with the hope to uh
to contain the economic crisis uh that
started in 20 in late 2019 I'll Harbor
has not been
um has not been implemented the
legislation at the same time so there is
a just a loop that has not lamented no
companies working on it no Farmers as
well at the same time Lebanon has long
history with the hash issue Lebanese
hashes it was one uh one of the
top-notch hardships in the world along
with the Moroccan hashish and it
exported legally uh with traffic rule to
a Middle East Country and Africa as well
yeah I've just finished a book about the
Phoenicians and uh hashish and Lebanon
clubs up a little bit in the the kings
of trading in the Mediterranean a number
of years ago so how about uh Libya then
is there any action in Libya
Libya uh there is no legislation as well
layout in uh it's legal regarding
cannons Morocco we we know that there's
a movement happening there to a degree
yeah Morocco legalized medical economies
and Industrial Hub in 2021
uh and to contain also the drug
trafficking there and a half Farmers
from the rape region uh to to go legal
at the same time Iraq is the first
supplier of uh hashes hashes on uh in
the European continent
uh so it's a so recreational camera be
still continue to be illegal although
there is uh some form of the tourism
regarding the uh regarding the legal
cannabis cannabis crops so European
Western tunnels goes to Morocco also to
see to have a tour in this kind of in
these farms in a reef region and other
parts of the uh of the country
okay so I've got a bunch oh man Qatar
Saudi Arabia and the United Arab
Emirates and Yemen in together no laws
pretty much not a chance of it and
everyone even regarding uh CBD uh some
months ago or some years ago I will
remember well but uh a British uh
citizen was jailed for uh for carrying
on CBD oil in uh United Arab Emirates as
well so it's a strict deal in there and
then Palestine intern happen in
Palestine and Palestine uh also it's
illegal and also there are it's what we
consumed in all this country you just
mentioned so including Palestine is a
kind of is consumed as well but we've
got Syria Tunisia and turkey
uh yeah all the country are uh
are illegal cannabis theory is legal
Syria have some cultivation as well that
could export something
uh turkey uh turkey is a illegal as well
and what's though the country you just
mentioned uh Tunisia Tunisia Tunisia as
well they have good hashish quality they
have some crops they export something
I believe all as well but yeah still
illegal
okay yeah I think it's been very
informative I've Loved learning about
all the different charities that are
happening at the moment for anybody who
hasn't read any of Dario's work I highly
recommend going to his website the link
is below and in the information below
subscribe to the newsletters there he's
one of the top journalists covering
cannabis is as far as I'm concerned so
Dario thank you very much for taking the
time to join us today
thank you very much
it was an absolute pleasure hopefully we
get to touch base at the start of next
year and we'll get an update on some of
these territories and hopefully we've
got some movement in Europe and uh
further afield as well
sure thank you until next episode guys