foreign
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I am delighted to be
joined to this episode by Dr Rob O'Brien
who's the CEO and CSO at Supra research
and development in Canada how are you
keeping today Rob good it's been a
beautiful day here to the morning here
it's a little grip but it's nice
I'm delighted to have you on I've been
reading all your latest publishings
based on the testing and research that
you guys have been doing at Supra do you
maybe want to give everybody just a
quick little overview in 30 seconds or a
minute
um how super came to be on your work uh
so far in the industry
yeah for sure I like to say I'm a
reformed academic I was a university
press Professor for a number of years
and we spun out a company super research
and development uh over time uh we ended
up getting into the um uh lab testing
base and then started getting the proper
licenses to test for cannabis uh at
which time there was a lot of companies
that wanted to that was pretty um
pre-legalization so they thought that by
having our license and their portfolio
they'd have a quicker path to uh
legalization so we're eventually
purchased by Valen's uh grow works
became the valance company uh and after
a year or so there I spun back to my
main Supra research and development
we not only do cannabis products but we
also do other Natural Health Products
and contract research work as well
okay very interesting so wealth of
experience first question is the iso
iec17025 accreditation that you guys has
is that the licensed
specifically test and work with cannabis
no ISO 17025 is an international
standard out of the international
standards Association uh Europe actually
France I think
um and it is a standard for any Testing
Lab it's basically a guideline to your
quality manual how you validate the
methods and part of that means that you
have periodically people come on site go
through your data with a fine-tooth comb
to make sure that you're collecting
things appropriately it doesn't prevent
Labs from cheating but it there's
there's a lot more oversight and for
consumers of the lab services they can
trust that it allows there's ISO 1705
accredited that they are capable of
doing the work
okay very good the first topic I wanted
to jump onto was the latest research on
THC levels there's been a a lot of
conversation as I'm sure you know in the
industry about there's no need for high
THC whereas some manufacturers seem to
think that high THC is the unique
selling point for them what is the
latest research that you guys have been
conducting on testing THC levels well
we've got to be careful with this
because my personal opinion is high THC
isn't everything it clearly isn't
um but in Canada when they brought the
legislation into legalized cannabis the
only thing that they allowed on the
label were the THC and CBD values
because the last thing they wanted is to
attract uh
youth to to that so they didn't want to
have appealing marketing that would do
that so the consumers then had only one
thing to take a look at and that was the
THC content versus the price and then
over time we've seen a steady increase
in THC values from the products uh We've
even recently tested products that were
legitimately over 30 THC
um so so this as this has happened it's
gone up and at the same time uh the our
our legal system has provincial
purchasing uh uh governments uh buying
the material from the producers and
they've set thresholds for THC purpose
as quality higher and higher so right
now uh you know if you don't have a
product that's 27 you're not considered
a prime quality product uh that's
absolutely uh ridiculous however
um our focus is not even talking about
that is if you put something on a label
we expect that you have within let's say
20 or 10 percent of that uh the correct
uh amount though
okay um can you tell me is the testing
for the THC levels being done just as uh
drawing and cultivation is finished or
is it after it's been put through
certain Machinery that we're losing
trichomes along the way
yeah this is part of the part of the
problem here
what's happening is that Health Canada
is requiring their certificate of
analysis or COA in the back from each
batch and they need things on
contaminants like pesticides Metals Etc
but they're also I need one on on the
content of the uh
cannabinoids and the issue with that is
that there's a high variance between uh
buds within a plant and then we have a
whole lot across the plant and then as
these uh buds are going through the
processing uh and mechanical handling
you can lose trichomes which reduces the
THC content uh so if you use a COA from
the Harvest that is pristine material
and maybe maybe you're leaning on the
scan a little bit by selecting just the
top Buds and maybe de-stemming them or
something like that uh you'll end up
with a very high COA which gets you a
sale but if you use that on all your
package labels uh particularly the small
buds the one gram packages which have
typically three or four buds in it these
are these buds are 30 or so less than
the the biggest ones and that's kind of
what we expect is happening uh but it's
an inappropriate use of a testing
protocol so with testing we need to be
fit for purpose uh so testing of one one
test and a lot does not really reflect
on what is in the packages and it's in
the packages that the consumer needs to
be considerable
okay so you've got obviously producers
and manufacturers looking to test as
much as the government are doing their
own tests and one wants to test at one
stage where it's at its premium and the
actual test that matters is what's in
the package when it goes under the
shelves
yeah well let's be to be clear the the
responsibility for testing is into the
quality assurance person of the producer
they're the ones that are responsible
for verifying the lab can do accurate
results and they're responsible for the
the numbers that go on to the final
label the government has been doing some
spot testing as I understand it but they
haven't been publicly disclosing uh uh
things uh so the only way we're getting
this out there is when a group like
myself is doing this uh type of study
and just revealing pulling the the sheet
back and seeing what's underneath it
okay so you guys at Super basically
work on higher quality and safer
products for big Brands is there a
specific territory in Canada that do you
think has the highest quality and the
safest products and if so is is it
applicable to America for the same
uh let's uh let's sort of step back with
that quote then answer this inflation of
the THC values is uniquely a North
American problem
and it's because the higher THC labeled
products sell more and sell for more
money it is simply that
um now when we did our tests we looked
at the BC cannabis source so it's only
one part of the each province in Canada
has its own purchasing agents and that
so we can't speak for unified but 93 of
the products we tested were more than 50
15 of the label 87 percent were more
than 20 percent and we even had 26
percent that were more than 40 below the
label claim nothing meant the label
claim and in a normal uh sort of study
you would expect that a plus or minus
should be above and below that's that's
what you would expect for normal
statistics but we're not seeing that
here
um I think that a lot of them producers
and let's let's not be wrong here BC but
even before legalization has been
regarded as some of the highest quality
product in the world
um and and I believe that is true but
there's just this pushed that the only
way they can get their products sold is
to have these higher elevated values
that they're leading they're doing what
they can to get those numbers and at the
end of the day the consumers are making
decisions on the THC value which is not
correct but that's the only information
they have to go from
um and you know they're picking a
product a over product B by the number
and it could be maybe product B is a lot
higher but they're more honest so that's
why we really have to do this uh I think
there's a lot of producers in Canada who
are fundamentally honest but they're
really they're using the wrong thing
here
and when it gets to health Canada and
others they're saying well the testing
Labs I guess we can't do it which is all
just complete [ __ ] uh because there
is uh aoac ASTM nist in the U.S actual
research that have standards methods
available for people to use any lab that
is wants to do it right can
but the problem is that if the lab needs
to buy a sample they have to report that
that's not their fault but some labs are
also on their part tweaking up the
numbers because that's how they get
business
uh and the other thing that's happening
in Canada is the cultivators can't sell
directly the the the the person that
cultivates so they sell the pro
producers producers to collect from a
lot of cultivators uh and they're
requiring them to use specific labs
so when you do this this gives the
processors undue influence over the labs
and those labs that get the highest
values are the ones that are getting the
most business uh so so that's all part
of the problem but this is I'm
completely committed to make sure this
this stops but right now it's it's
primarily a North American problem
and the testing protocols that everybody
uses are these the exact same set of
rules or as you said are people bending
and maneuvering themselves to be able to
get around certain rules to have certain
levels of THC written down
well let's be clear with ISO 17025 which
is not a requirement for the labs in
Canada so some don't even have that but
they don't specify a specific method so
this is allowing for if you have a
better method then you can you can do
that as long as you do a proper
validation and then do regular
proficiency testing programs or maybe
test against a CRM so to make sure that
you can get accurate values
um so we have a method that is uh six
and a half minutes we separate 17
cannabinoids and it's a run to run to
eight minutes if we use what's what's
published in some of the pharmacopias
the method of there is 25 minutes so it
doesn't fit for the practical sense but
our method does have us hit the
proficiency testing values very well
pretty interesting you had worked before
on commercializing biomass extraction so
would know a fair bit about this when it
comes to Europe and let's say the the
medical products that created it's a lot
more pharmaceutical over here do you
think synthetic biosynthetic or
extracted molecules directly from the
plant which one is the more suitable
ingredient for a pharmaceutical product
well look you know
a premise of chemistry is if the
molecule is identical then it's the same
irregardless if your aspirin is made
synthetically or or even extracted from
the little tree the difficulty with
natural products is there's also other
things that are co-extracted so if you
look at a pure THC product it's very
difficult not to have Trace levels of
CBD in it just because that's the way
the world works right
um that's not a bad thing for medicinal
products but I don't think in the
medicinal legalization markets that you
have in Europe that there's the same
type of problem because there's a
European pharmacopoeia and they require
label claims to be within 10 percent of
the of the label and we haven't heard
any reports that those products are are
a problem ironically a lot of the
products worldwide now are exported from
Canada imported from Canada because we
have a legal base here so ironically
when they're when they land in Ireland
and Germany
we can get the labels right but here in
North America we have this this issue so
that's complete uh Focus right uh so we
uh I I suspect that medicinal patients
in in Europe who are brine product maybe
even Source from Canada are are getting
good product
um and I should add to there's a big
difference between a a product that
includes buds because there's a natural
variation between Buds and one that's
been extracted and put into a a gummy or
another form that's more medicinal than
you would expect even a tighter
Tolerance on that because you know
you're home homogenized a material prior
to making the product
do you still think there's a lot of room
in the Blends and formulations of
cannabinoids and terpenes and flavonoids
to create new novel let's say
ingredients shall we call them for a
various of different products and
ailments yeah well in a bit I think
there's some products we're moving
initially we had you know cannabis 1.0
then cannabis 2.0 which is more of the
finished products but we're going to get
to more medicinal products my personal
feeling is is things like sublinguals
are much more reasonable than than other
things because we also need to dig into
the understanding of the pharmacology of
these materials so when you smoke a
material or use a vaporizer at low
temperature which is what I recommend
the neutrals of the other compounds that
get into your bloodstream and get to
your brain quite quickly
uh when you ingest it you end up having
metabolites that are formed and these
can have different much more variable
effect on individuals so for instance if
I eat an edible that has THC in it I'm
in a tunnel for four hours and I'm not
really that happy about it
um the uh the other piece is that if uh
sublingual again is more the neutral
into the system so we really need more
research on the pharmacology and how
that works and then develop the
appropriate response to that
um so there's things like the Entourage
effect that people talk a lot about uh
and then you would need a whole extract
to get those curtains but the other
thing people affect like if you smoke
that product or if you heat it in a
vaporizer at a very high temperature
you're not only getting those products
converted you're also getting a lot of
uh degradation products based on
temperatures so for instance if you uh
even vaporize a THC product at a high
temperature the THC degrades to CBN
uh and and we need to keep in mind these
types of things so with the vaporizers
as long as the temperature needs to be
below 200 Celsius we like to to even
Target 180. otherwise you get
degradation products and that can lead
to health impact negative Health impacts
and related things
very interesting it's been amazing
talking to you Rob I I hope we can get
to basically touch base before the end
of this year and get a recap on all the
new testing that you guys have done but
for now thank you very much for joining
us for anybody who wants to learn more
about super r d website is below I
highly highly recommend checking it out
and it's it's very informative indeed so
Rob thank you very much for joining us
my pleasure thank you till next episode
everybody