foreign
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I am delighted to be
joined on this episode by Tim mcdell
we've got a long intro here so bear with
me Tim is basically the current CEO of
Bristol extracts from Bristol New York
and he's also the chair of Finger Lakes
Committee of the New York cannabis
Growers and Processors Association he
was a founding partner of one of the
first regulated marijuana infused
product manufacturing companies in the
US and Tim was also a founding member of
tree frog cannabis Consulting and has
managed multiple infused product
manufacturing facilities and projects
from conception true to completion so a
man with a huge wealth of information
Tim thank you very much for taking time
to join the show yeah thanks for the
opportunity to be on
great to talk to you later as I said
when I was researching I was like going
holy [ __ ] this man has got a oh the the
the ingredients to to be doing exactly
what you guys are doing which is very
exciting things over New York do you
maybe want to give everybody a quick
little overview of how you got so
quickly to Bristol extracts and the the
original first step into the industry
yeah absolutely
um yeah thanks again for having me but
uh really started right place right time
in Boulder Colorado in 2009 a mutual
friend put me in touch with a guy who
was had started one of the first
dispensaries
um and I grow to support it he wanted to
do Edibles from the trim and that was
kind of the mindset on processing at the
time and then we ran with that
um he sold the dispensary in the grow a
couple years later we focused on the
brand marcaha out of uh Denver we moved
it to Denver then we expanded that in
2014 into the Nevada and Illinois
markets and really just owner operator
grew that we spun tree frog Consulting
off of that just as a small consulting
company that focused on processing we
always said from the plant was cut down
until products were shipped so we'd
worked with teams we were very
successful with the teams that we got
put in Medicine Man Technologies and
different security teams and uh we were
successful in winning applications uh
competitive application licenses in 10
states
um so it was a busy uh few years there
and then you know life changes and covet
happened and I grew up on the East Coast
um and I moved my family back here in
July of 2021 a year ago Bristol extracts
brought me on to help them enter into
the THC markets or Bristol extracts uh
hemp cultivator and processor since 2018
in Upstate New York uh grew 30 acres of
hemp for multiple years uh the hemp
Market kind of you know CBD markets in
the U.S have taken a big drop in the
last few years along with covid so they
pivoted brought myself in brought a
chemist in from Oakland California and
12 or 13 months later we were awarded
the conditional processor license and we
are anticipating the conditional
cultivator license uh in October so here
we are incredible that's the kind of
first topic I wanted to talk about so
you just recently got your NYS Auto to
use conditional processor license can
you maybe outline to everybody what does
that basically entail and allow Bristol
extracts to do in that stage yeah
absolutely so the conditional processor
license
um there was a lot of lobbying to allow
uh the hemp Growers and processors kind
of first run at the New York Market uh
that's one of the pillars of the these
conditional licenses the dispensary
license being the other for uh folks who
were directly impacted by the war on
drugs and so with the processor license
uh we qualified it for it for already
holding a hemp processor license and
having a cgmp certified facility which
is a good manufacturing uh third-party
audit and certification
um
so there are two tiers within even the
processor license uh one allows a
company to extract the plant biomass
into concentrates or extracts the other
simply allows you to manufacture so one
allows you to extract and manufacture
the other allows you to manufacture so
we are fortunate to be able to extract
and manufacture and goods and then
wholesale them to licensed dispensers in
the state of New York
okay incredible so you guys are going to
be one of the main players when it comes
to let's say an Edibles brand or a vape
brand to say they want to get into the
market you guys have the expertise for
them to be able to fulfill all their
needs all in one space sure and you know
we've been approached by uh several if
not dozens of
um West Coast Brands and some that I go
back a long time with and very
successful Brands Bristol has not
licensed or chosen to license these or
work with these brands at this point
kind of our philosophy right now is the
next 12 to 24 maybe more months in New
York are going to be difficult it's as
the market
we see how these dispensaries open what
kind of capital there is uh to even
purchase wholesale
we don't really want to bring other
people to the table I don't know how
great of Partners we would be or anyone
would be that
as the chaos of the Market opening
happens you know I've been through this
uh three times now and then a couple
other times as a consultant
um you know there it's just one strategy
you know the other uh folks that have
these licenses are choosing to license
Brands and you know that they may be
successful doing it so
and bring them out
to see what happens in the future and
how many New York auto processor
licenses are there going to be so you
said there's tier one and two tier are
they split evenly 50 50.
I believe it was if you had a cgmp
certified extraction room prior to
January 1st of this year then you could
roll that into the conditioner
conditional process if you were awarded
that license there's 39 total
um at least that's the last number that
I had read about a month ago 39
potential processor a conditional
processor licenses in New York I want to
say it's roughly half of those of a
little less
um can also extract but those numbers do
change a little and so
you know and then there's a smaller
number of you know let's say it's 20
that can extract and manufacture I
believe there's like 12 to 14 that can
also grow out of those companies
um which is you know great but it's also
a lot of it's it's a lot of balls in the
air it's very
advances so sometimes you get what you
ask for you know especially when the
Market's not open and we don't know
really when the Market's going to be
open we hear it's going to be open
December of 22. I think that we can all
agree that that it's not going to happen
maybe there's a political uh uh hey we
awarded we awarded licenses in this year
and that's great and good for them
um but an actual operational Market is
is several months out
yeah it's uh it's definitely going to be
interesting to see I think I was reading
something in the last 48ers about that
they're gonna have 900 different uh
dispensaries it's going to be
interesting to see the the shareholding
how many individual entrepreneurs are
there how much capital is is brought to
the market initially at phase one but I
think the it vertically integrated
companies like you just kind of
described there I think he's seeing
candidate that that didn't work his
specialization seems to be the key to
any successful business in any industry
and I I think a few New York companies
might learn that the hard way like
Canada
yeah I I mean the Cannabis industry in
general has taken a lot of bumps and
bruises here it's kind of correcting to
pre-covet plus some
um and you know money is a little more
expensive to come by these days and it's
a very Capital intensive
um business and the goal over these next
two years is that the state will issue
150 dispensary licenses
um but I mean you can do a whole episode
on how dazny and the New York state ocm
is a licensing these dispensaries and
how they're it's a public-private fund
to help get them going and there's a lot
of you know
it's it's a great uh Equity focused
um something different than any other
state has done I think we all support
that there is also the reality
of business that we really are looking
for more of a communication between
licensed industry and state government
um because you have a thriving gray
Market in New York and you know it's
legal no one should be arrested for for
marijuana
um but there is a challenge of when you
have tax paying companies and companies
with massive overhead competing with
companies that are selling
product that they're not paying any
permit fees or license fees and that's a
that's a big Rubik Cube that will see
how New York
uh how they handle that you know yeah
well I was over in New York there in May
and I was actually blown away but they
went to CBD stores that had cookies and
all sorts of different uh brands from
the West Coast not under the trucks as
well but we we did an all episode in the
license and the trucks just to clarify
one thing you said the government to
look at open up 150 dispensary license
is that the equity licenses that they're
given to basically people who've been
penalized by law that's right so they
that window just closed in the last I
think 48 hours they received 908
applications
250 licenses will be issued out of that
pool there will be what's being referred
to as standard licenses issued in the
future I think that the last Chris
Alexander executive director of the ocm
said that those would be their timeline
now is kind of mid mid next year so who
knows
um so we're still years out from the
real standard Mark what that's going to
look like how many of those licenses are
they going to give out per tier what
restrictions are they going to have on
them
um this first wave that's at least two
years long
the hemp Growers uh I think last count
there were 300 around 300 licenses
issued Maybe
200 plus of those got plants in the
ground
um and then the light the processor
licenses I think there's 22 issued as of
today so
yeah it's it's very exciting I used to
live in New York it's that I'm gonna
have my eye on continuously over the
next couple of years but if ever there's
an estate with a multitude of different
nationality and entrepreneurs and
connections that there won't be just one
size fits all in that one that's so
exciting you nailed it I mean I lived in
Denver the Last 22 years of my life and
you know and I moved to Rochester New
York so we're I'm six hours five and a
half hours from the city down there
every couple months but um just the uh
the diversity but also just the
interaction with people is is different
in New York I mean people want to
network they want to talk they want to
learn I mean they have hustle and it's
it's really refreshing to see
yeah it is it's one of the few places
that I've noticed as well where some of
the guys from the banking and finance
industry are posting about the Meetup
events that they're having and they're
all they're all smoking away whereas
they seem to be a lot of more churches
are more refined and don't seem to be as
braggadocious I think New York is going
to have
the shoulders swing and then there won't
be any apologetic Behavior or a new
billion dollar industry coming to the
city yeah I mean people are bold and
it's exciting man I mean even even the
well I don't know what you call it now
the gray Market I don't think it's
called The Legacy Market I think that's
something different that's my personal
belief but like that's exciting and
that's amazing and what a world to live
in that people are not being arrested
for cannabis it's the you know it's the
job of these municipalities and the
government to what do they want this to
be and they want it to be taxed they
want it to be regulated they want it to
be licensed so how are they going to to
manage that you know for companies like
us that will be hit with 280e tax
federal tax which is substantial I mean
it's hard to be a profitable cannabis
industry in the United States
um you know that I think I just read
last night that with the the top 10 or
12 msos in the country only one of them
is profitable
um but they collectively owe the IRS
over uh 550 million dollars and they're
choosing to just take the interest rate
that the that the government will give
them on paying back those taxes rather
than borrowing money or selling assets
to pay it off because it's cheaper to do
that but I mean that's those chickens
will come home to Roots like that's
that's a house cards you know yeah and
that's even something like truly would
have been swimming in cash if it were
not for the recent acquisition that
whoever was in charge of that one should
be losing their head as far as I'm
concerned so you know I bring that up
because for us where we're at right now
we have a 20 000 square foot facility we
have 30 acres of land
um
we have a lot of overhead you know we
have product lines we're developing out
Brands we're unloading more equipment
and more extractions very Capital
intensive but the goal is to keep it as
lean as possible and that goes the lead
manufacturing of you know the Six Sigma
mentality using Consultants to help our
current team but also not trying to do
everything at once it's a long game you
know it's going to be years before this
Market is open
um so how do we strategize and approach
that by by staying profitable
yeah staying a little bit hungry and a
little bit cold I think is the the
motherboard cannabis business for the
next few years I think you know to be
getting too comfortable I've got so many
things that I didn't get to talk to you
about because we're nearing the time but
there's one thing I definitely did want
to ask you've won the Cannabis Cup twice
uh those both generic wins and uh yeah
so we
um we because I don't want to take all
the credit I had a with the company mark
haha we we won two medals which are on
the wall behind me I'm super proud of
the team that did that those were both
Edibles that was our focus at the time
um that was 2013 and 14 I believe in
Denver Colorado
um one was a drink a blueberry chamomile
and one was a gummy I believe with so
many products um but we had a great team
there that company I had my core
management team for nine years uh you
know I was with that that you know
founded and and was grew that company
for over 11 years
um but then got to judge the LA the San
Bernardino uh Cannabis Cup and that was
a great experience
I'm really looking forward to what New
York and the east coast is doing with
these kind of uh award ceremonies you
know when you when you win they're a big
deal when you don't win you're like ah
it doesn't mean anything
same with everything in life if it's
working for you it's great if it's not
it's [ __ ] for everybody not
following Tim on Twitter at the Teemo
McDowell but is is how you recommend
following them a wealth of information
Tim thank you very much for taking the
time today hopefully we can touch base
maybe in the next six to eight months
and we'll see how you guys are getting
on and how the New York Market's getting
on yeah yeah I look forward to it it's
good to get to know you and thanks for
having me on thank you very much till
next episode everybody