[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i am delighted to be
joined on this episode by jeffrey
huffman who's the founder of 420 jurist
and a leading lawyer based in new york
how are you keeping today jeffrey doing
outstanding thank you sir
great stuff i'm delighted to have you on
i've been looking at a lot of your
second live streams on linkedin and
doing my research and you seem to be a
man who's going to be able to bestow
some knowledge on the audience so do you
want to maybe give everybody a quick
little overview of how you came from
graduating law school to opening up 420
jurist and your space in the cannabis
industry
sure it's a bit of a twisted journey um
i was in law school here in the united
states in the mid 90s um and for those
of you that
remember that time that was also when
the internet was getting going so i
actually started my career in tech
started a web development studio was in
a couple of uh sustainability startups
that use technology i was always doing
law in the background and a lot of those
entities i was a general counsel or
otherwise
was doing other some legal things
as cannabis legalization really started
rolling here in the united states
california started doing medical in the
90s and then finally in the
early 2010s specifically 2012 colorado
and washington legalized here in the
united states we were kind of hoping
new york would as well so i started
screaming very loudly about
we got to legalize we got to expunge
everybody's records we got to get all
the non-violent cannabis offenders out
of jail
but for various and sundry reasons new
york did not get around to legalizing
until 2021 and so once new york did that
uh this really became what i started
doing full-time
amazing stuff so we're hoping that the
delay with new york is uh an ability for
them to learn some lessons from the
mistakes that have been made in other
states and hopefully that's the case
first topic i wanted to talk to you
about was your ask me anything live
stream on linkedin it's become very
popular a lot of people talking about it
was that set up basically just as a way
to help us stow information on let's say
you're entrepreneurs who might not have
access to a lawyer of your caliber
uh correct so not just those individuals
but frankly to anybody right so
i'm a big believer that information
deserves to be known
that we in the legal profession and and
people in other professions uh do a
disservice uh to the community writ
large if they don't share information
i'm not saying that everyone has to take
on every client or do everything they
possibly can
in 24 hours in a day but it is important
to me that information gets out and so
that's information about what's going on
um both in the state as far as the
progression of legalization as well as
the expungement information and the
justice information which i mentioned
briefly before um so really i just
started doing it um because i'm a long
time uh fan of the website reddit which
i think is
uh the website that really brought the
concept of an ask me anything uh to
public consciousness uh if you're on
reddit then um experts in all fields and
frankly these days people perhaps aren't
experts but anyone that wants to open up
on reddit and do an ask me anything can
do so and then very similarly to what
you're doing with me today
linkedin started rolling out their video
feature uh stream yard is one of which
you're using is one of the ways you can
connect to linkedin and stream video for
any type of presentation or discussion
and so i said hey nobody seems to be
talking about this in cannabis so let's
let's take the ask me anything from from
reddit and and use the technology which
linkedin now has to do live videos and
let's do that every week at at 4 20 on
wednesday obviously 4 20. everyone knows
why that and just here in the united
states and i'm sure most other places uh
wednesday is the day that most people
are at work
monday and friday are the days you might
take off so we started doing it
wednesday at 4 20 and off we go
yeah no it's been absolutely brilliant
in any young entrepreneur looking to get
into the industry i highly recommend
watching along the sessions you'll learn
an absolute
a good amount of information next thing
i wanted to talk about was basically
your own practice 420 jurist and was
that strategically set up with a
specific aim in mind like i know you
specialize in licensing and permitting
and strategy negotiations and contracts
was uh
would the digital should all flow
organically or did the 420 jurist name
come from somewhere in particular
um it just makes sense right i mean i
needed something that the url was
available for
and uh here in the united states in
particular and i guess worldwide now 420
is just the code for
for cannabis right i mean it dates back
well into
uh
last century and it's funny to say that
these days um where this term 4 20 4 20
p.m during the day um you know 4 20
april you know we in the united states
do month and then day so april 20th is 4
20 so that's another day that has pretty
big significance in the cannabis
community um so obviously that was some
nomenclature that made a lot of sense
and then again usually the word lawyer
or attorney is taken if you want to look
for a domain name but jurist which has
the same root
as juror
so a juror is a person that sits on a
trial and makes a decision a jurist
can either be an attorney or a judge or
a person that works in the legal
profession here in the united states
so so 420 juris just made a lot of sense
yeah it flows off the tongue right and
as i said it's all about that domain as
well if you can get that catchy easy
domain is half the aim
tell me this the licensing and
permitting that you uh excel at do you
think that the new york authorities have
managed to get licensing and permitting
correct because we noticed that even
from over in europe you can see that one
of the first states that kind of
really set out to do a social equity
program a lot of the others kind of gave
it a little bit of fluff but nobody
really executed it are they delivering
on their promise from what you can see
and is it designed properly
so so far so good um in most regulatory
schemes that we have here in the united
states it is either a license or a
permit that the organization needs um
it's actually quite fascinating to me
when you look at different industries
where when the license is the important
thing and when the permit is the
important thing i used to work in the
mobile vending industry here in new york
these are the food carts that you see on
the sidewalks everywhere and in that
industry interestingly enough it's the
permit that's important and the license
is something that anybody can get the
permit is the thing that's difficult to
get in the cannabis industry it's almost
exclusively licenses the only thing at
the moment that they're calling a permit
is
what is going to be available to the
testing labs these are the labs that
confirm there's nothing wrong with the
cannabis that you grew that the the thc
level is what you say it is etc etc
for the licensing we are right now
getting ready to roll out and in fact on
thursday of this week
depending on when you air this today is
monday the 22nd that you and i are
talking but on thursday the 25th of
august the state is going to roll out
the first retail license and that
license will only be available to
individuals that were previously
convicted of a cannabis crime in the
state of new york or were arrested for a
cannabis crime and then convicted of
something else that came out of that
cannabis arrest
additionally they also must demonstrate
that they were an owner uh at least a 10
percent owner of a business that was
profitable for two years
we think that there's going to be
somewhere around 100 or 150 of those
licenses given out
and so and in addition the state is
actually going to build the dispensaries
for those individuals so the state has
raised 200 million dollars the entity in
the state that controls the real estate
portfolio
of the state here in york is going to be
responsible for this program so no other
state has even remotely come close to
some kind of equity program
such as that i mean literally
depending on where the dispensary is
going to be built in the state you're
looking at somewhere between an 800 000
to a 1.5 million dollar asset that the
the license recipient is not going to
have to build themselves the state is
going to build it and then the licensee
will simply rent that from the state
additionally and some of the other
licenses that we're going to see coming
either later this year or early next
year what i call the nine standard
licenses
this is cultivation uh processing
distribution retail etc um there will be
the ability for certain individuals to
apply is what we are calling a social
and economic equity applicant
and that would be minority-owned
business woman-owned business uh here in
new york we have a concept known as
distressed farmers so they'll be able to
apply and also service disabled veteran
these are members of our own of our
armed forces uh that were disabled um
while they were in service and so the
state's goal is to give half of the
licenses to individuals that would
qualify as social and economic equity
applicants they're going to get all
kinds of other benefits they're going to
have reduced or waived licensing fees
there's going to be a loan pool from
which they'll be able to get low or no
interest loans
when they come to the application
process they're not going to have to
have a right to property they're only
going to have to have a plan for a right
to property and just to unpack that for
you real quickly in many other states
that have legalized there's typically
been a lag between when you applied and
when you eventually get your license and
for most of them you had to have this
right to property when you applied that
means you either owned the building
where your business was going to be or
you already had an active lease and you
could see people sitting on a lease for
3 6 12
months or even more without being able
to open the business simply having to
hold on to that lease while the
regulatory authority was waiting to
approve their application so that as you
could imagine could be tremendously
expensive and so these are just really
fascinating benefits that the state is
going to offer to the social and
economic equity applicants and if you
include this first license that's only
going to convicted individuals all of
the things that i just mentioned there's
no state here in the u.s that has even
remotely come close uh to what new york
has proposed and is proceeding with here
yeah it really is amazing to see the
more people i talked to from new york
the more kind of positive news you see
that they seem to be doing it right and
as i said it might have been a case that
the delay that new york did has actually
been beneficial that they've been able
to uh structure this property and learn
from mistakes so i think you're right um
let's be very clear
we're humans and humans are really good
at doing two things blowing up bubbles
and making mistakes that seems to be
what we are really good at as humans and
so there are going to be problems as new
york sets up its program right they're
going to be mistakes and frankly they're
going to be very big mistakes
but i do think
you should be judged on how you address
those mistakes once they get identified
not how whether or not they happen
because i assure you they're going to
happen
so far new york has done a reasonably
good job of addressing problems when
they have come up
again we've only given out two
conditional licenses and this is a
conditional cultivation and the
conditional processing license and they
went to people that were already in the
states hemp program this application
that we're about to open later this week
is going to be the first one where we're
letting people into the program that
have not been part of anything um with
the state either hemp or cannabis uh
previously so the rubber is really going
to meet the road with this first
application and then again as i
mentioned when we get to the nine
standard licenses which are called for
in the law which legalize cannabis my
hope is that they start rolling out
those applications either very late this
year or probably more likely in the
first quarter of next year but look
there are going to be problems there's
going to be hiccups there's going to be
mistakes the way we will be judged is
how we get over those hiccups and
mistakes how we address them and how we
roll out the program as we go forward
yeah no agreed i know you're a busy man
so one last thing before you go
the we were over in new york just in may
there and there was the trucks were
everywhere the cannabis trucks that have
recently been impounded was that a case
of the license and the permit did not
match for what they were doing or was
that just a concerted effort to clean up
the
let's say the retail side of the
industry uh so i'll tell you exactly
what it is and it you can look i
actually just over the weekend did about
four posts on it on linkedin
and what i previously did i mentioned i
was very involved in the mobile vending
scene here in new york and that is
exactly what it is related to in fact
this was not an enforcement action
related to cannabis now that have been
it may have been a fallout component of
it but the reason why these trucks were
um seized and there have been two
incidents of it one
several weeks ago and one just recently
the one several weeks ago was because
the trucks involved had about two
hundred thousand dollars worth of
parking tickets and if you've got two
parking tickets the state of excuse me
the city of new york is going to grab
your vehicle and extract that money from
you so that was the incident that
happened a couple of weeks ago and the
one that happened just now
here in new york city every region of
the city is divided up into what we call
business well not every region but a lot
of the the commercial regions of the
city are divided up into what we call
business improvement districts bids bids
um and these business improvement
districts have a lot to do with them
keeping the quality of life and the
traffic and all of these types of things
at a nominal level for the businesses
and the residents that are within their
particular district
and none of the trucks that were selling
cannabis here on the streets had the
necessary permit and if you remember we
said previously that in the mobile
vending it is the permit that is the
critical piece of the puzzle that
literally you can't get in new york city
anymore and if you want to buy one on
the black market it's literally twenty
thousand dollars for a two year permit
but none of these trucks had one of
those permits so therefore they were all
illegally vending regardless of what it
was they were vending so it was very
easy um for the bid to communicate with
the police
and the police came in and said this is
great so it was specifically the times
square
business improvement district that this
did this they reached out to the police
they said let's do an enforcement action
against these folks that don't have the
required permit to be vending um by
parking there at the curb and that's
exactly what they did and i believe they
seized 19 trucks and those trucks will
be given back to their owners once they
come and pay the fine for vending
without the vending permit and it would
be my guess that you will see that
enforcement spread to other business
improvement districts around the city
now that they've seen this initial one
be successful
brilliant amazing real recap for that
that's very interesting we're at the
time now and i know you're a busy man
today so i'm going to let you go for
everybody wants to check out the
services uh
you can of jeffrey you can check the
website link below to be posted in all
the places that this is posted for for
now jeffrey thank you very much i hope
we can touch base in maybe 12 months and
see how new york has kicked off
everything um i would advise you to come
back maybe in three to six months
because like i said this first license
is gonna roll and we're hoping the first
couple of stores get opened uh uh well
they've promised before the end of the
year so late december so i think turn of
the year would be an interesting place
to check in and see if they've met the
grade there yeah absolutely brilliant
thank you very much for your time
jeffrey it's very much appreciated you
have a great day and chat to you very
soon thank you sir have a good one
bye-bye everybody