[Music]
welcome everybody to another episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined on this episode by
marion zambit marion is the head of
medical cannabis at the malta enterprise
and for those who've been keeping up to
date on the news you'll have heard that
mulcher lincoln making a lot of moves
with the medical cannabis industry in
europe
they've got a new tech startup and malta
enterprise by all accords are
going after this interesting with
augusto and it's great to be joined by
how are you keeping marion
we're keeping very well here thank you
excellent
thank you very much for coming on the
show i'm delighted to chat to you it's
great to see
malta enterprise making such innovative
moves in this industry and there's lots
of lessons to be learned by the rest of
the european governments
can we basically give everybody just a
quick overview of how you ended up with
multi
enterprise and the cannabis industry in
general
yes sure multi-enterprise has been uh
pivotal in the setting up of this
industry from its very first inception
so when two years and a half ago almost
two years ago we started conceiving of a
legislation
which allows for the use of cannabis for
medical purposes as well as research
purposes
we mode enterprise has had a central
role
both in establishing the legislation
as well as attracting the top companies
in the sector
to start setting up their activities in
malta
as we have gone along throughout these
three years
we have not only continued to attract
key
key companies to start working from
malta but have also supported them
throughout the implementation of their
setting up stage
okay amazing yeah because we've spoken
to a couple of the
people do you have over there like we
nick paters from materia ventures deepak
who we spoke about and then we had jonas
simerman on two weeks ago so
everybody seemed to be developing and
cultivating a lot of the top talent in
the industry are
making them all to their base it's one
of the things i think ireland are well
behind
when i when i see europe in the lex
long-term overview i've seen malda in
ireland being two of the pris
the premier destinations for your
corporation with the incentivized tax
rate
with the highly skilled workforce and i
think malta i've just gotten out of the
block so much quicker than ireland and
i i think the leaders over here aren't
as forward thinking as the guys that you
have in charge and malta
first topic that are going to move
straight on to it's
what i hope to see on a lot of packaged
products in the medical cannabis
industry over the next one and that's
the maid and malta sign
can you tell all the audience a little
bit about this and what's the strategy
behind it
sure the made malta sign um
should be a synonym of high quality
pharmaceutical grade products and i'm
using the term pharmaceutical
on purpose and not medical the reason
being that the regulator in malta the
molten medicines authority
is making it a requirement that
all the facilities are eugmp licensed
as though they were producing a fully
fledged pharmaceutical
with a marketing authorization so even
these are medical products and do not
require a
marketing authorization or do not as yet
have a marketing authorization
one can rest assured that the process is
as rigorous
and as as
as restricting as the one where
producing a fully fledged pharmaceutical
not only but the ownership of the
product
by the producer does not stop
at the point of batch release from the
production facility
but the ownership continues up to the
stage
where the distributor releases that
product on the market
so before the distributor releases the
the ownership and therefore the
responsibility and the liability
are still held by the producer in malta
this is obviously indicative of
the very high quality and the
how seriously we are taking the sector
and how
not difficult but how rigorous
and tara we are um
the medical cannabis sector in malta
builds over
decades of experience in the
pharmaceutical sector
maybe this is not something that
everyone is aware of
but malta has a very important
pharmaceutical cluster
it's a very well consolidated cluster
with renowned names operating in the
sector
companies like teva pharmaceuticals for
instance operate from malta
and this has made it such that malta has
not only
the right environment but there are the
right skills
we have the right regulatory expertise
and we have a consolidated and
established
cluster which is enabled also by a very
robust
ancillary industry so for instance when
you consider the cluster the cluster has
its own dedicated printing press
which is dedicated to printing of
foils vignettes labels and all the other
materials related to the pharma industry
we have precision engineering companies
which are
which provide the industry with the
tooling
for for instance tabletting machines
encapsulating machines
there are companies which are
specialized in automation lines
and therefore they come in very handy
for the for the packaging lines and the
automated
bottling lines and and all that so it is
a very very healthy cluster so when it
came to evolving into the medical
cannabis scenario
it was building up on all of this
expertise and this has facilitated
the industry in various ways these last
two days i've been touring around the
facilities that are currently setting up
in the medical cannabis sector
and all of them boasted of a team which
is highly skilled
and highly operational so these
companies were
enabled and to set up so quickly and
malta
mostly because they found the right
skills the right regulatory environment
and the regulator which is highly
competent the the malta medicines
authority
is in fact one of the most highly
reputed
authorities uh within the eu and it was
one of the first seven which were also
um fda accredited
so this goes to show and how highly
reputed the medicines agency is
having the medicines authority as the
regulator of the sector
gives more credibility more more
reassurance to anyone who is going to
use the maiden water brand
okay amazing i look forward to seeing
that made of malta brand grow now over
the next couple years i think it's a
phenomenal idea
and as i said i think when you look at
the overview of europe it's got to be
malt in ireland that can sell the
services
and the specific sectors for the
cannabis industry we're never going to
be the mass cultivation
operations but like what you guys have
done the extraction the distillation the
packaging this can all be done in a
country that has a great corporate tax
rate a great skilled workforce
and i think most global corporations
when they're finally in this space in
europe it'll be between
ireland and malta as with the
pharmaceutical industry we've got fiser
and the likes here and
you guys have made and a few others
there so it's it's an amazing
amazing to see and i i know again you've
got so much talent that are happening
there
tell me about what it's like attracting
the talent
is there a specific are you guys
pitching to
uh companies or are you guys having
companies come to you and you're setting
down the specific
terms and framework that allows them to
basically grow their companies at the
best trade possible
so obviously three years ago we were one
of the first movers
and we had first mover advantage however
we didn't make it too easy in that
we we adopted a process which is a
two-stage process
the first process is to apply with
multi-enterprise for a letter of intent
and that gives you the green light to
to start implementing your project and
then eventually you start working with
the medicines authority in order to
obtain the license
um our application process is very very
rigorous
so in order to in the first years when
we were attracting the top
companies there were three main criteria
namely the financial viability of the
project that we're looking into
obviously due diligence it's important
in all sectors
but in cannabis it was even more
important
so even the most minor of glitches um
could result in the non-approval of the
project
and third but not least we were looking
at
experience so in the beginning we wanted
to make sure
that anyone who is operating in the
sector has an established track record
of producing cannabis um
and dealing with cannabis in the sector
and that meant that the first companies
that
uh that were attracted to malta included
the big names
like uh like afria like mgc
like amec life sciences we have panaxia
we have all of it
we have material we have hoshi so
it was being first movers
and having this process this transparent
process in place
obviously attracted the big names into
coming to malta
at this stage however we are also
looking
and hence for instance attack for can
and we are also looking at adding depths
and layers to the industry
by opening up to startup activities and
startups bring energy startups bring
enthusiasm startups bring innovation
and unless you have a healthy cluster of
startups operating in any sector
you cannot guarantee that you are going
to have
um research innovation and development
of the sector
so this is our next phase where we are
looking at
at key startup activities we are finding
ways how to support them tech 4 can
is and i can say the name because i have
rendered that public themselves
um are very eager to start up the
tech accelerator activity from from
walter it's going to be the first
medical cannabis accelerator in all of
europe so we're very excited about that
so now the industry is not only
attracting just the top companies but
also adding flavor adapt and interest
by having these other companies joining
in the cluster
amazing yeah i think that's the proper
direction as opposed to focusing on just
one or two of the large corporations
cultivating
a sector that provides a multitude of
services will
ensure the longevity of the made in
malta brand name
it's been an absolute pleasure talking
to you on the show today i hope we can
touch base again in towards the end of
the year
and see where maida malta has grown to
and
yeah thank you very much for joining us
mary and i hope you have a great day
thank you for inviting me over have a
great day you too thanks everybody for
watching we'll see you on the next
[Music]
episode