[Music]
welcome to another episode of the
cannabis review i am delighted to be
joined on this
episode by matt lemers he is the
international cannabis markets
correspondent
n how are you keeping maddie well very
well thank you thanks for having me it's
a pleasure
delighted to have you on mate i've been
following all your articles regularly
you're one of the great sources of
information in the industry
and do you want to basically maybe give
everybody a quick little overview of how
you got into the industry and where you
are
at mjbiz sure yeah just briefly i guess
i
i've been a journalist for almost 20
years um
uh actually i'm canadian but i grew up
uh
outside of canada for the a lot of my
adult life and now i moved back to
canada about four years ago
uh specifically to take this job to be
the international editor for mj biz
so i live near toronto here
okay amazing and uh how do you think the
industry's grown so quickly in
in the time that you've been interest do
you see the media side of things
starting to ramp up a little bit more
that seems to be the slowest side of the
industry i've seen so far
i think the media side uh grew too fast
and speaking in canada anyways the media
uh grew faster than the actual industry
in 2018 and 2019 so unfortunately
um quite a few cannabis journalists
lost uh lost their jobs which is
which is really sad right so there were
a lot of people reporting on this
industry
a few years ago but there's not very
many of us left in canada
um the industry needs more reporters
right it needs
it needs more light than ever shine and
it needs
um a lot of analysis it needs just
um rigorous um analysis
and that's kind of one thing that uh i
might be missing in other countries
in canada we have a bunch of journalists
doing this but i'm not sure how many
dedicated
journalists are reporting on the
cannabis industry in europe or
in in australia they probably need more
yeah i couldn't agree with you more and
let's hope we see
a lot of people take up the button now
over here because you're starting to see
the momentum in europe
i'm going to kick things off with the
first topic of conversation and it's the
fate of the canadian lps
it's been a roller coaster even as of 18
hours ago the stock seemed to be sent
soaring by the news from amazon
how do you see the fate of the canadian
lps do you see them develop each other
until there's just one dominant company
or do you see the mergers that have
happened
recently uh then being able to just
compete for a market competition
themselves
well that's a great question um firstly
though
i would warn people against tracking
this
the stock market and concluding that
that's
kind of uh a barometer for the the
health of companies
um the stock market and the health of
cannabis companies
are not connected at all and we've seen
that in the last five years when
all the cannabis companies in canada
that were publicly traded
sword evaluation
even though they had no fundamental
reason to do so
so uh i don't follow the stock market
very much i
check in i check in on cannabis stocks
approximately once a month maybe less
i never report on it um it's a it's a
distraction it's noise
and it's not helpful for businesses or
for
investors because like i said um the
fundamentals of the companies
are so separated from how they're
actually
performing from the stock market there's
no there's no correlation at all
so um i i think that you need to really
get to know
um who's on the board of directors
um you need to get to know the ceo and
when i say get to know i don't mean
picking up the phone and calling them
and talking to you i mean you know
reading up on his background like has
the ceo ever done this before
um how what does the board of directors
look like does the board of directors
have people
who have been successful in their
careers
in this industry or an adjacent industry
in the past
um and most for most companies the
answer is no like most companies
um are led by ceos who have just never
done this before
um the boards of directors have people
who have never done this before and
and you see them struggling now but i'll
say there's
one thing that that doesn't apply to is
is founders okay so if you're going to
found a cannabis company
that doesn't mean you don't know what
you're doing but at some point the
founder has to step aside
for someone who has done that before to
bring the company to the next stage
and that's something that almost all the
canadian lps failed to do
most of the founders stuck around for
years too long so i don't even have to
say the names here we all know who they
are right they stuck around too long
and now their companies have lost
billions of dollars that was one of the
key mistakes they made
yeah no all i agree one of the voices i
love listen to the most in the industry
is a guy called rob mcpherson
i think he's based out of canada as well
and he always makes the point that a lot
of these companies are in the consumer
goods business
they're not in the cannabis industry and
stuck in your board or having the
expertise of consumer goods
uh makes complete sense but when you
look at the leadership of the companies
there's pretty much little to no people
who have actual
experience in these exact industries
that they're trying to target
which kind of leads me into this next
topic now leadership in cannabis
give me the top three qualities you
think a ceo
for a cannabis company need and it's not
the founder now the person that the
founder should be bringing in to run the
ship
what are the top three qualities you
think they should have
well first he has to he or she has to be
uh
they have to have a vision um so you
can't just come in
even if you're an experienced cpg
executive you can't just come in
and run your cannabis company company
like you would
any other cpg company without any kind
of vision like
what's your goal you know what company
what customers are you looking for
are you looking to delight you can't be
you can't be looking to delight everyone
and
that's another mistake a lot of
businesses make here in this industry is
that
they're like oh we want to have we want
to be the market share leader but what
market exactly
you know you can't just want to be the
canadian marketeer leader
without specifying which customers
in canada specifically you want to meet
meet demand for because you can't meet
demand for everybody if you do
you'll try and lose um
so you have to have a vision a very
specific vision
um you have to be disciplined i think is
the most important one
and that's something we we haven't seen
much of uh i say maybe in 2018 to 2020
maybe lately we have like some a lot of
ceos now
um they do have the discipline probably
that they needed a couple years ago
so rather than pulling the trigger on
that 800
million dollar m a um you got to step
back and be like
what's this really going to accomplish
for my company
should i buy should i pay 800 million
dollars for this company that has no
revenue
is that really a good idea probably not
um i mean the third one i don't know
the first two are probably the most
important the third one i don't know
maybe you
need to be a little bit flexible and
adaptable
and in how you're planning your business
because
if you're just going to bank on on one
market
you might you might get burned although
when i say that out loud it doesn't
sound that great because what you need
to do if you're
if you're an executive is you really
need to focus on where you can actually
make money
real money like where are the real
markets today uh not the markets that
are in your investor deck
so a lot of companies a lot of publicly
traded companies will have
a slide in their investor deck that says
there's a global opportunity that's
three or four hundred billion dollars
but that's not
real right that's not accessible
like here not none of that is accessible
to your business so why is it in your
investor deck
so maybe the third the third most
important thing is just that you have to
be realistic
and be honest with yourself and your
investors because that
300 billion dollar slide in your
investor deck is not
honest with yourself or your investors
it's not real it's fake
i don't even think it should be legal to
be honest with you because 99 of that
market isn't addressable for the
business so why is it there
why are you even talking about it you
know what i mean
yeah i agree i i completely agree with
you that's one thing in europe we're
lacking there's good financial analysis
and reports of the industry over here
you get a lot of the the usual the
industry will be worth
100 billion by 2024 but realistically
like it's not 2024 now we want to know
what it can do now for the investor
and for the entrepreneur setting up the
company out for the consumer
i'm gonna end with the last topic which
is basically
m a's in 2021 do you think this is the
year where we're going to see most of
the m a's or do you think
the us having a nationwide industry will
be
that year that happens will be the real
year of m
a's and what's your thoughts on the hexo
red car deal
um just broadly i guess it's in canada
all the lps are talking to each other
about m a like everyone's talking to
everyone
but what's slowing it down i guess is
that
um
there's not a lot of successful lps
right like a lot of them are struggling
there's some successful llps
uh but they're the quiet ones and i
think
earlier you asked about traits of
a ceo and i would say that
the most successful ceos that i've seen
in canada are the quietest ones
um and that's usually uh the guys that
are
privately owned right the publicly
traded c ceos are usually noisy
and they're doing interviews they're on
msnbc
and they're on bloomberg all the time
but
i think that's mostly a distraction for
people
um so i think you know get down to
business and just
and just run your business rather than
uh trying to
talk about your stock so much that was a
big distraction for companies for years
so what was your question again and
basically do you think that 2021 is
going to be
yeah yeah the m a's or do you think like
when the states basically have
statewide access and the big boys and
there started gobbling up the
competition
do you see that that year that that
happens is going to blitz
the the year that we're having so far
because there's been
you know i don't know it's a really good
question but it's hard to say
because it's also dependent on what
happens in congress right
uh there's like a i guess m a in the u.s
is slowly picking up but it's not really
picking up as much as you might
expect it should be because and that
makes sense because if you're if you're
a ceo of
a big american cannabis company
uh investing a lot of money in another
business
comes with the risk that your investment
might be moot
a year from now if depending on how the
us
legalizes cannabis and depending on what
regulations come into place
so you're kind of taking a a big risk
right now if you're
if you're spending a lot of money on mna
in the states the business you buy
could be useless one or two years from
now
um but at the same time maybe you might
be
getting a pretty good deal on that m a
because it might be a lot more expensive
in a couple years when
you know what the regulatory landscape
is going to look like
in canada it's a little bit different
the regulatory landscape is pretty
settled
the problem is we don't have a lot of
successful lps and
competition is so cutthroat um
that a lot of m a just isn't happening
right now
in terms of hexo's deal for reticam or
reedcam
um i think that was a great deal because
there weren't there weren't a lot of lps
in canada that grew their market share
in 2020.
actually i should take that back there
were quite a few but they were the
smaller ones
but rita can probably
one of the few large lps
that expanded its market share and i
think their market share doubled
um i'm going off memory here but i think
it was approximately three or four
percent to seven or eight percent
and that's a pretty significant um
portion of the market it's a successful
company
um that's probably profitable um
that expanded its market share
it has loyal customers it has a good
reputation it's
it was a great acquisition by exo i i
i'll go on
i'll go on and live and say it was
probably the best
acquisition by a canadian lp in the last
three or four years
because how many lps can claim to have
bought
another lp that was profitable and
that's growing market share
uh not very many i not come to mind
right now but there might have been a
couple right
so i think that was a great deal was it
expensive at almost a billion dollars
um yeah i mean that's it was really
expensive but like i said
the company is growing so i think i
think it's worth it
um the other two deals that sebastian
made
were a little bit rusty so i wonder if
because he also bought
a couple of smaller lps this year and so
i wonder if he would have pulled the
trigger on those two smaller mmas
if he um had known that this deal
with retican was going to go through but
you know i mean i give i give sebastian
credit because he's
he's he's going for it in canada he
wants to be the biggest
or the he wants to be among the top
three lps in canada
and he's going for it whereas companies
like like tilray
and canopy i'm not going to say they're
ignoring the canadian market
but they really have their their focus
squarely
on the u.s market and the european
market which is extremely risky
um and i don't invest in stocks so
but if i did i think i would probably
bet on the company that was that had
had a higher probability of success in a
market
that's defined and i wouldn't say
for somebody like that he's getting all
the patents going
yeah right so they have a defined market
right they know what their customers are
and
but i wouldn't say the us market is
defined yet because
we don't know what the rules and
regulations are going to look like
and the rules and the regulations kind
of set the boundaries
for where businesses can compete in and
they also set the
limit for where the market believe the
legal market can reach
um and in canada for example you
couldn't
you couldn't sell edibles in the first
year so yeah
basically for the first two years really
but so so the limit of the market the
ceiling was relatively low
but now that we're getting more and more
products the ceiling the mar the ceiling
for this market is growing
um the european market there's more
that's unknown that then that's known
so every business that's participating
in the european market
is taking a massive risk but i think
everyone knows that
although i don't think most investors
realize that the executives
sure are aware of that though look at
even denmark for example
the denmark market was doing very well
in 2019
uh in 2018 and 2019 and then just fell
off a cliff in 2020 because regulators
i'm not going to say they stopped caring
but they took their eye off the ball and
this is
an example of if you're competing in a
regulated
medical marijuana market what your
regulator is doing
is absolutely essential so
for some reason the jerk the the danish
the danish regulators kind of started
promoting this bizarre export strategy
for the country
so you have this weird situation in
denmark now where
uh danish producers are selling medical
marijuana that was made in denmark
in germany and there's no locally made
medical marijuana in denmark
so they have only like five or six
hundred customers in the last quarter
which is nothing it's drop in the bucket
right
so this is just a sign that the local
population
is just completely ignoring um that
that pilot that pilot scheme is an
example of how
regulations can be extremely risky in a
in a hyper
regulated market like medical marijuana
and
another point i want to make in terms of
the global cannabis industry to put
things in perspective
just getting a little bit off topic but
i think this is important um
we're very very early in in in this
in this medical marijuana not i'm not
going to call it an experiment but
in the medical marijuana and the growth
of the medic the global medical
marijuana industry
um if you look that i can like
look at it australia for example their
market was only worth a hundred million
dollars last year
100 million dollars divided by uh
dozens of companies competing for that
hundred million dollars and there's not
much left over
right which is why you have so many
companies that are losing money right
now
in australia and in canada it's the same
situation
um but to put that into perspective and
like how early how young is the global
medical marijuana market in australia
and germany everywhere
the canadian military reimbursed their
veterans
about 120 million canadian dollars
last year that is more money that than
was spent
in all of australia's medical marijuana
market
so the canadian military if it was a
country would be one of the biggest
medical marijuana markets in the world
now that's not saying the canadian
military is spending too much money
because they would either be reimbursing
veterans for medical marijuana or they
would be reimbursing them for opiates
so obviously medical marijuana is better
for you than opiates everyone knows that
who looks into it it's just an example
of how young the industry is and how
much potential there is for growth in
australia and germany and elsewhere
the canadian military reimbursed their
paid their
their veterans something like 14 000
kilograms
of medical marijuana last year which is
more
than the entire european medical
regulated medical marijuana industry
for unapproved medical marijuana so
there's rupert growth tons of room for
growth but people have to be aware of
how early we are
in this and things are going to go wrong
like in denmark
overall things are going to go wrong
things are going to rise probably right
you can only assume that
but you have to plan for setbacks if
you're a business if you're an investor
you're not going to
you're not going to count on perpetual
growth it's not going to happen it's
impossible canada's been doing this for
for over 20 years so canada has the
biggest regulated
federal federally regulated medical
marijuana market in the world
um but it's taken us 20 years to get to
this point
so a country that legalizes medical
marijuana let's just say
say for example i know france is doing
an experiment but
but say they end the experiment tomorrow
and they're like screw the experiment
we're just going to legalize medical
marijuana and we're going to regulate it
it's still going to take over 10 years
for that market to develop and to grow
and to even come close to its potential
so all these forecasts that the european
medical marijuana market
are unregulated uh for regulated
unapproved medical marijuana is going to
be some
crazy number by 2024. none of those
predictions are going to be accurate
they're all going to be wrong yeah no i
agree very wise words
i'm going to end it there for everybody
who wants to check out matt's work check
out mba
mjbizdaily.com matt it's been an
absolute pleasure having you on the show
i hope we can talk again in the future
dissect everything and see how
everything turns out because
from somebody who's been talking to
everybody in europe things are going to
ramp up pretty quickly here and it'll be
a
it should be a good l ride so your input
would be
valuable on that so have a great day man
thank you very much for coming on the
show thanks a lot for having me i
appreciate it