[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined this episode by penelope hamilton
from the cannabis community over new
york how are you keeping penelope
i am doing wonderful thank you for
having me thank you very much for taking
your time i know you're a busy lady so
we
ireland has an affinity with new york so
we have much as an interest that's
happening in new york i think as we do
that's happening in europe so it's great
to have an expert of your caliber on to
give everybody a quick little overview
do you want to maybe give everybody a
quick little brief of what the cannabis
community is and the objective and how
you came to be at it
certainly uh we are an online community
that's um was built onto facebook and
really
designed for a safe place for free
information
the community members can talk with each
other it is private and we're also
advocates and you know really try to be
a voice for them and hear their concerns
and we're an online media and news
company so we have um
directory listings shows i'm a content
creator and you know the director of
community engagement so keeping the
people
uh informed is basically what i do
okay excellent so we have a lady with a
wealth of knowledge now in front of us
so i'm going to jump straight into the
things uh first topic i want to talk
about was navigating regulation and
policy in new york
um
obviously it it's a huge myriad of
different uh sectors and different
licenses can you give maybe everybody a
quick brief of the mandate for the
office of cannabis management
are they the licensed applicant
receivers are they in charge of taxation
what's the exact uh
job of that board
sure um our legislation was signed uh
march 31st of 2021
and it took quite a long time for this
office of cannabis management to be
formed our legislation the mrta the
marijuana regulation and taxation act
was the building blocks the foundation
of how we would legalize and what types
of licenses etc
and then the office of cannabis
management is written into that to
establish the rules and the regulations
of how it would all play out you know
in person when we all get to actually
apply so they are developing the
regulations
um helping with the the local laws
building out those licensed applications
every little detail of how legalization
will work in new york state
okay amazing so in terms of the license
applications over here it would be if
you've got a bar or a gambling
institution it looks as if that's kind
of the the structure that people who are
applying for campus license would apply
under is that similar in new york or is
there a whole separate entity where
people apply for every type of cannabis
license from retail to cultivation to
purification and
lab work we have all separate licenses
so there'll be nine different licenses
open for the public
and it is sort of being paralleled you
know just like our alcohol and tobacco
so but it's not um the same organization
this office of cannabis management is
brand new so this is something that has
to be built out and then there's little
you know
group subgroups under that for advisory
and such too
um so there's
all separate licenses that we'll have
going out for each um and very specific
that it will not be vertical
which is you know seed to sale in new
york state for the large organizations
but we will have seed to sale available
for a micro license so that the smaller
individuals can get involved and you
know
offer a craft product
yeah well i think that having the
barriers to the big msl is just coming
in and trying to double up the big
market it's canada i think has proved
that that vertical integrated model
doesn't succeed when you have caliber
craft craft growers and a number of uh
highly motivated entrepreneurs can't be
stopped creating new products another
thing i wanted to ask you about is
taxation over new york does that fall
under the irs purview or again does the
new office of cannabis management have
the power to go
and uh retrieve taxes that are owed to
the state
so i mean the tax base was written into
the legislation that mrta
and it's being collected at different
um
different areas some is
at um
different steps you know it's not all at
the at the retail throughout the process
of it being grown processed so there's
different taxes that's applied
and then it's
collected and sent into the state
and then the counties will actually you
know collect and send into their states
as well and to be honest that is as far
as my knowledge on the taxation um you
know piece would be
and if they release figures of what the
kind of numbers that they're going to
tax at or is this still to be determined
before the first retail stores open up
in autumn yes we do have it exact but
you know we do know we do know what
percent will go to uh counties and in
any town
um that opted out of specific retail or
consumption site lounges they will not
be getting
their piece of the tax revenue either
so
that's an interesting stipulation i
think you might have a couple of votes
down the line to bring that all back in
when they see the revenue that's gone
into the legalized territories
possibly yes and they do have that
option they can easily opt back in
so
and so next thing i wanted to talk about
was community engagement
how do you see the industry over in new
york at the moment is there a
flourishing local scene in the different
five boroughs is there uh
individual companies you kind of see
leading the way we saw some of the
columbia care purchased there recently
what's your overview of the community in
new york at the moment
yeah i mean i think a lot of um
scratching our heads just watching too
because like you you just said the
columbia being um you know
purchased so a lot of changing hands
what's happening with etane so a lot of
questions out there who's going to
dominate and that's a lot of you know a
lot of negative talk too a lot of them
don't want those registered
organizations or those multi-state to be
monopolizing but i think we're going to
have some some good competition in new
york especially because we have those
smaller licenses and we're seeing a lot
of action across the entire state from
east to west with uh the legacy market
right now too they're calling it a gray
area so a lot of people are setting up
shop and
they're really not
quote-unquote legal
so
and are you excited now have they given
an exact date for the first retail
stores to open up in new york because
i'm sure there's a number of european uh
travelers who are frequent visitors to
new york who this is going to be the
icing on the cake to a trip to new york
now for the future
oh i'd love to be able to tell you a
date but no we do not have an exact date
we are just still trying to form the
actual regulations on how to
set these license applications up so we
have a few things that are going faster
social equity was written into our mrta
as a the main objective here in new york
state so we're trying to take our time
and see if we can get those uh social
equity the 50
are supposed to go to a social equity
applicant of our licenses throughout the
state so
it's taking a little bit of extra time
trying to get some things
you know to go in the right direction
yeah well i think that shows that equity
piece is a great uh nuance for investors
you might be getting in the industry
there's certain individuals now who will
have access to capital that may not have
had access to capital purely and the
distinct that they've got access to a
license ahead of uh
standardized companies which i think is
a good thing across the board
yeah just trying to lower some barriers
you know so new york's trying to get
very creative even as far as helping to
fund grants teaching uh you know really
to be there and guide them don't want
people to fail
yeah a good educational program now i
think is essential for getting everybody
up to speed on all the different do's
and don'ts for the industry
definitely yeah and it's it's
still so like i said so many questions
you know we know these are written in
all these different little um programs
and what we would like to do but it's
just not
formed yet so everything is we we say
we're
you know
building the plane as we're flying in so
you know and it's so true
and do you see
in your opinion do you see a certain
specific uh market in new york is it
going to be flower is it going to be
vapes is it going to be edibles do you
think it'll be health and wellness where
do you think the biggest sector is going
to be in the market or is it going to be
tourism just a casual footfall going by
dispensary down in
midtown or open
yeah that's a great question um
i think tourism is going to be huge i do
and
i would also say flower i think we're
going to see new york
um possibly really stand out with their
uh kraft flower like they did with their
craft breweries
and our wine
country because if you look at the rest
of the state we're agricultural based so
i think we're going to have some very
um talented may we say um you know
cultivation in new york state
yeah i haven't lived there for a number
of years i definitely know for a fact
that there's going to be a number of
different genetics i think that come out
of new york that are going to become
popular global strains and it'll emanate
from some little basement in brooklyn or
the bronx or something like that it
won't emanate from some lab in manhattan
oh yeah we're counting on that we're we
definitely have some wonderful legacy uh
strains already so i'm sure the genetics
are gonna continue at least that's our
hope
and have you guys seen the cbd market of
it is there is the ability to buy cbd
flower legal over there or is it just
going from illegality straight away into
all consumption of everything
it is um we really did have to fight on
that regulation because they did not
want us to have flour for quite a while
to be sold to people so the compromise
was
no pre-rolls for the hemp products for
cbd flour but you can sell the actual
flour so
okay very interesting
and it's is what are you looking forward
to most now over the first nine months
is it the opening of the retail stores
or is there something specific that we
need to know about that's going to be
happening in new york
um
i you know
this isn't to do with licensing but i
think i'm most excited about seeing our
people be able to grow and cultivate
their own cannabis because with our
legislation
all
adults 21 years and older are going to
be able to grow
their own cannabis plants at home so
i got to be honest that's my most
exciting uh you know
weight yeah that's incredible you've got
to have the potential for millions of
young botanists to be able to to have
their own plant and is that a limit is
there a specific amount of plants that
each individual person is allowed to
grow is there any rule set around that
or is it just limited to certain amount
of plants and you can do everything else
yourself
it is limited and again they're still
working on a lot of the regulations so
and that is not going to be allowed
until after the first retail sales uh
begin so um you know it's going to be a
little while medical patients will be
able to grow first and we're only
looking at three immature and three
mature plants per adult right now and 12
maximum per home per household but a lot
of people aren't going to be able to
grow or won't want to we don't feel
it'll be a competition we're just trying
to help
you know stop those those sales that
have been going on and have more access
so that people
who maybe can't afford their medicine
can now be able to grow their own so
well it's been absolutely thrilling
talking to your wealth of information
for anybody else who wants to check more
about the campus community the website
is down below i recommend checking it
out they're a great source of knowledge
and information in the burgeoning new
york scene penelope thank you very much
and have a great rest of your day
thank you very much and you as well
cheers
[Music]