[Music]
foreign
to the next episode of the Cannabis
review I'm delighted to be joining this
episode by Daniel Levinson who's the
founder at Atlas Canada Consulting in
based in Israel how are you keeping
today Daniel
I'm great how are you
I'm very well thank you very much for
taking your time to do this
thanks for having me this is great to be
here
delighted to have you on do you want to
give everybody a little overview of how
you came from property in New York
founding Atlas kind of Consulting and
being based out of Israel
sure
um so originally born and bred in New
York
um
grew up there and moved here to Israel
about six years ago
um at the age of 25
um after being involved in property
development and real estate uh real
estate investing in New York
um I
jumped in with seeing everything going
on in the CBD space I decided to jump in
and get involved with CBD sales in the
UK Europe and the US
um and
here in Israel uh decided to
um get more involved in the industry
um
work for an investment fund for a brief
period as a consultant uh doing deal
flow and after that opened Atlas County
Consultants uh to help you know some of
the companies with New Market entry
opportunities and fundraising and
Business Development uh in the industry
okay very good can we maybe jump on to
the first topic of conversation
[Music]
which is basically an overview of Israel
we all hear a lot of information out
there or these sort of things that uh
since the 60s or 70s you guys have kind
of been at the Forefront of this scene
do you maybe want to break down for
everybody what does the Israeli industry
look like what is the most prominent
sector is it biotechnology is it called
again is Medicore and D well you saw
there that Philip Morris recently
acquired an inhaler company that were
based out of Israel as well
yes I'm sure so um you know here in
Israel we have quite the
quite the experience with medical
cannabis
um first uh Dr Raphael michalam who
recently passed away unfortunately but
uh having first isolated uh CBD and THC
uh as independent compounds and uh
researching them and
um
you know from there we've had a lot of
experience
um in you know the r d side of things
um
from clinical trials to
um delivery devices as you saw with the
psych inhaler uh just getting
um
an investment from Philip Morris
um and we uh you know right now I I
think what's shining is you know the the
industry as a whole um we've had a
medical program since the early 2000s
for patients
um being able to access medical cannabis
we have you know many local uh
cultivators as well as importers and uh
brands that have entered the market here
in Israel
um we have 120 000 patients to date uh
on average
receiving about 30 grams of medical
cannabis uh per month and
um you know each each uh patient needs
their prescription from uh their their
personalized doctor
and uh we've seen just a lot of uh you
know
um
opportunity in that sector
um with with Brands looking to enter the
Israeli market and that's really where
we're trying to stick our our feet that
really help Brands come to uh Israel and
help them you know navigate the
regulation the uh
and and the market as a whole
we everybody knows that Israel is a
hotbed for starters especially in the
tech med tech space is the capital
access for companies who are starting in
this industry are looking to expand on a
global footprint is the access to
Capital there in the in the Israeli
industry
so it's you know it's still medical
cannabis it still has its stigmas
attached to it like in every Market
um you know capital is
you know definitely drying up in the
Cannabis space and specifically uh here
in Israel
um you know compared to the tech sector
um it's definitely harder to access
um not as many
investors
um you know feel comfortable with the
with the opportunities
but um we're definitely
you know we we've seen uh a bunch of
public
um
companies go public in the past uh
number of years
um so we have you know a
I'd say about five or six of our
companies uh listed here on the Tel Aviv
Stock Exchange
um as well as other other
exchanges such as the NASDAQ and um
the CSE
um and we uh
yeah it's just not you know I think it's
an issue in the in the more uh
in the broader medical cannabis Market
not just here in Israel
um an issue of access to Capital
yeah it seems to be the regulations and
rules are exactly where Prime investors
want them to be just yet do you imagine
that Federal legalization in the U.S
will spur on the Israeli industry like a
real Europe
a hundred percent
um you know being as I'm from New York
and having uh you know many contacts in
Industry relationships out in the U.S
um you know seeing markets like
California Colorado you know being there
uh in person watching them go from
medical to recreational and and now in
New York just spending some uh about two
months in New York uh just uh a few
months ago
um
you know seeing the
the
opportunities that that lie in in the
regulated adult use markets
um is definitely something we're looking
forward to some clarity and and
regulation in the U.S
um and I think that will definitely
trickle out as uh you know here in
Israel we're a pretty small country we
are 10 million people we like to uh you
know look at New Jersey as a as a
um
you know for analysis purposes but
um you know um being as I'm from New
York we're definitely uh and and the
recently uh adult use legalization over
there we are definitely looking forward
to you know that kind of trickling out
into the European markets and we do
believe Israel will will head that way
in the future
I was over in Tel Aviv myself personally
in June and I was actually surprised at
how many people were smoking cannabis in
public and there didn't seem to be any
real pushback is Tel Aviv more of an
employer when it comes to Israel or is
this tolerance widespread across the
country
yeah so we have uh you know we have
passed decriminalization here
um in Israel uh about two years ago
um
where now you know if you're caught
smoking and and uh you know up to a
certain uh holding up to a certain
amount we will not be uh you know you
will just get a fine at the end of the
day and
um
up to three strikes I believe that is
um but you know here in
it's it's not just Tel Aviv it's all
over the country we have a large you
know constituent of of adults
um you know between the ages of 18 and
and up who are you know who can be
consuming alcohol legally
um who you know are drafted into the
military at the age of 18 here and
um you know we're seeing cannabis just
uh you know open up its uh its doors to
them and
um you know being as we're a Middle
Eastern country there's a lot of you
know the the cultural
um
attachment to smoking is is definitely
relevant to this conversation as well
and uh you know I I believe they say
around 20 to 25 percent of of a at of
adults between 18 and and 60 have used
cannabis in the last year
um so we do have a large
you know kind of Black Market uh or gray
market and
um
you know people who who will
um dabble in it
we there's a lot of big companies coming
out of Israel we talked to Ilan Sobel
from bioharvest Sciences as we mentioned
the deal that got to fill up first what
is the the tip of the spear when it
comes to the Israeli industry is it
technology applied to the Cannabis
industry is biotechnology is it medical
or D what do you think is the strongest
part of the Israeli calibacy
um so so to you know to date being as
we're dealing with uh cannabis and it's
treated as a narcotic here in Israel
um you know we do have a lot of
Regulation
um as well as a pharmaceutical that it's
being treated as we do have a lot of
Regulation and hoops and
um
you know ways we need to uh Drive the
you know any any devices that are used
in delivery uh of this uh of this
medicine is considered a medical device
um so you know you need to go through
classic uh medical device uh approvals
for
um
you know with the Ministry of Health and
and as we see uh psyche medical going uh
for regulation with the FDA
um we uh
you know so so the hoops and hurdles
that that we're experiencing are are
definitely very difficult
um right now we're seeing a large push
on the consumer side and the marketing
and branding of of medical of these
medical brands that are coming to Market
uh but I do believe in the future that
there's a lot of r d and a lot of you
know more uh Pharma focused
um
pharma-focused companies that will come
to the Forefront as uh you know clinical
trials become more more prevalent in the
Cannabis industry and
um people start really focusing on the
Pharma and medical side of this plant as
well as you know as opposed to where we
have it now which is this quasi
um you know medical uh Slash adult use
conversation where uh we're not we're
not getting you know down to the to the
real uh to the real values of of where
we could be bringing this plant uh both
in the adult use aspect as well
um you know with the Pharma approach
which I I strongly believe in
yeah I think there's a huge value in
that side of the industry and those
people who can create formulations and
blends and terpenes and cannabinoids and
employ them to whether it's CB1 or CB2
receptors or inflammation or chronic
pain whatever it may be that seems to be
the big leap that's going to happen in
the Cannabis industry globally over the
next five to ten years
yeah yeah and I think unfortunately you
know we're we're missing a little bit of
that due to uh you know the the hurdles
that uh we're we're experiencing as an
industry uh along the different markets
um so
I I do believe in the next five to ten
years we we will start to see a lot of
Biotech companies and uh a lot of these
you know we we have a very well-known
terping company here in Israel
um
you know uh with with Botanical
um terpenes that are you know really
leading the way in in in r d around the
terpenes
um and the effects that it could have
um along with you know CBD THC and
um the other cannabinoids
yes there's benefits to page instead of
yet to be re brought to Market and
showcased as of yet and I think that's
where the most exciting part is going to
be what is the future plans for at this
kind of Consulting and is there anything
they would like to tell the audience
yeah we're you know we're continuing
helping companies look into Israel as a
market opportunity
um we are actively pursuing capital on
behalf of different companies as well
and
um you know trying to look into Europe
as uh Australia you know the the
emerging markets and really try to
connect the dots uh myself being from
North America and and New York you know
the U.S really I think there's a lot of
opportunities uh between cat you know
Canada and what's been done in Canada
um the U.S wants Federal legalization
right Federal Regulation exists let
alone uh legalization and
um you know Europe becoming uh the
market that it's gonna be we all know
it's gonna be
um I really believe there's a large
opportunity in in uh you know connecting
the dots and you know that's our goal at
Atlas County Consulting is really to
help companies uh you know connect the
dots and new markets whether it's
fundraising uh finding distribution
Partnerships
um
you know and and uh looking at JV
opportunities to uh help further the
market and help develop you know the
market
um as we're in this growth stage it's a
little painful of course you know during
this this time but I do believe that you
know the coming years where you know
things will start shining again and
um you know investment Capital will
start coming back and um we'll really
see you know the the Cannabis industry
really develop into what we know it can
be
yeah I think the industry is the
Quagmire that everybody's in at the
moment is going to get rid of some of
the people who are just here for a quick
book and I think the next three to five
years you'll see the real professionals
come into this industry and stay in this
industry and they'll be the ones that
will be able to foresee the future
growth of this sector globally not just
locally
yes yes definitely
uh helping the brands carry through and
um the real you know the real market
makers will start to emerge and uh we're
we're here to help along the way
well it speaks to that we look forward
to bringing the cameras over to Tel Aviv
next year and look forward to working
with you on that and hope to see you
Brussels in October if you make it but
time is up now for Daniel thank you very
much for taking your time to do this but
it's very much appreciated
thank you for having me this was great
and uh we're looking forward to having
you guys here in Tel Aviv uh very soon
we look forward to it until next episode
everybody
oh