[Music]
everybody the next episode of the
Cannabis review I'm delighted to join in
this episode by ronit Pinto who's the
founder and publisher of honeysuckle
magazine in New York how you keeping
today Ron I'm good thank you thank you
for taking your time to do this it's
very much appreciate it do you maybe
want to give everybody a quick overview
in a minute of what your position in the
industry is and how you came to get
there sure so I um I was born in Detro I
grew up in Texas I was born in Detroit
and then I lived in Tel Avie for a few
years and kind of bounc back between
Detroit and some other cities U before
laning in New York um in Tel Aviv is
where I started um writing so I have a
background in media and film in Detroit
I was working in Union film sets for
like big budget movies like Jim jarmo um
Only Lovers Left Alive and scream for
and Transformers
and um when I came to New York I decided
to stop crewing because you spend like
you know 18 hours a day on some Union
film set and I thought well I may as
well just put this to my own sort of
like
aspirations um and wanted to combine
media and film and so that's what we're
doing now with
honeysuckle um it kind of just
like um serendipitously coincided with
New York cannabis in a way CU um we
landed here in 2017 when when uh well I
started the magazine in 2014 but we
started our cannabis New York coverage
in 2017 um and uh that was like a few
years obviously before legalization so
we kind of got in at the groundup and
really like connected and got to know
the community and the local activists
and that has kind of informed our um
narrative until now so we've kind of got
to like come up with everyone it's been
great incredible yeah if there's a v
diagram of art music and culture pipus
kind is one of the few things that sits
right in the center that so it's a it
seemed to be a timely uh launch for you
guys yeah I mean it was you know we'd
always been kind of into like
underground subjects or trying to make
like taboo issues more mainstream um and
then we found that cannabis provided
kind of like a micro it was like
everything you can look through the lens
of cannabis you know it's political it's
um cultural it's um it's medicinal it's
a lot of things you can explore so
through you've had some big uh covers
recently in some of the magazines with
Little Wayne and with Erica Badu when it
comes to these big shoots are you in the
an a winter mold where you manage every
single piece of the shoot or do you give
free uh freelance to your stylist and
photographer um it's definitely a combin
like um combo I uh you know I work with
my partner Sam long who does a lot of
the photography so we did not personally
shoot Little Wayne but he did shoot
Erica and Alan coming and um you know
Whiz
Khalifa I am more of a big picture
person so I'm definitely like producing
it it's usually my idea you know I'm in
contact with the Reps who who connect us
with the cover artists um I honestly am
a little
intimidated uh during the shoots with
celebrities I don't I'm a little shy so
I more like to kind of sit back and then
I trust the people that were working
with but of course I'm like extremely
involved you know um but just not like
super Hands-On I guess like during the
shoot I don't know it depends you're
probably a good person to ask you guys
seem to be uh you've won a lot of awards
and there's a lot of recognition from
the political side of of New York when
it comes to the Cannabis industry in
general is it mayor Adams or is there a
specific politician who you think
deserves a bit of Praise when it comes
to the
industry um that's a good question you
know I think a lot of them are new
obviously cuz like cannabis is new um I
think you know we've been working with
desita Dawson since pre- legalization or
prmr since like 2017 um she's you know
we've done a lot of campaigns with her I
think the governor hok actually has been
pretty supportive also for um you know
cannabis um progress and we've worked
with taine Wright from the ocm um I
think that there's a lot of people who
are pushing the narrative you know have
brought Equity to the Forefront um
there's obvious like continual
challenges as in any industry especially
in a capitalist Society you know where
you're going to have like the
competition or interests of like bigger
corporations and I think that's like a
conflict that we see here in New York um
and I I think people are doing their
best to sort of like mitigate that or
provide um a kind of balance between the
different sort of parts of the
industry the first main topic I wanted
to talk about was New York's new wave
and like most people would know about
the new wave of Art in the 70s new W of
Music in the 80s are we about to see
from New York City a new wave of
cannabis in America and some of the
biggest companies that are going to
exist in this industry are about to be
bured in this
city yeah I mean I think that um New
York will definitely Define a new kind
of cannabis culture for sure like you
know we've seen obviously in California
it's been around and it's so accepted
and just like an ingrain part of the
West Coast culture uh it's less feels
less stigmatized there less a little
less I shouldn't say less political but
less charged than here in New York um in
terms of Brands I don't know the trend
that I see is that there's like many
Brands and it's more kind of customized
so they're sort of like um different
hierarchies kind of more like fashion so
um you know like like kind of like uh
like we've noticed these um like kind of
like sneaker sort of sneaker Brands
where you have this sort of like Elite
really high-grade cannabis that people
love that's um sold and manufactured in
smaller batches but it's more expensive
it's at a higher price that's definitely
trending I'm not sure how scalable that
model will be but in terms of companies
like I don't know if it's going to be
smaller Pockets or like uh big ones that
emerge or combination
um we'll see like you know some of the
msos in other states haven't done well
so a lot of it depends on how the
companies and brands are like touching
and reaching their consumers I know a
lot of the Legacy um you know people who
have been doing it already have their
customer base so I don't know if that's
going to like scale or stay the same um
it'll be interesting to see yeah I
haven't heard of one brand in particular
that's like blowing up you know but I I
do know like several ones that look to
be like
successful I noticed as well that
cookies opened their first New York
store there from one of the Articles you
guys did do you see the eventuality that
the Big Brand like cookies that comes
into the city is going to be able to
have a dominant hold or is New York
going to always be one of these Outlets
there's too many creative and
entrepreneurs in too many categories for
this to be dominated by an outside brand
that as you said like almost with
fashion that there's always a hip New
York New York designer that everybody
body wants what they've got yeah I mean
I think we all love cookies and um
appreciate and acknowledge obviously the
Legacy that burner has created um in the
brand that's a really tough question
like I don't know you know what I mean I
think that um I think that cookies
obviously has a following and and we
loved our event and everything that
we've done with them um but New York
will be tough because I do think people
are sort of like patriotic and you know
want like the specific New York stamp
but I mean I'm sure I'm sure they'll do
well um I guess time will tell I mean
look we're going to have a lot of like
outside state state um companies coming
in so um yeah from somebody who's lived
in New York for a number of years and
knows the city well enough it always
seems to be in New York that everybody
wants to know what's the next best thing
and do you see a scenario do you see H
is Edibles are allowed within the rules
correct yeah has there been any Artisan
stores and let's say dining experiences
that are starting to happen now you see
a lot of it over in LA with some kind of
famous 420 chefs and and whatnot are you
starting to see that in New York at the
moment yes yeah there are a lot of
infused meal events like the Mooney
house host some and you know there's um
chef Mike Hawaii Mike um Chef
Leighton uh you know as to the
legalities of the operation I'm not
exactly sure at this point like I know
some of them have brands that are um
legit and that in that like in that
like in terms of legality um but yeah
there's a lot of dining experiences a
lot like you could probably find several
a week if you look for it
okay I would imagine that a good
combination as well is going to be the
music side of the industry plus I would
imagine there's going to be catering to
tourists there's going to be a number of
experiences about that but I see the the
music scene in New York and the Canabis
scene in New York coming together to
create some unique and spectacular
spaces for consumption and not just
oneoff
events um music events you mean like
more immersive yeah um yeah I mean like
which ones are some of the ones that
you've
noticed just in terms of um will that
start happening in the future is more to
the point do you see that I'm sure
there's a lot
of music artists that have capital on
hand that are going to be able to open a
nightclub but without s on alcohol will
have cannabis consumption lounges in
there and blend that with the music's
lifestyle yeah for sure I mean I think
that we see it now you know maybe more
underground like we did a great event at
um the house of X that was like um a
Black History Month burles show based on
Josephine Baker uh we worked with this
amazing woman um Mia and uh or
choreographer and performer and like
there was consumption in a live jazz
band and we had it sort of themed about
about the end of prohibition um you know
styles p and his manager Daniel do a lot
of stuff like quarterly almost with like
jiss and they have it at Irving Plaza
and there's you know Brands there and um
music there's the Olympics so a lot of
these like cannabis kind of award shows
and cannabis music concerts are melding
together to highlight Brands as well um
and obviously there's like you know like
AST Club who has like intimate uh nights
with you know rappers and hip-hop
artists and DJs um and there's like a
lot of kind of underground places like
that when it comes to the card licenses
and the suspension that happened
recently we've had a couple of experts
from New York on at different stages
explaining the different timelines of
what's Happening currently where does it
stand at the moment are the card license
completely suspended or are they still
able to fulfill the applications that
were already put in they're trying to
codify it that will protect the card
licenses they hav done that yet um from
what I you know some they have like tear
so like some people who had real estate
and have invested you know a certain
amount are able to get their licenses
and have opened um others I think
they've opened the C program
SE um and they have to
reapply uh so I'm not sure if card is
going to exist um I know that they want
it to continue or if they're going to
have to reapply and how they're kind of
like divvying up um the people who have
already been allotted
licenses if there was business people
from Europe that were looking to come
over to New York and learn about the
industry what's the one event that
happens in New York every year like
we've got mjps in vas that happens
you've got the h a couple of the other
ones Med can and that what's the big one
on the calendar every year that somebody
if they want to learn about the New York
industry should be
attending um well I think coming here on
is a great time um because you can
there's so many parties and events and
you can see more of the industry like
how it works and how how consumers
operate and what the culture is um in
terms of events you know they've had uh
I mean Trailblazers came here MJ
unpacked was here um Ark view um I'm not
sure like it I'm not sure where
everyone's at right now I know some
companies have stopped coming here some
companies are still coming here but I
think that like 420 is a probably really
good place to survey the scene make
connections if there's something you're
looking forward to over the next 12
months in the New York industry to come
to fruition what is the the thing that
you're looking forward to
seeing um that's a great question I
think the you know more really kind of
like cool dispensaries like Union Square
travel agency just did a redesign that's
just stunning you know Gotham's doing
doing some cool branding so I think I'm
excited about the marketing and branding
surrounding that cuz I love like sexy
campaigns and just like overall visuals
um and I'm definitely excited to see
more consumption lounges you know I
think that there's a huge need people
don't want to drink alcohol like they
used to um you know they want different
options maybe even other kinds of plant
medicine integrated in there with
cannabis um for like mocktails or
infusions so I think like uh exploding
the sort of consumption Lounge nightlife
scene as an alternative to the
traditional bar is going to be really
cool um and then I also remembered just
to your point about music in cannabis
like rolling loud is a good example of a
big Festival that um highlights cannabis
and kind of has made it part of their
primary vertical or like one of their
main lanes and it's a blast and a lot of
fun so I think that's a good way to go
too amazing well Rish it's been amazing
talking to you for anybody who wants to
check out more about Hony sule magazine
the website is below and it'll be in all
available descriptions wherever you
listen or watch this highly recommend
checking it out thank you very much for
your time onun it it's very much
appreciated thank you have a good day
until next episode everybody