[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined in this episode by brad racino
he's the editor and publisher of
cannabis insider new york how you
keeping today brad
very well thanks for having me thank you
very much for having me on mate i've
been uh following all the articles you
got from publishing 80 and they're done
to a very high caliber so i've been
dying to have a chat with you and get
your uh your
opinion on the new york state as opposed
to just new york city can you maybe give
everybody a quick little overview of how
you got into the cannabis insider from
the industry that you're in
sure yeah i was an investigative
reporter and editor in san diego
california for the last 10 years and
relocated to new york
last year with my family to be closer to
the rest of my family and was looking
for
some kind of a position that would allow
me to dig deep into something really
interesting and boom cannabis is right
there waiting for me uh just timing was
perfect and we launched uh late last
year and hired our first reporter late
last year and started actually
publishing in february of this year so
just a few months and it's been going
really really well um this is a very
undercovered industry i think a lot of
major publications still aren't taking
it seriously yet which is very
surprising but also good news for us uh
but it's it's just a fascinating journey
so far and really fun to watch as this
market develops from the ground up
yeah i think new york is probably one of
the most interesting territories with
the amount of a capital that's available
to businesses that are over there that
it is surprising to see that none of the
big publications have been doing this
properly and the caliber you guys are
writing at is a is a
testimony to the challenge you guys have
i've got to jump into basically the
first topic and it's new york state
overview now we've already had a couple
of guests on to talk about new york city
and the five boroughs and whatnot but
from buffalo to rochester to the five
boroughs where do you see the
concentration of cultivation happening
in new york state
well yeah it's interesting because when
when people talk about this market they
only so far i really hear discussions
about retail and about cultivation
retail everyone seems to want to be in
new york city cultivation is happening
upstate that's where the vast expanses
of land are where the farms are where
the farmers already are where they've
been growing hemp for the last several
years
now can turn those into thc growing
farms
but from you know from western new york
i'm in central new york right now
syracuse area
if you go directly west from here you
hit buffalo right by the border you go
directly east you hit albany
all of all of those cities buffalo
rochester syracuse albany are all
prepping um for this market in in
different ways
you see some people yes looking for
retail locations but others really
looking to get their hand in the
cultivation the processing there's a lot
of talk about distribution up here and
how that's actually going to happen and
play out because this is a huge state
when people talk about new york new york
they usually think of new york city and
they don't think wow the rest of this
that goes all the way up to the canadian
border all the way west to the great
lakes there's a lot of land to cover so
um there's that's going to be an
interesting market to watch and how that
develops up here particularly uh but
yeah other than that i mean a lot of
politicians there's a politician a
senator in rochester who's been for uh
on the forefront of introducing new
legislation around the business
marketplace of cannabis um
and a lot of local politicians at least
uh here in syracuse who are still
navigating the waters of like how their
community feels toward this topic and
and whether they want to institute
zoning um you know laws to
keep these things separated so it's it's
playing out in a bunch of different ways
up here but it's all all interesting
amazing so we kind of know where the
cultivation retails happening in terms
of the extraction facilities and the lab
testing and then uh
the the manufacturing side of things are
these gonna be basically in cities that
are already open wondering what
manufacturing these facilities are
you're starting to see
new facilities being dropped up in
certain locations around the state
because obviously everybody can't be
setting up a facility around new york
there's only going to be so much
business that uh to go around
yeah so
right now i'm not an expert on this yet
because there hasn't been a lot of talk
of it i know for the lab side of things
there's only two labs in the entire
state of new york there's one relatively
new one i think down in
in the hudson valley
and i honestly don't know where the
other one is but that's that's all there
is um there is some talk of people
starting new labs but again everyone's
hesitant because the regulations aren't
out they have no idea
what this is going to look like so to
invest that amount of money uh a lot of
people are hesitant to do that uh
processing same thing there's been
some really interesting partnerships
especially with
private businesses and native american
nations
there's been some joint partnerships in
developing cultivation and processing
facilities uh in a couple parts of the
state which is really interesting to see
but
um no i i don't have any more info on
that because again the regs aren't even
aren't even out in draft form for those
so in terms of the regulations the
logistics laws shall we say haven't even
been drafted and put out to be because i
can imagine that's going to be one of
the areas of contention and
profitability with the size of new york
that uh having flower distributed at a
premium quality across the state is
going to be of a permanent importance
and keeping it safe from theft
yeah yeah exactly and it's it's a huge
missing piece of this puzzle and the
office of cannabis management and the
cannabis control board has said
repeatedly as as recently as just a
couple weekends ago that they expect
uh product on the shelves by this fall
and that's that's just you know uh four
months away falls in september that's
not that long and there's this huge
element of you got retail regulations
out you have conditional cultivation
regulations out but what about
everything in between and how does it
get from the cultivation facility to the
retail stores like if in new york if
you're transporting or you have more
than three ounces it's still illegal in
this state so
how are you going to transport that
stuff from the facility to the retail
shop if you don't have distributors
licensed or you don't have regulations
around it there's a lot of things that
are missing and a lot of people are
very
concerned for the timeline uh when this
stuff actually happens
yeah i seem to think that that's one of
the big huge things that everybody has
been missing so far it's okay to grow
and it's okay to sell it but getting it
from a to b hasn't really been foreign
as much yet
yeah yep
i've got to jump onto the next topic and
it's fifth avenue stores so i was over
new york last weekend as you know
yourself and while we were over there we
were seeing a lot of uh
mobile dispensaries around the place and
they were looked like these so these
were only pretty much on fifth and
seventh avenue it was in kind of the
touristy areas but they were selling thc
flower edibles vape cartridges all of
the cbd stores pretty much had the thc
stuff there already so
do you see these kind of places being
the future of purchases in new york or
do you see a fifth avenue apple sized
cannabis dispensaries happening over in
the city
that's a really really good question and
like you i was just in the city last
weekend and same experience walked into
a cbd store and just for fun said what
do you have by the way weed and you just
laid everything out all from california
no problems um
it's
i don't know i mean i'm not a uh
i'm not an expert in consumer behavior
in the state of new york or city of new
york i don't know what people are going
to value so the ocm and the ccb think
that
that the regulated market is going to
contain safe tested verifiable product
that people can trust and it's okay to
pay more it's okay to pay a premium for
that but there's got to be a level right
where people are saying if i can get an
eighth of california flower off this guy
on the street for 20 bucks and i but i
have to spend 75 at a retail location
there's going to be something a give and
take there where people just aren't
willing to go above and beyond um i
think that for the time being those gray
market
sellers and retailers are
going to dominate the new york city
landscape and the market i also think
it's you know it's going to be a while
before those fifth avenue stores and
retail chains are up and running they're
the the first round of retail licenses
in the state of new york are going to be
given to justice involved applicants and
the actual retail stores where they're
going to be selling from are already
predetermined and these are built out
using uh state and private equity funds
the 200 million dollar fund that the
governor has said she set aside for this
particular reason
so
i i highly doubt those stores are going
to be built to the caliber of like an
apple um or a saks fifth avenue and it's
going to be well after those stores are
established and have a foothold that i
think the ocm is going to now then allow
the big boys to come in the people with
the well-heeled interest the big pockets
to establish those that kind of presence
it may be i mean i would not be
surprised if it were two years from now
before those stories even opened um
so
i i think the next next year to two
years is really going to determine
what users uh get accustomed to what
they're willing to pay for the
experience that they are going for in
new york city um to to kind of habituate
themselves to like what what they're
after what they want to see in the new
york city retail market um and i think
that those people with the trucks and
the people with already with the cbd
stores definitely have a strong foothold
for the time being um
yeah
yeah no i think i i couldn't agree with
you more i think for the next few years
they've got a little pot of gold that's
going to be made there before the real
capital comes into the market and puts
the real legality in the laws up against
these stores and either shuts them down
or stops them selling the product that
they're going to make monetization from
one of the things you guys have a
conference on may the 20th if i'm not
mistaken as well anybody who's watching
this who's in new york at higher end
checking it out the website for a
cannabis insider is just below it's uh
i'm sure going to be a great event next
topic that i want to talk to you about
before we go is the current landscape
one of the things i was actually reading
about from yours on your site was the
acreage holdings court case
so in terms of the current landscape do
you see the big boys being able to get
away with a a
oligopoly over there or do you see that
that air court case is going to go in
favor of the the smaller
defendants
that case in particular i wouldn't feel
confident weighing in on it all i mean
you got it is it david versus goliath it
is a really interesting case to see um
to see how it plays out
but again you got acreage which is got
very deep pockets and i'm sure a team of
attorneys going up against a much
smaller plaintiff who's bringing these
charges so i i honestly i wouldn't feel
comfortable weighing in on that well
that's not a problem we'll jump on to
the next one so some of the job reports
and the job statistics that i was
looking at reading about is that within
the next five years new york looked at
50 000 jobs to the industry is that the
new york state as a whole or uh new york
city yeah no it's a state as well
are they solid numbers based on other
relative industries in the state like
alcohol or tobacco or anything like that
yeah and that's a really good question
because when we first saw those numbers
um i was
skeptical um and so had our reporter
sean teahan look into it and say hey can
you actually verify that this is real
that these they're not just pulling
these numbers out of nowhere and he did
a story on it uh just a few weeks ago
maybe a month ago where he talked to a
bunch of experts who said actually you
know what yeah these are legitimate
numbers and legitimate forecasts that we
can uh that we can kind of lean into and
i think it is it is based on other
states but they have seen play out over
time similar industries
um also the
the unionization kind of mandate that
all of these licensees um have some kind
of lay project labor agreement with um
with unions and unions are very strong
in new york and the entire northeast so
that's a a huge
job pool or applicant pool from which
they're going to be drawing from
and a lot of people a lot of people on
labor so i think
i think that those numbers are
at least legit if not being slightly
conservative um because there's as you
know there's so many ancillary
businesses and companies that are going
to spring up around there's some that
we've never even thought of things that
you just are outside the realm right now
that will make a lot of sense in a few
years
yeah i agree i think uh there's things
coming around the corner that people
can't see as of yet that might have
turned some of these parts of this
industry on its head we're coming up to
their time there brad i'm gonna let you
go because i know you've got a busy day
i want to thank you very much for taking
your time to join us
for everybody who hasn't subscribed or
signed up for new york state cannabis
insider i could highly recommend it the
the writing and the articles are very
well put together and very well done so
it's a credit to you and your team brad
thank you so much thanks for having me
this was great very pleasure talking to
you mate and chat to you guys next time