[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I'm delighted to be
joined in this episode by Christina
Damon who's a partner at ice Miller a
leading law firm based in Ohio how you
keeping today Christina I'm doing very
very well it's a pleasure to be here and
thanks for having me delighted to have
you on Ohio is a Hot Topic in the global
world of cannabis at the moment so I
thought what better to get the top law
form on to give us their perspective on
one or two different issues do you maybe
want to give everybody a quick overview
in 60 seconds of your position at your
firm and how you guys end up touching
against the Cannabis legislation
certainly thanks so much I'm a partner
in our how in our litigation group but I
have a crossover practice that works
very very closely with our regulatory
attorneys and our firm first got
involved with cannabis law RIT large uh
here in Columbus Ohio when Ohio
legalized medical cannabis we worked
with a number of of early operators to
apply for those licenses and secure
those licenses either through the
regulatory process or through eventual
litigation which is where I played a
prominent role with respect to it and
then it's been Off to the Races ever
since okay incredible so we're based
over here in Ireland and as I'm sure
you've seen over in your fa the social
media activity around Ohio and what
happened over there seems to be uh the
message is definitely not the same
across all platforms can you maybe give
everybody overie what happened in Ohio
what's the reason to celebrate and what
does it mean for the future absolutely
so as I'm sure everyone is aware this is
probably an easy fact to confirm that
Ohio has legalized medical cannabis
sales uh and it's only accessible to
patients that receive recommendations
from doctors for the use of medical
cannabis pursuant to uh a qualifying
condition that's been the case for
several years and it's become a mature
market and there's a series of
dispensaries that are coming online as
we speak over the next few months there
most recently the legislature combined
uh what was an over the several
oversight agencies to have the oversight
agency be under the Ohio Department of
Commerce so now all of Ohio is regulated
through one regulator which sets us up
well for our current stage so as
everyone that is listening here I'm sure
has heard Ohio has legalized adult youth
but what does that actually mean right
um and so as of last Tuesday after the
election on what was called issue two
Ohio uh passed what was an initiated
statute an initiated statute is a unique
feature here in Ohio that allows for
citizens to put together an entire
chapter of what is the Ohio Revised Code
and so it is a literal chapter of the
Ohio virus code that sets out all the
legal parameters concerning adult use so
it's extremely detailed it includes the
licensing process it includes certain
prohibitions concerning the program it
includes certain protections concerning
the program as well as safe harbors for
financial institutions and employers to
make certain decisions so why I I I kind
of get into that detail right away is
because this was not a RIT large we've
legalized cannabis and anyone can sell
anyone can buy anyone can consume today
it is it is part of a regulated
structure and as it stands today it
actually isn't even effective under the
Ohio Constitution an initiated statute
comes effective in 30 days so as it
stands today it is still technically not
legal to possess and use cannabis in
Ohio the effective date of the statute
is December 7 and so it's at that point
when uh consumption and use becomes
legalized um but you yet will be able to
purchase any Adult Ed cannabis so happy
to talk about that but uh wanted to just
give you that quick overview as to the
exact snapshot on where we are right
now very much appreciated always like
get into the facts of any issue and not
listen to Just people who have a vested
interest can you maybe tell me when it
comes to the 7th of December the is
there an application process that's
going to start from the 7th of December
for the cultivation Logistics and the
various different ancillary businesses
that are going to serve this sector to
apply for licenses that would cover them
under this absolutely so as it stands um
under the current structure uh the new
division of Campus control which is
created by this statute that is under
the Department of Commerce it will have
to create what are the regulations that
govern the statutory Provisions that are
in the initiated statute so first step
in fact before even a license process
can commence is the regulations have to
be published they have to go through the
Nos and comment period and then be
adopted before they can proceed with the
applications there are set parameters
within the statute that requires um the
division of cannabis control to prepare
those in short order and to uh in short
order thereafter begin accepting
applications and then as it relates to
those applications because this is I
think is a key component the way that
this the current statute is structured
is that it contemplates that all of the
current medical operators that are
licensed will have the right to secure
an adult use license for the like
operation so Ohio has four major types
of licenses the cultivation license the
processing license the lab license and
the dispensary license and so as it
stands under the current statute each of
those license holders will have the
right to secure in addition to their
medical candidates license an adult use
cannabis license and so right then the
cultivators can sell to the processors
and the processors can sell to the
dispensaries um in the adult use
market and then there is also a
component that contemplates an
additional round of licenses that's
specifically geared towards social
Equity candidates and that program will
be run initially through a through
what's a certification process under
what is the Ohio Department of
development which oversees all of
business certifications along those same
lines like a minority business
Enterprise for example or a women uh
business
Enterprise and once that certification
process is created and businesses are
certified then the application process
can commence as to those applicants as
well and then one final piece on this is
every two years under the medical
program the regulatory body is is told
to review and assess whether there needs
to be additional
licenses that same concept is employed
here in the adult youth program so every
two years the program is intended to
analyze whether the market is um being
Market needs are being met or if the
market are not being met and if it's the
latter then the and this has actually
occurred in the medical cannabis program
open up they'll open up the licenses for
additional applications and additional
entry into the market so with the
medical program for example I I
mentioned just a few minutes ago that
there are dispensaries that are turning
online those are from that two-year
review determining that their patient
population could support additional
dispensaries throughout the state of
Ohio okay incred detail thank you very
much for that next topic I wanted to
move on to was what can we expect in the
United States newest adult use Market is
the ability to sell Beverages and food
products within the realm of the
legislation that they proposed or do you
see which side of the industry you see
being the dominant player in the Future
Part of the Ohio sector certainly so
Ohio is a control state it is a control
State as it relates to the medical
cannabis program
it will be similarly controlled as it
relates to the adult youth program so as
it stands and as it's contemplated today
the program does not have for example a
feature like a consumption Lounge like
we've seen in other states it is limited
to sale at
dispensaries there are pro provisors
within the statute that allow land
owners to prohibit consumption within
their premises um as well as as it
relates to the residential land owners
to prohibit what is a hom grow component
of the program which is a feature that
we haven't yet chatted about because we
focused on the the licensing but hom
grow is just exactly as it sounds it
allows for grow of cannabis plants in
any individual's home um across the
board with the program you have to be 21
and older including with the home grower
component of the program and you are
permitted to have each adult within a
household to grow up to six plants and
each household can have up to 12 plants
and this this isn't just your you know
home Garden where you're planting your
cannabis plants it has to be in a
security area whether inside or outside
of the home and it has to be secure such
that it cannot be accessible to children
or anyone who is not of age of of the
age of
21 okay um are there brands that already
exist in Ohio when it comes to let's say
the hhc and the Delta a side of the
industry that are going to be able to
translate into this adult use Market or
do you see the big brands from other
larger States coming in and influencing
the
market it's a great question because
Ohio right it has a separate hemp
program and so I'll kind of set that
aside I great topic for a separate
webinar to go through um large United
States on that but also in Ohio um the
way that the statute is written is it's
an attempt to be comprehensive regarding
the sale of any product that may contain
th she whether it be Delta 8 Delta 9
Delta 10 any of the um variations
thereof as well as the cannaboid profile
of the plant so the intent is is that
any sale would be through one of these
licensed
dispensaries and within the state of
Ohio right now we have a number of kind
of
Marquee uh companies that are you know
being that are very successful some of
which are Ohio kind of homegrown some of
which are in Partnerships with companies
that are successful in other states and
then some of them are other um companies
in other states that have come into the
Ohio market um to participate here so it
really is the Gambit at the end of the
day which is exciting right um and
because it's a control State there's in
fact a cap on the number of licenses so
it's a cap on um the number of licenses
you can hold within kind of those four
categories I was talking about obviously
Labs need to be independent right they
cannot also be affiliated with a company
um in Ohio has um one of the best uh
testing progr programs in the nation
it's gotten extremely positive reviews
um across the board which is very
exciting and something that I I
personally very proud of with respect to
the
program and then as it relates to the
cultivators you can only own one as a
company same with processors and then as
it relates to the dispensaries currently
you can only own up to five with the
adult use proposal you can have up to
eight which makes sense because the
Market's growing and there'll be a
bigger um demand when you factor in the
adult use Market in addition to the
medical
Market we recently had a citizen
assembly here in Ireland where we missed
out on legal adult's Market by one vote
if there was a piece of advice that you
could give to territories that are
looking to open up this Market from the
activism side of the thing all the way
up to the legal side of the thing what
is the one lesson that you think could
be learned from the Ohio process that
everybody else could take away that is
an excellent question I'm really glad
that you've asked it putting together
the statute was not a simple task and it
was not done by one person it was done
by listening to interest groups to
operators to Regulators to Ohioans to
understand what makes sense for what is
Ohio today and so my piece of advice
would be to understand you can't have
everything and that's where the initia
statute was very beautiful because you
could integrate lots of different
components um but in the end at the end
of the day it did did not integrate
every single component that you've seen
in every single market right um and so
there was a balancing act that went in
in order to address each of the voices
and make sure that Ohioans when they
went to vote on Tuesday felt confident
that this was something that that would
be um something that they would like to
see in their
state yeah it seems to be regardless of
the territory it's the political
persuasion of the voter that needs to be
appealed to and it has to be palatable
for that voter whether they swing
whichever way left or right yeah that's
right in part but we've seen really an
interesting Dynamic with the vote this
last week in that there's a lot of
bipartisan support with respect to adult
youth cannabis in Ohio um and that
actually was one of the instigating
pieces to even go down this path which
by the way started over two years ago as
it related to this specific initiated
statute was that Ohio's just
overwhelmingly supported it and that
would have had to have been something
that crossed party lines because of the
current um affiliation structure or
affiliated kind of dynamic we have here
in
Ohio it's been in incredibly fascinating
talking to Christina you're a wealth of
information thank you very much for your
time is there anything that you're
looking forward to seeing over the next
12 months in the Ohio industry come to
fruition yeah I'm hoping I'm really
looking forward to seeing its continued
growth um I think it's been a slow and
steady growth and these next 12 months
are going to be critical to that um so
really looking forward to it and just
keep in mind some some of our key dates
you know we're leading into next year
and then toward the end of next year as
the program rolls out amazing for
anybody who's looking for a top LA from
an Ohio ice Millers website is going to
be below and in all the descriptions you
see you can also check out more about
Christina and her special skill set
thank you very much Christina for
joining us it's been very much
appreciated and hopefully we get to
touch base in about nine months 10
months time when we can see that
everything's been knocked out of the
park by Ohio and they're leading the way
absolutely maybe I'll be reporting live
from a dispensary how's that sounds
great you have a great weekend and thank
you very much for taking your time again
me too byebye
[Music]
thanks