foreign
to the next episode of the Cannabis
review I'm delighted to be join on this
episode by Adria G Barry or Barry who's
the director of the Oklahoma medical
marijuana Authority how you keeping
today Adria
doing great how are you thanks for
having me fantastic thank you very much
for coming on uh Oklahoma is one of
those states that has a lot of action
going on it's always good to Great to
learn from the the most important people
in the industry can you maybe give
everybody a quick little overview of how
you ended up at the Oklahoma medical
marijuana and your position there sure I
was appointed to this position August of
2021 so it's been almost two years now
and I took the job
um at the request of uh the the Governor
of Oklahoma governor Kevin Stitt he
asked me to come in and see what was
going on see what needed to be done at
the time our department was under a
larger agency the State Department of
Health now we are actually a standalone
agency the legislature moved us over and
we are now our own state agency who our
entire job is to regulate and license
the medical marijuana industry and
patients in Oklahoma
okay very interesting we talked to one
of your residents there rightly at
business intelligence a businessman who
gave us a quick little overview of the
the industry but I kind of wanted it to
start at the first topic of
implementation versus impact and
has everything that's been that they aim
to implement been implemented are there
things that got left off the the
licensing and what's been the impact the
biggest impact of the the laws that have
happened in Oklahoma
well I think if you're asking about
implementation for do you mean the
people who voted to legalize in in
Oklahoma in 2018 yeah and the laws I'm
sure at some stage a set of politicians
had to sit down and go okay how are we
going to implement this in the state of
Oklahoma state by state seems to have
been so varied and so different has the
impact been what the guy people who are
the ladies and men who've implemented
the laws been what they had hoped for or
has there been some lag in certain areas
yeah there have been well lots of
differing opinions and when State
question 788 it was a petition written
by citizens of Oklahoma that's what
legalized medical marijuana in Oklahoma
as I'm sure you've heard
um and that happened in June of 2018 the
people who wrote that and voted on that
voted for a very free market approach to
the medical marijuana industry so they
didn't have any there were no caps on
the number of plants that could be grown
there's no limit on the size of a grow a
cultivation facility there's no limit on
the number of commercial licenses that
we can grant no limit on the number of
patient licenses no qualifying
conditions so as you can tell from what
I'm saying it was a very free market
free approach to medical marijuana one
that hasn't been done in any other state
so Oklahoma has been the kind of the
test case for how the free market works
and when it comes to medical cannabis so
um the session the legislative session
after that state question passed the
legislature did come in and wrote some
laws to to put a little bit of a
regulatory framework around the industry
and I think that if you ask how the
implementation was intended versus the
impact I believe that all of the parties
involved would say there were definitely
unforeseen
um consequences of the way that the free
market approach worked uh one of those
is that the the very low
there's a very very low barrier to entry
into our industry which is not by itself
ever a bad thing right
um but what has happened in Oklahoma is
that even the criminal organizations are
getting an omma license or we're getting
an omma license they found ways to get
around and so they look on the surface
like they're legitimate but they are
actually
um not legitimate businesses so what's
happened is we are now
forced to to distinguish who is a
legitimate business owner versus who is
a criminal actor
um and that takes up a lot of our time
here at the regulatory agency so the
implementation versus the impact I would
say there were definitely some
unforeseen circumstances
and when it comes to Oklahoma excuse me
is it a blue or red state
it's a very red state
okay so it's uh it's great to see that
there was such an open uh uh platform to
be able to do these kind of things but
like with everything when you opened the
gates there's always going to be a few
little things that you need to tidy up
once the gate have been opened when it
comes to the regulatory framework the
more permissive license approach that
you guys had as you said there's some
nefarious actors getting into the market
that you didn't necessarily want is
there software or is there now a
separate uh agency within your
department that literally look after due
diligence for business owners and ensure
that everybody meets the high standards
we are
we're
seeing sale tracking last May so it's
been exactly one year that has helped us
tremendously by
um helping our inspectors who go out
into the field they do their research on
our cdcl tracking system before they go
out and compare the two so uh oftentimes
you're going to find that the criminal
actors or people who are trying to get
around the the rules are not utilizing
the seed to sell tracking system
appropriately that's just one way
another way that we are identifying the
uh Bad actors or the criminal actors in
the industry is on the front end on the
licensing end we've built up a an
investigative unit within our licensing
department that digs deeper into license
applications so we know a little more
what to look for now to see if they are
trying to if these criminal
organizations are trying to get into the
legitimate industry and we just are
doing our due diligence uh putting
astringent
read on every single commercial license
application the first couple of years of
the program that was not the case
okay very interesting so for a country
let's say like Ireland over here in
Europe who looks like legalization is
coming around the corner what would be
made the two things that you would
recommend politicians and lawmakers
ensure that that is a part and a core
part of any industry from your previous
experience
I would definitely recommend that you
have a
um Quality seed to sale tracking system
before you ever start allowing
cultivation processing and selling of
cannabis whether it's medicinal or adult
use and the reason there is not because
I'm thinking of it as an illegal product
termed legal I'm thinking of it as a
product that at the end of the day a
consumer or a patient is going to inhale
into their lungs or apply to their skin
or consume we want to know that that is
safe and once cannabis becomes regulated
in a country or a state that is exactly
the expectation when a patient or a
consumer goes into a dispensary I want
to be able to say with confidence to
them that they can trust the products
they're purchasing and the only way they
can do that is if we are tracking it
making sure that it is tested properly
and we are doing our due diligence to
ensure that it's not a product that has
been
sold I on the illicit market and got
into their hands so at the end of the
day CD cell tracking is incredibly
important but another thing that I would
say is just making sure you have the
um correct uh to lawmakers I would say
make sure you're talking with people in
the industry and talking with patients
so that you're not making laws without
their input because this is a very very
complex plant it is not
um cut and dry there is so much to know
about cannabis regulation and you've got
to find the experts whether they're
industry patients scientists Physicians
consult with all of them to make sure
that you're ahead of a lot of the
technology and The Innovation that's
happening with cannabis
we have a king over here in Ireland
Huffman at the moment called the
citizens assembly and they're generally
gathered when there's got to be a new
change in laws whether it's gay marriage
or abortion rights we've now got one for
drugs that seems to be going very
positively and they seem to have done a
number of things that you recommended
there we're still dealing with some of
the
let's say we'll call it misinformation
from specific either medical
professionals or outside medical
professionals has does that still
continue in Oklahoma as much as your
industry has been a success or is it
does it dumb down once the industry gets
going because it seems to come from
misinformed and uh completely out of
sync information
right no I that is something that I
think is going to take years and years
and it's just going to take a cultural
shift and that takes time you know but
even though we have such a large
industry a lot of the Oklahomans who
voted yes to legalize uh medical
marijuana did so because they thought
okay well this is medicinal it will help
someone I'm going to vote Yes what ended
up happening in our the more rural parts
of our state uh some of these Bad actors
and criminal organizations moved in and
created and built these gigantic
cannabis Farms they took all the water
we have water is a finite you know
precious resource and in Oklahoma it is
an emotional
um thing people are very protective of
their water so a lot of these cannabis
farmers were not being good neighbors
and that's put a really bad taste in a
lot of oklahoman's mouths especially in
rural Oklahoma and if you've been
following we had a petition on the
ballot for adult use recreational
cannabis use back in November no back in
March sorry and that failed it failed uh
by a pretty big margin and I believe
it's from what I'm saying to you that
the people who thought that medicinal
marijuana was just was to be helpful
have unfortunately
seen kind of the bad sides of the
industry in Oklahoma and
and don't want any more of it so we have
not we've gone a little bit backwards on
that culture War as far as the
misinformation is kind of the bottom
line there
yeah it's very interesting as you said
that it's such an easy entry point into
this Market that anybody can get in you
seem to see that across the world in
cannabis that anybody with a bit of
money can get into is you then realize
once the industry's up and running to
that okay we need real players in here
we need to set boundaries and licenses
and all the variables that are going to
ensure that if it was the cocoa Market
or whether it was the vanilla Market
that they're all regulated to the same
standard
absolutely yes
and next last episode I'm going to let
you go in a couple of minutes because I
know you're very busy lady
um patient care and education when it
comes to Oakland is this um widespread
across the state are there a specific
private entity companies to take care of
patient care and education is it a is it
a capital Mark where anybody can open a
private Clinic have my own doctors and
once we have the patients everything up
and running or are there certain
Frameworks that are in place to hinder
patient access
pretty free market just like everything
else and what we're fine in Oklahoma
that goes back to what you were just
talking about is that the physicians in
Oklahoma have been resistant to learning
more about cannabis and recommending
cannabis so a lot of times they might
recommend for a patient to get their
patient card but then they don't really
have the education or the knowledge to
recommend dosage or type of consumption
so what has happened is uh some groups
have popped up that are not Physicians
that are more a patient Educators so
they've been able to create their own
lane on educating patients and
I think that there's a lot of room to
grow and we're working as the regulatory
agency to try to put together some
materials for patients based on science
and medical knowledge and research
um
it's still limited here in the U.S I
know I'm sure you know that from
everyone you've spoken to but you know
people like Dr grinspoon Who are
Physicians who have done the research
and do know the efficacy of it are
helpful to all of us because we're able
to point and say look
there are Physicians that have done this
research in Oklahoma they're a little
bit uh resistant still so patient and
education patient Education and Care
is really something that needs
Improvement here in Oklahoma
yeah it seems to be not the same way I
think across every state and every
country that I've talked to that the
current doctors are of a specific age
and it doesn't necessarily make sense
that we hope that the new wave of
doctors Coventry or actually learn about
the ECS and all of the various dosage
and ratios and profiles and even terpene
benefits that they can start formulating
good individual size medicines as
opposed to there's a one-size-fits-all
model and when it comes to Oklahoma over
the next coming years what is your
biggest your top two things that you
want to see get enacted in Oklahoma
well for us we just want to do our job
and a part of what the past couple of
years have been since I came here was
just building the staff training the
staff to make sure that we're actually
out and uh checking in with businesses
doing compliance inspections uh paying
attention on the front end to these
licenses I want to see us working like a
well-oiled machine we're just not there
yet we're still a little clunky because
we're still you know a lot of our
departments in training mode learning it
takes time to learn all of our rules and
regulations so that's that's the goal
for a year from now for us to be running
like a well-oiled machine with
transparency towards the industry and
patients where they know exactly what
we're doing and we try to we try to make
sure they always know what we're doing
as the government body we are not ever
trying to hide the ball we want them to
know what to expect from us but that and
then
um
we are starting up our own quality
assurance lab and we're going to partner
with our Department of Agriculture to do
that and uh part of the reason we're
partnering with them is because of the
current uh insurgence of the hemp
derived cannabinoids that we're seeing
all across
um I'm sure the world but definitely
across the United States that are
largely unregulated
yeah hhc and Delta 8 are all over Europe
as well so yeah it seems to be they're
making up a huge chunk of the actual
sales what's the size of the market in
Oklahoma on an annual basis
oh that's a great question I don't have
that number off the top of my head and
we actually just
um we have some data on our NCS
dashboard that might be helpful with
that but I don't I don't have it off the
top of my head I'm sorry I have to talk
not at all I will check that out it's
been amazing talk to you I know you're a
very busy person and so on it's the
start of the day over there you've got
lots to get doing so I won't take take
up more of your time it's been a
fantastic talking Adrian hopefully when
Ireland starts getting some movement and
regulations we can touch base which
again and see what we can learn in
Europe from all the excellent work you
guys are doing in Oklahoma okay
thanks so much for having me it was
great to meet you
it's been an absolute pleasure and until
next episode everybody