foreign
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I am delighted to be
joined on this episode by Dr Lutz harms
who's the senior director at GW Pharma
in Germany how are you keeping this
morning nuts
I'm very well thank you very much Ian
how are you doing I'm very well thank
you very much it's a Friday we've had a
bit of snow here in Dublin so all is
good in my world
um
pardon when winter has started it surely
has yeah I think the Christmas feeling's
starting to come around now so thank you
very much for taking your time to do
this I know you're a very busy man and
uh hopefully we get to bestow some
information on the audience can you
maybe give everybody a quick little
brief overview of how you ended up at GW
Pharma as their first employee and your
position in the industry
yeah happy to do that
um yeah I'm a the pharmacist and
pharmacologist by by education and after
my PhD I started my business life in big
Pharma for more than 20 years and then
in 2017 I joined GW to
launch
um the first cannabis derived
anti-epileptic drug in rare childhood
epilepsies so that's what where I
joined GW then
very interesting so the topic of this
episode is what are orphan drug trials
can you maybe give everybody an overview
of what is an orphan drug trial and why
are they important in the industry
sure
um
yeah often drug trials
um that that's a clinical study
in a in a rare rare disease rare disease
is defined
less than five people affected out of
ten thousand so we're talking really few
patients here that are suffering from
really sometimes very serious
diseases with no effective treatment
here
so in this case you start the clinical
study
to to
uh prove the safety and efficacy
in this rare disease
in some cases
these are a few few weeks only the for
this for this study
um and then some sometimes in some cases
it's
um taking you even a couple of months in
order to start and then finish
to study
um
at the end of this trial then
usually you publish the results of the
study in a peer-reviewed journal so this
is this is all about a often drug trial
okay very interesting so this seems to
be one of the Avenues that for
cannabinoid derived pharmaceutical
products that orphan drug trials are
maybe one of the best avenues for for
biotechnology and technology companies
to be taken is that correct
uh absolutely I'm convinced that that's
the the way to go
um you have to to prove uh again safety
and efficacy that's important for
patients and their their families uh of
of anything that that would become a a
reimbursed drug in the end for for the
sake uh of of these these patients
yeah and I suppose the objective is to
make evidence-based medicines and the
the evidence needs to come from trials
absolutely correct I just can Echo what
you what you just said it's all about
the evidence-based based medicine and
for this you need the data in improving
statistically proven
um public published peer-reviewed
randomized trials so there's nothing
nothing else than that
okay next topic I wanted to jump on to
was launching up at the OLX and a lot of
patients and a lot of consumers out
there I don't think would have a
complete understanding or Nuance to
overview of how a product like epidelex
is created and when it comes to the
launch of epideotics what was the exact
process what's the kind of time frame
that you guys would have been working
under
yeah so uh this is basically once you
have started an orphan drug trial it has
been successful and published then you
go into the next phase to launch a drug
and this is then all about you bring
these studies
um to The Regulators in the US it's the
FDA in Europe it's the IMA and they you
compile all your data you have in in our
case with epidiolex
um it has been five successful studies
to launch this product into
uh rare childhood epilepsies
all five were successful and showed
exactly the same safety and efficacy so
so we put everything together and
brought it then to the in Europe to the
EMA and in again as I said in the in the
US to the FDA
um and this uh they take they take from
the moment you submit your data until
they give you their assessment
um it takes you one year
roughly depending on the outcome and
depending on the results you you can
offer
um and once and we did that in Europe to
to say that we did that in Europe
um in 2018 and then one year later we
received the approval in September
um to launch this truck in Europe so
that is really the the milestone for for
any drug
to be available for patients in Europe
yeah it seems to be very successful so
far and everybody understands or knows
about the Jazz Pharmaceuticals purchase
the GW when it came to the research and
development of epidemics was was that a
decade-long or indeed process because if
I'm not mistaken episiotics is derived
from a strain of hemp that has a high
potency of CBD is that correct yeah I
mean epidiolex is a purified
um cannabi dial
drug
so it's THC free
this is important to note because many
people might combine THC CBD cannabis or
mix everything together though so this
is really pure kind of cannabidial
um
grown in in the UK grown in the in the
UK
um purified in the UK and manufactured
in in the UK so uh that's true exactly
it's a has been the second drug out of
the GW research the first one
um has been sativax a mixture of 50 50
mixture of THC and CBD cannabi dial for
the treatment of specific symptoms in um
in Ms
and when it comes to excuse me the
future obviously the Blends and
formulations of getting the rare
carnabinoids and terpenes and having
perfect Blends and creating products at
it that is is the objective in the
future do you see the biosynthetic
companies playing a big part in that
role because obviously with plant matter
you can't isolate as a specific amount
of the cannabinoids that it's going to
have to be criticized or fermented in
some way in a bioreactor you you're
tipping on on a critical topic maybe for
for Paving the path in the future for
um cannabis industry
um I'm sure that there is much more to
to investigate and research and find
into the the various kinds of uh noise
and
indeed the quicker you are you to
isolate different molecules the quicker
you can dive a bit deeper into the
effect of these different molecules and
for the sake of of patients in many
other diseases to come
yes very true very true so last step I'm
going to jump onto Before I Let You Go I
know you're very busy manners ax Market
has access requirements I noticed on my
research that you guys in Germany have a
process called the amnog process can you
maybe give everybody an overview what is
that process and does every country have
their own version of that or is it
something unique to Germany
uh yeah you are you're uh you're closing
the German journey of of a drug
basically uh in in all countries after
after the studies and after the
um approval in Europe you need obviously
a price in in your Market the process is
looking different country by country and
in Germany we have the so-called amnoc
process uh which is which takes roughly
one year
and it's a it's a two-step process if
you like and it starts
um with a with a new dossier you have to
prepare based on your data and you
submit this dossier to the federal Joint
Committee
and they give you an early benefit
assessment a benefit assessment that
that brings your drug a little bit into
comparison and contacts with existing
drugs on the market
um not all not only in terms of data but
more so also in terms of price
so and based on this on this assessment
based on the dossier that you have
prepared
um you get you get one of
um a five scale
um benefit
and with this with this benefit
assessment you step into into the second
phase
in the second phase uh is a discussion
and a negotiation with the with the sick
funds in Germany
and uh depending on the on the scale you
get on the on the rating you get
um you have
um the chance to discuss and negotiate a
price that is finally reimbursed then in
the market and with this you have not
only an approved drug
um but also a reimbursed price to make
the the product available in the market
it is important to note in Germany that
still an exception in in Germany uh the
the day the day one after after the
approval you can you can bring this drug
to patients you can bring this drug on
on the market however the price is
negotiated afterwards and then you get
the full reimbursement
and that's the the third important step
uh to be mentioned and to be kept in
mind
very interesting and to your knowledge
does every country around the world have
their own process like the amnog process
that you have in Germany yes absolutely
absolutely
um UK has the famous uh nice nice
process
uh France has a different one and Italy
comes again different uh so these are
many different kinds of setting the
reimburse price in depending on the
country
very good but it's been great talking to
you one question before I let you go in
terms of the German recreational Market
from a scale of one to ten confidence
that the government are going to be able
to actually bring a recreational Market
to fruition
okay
um
I I go I go I go on five
giving me a bit space uh up and having a
bit space down I think devil is in the
detail here the willingness is there to
do that
um I think here really uh the the
question comes about the source of
delivery the quality
um and in the day in in the end uh how
strongly they want to keep an eye on on
quality batch to batch consistency and
we discussed it earlier on data
yeah yeah very true it's it seems to be
a lot of hurdles ahead and for uh for
the good at the European industry
hopefully Germany can be the leading way
but we saw a Czech Republic bring in a
set of rules there the other day so I
think uh how blue we've got a an
interesting industry ahead for the next
five to ten years
absolutely
it's been amazing talking to you lots
thank you very much hopefully we get to
chat again in the near future and we can
get an update from everything that
you're up to but for now thank you very
much guys for watching and we'll see on
the next episode
[Music]