[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I'm delighted to be
joined in this episode by Yuri Pernell
who's the CEO of NextGen Europe based in
Belgium how you keeping today Yuri fine
fine fine and yourself very well thank
you very much for taking your time to do
this I know you're a very busy man do
you maybe you want to give everybody a
quick little overview of your position
in the industry and how long you've been
in the sector um I'm in the sector since
2019 uh I have different positions in
Belgium I'm the CEO of next genen uh we
are market leader in the CBD of in the
Cannabis Light Industry um as everybody
knows Belgium was one of the first in
2019 to have a a legal framework to sell
CBD flowers as a tobacco substitute so
with my background as tobacco business
uh I jumped on this and U today they
we're market leader with a between 50
and 60% market share in the regular
Belgium market and next to that we have
our Brands pure CBD pet CBD um and our
retail Network Flora point that you can
see behind me um where we have uh five
shops and um we distribute pure CBD and
different um shops pharmacist and parap
pharmacist so that's my Belgium uh my
Belgium position and next to that I'm a
business partner with uh cure support
Laban and uh there we deliver a white
label and private label uh CBD products
um all over Europe we deliver in 70
countries uh all over
Europe and the rest of the world first
topic I'm going to jump on to is an
overview of Belgium can you maybe break
down for everybody what are the exact
regulations in Belgium is there a a
thriving market for the flour under 0.2%
is there a big Medical program what's
the political Outlook like in
Belgium H it's a typical Belgium
situation um today um I think it's all
very clear today the flowers below 0.2%
THC can be sold as a tobac substitute
that means uh from a bounded Warehouse
with a with a tax stamp on it like
cigarettes are sold so that's very clear
um so um next to that we have a CBD
markets where Cosmetics Cosmetics are
allowed like in any any other European
country um and CBD and oil uh is
forbidden due to the Nova food so but
there's
a an amount of CBD oil is sold uh but
not uh for intake uh you can sell it but
on the packaging uh you have to mention
that is not for uh intake so uh that's
the situation on CBD or canabo business
if you see the business of uh THC
flowers um there's a lot of noise for
the moment um on the Belgium Market uh
like in the rest of Europe uh Belgium is
watching what's happening in Germany
what's happening in Czech Republic
what's happening in Switzerland um if we
see the polit politic landscape today
and there has to be vote um it's in
favor of the legalization
um but some politician have to enter a
low proposition what's not the case for
the moment and will not be the case this
this for the moment because next year we
have um we have elections so everybody
is looking at the elections um what we
see in the paper that a lot of politic
parties uh or or other uh parties who
who are involved in this uh giving their
opinion that we have to go to
regularization to decriminalization
Etc um we are working on a blueprint uh
that we're going to launch uh next month
with the with the European cannabis
Summit in Belgium uh we're going to
launch also our blueprint how we see it
and a full uh closed system that has
fully control of the government um so we
believe that there's a there's a market
for regularization of the THC business
um and we have uh therefore we made a a
blueprint that we're going to propose uh
and launch in
October and when it comes to the medical
side of the market is there a thriving
medical cannabis industry or is it
limited by the amount of patients that
can access
it in Belgium uh you can buy uh
CBD as a maestral uh but it's it's not a
big Market uh next to it THC flowers we
don't have medical THC flowers
uh in my opinion there's not such a
thing as
uh Med medical and and recreational it's
all the same flower it's all the same
plant uh the only thing it's it's
cultivated differently and and more
strict if it's medical um but in Belgium
uh the pharmacist are not selling
flowers as it's not for it's not legal
to sell flowers um THC flowers above
0.3% THC uh even medical so it it isn't
existing in Belgium on the Belgium
market and when it comes to the
political overview is there one dominant
party in Belgium or as you said with the
elections next year is it going to be a
coalition of parties and if so how many
of those parties are pro cannabis
legalization
um as you know Belgium is is a very uh
there's almost three countries and one
country so we have two countries and one
country um the southern part the French
speaking part uh is run by the
Socialists uh they're in favor of
legalization last week also
the the minister uh uh did an
announcement that he he he wants to
legalize uh cannabis THC cannabis in in
Belgium uh on the flamish part um we
have the Socialists who are um Pro
legalization we have the liberals who
are pro uh and then we have nvea and
vlam block who
are right and extreme right parties who
are against it um so everything will
depend uh on the elections next year
um but it's up to the to the Commerce to
us to come with a plan that nobody uh
the market is there so we we we I think
we're obliged to to to to regulate it
legalization I don't I don't like to use
the word legalization because in my eyes
it's legal the market is there um I
think in Belgium we have about six ton
uh of illegal sales um by month uh if we
if we do a comparation with the with the
Dutch Market I think Belgium
six ton every month again we have six
ton of of illegal THC assault uh and 80%
of the of the sales is to non
problematic uh users so I don't see why
we cannot regulate this Market because
now it's illegal and it's uh but there's
a nobody do does something against it if
we if we can focus on the 80% of the
nonpr problematic users to bring them in
a framework where they can buy uh
controlled uh THC with labo tests Etc on
it uh I think everybody is a winner in
this
situation and do you see in Belgium that
everybody's kind of waiting for one of
the EUR European countries whether it be
Germany or the Czech Republic or
Switzerland as you mentioned is
everybody kind of just keeping a step
back and seeing what comes out first or
do you think they're actually very
driven to create their own policy and
framework I I think yes you have to look
and you have to be aware what's
happening in the other countries on the
other hand every country has its own
background and way of of handling uh the
situation and uh and and narcotics Etc
um I I strongly believe that Belgium
doesn't have to look at what they didn't
do with CBD the legalization with
flowers to put it as a tobacco
substitute that's the first country in
in Europe who did it in 2019 followed by
Luxembourg now Luxembourg is going from
0.2 or 0.3 THC to 1% THC like the Czech
Republic um Belgium is is is keeping 0.2
so I don't believe Belgium has to look
they have to look but they have to draw
their own uh legal framework on the
regularization of of of
THC moving on now to the nextg story
you'd mentioned that you come from a
tobacco background and you saw the
opportunity here you guys also
successfully had some investment in 2021
do you mind to maybe give everybody a
quick little run through of the story of
NextGen from the start to where you guys
are now as one of the dominant players
in
Europe um so next gen was founded in
June
2019 uh due to the legalization of uh of
of of the legal framework of
selling uh CBD flowers or cannabis light
flowers are below 0.2% as a tobacco
substitute I used to work for Imperial
tobacco and gaher uh in the tobacco
industry uh so I I know how to handle
bounded warehouses tax stems Etc um we
jumped on this business um we get
supplied by this DH um after three
months we took over also our importer
and our we did only the distribution so
three three to six months later we took
over DH who was the Importer um we
deliver at all um organized uh
structured clients uh as as night shops
uh press shop uh Etc we have about 2,000
2,500 shops that we deliver our flowers
to um next to that we launch pure CBD as
as a wellness brand where we sell to the
CBD stores and to the to the to the
pharmacies and Par pharmacies as a small
Market that's growing uh it's growing a
little little by little and people get
more and more aware of of of of of the
benefits of using CBD or cannabinoids in
in their healthy lifestyle um we open we
took over also over one point of sales
Flora point in the meantime we have five
of them uh because that gives us access
uh to the consumer uh to have data and
and and insights what we don't have in
this market um and also we want to
create we want to be uh in pole position
if legalization happening if uh we can
sell through uh
Point of Sales that we already have our
Network that's that's one of the main
reasons of of Flora point and to have a
fully integrated
uh fully integrated uh uh structure um
we we've been sold I I've sold my shares
to always pure Organics in 21 um always
pure organic was a Manchester based
company um white label private label due
to the brexit Etc they were looking for
a a European food ground they took us
over um but the deal didn't happen uh
and the story is that today APO is is is
in bankruptcy and I bought back the
company uh I took back the company in
May 2022 so we restructured it and uh
today the company is in on the one hand
uh in hands of of myself and uh on the
other hand in hands of Laban um cure
support we're the majority shareholders
of the
company you guys look to be very well
positioned for the coming years for a
lot of m&amp;a activity that may happen
across the brands and the distribution
and the retail sort of things are you
hopeful that we're going to see a
cannabis industry over the next five
years in
Europe yeah what we saw in 20 21 20 till
the end of 21 a lot of m&amp;a activities
happening a lot of crazy prices were
paid for uh CBD uh businesses uh I think
we're today in a normal situation uh
where m&amp;a activities are happening with
with companies with a positive eida with
a brands with with a with a vision with
a with a mission and and not anymore on
uh on dreams and uh so yeah I believe
that again there there there are three
two two axes in this business there's
one is the smoking smoking axe uh where
I believe tobacco companies can be very
interesting in U in jumping on on on
this on this business uh some of them
already jumped in or or are closely
looking at jumping into this business
and on the other hand we have the the
CBD business who has a 50 Shades of Gray
uh in the wellness sector
uh big big
Pharmacy big Pharma companies are
looking at it um some of them are are
want to take uh um yeah
um bre how do you say in English brevit
on it or
or um octro on it or Etc um we we will
see the the the business moving uh more
professional uh more structured and all
the the Cowboys like I call them uh that
we saw in the in the early stage of the
of the of this business are gone now and
only the the serious uh companies are
are are staying um I don't
see uh CBD cannabis as as a as as a
standalone company we are seeing it as a
a part of the wellness lifestyle uh
Brands uh fast moving consumer Brands um
and that's how we treat uh how how our
strategy is our strategy is based on
that we we we're launching we having
lifestyle Brands um with our company
yeah it seems we brands are going to be
the winner of this industry One Last
Thing Before I Let You Go when it comes
to the actual main supplier side of the
ingredient things there's been a lot of
talk about using fermentation
engineering to be able to produce these
molecules in large scale batches do you
see a scenario where Europe actually is
dominated by a couple of Biotech
companies that can do 5,000 lers a day
of a pure molecule and that's the main
ingredient do you always see a
cultivated um oil always going to be
available I I believe both both both uh
both ways uh what we see that we receive
from the Cosmetic and from the Pharma uh
because we deliver uh raw material also
and we see more and more demand of of of
synthetic uh because there you have
proven stability of the product what you
don't have if if if it's not coming out
of the label um if it's from Growers you
don't have the stability and in in
cosmetics and in food
uh it's difficult working with a
non-stable stabilized product yeah very
much so for I very much look forward to
heing you speak at the Cannabis Summit
in October in louen for anybody who
wants to know more about next in Europe
the website is below and the individual
website will be available wherever
you're listening or watching to this
episode Yuri for now thank you very much
for taking your time to do this it's
very much
appreciated thank you and uh looking
forward to see you in h Len next month
yes very much looking forward until next
episode
everybody bye
cheers
Happy Days Yuri it's just finished up
recording there yeah okay
[Music]
happy yeah mate thank you very much okay
you're happy with the content yeah I'll
send you over a link so you can watch it
yourself first to make sure you're happy
everybody's episode gets to be reviewed
by the guest first to make sure they're
happy with