foreign
this time to Philippines to talk to one
of the biggest experts in the
Philippines I'll tell you about cannabis
and his name is Gem Mark Mutia he's part
of the Philippines Society with
cannabinoid medicine how are you keeping
today Jim
I'm doing great thanks for having me
Owen delighted to have you and privilege
to be on this show well thank you very
much mate it's delighted to have you on
and help educate everybody and what's
happening in the Philippines in the
Cannabis industry and to be able to
bestow some information on to everybody
can you maybe give everybody a quick
little overview of how you came to be
part of the Philippine Society of
cannabinoid medicine
well uh it uh the Philippine cannabis
movement started uh was jump started
because of the uh weed documentary and
CNN by Sanjay Gupta that uh it uh was a
very famous here in the Philippines so
it basically catapulted the Philippine
cannabis movement and uh shortly after
that time
um my late sister was diagnosed with a
stoma cancer so uh that's when I started
uh looking into this uh medicinal
cannabis and uh that's when I started to
uh network with other like-minded
doctors and that's how the society began
um So currently we are lobbying for the
uh legalization of uh medicinal cannabis
interestingly here in the Philippines in
two since 2002 it's already legal to
import uh medicinal cannabis
pharmaceutical uh from abroad uh but
unfortunately only one out of six
applications have been granted so of
course uh importation uh from uh to a
third world country is a very expensive
idea and very unsustainable that's why
we are pushing for and advocating for uh
access a full utilization of cannabis
here in the Philippines
okay thank you very much so the first
topic I wanted to just do a quick
overview of the Philippines to go
through a couple of different items to
see how it's comparable to different
parts of the world so you guys have a
medical cannabis program you've been
able to import medical cannabis what is
the list of ailments that sits on your
medical cannabis program is it chronic
pain neuropathic pain or is it Trafford
syndrome and and seizures and it's it's
restricted to that
so uh the Philippines of course has uh
one of the most notorious uh drug laws
in the world
um they put uh they put the
uh
entry in there where you can uh import
uh any Dangerous Drug uh for medical use
as long as it is approved in the country
of origin it's called the compassionate
special permit but it turns out it's not
that compassionate at all because uh the
the
the requirements uh it's very difficult
uh to uh first of all you have to find a
neurologist and you and it is only for
uh those with intractable epilepsy so in
short uh only those with the drave
syndrome and Lennox gasto syndrome can
uh apply for a permit and the
requirements are very difficult for a
normal Filipino to attain so uh as for
the qualifying condition that's uh the
only condition intractable epilepsy and
only neurologists can prescribe it so
not so unlike uh other uh epilepsy
medications where uh any uh doctor can
prescribe uh for epidiolex only
neurologists can prescribe it so it's
very very strict even though it's
accessible on paper it it's still uh
virtually inaccessible
yeah it seems to be the pattern across a
number of territories in Ireland it's
very restrictive as well we've got a
pretty what seems to be an open cannabis
program but when you actually peel back
the layers that a doctor has to get
permission from a consultant there's
only a handful of diseases five
different diseases that fit on the
program so it seems to be that a lot of
the countries are taking baby steps
towards a fully fledged market so use
that only neurologists are allowed to
prescribe over in Philippines that's
basically the only rule that they have
no regular practitioner no regular
doctor can let's say advise a patient to
go to a neurologist they have to book
appointments straight with a neurologist
is it
uh yes uh here in the Philippines uh you
can go straight to a neurologist uh
unfortunately it is very difficult to
find a neurologist that is willing to or
has a faintest idea about medicinal
cannabis so that's another hurdle to
cross and if you find a neurologist uh
uh
the cost of importing epidiolex uh
the cost of epidiolex is a
uh already like uh almost one month
salary of a normal uh Filipino family so
they can only afford the medicine if
they don't eat for a month so uh that's
uh one of the that's the main reasons
why uh we are really pushing for locally
produced uh uh medicinal cannabis
yeah what we saw from Jaws pharmacals
really recently published at their own
course to turn over a billion Euro in
epidiolex sales and at 163 million in
the last quarter alone so it does I
don't think that they seem to be making
it a product or uh that can be
satisfying the world needs do you see a
locally sourced version of a product
like epiglax or dravenol being created
in your part of the world
uh yes uh there is a bill now uh it has
been it's already
the medicinal cannabis compassionate
bill I was first filed uh three
presidents ago in uh 2013. uh
unfortunately it doesn't get passed uh
but basically it's
um about uh establishing medical
cannabis compassionate centers uh which
controls everything from cultivation to
manufacturing and dispensing you know so
if the that's uh What uh is up in the
Congress right now so government
produced uh medicinal cannabis so uh we
are seeing a bit of uh light right now
because uh majority of the Senators and
majority of the congressmen
um have uh allegedly
supported it and uh our new president
uh uh allegedly also uh is very
supportive of it uh of course uh
everyone uh knows uh what's happening in
Thailand what's happening in Thailand uh
the bill here actually
the Philippines was the first to file a
medical cannabis bill but unfortunately
uh Thailand has overtaken us uh and in a
blink of an eye with a pandemic they
have gone from medicinal to now
recreational so uh I think
um the Philippine policy makers uh have
noticed that and also as well when we
talk with the other Southeast Asian
Advocates uh we know some of them uh
just like in Malaysia where death
penalty is uh
um uh applicable for cannabis they I
think they're about to do also a 180
degree turnaround so from uh death
penalty to Nato legalization so it's
very uh nice and uh of course uh it's
long overdue so uh yes we see a locally
produced uh not just CBD only but uh
hopefully all the uh medicinal
properties of the plant can be uh
locally produced uh in pharmaceutical
grade
yeah that was going to be my next
question where you guys are positioned
in the world you've got Australia below
you and Thailand above you to the left
do you think that they will have an
influence on the Philippines government
because Australia seems to have a pretty
successful program currently running at
the moment Thailand if they ended up
going and enacting what they say could
be one of the biggest tourist hot spots
when it comes to the industry do you
think that they will have an effect on
Philippines or is the Paul of somebody
like China in that area who have a
pretty strict uh no rule when it comes
to even CBD we'll have more influence
over those two other two territories
uh well yes uh the Philippines is a very
globalized country uh we're one of the
most hospitable to uh uh foreigners and
others that's why uh we we are uh aware
of the of the uh uh developments uh
abroad
um that's why uh we think uh we are
coming around unfortunate uh most of the
uh uh literate population I think is
open to the idea unfortunately uh the
Philippines is still a country uh where
majority is uh in the uh class D and E
social economic class so we we have a
lot of educating to do
um but uh uh well first of all uh the
previous president with the harshest
drugless Rodrigo duterte he uh publicly
uh claimed to use cannabis
um and uh the former president Gloria so
Gloria Arroyo also which is now Speaker
of the House admitted so I the Philip
the Filipino politicians and much of the
uh educated uh open-minded Filipinos
there are uh very willing but uh uh
unfortunately uh we have a lot of uh
educating to do as we the uh
other countrymen of course the
stigmatization of a cannabis the
demonization is still a very present
surprisingly The Mastermind of the uh if
you're aware with the modus of the uh
police before of the the previous uh the
previous chief of police now Senator
Robert uh I mean Ronald De la Rosa he's
The Mastermind of the drug operations
responsible of course for the thousands
of uh uh uh allegedly uh victims of
drugs he uh is now in support of uh
medicinal cannabis so it's very very uh
it's very very uh inspiring and we hope
also to do some modifications in the bin
because again the bill now is already
eight years old and we have seen uh it
was patterned uh eight years ago and
because of the developments uh around uh
the world we want to somewhat
um uh see some modifications on it uh
the lessons that other countries learn
we want to uh apply it into the current
bill
foreign
was the Cannabis and the central nervous
system do you see the real breakthrough
in medical cannabis coming from research
that targets specific parts of the
central nervous system utilizing
cannabinoids
well uh of course uh uh the CB1 receptor
is the most abundant g-coupled protein
receptor is more abundant than a
dopamine and opioid receptors so uh we
really think this will uh have an uh uh
it will really disrupt the uh how we
treat uh neurological problems and uh
uh hopefully uh with other uh diseases
as well
um of course uh if one will study really
cannabis we will know that uh it was
used as a Panacea or like uh for a
cure-all
um but uh it's not just uh with the
discovery of course of the
endocannabinoid system is uh uh proof
that uh it uh has a mechanism of action
in this uh in these uh diseases so uh
the neurological diseases will be a big
part of it but uh also other diseases as
well
yeah that's it it seems to be okay for a
while
ah yes yes or when thank you very much
chair Mark it's very much uh appreciated
and getting to talk to you and giving
everybody a quick overview the
Philippines hopefully we can get to
switch base over the next six to 12
months and have a party to this
conversation in both Ireland and the
Philippines have merged a little bit
forward in their medical cannabis
programs
yes uh thank you so much uh really the
15 minutes is uh it's a short time we
can't thank you and uh I really look
forward to our uh next uh session thank
you very much uh for all the listeners
and of course to you Owen thank you so
much very much appreciated for everybody
wants to keep up to date on the
Philippines so I did the medical
cannabis industry highly recommend you
go to LinkedIn and follow gem Market
here he's one of the top voices and
sources of information from that part of
the world so Jim thank you very much
again for joining us
all right more blessings to you Owen and
catch up with you soon and you too my
friend till next episode everybody