foreign
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I'm delighted to be
joined by this episode by Andrew bonello
who is the president of relief Malta and
he's worked since 2019 tirelessly to
represent the voice of cannabis
consumers in Malta and I'm delighted to
have you on the show today Andrew thanks
for joining us thanks for watching me
Ellen glad to be here great to have you
on so we're going to touch on all things
Malta and try and explain to the
patients and the consumers out there
what's going on in your exact territory
so do you want to maybe give everyone a
quick overview of how you ended up
becoming the president of really vulture
and we do that in under a minute
well yeah sure and basically um I've
been an activist for at least the past
10 years
um basically due to the the Draconian
approach we've had
um locally towards cannabis consumption
and possession and things were getting
out of hand the arrests were happening
on a daily basis and we saw some um
crazy prison sentences as well so it was
it was time to set up step up and
actually get out and do something about
it so we had a changing government in
2013 where they seemed to be um pretty
interested in listening which was um
great and and once they kind of opened
the door we barged in
okay amazing so it seems to be a story
that's replicating itself around the
world that everybody thinks they've got
their own isolated case whereas the laws
were very Draconian very severe people
have stepped up to the plate like
yourselves and there's a number of
activists in Ireland doing the same
thing to help kind of uh uh smooth out
the edges of the laws and if not get a
full adult use Market gone can you maybe
give everybody a quick overview of what
are the kind of cannabis consumers that
malted in terms of demographic and is it
70 male 30 female is it mostly under 35
year olds is it over 60 year olds what
does the consumer look like in Walton
well look I mean obviously it's hard to
be precise because when you have such a
um
a Draconian Zero Tolerance type setup
and there's no way to know exactly you
know what the good demographics are
because it's so underground but
um I will say this that your your
typical
um uh cannabis consumer and mortar is is
just a responsible person
um who usually has a job and a family
like everybody else
um it's just that they they choose to
use cannabis over maybe some other legal
types of substances
okay and is there any uh any uh figures
calculated so far what is the size of
the population that use cannabis in malt
over in Ireland it looks like it's in
around 10 percent of the population of
Ireland will consume cannabis as
recreational uh activity
yes well our our past parliamentary
secretary had come out and said that um
we were around the 40 000 Mark and
that's cannabis consumers don't forget
that we are a population of 450 000
maybe close pushing to 500 000 now so
yeah I'd say it's around 40 000 but
that's being very conservative
um now that things have moved forward
obviously we'll be able to collect more
data which is something we've been
pushing for to be able to obviously
Implement
um sort of better
policies to update our policies as well
um regard together with what the data we
managed to collect
okay and next topic I wanted to jump
onto was basically just an overview of
Malta and cannabis so
we saw that you had very Draconian laws
then we you had an election they had a
different viewpoint on medical cannabis
then that would they basically had laws
where companies could set up facilities
to be able to import product rebranded
repackage it and ship it out into the
the likes of Germany's medical cannabis
Market is that currently exactly where
the industry's out of Malta or is there
any talk about an adult use recreational
market and the potential for cannabis
tourism to take place in Malta
well
um medical cannabis entered the scene in
around 2018.
um and and unfortunately so the
companies that were attracted were were
sort of the bigger well-established
well-known companies that um came here
to set up
um to set like you said to import
basically Rebrand and Export and this
started to happen before actually local
patients were able to access a medical
cannabis so there was a bit of a
um an overlap over there so we had to be
quite um vocal about that
um so the medicines Authority then had
to start letting
um some some pharmaceutical companies
here Imports to be able to satisfy the
the local medical cannabis patient
Market
um so that that that sort of came in
after the the cannabis companies were
established locally but um at the moment
yes there are over I think between 50
and 20 companies here which like you
said Imports
um from from other countries and
repackage and and Outsource but we do
finally have some some cannabis on the
market which is from The Local Company
so the price is obviously and did drop a
little
um but and then with the new law which
came out at the end of last year which
was an amendment to our sort of
Narcotics act where it's entitled
um sort of cannabis to be grown at home
for plants are allowed to be grown at
home without fear of persecution
or arrest
um so once once that sort of came into
effect then the the medical cannabis
prices started to drop even further so
um they've gone down to sort of quite
affordable at the moment and we have a
system where your your local GP can
prescribe cannabis
um but of course you have to get a
control card first and that has to be
signed off by the superintendent of
Public Health
um but the onus does then fall on the
doctor so the doctor has to take full
responsibility for what he's prescribing
um and so so that's kind of the
situation we are at at the moment
regarding recreational Cannabis um yes
we had in in the last amendments which I
mentioned and which came out in December
2019 we
um we're going to be having well a an
authority for the responsibilities of
cannabis has been set up with the
chairperson and the board
this um Authority is still sort of being
still being finalized and and they're
still trying to put sort of their team
together hasn't been concluded yet so
that's taken about a year
um but when when all this happens
according to law basically we'll be
allowed to have associations which will
be allowed to have up to 500 members and
dispense to each member up to seven
grams of cannabis a day up to 50 grams
of cannabis a month
um unfortunately there won't be any um
on-site consumption so there won't
really be social clubs there will be so
they're called associations where you
will go in as a member be able to
acquire cannabis and and leave and so
the only the only legal Place one can
consume is in their own Hub in their own
house at the moment but of course we can
we can walk around in public with seven
grams on us
um the police can't do anything about
that or take it which was quite a big
win for us and also um the inclusion of
the expungement of criminal records
which came into effect as well which is
um something very positive but we still
have to see you know how many people
have applied uh how many people have
been actually given
um how many have had the the conduct
expunged
okay very interesting so the the home
grow rules seem to be in the Catalyst
snow for these well obviously not Social
Clubs because they can't consume on
there but let's say membership clubs
where uh a consumer can purchase their
own cannabis grown by a much larger
facility is that expected to be
announced very soon or is that a the
ability to do that available right now
um to the ability is not available
yeah which is what they want to do
everywhere and when it comes to the
control cards for medical cannabis as
you said the doctor is responsible for
whatever they prescribe and the amount
they prescribe but how hard is it to get
a control card is there a specific model
that uh everybody has to follow the
exact same rules or is there uh yeah yes
sort of Department of Health or what
what governmental body is it is it don't
run through a remote
it's the superintendent of Public Health
is is basically
um the person that would sign off your
control card at the end of the day but
you know you have to first of all see
your doctor and you have to prove to
your doctor as well that you have been
on at least two medications
um that that have not worked for you
basically uh for for your ailments so
once you can prove that to the doctor
um then the doctor will apply for you
um to get your your control card through
the superintendent of Public Health I
don't know how many have been rejected
unfortunately I do know that people that
have had the past
um substance abuse problem who have
entered the rehabilitation center
um any time in their lives will be
rejected
um also people that that drive vehicles
for a living will be rejected so there
are some rejections that um could take
place but I think on the whole
um when we look at the way medical
cannabis is dispensed throughout Europe
I think Malta is is is probably one of
the according to to the doctors anyways
one of the the best
um the best in in Europe
yeah you definitely seen to be one of
the model countries so far in the
European industry I wanted to touch now
about basically the letters you guys
sent to Ursula Von derlain about the CBD
fluores seizure so this is a big thing
in Ireland at the moment there's a
number of court cases going to happen
and it seems to be that uh one thing
that seems to be happening all around
Europe and more so you can understand
police and the guards they don't
understand what CBD flare and what's
regular Flair so for them it looks like
a duck and it smells like a dog cracks
like a dog but then it must be a dog so
and how did those letters go that you
sent in and was there any reply back
from her office
um now we we've got a reply and an
acknowledgment
um but the situation is this look um I
know you have the same situation in
Ireland
um but we actually had a law
um our law was amended in 2019 like I
said and in that law it says that
um cannabis is now going to be
considered anything with 0.2 percent THC
upwards anything below uh 0.2 percent is
not considered cannabis in the law so uh
unfortunately it's being interpreted by
the prosecution in in a different way
you know because they're saying that um
it's cannabis products a sort of CBD
sort of products are one thing but CBD
flower is another thing so our letter
basically to to Wonderland was trying to
get some sort of harmonization going
where uh we you know just 100 kilometers
away from where I am sitting right now
uh in Sicily for example you can you can
buy CBD flower from a vending machine
and you can probably cross borders with
it without any problem but in then in
another European country like ours then
you will get arrested
um your house will be searched your you
know they can they can block your
finances freezing your finances and and
lock you up for up to 48 hours and this
is actually still happening you know um
we're having places rated
shops are being raided individuals I'm
just buying CBD flour online up to three
or four grams are getting arrested and
raided as well so there's a lot of
ongoing court cases at the moment so it
seems to be a bit messy when it comes to
CBD flower so we really would like to
see some sort of harmonization and
something to be sorted out as quickly as
possible
yeah I think a lot of European entities
are hoping for the exact same thing last
thing I wanted to touch on was basically
the 7th of September meeting in Prague
that recently happened we also see that
there's a politician from Malta that's
part of a European Coalition of
different coalitions sorry of different
politicians looking to change the law
what can you tell us about the the
action that they're they're enacting at
the moment and is it going to be of much
use to the industry
well I mean at the what what happened
over there was obviously a very positive
move it was something we had suggested
as well before or just after the law had
come in that we need to get together
with other like-minded countries and try
and move forward together
um especially us being such a small sort
of nation
um so it was what they did release a
letter obviously they released a
statement after that meeting which which
was very positive as well but I do feel
that we need other countries to to to
join to make it stronger so we can
actually take it to the European Union
and discuss it so as a whole
um so so that way hopefully things can
move forward obviously let's not forget
the the international conventions as
well to deal with so it it is more
complex than one might sort of think you
know it's not just something that can be
done overnight
um there are a lot of countries that
have to agree if one country wants to
legalize uh you know the other countries
seem to have to agree as well so it is a
bit convoluted so so having these
countries getting together even if it
was just a few like you said in in
Luxembourg was was a major first step
yeah and hopefully there's many more
positive steps to come and we have a
European wide industry within the next
number of years where we can all travel
freely and Sample the best cultivars
that Europe will have to offer
let's hope and let's hope that Malta
will have its own cultivar too and
people will be coming here to taste
hours well that's I think that's
everybody's game is that they have their
own identity their own cultivars and
their own products that there's no need
for international msos from North
America to come over and set up here
when there's already the talent and the
new one stability already here
totally agree I think but if we're going
to build something it's got to be built
from the Grassroots
um you know it's the consumers that know
what they want
um they they might not want the sort of
McDonald's type of cannabis just to to
be the first thing to hit the market so
uh that's why we're kind of really
interested and like the the the setup of
kind of a social clubs where you can
really get to socialize you can get to
meet your peers
um and and obviously if anyone ever does
develop a problem you know you've got
help there then
um you can get educated there's so many
things you can do within a can of a
social club
um with the consumers so I look forward
to see this spreading around Europe
faster than any sort of big business
taking over yeah I couldn't agree with
you more it's been amazing talking to
Andrew thank you very much for your time
hopefully we get to touch base over the
next 12 months and we can get an update
on Malta and how everything is going for
you guys but for now thank you very much
for your time anytime Owen thank you
very much for having me until next
episode everybody
foreign