foreign
director at connect poor Pharma how are
you keeping today Hannah
oh and hi I'm doing great how about
yourself
I'm very well thank you very much for
taking your time to do this I know
you're a very busy person do you maybe
want to give everybody a little overview
of your position in the industry and
what connects Poor's objectives are
yeah sure sure so my name is Hannah I'm
in the medical cannabis industry for
five years already so basically five
years ago Ukrainian investor started the
company in Portugal with intention of
good weight in medical cannabis here and
basically I was the first person who
joined the team at first I was
responsible for planning of the project
and now I'm mainly focused on the
business development which includes
sales which include access to the new
markets existing one and all and also
the commercial activities of the company
yeah and can explore them basically we
are one of the license holder for
cannabis cultivation in Portugal there
20 companies I guess for that cultivates
medical cannabis and basically we are
one of those
okay excellent I'm going to start off as
the first topic with cultivation of
Portugal because you guys have a
facility there can you explain to
everybody the informed
um certification that cultivation
companies need in Portugal and what's
the overarching parameters that
accompany that cultivate support people
that's going to need to have in place
yeah sure so basically we are in 2023
and Portugal really kind of is
considered to be one of the best one of
the best place to cultivate medical
cannabis in Europe because the policy is
very transferred the increment is very
familiar with the with the process so
it's quite easy not not easy but it's
very kind of logical how to get the
license here in Portugal and as I said
there are already 20 companies in place
new players are coming uh and yeah so
the the idea is that the first step is
to get the pre- license which is kind of
you submit the documents to get
um
to give informat idea basically what are
you doing what is the what is the plan
of yours and then you start building the
facility and once you do this you go
through the gcp and GMP process and if
you do this you can cultivate and you
can process the product within Portugal
and you guys are an indoor facility
against outdoor
yeah yeah so the logic of Portugal is
that since the climate is very good
there are a lot of companies on the
south that is cultivating basically in
the greenhouse we chose a bit different
strategies so we cultivate indoor uh
because we kind of value consistency of
the product we value purity of the
product our product do not need
radiation because of this we always
focus on kind of making sure that our
product is very high quality
uh yeah that what makes us a bit
different from some other companies
and when it comes to the genetics and
picking the strain that you guys are
going to cultivate and grow D is your
head of cultivation uh expertise from
outside of Europe or from inside of
Europe
well we basically our
main head grower is from uh he was
working previously in Colombia so
basically we hired him from from there
so he had experience outside of Europe
but also according to gcp standards
incredible so once the product is
cultivated in Portugal we put a lot of
new markets that are popping up in the
EU do you maybe want to give us an
overview of what are your top tier three
new markets that you see in the EU over
the coming years and uh what are some
places that may be going over the radar
currently
sure So currently we are selling the
product to Germany we have a partnership
with sanity group we really like each
other I guess uh we I think we found our
Synergy uh when it comes to the new
markets to be very honest UK's Hot Topic
obviously uh and I personally very much
believe in the Polish market to be for
me it seems that the Polish market did a
very good stage of development uh
basically from 2020 to 2020
that from 2021 to 2022 the markets
tripled uh people are already get used
to the fact that it's possible to get in
Pharmacy prescription for medical
cannabis and also Poland has very long
history with the CBD market so basically
the Poland was the Pioneer in this
industry and because of this people I
really kind of get used to the fact that
cannabis can be consumed and have a lot
of natural and positive effects on the
body
so yeah that's that's Polish is the for
me is one of the hottest uh subject
right now subjects right now
and obviously Poland and such a long
manufacturing history and what are the
parallel houses of Europe when it comes
to this do you see the manufacturing of
Edibles let's say or pre-rolls as Poland
being one of these territories when this
does become a viable uh product market
for consumers
foreign
well to be very honest I'm very
skeptical about the whole uh possibility
of Distributing of Distributing Edibles
in Europe because once again in Europe
cannabis it's considered to be
pharmaceutical industry what what makes
Poland different is that for instance in
Poland there is possibility to sell
babes there are some pharmacies that
produce Vapes in in Poland and it's
actually quite a unique because I don't
see this possibility exist in Germany
for instance uh yeah but when it comes
to the recreational Market let's say
since no one no one none of the
countries is yet uh recreation in Europe
it's very difficult to predict what
would happen
do you see any country regulating
cannabis for abuse purposes within the
next three to five years or do you think
it's going to be a medically dominant
sector
well everybody had High Hopes when it
comes to Germany uh as we know it didn't
happen at least the way everybody
expected it to happen uh so we'll see
but in any way in any case Germany is
always a Pioneer in the industry in in
Europe so I think most likely the
Germany would be the first one
and what is the level of competition
Germany for supplying flour at the
moment is it pretty extensive or there
are a few companies that are well
established obviously you guys have your
distribution agreement with the sanity
group
uh I won't lie it is competitive
but if you produce good product if you
know what you are doing if you
understand the logic that
the buyers have when it comes to the
purchasing the product then you're good
I guess
when it comes to
if the cult of Life flower in Portugal
and it's been distributed into Germany
Are there specific fulfillment centers
that let's say the sanity group as your
partner would have where the product is
picked in there and it's stored before
distribution Nationwide and what are the
the levels of
um security and commands that are
required for these distribution centers
well there are
GMP partners because we for instance do
not have gmps so for us to sell the
product directly to Germany we need
first the product to be processed within
the GMP facility so this is one of the
partner of ours when it comes to the
distribution it depends on the what the
buyer have what the company in Germany
has so we also have our own distribution
entity uh but basically being able to
import the product into Germany is not
that difficult let's say there are
players who can help with that
I wanted to move on now to Ukraine's
Brooklyn Canada as the lady was born in
Ukraine and as a ukrainian-owned company
I've read a lot of headlines and seen a
lot of Articles over the last couple of
weeks where there was no real depth to
what we're talking about to maybe give
everybody an overview of what is
happening currently in Ukraine when it
comes to cannabis and how optimistic are
you that this is potentially going to be
a big New Market
I'm actually very optimistic to be very
one that's taken into account that I'm
Ukrainian I personally saw three waves
of trying to legalize cannabis in
Ukraine so first one started even with
the previous government and there is a
specific group of people who are pushing
the law for four years already and I'm
really happy that we finally succeeded
doing this so the idea is the following
basically the country understand High
need in cannabis right now because we
have a lot of patients and we have
military who are in pain constantly and
cannabis is considered to be a best kind
of treatment for this right and because
of this the lensky announced that place
legalize medical academies because we
need it and the department did it so the
law was adopted in the first hearing uh
the Next Step would be second hearing
and basically it might be a case that
the law will change a lot so the idea is
that currently the law is not perfect
because it allows cultivation within
Ukraine so I anticipate there are a lot
of cultivation facility would appear in
the the ones the lawyer is adapted
however the law prohibits import of
medical cannabis in the form of API and
in the form of a herbal medicine drug as
it being sold in Europe so only import
of Finnish pharmaceutical product is
allowed which is a problem because of
this last week the whole week I spent in
Ukraine I was invited as an expert to
explain how it works in Europe so my job
was to show example of Germany my I was
explaining how it works in Poland a
regulatory rise to allow actually input
of the product why it's important
because once again the whole idea of the
law is to allow cannabis consumption
we've seen Ukraine for those who are in
need and if we stick only to Ukrainian
products the product will appear on the
market only until like not until 2028
right because of this uh
my job was to explain how it works in
Europe how to how to draw a lot away it
allows quick access to medical cannabis
and to be very want to say have High
Hopes uh it's very early to say because
the second hearing of the law would
happen somewhere in September
before that there would be a lot of
discussion in the Parliamentary
committee but to be very honest it seems
that the position was heard it seems
that there is an intention of actually
bringing cannabis into Ukraine
and so previously until date there was
no medical cannabis program in any way
shape or form in Ukraine
no no not at all Ukraine has one of the
strictest law when it comes to cannabis
So currently if you want to cultivate
him cultivate hemp you have an ability
of cultivating hemp only until 0.08 THC
in seats meaning that Ukraine even have
their own variety when it comes to seeds
for hemp or only because those seeds
that are allowed in Europe are not
allowed in Ukraine and to be very honest
when it comes to the Cannabis it's very
strict regulation and because of this
this law is a huge advancement really
huge advancement the people who was
working very hard on legalizing it for
four years did an amazing job really
amazing job because they kind of uh
showed that it's possible we need to do
this once again because people patients
military needs it to give anyone else I
I personally since the war started I
I've obtained quite a lot of inquiries
from friends of mine who are in military
to somehow bring them cannabis uh
obviously it's illegal but then
there were requests mainly because
people understood that they need it by
themselves
and when it comes to German markets do
you see that being the key influencer on
the European wide sector do you think
when the German Market is fully fledged
and we've got all this nation and maybe
within the next 12 to 18 months we see
some sort of Returns on the tax amount
that's been taken in by the government
do you think that's going to be a big
influence for the likes of Ukraine
um it will have some impact but you need
to understand that for instance if you
compare Ukraine and Germany Ukraine is
like eight years behind right so uh
let's say I
working also towards the direction of
showing how it works in Germany so we
are kind of couple steps ahead so
basically we use already practice that
exists in Europe and then we apply it in
Ukraine but we are still far right so
until the moment there would be actually
Market there's still a couple of years
uh but yes obviously Germany is a
Pioneer in in medical cannabis in Europe
um
basically the way Germany sings the rest
of the country follows like Czech
Republic like Poland so for instance
Poland also recognize the German
Pharmaceutical
so yeah I guess Germany makes
a lot of impact on on the European
cannabis landscape
it looks as if Europe is heading in a
direction where we've got a clearly
defined Medical Market and then the
actor recreational or adult use Market
is going to be under the Cannabis Social
Clubs not-for-profit model and it looks
like that could be implemented across
Europe do you see that happening
yourself
well yeah and the reason for that is the
following right so the big difference
with Europe and for instance yes is that
Europe chose to regulate cannabis as a
pharmaceutical industry and it makes a
huge difference so there is no kind of
in-between process right so either it's
pharmaceutical or it's not right when
for instance in the years they kind of
chose the specific cannabis regulation
and because of this I guess uh Europe
moving with the past of Social Clubs
mainly because uh there are no other
paths possible because once again you
cannot put recreational into the
pharmaceutical industry right so yeah I
guess that would be that that's
something that would happen in the
future I believe that
so we see the example of Malta we see
Spain we see Germany following the
similar path so yeah I guess it is a
pattern
and for now we're just hitting our time
limits for anybody wants more
information on Connex poor the website
is below it's going to be in all the
descriptions Hannah thank you very much
for taking your time to do this and
hopefully within the next 12 months we
can have another chat and get an update
on Ukraine's potential has become
yeah I really hope I would be kind of
trying to update you on this uh I'm kind
of using my LinkedIn for this and yeah I
mean like I really have high hopes and
it seems to me that there is a high
chance that that actually happened
well we left our fingers crossed over
here in Ireland that Europe starts
progressing at a quicker Pace than we
will see progressed in the last year or
two but for now thank you very much for
taking your time to do this
thank you so much Ian thank you
until next steps everybody