foreign
review I am delighted to be joining this
episode by Giacomo buleri who's the
founder of the blairy law firm in Italy
how you keep it today giokomo
hi thank you all for invitation thank
you very much for coming on the show do
you maybe want to give everybody an
overview of how you came to found your
own law firm and your position in the
industry at the moment
yeah I'm I worked as advisor in um yeah
the European Industrial Hemp Association
and uh
Italian National Association has uh as
well as advisor for
um some companies who are interested to
develop their business here in Europe
okay very interesting and you maybe want
to jump onto the first topic and we've
had a number of guests from around
Europe and we've been able to piece
together a picture of various different
countries but can you maybe give us an
overview of what's happening in Italy
when it regards to the Cannabis industry
both medical and adult use
yeah uh I think that the situation in
Italy is a little bit complicated as
everything in this country and but
especially uh in the hemp sector we are
making progress in two directions
first the Ministry of Agriculture is
defining the sector plan for hamper with
the trade associations this is an
important step because it will be based
on the concept of the wall plant as an
Agricultural Product
it will allow Farmers to grow and
process the whole plant for legal
purpose and lower two for two or 2016
and this is very important because it
guarantees the agricultural part and is
in line with the concept of the wall
plant approach also promote by the the
United Nations
and second we are waiting for the
consequence of the tarlacio the Italian
Minister the Court ruling Vietnam the
part of the ministry decree of medicinal
plant that limit its use to seeds and
derivatives only this called Ola for the
development of the sector for the
farmers who who cultivate the ngaecp
according the European
procedure who will first be able to grow
them and transform them into until
essential oils and then Supply the
product to herpes and pharmacies who
will be able to make galenic
preparations I think that the minister
of health will not agree on this on this
scenario but All That Remains is to wait
for the ruling to become final next
September for adult use is a question of
political choice and political will and
now in Italy I think there is not a real
political will to proceed in the way of
the regulation of the adult use of
cannabis and the medical cannabis is a
question who don't present real problem
under the regulatory law aspect is a
real problem of Supply because here in
Italy the possibility the growing it's
our law just for the Army and now we are
waiting for uh a partnership between
Army and private companies but the way
is
fun to uh to because we need to
work
and on the training of the doctors uh
because if the doctors don't prescribe
cannabis the pharmacy don't sell and
there is not a real business so this is
a situation is uh moving forward for we
we're making
important steps for hemp not for animal
to use not really for medical cannabis
okay very very informative and is there
a territory or does Spain have a large
output of hemp grown every year is it
one of the biggest producers in Europe
or is it still a small industry
yeah I I I think so
um Italy is a country with a big
possibilities but we need to take an
example in my opinion from the North
American for example market for the
um less bureaucratic liberalist approach
to the Innovative sector we we are
fighting again in this situation here in
Italy but we are step by step moving
forward
especially to to avoid a situation of
overproduction in a sector as in another
country and we are work in progress too
and as other countries in the in in the
Hampton cannabis sector we are sold some
problems through the court and through
the state or in the court
okay and in over in Italy do they have
we see around Europe there's lots of uh
CBD stores that sell CBD flower and hhc
and and some of them were Delta are they
available in Italy or are they uh just
not around at all
okay good question
and uh because it's the other end of the
discussion now in the one hand we are
talking about the step forward but in
the other end there are still gray areas
for CBD flowers here in Italy so-called
cannabis light now uh where there is a
sector where there are different
interpretations from case to Case and
from iRead wire so in uh from a
municipality
um
um near closure uh
can be happiness that in in a town there
is a criminal trial and another cow
there is not a criminal trial I believe
that the outcome of the criminal trial
in Parma against Mr Luca marola the
founder of his joint will be decisive
for media attention and the political
weight of this trial of course I think
that this outcome
uh could be uh could help us uh the CDD
flowers regression because the CBD
flowers must be must find a clear
position as an election product as in
Belgium a Luxembourg or in the street
Center because I don't think that the
Italy can continue to sell this product
as a horizontal product or for just for
collecting because this is not a big
business is a business just for uh
for a little companies and not for
bigger companies not good for investment
there is not Clarity and certain are
certainly low
and do they have any rough estimates of
what the medical cannabis Market size is
how many people in the country are open
to possibly subscribe and then is there
is there Market data for the adult use
Market is it five percent of the
population or or do you have a rough
idea on that figure
yeah I you're right because uh because I
think that
we need to create this Market too in the
Cannabis dismissed this business we need
to start uh and began from the training
of the doctors and for pharmacies
because if these doctors prescribes very
few yet cannabis Pharmacy don't sell if
a pharmacy don't sell don't buy and the
pharmacy don't buy there is not a real a
real market so we need work on uh on
home training of doctors to training and
distribution because without training
there is not a real distribution in
Italy now in the in in one end but in
other hand we I I
see this is my personal opinion that we
can start to to import some API some
product because we have yes yet sunlit
regulatory
problems who limit the possibility to uh
create a vertical facility from the
plants until the final product
especially for the extra
gtmpx set for pharmaceutical use so care
could be
um an intermediate situation where some
API are import from other member states
in because we need the u a u GMP Sor are
working on it too
and do you find that there's any reports
and
um data sets in Europe that actually
realistically have projected the size of
both the CBD side and the hhc and the
medical Size Market and gotten a roof
valuation on a country by country basis
or do you think that it's all
the information is not exact
yeah I I think that uh as I also
explained and uh in in the working
groups European and National level where
I participate the solution must be
unified uh European level we need a
simple a single room sorry a single a
single approach and we must avoid a
two-speed Europe uh where some countries
can freely produce and sell a wall plant
of cannabis and CBD products and other
countries where the same products cannot
be produced and sell it because this
situation only creates damage to the
business and Distortion of the common
market organization and the market
competition because the countries as
military accounts as Italian Spain with
a restrictive regulations we find
themselves in their position of being
subject to the import of the same binary
products due to the due to the aspect of
the free Monument of goods uh with the
damage only for the to the National
producers for example if in Italy you
can't produce a tea with leaves but you
can import the same products from
Austria or from Croatia this is a
situation we need to resolve it to avoid
a true speed Europe this is our problem
in Europe but at the same time
at the European level the work is
spending and the main and the relevant
direction generalities
are working on their respective papers
on Cosmetics on feed on the food and we
are working on on the human use and the
human destination because the real the
real game is played in Europe not in the
single member states because we know
there are member states with a extensive
interpretation with temporary framework
uh
a vet already although uh producing sell
it for CBD products as uh France Poland
but there is a
complicated and particular situation
where it's not possible obtain a real
registration at as food sampling metal
but we're we're there is a similar
procedure of notifying procedure
that are allowed to say there's some
there's the CBD products in some
countries so we need to avoid this
situation where some countries can
freely produce other
where the same products cannot be
produced and safe
and One Last Thing Before I Let You Go
you mentioned the Core case that's
happening in Italy and Parma that's
basically going to determine the next
kind of stage of what the industry looks
like we've got one in Ireland as well as
I'm sure you're aware that some of the
companies have core K course there are
court cases against uh our government
and that case is going to determine how
the industry in Ireland is it a case of
all these different single layer
countries in the European Union will
they have their laws overruled by the
Euro Community European commission no
matter what they do or is there always
going to be this fragmented framework if
everybody doesn't get inside with the
exact same laws
uh they
um is a matter very very important that
the national courts are applying the
European law the Italy the third last
Italian administrative Court the French
State Council are stated that the
European law prevails on National rules
because the national rules that are
[Music]
that card against the European the
European law for example against the use
of the world plan are against the
produce a quantitative quantitative
restriction
that is it's forbidden and this
principle are stated uh is as already
stated from the European Capital Justice
in 2003 the first time against Sweden in
the Hammerstein case in recently in 2020
in the carnival place the statement of
the European court of justice are the
the point of reference of the national
court and for European commission too
and the that's working this paper the
European commission are working on a
line at the single destination of use
regulation with the interpretation uh
stated by the European Capital Justice
on the uh
this is this is the situation now Europe
very very good geokomo I know you're a
very busy man so our time is up now I'm
going to let you go and get home for
your house after a long day but I very
much appreciate you taking your time to
do this
thank you until next episode everybody
[Music]