[Music]
welcome everybody to the cannabis review
i am delighted to be joined on this
episode by dan yulowa who's the editor
of heady new jersey and he is here to
talk to us all things about new jersey
dan how are you keeping
i'm good i'm good how are you
i'm very well thank you very much all
it's going well over here you guys are
talking the town at the moment can you
maybe give everybody an overview of how
you got into the cannabis industry and
how you're the editor of uh eddie nj
yeah so i i got into this you know a few
reasons you know it was something big uh
that like our governor phil murphy said
when he was running through office uh he
supported uh you know seemed like a
great industry to get into on the ground
floor and something that was um very
political and i've been involved in
politics for a long time and you know
i've been a journalist covering politics
so covering cannabis politics in the
industry seemed like a great fit
it's okay
yeah yeah it's been some journey for you
so far
yeah
excellent so you already have experience
in the kind of overview of a political
system and how a process of regulation
would have already happened and you're
applying those skills to cannabis
industry in new jersey how long ago is
hedy nj set up uh
can you tell the audience
yes my business partner uh likes to be
called dknuck he set it up in 2017 when
it looked like governor murphy
uh was going to win the election and
that like he promised that the um the
cannabis would be done quickly
unfortunately it was not done quickly
the process was a little longer uh than
we liked but you know we're still moving
forward and it's going out really well
you know we had our uh adult use
regulations were announced and you know
that we're having the process for
companies to start applying for licenses
for that soon
okay amazing so that's kind of leads me
up to the first topic i want to talk
about it's just an overview of the new
jersey situation so everybody kind of
has a clearest perspective over here in
europe i'm sure everybody in america
knows but can you maybe give
how far away are you guys from selling
products in the stores are there a full
range of products already available i
saw something about there being a ban on
baked goods and candy edibles is that
being enforced or part of the regulation
yes yes that's that's one of the most
difficult things about like our
regulations is that while they were
really good towards like being conducive
to uh small businesses opening and
people who had been really harmed by the
war on drugs you know uh securing a
cannabis license one thing is they're
not going to allow baked goods they're
not going to allow a lot of the
chocolates a lot of the gummies that
people really like in the underground
market quite unfortunately but you know
their internal
regulations they might be changed within
a year so we'll see about that but we do
have our medical cannabis dispensaries
uh that sell like they do have flour at
least so i mean a few concentrates and
lozenges uh so though that uh we're
looking at sometime next year in the
first half of the year either winter or
spring we're looking for the official
start of the adobe sales to begin
okay amazing and is it is it a
free-for-all for brands who are selling
flower now in new jersey is it the
people who get in get the best locations
the best retail stores set up or uh what
how exactly would the flower be
dispensed has it gone through a medical
facility or is it going through a
dispensary
yes we have like our medical
dispensaries uh most many of them are
going to be allowed to uh sell don't use
cannabis so they'll be the ones uh
dispensing the cannabis and then you
know we're going to have a license
application
process for more dispensaries
exclusively adult use so that's like uh
that process those dispensaries might
take a year or two
to open at least while like our medical
dispensaries can start sailing next year
okay so it seems to be there slowly
slowly methods so uh yeah burn
themselves too badly just in case
anything did go wrong whereas nothing's
obviously gonna go wrong we know this
can you maybe as a political writer and
somebody who has an overview from a
political background explain cannabis
control board in new jersey and around
america what is the criteria made up of
for these boards to be created is it uh
civil servants who've been working in
government a long time mixed with
business folk or what exactly is the
criteria for in new jersey's cannabis
control board
so that's a really good question so we
have ours is the cannabis regulatory
commission in new york it's the cannabis
control boards but they're very similar
uh i would say so in new jersey it's
really people who have been involved in
the policy and the politics of this
and uh they're all they're all political
and appointees for example so it's
really
um
a partisan process in that respect but
then like a lot of the people who have
done who
who were appointed to our board we have
five people in new jersey you know they
have like a lot of great experience in
the policy of this but people have like
criticized it saying that you know
there's nobody in the industry on the on
the board but then there's nobody with
who could be influenced that way too
okay so it's a it's a
there's a double-edged sword there that
having industry people generally does
help make the the legislation and the
overview of the industry that little bit
clearer for the people writing the rules
but at the same time they don't have a
vested interest when there's nobody in
there who doesn't have a toe in the
industry per se
yeah yes that's really the catch so so
far like our crc has done a good job
it's just as you were saying you know
slowly but surely we're getting there so
one just has to understand that place
right now
and do you guys have a limited amount of
licenses or is it a
an open market system that there is
there is no cap on the amount of
applications that can come in there's
just a certain
crate or a
level that businesses will have to be
set up by i'm sure you just don't get
handed a license you have to prove the
premises exists capital in the bank
accounts board of directors have to be
vetted and all that pertinent
information
yes that's a really good question
because we've been having like a problem
with like our medical
uh cannabis cannabis whereby we only
have 23 licensed uh dispensary locations
but we only have 12 license holders for
medical cannabis and that process has
been very elaborate with need for like
great amounts of capital so we're really
looking for towards like adult use where
there's only one official uh cap 37
large-scale uh cultivators
uh
will be the max um but that even that is
like a two-year thing that ends february
2023 so otherwise there are no caps and
there's no caps on micro uh cultivation
either so that's that's one of the
things that's really heartening uh that
makes me like excited about our adult
use market yeah
yeah i think the utilities market is
where everybody has the real excitement
in can you maybe give us um
how long does the process for a license
take currently at the moment or do you
see a lot of the brands waiting for the
recreational licenses to come up or are
they already available for business to
apply for
no no so the the interim regulations
were released in august uh the um nobody
the
request for applications rfa process has
not yet begun uh but it is like a really
good question like what the process is
going to look like because like our
medical cannabis license process has
been very difficult that it was very
expensive that so few companies have
been licensed so this is really trying
to change the whole process
and create a new process it's a lot
easier but it's one of those things
we're still seeing like how it's going
to play out
and in terms of taxation has that been
set as they're being
kicked back from the industry so far
have they said a ridiculous taxation
level to uh products into the industry
or has they been reasonable and sensible
yeah you know we're actually reasonable
in that fashion i think a lot of people
were looking at california or that they
have with some say like no like an
oppressive tax that makes it that their
grain market in california is insanely
thriving because the tax is so terrible
so we have a competitive tax we're
actually better than new york in that
way so i'm excited for that actually so
we'll see what happens
okay and do you see the kind of brings
me on to the last topic now the players
in new jersey do you see the players in
new jersey being the cookies the players
that are already kind of already
established in the the certain other
states that have legalization or do you
see uh entrepreneurs in new jersey in
new york that could take the eastern
seaboard by storm
yeah i think we really here in new
jersey want like our locals to receive
the licenses we really want to create
local uh companies you know there's a
lot of them here that have a lot of
entrepreneurials uh entrepreneurs here a
lot of people with a lot of like zesty
like create a company get that going and
you know we have in our um regulations
that micro licenses are favored those in
like neighborhoods that were really
impacted by the war on drugs are going
to uh be favored and getting a license
and we're looking to really see like
companies like that you know we already
have you know of our 12 license holders
10 of them already multi-state operators
mso so like i guess like a few the few
remaining ones might be able to get one
in but the ideal is really you know to
favor small businesses you know the
small manufacturers that make like the
giordelli's chocolate for example of
cannabis something like the high end or
the niche product like that where's the
pbr the pbr of cannabis too you know
something like niche kind of like quirky
that way you know we're looking for
products like that and that's what
people are really excited about
so it's gonna be really interesting yeah
i think there's definitely gonna be a
territorial aspect about this where
everybody's going to want to have their
own brand or their own unique product
that's reflective of their demographic
and their to exact territory that you
might love coca-cola but you'd always
buy a local farmer's cola if you bought
it at the market type thing
yeah yeah so that'll be like really
interesting to see
and then like there's restrictions
around brands because then like if
you're going to be selling cannabis you
can't really have a mascot so companies
can actually like really be creative i
think in the way they brand themselves
and differentiate themselves because
arguably like i haven't really seen a
lot of differentiation a lot of like
interesting brands in our market so far
and i think that's one of the things
about cannabis in general is that like a
lot of these brands are not that
memorable
i'd say like cookies is up there but
like who else
but this is the thing we think that uh
there's certain territories i think
ireland is definitely going to be one of
them once legalization fully comes here
and we've got to grow at home laws and
we've got some of the best farmers in
the world over here i don't know for a
minute that there'll be a number of
strains
genetics created out of this country and
a number of baked goods and uh edible
products because if we're renowned for
two things it's farmer and good food so
i can see uh europe definitely coming to
the to the global market when it all
gets legalized over here
oh yeah that would be really interesting
yeah like i always hear about ireland
you know they say like the guinness is
different because the waters would be
interesting to see what like what unique
irish products come out yeah well that's
it look what we did with alcohol you
never mind what we're going to do
canada's next
now
for everybody who hasn't checked out the
website it's
headynj.com the link is just down there
below some great articles highly
recommended especially if you're in the
states it should be a must read for
everybody if you're in europe highly
recommend checking it out to keep you up
to date with what's going on in new
jersey what are you excited about over
the next coming months let's say the
next 12 to 18 months what are the big
things that you're looking forward to is
it having a a pre-rolled brought freshly
out of the store or is it a buying some
premium flour that you haven't had a
selection from yet what's the number one
thing you're looking forward to
yeah so like the like the opening of our
adult use market should be interesting
and uh it'll be interesting to see like
what products are available because
that's been initially our medical
cannabis
has also
been
has not been like really like high
quality it's also been like a little
expensive
so we're hoping that like eventually
that goes away and seeing like
affordable cannabis
seeing like different uh unix trains and
unique uh flower will be like really
interesting and seeing like a lot of
these like new companies like getting up
and running getting licenses
will be like really interesting so i'm
excited for that you know people say you
know we new jersey could have the second
biggest market in the united states
after california because we because
unlike california it's really easy to go
from like city to city like on the east
coast here for example baltimore
maryland washington dc philadelphia
pittsburgh they're all pretty close
three-hour drive for the weekend and
their states really aren't moving
cannabis so as the first mover you know
we could really have you know the uh the
advantage there
so there's got to be a tourism corridor
for smoking the best place on the east
coast within the next few years is there
yeah yeah that's what we're having here
that sounds like a great plan to me man
i'd be booking my ticket straight away
if i knew about that so we're nearly up
at the time here i can't thank you
enough down for coming on the show it's
been great to chat yeah i hope we catch
up again in the new year when the adult
recreational market has fully opened its
legs and up and running and we can give
us an update on how everything's going
down
absolutely yeah yeah it was great
talking to you then you too thanks
everybody for watching we'll see you in
the next episode