[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined on this episode by benjamin
alexandre jean-hua who is the ceo of
augur associates over in paris and
france and set up the topic of today is
going to be an overview of the french
cannabis industry benjamin how are you
keeping today
i'm doing very fine thank you very much
it's a great coming back to work after a
little bit of a break uh during uh
during christmas so it's great to be
back
yeah there's always you're either
jumping at the bit to get back from work
after that break or it takes you another
week or two to get yourself into gear
here you're one of those two people so
let's jump straight into things can you
ever give everybody maybe a quick little
overview of how you got into the
cannabis industry and uh augur
associates and the the services you guys
provide
yeah so i've been working for the past
10 years in drug policy i started
working at the u.n especially for unodc
the office for drugs and crime in
central america and south east asia and
i came back to france about seven years
ago to work more on the civil society
side of drug policy among the influence
and lobbying aspect of it
and um
[Music]
one thing leading to another uh with my
current partner aurelia
we
co-created the professional hemp union
about three years ago uh which gathered
for the first time professionals from
the cbd and medical cannabis sector in
france so very burgeoning markets both
of them um so it was the first
professional representation in order to
have a united front to talk with um
legislators and and and elected
officials and the administration
managed the
union for about a year we produced
several groundbreaking white papers that
helped shape
both markets regulations uh in the year
afters and uh about three years ago we
started to create ogre associates uh in
the um
uh
the we needed to find a new way to
accompany the development of juicy class
systems and so the idea was really to
create a highly specialized group
that was a
open to to support companies from france
and from abroad that wanted to do a
business in
cbd in medical cannabis market we do
also a lot of industrial hemp projects
um so now we
work in france a lot but because of
koveed we started working a lot in other
countries and so now we have uh we're
heading projects a little bit of
everywhere uh in the world
so it's been a fantastic ride since then
amazing yeah you guys seem to be at the
central focal point of the french
industry i kind of wanted to bring you
on to give everybody a little clarity on
the french cannabis industry so we had
in november 2020 the court of justice of
the european union confirmed cbd wasn't
narcotic then we had in november 2021
which is last year a legal firm called
latham and watkins with a lawyer evelyn
von k muellen won a court case that
basically solidified that you could have
0.03
in your cbd and you could use the whole
plant to process oils and to use for
tinctures but then separately cbd flower
has been banned for sale have i
summarized that correctly for where we
are at the moment so mostly and and they
really sometimes in the detail in the in
the details um the 03
is not directly coming from the kind of
a case but more in the ongoing
discussions at the reform for the
agricultural common policy from the eu
that's
we raised the bar at 0 3
which it was prior to the end of the 90s
where upon you know lobbying efforts
from the agricultural french actually we
lowered down at zero two percent
um
interesting to know that it's not
so much of a norm but rather a
limitation upon which farmers can
receive subsidiaries from that
agricultural common policy so it's a
little bit of of this and on on the
other side um
flowers is
open to sell but only on b2b so the
issues is direct to consumer cell
okay so how would they see
how would that make sense that if b2b
also it's just the processing of flour
they're allowed to sell flour to each
other okay i get you and we i can only
you can understand that to a degree with
the similarities with thc and cbd flair
being almost identical and the police
not being kind of informed enough to be
able to know the difference between the
two flowers so do you see this
behind that behind that we we do know
it's a fallacy because it's not causing
a problem in many other countries where
they do have different markets and
capacities for police forces to make the
difference through very useful and easy
uh
you know easy use uh types of of of
monitors and testing and testing kits so
um the issue is a much more political
ploy than than that you have to
understand that the context right now
france is the one of the presidential
campaign um and so uh everything is kind
of tainted by it by this and macron for
the past two years has uh went into a
direction uh with his government in uh
making clear that they didn't want to uh
legalize
flowers from the hand markets because
they would give too much for them the
impression that they're regulating
legalizing cannabis
that's the real reason
do you see what you've seen over in
ireland here now a number of the stores
that are selling cbd flower have been
targeted directly and there's a couple
of other people around europe that we've
talked to it seems to be that the
industry for selling cbd flower will
only be able to flourish when a
recreational market is actually in place
do you see that being the case
no because i think it's already
flourishing and it's uh you know
whatever governments want to try to do
uh and let's take the example of france
uh for the past three years there's been
you know up and downs of of of
repression against retailers uh mainly
of cbd flowers uh with you know back and
forth in that in that regard so it's
never been uh what we call in france a
long fluff tranquil a long tranquil
river um the the the idea right now is
that it's directly
forbidden by the french government but
we a lot of people consider that it's uh
it's a contradiction to the european you
know flow goods uh of of commerce goods
you know and so we we we we're gonna
we're gonna see a lot of movements in
the legal aspect of it so i don't think
there was there's a need
right now or even if it's you know
germany aside you know uh there isn't a
lot of european countries that are
moving into that direction of complete
cannabis legalization
but we do see you know a use and
ecommerce of ham flowers a little bit of
everywhere so i i do think that
depending of the country regulation the
market is more or less open but it's
going to be existing because in france
even if
very hypothetically they stop selling
flowers in every retail stores on the on
the territory they're still
online marketplaces you know and suffice
to change your website to put it on
another server in another country
and you're good to go um so there's a
lot of you know contradictions and
issues with the new recommendation and
my take is that it's not going to hold
but it might take you know a couple of
years still to get a proper regulation
back in france
okay so you see the european ruling
within time being the de facto ruling
across all the european nations and the
governments will just have to abide by
because we can see a number of different
court cases froms flower centers
happening all across europe so the
argument isn't going to be able to
withstand do you think over a long
period of time
well i i you know i come from drug
policies and drug policies when you look
at the science look at the data you know
that prohibition you know whatever the
substance usually don't work and creates
you know unfundable
negative consequences that are much more
harmful than the than the products in
itself and so there is a sense of
denying reality you know these products
exist the use of those products exist
and if we take the flat the the flower
heaven you know flat have flowers it
even has you know very very strong you
know uh helpful capacities in order to
substitute more harmful products to uh
this one
so we can consider that you know
the wave is going to move forward at
which speed and what is going to be the
tempo is going to change depending of
its countries but i do think indeed that
there is no way around it you know
if the market is not properly legally
regulated it's going to be taken by the
black market and black market don't care
about quality products don't care about
you know which age they're selling their
products to
and obviously there's no taxes and and
and all that so it's it's a it's a
question about just recognizing reality
and how can we reduce the harm of
potential harmful products to the
maximum and and not denying that you
know those products and their users
exist
yeah couldn't agree with you more on
that i want to jump on to the second
topic that i want to talk to you about
which is the cutting edge of cannabis so
from the people that i've talked to so
far you can kind of start to paint a
picture that malta are becoming one of
the leaders they've got a enterprise
board that have a million euro tech fund
for the cannabis industry denmark have
their ornamental flower industry which
gets backed by the government germany
are no doubt our renowned entrepreneurs
and with the recent news we'll have a
number of different cutting edge
technologies who do you see is the kind
of the foremost experts in europe when
it comes to this uh cutting edge
technology in cannabis and is there a
specific company or two that you think
everybody should keep an eye on
i think it's a really good question i
think the the sad truth i think is
europe is lagging behind a lot in
comparison to you know what's going on
in the u.s and canada and especially in
israel in terms of you know r d and and
can attack development uh i think we're
lagging behind a lot so it's very hard
to find you know and i think it's a
great news because it means that the
leader spot in that domain is yet to be
taken so it's up to the government that
will put in place the sufficient and
proper regulation in order to foster uh
proper you know r d and entrepreneurship
into those
those markets i think dalma denmark is
doing great things on the medical side i
think germany is going to be you know
the central actor and the norm maker for
uh many of the you know the the markets
medical and social use
i think in in both of things they're
gonna be uh become the leader um
i think the uk as a vibrant uh ecosystem
uh that is you know
you know more or less uh being helped by
their own national regulations
um i think it's an interesting you know
uh market to explore i think there's
great research that is being done in
spain right now i think it's one of the
the country to look at it for you know
clinical and and observational studies
of interest um and hopefully uh you know
we'll have things in france you know we
have great people working on genetics uh
manipulation and i think it's uh one of
the the greatest you know um uh frontier
that we're gonna have in order to have
personalized
medicine in cannabis which is i think
the way to go forward
um so yeah i think it's an exciting time
and i think the the competition is only
it's only starting
yeah i couldn't agree with you more i
think israel are the tip of the spirit
at the moment when it comes to the
warranty in this sector and uh europe
has a lot to learn but as i said i think
when europe does get going i think we're
going to put on a turbo skates and we'll
uh catch up fairly quickly if not exceed
some of the territories already
mentioned i hope ireland becomes one of
the dominant players like we are in
europe where we're at the steppenstown
between north america and europe for a
lot of services and uh various other
segments of the industry but i think
it's an exciting 2022 we've got ahead
for the year
yeah i agree i think you know working in
cannabis is never tranquil it's always
new things happening and so it helps
build resilience which i think is the
number one quality that you need to have
to work into that that mo this markets
uh but it's back it's it's it's
incredible because we're we're
making as we're building as we're making
it you know yeah it's it's always
creating new things each client that we
work with it's kind of a new
challenge
and a different service that we haven't
reproduced or done before
and
hopefully we can help build uh the
ecosystem in order to have weight
because today you know um
we're not you know taken seriously by
some governments because it's still a
fairly small industries um so we we see
the the growth behind it so we're in in
you know we're quite certain that the
balance will shift and we're trying to
move that shift as soon as possible
amazing well we just come up to our 15
minutes i've been looking forward to
talking to you a while benjamin and it
didn't disappoint it was a clear and
precise informed conversation so thank
you very much for taking your time out
of the day for anybody who wants to know
more about our gore associates you can
see the website there i highly recommend
checking them out and if you're a big
european uh business you should be given
get in contact with them so benjamin you
have a great rest of your day and
hopefully we can talk in a couple of
months and see where france is at
thank you so much it was a pleasure
exchanging with you and i look forward
in watching the new shows thank you so
much
everybody bye
[Music]