foreign
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I'm delighted to be
joining this episode by Lucas hurt who's
the publisher and editor-in-chief of
magazine canopy and the publisher of
cannabis therapy magazine how you keep
it today Lucas
I'm very good Owen and thank you for
having me on your show I'm delighted to
have you on so the Shepard public are
making a lot of waves in Europe I taught
who better to get on than a man who's
going to have inside information on all
the various topics
yeah yeah that's true
so can you maybe give everybody a quick
overview about your uh your Publications
that you have canopy and your order
magazine and then we can jump into the
Czech Republic topic
okay so very briefly I'm publishing
canopy magazine which is which is a by
monthly magazine in the Czech Republic
It's we print around 10 000 copies every
two months and it's being sold all
around the Czech Republic and also in
Slovakia and apart from that we started
a couple of years ago also a English
online version called cannabis therapy
magazine and we tried to publish the
Articles which are interesting for
international audience in English there
as well and currently we are also
working on some kind of
automatic translations into into other
other languages so that we can you know
have more broader audience even from
some non-english speaking countries such
as like Spanish or French or German and
stuff like that
and basically the magazine is focused on
medical aspect of of cannabis but also
we we take up the topic of the
recreational legalization because it's
being discussed here in the Czech
Republic more and more and I'm sure that
that's the most the thing which
interests you most
yeah well it's you start hearing the
dimension of the chapter public a lot
over the past let's say six to 12 months
it was all Germany up until the last six
to 12 months and it seems to be you guys
are coming up on the inside line very
fast can you answer me this a what is
the cause of the the positive
discussions that are happening in the
Czech Republic around legalization of
cannabis now what was the first kind of
the influence point where everybody
started to change their tone
uh it was basically the last
parliamentary election when we got the
new government and this new government
is is like European Pro Western and kind
of uh like it's like conservative party
which is which is on the top but this
conservative party uh or actually the
Prime Minister who is from the
conservative party his name is petrified
and he has a very good friend
former National coordinator engine and
this engine composure is pretty world
renowned drug expert on drug addiction
and Drug policies and he was our
national recorder for eight years but
the previous government they just threw
him out because they they weren't
interested in arm reduction policies and
stuff like that they just wanted to
continue the prohibition but the new
prime minister last year when the when
the election was over and the new
government was formed the new prime
minister petrified he just took him back
and since he's back he just he's working
very hard on this uh we call it like a
ham reduction policies which we want to
focus on basic human rights and where
where what better place to start is than
the Cannabis because you know with
cannabis in the Czech Republic we have
uh digital public has a very good
relationship with it like uh for past 20
years the general attitude was very
positive most people have nothing
against cannabis it's like we are very
open-minded Society very liberal but the
laws and the prosecution from police and
from the just justice system was always
there like in other European countries
so we have many people who are in jail
only for growing and using cannabis for
their own purposes without even selling
selling it and there are some very like
exemplary cases of people who didn't do
anything didn't harm anybody else and
they end up like young people and they
end up in jail for five or more years so
we want to change that and under this
leadership of Enzo Bogel who has the
blessing from the prime minister to do
this we are just working on the
regulation bill which would
uh we choose to stand on three pillars
one pillar is allowing home growing for
your own purposes which should be
allowed to anybody who's over 18 years
old and then the second pillar is
existence of cannabis Social Clubs and
the third pillar is a regulated market
so obviously uh in terms of
international laws and single
conventions and the EU law the biggest
obstacle will be with the regulated
market and this is taking up the most of
our time I mean our time the people who
work on this because I'm a member of
several subgroups who are working on
this under umbrella of National Drug
coordinator and the government offices
so we have like five subgroups and these
subgroups are trying to prepare the uh
the draft of the law and then the expert
Group which is on the top of these five
subgroups will be presenting the draft
of the law to the politicians to the
Parliament and the legislative process
will begin so basically yeah that's what
that's what happened and the main the
main Drive behind this it's definitely
the personality of engine who put his uh
like credibility his
is a knowledge and everything behind it
they put it into this effort and he's
leading the effort and he gathered many
experts from the drug policy field also
with we are in toxic to the police and
with the with lawyers and also we
escalated people from various Ministries
like Ministry of Health foreign Ministry
interim Ministry so it's a it's a hard
effort and it takes a lot of time and
lots of work but hopefully we'll be able
to to prepare something which will be uh
which will be okay for the politicians
for the for the politicians in
Parliament the MPS and then in the
Senate and if this if this law passes we
should be able to legalize somehow in
like next year so hopefully 2024 should
be the year
very interesting can you tell me the
subgroups and the expert groups that you
talked about is there a specific
division in government or a specific uh
person in government who is in charge of
setting up those subgroups and expert
groups or is it a multitude of different
departments
[Music]
basically who was deciding who will be
sitting on each subgroups is people from
office so it's all all under him and he
has some people working for him who are
actually like administering
administrating this agenda because he
has you know many stuff to do so he has
people working for him but generally
it's not like there will be like one
Ministry which should be overlooking all
it's like this it's all coming from the
offices of the government where energy
corporation works so in every subgroups
there is someone from Ministry of Health
from minister of interior there are some
uh National anti-drug Police Force there
are people from the custom offices and
they are they have their representative
in each of the subgroups and the
subgroups are divided semantically so
one one of them is international law the
other one is uh home law and like lost
in the church public and the prohibition
and the repression the third one is
economy and Texas and so on so in total
there are five of them and remember of
two of them but I'm trying to follow the
work of the other three as well but so
far I can't say anything openly and in
public because it's all like behind
closed doors at the moment the first
but the first Public Public Announcement
should be by the end of March
okay end of March and in terms of
working in unison with your neighbors
Germany do you believe that the the two
political leaders of each country have
had discussions on this and are kind of
moving in unison or do you think they're
on two different uh trajectories that uh
it just seems it might look as if
they're working together but it seems as
if Czech Republic are going a hell of a
lot faster than Germany
uh definitely there are talks between
not the not the politicians but between
the officials so the team of uh is in
close talks with their counterparts in
in German and German government so it's
the uh the German drug experts who are
working on the bill so we are trying to
like discuss our next steps and try to
be in line because we also have a long
shared border so you know we need to
discuss the things you know if one
legalizes and the other one doesn't so
what would happen because you know you
have the three of free of trade free
trade in in the European Union so you
know it's like loads of things to be
discussed and yeah we are so we are in
Costa not not me but not me personally
but people from our team from Indigo
virtual team are in close touch in close
touch with them and they are trying to
you know make the same steps or similar
steps in order to be in line somehow
excuse me do you think that the the end
result that they're going to get is
going to basically be a change of
European law or just uh we're moving on
ahead because it seems that if you guys
about Germany and Czech Republic
Legalize It seems to It's Gonna
obviously be a domino effect then that
no country is going to want to have a
border with a country with a legal
industry where their citizens can just
walk over and buy what they want and
then walk back into the country
uh yeah well the the that's the biggest
issue and we are just talking about this
a lot because you know everybody is
usually scared of this single convention
and the U.N but but in reality uh like
nothing can happen if we don't you know
if we don't listen to this uh it's U.N
single connection anymore but the
problem is European law because if the
European Union or the European
connection commission says you shouldn't
be doing this and we will do it anyway
they could punish us somehow so and
nobody wants to be in like you know have
problems with the European commission
and the European Union so uh that's the
biggest problem now and like the the
biggest uh threat to this effort is
probably is is that the European
commission will say no we are against it
and you cannot do that and then
obviously Czech Republic is a small
player so we would need the help from
German government to try to not I
wouldn't say Force but try to persuade
the European commission and the people
that are responsible go for this
decision to allow it at least somehow or
you know maybe it will end up that they
will say you know you can Legalize It
for the home growing because it's like
human rights issue because you shouldn't
be putting people behind bars because of
growing few plants but the regulated
market could be a problem so
we will see what happens we are still I
think what the European commission says
so far there was just some indication
but nothing official so I think in the
Czech Republic and in Germany the
proponents of this legalization efforts
are are waiting and accepting expecting
what's what's gonna what's gonna come up
come out from the European commission so
we will see and if they say no it's
gonna be a huge problem so let's fingers
fingers crossed
is there a team or a specific person in
the European commission that is going to
be the sole Arbiter of this case or is
it going to be a panel of people
I personally don't know because I'm
actually not the member not the member
of the subgroup working on this
International International relationship
and international law so I don't have
the information from this group yet I
will have them as I said in the at the
end of March but so far I'm just focused
on my two groups and I'm following the
news from the other groups as well other
groups as well but I don't know how this
is like in in the in regarding the
European Commission because I'm not
doing this uh like in very depth in
depth I totally understand well
something I wanted to ask you about what
is the kind of Fest in Prague is that
the top uh events that you guys have
every year in the in the city yeah yeah
yeah it it grew from a small minor uh
trade show to one of the biggest and
largest cannabis trade shows and expos
in the world I think probably it's the
second biggest to Las Vegas and maybe
it's comparable to Spanish but
definitely it's huge popular and there
are many people even from other
countries coming here for this trade
show like from Germany from Poland and
Slovakia and other countries which have
pretty strict cannabis laws so they come
to Prague in every November and it's
very good the the main organizer of the
of the carafest he doesn't just do the
trade show but he always organizes a
professional conference which is
attached to the to the trade show and
there are always like very important
figures of the Cannabis World from
science from politics there are many
patients there so it's really great that
if some people if people come to visit
Canada Fest they just don't see the
companies and they just don't just buy I
don't know like flower pots and seeds
and stuff like that but they can also
attend this professional conference and
see the important people who are doing
research for many years and who are who
are very knowledgeable in the field of
cannabis to give their talks so it's
it's like it's it's a lot of Education
as well
okay very good so it's on every November
for everybody that's watching Everybody
usually it's always the first first
weekend in November okay very good it's
like around 30 000 people coming every
every year
well
um so tell me this before we go you've
got your first edition of canopy
magazine coming out this Thursday do you
want to tell everybody a little bit
about uh what's going to be in the first
article and what people can expect from
the magazine moving forward
yeah it's it's like the first issue of
this year because we are we've been on
the market for for nearly five years now
so it's yeah yeah
this year and uh Dennis obviously Focus
mainly you know as I said in the
beginning originally the magazine was
focused on medical aspects but because
what's happening in the Czech Republic
as we were talking about uh we focus
more and more on the on the politics and
on the regulation upcoming regulations
so we have a large interview with One
famous hip-hop rapper from the Czech
Republic who is who set up who
established a like a chart he calls it a
chart 420 and he tries to speak with the
politicians who are actually against
against this legalization which is
mainly the Christian conservatives like
in every other country and then the
extremist from the from the like right
side of the spectrum uh so yeah that's
that's basically it and in the from the
medical aspects we are just talking
about uh health health problems uh
women's health problems and how cannabis
called them help them this is the main
main topic of the of the issue and also
as in every issue we have many patient
stories we have uh growing articles
about growing because we want to
encourage people to grow their own
medicine at home as well of course in a
legal way so we are talking to CBD
strains which with up to one percent THC
which is also very interesting
development here that since since 2022
we have uh one percent THC legalized in
the Czech Republic so we are the only
European Union country to allow this and
only second in the whole Europe to
Switzerland
and yeah that's this contributed also a
lot to like the Cannabis boom in the
Czech Republic
because you know the more th you can
have in the plant the more the more the
the Richer profile you can have in the
in the CBD product as well and yeah so
basically that's it it's like we have a
more and 100 pages so loads of
interesting stuff to read and we hope to
be able to translate as much as as we
can to English and then hopefully uh to
other languages as well
amazing it's been fantastic excuse me
fantastic talking to you Lucas um I wish
you guys nothing but the best in the
Czech Republic and hopefully we can
touch base again this year and see how
things are moving along steadily and all
the best at all the subs group and
experts groups that have been set up
of course it will be my pleasure
perfect until next episode everybody
thank you
foreign