foreign
Philippe or Spina who's the director of
Business Development at Colombian
Organics how you keep it today new
hello how are you doing very well mate
thank you very much for taking your time
to do this
no thank you for you for the invitation
um can you maybe give everybody a little
overview of your history in the Cannabis
industry today and your position at
Colombian Organics
yeah right now I've been working in the
Cannabis industry for five years I've
been working in commercials in projects
in the production instruction but right
now I'm making the commercial part since
like three four years ago working in
this difficult industry that's not easy
and especially here in Colombia because
you know you have all the laws you have
the government and everything else but
my experience goes especially to
commercialize and the marketing
advertising of the Cannabis industry and
of course helping all the companies to
sell their products Airway flowers
instructions whatever they have
okay very interesting and first topic I
wanted to jump up was basically an
overview of Colombia can you maybe give
everybody I know we had it was Medical
in 2016 Industrial in 2019 and then
potentially an adult use market now in
2023. can you maybe tell everybody how
expansive is the medical program
currently and do you know a rough number
of patients that are on it
yeah right now the problem uh with the
medical programs is that it's not really
together they are not working together
with the companies and the government
and they have their companies here uh
the access is still really difficult to
the patients they need a long process
it's really bureaucratic for that reason
so medical cannabis right now in
Colombia is specialized in cosmetics and
other kind of products that are not like
medical like the pharmaceutical products
we were waiting for uh obviously
especially for the for the technology we
have here also we don't have like all
the stuff and all the people for the
kind of products that we need for
pharmaceutical product to the medical
patients uh talking about the industrial
the industrial hemp for example we don't
have so developed the market for for
this kind of products because they don't
have
we don't have the extensions in Colombia
we have like like all the land and it's
really good and Colombia has really good
conditions all year round but the
problem is the extensions and the
Machinery that you need for this
extraction for the hemp that is really
different from the USA that they have so
big volume of this production
and right now that you tell it uh last
week we lost the chance to have the
approval of the adult use in Colombia
because they because in the Congress it
didn't pass it didn't pass the the bill
from the Congress we just miss it for
five boats of the Congress but you know
they have time this year they are going
to present it again so maybe next year
we have the good news for the auto use
in Colombia
okay and can you tell me what makes
Colombian organic so special in the the
expertise areas that they have
yeah the best part from Colombia is uh
the experience that we have in flowers
that we have in flowers and genetics we
have really good experience because we
we will be working with flowers like uh
70 years ago uh when we started from uh
different kind of flowers like roses uh
sunflowers tulip ones those kind of
flowers and other experience were
translated to the Cannabis industry and
we have these uh low-cost uh jobs for
the for the people it's really low cost
uh it's really good for us the land is
really good it's really 30 for us the
procedures we are used to agricultural
procedures but the only thing that we
are missing right now is like the the
company over bu or the company
uh we see like Farmers farming but not a
company it's cells a big Enterprise we
need to understand hus Farmers has a
company
okay you see a lot of talk in Europe and
I'm sure a lot of investors talking
about Colombia are going to be a future
supplier for the European side of the
industry is the is it the lack of
technological equipment is this is the
thing that's hindering large-scale
export from Colombia
yeah kind of kind of the lack of
Technology as always because you know uh
we are always talking about Colombia and
Latin America has the raw material
suppliers but that's what we need to
transform here we need to focus on high
technology products added value products
not just the raw material what's
happening right now we are we are being
or we are seeing in Europe has the raw
material in the case of dry flour for
example that is just the first step in
the process of the cultivation you know
um but what's happening right now we are
just stopping in that time of the moment
the same that happened with coffee with
coffee a couple of years were like just
making raw material raw material and
exploring the raw material to bring back
a final product you know that's what we
need to do with the Cannabis but right
now we not too many years making the
final product here but the lack of you
know of technology is is something that
is really difficult here and also their
certifications uh I I totally in
conversations before that the
certifications it's really important for
us because we are uh a company or we are
a country from Farmers you know Farmers
don't have
the they don't they don't they don't not
used to
work with big companies big procedures
uh big Enterprises so they don't
understand this about the certification
if you talk with uh some Farmers here
about the ACP they don't even know and
imagine that we we need to make some
final products with the GMP for example
they don't know what is GMP and they
don't know what it means that that's
part of the problem also and we
discussed before I think it's truly
we're the only company with the GMP
certification is it in Colombia the rest
are the model is to export to somewhere
like Malta and then that facility in
multi will have EU GMP certification
exactly that's the only solution that we
have right now there's only one company
here with the GMP and they even had to
bring someone from Germany to get that
certification and that's that's a big
problem and that says a lot uh from a
country that it's it's a post that is
specializing in the economics industry
that we don't have uh dnp certifications
here yeah uh what are making the other
companies they get the gacp
certification from National companies
from natural institutes and uh taking
abroad to Portugal where they transform
into GMP
and is there a certain certification
that's required for export into the
United States and Canada
uh right now not because you know the
USA Market is just opening the doors to
the Latin American Market they are just
waiting uh they're just asking for the
total panel the quality panel of the
policy for example heavy metal
pesticides microbiology all that panel
of the laboratory but they are not
asking right now for certifications
Canada it's a difficult country but then
they are just asking for jacp it's the
minimum
I saw recently one of your posts and it
was a good question that I wanted to ask
you one of the kind of successful
countries in Latin South America has
been Uruguay so far can you tell me what
Colombia can learn from the Uruguayan
model
yeah I I think I I tell it in the in the
past uh but is the
they were really close with the
institute in Uruguay you know Uruguay is
uh 3 million population country so it's
really easy to them
[Music]
to work with the companies really close
with the Institute with the National
Institute for City International
Institute that is regulating right now
to cannabis and that's a missing
we don't have that relation so close
with The Regulators for example we had
here we have many institutes that is uh
in charge of the procedures and you need
to make a procedure here uh procedure in
another Institute but they are not
connected between them so it's really
difficult disconnection with the
Institutes of the government
I think that's one and the other one is
the they they specialize in the first
moment or in the first year
understanding the needs of the market
they really understood that since the
first moment and that implies for
example that they brought the generics
from Switzerland from Europe and they
are cultivating the genetics why because
they understood that they if you want to
export to if you want to export to to
Europe you need the genetics from Europe
you need the genetics that you like from
Europe so that's really good point for
from to learn from your wife
and when it comes to Colombia on the
extraction side of things we obviously
know that you guys are world class at
the farming cultivation side of things
how many extraction facilities exist in
Colombia and do they excel at the same
level as the cultivation
uh they are not at the same level of the
cultivation uh you're missing a lot of
companies making construction here but
what happens for example the cost of
extraction here is really high it's
really really high because of the volume
because of the technology for example uh
because of the relationship between the
between the companies as I told you more
or less right now that I can remember uh
maybe more than
400 license for extraction for 100
license for extraction but from those
400 just operating really really
operating no more than 50 companies so
it's it's really difficult for
Destruction companies here
because the same the volume is not
really good for the expensive that it
represents to extract here different
from the USA you know from the USA you
have a big company a big factory making
structure because they have a lot of
hemp for those destruction you know the
instruction for the extraction for
example here the full spectrum our broad
spectrum is more expensive here even if
the flower is cheaper but the process of
Destruction is really expensive
okay and the company you work for
Colombian Organics you have more than 25
years experience in this sector can you
maybe explain what sets of Colombian
Organics differently from the other
companies that are in Colombia and what
the future Ambitions for the company may
be
I I can assume it uh I can't resume it
really well in two word genetics on
flowers the experiencing flowers from
the company because this is a familiar
company and the family is been working
with flowers from 50 years ago from a
recognized company here in Bogota and
Colombia but uh genetics genetics is
like the the main point from for them
because they specialize in making that
final hunting uh taking the best
genetics to the cultivation taking the
best procedures for this reproduction of
the genetics and that's why we have
right now seeds in UK in Thailand
um
soon in Switzerland United States we
have also the the seeds and soon in
Argentina for the same so that's why we
know or we are recognized in Europe and
in the market because of the experience
and the trustable that is the company
working with genetics because you know
it's not easy working with genetics
because it's not the the final product
it's a product that you are going to
have after the cultivation but the trust
that the companies are the owners of the
company have been making with this
company with all the commercial fares
it's really good and they trust people
Trust on them and in the experience from
the company
and when it comes to the political
overview in Colombia we we see around
the world that it's generally the
Democratic side of the politics are are
leaning towards an adult use market and
the conservatives are more one just a
medical Market is that the same in
Colombia
yeah it it happens the same in some ways
that's why uh last week we lost the
opportunity to regulate the adult use
because of the conservative uh body they
were saying like no we denied that
option because they have all these kind
of tops that it's not for the Cannabis
industry
uh but in one way or another the world
needs to regulation the regulation of
the of this plant you know it's it's
more the benefits than the but when you
make it and results uh show it you know
Canada is a good example or why is the
best example for example
um it's not perfect but it's better than
having a black market
on streets with their kids with all
their bad on the negative part of the
black market in the cannabisi industry
yeah I agree with you I know you're a
very busy man so last question before I
let you go what is the top two things
that you look forward to seeing over the
next couple of years happening in
Colombia
the first thing is that the farmers
understand that they are working with
companies internationally that they need
to understand they need to see
themselves themselves to us uh
Enterprises big companies with
procedures uh with good Productions and
the second one understand the market if
you don't understand the market you
could have the best uh production the
best production plants and the best
production projects
but uh it's useful if you don't have the
market you know
okay very interesting you might know
you're a very busy man so I'm gonna let
you go so thank you very much for taking
your time today
oh thank you to do and have a good day
and good podcasting
thank you very much until next episode
everybody
[Music]