[Music]
welcome to the cannabis review everybody
i've got a great episode for you today
i'm delighted to be joined on the show
by gino kenny she knows a td for
dublin midwest how are you keeping gino
i
am great great thank you very much for
coming on the show mate i know you've
been a long advocate working in this
industry and uh you've been a campaigner
for
medical cannabis program in ireland you
also introduced legislation to legalize
medical cannabis and led the successful
national campaign resulting in the
change of law
can we start basically there what's the
overview at the moment of ireland's
cannabis program as you see it
um well yeah you're right on
five years ago almost to the day
i introduced the bill around medical
cannabis and
and obviously it you know eventually
pushed
the government into changing the policy
after a very very long campaign
and also campaigners families and
individuals
had campaigned for access you know for
themselves or their family members so
that was the kind of the cutting edge of
the campaign
so at the moment um the medical cannabis
accounts program will be
will commence in the next i think week
um
and for the first time uh if you have a
qualified condition under the program
and you can get metal a medical cannabis
product
described for that condition now it's
it's quite restrictive
and we were very critical at the time in
relation to the omission of
chronic pain um but
you know that's it is what it is uh
and hopefully we can campaign in the
very very near future in relation to
um you know widen the scope of the
medical cannabis access program
in relation to other conditions and
people getting access
and via the you know the long-term
illness game on the metal card so that's
that's where we're at it was i said it
was a very it's a long campaign that is
in some ways only begun um but
you know uh we keep pushing forward in
relation to kind of
reforming uh and getting i mean people
getting access to medical cannabis
avoid the program and broaden it out in
their very near future
okay and can you tell me who who's he
responsible for
the the choice of ailments that are
being able to
receive this program so the hpra
which is the health product regulation
authority they commissioned
the document in 2017 in relation to
uh medical cannabis in ireland and they
recommended a medical cannabis access
program with them tree conditions we
were very critical at the time
um they have an expert group and that
kind of
you know made that kind of
recommendation and
and at the time i said you know why was
chronic pain
and other conditions i missed it and
they gave an explanation which i thought
was kind of
slightly kind of you know didn't really
hold weight
um but they're they're the kind of
i suppose they're the group and kind of
authority to have you know put the the
program together
and but at least it's on the positive
side at least it's a start
you know and from where we were um
and it's been as i said it's been very
protracted but at least
now families and individuals can get
metal cannabis products on the
prescription rather than have to go to a
licensed
system which the license system will
still be in existence
but um you know families hopefully can
get it under
on the prescription very very soon um
and
don't have to go through all the kind of
bureaucracy and the kind of
the the arbitrary nature of the met of
the licensing system
okay and it brings down to the next
topic is your bill that you're proposing
you're going to be debating at the dell
this summer
do you want to give everybody an
overview of exactly what it is that
you're going to be debating in the doll
yeah so the bill
i'm proposing to put forward uh the
cannabis regulation and control bill
obviously this is for recreation use and
the the two issues shouldn't be
completed
and related to medical and uh recreation
use sometimes you do
no but you know um sometimes
we can't help that but uh so the bill
it's been drafted at the moment
um i'm hoping to introduce this time in
the autumn
probably october um because the doll
comes back on the 14th of september
um and we hope to have the bill ready to
go in around that time
and so
again it hasn't been drafted but it
essentially will
uh you know you know supposed to cause a
debate
uh in relation to um end of prohibition
and kind of making cannabis legal in a
framework of regulation
and the framework of revenue and the
framework of
where people are you know you know not
criminalized for
cannabis use cultivation and possession
because
it doesn't work um and has been a
failure
essentially so um you know we need to go
beyond
failure and go beyond when you go beyond
failure
you have to look at something very very
different and a paradigm
shift and that shift is legalization and
so
the bill hopefully will kind of
instigate that debate
um and kind of create a kind of i
suppose
you know i suppose an atmosphere where
you know we have to look
beyond the kind of very
antiquated laws around cannabis use so
that's what it will do
to find our finer details i you know i
can't really comment at the moment
because obviously you know
uh we can get you back and we can
discuss those yeah i think it's better i
think
can you give me an example let's say for
everybody watching here
let's talk as to the procedure if it
does happen so you bring it
a bill to the doll you'll debate it
let's say you convince your opposition
that
they're going to be in favor of what
you're proposing everybody says yay the
bill gets proposed trump talk is true
like the next three important steps that
happened that bill then
to be able to let's say it progresses to
where there is a dispensary
that some uh somebody can go in with a
medical card who's over the age of 21
and can access that as an adult consumer
without getting
it under a medical program i mean he
wants the duration of time and how many
well it's very difficult it's very
difficult to put a time
um frame on it i mean things in here
work extremely slow especially if you're
in opposition
that the vast majority of opposition
bills never see the light of day they
never get past
you know the year they introduce a bill
it's debated and then it's voted down
that that's what happens to vast
majority of bills and even bills that
kind of go beyond that which would be
second stage
then they go into committee stage uh or
pre-legislative scrutiny
um does every chance that it will never
see the light of day
you know so you know do you see what
if the opposition came in and could they
take your idea and your bill
and they can't afford themselves
yeah no they can and if they want to do
it i'm i'm fine
you know i i'm fine if the government
say
you know okay we looked at you bill you
know we
well you know and we let it pass the
committee stage
in some ways it has happened under
opposition bills where
like an opposition no idea or a bill has
been basically
the guts of it has been taken from by
the government in situ
and they've legislate for if they want
to do that fair enough that's that's no
problem
i don't i don't i'm not sure if that
will happen um
but the main thing is that we introduce
a bill there's a debate in the doll
there's a vote very soon after um and
then
you know the the doll then gives
direction on where the bill
needs to go does it kind of be does it
fall completely
uh is there an amendment to the bill you
know the best case scenario that
you know it's it's it's voted on and it
is
it's agreed that it goes to probably
pre-led
scrutiny or committee stage you know
that would be
i mean that would be a big kind of step
in relation to end of prohibition
ireland if it could get to that stage
you know pre-leds of scrutiny so there's
a long long way to go
in relation to this uh it's obviously a
numbers game as well
like the government have a majority and
if they want to vote any opposition
bill down and they can um but we would
be looking for support
in the government particularly the green
party the green party have a very good
policy around
um cannabis use so we'd be hoping for
for their support whether they're
they're in a kind of
pact with the finale of vienna fault um
kind of you know coalition so you know
we'd be looking for broad
a broad spectrum of support to you know
look at the kind of merits of
legalization and end on prohibition okay
and the last topic that we want to talk
about is the inflection point for
politicians
it leads us on from what we were just
talking about is it going to be the case
of
let's say finite fall infinite we know
that green parties you guys are in favor
of this
the other parties that have claimed to
not be in favor is it going to be job
creation
is it going to be revenue earned for the
uh the
tax and licensing excise people is it
is it is a patient access what are the
the reflection points to uc politicians
actually do you know go what we're going
to support this now
yeah that's a good point um and we've
seen over
the last couple of decades how social
issues
um you know i suppose people power
and kind of uh persuasion
has changed politicians minds
uh so there's a kind of uh there's a
revolution going on around
in relation to social issues uh and
again we just we just
just look back the last six or seven
years of certain issues that were kind
of
in some ways slightly taboo uh but
they're kind of mainstream
in some guys um and you know
book reform is probably no different um
there is a lot to do around us what will
kind of change
people's minds and i think there's a
number of factors
um i think you know public opinion
is ahead of politicians on this right by
uh i think by a good margin uh
and when you parallel um
the moving parts of legalization on the
table
i think the majority of people in
ireland actually majority people
most countries will say look at keeping
cannabis illegal doesn't hasn't
worked right it doesn't work and it's uh
counterproductive
so we want to do something very
different and that different
is uh
the opposite of what what is happening
now
and what's happening now is people are
being criminalized people
are um people going through the criminal
justice system
and you know being criminalized for
cannabis use that doesn't work
uh so we want to do something different
and and
if there's enough kind of a public nude
out there
you know and to push you know they want
change on this
then things can happen very very quickly
you know and things can happen
you know unexpected unexpectedly um
and other parties that had a kind of an
opposition to certain things
you know mines do change you know they
do evolve
uh but the cutting edge of kind of that
change is always a public opinion you
know it's people on the street
uh people kind of contacting their tds
and so forth and saying look in on this
issue
we don't we believe that you know
it's wrong to criminalize and
criminalize people
and we need to do something very very
different and with a better outcome
with kind of harm reduction so there are
all the factors and the factors there's
other factors as well
about as i said health land approach
how it actually could create revenue and
how it could you know where does
regulation because there's no regulation
whatsoever
around cannabis use uh there's a so once
you have prohibition
that then a vacuum exists and
where does the vacuum people certain
individuals and groupings
will fill that vacuum in and at the
moment that vacuum is being uh filled in
by the black market
s and criminal gangs and they use all
sorts of unscrupulous
um uh tactics to you know
you know to kind of for distribution and
bringing
minors into kind of the distribution
drugs and it's pretty insidious
and so why allow that to happen you know
governments are allowing this to happen
um
and are they're waiving control over the
distribution of cannabis so
you know what air bill would do is
basically uh cut the black market out
not entirely because i think sometimes
there will be
you know there will be kind of the black
market in the background but less
so in relation to end of prohibition so
all down factors on um you know
and you know trying to kind of debate
tds uh that may be an opposition to it
and kind of
teasing the kind of things that they may
have concerns about so all that factors
i think uh will be a very robust debate
and an interesting debate in the in the
next couple of months
yeah i couldn't agree tomorrow and i
think that debate needs to uh
maintain the fact that any revenue comes
from the cannabis industry needs to go
back into the stakeholders in each
neighborhood where that
industry is making money so police
reinvestment schools reinvestment health
reinvestment so
it's not just an industry that's there
to make money it's an industry that's
there to generate revenue for the
community that those businesses are in
and help benefit anybody and i think
you'd want to be a cold-hearted sob
to even not be in favor of that
regardless what your stance on other
drugs may be
exactly exactly on and i think things
are changing like you know you see the
united states you see
mexico you see other countries around
the world they are looking at
things differently than than
they've done what they were doing before
and
kind of you know the misuse of drugs the
acts itself
is quite antiquated um
and you know it needs to be performed
particularly around cannabis use
and i think there's obviously there's a
kind of a middle road
uh called decriminalization and i'm all
for decriminalization
um but it doesn't decriminalization
particularly on cannabis doesn't go far
enough you you have to be talking about
legalization
and um and regulating this market yeah
yeah yeah because if you're talking
about equalization
it kind of fudges the idea um
and some people like i think the
majority of tds would be for you
decriminalization in
some form uh but they need to go before
and they've been talking about this for
decades right does it
like this place they can
it's a talking shop have you understood
there's a lot of talk and not enough
action
you know and particularly around issues
where
you know where working-class people are
really really affected
um and it's a it's a class issue as well
uh so we need to kind of you know keep
kind of raising the issue
around kind of why kind of uh
prohibition
and kind of criminalizing people for
personal drug use doesn't it's
counter-productive and i think other
countries are saying that and they're
gonna have to do something different
because
you know it's about kind of um
you know it's it's about kind of
it's it's a societal thing as well and
it's an issue where you know
uh people can be drawn into that kind of
the alternative economy
in relation to distribution of drugs and
and that can as i said that can be very
insidious relating to communities and
individuals and so forth
so we need to do something very
different uh from
what has happened and what will you know
what will be the future and that future
is uh ending
prohibition and kind of doing something
very very different what we're doing
before
yeah couldn't agree with you more and as
the generations move along as i said i
think those outdated policies that
became and the reagan era is there long
since gone
anybody born after 1980 now has a bit of
cup on it about them and understands the
world that they live in and
grew up with this as a thing and realize
the garbage that's out there in the
illegal market and the fact that it's
now considered
like wine over in california with
billion dollar companies so
those companies aren't going to just sit
over there once they're allowed to go to
north or europe they're going to be over
here in ireland should be taking
advantage of
the jobs and that are going to come here
with a book gino i can't thank you
enough for coming on the show mate i
hope
we get to touch base towards the end of
the year and find out more details in
the bill yeah and
give everybody a little bit more
information but have you enjoyed the
rest of your day and keep up the great
work
thanks pal see you later guys thanks man