[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined in this episode by fellow
irishman and one of the most successful
irishmen to ever set foot in the
cannabis industry to date
he is basically the president and
founder of multi-jurisdictional
vertically integrated family of cannabis
businesses that are involved in
cultivation distribution and retail he's
also established patience care
collective in berkeley in 2001 making it
the oldest continuously operating
cannabis retailer in the united states
and he has a wealth of multitude of
experience that we're hopefully going to
be able to drench him in this episode
this is marco bryant martin keeping
how you doing on thanks very much for
having me on man appreciate it i'm
delighted to have you on me but i was
doing the tags even the name i was like
what title i'm giving him he's got so
many
different things that he's been
successful at so it's great to be able
to chat here and hopefully uh spread a
bit of education to the audience
watching these episodes
can you maybe give everybody just a
quick little overview of how you ended
up over in the cannabis industry in
california going from music into that
scene
yeah um basically um
around 95
sometime around then 90 well actually
they say in 94.
we had started a clothing company it was
called uh communion it was the first
ever clothing company on the internet
um
it was organic hemp
back when you couldn't even wear a full
hemp t-shirt you know had to be a mix of
cotton
and then we started
we we met this group called the cannabis
action network
in in berkeley they were doing a uh they
had a booth on the street every every
weekend and my partner at the time mike
mattel he met him and mike's an artist
and he ended up doing some art for them
um for and then we ended up helping with
a concert that they did in golden gate
fields
uh um
ended up helping him with the cannabis
cup over in amsterdam for five or six
years from like 95 to 2000
um
did a lot of activist work for them
basically for the further for the group
and then
and and started doing because we was a
rape promoter we had a lot of experience
in putting on events and dealing with
cops and that kind of thing you know and
uh
and um
so that kind of leads me on the first
topic i kind of wanted to jump into it
like you've got such a long story that
because probably 15 minutes i'm going to
try and rush different things along at
certain times because i think we can
give you three or four episodes
yeah we cover so many things over a new
episode let me just jump straight on to
the pcc the success and the longevity of
the pcc
why did you start it what's the key to
the longevity of success with the pcc
and how can people in europe and ireland
learn from the successful things that
you've implemented over there
great questions
we started pcc because
we were empowered by cannabis and that
it's the government's lying to you about
it not having any medical use um and so
we decided we would go for it we opened
it up um i was in uh april the 4th 2001.
um
we were i think some of the stuff that
kept us open is that we were political
we
we always had some kind of like flyer to
give out to people that they could call
their representative or something we
always took care of patients like really
took care of them you know we weren't
just in it for money um and one of the
big things was that we we didn't grow
proposition 215 which is what a lot of
dispensaries were based on before the
last change in 2018 pop system 215 was
1996.
it was
very gray
area type thing in regards to what you
could do but it was pretty clear on a
couple of things like you can't have
retail and have dispensary car you can't
have a dispensary and cultivate so we
didn't cultivate
ever and anyone that did cultivate and
had a dispensary pretty soon the dea
would come along and [ __ ] lap your
head off no problem
um so i think there were some of the
reasons why like patient-centered
political
and and being aware of the environment
and the climate and so what can people
in ireland learn uh they're not going to
do it the politicians are not going to
do it it's as simple as that they're
self-serving the vast majority of them
not unless the people of ireland
actually want it and actually forced
force the issue
writing to your td your senator coming
to one of the pfsa protests
sending an email joining pfsa
keeping an eye on the european news it's
like do you want your mother to have
access to medicine when she gets older
and she needs it or your father or
someone who gets cancer i mean it's it's
pretty real
okay very interesting and i'll move on
to
the farms what was the uh the objective
with theirs basically the laws allowed
you to change that you could have a
separate entity that would allow
cultivation and you want to basically
ensure that the patients had organic and
a very high quality product is that
right and sends it's very well said yeah
you'd have to add energy to it you know
it's like the positivity and the energy
the plant is like whatever you give to
the plant plants going to give back to
you
so we wanted to make sure that it's not
only grown correctly but curing which is
cure growing is about half the battle
curing getting all the gases out and
getting into the state where it's like
stable and it's the best medicine you
can get is a a lot of a lot of people
still to this day even more now these
days skip that step it doesn't burn good
it's not good for the patient you know
so we wanted to be able to control that
to a certain extent now it's not as if
pcc
it just carries foxworthy it's got
hundreds of products you know what i
mean but for a certain amount of that so
that that was for pcc but also there's a
lot of dispensaries around so then we we
started
our own distribution company called
california cannabis distribution company
maybe i'm jumping head there far i'm
sorry
and the reason we started that was so we
could distribute our own flower when
cannabis flow when the law has changed
you
you can't be a farmer and then sell
directly to a retailer anymore that's
when but to the first of january 2018 um
you had to that's you have to as a
farmer sell to a distributor so then so
we had to retail we had farm then we
started the distribution company so
we're vertically integrated and we don't
really need like anyone in in in that
regard to get ourselves to a certain
level
okay incredible one of them i'm very
curious about is when it comes to the
logistics and the shipping of the
product from from point a to point b is
there a specific license that the drive
is required to have there is there
specific insurance that goes with the
trucks or is it basically just
if nobody asks nobody says
no no no i've been shipping wheat and
moving wheat around california for for a
long time before it was legal and like
one of my favorite things about
legalization is that you have a shipping
manifest
an fn shipping manifest do you mean what
i mean it's like a cop can pull you over
and you're like here you go i'm going
from point a to point b
you know that's a beautiful thing about
it and you have to have
uh it's also on a thing called metric
m-e-t-r-c it's an acronym but a state
it's a tracking program basically every
gram is tracked everywhere it goes
whether it's from the farmer
to the distributor our distributor can
sell to a distributor and then what's
called the final mile the final mile is
like from the distributor to the retail
and then all of that's insured you can
ensure your product these days even
though it's expensive your your vehicle
is in short again it's more everything
is more expensive for your own cannabis
it's a simple that the way it is these
days anyway you know because it's
federally illegal so it might be legal
at a state level but it's still
federally illegal so insurance and all
of those type of things that this thing
is pretty hard
yeah it's a highly valued commodity as
well i'm sure there's a number untoward
characters who have their eye on that as
well so yeah i can imagine so security
detail in licensing and insurance are
all required to be able to ship from
point a to point d including the final
mile is that correct that's correct
brilliant right well now i want to jump
onto the main topic that i wanted to
bring on this and it's basically
patience for safe access in ireland so
you've been instrumental in the founding
and the the energy behind this
organization the non-pro not-for-profit
organization in ireland can you tell me
a little bit about the group that's set
up and what the what's the pr primary
objective within the next 18 months for
phsa
great question uh myself kenny tynan
alicia meyer and martin condon started
patients for safe access a couple of
years ago we we met on zoom for a long
time through corvid started the
organization like filed for the
non-profit got the bank account and so
on and so forth we're planning an online
conference for a while but then like
covert opened up so we ended up aiming
to do our first conference there and
that was in june the goal of the first
conference was to unite
the disparate groups cannabis activist
groups around the country that was one
of the main goals to get all of these
people into the same same
chickens outside rooster
my goal the goal was to get all these
people into one room so we could all see
we're on the same page and uh
unified basically and then and they used
to notice uh crown
major group for farm tom carl amy brown
uh peter reynolds all these people know
are a larger part of patients for safe
access like we have a weekly meeting
every week like and
it's a larger group
we're taking on larger things you know
um
so that's that's how we started boy was
it started um
i've seen cannabis help
a lot of people on the way out it's not
you know there's no cure for stage four
cancer let's be real you know what i
mean but like it can give a person a lot
of dignity on the way out that's a key
thing that it does if it used properly
it can help to save and stave off cancer
and be health
efficient in that way uh i've seen it
cure cancer time and time again
obviously not stage four
my mother died of cancer maybe that's
why i'm you know a little more connected
to that like my friends have died of
cancer my dogs have died of cancer i
mean
[ __ ] cancer man you know what i mean
it's like cannabis really really helps
and so i want and i've seen it like
firsthand anyone come along challenge me
see what you can
nah i've seen it firsthand i'm the man
with the experience i'm the person with
the experience you know and
to for
the politicians in ireland not to see
that we need to make the politicians in
ireland see that that's a reality a
reality and they that the people of
ireland need to have access to safe
medical cannabis simple as that not just
for
the three
um conditions you have now i mean one is
draconian right ms they're saying that
you you can if you have ms we recognize
you're sick but it's only if you're
really really really sick and about to
die that you can get cancer that you can
get access to cannabis that's draconian
like the doctor's number one like rule
is do not ham
where's stephen donnelly in all of this
except for denying it it is an old
ireland and there's a new ireland you
know we're trying to appeal to both
ireland's because the new ireland wanted
is a lot of people use it and you all
ireland don't want it they're afraid of
priests they're afraid of their doctors
let's be real about it you know those
days are gone
those days are gone
you know so what's our timeline in the
next 18 months
legalize medical cannabis in ireland
add more conditions
chronic pain
endometriosis
like psychological things
just
there's a lot there's a lot it can do
and bring in industry in ireland i have
a challenge that you look at my fridge
now right there's barry's tea in my
cupboard
there's kerrygold in my fridge and
there's a bottle of tealing and streams
in in irish stuff that irish people and
other people buy around around the world
there's way more kerrygolds sold around
the world than there is in ireland why
can't irish people have the right to
grow cannabis
to have an industry to be a distributor
to be a retailer to be a manufacturer to
be a cultivator and not just provide for
the general public in ireland but also
like germany's got a problem right now
they don't have enough access to
cannabis to medical cannabis so that's
where we're coming from
well it's dead matter couldn't uh yeah
it's very empowering i have to admit so
basically getting chronic pain
neuropathic pain number of conditions
added to the end cap and bolstering and
allowed a much deeper wall of patients
to be able to access these medicines and
much be a wider range of pharmacies and
doctors prescribing them and selling
them i think is we're all on the same
ball regardless of what company you're
in or what territory in ireland i think
that's the objective for us all now to
get done over the next 12 months it's
been absolutely amazing talking mate i
think we'll have to deal with part two
and a part three would you where we can
i would need to say one more thing if i
could sir yeah of course because the
doctors that's the blockage right so
it's like write to your td you're
listening to me write to your td
call your td visit your td
tell them you want the mtap program
that's under review minister donnelly
was brought up by two politicians a
couple of days ago on the dial
and he answered that there it's under
review put pressure on your government
to change the mcat program to allow
cannabis to access for chronic pain and
for endometriosis and other and other
issues that's they're the first steps
and it shouldn't it's just it's it's
tied in on a consultant like for example
if you're a
person that wants to change your
sexuality in ireland
there's a 10-year waiting list 10 years
ireland's health system is draconian
it's not like it's supposed to be a
third world country it's not you know
things need to change in that regard it
can't be just consultants but you wait
years and years and years to see
doctors have got to be able to general
gps like in denmark and in america have
got to be able to have the right to
prescribe that if you see your doctor
talk to your doctor tell them what you
believe we got to empower take our
empowerment and spread our empowerment
to our politicians and our doctors and
our health officials
thanks for your time
mate absolutely brilliantly said uh
thank you very much for taking time and
this will definitely be doing a part two
and being able to bring more information
to the audience but for now mate you
have a great weekend and i look forward
to chatting to you again very soon
alright take care thanks very much for
having me on and thanks very much for
doing the canvas review
anytime at any time till next episode
everybody
[Music]