foreign
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I'm delighted to be
joined that this episode by Professor Dr
Marcus Vice who's the managing director
at Alpha topics gmbh hey keeping today
pereza
how are you keeping today you will yes
I'm well thank you very much
um
I will be happy to answer your questions
well thank you very much for taking your
time to do this I know you're a very
busy man so I will keep this brief and
to the point can you maybe give
everybody a brief overview on your
career to date
yes I did a normal University career
um and I left University when I was a
young Professor at this time
I took over the general Mana manager
position of a small Laboratory
um which was founded
for a research project and this was the
starting of a founding of different
companies providing services for the
pharmaceutical industry in terms of
quality control and Regulatory Affairs
and
um and in the meanwhile I'm 63 and only
one company is left and this is Alpha
topics and with this company I do
training
for the pharmaceutical industry related
to any topic which you can think of in
the context of quality control
manufacturing chemistry of all kinds of
pharmaceutical products and medical
devices and I do also some consultancy
but only
in these topics I'm really interested in
and I like and the Cannabis is one of
them and and this is also related to my
professorship because I'm a professor of
pharmacokinancy so
um so my um yes University
career and education is related to
Herber medicinal products
okay incredible can you maybe explain to
everybody the first topic what are
phytopharmaceuticals
yes this is something very special in
Europe and the European Union uh because
we do have um Harbor products as
medicines this is part of our regulatory
environment in Europe This is in
principle also possible in in other
regions in the world however
um in Europe it's distinct because
um we do have clear guidelines
um
how to deal with these products
considering the
very specific
aspects related to these products and so
any product which is manufactured out of
a plant
um or um
or as a plant material and which is not
a purified compound is considered to be
a phytopharmaceutical so
um degree of purification is sometimes a
matter of debate so
um I would say see Martin could be drawn
at a purity of 90 to 95 if you have
natural compounds of that Purity they
are no longer considered to be phyto
Pharmaceuticals so phyto Pharmaceuticals
are mainly mixtures of compounds
contained in extracts prepared from
herbal starting materials and these
extracts or other preparations are then
manufactured in normal dosage forms like
capsules tablets
liquid dosage forms and form an own
category so-called herbal medicinal
product we do have even a distinct
committee at EBA at our European
medicines agency this is the herbal
medicinal product committee responsible
for this group of
products and very distinct guidance
documents for these products and also
distinct approval procedures in EU
member states
and those the biosynthesis for your
fermentation is that covered under a
phyton Pharmaceuticals no there is an in
normal cases there is no fermentation at
all so
um a normal phytophobical
um you take a plant material
um from cultivation or sometimes it's
still collected in the wild then you try
it then you Mill it and this Millet
material is then extracted the extract
might be purified
and maybe also standardized to to
distinct ingredients and this extract
then is
manufactured in the dosage form so
fermentation sometimes is also um part
of the manufacture but these are very
rare products
and can you explain what are the
benefits of phytopharmaceuticals versus
let's say a synthetic molecule
I think it's difficult to have to have
it summarized under benefit
it's something different because it's
therapy with multi-component mixtures
and of course one can pass postulates
synergistic and maybe also antagonistic
effects in the end it's not a single
pure compound so it's a complete
different
um
concept of
medical use of these kinds of products
and in the end we do have a long
tradition of these products in quite a
few EU member states and and this
tradition builds the basis to have these
products um as medicines
okay can you explain on the second topic
what is the European pharmacopoeia
so the European pharmaco PR is um
um a compendia which is issued by the
Edco m ediko m stands for European
directorate for the quality of medicine
this Edco m is located in Strasbourg and
it's part of the Council of Europe it
has nothing to do with the European
Union because it was founded
um after a second world war and at this
time there was no uni uh European Union
at all and at this time a decision must
be taken which organization in Europe
could be responsible
um to build up
um
pharmacopoeia which is not dedicated to
a single EU member state or a single
state in Europe
but is valid in um in any European
country and at this time the Council of
Europe was the only organization in
place and therefore
this organization which is normally in
charge for human rights and and other
topics far away from Pharmaceuticals
um was assigned to take over this
responsibility and since then
um
at this time
um there were 12 European countries
Switzerland included for example which
is not an EU member State and and they
um assigned the so-called European
pharmacopoeia convention and this
convention was a basis for this European
pharmacopoeia today we do have 46
European countries following the
European pharmacopia and the young green
pharmacopoeia provides standards for
active pharmaceutical ingredients for
packaging material for
excipients and a lot of issues related
to quality control and the ability
testing of pharmaceutical raw materials
and products
there is a clear reference in the
European
legislative environment making these
definitions and requirements in the
European pharmacopoeia legally binding
for any EU country having signed as the
pharmacopoeia convention and
it is yes a lot of products which are
well known
and no longer under patent protection
are included into the pharmacopoeia and
quality standards are defined of course
there are still National pharmacopors
Ireland UK Switzerland
a Germany France Poland and other EU
states do have still National
but as with the time the European
pharmacopoeia gets bigger and the
national pharmacopors get smaller
because at this time when something is
included in the European pharmacopoeia
it will be deleted deleted from the
national pharmacopors so when it comes
to the role that the EMA plays in drug
Discovery and development can you maybe
give everybody a brief little overview
of if somebody wants to basically
develop their own drug or their own
active pharmaceutical ingredient does it
go through the European medical Agency
for approval and what are the main steps
for this to happen
so first of all we still in Europe do
have not
um EU approval for any products so this
um eu-wide approval in the 27 member
states is only open for certain products
um so for example Vex signs everybody
knows that because of the pandemic and
they need to be approved by EMA and also
if you have new zero piece or you have
um yes distinct indications like a neuro
protective agents
um or a neuro degenerative
illness this needs to be approved
through this so-called centralized
procedure so the normal approval um and
this would also be the case for cannabis
is not
achieved by EMA because for herbal
medicine products um they are not
considered to be new chemical entities
they are considered known herbal
products and for this
um you have to go through National
procedures in single EU member states or
you or you can also decide to have
um a so-called decentralized procedure
which means that
um you apply for approval in a group of
EU member states you can select and then
you will select one of the member states
as being the so-called reference member
State responsible for the whole
procedure so if further cannabis Harbor
medicinal products will be developed my
expectation is that they will not be
approved by EMA as this might be the
case if this cannabis medicine will be
developed for diseases which have to go
through the uh through email for example
cancer any cancer product product has to
go through email but in the moment there
is no uh no cancer indication for
cannabis it is it is more related to yes
indications which are not needed to be
approved by email
we see a lot of news and reports of some
biotechnology companies being able to
develop inflammation drugs whether it's
for cardiovascular disease or for bowel
disease are these products that get
approved by EMA it depends on the
indication there's a list of indication
but normal
um
vascular diseases are not part of this
list so it it must be a severe illness
and um and and an illness for which it
was decided that it must be available if
it's developed for all patients in
Europe
um so um yes I it's just you you can
download this list from the internet
um and it's uh it's part of a European
regulation what needs to go through
email what could go through EMA and what
could not and and cannabis medicines
phytomedicines
um will only be able to be approved by
IMA if there is really an indication of
an often severe illness
um and
um or for example if if cannabis would
be antiviral
um then also a centralized procedure
could be chosen but in the moment I have
no indication maybe often indication
often indications must also go through
email
often means this is an indication of a
rare disease and this is also something
which is approved by email so this this
could be possible and biotech
is not phyton medicine so um there is uh
that's very often a misunderstanding so
biotech they develop very often
biological medicines which are not fight
of pharmaceuticals so phyto
Pharmaceuticals are characterized by the
way of their manufacture I have
summarized a couple minutes ago
and
let's go with
the ingredient side of these helped
their potential new medical products
that are going to be created from
cannabinoids and molecules within the
cannabis plant is the most advantageous
option synthetic
fermented biosynthesis or a
phytopharmaceutical that comes from a
plant which is the most
advantageous route you see happening in
Europe
advantages depends on what is the um
what is the target of development so it
could be both
um so um if you if you look for
Innovation
and being on the on the edge of the
knife regarding innovation of course
isolated cannabinoids or maybe also
synthesized
um molecules which are similar to
cannabinoids of a partial
[Music]
um
modified molecules originating from
cannabinoids
um CIS might be they might be considered
to be Innovative products and the normal
extract from Cannabis or other
preparation might be more or less more
regarded as something which comes out of
traditional medicine but which could be
further developed of course in a more
um in a more advanced context
and lastly Before I Let You Go what are
the the things you look forward to
seeing the most over the next let's say
five year period when it comes to
cannabis-based medicines
um I'm involved in quite a few projects
I'm aiming to develop cannabis medicines
in in different indications and from my
perspective this is very important that
this is is done because in the moment in
these EU member states in which cannabis
medicines are allowed they are
distributed to the patients based on
single patient prescription and in
Germany for example asthma gistro
preparations with without any approvals
is a kind of a so-called
No Label use because there is no real
approval process and there is only
limited evidence so we need evidence we
need approved medicines and with
availability of these approved medicines
we will then not only have these
approved medicines in the approved
indications but we will also have a kind
of a No Label use which is better than
off-label use because if if you have a
No Label use
safety has been proven and approved not
necessarily efficacy but this is a
important next step to get more in the
moment we only have sativax as a
phytomedicine and we do have of course
epidiolex and and synthesized
um a canopy THC products but we need
further cannabis medicines in order to
to further establish data on safety and
efficacy in different indications
there's a lot of a lot of dream and wish
in this whole industry and we need
evidence
yeah I couldn't agree with you more
fact-based evidence is Paramount now in
the European industry it seems to be a
lot of people picking themselves they'll
put out any real evidence to back behind
their claims
yes we need evidence so
um and this is very often very often not
given for cannabis medicines and yeah
well our time is up now and I know
you're a very busy man so I'd like to
thank you very much Professor for taking
your time to do this today for anybody
who wants to learn more about Alpha
topics you can see the website below I
highly recommend checking out the
website and if you're on LinkedIn adding
professor waitvite as a as a connection
Professor thank you very much for your
time today you are welcome