[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined on this episode by rhys cohen
rhys is delivered a number of uh
consulting projects for a lot of the
australia's leading cannabis companies
had his own previous consulting agency
he is now the senior corporate
communications manager at the massive
cam group and he also sits on the
non-executive advisory board of the
lambert initiative for caterpillar
therapeutics at the university of sydney
and also the editor of large was
previously leader of large of cannabis
er australia's largest b2b industry
magazine how are you keeping reese
i'm grand thanks yeah it's um a
beautiful afternoon here in melbourne
delighted to have you on made it's a
lovely sunny morning here in dublin so
glad that our times was able to come
together and can you maybe give
everybody a a quick little overview of
how do you got to the position you are
in the cannabis industry and maybe your
dissertation that you did in the sector
sure um i've actually done a couple
funnily enough so i got started in
cannabis in 2015 i did my honours thesis
in the politics and economics of
cannabis legalization with a focus on
colorado at the time
medicinal cannabis got legalized in
australia just a few months after i
finished my degree so i started calling
myself a consultant and built myself a
website and sort of went from there i've
had a few uh uh different incarnations
over the last few years as you mentioned
i i i am on the non-executive advisory
board of the lambda initiative i also
used to work there for about a year and
a half or two
in a sort of project management capacity
i've uh also previously run fresh leaf
analytics which is australia's most
prominent sort of market intelligence
company for the medicinal cannabis
industry i spent some time working with
martin at cannabis and i was very sad to
see him go and recently as a few weeks
ago i've i've joined uh can group as
their senior corporate communications
manager so uh talking and writing and
working on a bit of commercial strategy
as well that's kind of the
overview perfect so a complete in-depth
knowledge you seem to have of australia
the topics i wanted to talk to you today
about first and foremost was the
politics and economics of cannabis in
terms of the politics in australia did
you find that the right-wing side or the
of the government were against the
legalization of cannabis and it was the
democrats in the greens shall we say
driving the initiative forward and do
you see that as a is that the same
template that you see around the world
are you starting to see the right
leaning parties swing into the cannabis
industry a lot more
it's interesting i mean clearly that's
very different conversations to be had
about medicinal versus non-medicinal
cannabis and the politics around that so
medical cannabis was legalized in
australia under a conservative
government in 2016.
but it had unanimous political support
from
every party of every political spectrum
no one in australia who's in politics
disagrees with the legalization of
medicinal cannabis obviously there's
some dispute about how exactly it should
work in practice but it has
comprehensive support and that's
reflected in the general population as
well probably up around 85 90 of the
australians support medicinal cannabis
when we're talking about non-medical
cannabis popular support is closer to 50
of australians think that cannabis
should be legalized for non-medical
purposes but once again it depends how
you how you ask the questions in the
surveys so to speak
and at the moment neither major party uh
supports any change to cannabis policy
and it is like you say the parties uh
further to the left the greens and and
the reason party and other left-wing
parties that support such a move as well
as the hardcore libertarians which we
tend to associate more with the right
wing of politics and that sort of
weird coalition of
left-wing far left-wing politics and and
hardcore libertarians is something that
we see in many other places around the
world you know particular colorado and
many u.s states as well there's been an
unholy marriage of those political
forces that have pushed through
non-medical legalization um
but it's not uh you know further
cannabis law reform in australia is not
really a topic a big topic of
conversation although we had our federal
elections uh over the weekend and it was
encouraging and or interesting at least
to see that the legalized cannabis party
at grassroots movements with no real
sort of resources to put into
campaigning uh managed to get nearly
seven percent of the senate vote in the
state of queensland and between two and
four percent of the senate vote in our
other states and territories as well so
um it's maybe becoming more of a
political issue but we'll have to wait
and see
okay so seven percent would have to be a
a good chunk of change of voters that
would actually go out of their way to to
give their number one vote to a party
dedicated specifically just cannabis
legalization
yeah it's pretty significant and
what was interesting to me in particular
was that
it it was queensland was the standout
state and what we know about queensland
with regards to cannabis is that about
50 of all of the approvals to prescribe
medicinal cannabis in australia are
currently issued by prescribers based in
queensland so we're not quite sure if
that also correlates to patients because
people get prescribed across straight
lines and that's becoming more and more
common and we don't really know where
the patients are but the prescribers and
the clinic networks and the pharmacy
networks that they are that they work
within are based in queensland so
something's in the water
okay so basically in terms of the
medical industry you've got let's say 70
80 favorability but when it gets down to
recreational it seems to be around that
50 mark seems to be the kind of magic
number worldwide where it was new
zealand's uh legislation that they had
it would be the same over in europe to a
degree and do you see that number
shifting with the the economics that the
medical industry is providing for
australia are they starting to see a
little bit of uh income come into the
government where they're like actually
hold on a minute we'd like 5x or 8x this
kind of revenue for our tax covers
potentially i mean look at the medical
industry is growing really rapidly you
know best estimates suggest that last
year the industry made maybe 200 million
dollars worth of revenue
this year it'll probably at least double
so the money's coming in whether that is
what's changing people's hearts and
minds i'm not so sure about if you look
at popular support for non-medical
legalization over time it has increased
you know a couple of percentage points
every year for many years
so
that which you know predates medical
legalization so maybe it has more to do
with the reduction in stigma and the
normalization of cannabis um
uh instead yeah
more so than people seeing uh dollar
signs in their eyes because you know
there is an opportunity here there's a
commercial opportunity but it's it's not
easy work and it's not you know
enormously profitable right off the bat
yeah i think the r d that needs to be
put into this industry uh
will scare a lot of companies away when
you see the kind of capital how
extensive it is how quickly the cash
burn rate can be in some of these
companies
yeah it gets pretty real pretty quick so
you know can group that i'm now part of
you know we're we're we've just finished
the first stage of a really massive
construction project for our sort of
vertically integrated cultivation and
manufacturing facility in australia and
the cost of that's i think somewhere
around 120 million at the moment you
know we also just uh earlier this year
launched a full
phase three placebo controlled
randomized clinical trial to investigate
our proprietary
cbd capsule product to investigate
whether it can help people with sleep
disturbance and which obviously we're
trying to get that into the
over-the-counter cbd uh channel in
australia so you know if you only took
those two expenses uh that'd be more
than most cannabis companies are
prepared to put into anything and then
of course there's all the money that
we've spent over the years on um staff
you know r d um developing new um new
genetic lines and our cultivars et
cetera et cetera so it's not it's not
for the faint of heart
yeah well i think if you have the
overview of the industry that's the one
place australia you can see is the
genetics and look and the specific uh
seed types that you guys can create and
then export all over the world is going
to be the money maker i think from that
territory i think i think i think well
yeah two places where i think will play
really well one is at the plant end of
the spectrum like you say because
australia you know we're
we're a banana republic you know all we
do is is dig up and send and send out
coal and we do primary produce really
well so you know wheat cotton rice we
put as a country a lot of money and a
lot of focus over a lot of years into
improving um
those sorts of crops and so we have this
great
r d machinery that can now be put
towards
cannabis and the cannabis plant itself
so we're really accelerating some
progress there in some really exciting
ways so that's the first one and the
second one would be at the pointy end at
the clinical end because we do punch
above our weight globally in terms of um
in terms of clinical trials in
particular it's comparatively quite
quick and easy to conduct clinical
trials in australia compared to the us
or europe and our regulatory standards
for therapeutic goods and for clinical
research are at a level where um you
know it's uh it's not like doing a
clinical trial in in um uh like in a
country whom i won't disparage as an
example but you know we are comparable
in terms of the quality of research that
we do with uh with um north america and
europe
amazing the next topic i wanted to jump
onto is industry analysis now i know
you've got a lot of expertise in this
can you maybe give everybody let's say
two good sources that you think are uh
places where you can see good
interesting analysis because as we
talked just before coming on there's a
lot of places that are just literally
seem to be making up numbers to tell
each other how great this industry could
possibly be whereas a real financial
breakdown analysis of some of these
sectors would not deliver the numbers
that some of these guys are producing
yeah i guess it depends what you mean by
industry analysis and which industry so
like in australia for example
there are very few sources of
information one
um has been fresh leaf analytics the
other i would say in terms of cannabis
coverage would be cannabis
i think they do exceptional coverage
obviously i would say that i'm
conflicted but i really recommend that
you check them out um what i'm excited
about
actually is more mainstream pharma
business intelligence companies
starting to service medicinal cannabis
companies so we're seeing that now like
you know companies that have been set up
they've been monitoring
say for example retail sales of
medicines through pharmacies in
australia for
big pharma companies in order to provide
them with insights they're now also
capturing information on medicinal
cannabis products and you know it's a
classic cannabis thing right to to
assume that you need to build a cannabis
specific solution for a problem from the
ground up well in actual fact people are
doing this sort of stuff all the time
already for other industries and there's
an opportunity to piggyback off it
globally though i would say you know mj
biz obviously
and
i think prohibition partners have been
getting a lot better um but
but the challenge is
you know all forecasts are wrong some
forecasts are
useful
this this industry is still really a uh
you know uh how long's a piece of string
operation so i i try as best i can and
avoid forecasting out any longer term
than 12 months you know
yeah no i agree i think the golf or the
campus industry is almost like a golf
shot at the moment you can think you're
going to hit the same shot it might look
like the exact same shot but the chances
have you been able to replicate the
exact same shot over and over again
pretty much
but as a general piece of advice i'd say
like the the the more i the the sources
and the forecasts that i trust the most
are the ones that are the most
transparent and the most comprehensive
in uh disclosing their methodology
you know you can have a a wild forecast
that's you know out of left field maybe
it's too conservative or people think
it's too ambitious but so long as you've
got your methodology and you're explicit
about it
people can argue with the methodology um
and that's a fine argument to have
arguing with the end number is kind of
pointless unless you're actually talking
about
the nuts and bolts
yeah i agree with you and last topic
before i let you go i just wanted to get
a quick little overview of everybody of
australia that some people who might not
know the industry and understand it it's
medical only now recreational a couple
of the leading companies that you see do
you see europe being an actual realistic
market for australian companies because
we see little green farm up in denmark
at the moment some supply the german
industry but at the same time we've got
all the canadian companies supplying the
german industry and not to not to burst
our bubble but there's going to be
german companies who are going to supply
the german industry so how do you see
that playing out
yeah totally i mean look we we've got
our own situation here at the moment in
terms of oversupply
you know there's uh over 300 products
that are available to be prescribed in
australia at the moment most of those
are imported from overseas many of those
are of questionable uh quality and
compliance standards what i'm really
excited about is earlier this year the
australian government
implemented new rules they'll go into
effect
in about 12 months time
but
from june
next year we are going to require all
products that are imported to australia
to be manufactured to the same quality
standards as products that are made here
and australia is um a signatory to the
um to the international sort of gmp uh
the pigs pensions so you know we have
mutual recognition agreements in place
with germany for example any medicinal
cannabis product that's made in
australia um you know is already uh head
and shoulders above
any product that's been manufactured uh
in a gpp facility or in a gmp facility
in a non-mra country um so we will
have our you know we have a shot at at
exports and at servicing the
international market
we'll need more than just germany and
germany's medical market to sustain just
the australian companies that are
exporting um but you know as we see more
countries opening up and markets
continue to grow i think
you know the future of the industry is
pretty strong
um
and australia is part of that i think
we're you know outside of north america
there's australia germany and israel are
the only meaningful markets for medical
prescription medicinal cannabis access
globally and then of course there's all
of the cbd stuff going on in the uk um
which is a bit of a different kettle of
fish
yeah it's going to be an interesting
couple years now to see how all the
pieces fall on the cards um it's been an
absolute pleasure talking to you for
anybody who wants to follow reese go to
rhys cohen on twitter at whis cohen and
if you want to know anything about the
can group the website is below there for
a buddy to check out all the details
will be in the
subscription and thank you very much for
taking your time to talk to us today
it's been very informative nathan i hope
you have a great rest of your day my
pleasure thanks so much thanks everybody
until next time