[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review we're going to be
talking all things investing about u.s
canadian and european on this episode
and i'm delighted to be joined this
episode boy one of the top influencers
on social media and twitter and retail
investing at the moment roger aka puff
daddy how are you keeping roger you well
oh i'm well i'm doing well here in
canada enjoying the weather finally
we're out of the snow so yes uh things
are looking up in canada here so
happy to join you
great to have you on the show so i've
been uh following you on twitter and
going through some of the red redder
devices and you guys seem to be uh one
of the top sources of information when
it comes to the industry outside of the
media organization so i thought what
better than to get you on and kind of
help educate everybody while we can so
i'm going to maybe jump straight into
the first topic and if you could give
everybody a little overview of the
what's an american msl versus canadian
mso and why are uh why would you take a
position on one of the other
yeah so we'll start with uh canada um
that's basically where i started uh
my investing in the cannabis space back
in 2015.
in canada we
announced in 2017 that
cannabis was going to be legal in in
canada and
a huge huge opportunity for investing
we had companies such as canopy growth
aurora cannabis
[Music]
hexo t god
um
afria
um tilray
all all
large uh canadian names and there is
quite a bit of excitement going into
legalization
um
the
back then the the big thing that was
driving uh
stock prices especially in the canadian
space was
uh licensing
and build outs so it seemed like every
time that
canopy or aurora or tilray announced an
acquisition
or expansion of their cultivation or
a new million square foot cultivation
center
the stock prices seem to really really
take notice and jump up in price
unfortunately what happened when the day
actually of recreation happened
there weren't enough retailers out in
the space to actually sell the product
so we had an abundance of plant and and
flour to sell
but the market because we had not enough
retail especially in our larger
provinces such as quebec and ontario
made things really really tough
initially on on the large
canadian lps
and ever since then they've been
struggling to to get that supply demand
equilibrium
[Music]
at a right point and we've seen a lot of
closures now with the canadian lps with
the amount of cultivation that we had
just too much supply
um the demand is there
but uh the amount of supply that we had
in canada so
back in 2018 um the us
name started popping up on on stock
exchanges like the csc and the otc
now obviously it was the beginning
stages there were some some states that
were recreational such as california
um colorado
that uh had huge markets but there's
lots of opportunities in the medical
space
certain states had medical programs some
states had medical and recreation
programs and that's where
i thought it was a good time to
transition from the canadian names
to the us names so that's when i really
started to change my focus to us msos
yeah it seems interesting from the
outside it seems with canada that
the way to move your stock price is
basically growth that if there's no
consumers to buy your product then it's
acquisitions of
facilities or growth of facilities where
i think america seems to be complete
opposite where there's a huge consumer
base ready there and i think it's about
getting the product to those consumers
as opposed to the flip side of canada
yeah and and like canada was a different
bird in the fact that
basically you had all these licenses and
cultivation licenses
awarded before the program started and
so you had this massive buildup of like
i say cultivation but you didn't even
really know what your market was going
to be in canada
and
at that time the the canadian lps were
being handsomely rewarded with
you know uh straight up arrow uh stock
price moves of like 20 30 percent a day
i mean that was the golden age of
cannabis where you know an announcement
of an mna deal
between two companies for three billion
dollars uh you know companies like
canopy would go up like thirty percent
forty percent in a day
um and that seemed to really really be
the talk of the town uh back in 2017
excuse me
so
uh in the us it's a lot different
because
it's a lot more restrictive especially
when it comes to medical licensing
there's typically limited amount of
retail licenses awarded uh typically
limited amount of cultivation licenses
awarded so it kind of keeps in check
um the amount of retail
and and the amount of cultivation
available so typically that that helps
keep keeping prices
pricing a bit stronger
longer term now eventually supply will
catch up to that demand and you will see
a little bit compression on pricing
but then there's the opportunity for
some of these
medical markets to turn recreational and
then you're opening it up to a whole new
consumer base so
it's very interesting it's very complex
still in the states and obviously we've
seen the last
14 15 months
some price compression uh in the us
and i think that's mainly due or a lot
of us feel that a lot of that's coming
from the lack of federal um
legislation or
or help by the the federal government
especially the democrats to get anything
uh done to uh to move uh
move the industry along so
yeah do you tell me is the big thing
between them the access to capital do
you think is that the the site bank
connect is the hindrance because one of
the next topics i want to talk about was
the m a activity and i've been kind of
wondering is the access to capital in
canada going to allow for those
companies to do mergers and acquisitions
in the us space and take their footprint
via that model or do you think the
the likes of new york legalizing now
with everything on sale from september
the capital markets are generally in new
york and you'll get access to capital if
you're a company based on that uh
territory
yeah so like when it comes to safe
banking and access to capital i think
uh
you know you've got almost two different
two different things going on in the us
you have your top msos we call them tier
ones your your top say five
uh msos from cure leaf uh green thumb
uh truly cresco labs uh verano and you
can even add another company or two in
the in the mix but typically those
companies
their access to capital they seem to be
you know
able to to
you know raise money through debt or
if they wanted to do uh shares but at
this point because the share prices have
been compressed a lot of them have
issued debt debt and they're getting
rates around eight percent um if if safe
banking was was uh available chances are
the rates would have been a a little bit
lower than that could have been you know
four or five percent at the time
but
those companies aren't struggling for
capital i think where you're seeing the
the big uh issue is when you start
talking about social equity
licensing and smaller business when they
don't have access to loans from banks to
you know start a dispensary or open up a
store it makes things really tough and
even if they do have access the rates
that they're paying are a lot more than
the top
uh tier uh us msos at eight percent you
i've seen
i've seen companies that have been
getting like 25
which is almost loan shark pricing
so and that's and that and that's if you
can even access that uh type of capital
so
um yeah
there is a bit of a
divergence but i mean
still being listed on the otc and cse
has given uh the publicly traded msos
access to
capital that's allowed them to expand
quite a bit over the last two three
years
very interesting next topic i wanted to
talk to you about is your market
position have you looked at all in terms
of the european sector obviously you
probably know about germany legalizing
over here or is it still a couple of
years away for retail investors like
yourself to be taking positions in
european companies yeah obviously uh
with the announcement in germany that
opened a lot of eyes um
i i have looked into the the european
market i think it's still a little bit
early not saying that getting in a
position now
um depending on your your timeline right
like if you're looking
two to five years down the line getting
it getting uh starting a position now
certainly uh
um
might be
prudent considering like you say the
germany situation because i think
as germany goes you'll see other just
like in the us you'll see
you know gradually you'll see
different states and and in europe
you're going to see different countries
follow probably germany israel um going
forward expanding those those markets
and it's a huge opportunity
yeah now i agree do you think
that some of these
american msls are going to have their
way
would you guys forecast with growth in
europe into your investment or you guys
strategically focus look if we make x
return across full legalization
federalization in america that's enough
for our position to make sense anything
after that is going to be a bonus
yeah i mean right now i think that
for me anyways or my investment thesis
is that the u.s market is still you know
in its emphasis and has a long ways to
go to maturity and uh i think
you know we're talking like rhode island
just announced they're the 19th state to
uh go recreational in the in the
um i think there's going to be large
opportunities and and and places like
florida to go recreational
um you know two three years down the
line pennsylvania could be fairly close
in in in the next year or two
um so
for me right now my focus is still on
the u.s there are some canadian lps and
also
companies like cure leaf
that have
um some european um
assets and and uh
are starting to expand or or
focus a little bit more on europe but i
think right now because the market's
still um
you know
the announcement with germany i'm not
exactly sure a hundred percent
um how quickly
uh that's gonna
take a place and then what kind of rules
and regulations they're going to have
so they came back the other day saying
that the new minister for health is
going to rush it through this year he
came back last week saying that he's
going to try and push this through and
have something ready for the start of
2023. and and that would be and that's
great but
two when it comes to something like that
the amount of time it takes to build a
cultivation facility and then on top of
that like you have to get all your ducks
in a row when it comes to environmental
reviews and permitting and stuff like
that and then on top of that once you
finally get your facility built it could
take three to six months before you'll
have an effect you know a product that
you can sell to the consumers so it's
great and i know there's existing
facilities already but
if it happens like that eventually the
businesses will catch up but it'll take
some time right that's a lot of capital
that's going to be required to build
those facilities and i'm sure there's
lots of money available whether it's
private companies
um to take the the opportunity forward
but uh yeah that's great like you say
the the quicker the better and and
that's some of the problem we see with
the u.s market is that
um politicians don't do what's best for
the constituents that they
um that they're leaders for and
sometimes delay things and and and uh
and it ends up just making it very
cumbersome like new jersey had probably
four to five month delay when they were
supposed to start wrecking and that had
an impact on a lot of companies that had
ramped up production
uh ex with the expectation of uh of
sales probably you know january february
2022 and ended up being you know may
before they got the
got to open some stores so
but yeah it's an exciting time for sure
and i think it's there's a long way to
go especially like you say uh europe's
probably you know the dominoes will fall
just like in uh in the us when it comes
to individual states so
yeah well i think you and i by you see
the same there's going to be a couple of
dominant brands in about 10 years time
that'll have merged and that was uh
acquired pretty much everything out
there and it's whether you've got your
dollars behind the coca-cola of this
industry or the mcdonald's or whatever
the large-scale operators may be it's
going to be an interesting ride to see
who that ends up being
yeah for sure and like you say uh um the
brands and and companies like i think
the news in germany definitely opened
some eyes and i i wouldn't be surprised
if you do see maybe a few american
companies
uh start to focus a little bit more on
what's going on
on europe you know there is an abundance
of opportunities still in the in the us
that it's early stages but uh
yeah europe could be a huge opportunity
and obviously a country the size of
germany going uh going recreational i'll
probably really start kickstarting the
uh the cannabis craze and uh in europe
so
yeah i look forward to it very much
we've just come up to our time there i
want to thank you very much for joining
us anybody who isn't following puff
daddy junior on twitter i highly
recommend it there's also a great large
reddit group that talk about uh us msos
and canadian msl and again another great
source of information thank you very
much for your time today mate
yeah no problem thanks for having me
thanks everybody chat your next episode
[Music]