foreign
cannabis review I'm delighted to be
joined on this episode by Andy Mansfield
who's the managing director at EU Canada
jobs how you keeping today Andy I'm
doing great how are you doing Ellie I'm
fantastic thank you very much for taking
your time to do this I know you're a
busy man just back from Mary Jane can
you maybe give everybody a little
overview of why you guys set up EU kind
of jobs in your position in the industry
up to date
yeah be glad to so we started eukana
jobs because we noticed a couple of
years ago that it was really difficult
to find talent in the industry we were
working on a separate uh cannabis
project here in Europe and we're looking
for staff and just found it difficult so
we ended up having to go through indeed
in other places like that and you know
it just didn't work
um the the talent was you know spread
out all over the place and then when we
tried listing jobs uh also it was not
really working finding people uh that
that were familiar with cannabis and
um yeah just decided that that needed to
be changed we also know that or knew
from back in the U.S that there are a
lot of different types of cannabis
specific or cannabis industry specific
jobs platforms there they seem to work
really well
um and so we decided that that was a
good way to go here and just try and
help the industry and help individuals
trying to get into the industry
yeah it seems to be an opportune time
that you guys have set up with the
industry grow and that the rate it's
going to grow over the next five to ten
years and hiring Talent is is a
specialty in any industry whether it's
cannabis or not can you maybe uh give
everybody an overview when it comes to
searching for cannabis jobs in Europe
how do you guys partner up with the
various Brands and how do you guys find
the employees looking to find these jobs
yeah so you know initially for
partnering up with the companies it was
good old-fashioned uh you know sales
calls reaching out to the companies
explaining what we're doing and we're
lucky to find some big companies and a
lot of small companies who are
interested in partnering with us early
on now of course at Mary Jane we found a
lot more companies that want to join the
platform but for the company that was
just you know reaching out explaining
what we're doing and and if uh for the
most part almost everyone said yeah we
definitely need something like that
which also helped encourage us to keep
pushing forward uh which you know
sometimes it can be when you face
challenges it's always easy to want to
give up it's a matter of just you know
seeing the vision and pushing forward
the uh finding the candidates is of
course a little bit more challenging you
know you can't just reach out to the
hundreds of companies or reach out to
candidates like we do to the hundreds of
companies so we're using social media
um you know whether it be through the
meta platforms or LinkedIn
and also going to
um events like Mary Jane we've been to
several others over the last year so to
really just reach those people who are
at these events since they're obviously
interested in the industry
um Mary Jane it was interesting to see
how many candidates or potential
candidates were like oh this is a great
idea or I can work in the Cannabis
industry and very surprised it's like
well of course they need workers it
doesn't come from any from nowhere so uh
very good response and so we're
continuing with just the social media
strategy trying to reach out and get the
word out to those candidates
I could imagine the amount of interest
that there would be from regular people
just wanting to get jobs in this
industry especially if you've got to
look for cannabis already when it comes
to the current jobs that are around at
the moment does it seem to be marketing
and cultivation or kind of at the
Forefront of this at the moment or as a
business development and advertising
what are you seeing as the most popular
jobs currently in the industry because
the the runway for growth is not exactly
clear yet for a lot of companies so what
do you see is the most advantageous
route for people to get into this
industry right now
yeah so you know the three top uh kind
of categories that we're seeing right
now are Marketing sales and I.T
um which kind of makes sense you know
obviously I.T is involved in everything
nowadays and Marketing sales you know
regardless of what your product is
um if you're not selling it we're
getting people interested in it then
there's no point being in business so
those are the three biggest categories
uh cultivation is actually fairly fairly
small part of it uh which also kind of
makes sense
um so but in the end it's really
important that people just see what
they're interested in
um you know and not necessarily say well
there's a lot of marketing so now I need
to become an expert in marketing and
change what my interest is with any
career it's really important to think
about what you want to do and then try
and see if that what your interests are
fits with the jobs that are out there
um you know for a lot of people who are
just starting off you know maybe they're
young and maybe they're still in school
a good way to go is by doing internships
so that they can actually go work at
some of these companies and uh get to
learn a little bit more about the
business and then they might be able to
find uh they're their path in the
industry that way because you know a lot
of times we just don't know exactly what
we want to do until we start
kind of doing things and then we kind of
find our way
and is there a certain territory out at
the moment that is kind of posting a lot
of the main jobs is it Germany or are
there other territories around Europe
and what do you see like let's say in
the next five years has been the most
advantageous territory
yeah right now definitely the majority
of the jobs are in Germany Germany
currently has the biggest Medical Market
um all the medical markets of course
have their issues with patient access
and insurance reimbursement so there's
always issues in and they're different
in each country but Germany still has
the biggest medical market right now so
it's the it's where the most jobs are
um that would probably continue uh over
the next five years or so Germany is
kind of pushing the legalization uh
envelope right now the most and they
expect to have cannabis Social Clubs and
home growing in the next year or two and
after that also have different types of
um research projects they're calling
them where you'll be able to have
legalized sales in individual cities how
those details will work that no one
knows right now but the point being
Germany's probably going to continue to
be the most uh the biggest Market
um as other countries like the Czech
Republic are looking at legalization of
course those types of things can change
the Dynamics very quickly if the Czech
Republic were to do full legalization
before driver then of course that's
going to increase jobs there
dramatically but you also have you know
Portugal Spain France the UK everyone's
discussing it all the bigger countries
and smaller countries are discussing
different types of legalization Pathways
and all that can change with politics so
quickly so you know what what who will
really be the biggest Mark in five or
ten years we can't really say
for now looks like it's going to be
Germany when it comes to the job Zone do
you see the UK as being a bit of an
outlier with brexit happening I would
imagine that the X-ray
certification or the extra immigration
level that's going to be involved for
employees let's say if you're in the
European continent going to the UK and
surely being taxed and all the other
different hurdles that are coming to
fruition from brexit do you see the UK
as one of the markets that's actually
going to be lacking when it comes to
people applying for jobs because if
there's an option between Portugal and
Spain and the UK I think you're going to
have a lot of people choosing the
European continent
yeah I mean I think there's two sides to
that you know on the one side
um sure if you know if someone's in
Czech Republic or Germany and they see a
grow a grow opportunity or whatever type
of uh you know uh career opportunity in
Portugal it's super easy for them to
just go down there and start working so
for the European continent that's going
to be easier but what it does allow the
the advantage for the UK might be that
everyone in the UK then uh kind of their
jobs are somewhat protected because it's
more difficult for someone from the
European continent to come over uh and
and take those jobs so and you know that
was part of the brexit argument I think
all along so in some sense that might
actually help the UK Market develop on
its own and be a little bit more
self-sufficient and stronger
um and the UK is you know it does have a
medical Market already and they're
working on their different uh are having
their discussions about what
legalization could potentially look like
um
but it's really difficult to say once
again it all depends on those politics
and what really happens with with those
legalization discussions if the UK works
with somehow all sudden due legalization
then the market would explode there
um and you would probably see a lot of
people trying to move over there to be a
part of that
yeah I don't think with the politicians
currently in the UK that there's any
sign of legalization coming in the next
World I agree when it comes when it
comes to the certain territories around
Europe one of the things we see in
Ireland that Ireland is very well
positioned for is being the entry point
into Europe and offering services such
as law and finance and Taxation you've
obviously then got the likes of Portugal
and Spain you've got the climate for
cultivation and then you've obviously
got places to like North Macedonia and
Romania doing extraction and other areas
do you see the Europe is going to be
broken up into those little segments
where this territory excels at this and
this territory excels at that and it all
then gets moved around Europe or do you
see each individual territory having
their own extraction their own
cultivation their own finance and what
is your outlook on the European uh
industry when it comes to those
segmentations
yeah I think in the short run you're
going to see individual countries kind
of like you have the US with individual
states having to do it have their own
Industries I think you're going to see
that in the short term in Europe too
because right now
um for medical purposes you can do
Import and Export but when for a
recreational purposes you're not going
to be able to do any type of import
export it looks like based on the
current uh EU regulations and and the
way the EU is is kind of sticking to
those regulations I think in the long
term medium to long term five to ten
years you're going to see those
regulations be changed or
reinterpreted or something to where
you're going to see regular import
export between the countries even for
recreational purposes
um but until we get to that point
probably you're going to see a lot of uh
industry homegrown type Industries for
at least for the recreational side of it
and when it comes to the Homegrown side
of things we look in Europe it seems to
be breaking into a pretty clear and
concise industry that pharmaceutical and
biotech are going to be taking care of
drug development and potential
ingredients for cosmetics and beauty and
various other things and then you're
going to have a homegirl Rule and the
Cannabis Social Club model do you see
the the the cultivation expertise in
Europe being able to grow from one of
the benefits of the homegirl Rule and
the the social club model or do you
think that the likes of low-cost flower
from Colombia and other destinations are
still going to be imported into you
yeah I mean I think that's really hard
to say you already have Imports
happening from all over the world into
the EU uh fully legally you know through
some a few different uh Distributors
importers uh who kind of found some
interesting uh
ways to interpret the the import rules
uh and that's that's a benefit but I
think in the long term
um you're going to see people watching
uh certain quality and also people many
times prefer something that's more
locally grown
um you know whether it be for
environmental reasons or uh
nationalistic or Pride reasons you know
they want something that was grown here
at home so you always have some imports
but I think there's always going to be
room for good quality products grown
right here in Europe
yeah I think kind of it Canada seems to
be a good model that not everybody wants
the low-cost huge MSO production of
cannabis they the the small cultivars
and the craft Growers seem to be taking
a large market share there and I would
imagine that if you live in France or
you live in Ireland or you live in
Germany or Czech Republic that they're
going to be a little bit of national
pride towards choosing the product that
gets made in your own individual country
exactly and you saw that you know uh you
saw that with craft beer craft
distilleries and all these other type
these other Industries where you you
always have the big players who have a
huge part of the market share but
there's room for those smaller Growers
or smaller suppliers for those products
where uh you know like you said it's
quality it's interesting cultivars it's
it's
playing on the national pride different
things like that there will always be
room for that
um and I think you'll see that also with
cannabis here like you said you're
seeing it in Canada and the US now
already and I think
um you know it took a long time for the
craft beer and craft Distillery
Industries to develop from the bigger
Industries but I think with cannabis
you're seeing that kind of accelerated
much more quickly just because of the
um you know the pre the other industries
that have already kind of spawned those
types of craft movements yeah now I know
you're a very busy man so one last
question before we go what are you
looking forward to seeing the most
happen in Europe over the next 18 to 24
months is there one thing that you think
will be a domino effect or is there one
personal thing that you would love to
see happen
either if we could see uh the
legalization in Germany uh continue
forward
um and I think that's going to be
through the uh you know the individual
cities doing research projects if that
could get kind of ironed out uh
including which I think is going to be
extremely important having the import uh
allowed somehow for these research
projects which should be allowed under
the current rules that I think you will
see a huge development of of those
individual City Markets and that will of
course then I think really start to
change the public perception
um of of cannabis even for recreational
purposes and we'll show people just like
it did in the US and Canada that it is
not evil uh the recreational uh or
legalization for adult use is not going
to bring all these horrible uh
consequences and actually brings a lot
of positive consequences so hopefully
that can get kind of uh reported
somewhat in the next 18 to 24 months and
and start to see some data come out of
that to start changing uh public opinion
further and political opinion in the
right direction
Andy it's been actually great to happen
to you hopefully we can touch base
towards the end of the year and we've
got a some sort of advancement in the EU
for any company or employee who's
looking to get into the industry I
highly recommend going to EU cannabis
jobs find them on our social media on
LinkedIn and on Twitter and give them a
follow because they're going to be at
the Forefront of employment in this
multi-billion dollar industry over the
common future Andy thank you very much
for now mate and I hope you have a great
day thanks for the pleasure and we'll
we'll talk soon have a great day until
next episode everybody
good
thanks Emil and Andy mate much
appreciated yeah that was great I think
that went well um appreciate it and have
a great great day yeah YouTube okay see
you
oh wait you're muted