[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I'm delighted to be
joined to this episode by Tim Daly who's
the CEO at True Green Green Global over
at America smart packaging technology
company how you keeping today Tim all is
well thank you very much and happy New
Year to you thanks for having me on
thank you very much I'm delighted to
have you on you guys are one of the hot
new companies in the American industry
at the moment can you maybe give
everybody a little overview of your
history and business to dat and how you
ended up a True Green Global absolutely
and and thank you for that introduction
that's fabulous so uh my my career has
been spent in uh iot so in create
creating smart objects smart rooms
typically to add value so the the
typically use case is supply chain So
digitizing Physical objects digitizing
physical rooms to track things as they
move through so essentially moving
terrestrial data sets into the digital
into the into the cloud for Value
whether it be knowing where things are
so you can do accurate instantaneous
inventory counts cycle counts or
creating intelligent objects that know
exactly who they are where they are uh
and can prevent provide some sort of uh
value for an end user so uh use cases
like authentication tamper detection
open close messages
Etc okay interesting and moving on to
True Green Global in terms of the supply
chain where it is do you see the True
Green Global adds value to the supply
chain so what what's interesting in
cannabis it's it's truly a broken
industry um it's a asent industry in the
United States and unlike traditional
Industries manufacturing government
retail globally that use best practices
in supply chain cannabis is an area that
where the supply chain is effectively
broken it's currently an analog process
so you have individuals touching every
item scanning them with a barcode reader
putting them down and touching the next
one so in an industry that's highly
regulated like cannabis where there's
requirement to do individual unit counts
cycle counts Etc either on a daily
monthly uh or quarterly basis when you
have the human element involved there's
going to be errors there's going to be
it's expensive
uh there's significant amount of Errors
so it's a simple matter to take the best
practices of supply chain that are used
globally and bring them into an industry
I.E cannabis that darely needs them so
it creates incredible efficiencies saves
time saves money reduces all those
errors and helps keep businesses
compliant with the regulatory
requirements and from my research as
well I seem you guys are adding value at
the payments side of things can you
elaborate a little bit on that for the
audience so that and thanks for bringing
that up that's an exciting area we've
been we've uh recently acquired a
company that uh had over the last three
years built out a hyperledger fabric
payment solution and this solution was
specifically built for the Cannabis
industry so as I mentioned a minute ago
the supply chain side has been broken in
cannabis uh the payment side as well is
broken there in the United States so
there's truly no effective legal
efficient lowcost payment solution
available uh of course part of this goes
to the fact that cannabis is currently a
scheduled and illegal substance at the
federal level um but there just are no
Payment Solutions there's ATM Solutions
they're expensive They Don't Really Work
Well and they're skating the skating on
the edge of legality so the other thing
that uh to on the other side that we
brought of course is the payment side
and so we've purchased this company uh
they are the first block stable coin
blockchain payment solution that instead
of skirting the SEC in the United States
they went directly to the SEC about
three years ago worked with the
SEC uh to prove that this solution is a
is truly a um security and that is
should be registered and and and
regulated by the SEC so this solution is
the first
Global approved SEC stable coin payment
solution and in the most simplistic
sense because everything I just said is
is very technical and confusing but
suffice to say we are rolling out in the
first quarter of this year within the
United States a Starbucks Starbucks app
like payment solution for cannabis so uh
download your Starbucks app you uh
answer some basic questions because this
is an SC register security you've got to
answer the know your customer rule
anti-money laundering Rule and then once
that's done you'll connect your bank
account to the app you'll upload let's
say $100 like you would in Starbucks
that $100 is directly deposited into US
money market account you'll walk into
your dispensary make your purchase
you'll show your phone the bud tender
will scan the phone it'll remove from
your wallet those dollars for your
purchase and all is good with the world
and this is all done using an SEC
approved patented stable coin
platform yeah I think the key word from
that there you said is Solutions the
more I researched into the company the
more it is that you guys are actually
providing poor and key key solutions for
businesses across the the Cannabis
industry I wanted to move now on to the
smart packaging side of things and the
technology behind it most people might
have heard of nearfield communication
but the ultra high frequency radio
frequency identification can you maybe
elaborate on what is behind the
technology so everybody could understand
sure yeah so UHF ultra high frequency
RFID is the global standard for
digitizing individual objects and then
tracking them throughout the supply
chain so RFID uh it's well seen and well
used across all the US in retail and I
think one of the real good examples of
that would be the large retailer wall
Walmart so Walmart requires that every
product that is shipped into Walmart
with the exception of grocery items has
to have an RFID tag on that and the
purpose is it allows for simple
frictionless intaking of objects so you
use an RFID scanner you scan it it sees
every individual object in there
immediately connects that to their point
of sale uh and inventory systems those
products are then moved into some sort
of inventory room in the back uh the
there could be fixed readers that scan
the room automatically every second or
so and see all of the objects there and
then can reconcile that immediately with
what's supposed to be there so we know
what's supposed to be where we know
exactly where it is and when then those
objects move from the inventory room
onto the onto the floor of the actual
retailer we can see as they move from
here onto the floor and so we know where
things are at all times it provides
incredible business intelligence it it
it reduces things like product stockouts
uh it reduces things like over
inventorying so you don't have to tie up
all your money in inventory you can be
incredibly efficient with what you have
and knowing where it is at all times so
that yeah effectively is a global global
standard for digitizing objects you know
it is incredible and it seems that you
guys offer complete Security in the
supply chain which is lacking to a
degree in a number of states and uh
somewhat in Canada as well yes yeah you
know it's it's interesting so we're
we're operational in a number of big
states in the United States
and you know I've always said that you
can have a business that is regulated or
is the the the states mandate your
business and that's great um however
what our approach has always been that
we need to to grow organically we need
to be able to go to operators whether
it's a producer whether it's a
dispensary or a vertically integrated
SSO or MSO and we have to truly add
value it's to save the money uh keep
them complying Etc and and that's what
we've done our our customers are find
finding huge savings incredible
efficiencies and what was nice is in
Maryland the other day um one of the the
officers who performed the regular
audits came in and saw our solution in
place and they were extraordinarily
excited so they took samples back and
they want to try to propose that that
type of solution be mandated for for all
producers and dispensaries in the state
and it makes sense um it creates
efficiencies it allows for The
Regulators to know where the product is
so Regulators can now walk in they can
have their own handheld RFID scanners
and they can scan a room instantly they
can then reconcile that with what's
supposed to be there so by digitizing
objects with ultra high frequency RFID
you offer value to The Regulators you
offer value to the producers you offer
value to the dispensaries and the end of
the day It ultimately becomes valuable
to the customers because one with all
these efficiencies you can save save
money and therefore sell the product at
lower price and two the the customers
know that these are legal tested
products that have been through the
legal supply chain and that they've not
come in from the gray markets uh so
everybody every stakeholder in the
Cannabis World benefits from digitizing
Individual cannabis
units and it seems as automation
robotics come into the manufacturing and
packaging and distribution side of the
industry that your technology is tailor
made for these advancements that are
coming in the industry oh there's no
doubt about it I mean machines these
these things have to speak to each other
and I think a good example of that that
from personally from my career before I
was working in cannabis I put together
helped sell in and build and deploy the
entire automation system for Tesla uh so
at Tesla there were all these INE
efficiencies because they were using
barcode scanners uh by adding RFID to
all individual um bins racks and
ultimately uh individual items like
battery uh pallets they were able to
track where everything was they created
incredible efficiencies and when you
needed the red door to come in for that
model S at a certain time you knew that
the red door left the inventory room you
saw the gateways it goes through so you
knew that that product was going to be
there when it needed to be there um so
it's about creating efficiencies and if
you're going to automate you have to
have systems that will speak to each
other and understand the data and the
outputs we've had a lot of talk about
the DEA rescheduling over the last
number of days we've seen the stocks
from a lot of the msos take a little
bump which was well needed for anybody
who's got a skin in the game there what
do do you think within the first Q one
of this year that we're going to end up
having some positive feedback from them
everything is pointing towards something
positive whether it's to scheduling down
to schedule three or whether it's a full
Federal legalization plan obviously
everybody hoping for the letter yeah I
mean I think this this Administration
desperately needs a win and there was a
lot of hope that they would be a much
more favorable or Pro cannabis
Administration so the the of course the
expectation is that the DEA will provide
a favorable rescheduling ruling and
personally speaking speak I don't hold
out any short-term hope for legislators
or politicians to get something done um
I do hold out hope that there will be a
rescheduling and by rescheduling from a
one to a type three substance that's a
game changer for the industry I mean it
frees up cash flow allows for those
standard 280e exemptions and it will be
a true GameChanger and of course to your
point you can see that that starting to
be built in in a small way into some of
these these publicly traded cannabis
stocks right
now yeah and it seems the winners if if
we do end up getting federalization the
brands will be the kind of dominant
players in the industry like it is in
beverages and and in any consumer
package Goods side of
things yeah I mean I I've heard numbers
from some of the larger publicly traded
msos on what a rescheduling would do to
their balance sheet in terms of cash
flow and it's it's a night and day
change and you know the challenge again
the challenge for the industry and one
of the reasons why they've not adopted
best practices is it requires capital
and most of these businesses are are un
well underwater um the last year has
been a very difficult environment for
attracting outside Capital to come in so
with the rescheduling that will free up
significant free cash flow day one and
it will allow these businesses to make
investments and things that will create
efficiencies and and ultimately provide
a better experience for all stakeholders
yeah Hopey year 2024 now we get
Germany's industry starts getting some
momentum and we see some change happen
in America and uh we look forward to
seeing true Gan Global dominate on a on
a global
scale well we we truly appreciate that
you know our our goal is to bring to to
to fix the broken parts of the Cannabis
market like I said earlier it's it's the
supply chain side and it's the payment
side and
again UHF IDE is not truly inventing the
wheel we're just bringing to bear in
cannabis tried and true best practices
from supply chain and we're adopting it
and adapting it to the nuance and
requirements of the Cannabis industry so
it's an exciting time uh we we see that
we're changing customers and and
improving their their bottom line and
their efficiencies across their entire
organization so it's it's thrilling it's
a fun time to be in the business it's
been incredible talking to Tim hopefully
we get to touch base now in Q2 this year
and we can get an update and we've got
some positive news in America for
anybody who has not been to True Green
Global's website the link is below and
it'll be in the description wherever you
watch or view this I highly recommend
follow them on social media and go to
visit their site and Tim thank you very
much for your time today it's very much
appreciated thank you very much I truly
appreciate it we have a wonderful day
and a wonderful weekend cheers until
next episode
[Music]
everybody