[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined in this episode by russell pace
he's the founder of the cannabis
horticultural association russell is
also a cannabis cultivation consultant
with a specialization on nursery
production and integrated pest
management he's been group cultivating
cannabis for the last 20 years with the
past 16 in humboldt county how are you
keeping russell
good good thanks for having me i
appreciate it it's really nice to uh
connect overseas
the technology is awesome delighted to
have young major one of the people who
got a wealth of information and
knowledge that could be bestowed to the
audience so the objective was to give
everybody a quick little overview of a
couple of difficult topics and do you
maybe want to give
i actually generally i'm going to jump
straight into the first topic instead of
doing a big long introduction so
soil science can you maybe give the
viewer a a couple of minutes overview of
how important soil science is to the
cultivation process
yeah sure you know i'll try to give an
overarching uh
topic you know
soil science to me is uh you know the
complexities between soil biology and
soil chemistry and a lot of times you
know people just think of soil science
as just what what the chemistry is but
you know over the last decade for me
personally i've learned how important
biology is too you know and i got sort
of tipped off to it you know through
elaine ingham
and her whole soil biology
uh court all of her courses and that
whole industry that's been developing
and you know basically people think
sometimes you just add nutrients into
the soil and the roots of the cannabis
plant or any plant uptake those
nutrients and then that's how the plant
absorbs the nutrients
but what's amazing what's what's going
on actually inside the soil within the
within the biology is just it's so
staggering how many reactions are
occurring in the soil
you know like i i try to remember how
many
billions of uh of microbes there are in
one handful of soil but it's it's an
it's a staggering number of microbes in
one hand of soil you know you have your
protozoa your amoebas your flagellates
your ciliates
your bacteria your fungi
your arthropods there's like a whole
range of of life that's it's occurring
in the soil
and so
you know basically what when the when
the nutrients go into the soil they're
not always in bioavailable form or if
they're already in the soil they're not
in bioavailable form and what what
occurs is that
there's this really complex interaction
between the root systems and the soil
microbiology
and the root systems are actually
releasing exudates and exudate is just a
chemical that or you know actually i
think they're more like carbohydrates a
lot of the times it's like a it's a
secretion
there's a secretion that's occurring
from the roots going into the soil
they're crossed there's a crosstalk
going on with the biology where the
plants root systems are releasing these
exudates
to communicate
with microbiology and then they'll talk
to fungi and be like here you can have
some of this but in exchange i need some
potassium or phosphate then the fungi
high fill network can extend like you
know many feet outward and if they're
connected it's like a little super
highway that over here you know i'll try
to get a screenshot over here it feeds
through and can actually transport
nutrients all the way over to the
plant's root systems for the plant to
grow so this is like incredibly complex
interaction and at first you know this
whole thing was just like the industry
you know enlarges like feed the
nutrients in the soil and the plants
uptake them and it's moving more towards
feed the soil like make sure you have a
healthy population of microbiology in
the soil because what that does is it
allows you to optimize the nutrient
uptake and it's means it means that you
don't have to use as much nutrients if
you have a really healthy soil biology
you can use a fraction of the percentage
of nutrients
and still achieve the same result or
even better because of plant health you
we all know like our how important it is
our microbiology and our stomach like
they're starting to recognize like our
our health is like intricately tied to
the microbiome in our stomach well the
same with the earth and it's that old
alchemist saying as above so below like
it's the same process that's going on
and we need to be aware of how important
soil biology is for soil science
okay let's a brilliant overview so you
can see a future now where you're
getting basically let's say grow at home
kids are going to have
soil pre-planted and as important as the
genetics part of the the cultivation
process which uh again is a hollow
marker to open up into
and second topic i wanted to talk to you
about and maybe give
it something that i wouldn't know too
much about is agro ecology can you maybe
give to everybody watching a good
overview of what this is and how you
specialize in
yeah no so agroecology is something
that's not very
it's i understand it but i it's not in
my wheelhouse it's it's more of
agroecology to me like i talk with
agroecology a lot with my buddy matthew
gates who is an entomologist down in san
diego he has a handle uh sink angel on
instagram he's a absolute powerhouse of
knowledge you know so
one thing that that's important for me
is that i don't always have all the
answers to everything but what i do have
is the means and ability to access all
of the answers to everything that's
something i pride myself on but you know
it's like to me there's this concept of
agroecology
where you're tying in agriculture
with ecology it's like it's the
combination of the two
and they they sort of espouse the term
agroecology to try to
optimize you know these large
agricultural
um
plots you know and they try and they're
trying to tie them into some type of
with some type of ecological framework
you know
and so maybe agroecology looks something
like oh we have a bunch of acres of this
one crop but we're planting
uh rows intercropping rows of some type
of companion plant to attract beneficial
insects you know agroecology means oh
we're gonna cover crop this winter
all of those kinds of any any type of
way that you can integrate some
ecological methodology
into
traditional agriculture
that to me is what agroecology is i'm
sure there's agroecologists that will
chime in and you know offer their
more technical definition of what it is
but that's to me what it means and
it's kind of like one of those terms
where
i don't know people overuse it in some
some like you know
it sometimes gets misused in the
industry like you know like uh what am i
trying to say um
no no when people it's sort of like when
people use like when it when it when a
company that's trying to create a
product like a food product and they
call it natural you know it's all
natural
you know it sort of gets overused
sometimes in some some fields so it's
important just to understand it for what
it is like which is an important way to
integrate ecological methods into ag
agriculture
yeah that's brilliant is the objective
of this is to educate everybody i don't
think half the people out there have the
answers to everything but i think by uh
sharing these ideas and bits of
information is how everybody kind of
gets up to speed what are they curious
to ask you about um humboldt county well
it was a maybe a year or so ago got a
jurisdiction almost like champagne
when it comes to cultivation of cannabis
do you know the exact uh purview of
exactly what that law is and what it
means to the industry
uh yes the the old appalachians battle
as they say
yes the appalachians yes i'm i'm
definitely sort of in the midst of uh
just watching everyone work towards
creating appalachians now
uh i don't think there was it wasn't a
law it was just you know there's
there's classifications they're trying
to establish i don't know
the details of like
it's it's a complicated topic because
basically i mean i'll go on a side a
side tangent here for a second you know
it's like if you look i have mixed
feelings about it because
if you look at the true
appellations and terroir that's
associated with wine production right
you know we all are well tuned into that
these grapes are growing in the ground
for decades right decades
and cannabis is a plant that is one
season and so there's a lot of complex
variables when you're trying to
identify how
a farm is going to apply
that you know for a perm for for a
classification for appellations of a
certain region you know like how how
does
the terroir of the soil of the sea air
affect the growth of a cannabis plant
how does it affect the secondary
metabolite production you know like the
champagne region in france wouldn't
suppose i don't know a lot about it but
it's a specific type of soil obviously
those roots grow in the ground for
decades and they're sucking out those
minerals you know there's like acidity
levels there's like very specific things
that produce a flavor
and i don't know i don't know how
they're gonna necessarily achieve that
in cannabis but they're working towards
it i think it is possible i think
there's a pos there's definitely a
framework of possibility where if you're
you have to go into the native soil you
can't have potting soil you know you
have to be in the native soil you have
to you be using inputs from that
environment
you know and there's important variables
that need to be set in place for those
appellations to occur but it is
occurring it's also happening i think in
mendocino county it's the whole emerald
triangle that's really the hub it's like
the emerald triangle in northern
california
is that hub where all the appalachians
are being talked about and trying to be
developed so i know it's kind of like a
tangent but yeah that's really
it's really interesting to me and it's
it's in the it's a lot of it's in
development like they're
i think there's what's that what's that
group the origins council they're called
the origins council they have a lot of
information
on appellations too you can check them
out
um you might want to talk you might want
to talk to them that might be a good
person to reach out to yeah let's try to
get step by step i understand every
single component of this global industry
so ireland can be a key player when it
all goes legal worldwide yeah what's it
what are your laws in ireland right now
it's curious so there's a basically an
mcap medical cannabis access program but
it limits to a handful of different
diseases and the products are obviously
just brought in um
some of the
let's say less yeah canada who didn't
get it exactly right and have a huge
europe is getting a bit of a tidal wave
going now in fairness you've got germany
are going to have a recreational market
hopefully soon you've got movements
going on malta are going to be a big hub
in terms of cultivation and processing
of flowers so you'll start to see step
by step
europe come over and i think you'll have
especially cultivation the farmers over
here are already some of the best in the
world as it is so i think when they get
to tap into the genetics and the real
understanding of the cannabis plant and
i think you'll see a lot of new strains
and genetics coming out of europe but in
time
the last topic i wanted
about was
the best weed is grown in ah yes i've
asked a ton of cultivation people this
i'm not putting you on the spot and i've
got no it's fine hey i'm in humble i'm
in humboldt county so
i've been in humboldt county since 2006.
so
i would say i would be very careful and
i would say the best weed in the world
is grown in
the emerald triangle which means
humboldt county
trinity county and mendocino county
northern california the emerald triangle
i could say humboldt county
you know but i have too many friends
they're in mendo and trinity too
and they all grow it's it's the whole
bio region of that that area
where you know it's been cultivated
forever it's you know they these people
these
generational farmers have battled the
police
forever and they've been getting seeds
from overseas you know from afghanistan
and pakistan and land races from down
south america you know and
they've been breeding and cultivating
these like this is the hotbed of where
all this breeding has occurred has
occurred
so i would definitely without a doubt
say the emerald triangle is the zone and
humboldt county is obviously one of the
best known names like you don't know
about trinity and mendocino so so a lot
of times when you say humboldt county is
the best wheat in the world
there's a certain sense of pride in that
because i've been in the county i'm
right on the county line like i go two
miles east and trinity counties right
there so you know it's like we're right
right on the border there um
yeah humble county is the best you just
so many amazing genetics and uh up here
breeding i'm breeding i'm doing a
i started a seed company part of chaws
we're doing seed production now so we're
producing our whole line of genetics for
concentrate production
and that's really exciting so that's in
the developing works right now and uh
yeah that's it emerald triangle final
answer
yeah i have a figure we we've done some
stuff before where we figured out where
the best oysters are grown in the world
and it turns out it was in galway by
this irish family and it was because
pacific rain water came off the burn
another bit of soil came off the land
and it combined with atlantic waters
where they were only place in the world
that had ferrari oysters they were
called the graded in zero to ten in
terms of the best size these guys had
zeros and they used to get
the owner of uh harrods all the time so
i pretty much picture the emerald
triangle is that exact synopsis plus for
oysters the exact nutrients the exact
pollution care air count the exact
lighting and phd that they they get so
uh yeah yeah it might be somewhere that
everybody should check out on their uh
tourism police yes come come check out
humble county we have the redwoods the
tallest biggest trees in the world the
redwood the redwoods are amazing to see
the avenue of the giants it's amazing
it's been absolutely pleasure talking to
russell meadow kataki all day about this
stuff if everybody wants to check out
the
website for the cannabis horticultural
association you can see it there below
i'll have it in the link as well below
it's been a pleasure talking to you also
mate you have a great rest of your day
and uh i look forward to chatting to you
again soon
yeah thanks a lot anytime appreciate it
take it
easy bye