[Music]
welcome to the next episode of cannabis
review I'm delighted to be joined this
episode by natal pansy who's the founder
and CEO at sorting robotics how you
keeping today Nel doing all right
thanks very uh pleasure to speak to you
um can you maybe give everybody a quick
little overview of your company and the
position you're and how you ended up
focusing on the Cannabis
industry yeah so um a little overview of
the company uh we're uh robotics company
that specifically builds robots for
cannabis
manufacturers um super high level we
started uh back in 2018 uh me and one of
my co-founders were working at Nasa um I
was working on a device that's currently
on the surface of Mars producing
oxygen uh from the Martian atmosphere
and and that was really great and then
we wanted to build a company of our own
uh and so we built this company coming
straight out of NASA we actually were in
e-commerce doing inventory management
for your e-commerce Sellers and then
2019 T frame we wanted to Pivot the
company into a much bigger Market where
we found cannabis as like a a really
strong opportunity and we love the plant
we loved robots so it made a lot of
sense so then uh in 2020 we uh sold off
the first part of the company and then
uh kind of solely focused on making
robots for cannabis
manufacturers and uh launched our first
product in
2021 and the That's All She Wrote and
now we've kind of built a bunch of
things from then and um we we are here
today a super high
level yeah it's been very interesting in
research in your company I've
interviewed over 300 different CEOs and
Founders and the one thing everybody's
kind of agreed with that automation is
going to be a
ma automation is going to be a massive
opportunity within the industry the
technology you guys are implementing can
you maybe give everybody a little run
through or what are the current
offerings you guys have in terms of
Robotics and how they fit with each
individual category and
segment sure uh we've done quite a few
different things uh I would say our main
focus these days is working on pre-
rolls so right now we sell kind of every
step in the proll manufacturing chain so
we sell a machine that manufactures
pre-rolls kind of packs them whether
they're pre-rolls or blunts or straight
tubes uh or half Gams or whatever and
then we have another system uh that we
invented back in 2021 called the GCO
robot so the GCO robot will inject
concentrate down the center of P roll
kind of like a like a Twinkie a little
bit and uh that will inject them whether
it's distillate or you know batter or
whether it's rosin and uh that improves
the THC percentage also you know kind of
changes the flavor profile of the proll
and then just recently uh we launched
something called Stardust which is a
system that kefs the outside of PR
rolles so what does that mean it means
you take your pre-roll that you have uh
kind of already finished and ready to
sell but then now you spray the outside
of it with distill it and then uh you
coat the KE or you coat the pural with
keth or thca Crush diamonds or bubble
hash and then it looks like a a fuzzy
pural on the
outside and um and then later this year
we'll be selling a uh system that takes
those PR rolls and then kind of decides
whether you want to put it uh you know
crutch up or crutch down into a tube
seals it puts a label on it and then
that way we'll have you know every step
in the process um for any p on the
market yeah and that's uh that's
basically our main things we also have
what are the types of quantities that
you're able to manufacture on an hourly
or daily basis we previously interviewed
a guest to it seemed to be that they
were churning out 100 million cones um
that seems to be a lot of cones what's
the kind of production capacity of the
machines uh so on the cone side we have
a machine that can do up to 2500 cones
an hour and then uh we also have another
system that will be able to
do about 1,00 to 1200 cones an hour
where we'll be doing like blunts or
cones it's kind of a highly variable
option and then on the infusion pieces
of the uh
setup uh let's see the injection one
we've had customers go all the up to
like 1500 joints per hour and then on
the keing side that's around uh so far
our max speed has been 1,200 joints per
hour so uh some of them are different
speeds depending on the process um yeah
that's kind of the
approximate speeds and feeds for
that
um when it comes to the technology that
you guys do use obviously you're you're
special specializing in robotics at the
moment but the ls of computer vision and
some machine learning models is there
any other applications I would imagine
computer vision in the cultivation world
is something that could be implemented
across the
board uh yeah I mean we've done a bunch
of computer vision before so especially
on the cultivation side so we actually
first started in the industry making a
computer vision powered biomass sorder
this way we could take hand trim and
then separate out all the constituent
parts of hand trim what does that mean
it means uh when we got uh large batches
of hand trim we could take out all the
small buds and then we could take out
all the stems and then we could take all
the leaves separate them into different
piles and then we could send the leaves
to get extracted we could throw the
stems away to save on taxes and then we
could take the buds and sell them for
pre-rolls and uh that was a pretty
interesting project because the computer
vision had to operate uh and make
decisions you know within like 40
milliseconds and um we did some more
research on that to uh understand if we
could even do a phenotype classification
and we uh we did pretty well there and
and uh it kind of noticed that at the
moment when we made that so that was one
of the very first things that we made so
about four years ago the Canabis
industry was still too new to absorb a
technology like that I think these days
that'll be a bit more important um but I
have seen some computer vision uh on the
grower side to kind of like analyze the
plants and I I saw one machine that was
trying to do computer vision scanning to
see if any uh of the flowers are herming
at a very high level otherwise you'd
have to like walk through you know rows
of plants and like check for seeds but
um there's some kind of like color
markers that you can do and do like a um
highs
Spectrum uh kind of analysis for the
plants to see like if they're kind going
Ary so yeah there's a few applications
especially in the cultivation side just
because otherwise you have to absorb
every plant and inspect them one by
one and what were some of the initial
challenges that you face when you're
building the robotics is it the hardware
or the software side of things which is
the biggest headache or are they equally
uh difficult things to
overcome uh I mean when you're doing
robotics it's not really just like a
hardware and
software individ ual approach right
because they got to play nice together
so it's not like twice as hard as either
doing one of those independently it's
like three times as hard because it's
got to work together right and that like
that that interface is always very
dicey um I think it just depends on like
what the approach is
um yeah like
uh for
example the the first system that we
built uh the rocus order which was our
kind of top level um very first product
into the market not the Cannabis Market
but the the e-commerce
Market that one was really difficult
because it was both a very complicated
Material Handling problem and then there
is some sophisticated computer vision to
recognize things and to make sure that
that was reliable enough that the system
would even be valuable because if the
computer vision wasn't topnotch then it
didn't even matter you know what you did
on the hard
side and and that was one of those
problems where they were both equally as
hard it was just kind of wild um and
then when it came to the uh let's say
the biomass sorder that we made that one
was almost completely software side what
made it difficult the hardware side was
really just like recreating some expired
patents kind of like a waterfall of
Agriculture where like you have a bunch
of material that falls off a ram and
then you shoot it with puffs of air
uh and that one was very much software
based because there was a lot of timing
involved the computer vision was really
complicated and then I guess if you
think about uh about go that one was
very much a hardware based problem the
software was more just like Control
software um so it's a bit
simplified
uh but the the actual like
implementation of the Control software
and making sure that the hardware was
extremely uniform
um extremely well-refined so that way
you could control the dosage of this
concentrate into
joints there's like a lot of little
things that you have to get right on the
hardware to make sure it's a consistent
uh product and yeah that one definitely
took a while and especially because uh
concentrates have a very very wide range
of operation and so if your machine
doesn't have the ability to at least
like accept that wide range it's not
incredibly useful so we had to we had to
make it like very very variable very
variable um and that was very much like
a hardware problem for sure so I guess
it depends um which part of the value
chain we're kind of going after because
sometimes it's less software and
sometimes it's more Hardware it's it
just really
depends what's the level of skill
required for somebody to work one of
these machines would imagine the dream
scenario for you guys is that these
machines are dotted in different
factories all across the world and are
able to produce X type of quantity is
there a special skill set that's
required to work the robots or is it an
easier barrier to entry to hire staff to
manage these
facilities so we have a saying here
whenever we design a machine for the
Cannabis industry it's we want to make
sure that the machines are able to be
operated by someone who um is not
sophisticated at all like they haven't
they didn't even graduate high school
and they're high and so that's kind of
our goal like you can be intoxicated and
be like 16 years old uh because in many
cases the people that are operating the
machines they might be migrant workers
they might not even speak English and um
in other states they might be coming
back from their break where they just
smoke their joint or took like a dab rip
and then went back into their
manufacturing company to to continue to
work and so because of that uh we make
the machines themselves be pretty
straightforward to operate and even when
we troubleshoot we make it so that if
you just follow the directions they're
pretty straightforward to
operate and we also provide this like
pretty robust uh customer support system
like all of our systems ship with a
dedicated slack Channel which is like a
you know internal Tool uh to communicate
between
teams and that allows us to be you know
very very deeply embedded
in um our customers operations of the
machines and we get to see if anything
goes wrong we also have like remote
support as well to see if anything goes
wrong we can actually like log into the
machine and see the video operations of
the Machines working to to debug what
happens and so uh
I I specifically made it such that we
don't have to have like some you know
automation technician running the
machines because those don't really
exist in the Cannabis industry today and
um that quality of workers just really
just too expensive to make the operation
of the machine uh financially
[Music]
viable you guys are one of the Premier
technology companies that's innovating
in this space what are you looking
forward to seeing the most over the next
12 to 24
months so specifically for our company I
think I would be really I'm really
excited to see when we finally get our
kind of fully automated line all
stitched together it's something we've
been working on for the past couple
years to have um you know modular
segments kind of like what I described
right now which is all of our products
and what we're really working on now is
making it so that each one of these
segments can be either used
independently or you can kind of snug
them all together and have a fully
automated line where one machine hands
off to another machine which hands off
to another machine which hands off to
another machine and and have that whole
line be able to be operated by one
individual and uh I think that'd be
really cool um especially for the three
puts that we'll be getting
considering the current market size in
the different
states uh what I would also like to to
see it just uh to help the whole
industry as well as some form of um you
know Federal changes at least in the
United States I think that would be a
pretty significant um Boon to the
worldwide uh cannabis industry I know um
Europe now finally has Germany who just
approved which they thought they were
going to do it last year but now I guess
they're doing it this year and um that
sounds like a good thing for the
European Union I think once the United
States kind of I don't know figures out
whatever their plan is then we're going
to see a significant change globally as
if the reserve currency finds it legal
and safe to bank then everyone else
should probably find that as
well yeah it's going to be exciting
couple years for sure for anybody who
hasn't ever visited uh sorting robots
website it's below in the description
wherever you're watching or listening to
this highly recommend following them on
all social media and checking out Noel's
page as well notel thank you very much
for your time today it's been very much
appreciated yeah for sure
thanks until next
[Music]
episode