foreign
ER who's the founder and managing
director at the warrior unlimited BV the
Warrior's seat IPO management
consultancy firm at the intersection of
AG Tech sustainability and cannabis
Innovation how are you keeping today
Leonard I'm doing very well Owen thank
you so much for having me delighted to
have you on to cover this topic that I'm
sure a lot of people want to know about
but don't get too much information on
can you maybe give everybody just a
quick little brief overview of how you
came to set up the warrior and the main
objectives of the company
absolutely I I came from a career of
institutional finance and happened to
join the firm that was at the start of
the who cares wins paper that really
began the ESG movement so when I started
in Morgan Stanley
um ESG and looking after sensitive
accounts from the point of view of ESG
compliance and and and management it was
something that I always had
um an eye into and in 2013 when Colorado
and Washington state were legalizing in
the U.S and I saw a need for these sorts
of skill sets uh and institutional now a
know-how in the nascent cannabis
industry it was a bit of a no-brainer so
we really came into the Cannabis
industry
um aiming to create institutional
benchmarks and standards both from the
point of view of Professional Services
and execution but also this ESG side and
managing environmental social governance
variables throughout expanding this
nascent industry
okay very interesting
um can you maybe give everybody an
explanation of what is regenerative
growth
absolutely so when you think of
regeneration it's creating growth from
the point of view of Decay or waste and
in a way the Cannabis industry as a
whole is regenerative right after nearly
a century of prohibition of decay of
waste of incarceration of vulnerable
asset classes we now have the
opportunity to create value to create
jobs to create opportunity out of the
industry that stems from this plant and
that goes from the medical cannabis
industry to the wellness and
recreational adult use cannabis industry
and to the industrial applications of
the Cannabis sativa l plant or the hemp
plant so for us we see it as a very
holistic concept of regenerating
communities regenerating economic uh
impact regenerating Agriculture and
phyto Remediation and carbon
sequestration of ecosystems so we
believe there's an enormous potential of
this plant as a whole to create new
generative Industries in a place where
we've had
either obsolescence non-existent or
decay
okay very interesting so the first topic
I wanted to talk about was
sustainability in cannabis can you maybe
give everybody what are the top two uh
let's say the top two tier things that
any cannabis company let's say with
indoor and outdoor should be an
automatic part of their business
principles to be able to ensure that
they're making a sustainable product
I think we have to actually take a step
back prior to that
um so when you're creating a plan for
your cannabis value chain whether you
plan to be vertical or you plan to be
integrated into one part of the supply
chain location is
um the primary variable
we believe that in the next decade most
of the world's cannabis will be
cultivated in the Sun Belt or the global
South whatever name we want to ascribe
to these regions but cost effective
regions with abundant natural resources
is where we believe cannabis should be
cultivated so from the point of view of
even before we understand the impact of
one particular style of cultivation
versus another we need to give a very
strong weighting to put in your business
in the right place to start after that I
I would say understanding in the impact
of energy on your cultivation practice
and your overall sustainability profile
is key so as you put your cultivation
Assets in a place with abundant natural
resources utilizing them appropriately
with climate controlled Advanced
greenhouses that take into account as
much sun Spectrum as possible those
sorts of variables are are probably the
top on everyone's list when setting up a
business
okay and when it comes to the medical
cannabis side of the industry I'm
correct in saying that all has to be
grown indoor under strict conditions
with HVAC systems and ECS systems is
that correct that that is not entirely
correct no
um so you're you are correct that
medical cannabis has to be grown under
gacp environment so good agriculture and
collection practices however there's no
uh explicit note of what that means and
there are multiple medical herbs that
are grown under gacp that are grown
completely outside in the elements the
majority of medical cannabis is either
grown indoors as as you mentioned in
greenhouses either Dutch venlow style
fully climate control Advanced
greenhouses or
um hybrid uh greenhouses which are more
like hoop houses with ventilation and
basic uh climate control but without the
advance the 24 7 monitoring that we have
in benlo style greenhouses and if you
look at the supply on the current market
let's say in Germany the majority is
indoors but that's only a function of
the
um the market itself so when 26 of the
German Market happens to come from the
Netherlands and the Netherlands has one
company that has a monopoly on medical
cannabis and they grow it indoors well
that's 26 of the market tilray and
canopy growth take another big part of
that and it comes from Canada right so
we we're naturally accustomed to
thinking that cannabis can only be grown
indoors but in reality gacp practices
don't have that level of granularity and
control
okay so you see a future basically where
cultivation's got to be around the
equator and that European countries will
be able to ship this product in
repackage it in certain territories and
then then transport it logistically to
the dispensaries and pharmacies I I do
believe that that sort of Hub and spoke
model is is the future but that's not to
say that on Continental Europe we don't
have
um low-cost uh energy abundant
cultivation centers ourselves so the
um the Balkan areas of Northern
Macedonia northern Greece uh Bulgaria
when it comes online uh Romania to to
some extent so those areas around the
Black Sea
um are very well conducive to producing
high quality cannabis with minimal
natural resources and the cost of Labor
that's significantly lower than the
majority of Western or northern Europe
uh do you know of any facilities that
are basically be able to have designed a
facility that's completely off the grid
where the water irrigation's recycled
it's got solar panels for electricity or
are we still a couple of years away from
that dream you know that's uh I I love
that question because that is the
Warrior's aim that is the proof of
concept to create that
um I haven't visited a facility like
that yet we have a few clients that have
the solar panels installed that do rain
water collection but the rain water
collection is supplementing Wells and
things of that nature so it's still in a
supplementary basis versus completely
off off the grid
um and I think even off the grid
um
it would be challenging to have the
Confluence of uh fully Off the Grid
energy and water sufficient enough for
cultivation at scale so I'm I I there's
a couple of regions where I could see
that happening but but it would be a
challenge Columbia is a place that that
I think could uh could potentially be
close to that
yeah we hear a lot of news out of
Colombia with the they're supposedly
going to be the supply side of the
European industry is that a realistic
expectation or are there new territories
that we haven't basically isolated and
highlighted yet that are going to be
able to surpass or is the climate in
Colombia like we've been told at the
perfect climate to be able to grow dry
and do all the things with cannabis so
first of all I I don't think Colombia is
a perfect climate
um I think it has very high humidity and
you need a particular set of genetics to
be able to do well in a climate like
that in terms of the pure kind of
cannabis connoisseur it takes a certain
terroir which is largely found similar
to Wine growing regions so Catalonia and
the alpuhar mountains in Spain have very
good quality for for growing cannabis
obviously Northern California Southern
Oregon as as well so Colombia may not be
perfect from the point of view of purely
cannabis but the amount of sunlight they
have the amount of rain they have that
combination that balance allows you to
create the Matrix of sustainability and
I think that's this key the key takeaway
that we wish all of our clients to take
away is it's not a checklist we're not
go going through any sort of this is
good this is bad shape up level up it's
really a matrix and adjusting this
Matrix to your budget to your
environment to your specific needs of
cultivation that's what we're always
after so from that point of view
Colombia does have something special but
I don't think it's any more special than
a place like Thailand which is rapidly
opening up and ramping up I think more
and more African countries both Northern
African and sub-Saharan are going online
so I don't think there will be a
shortage of Supply in the next decade
and I wouldn't point to any one country
in particular to be the future of
European Supply
Okay so
last topic Before I Let You Go is
cannabis and energy when it comes to
energy use and consumption and cannabis
what is going to be the the next big
landmark in terms of being able to
decrease that output is it AG Tech
inventions or is it Innovations with
current methodologies that are already
in use
I think it's in my opinion it's the
latter
um we need to start treating cannabis as
any other pharmaceutical or agricultural
commodity and not as a stale worth of
prohibition and the reason we're so
accustomed to growing cannabis indoors
is because we had to we had to grow it
in basements and attics and abandon
buildings and national forests right
under the cover of darkness and Tents
and
closed-loop irrigation systems but being
here in the Netherlands and that's the
main reason why the warrior chose to be
headquartered in the Netherlands to be
at the center of agricultural Innovation
we understand that growing cannabis as
an agricultural commodity in Dutch
venlow climate control greenhouses
significantly reduces the energy
expenditure on cultivation the main
driver of energy expenditure is lighting
so when you shift away from fully indoor
or even worse vertical where you have
two tiers or three tiers of lighting in
the same space you start to reduce that
overall impact quite significantly and
even putting a cultivation Center that's
Greenhouse based here in the Netherlands
on the 52nd parallel would largely be
equivalent on an Apples to Apples basis
of using about one quarter of the total
energy to having the same size canopy
but fully indoors
okay incredible
um last question before I go what is it
you're looking forward to most over the
next 12 to 24 months in let's say the
European cannabis industry have we got
to be optimistic or are Germany going to
fall at the hurdle or uh you see the
Spanish Medical Market that comes online
at the end of December being a success
what is it that you're most looking
forward to
I think having been Incorporated
um in Europe now here in the Netherlands
since 2018
um we've done most of our work in the
medical sector and I think we're excited
to see what the adult use uh Tipping
Point is going to be
um and you mentioned Germany and we're
certainly excited about that but if
we're looking at 12 to 18th month
Horizons I I have to be a little
nationalistic here and mention the
gishlochenketon Dutch closed loop
experiment and we have a good feeling
that 2023 is going to be the year of
opening up of production and we may see
the First full vertical uh integration
fully taxed fully legal of recreational
Cannabis here in the Netherlands and the
licenses that are vying for this right
have been in the running since 20 20
there's been a lot of consolidation a
lot of changes and switches and pivots
but we feel really good about the cohort
that's now settled in and we think the
first sale of a legal adult use product
is going to be in the Netherlands
well that sounds very exciting to me I
hope that we can get to touch base in
about 12 to 18 months and see how far
things have gone for everybody wants to
know more about regenerative growth and
all things sustainability highly
recommend you check out the Devore your
website the link is below and we'll be
all in all descriptions Leonard thank
you very much for taking your time to do
this it's very much appreciated
thank you oh and it was a pleasure to
chat have a great rest of your day thank
you you too until next episode everybody