foreign
who's a partner at Arman Nino Mike has
been a tax professional since 1999 as a
significant experience in federal state
and local tax for both illegal and a
financial perspective how you keeping
today Mike
I'm doing well how are you I'm fantastic
thank you very much for taking your time
to do this it's a topic I've wanted to
cover for a short bit of time and no
better man than yourself to be able to
help give us some guidance on this topic
yes looking forward to it great stuff do
you maybe want to give the audience a
quick overview in under 30 seconds of
how armanino ended up having a tax
division and how you ended up being
ahead of the Cannabis Tax Group
yeah I started uh several years ago back
in 2015 and I noticed that you know
cannabis was going to go state by state
and it was not going to be federally
legal for quite some time and it still
is not in the U.S and so
um you know learned about it and then
um wrote the Treatise for Thompson
rewarder it's all multi-state cannabis
Taxation and so I'm one of the leading
experts in how this industry is taxed
across the U.S
okay fantastic so there's a couple of
things that from a European perspective
I'd love to find out about the U.S tax
state by state so hopefully you're going
to be able to help so first and foremost
why are the taxes so high on a state
level is it just uh the governments and
the states don't understand how it
should be taxed or it's a part of greed
thinking the industry is going to bring
in more Revenue than it actually does
yeah unfortunately the the States you
know when they determine you know how to
tax this industry instead of taxing it
at a very low rate say alcohol or
tobacco they determine how much revenue
do they want to generate from Cannabis
then they figure out how much legal
cannabis will be sold that will be taxed
and then they back into the tax rate
which you know ends up being such a high
rate that many cannabis companies are
having trouble uh keeping their business
open because the the taxes are just so
high and the illicit Market is thriving
under these conditions
okay interesting is there any state that
have gotten it right so far or is
everybody doing the exact same mistake
that their predecessors have done before
them
yeah unfortunately the the the the newer
states that are coming onto the market
you know such as New York and others
um are making the same mistakes and and
in New York's case they're taxing it uh
not on price but on THC content and so
you know there could be some
manipulation of you know the the testing
labs to to
score something with the lower THC
because that means that'll be a lower
tax in in New York
okay and so when it comes to the news
that uh Governor Gavin Newsom of
California basically got rid of a
cultivation tax I think it is and
changed excise tax what's the big deal
with what he did there and was it a
crazy uh play for the get-go they're
they're more riding around at the moment
yeah in California they they structured
their tax system somewhat like a
value-added tax that's used in Europe
and they wanted to tax it all along the
way you know from cultivation to
distribution to manufacturing to finally
retail
um but at the cultivation level you know
that was just uh the tax again was too
high and you know now that it's gone
away it's a little too little too late
kind of scenario for many California
um cannabis Growers because the price of
you know wholesale cannabis has gone
from say two thousand dollars a pound to
now less than six hundred dollars a
pound uh and it costs you know many of
those Growers about that much to to
produce the product
okay and so do you does it look like New
York so it seems to be the one that
seems to be uh maybe hopefully getting
it right or from your perspective are
they making the same tax and mistakes
that the other states are making
yeah again New York you know decided to
use a um THC content as their means of
taxing this industry uh at the retail
level and and unfortunately I think that
there's just this race to higher and
higher THC levels you know to to you
know come up with a product that has the
highest THC which you know I I think you
know once you get to a certain point you
don't need more THC and you know New
York wants to tax you know it based on a
THC content and I don't think that's
going to be a solution either because
the price of cannabis you know when you
buy it legally is going to be so high
compared to the illegal market and there
hasn't been enough enforcement of
illegal operators
um that you know I I think it's still
going to be a problem there in New York
um when it comes to setting the actual
percentage of taxes not to enter the
governor's office is down to the
taxation like the IRS is it down to who
exactly decides right it's going to be
15 or 12 percent
yeah and it varies you know depending on
the different you know governments and
how they do it some of it is done by you
know uh committee some of it's done at
the legislative level
um you know certainly the governors of
each state you know has to sign off on
all of this so uh it goes through many
layers of review but unfortunately
there's too many uh hands you know in in
this issue and and everybody wants
cannabis to pay for all of the different
projects and things that they've been
wanting to do for years and didn't have
the revenue to do and you know many
state and local governments see cannabis
as their
um savior in this respect
I would imagine there's a lot of
internal battles with the different
departments when a State legalizes the
industry to see who takes on the revenue
is the best model to create a new
division like let's say Colorado's
marijuana enforcement division or the
Cannabis Bureau in California is that
the best model or is it to be integrated
into the department of health or
Department of cultivate or agriculture
yeah and you know there's there's
usually like you know a grant for power
whenever cannabis becomes legal and you
know all these different agencies want
to have their say-so in in it and it
just further complicates it and makes
more regulations added to uh which is
already a very highly regulated business
and it just makes it more difficult for
operators
um to work in this this Arena so yeah it
would be great if there was just one
centralized
um you know body that you could get all
of the regulations done in that area but
you know you get environmentalists
involved you get you know work safety
people involved there's just so many
different you know agencies that get um
pulled into this that it just becomes a
nightmare for the for operators all
those Durant and countries like Ireland
and other countries in Europe that I can
learn from the process and and try and
ensure that it's a lot more smooth
sailing over this side of the pond
exactly and I I think what they should
do is is try to model it as closely as
they can to alcohol and tobacco where
you can have operators work in this
Arena maybe take advantage of rules and
regulations that have already been
established for alcohol and tobacco and
then parlay that into cannabis to the
extent possible so that it is just not
quite the burden that it is right now
okay next topic I wanted to jump into
was basically unpaid taxes in North
America the the likes of Matt at MJ
beers and some of the other great
articles they've read so far have been
highlighted this and it seems to be both
countries Canada and America are in the
high hundreds of millions of unpaid
taxes towards the their respective
governments is this a part of just
normal business or is this something
that investors or people look at the
industry should be alarmed about running
up this level of of our debt
yeah this has been a quite a an issue
for for the industry and you know again
the taxes are so high that you know many
of these companies can't pay these taxes
with their working capital and so what
they have chosen to do is not pay the
tax and you know run their business as
best they can and and kick the can down
the road and hope that you know it
becomes legal that these
um as tax assessments at some point get
negotiated for a lesser amount that they
work out some sort of uh an agreement to
maybe pay the taxes over a a long period
of time say you know five to ten years
uh and and hoping that their business
will then you know turn around in the
interim
yeah so it's more protecting your
capital for growth and uh arguing let's
say sense in the dollar down further
down the line and do you think this is
sustainable we I mentioned Our Fair
before that it seems to be that this
industry like other Industries will be
end up being dominated by a handful of
players in the different territories
like chocolate like uh crisp
manufacturing there's a various other
consumer package Goods that you could
point to this area where there's just
two or three big competitors was it a
case of in this industry that anybody or
Capital can get into it and we're now
just seeing the byproduct of the
strongest will survive and the weaker
companies are the ones falling off and
the ones with good balance sheets and
good executive structure and board
management are the ones that are going
to thrive long long term
yeah I see this you know being similar
to the Beer industry you know they're
going to be some major players they're
going to be worldwide brands that are
going to dominate you know the the
majority of the business but then there
will be like craft Brewers and others
that are smaller that will still you
know thrive in this industry because you
know cannabis you know affects people
differently based on your your body
composition and for some people one
product will have a great effect and
another product in that same product for
someone else could be you know does
doesn't do anything for them and so once
someone finds the product that they like
and a brand that they like and and the
effect that they get from that brand
um they're going to gravitate to that
and I think those entities will will do
well and and they could still be
acquired by the national uh and
international Brands and remain as as as
a small craft producer because you know
you don't want to lose that following
and and roll it up into a national brand
and and lose all that um marketing power
yeah speaking of Brands and marketing
power we see that the kind of top retail
Prospect over in America cookies have
already made some Ventures into the
European market I see them being one of
the dominant uh dominant brand names
across every single country I think what
Berner has done been done so far has
been pretty phenomenal
yes they're they're one of our clients
and I I started working with them when
they had their first dispensary and uh
now they've become you know a worldwide
brand and you know continuing to grow
and you know that's going to be very
important in this industry is branding
and just like
um Coca-Cola and other worldwide Brands
um once you know you can dominate the
market with your branding and people you
know gravitate to that uh is very
helpful I mean what cookies is doing is
really produ you know promoting a
lifestyle you know so it's more than
just the the cookies
um you know cannabis product you know
they have you know clothing and other
things that you know would be similar to
maybe like the Supreme brand that is
this Urban you know Lifestyle brand that
you know gravitates with many younger
people
yet now as we said they've been doing
phenomenal to work so far and I look
forward to the day that Dublin has a
cookie store on one of our main streets
here I know you're a very busy man and
I'm not going to keep you much longer I
just wanted to mention about the
Cannabis Summit that we've got on next
week very much looking forward to having
your expertise on the panels when we
have this event next Saturday on the
25th
looking forward to it it's going to be
great
yep your first Point again this will be
on me and I look forward to meeting in
person but for now thank you very much
for your time Mike
thank you it's great talking to you
until next episode everybody