foreign
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the counterpress review I'm delighted to
be joined on this episode by Paul
Finnegan who is a founder and product
director at nature can how are you
keeping today Paul
really good Ellen thanks very much for
having me on would you like to have you
I'd make sure you guys are one of the
stars of the show with the UK CBD world
at the moment so I was great to talk to
the the top companies in the industry do
you maybe want to give everybody a quick
60 second overview of how you found
yourself at nature can and founding that
with your partner
definitely yes so but my sort of CBD
Journey started about five years ago
when I first started looking into the
product and seeing that it was looking
like it was being legalized and in
Europe in 2018 obviously
um so I went out there looked at sort of
how we were going to set up a supply
chain basically that was going to be a
little bit future-proofed on the THC
side because it was a bit High over in
the in the us at the time the sort of
limits and everything well still it
still is
um so I set up a supply agreement over
in Oregon over in the states and then
luckily met Andy Duckworth who's my
partner he was the CEO of my protein
so he built that business to you know
350 million turnover you know fully
globalized in all the different
countries
and he jumped on board and we managed to
get into
first of all the UK then set something
up in Germany Ireland
expanded into a few more spots and
eventually now we're at sort of 45
countries trading CBD
it's an incredible old story I'm sure
you've had your hair pulled out dealing
with the Irish last time we've got over
here we won't talk too much about that
yeah you know we've we operated in
Ireland from the start as well and we
saw that it was
you know a little bit difficult people
were having issues with I think there
was a big sort of raid a few years ago
on one of the big High Street stores and
other problems as well
yeah well that made us concentrate our
mind on making sure that every bit of
these products were sort of to those
regulations and that was one thing that
we did from the start where
that was always the worry that when
you're dealing with controlled drugs
like the THC element of it
that you
and if you want to deal in all the
different countries the best way is to
stay
as low as possible so
we've always developed the product to
keep removing keep getting lower loqs on
the on THC because that's the trip up in
every country you know if you go over
that limit basically but Island
especially very hot on it
yeah that's it it seems to vary across
Europe as much as they've got the set
standard of 0.02 or three percent
Ireland seems to have it and no holds
bar that it's zero percent to THC
completely the topic I brought down I
want to talk today about is the Cannabis
supply chain can you maybe answer a
couple of questions on this first one is
basically where do you think the
majority of CBD is sourced from
currently available on the market is it
North America is it Eastern Europe is it
Central Europe where do you think it's
the main market for CBD
the main Supply so the raw ingredient is
from the states in my opinion there is
obviously some supplies in Eastern
Europe as well that um
built up over the last couple of years
but because of the the length of time
that they've been doing it in the states
in the competitive pricing that the
price of the biomass
but a lot of it is coming from North
America still just as a an aside from
that I was over in Thailand just before
Christmas because obviously that
Market's all opened up now
and the pricing over there is extremely
expensive still for raw ingredients so
the biomass is incredibly expensive all
of these extractors have just invested
you know five six million into their
facility and trying to recoup some of
those um the capital expenditure from
that so it's incredibly expensive
initially in these markets but as they
mature obviously with scale and
everything else they start coming down
in price that's why I think that the US
has still got a good hold because it's
very competitively priced but the
quality is is good as well
okay very good how important is
extraction to the process and who do you
think are the best territory in the
world when it comes to the extracting
side of things
so
again it because the US have been doing
it for so long and that you know all
extractors are definitely not created
equally I've been to sort of 25 we're
very close to our extractors you know
work exclusively over with um with IAH
in Oregon
they've got machines that are from Roto
Chrome and which is a European business
and they deal in absolute specialist
purification so you're getting
you know to to parts per million of each
product or phytochemical whatever it may
be
so I think
you know when you invest in those types
of machines and extraction it makes a
huge difference so at the very front end
with cheap machinery
you know you you don't know what's being
left in there you can't extract the the
bits that you want never mind the sort
of control drugs talking sort of
chlorophyll and lipids and everything
else but when you've got these machines
which you know the seven figure costs
these machines to buy we've got two of
them in that in that facility they're
extremely precise and you know that's
where I think it needs to go
very interesting and move a narrative UK
just a couple of questions that I think
you might be the perfect answer on a
scale of one to [ __ ] show how bad is the
novel food process currently at the
moment
oh
do you know what this one is this is the
the difficult one because
I've got a caveat it all by saying at
the start
this has become so big so quickly as an
industry so to police it was always
going to be incredibly difficult
some of the weight decisions that have
been made would not be what I'd do I
went you know I think it should be done
at ingredient level for a start that if
you've got a safe raw ingredient then
you know by putting it in a chocolate
cookie that's been in the supply chain
for
to 300 years is not going to make much
of a difference and so that that would
be my first thing but what I would say
is
you know there's so many people
that have got into the industry you know
over the last few years
there's so many people that are looking
at abusing the system as well where you
know we were one of the first ones that
got to the next stage on novel foods and
I think there was 74 businesses or 92
businesses originally on that first day
that got across or Aura actually
applications of which we had nine
and then the pressure was put on the FSA
from all sorts of different sources more
sort of documents submitted so they had
to take them through to the next stage
and then let sort of um
discount them at the next sort of part
of the process which was never how it
was meant to be so I'm hoping it's going
to be sorted soon but I'm also not
holding my breath
yeah do you think it's a case out
because Europe is so heavily influenced
by the farm industry that the synthetic
and the biosynthesized molecules are
going to be the ones that they end up
going well we know this site this is
replicable this is going to be easier
for us to manage than extracted plant
matter
yeah I think that that does make it
easier but I think the problem with it
is
consumers don't want that product you
know they they want a natural
alternative that really works and you
know the vast majority of people in CBD
believe in the Entourage effect and that
it's the raw plan with you know some of
the other minor cannabinoids working
together so I don't actually think
consumers want so you're almost not
solving the problem because that you
know people still want to buy the sort
of natural alternatives
so I think this you know one of the
things is that the industry hasn't done
itself any favors as well by
proving a lot of these
things and you know some of them are
massive money if you're doing a global
study and it's 25 million that's you
know a lot of cash to fund and there are
some companies doing that but
unfortunately it's more of the sort of
big farmer and what we're doing at the
moment is
um studies at University so we sponsor
PhD courses in like Prof dot courses and
with that we do studies about
you know you're in build up
um how it works for sort of sleep with a
blind Placebo test and things like that
and I think
we've got to build up the evidence as
well as an industry to show how safe
this product is and how well it works
for people
yeah I think the efficacy and the
clinical trials and they're proven that
uh statistics are going to outweigh just
people's nuanced opinions on this but
one or two questions on the UK how
realistic is the UK going to have an
adult use cannabis marker within the
next five years
so I think about five years would be a
sort of timeline at the moment we're
actually in the process of buying a
pharmacy license and moving into metcan
ourselves
we're the same in Germany where we've
got a venture set up over there
and
like Germany's getting this recreational
Market you know hopefully fully
legalized in 12 months in 2024 around
then and the more that I hear about it
and the more as time goes on it just
makes absolute sense where
you know we can there's tax money to be
made out of it as well and it not to be
the sort of
[ __ ] show of the states as well Excuse
excuse the French but um
you know that sexually illegal you know
heavily taxed per state you can't move
it interstate and everything else to
sort of create proper Commerce so
I do think we'll do it but I think we're
still sort of five years ago we're
definitely going to be behind the
Germans and watching what they do I
think yeah the Czech Republic as well
look like they might even steal a march
on Germany with the the Coalition of
politicians they've got at the moment
yeah you I spoke about this yesterday
actually and um
that is going to be a really interesting
one we we have a facility one of our
partners over in the Czech Republic that
made capsules for us and incredible
business
and you know they're looking into they
they do a lot of CBD capsules now as
well and
somebody like that is well placed in a
market that's but that should be the UK
especially after we've brexited and
everything else we should be the ones
that are growing this with you know cgmp
Farms that are exporting to all these
European countries and exporting now
that we've taken it back you know what
didn't want to brexit I'm just going to
say as well but
um especially to an Irishman
um
we're but we've got to make the most of
it now if if this is what we've done
then we've got to take the laws into our
own hands and look at how we can this
industry is going to be enormous in 10
years time you know never mind how big
it is now we're playing the long game
here and it's it's just going to get
bigger and bigger as more places
legalize but if we don't get a move on
we'll be left behind we'll be an
importer instead of an exporter the
people who you know aren't making the
cash out of it are the ones who are
supplying the cash to everybody else
yeah you would have told what the Tories
being empowered that they're very
business friendly and they facilitated
the GW Pharma r d that allowed the Jazz
acquisition I think Richie siddock just
seems to be the worst possible person in
charge at the worst possible time for
the Cannabis industry in the UK
yeah and for me I think it's a vote
winner with the public but
you know without getting too political
the donors behind the Tory party and
everything else what's their sort of
interests in allowing you know
sort of have they got alcohol have they
got farmer Investments all of these
types of things where and they're the
guys that don't want this the farmer
guys the alcohol to be pushed through
yeah it seems to me that Europe is going
to spill into its own model where it'll
be Social Clubs Allah Spain that'll
start to dominate around Europe and
it'll be more known for profit
organizations as opposed to profit heavy
dispensaries for cookies and whatnot in
the states and then the other half of
the industry is going to be applied
pharmaceutical ingredients that are
going to be Pharma companies will take
control of a couple of molecules and
create a range of medicines from that
seem to be there will be a massive
divide between the two sectors
yeah that's that's what what I always
say it you know big Pharma doesn't want
you to grow your own medicine do they no
no same way as McDonald's don't want to
give you the recipe to their Big Mac we
want you to come in and eat the whole
thing themselves totally
so tell me this it's really a 15 minutes
what are the things you're looking
forward to over the next 12 to 24 months
which you guys and all the projects you
have working on
so
um really excited about metcal
um that's really this year going to be a
big Focus for us in the different
territories
um
CBD expansion into the Far East we're
already sort of trading in the Far East
but that's going to be further and you
know some of other wellness products and
we've just got so much good MPD that
we've worked on over the last year two
years that some have been soft launched
some into different territories and
we're going to expand that across
everywhere but I think that the big
thing with that is because of the way
novel Foods worked and everything else
it's been a bit restrictive on MPD
whereas we're gonna can't do it in the
UK but everywhere else is going to see
some fantastic products coming this year
amazing well it's great to talk to you
Paul hopefully we can chat up towards
the end of the year and get an update on
all the great things that have got to be
happening with nature Canada medcan but
for now thank you very much for your
time and it's a pleasure to chat you
thanks very much for having me Owen
cheers
[Music]