actually for um
[Music]
welcome everybody to cannabis review i'm
delighted to be joined by two of
ireland's pioneers in the cannabis
industry into the loudest voices it's
great to be joined by natalie regan and
martin from martin's world how are you
getting on guys
excellent very good oh good
excellent thanks very much for joining
me on today's show
um i'm going to get started on a topic
that we can kind of kick into that's
been making a lot of the headlines
at the moment a lot of people already
know who you are can you
give us your uh overview and what's
happened with the little collins
reaction that
your lawyer said do you want to give us
exactly the breakdown of what you think
has happened and why it's happened for
the audience well i'm not a lawyer yet
but i'm on the road to becoming one i'm
studying and trying to qualify at the
moment
but the the cusp of what's happening
with little collins is they are a cbd
uh business in galway and kilkenny and
they sell a range of cbd products from
butter to foodstuffs to oils to flour
all cbd and all
permitted under eu law because they
contain less than two percent
0.2 percent thc so in the last i think
may 2019 was their first raid and
they've gotten raided by the guards
repeatedly
since then i think four or five times
and
the issue up until recently was that
um ireland has no has a zero tolerance
policy to thc in our legislation
so regardless if it's cbd or not whether
it's eu permitted or not ireland's law
ha
is silent on thc so any my new trace of
thc
and cbd products by default are illegal
so they've been targeted they've been
raids they've had all their stock taken
off of them
and jp currently has a criminal
proceedings
against him due to this so we had
a recent kind of vape case in november
2020 from the eu so the ecj in that case
stated that
um the mark the member states cannot
prohibit the marketing of cbd products
and that is lawfully produced in other
member states in their member states so
ireland cannot ban cbd products that are
lawfully produced in another eu member
state country
but unfortunately our misuse of drugs
act hasn't been amended to reflect that
yet
so we are now in a position where eu
have
legally permitted cbd products but
ireland because of our silence on thc
content
cbd products are effectively illegal
so that is where we are today so we are
what's the process for getting that
amended they would have to
amend the misuse of drugs act so in the
misuse of drugs act it just says the
cannabis sativa plant is illegal
and it's scheduled under their misuse
the drug schedule
so they would have to amend that to say
either the cannabis plant is not illegal
which we would all love because it would
bring in legalization
but failing that they'd have to amend it
to
uh allow 0.2 percent thc
that opens up a whole kind of word
support
sorry there's no path forward at the
moment for people to amend that
uh for the audience to understand that
uh we we
we've now got the problem is there a
solution that we can we can present to
the audience as to look if we do x y and
z this is how we can amend this to have
the zero point three percent
thc quantity uh allowed in there
well it's just campaigning to the
minister for justice and the minister
for health and the t shock and raising
your voice loud enough so they'll have
to hear you
unfortunately we're not getting very
good responses from any of the
departments at the moment
so you contact the department of justice
and helen mcintyre will save the
department of health issue
you contact stephen donnelly in the
department of health they'll say it's
justice
issue you'll contact the t-shock and he
will say oh i'm talking to
helen mcinty the mr minister of justice
about this
but then again helen mcinty will say she
has no idea
that it's not in her remit go back to
stephen donnelly
so at the moment you're just getting run
around in circles from department to
department
um with no satisfactory response like
even if they turned around and said
we're working on it
yeah we'd accept a timeline like we
understand that these things do take
time they can't be changed overnight
it's not a click of the fingers action
that can be taken
but at the moment there is no
willingness to engage
from any governmental departments on
this issue and i think that is
the the crux of the story is they're
still they're still raiding premises
they're still
targeting cbd businesses and they're
still criminally prosecuting people for
cbd but at the same time from
where i'm sitting it only seems to be
certain businesses that are getting
targeted
you're not seeing the likes of holland
and bearish or booths
or anything like that who also stock cbd
products you're not seeing
the same level of enforcement to those
businesses as you would to the
the small local cbd shops in ireland
okay and martin are you hearing the same
it's it's the
we we'd be hearing it as well the deaf
ears you go to one department
you go to another department and you
just keep getting pushed from person to
person how are you coming across
your interactions with the guards and
members of politics so far
yeah well i've been campaigning for a
long time i
aired some protest that we attended back
in 2011 yesterday that was from the 420
protest of 2011
and even back then we were saying a lot
of the the similar things we were saying
today we had
luke mean flanagan down at that event we
had vincent lavery
it was an amazing uh very well attended
event um
but unfortunately here we are today
where we still don't have access to
cannabis we have a medical cannabis
access program
but still nobody's gotten access through
it we have a few patients who have
ministerial
uh license um but that that few is
isn't anywhere near the the many who who
need access to it
um so it seems like uh they're just i
don't know what they're biding their
times maybe to get things lined up so
big industry can come in and because it
seems there's no interest there at all
for
allowing somebody like little collins
let's say for setting up their business
they're coming down heavy on them
but meanwhile the likes of gw
pharmaceuticals
and are being sold for our 7.2 billion
and they're making massive deals so on
one hand we're criminalizing people
trying to set up industry here in
our own irish people and meanwhile we're
kind of like applauding these other big
massive companies who
are looking to sell into ireland uh the
same products we're criminalizing these
other guys for
and i don't know i i don't blame people
for thinking there's a conspiracy out
there to keep cannabis
illegal and because when you try to
engage with the politicians
and they don't take you seriously that
they treat you is not
very well pointed out they start making
you running around and chasing your tail
effectively
and you just have to think that there's
something bigger i play that they're not
willing to
play ball at all and because this isn't
an issue that we only brought up
yesterday as i said that protest i
aired yesterday was from 2011 and the
campaign for cannabis legalization i
believe it started back in 1990
um in cork so it's uh it's it's a sad
situation here today that uh patients
they're
they're seeing people benefit from
cannabis and they're not getting access
to that cannabis themselves because of
ignorance uh out there and unwillingness
to engage in conversations around
cannabis and cannabis and medicine
yeah i think it's a complete lack of
understanding has put fear in them that
nobody wants to put their neck on the
chopping board
and to a degree you can understand that
but at the end of the day the
politicians are there to serve the
people and enough of the people wants a
specific
thing then surely it is a workaround and
a responsible solution that
if you got the community together
everybody be able to put their two cents
in and be able to come up with the most
regulated and well-worked industry that
we could all come up because i think
everybody agrees
nobody wants this anywhere near children
nobody wants this anywhere near
teenagers this is a an adult use
product as is alcohol and it should be
treated no differently we
i think we'd all agree on that yeah i
certainly agree with you
okay perfect i've got a question for you
about now and i'm going to let you go
first
timeline for legalization what's your
dream scenario
and your kind of expectations of reality
martin's laughing because he already
gave out to me for my comments on this
people
[Laughter]
my my dream is to have it legalized
tomorrow i have a legalized yesterday
like we are ireland as a country are
falling
so far behind the rest of the world
we're being laughed at
like we are absolutely being laughed at
globally by experts of
just our draconian laws our draconian
approach
it is ridiculous like ireland as an
agricultural economy have the
perfect island and the perfect scenario
to introduce
cannabis legalization and have it
homegrown
and have an irish industry of it and
irish products are loved all over the
world and i'm sure cannabis and hemp
won't be any different when the time
comes
so i think realistically i'd love to
have it done tomorrow that is my dream
but how long are we stuck with this
government who aren't going to engage
with us
and that's what i'll base my answer is
on how long are they going to be in
government
how long before we actually have
meaningful change and a meaningful
government that are actually going to
listen to the people and implement what
we want implemented
and implement what we need in this
country and a way forward in this
country
okay yeah
i certainly don't think natalie's wrong
in what she's saying i would agree with
her that uh
currently as it stands the way we look
at the scene
and i think we we are looking at until
the government changes
and but what i'm hoping to do i do see a
way in which like if
i didn't like the answer natalie gave us
she said and uh that that was
at the end of gino's event but i do
believe that they're not wrong on what
they're saying but
i do believe we can change that we can
speed it up and it's the the people can
be the catalyst in it
and that that's my that's why i'm out
there engaging in civil disobedience
protests
um because i i don't want to give
legitimacy to the law by respecting it
it's a it's a law that disrespects me
it discriminates against me and i don't
want to give it legitimacy and i don't
think anybody out there all should be
giving it legitimacy i think we should
be all marching down to the
guard station presenting ourselves
whether it be in in
kind of a solidarity with little collins
or whether it be just in solidarity with
the cannabis community at large
um we don't deserve this treatment and i
i think we could bring
the system to a halt and by people just
showing up at
the doors of a guard station and
together collectively
and just saying look we're here and
we're breaking this law
and um go do your job now if if you can
at all
um i believe if the whole community
stood up and actually engaged in
a meaningful way in this massive
disobedience kind of campaign
and the guys at the top would have no
choice but to address the issues because
the
the people working on the the floor they
won't be
able to keep up with the paperwork that
they wouldn't even have enough
room there to keep up with the share
volume of paperwork that would have to
go through the station
to deal with what i would hope would be
a very large
campaign of civil disobedience again as
it stands currently there's about a
two-year backlog in the the court system
so that's you have a right uh in
under your human rights i believe uh to
a speedy an expedient
trial and so if the backlog gets the
tree in foyers
i believe again another breach of your
your human rights there
where you're not even getting your trial
seen to in an expedient time
because i do believe that the misuse and
drugs act that has violated our human
rights in in more ways than our
constitutional rights in more ways than
one
and um yeah i think we we we have an
opportunity now really just to take uh
the system and bring it to a halt
but i think like with the little collins
thing recently for many
in the cannabis community like martin is
doing this a lot longer than i am
it's the straw that broke the camel's
back for many people like enough is
enough
like you're gone beyond targeting
cannabis users
and personal possession now you're now
targeting cbd like it's getting a bit
ridiculous now
and i think it is the straw that broke
the camel's back for a lot of people
and
it's a pity that that was the straw
because their business at the end of the
day and that
they knew the risk that they were taking
but there's been patients up in front of
judges before i've seen i've reported on
cancer patients who have been
criminalized for
growing cannabis and the judge would
completely dismiss
all of their claims that they were used
are growing it for medical reasons
and there was never an outpouring of
support from the cannabis community for
for those people um
unlike uh what little collins has got
and i commend the community for it i
think it's great but i would love to see
that reflected to each and every person
who's brought the court for a cannabis
conviction because
we're all in this together we're all
being targeted by the same misuse of
drugs act
and it's discrimination i believe it
better it is
yeah now and i think little collins got
the media uh
behind us with uh the use of social
media at the moment
not every case gets to see the light of
day unfortunately
and some do slip through the cracks um
i'm gonna finish on one last topic
and i think it's something that it's
worth highlighting
our irish cannabis community seems to be
growing every week
seems to be new young entrepreneurs you
you educated voices
some current educated voices who've been
doing this decades you've been doing
this long time again like yourself
martin
um it's in a good positive place at the
moment would you agree
and a second question do you think we
need a centralized database now
to start gathering all the different
businesses and different publications so
we can
present this as a create a jobs report
and maybe kind of try and present some
financial
data to the politicians and prove how
much this industry is worth to the
government
like i don't think that ultimately
what they're going to listen to the most
is money yeah
they're not going to listen to sob
stories they're not going to listen to
all this poor fellow that poor girl
they're not going to listen to any of
that what they're going to listen to
is money and money talks when you're
talking to the government
and i think if you can present them with
a realistic
realistic workable situation i think
there will be a lot
faster to listen then if you just if you
kind of like oh
just turn up with sob stories shall we
say no they're not sob stories either
because they're valid people and they're
they're important in their lives
if you're being ruthless like you can
get immune to the substories
as you were saying it's about having a
bit more depth behind that
yeah and i think like you you do have to
like even in my i've done a couple of
tweets recently where they've
uh confiscated x amount of cannabis and
i've said right 20
basic 20 v80 look how much is going back
to the revenue
if you break it down that simple i think
they will actually listen
but i think at the same time they're
probably uninterested
and frankly they probably couldn't be
bothered
they don't want to do the work for
themselves they don't want to do the
research they don't want to
actually see if this if cannabis
legalization is a viable
option so i think it's on the shoulders
of everybody else to
turn around and present this to
government
yeah agree martin yeah i would agree
with you there certainly that the uh
the cannabis community is growing uh in
more ways than one
um certainly online that there's been
more and more uh
people stepping out of the shadows and
becoming vocal around it
um i wish there'd be more vocal all
along and uh we're even louder in their
support uh people like
blind boy um like he kind of came into
this situation there recently
and but again i would love to see maybe
somebody like blind boy uh engage in a
civil disobedience protest if he uh
believes that cannabis should be
legalized so much because uh
you're not put put your uh money where
your your emotion kind of thing uh
but but uh yeah i definitely do think
the cannabis community is getting a lot
stronger and there's
uh definitely moves being made by the
activists now to try to form a
centralized
kind of movement to try to bring all the
different groups in under the one
umbrella in order to unify our voice and
so
we can be stronger more uh more
efficient in uh being
heard by the politicians i think it's
important that we're all
pretty much uh saying that the same
things um
and we can't really do that until we
start having conversations together so
there is efforts there to bring the
cannabis community
uh together um not just so or so to the
border but not north of the border too
it seems like there's an all ireland
affair
um happening at the moment within the
cannabis community uh bought norton so
even across the the pond in the uk it
seems like uh
the the branches are all the general run
together um so to speak
yeah nowadays it's excellent to see the
industry grow as it is and i hope that
uh
we can maybe do this once every two
months or something like that get the
three of us together and have one of the
chats and give an update on the industry
to the people because
as much as we focus a lot on the
business side of things it's always
great to have a uh
education and information to available
to everybody and to
be able to promote the issues like
little collins and stick up with them
when they when they do happen and not be
silent on it so
thank you both very much for joining the
show no problem it's a pleasure
thanks for having us yes have a great
day everybody and we'll chat you soon