[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i am delighted to be
joined on this episode the founder of
puff and stuff based on cork is jim
weather's gym how are you keeping today
not too bad thank you and i really
appreciate you having me on delighted to
have you on major big news at the moment
over here in little old ireland so
yourself and jp are causing the right
old ruckus can you maybe give everybody
an overview maybe not the start of the
story of puff and stuff but from the
initial first uh
legal processes that you guys went
through when that started and what
instigated that process so we can get
everybody as much information in the 15
minutes yep yep um so basically in 2000
in may and 2019 we were rated um
and so that's that was basically a week
before jp was rated so we were rated on
a saturday and then he was rated the
following on friday
um the difference really though between
our cases is um even though it's
pertaining the same products jp's
started from um
being rated by by customs because of
importing a product where we were rated
because an individual bought a product
from us was walking down the street and
then was stopped and searched by the
guards and then
when he told them that he bought that at
us from our shop
they came in the following day and asked
for samples which we gave with no
problem and and showed them the lab
reports confirming what the content of
thc was
um they were kind of um
oblivious to um the difference between
cannabis and hemp um so
about seven months after that um we got
raided and uh they came in and seized
all the products from us
and then um then left and then about
three months after that then they came
in and arrested me
um and then seven months after that then
they arrested my wife so right now both
my wife and i are being charged with uh
sale and distribution of cannabis
okay so all of the proceedings that
we've been seeing over the last week or
two have stemmed from those initial
first processes
yeah so what happened was so we were
rated in may and then in january of 2020
uh jp and us both filed judicial reviews
to have our cases thrown out because of
what the um basically they're you know
is unconstitutional what they're doing
um it's against eu um you know we're
following within eu laws so um we filed
a judicial review exactly the same week
and at that time the judiciary review
board put our two cases together so for
the past year just over a year
our cases have been running in
conjunction with each other
since then there's been numerous other
cases um
coming about so basically from my
understanding that they're just um
they're going through the process as
well but the two biggest high-profile
cases would be jp and or laurel collins
and pup and stuff now
little collins has been a lot more vocal
than i have been um during the first
four months of our encounter with the
guards and being raided and arrested you
know i was publicly out on you know
in the newspapers on nearly every radio
station but then i was advised with my
solicitor that i needed to stop
it was really pissing them off
that i was out there
making a wave for them so i stopped and
then jp just continued on so since then
we kind of have been just in the shadows
a lot of people have completely forgot
that we've been
um that we're actually involved in this
and then it's just been recently over
the past couple of weeks um where i've
been starting to get a bit more public
about it um and then jp has been tagging
us to um to include us in in the case
because actually that case like i said
even though we got two separate cases
they're actually being they're exactly
the same case within the high
court okay perfect so you guys are two
separate cases the judicial review put
the two of them together so they could
review them both separately do you have
two separate law entities uh
representing both of you guys or is
there one individual firm now that
represents you both
so we have different um
you know different teams um but they are
working together um
in a sense so basically whatever we file
jp files whatever jp file we file the
exact same thing so at this point in
time um everything is done you know we
followed the last papers uh friday
actually i signed the last um after
david's um so we went to court on
tuesday it got adjourned again until the
22nd of february
what's going to happen on that date i'm
not quite sure
um but from what we're hearing that the
actual hearing date to finalize this is
going to be the 14th and 15th of july is
going to be the um the deciding factor
whether they're going to drop the
charges or
the the judicial review will allow the
prosecution to continue um their case
against us
okay so that's very devil's advocate
let's say the
charges get dropped it's now open season
for the consumer watching this and for
people watching this what does that now
allow have happened in the irish
industry it's obviously not going to
regulate any sort of thc products would
it just move it in line with the zero
point zero three percent level of phc
well the point it would it would put it
in line with 0.2 but
so
um yeah sorry i lost my train of thought
there so france so the exact same case
is going on in france right so that
france has finally changed their their
drug laws to allow 0.3
uh thc in
products whether if it's cbd or food
products so 0.3 is allowed
so that we would suspect that ireland is
going to follow suit
it's going to definitely open the market
you know if we win the traditional
review the cbd market in this country is
going to probably explode but i don't
think it's going to be something that's
going to happen instantaneously because
they're going to have to change the
misuse of drug law which is going to
happen as long as we win the judicial
review that will happen it will allow
the 0.3 or 0.2
now
there has been um rumors i say rumors
i've actually got a letter from a tv not
a td sorry from a minister about three
years ago confirming that they are going
to change the misuse of drug act to
allow 0.3 thc
but the only thing it stated was that
would be in the future well it's been
three years and that still hasn't
happened and here we are we have about
six cases going through the judicial
system costing this state
tons of money for something that they
have already admitted that they're going
to change at some point in time
yeah well if we've learned one thing
throughout this process anybody who
didn't know anthony politics now knows
the policy makers are not the quickest
of animals in the world and you don't
want to have patience and thick skin to
be dealing with them yep so but i mean
so the market's not going to open up you
know you would really hope that that
would happen but because of the drug
laws are not going to be changed and it
could take you know well france actually
did it fairly quickly so it's just a
matter of how quick the irish government
is willing to make that change and then
at that point you know the market's
gonna open but then you're gonna have
the contingency of whether or not
they're gonna make the flower still
illegal which france kind of did um so
france's stance was the exact as ireland
so now they've allowed the point three
percent thc they've allowed extraction
from the flower to produce cbd but
they've out they have banned the sale of
flowers to consumers
so um it would appear that ireland would
hate the same stance but france is
actually being taken to court now
to clarify
that the flower can be sold to consumers
um because it's a huge market i mean it
is it will just be a
very good you know outcome
yeah well we talked to benjamin
alexander john warfra who's the ceo of
augur associates in paris there last
week and i posed the same question is
this the end of the cbd flower sales now
so he lee seems to believe the cat's out
of the bag now um
it's going to find it very hard to put
it back into the into the bag and get
rid of the whole industry otherwise you
end up turning into a black market
industry well that's you know that that
could possibly happen so here's this
could that can you know it's all
contingent on a risk assessment so what
the european court of justice said when
they ruled on the candidate case or
overturned the candidate case in france
basically was that if a member state was
going to completely ban thc
an entirety um that they were not going
to allow any percentages that they would
have to do a risk assessment to prove
that the product that is being sold um
is a risk to um
to consumers and
fortunately for us
um and and france that there is no such
um study done now
there is studies to confirm that there
is no health risk at all so we
definitely have that in our favor but it
appears that france has come up with
something i've heard i don't know
exactly what it is but they've come up
with something to say that it is a
health risk and that that's what they're
grasping at those straws to try and keep
it that way um so i have a feeling that
that could end up going back into the
european court of justice at them to
find make a final decision on that
okay on a little lighter note now you be
a man answered his question so where is
the best cbd flower being produced in
the world at the moment are the north
americans catching up although they've
been thc heavy or have the europeans had
maybe a little bit of a head start when
it comes to this territory where they've
kind of had to deal with this first
well that's an interesting question uh
so if you look at the markets and you
kind of got to split it into threes
right and and what i mean by that is the
united states we'll say north americans
united states and canada um europe and
then and then switzerland on its own so
with the united states and switzerland
the allowed thc amount in a cbd product
is point or sorry is one percent
yeah so um so you cannot include
switzerland in this um now what i've
known in the past with switzerland uh
you know going back almost four years
ago
what they do is they wash their products
um and that is to drop the cannabinoid
profile of percentages
and then they test it again and if it's
not a if it's still above the point two
percent to be sold within the european
market then they wash it again and wash
it and wash it until they get it below
it
so when you go to switzerland you can
you know i think every single petrol
station you can go buy cbd flour but it
is one percent
um so
um so to answer your question i think
that
europe has um
i think really progressed with the lower
percentage of thc products so you can't
really compare switzerland or the united
states within the european market
because of the major difference in
um
is there a quality difference in flower
regardless of the thc content
is there a drastic difference let's say
in terpene levels or in
i think i think for for quality as far
as appearance looks uh it is definitely
going to be um
the lower of the thc content um
the the bushier cut is going to look
like it's going to kind of look like
bushweed um you know so then as that um
starts going
um
with higher thc so getting around the
point 2.3 the flower the plant is going
to look much nicer you know but a lot of
that can you know controlled by also the
you know the grower and how they're
producing it uh or sorry how they're
processing it from you know the drying
to the curing a lot of these people are
now using machines
um to to dry their product which is
causing it to be browner rather than a
green so there is this distinctive
difference now that you can look between
cbd and and cannabis
um cannabis is more of a you know the
greener color where hemp now is tending
to be um the brownish i think that
they're kind of rushing uh their process
that's just you know my opinion um
i mean i'm sure that every single cbd
producer out there you know growing
flowers can't keep up with the with the
demand
you know they need to do whatever they
can to try and get it to market and
expediting the the process of drying it
and curing um i think is uh affecting
the quality of this somewhat
without it the sooner it's regulated and
we get proper sale of approval on
specific products that we're able to buy
as a consumer i think the better for
everybody
agreed yeah for sure well we're up to
our time now thanks very much for uh
coming on the show gm if everybody wants
to check out puff and stuff there's the
website below i'd highly recommend going
checking them out and they're a raw
authentic supplier for europe and i have
a great selection of stuff so the best
look what everything over the next few
weeks jim hopefully we're going to get
to touch base with you uh just after the
case and we've got champagne but
hopefully on the on the 15th the evening
of the 15th of july i hope there will be
some some fireworks and major
celebrations going on because this is
going to be a landmark
um you know it's just the first stages
of of um
of the legalization legalization of
cannabis you know so
it's in the diary there now i will be
back to you beforehand best of luck
thank you very much for coming on the
show it's very much appreciated for
giving your time and uh yeah i hope you
have a great first year evening you too
thanks thanks everybody for watching and
we'll chat you next episode
you