[Music]
welcome everybody to another episode of
cannabis review i'm delighted to be
free is the founder of client ifn
plus law firm over in germany how you
keeping kite
i'm fine hi thank you thanks for having
me i'm delighted to have you on the show
um i've been going through a lot of
europe and talking to a lot of the
leaders and trying to piece together the
entire industry so germany seems to be
is going to be the market leader for
europe and set the kind of blueprint i
think that a lot of other states in the
european union will follow so
great to talk to an expert like yourself
a man who's at the tip of the spear of
this industry you
perfect would you want to uh basically
give everybody just a quick little
overview of how you got into the
cannabis industry and then we'll kick
straight into the three topics
sure sure so i'm a lawyer since 2003
i had a regular life here in the german
countryside
and then germany decided to legalize
medical cannabis in
april 2014 2017 sorry
and then i started a blog on the new
developments on medical cannabis and cbd
came up
at the end of the 17th the beginning of
18 nobody knew in germany what cbd was
and nobody know how to deal with it
legally
what's the legal framework for cbd
products and then
i was invited to write for prohibition
partners
european cannabis reports i was invited
to
the nga bis conference in 18 to toronto
it became a member
of the international cannabis buyer
association and
clients from all over the world from
europe
national international came to me and
sought advice for the german market how
to enter the german market what's the
legal framework here
and since one and a half two years i'm
only doing cannabis
clients cannabis related mandates and
yeah and happy to see what's what's
coming
along this year as well because we'll be
looking for a
fundamental reform and or
fundamental change in cannabis policies
but we will come to that later
okay brilliant amazing salman with a
wealth of experience first type of
conversation i want to talk about is the
german hemp industry
i was reading up and i've done my
research 1982 to 1996 for some reason
the whole industry was banned
is there a reason behind that ban and
what was the reason it got reinstated is
there something people can learn from
that reinstation
from today's legalization
yeah so due to the single convention
which was agreed on in 1961 and the
following
international agreements
from 97 1971
and germany had to comply and
install rules on cannabis and hemp
and by that time cannabis had a real bad
stigma
so they thought we can't even allow low
thc
cultivation on german soil because it's
too complicated the police can't
uh distinguish between high thc low thc
hemp and so they banned it completely
what they then saw was that amp
is an excellent and
a very versatile plant um
because you can make ropes textiles you
can make
for for for construction purposes you
can you can use
ham and that
that came back the the awareness of
hemp as a as a as a power plant
which you can use for for everything so
they decided in 1995 to
have a reform on the cannabis on the
hemp rules
and they wanted to explore the full
market potential of the hemp plant that
was the aim by that time
and then the cultivation was allowed
again
the strict rules though so
the bee farm something like the fda in
america they have to you have to notify
the bee farm that you start
growing that you that you seed the
the hemp seeds then they come
by and control that you really plant
the seeds of the hemp plant because you
get subsidies
from the european union and at the end
of the harvest period
you um have to test it and it has to be
from the european uh variety catalogue
so it has to be a certified eu's variety
and it doesn't it can't exceed 0.2
thc at the moment of harvest 10 days
before
20 days before and 10 days after and the
rules are all laid down in european
um union directives how to test it
at what time and the b farm is coming
and checking if everything is fine and
if the
eu variety exceeds 0.2
two years in a row you can't exceed it
anymore
very very complicated and the biggest
problem for the hemp industry in germany
is
that you can't use really the upper part
because due to the novel food
regulations you can't
you can't really use the the flowers for
extraction
uh as the the extraction
or the extraction market for cbd oils
is not yet has not yet fully unlocked
its potential
as uh you can't sell so much stuff right
now because
the police rates are going after the cbd
shops and stuff like that
so that's a big problem in in comparison
to to canada
and the us and even china
that's the problem which all european
farmers and
german farmers have as well yeah i agree
i think what
you have happening is the law that got
passed by the european council that
doesn't seem to have been enacted across
a lot of the council states we have it
in ireland as well and in one side you
can understand the police have no idea
what a low thc content plan does look
like until it be lab tested so
it's kind of uh one of those myriad out
of uh
murky waters at the moment in terms of
the regulatory
framework in germany how hard is it to
get licensed i have in some other
reading i was doing there was 575
licensed temperature producers in 2019
do you think that's grown significantly
and if so
has it been through an ease of framework
or is it very difficult to apply for
hemp license over in germany
for cultivation you mean yeah
you have to be a farmer and a full-time
farmer
and only farmers are allowed to grow
hemp on the soil and
only outdoor not indoor and it's even
questionable
if you can put a tent on the of the
plants
if you grow it out or so it has to be in
the soil and you have to be a farmer
uh but as a if you're a full-time farmer
you get the license that's no problem
but due to the fact that the the upper
plant
can't really be used at the moment we
have even the problem with hemp tea
empty leaves hemp leaf tea which was on
the shelves
for decades in the german retail and
law enforcement decided a couple of
weeks ago to go after the hemp leaf
traders
and shops you can't imagine
because the things are heating up in in
on the at the horizon of the federal
election because we will
expect a change in cannabis policy so
the the old law enforcement the old war
on drugs
uh warriors uh uh are fighting the
last war so to say but if you can't even
use the leaves
from the from the hemp land which you
need for your for your margin
for your for your uh for your for your
costs
contribution that's pretty hard so
and for the rest of the plan for the
stem and
the the fibers you need a lot of
investments you need
expensive machines to really um
yeah to to get the best out of it and to
make the the best product
for for for every other purpose so it's
it's very tricky it's a very
complicated situation for for hem
calculation
right and tell me this i have something
i'm trying to figure out across all the
different states
as we know the different extraction
types for getting cbd oil are various
we've found out that across uk and
ireland that a cold-pressed isolate
is legal because it hasn't been proved
to be part of the novel food and et
cetera is that the same in germany
are you allowed to freely sell a sale at
cole's pressed iceland cbdo
we were always looking at the website of
the fsa
fsai from from ireland and they always
wrote it on their website the cold
pressed products are not novel food
for a couple of years if you look at
this webpage now
you can't find this sentence anymore but
i'm happy to hear that
the cold press products are still legal
in ireland
and not deemed as a noble food they are
not deemed as another food
in austria as well we know for sure but
we know one court decision
in germany from the administrative court
of schwerin
from may last year they said no
it hasn't been on the market uh before
1997 it's a novel football
and we don't know if this case went to
the court of appeal
so it's not really clear if cold pressed
products
are not novel food and in my opinion
yes because it's not an extraction it's
not you it's not
in the in the novel food catalog they
are only extracts
mentioned
i'm pretty sure you you can find
evidence that uh cold pressed
ham juice has been consumed uh before
1997 to a significant degree
yeah like any any person when i have a
brain would realize to cold press
something doesn't take a huge technology
uh to be able to facilitate that action
the last thing i would like to do is a
dangerous
have been consumed for ages for for
decades
for centuries but no yeah well we had
professor o'neivy
from uh one of the famous universities
in the states on last week and he's a
professor in biology and molecular
science and
he was one of the founders of the cb1
and cb2 receptors
and basically annihilated any reasonable
person's argument
as to the non-existence of an
endocannabinoid system and the benefits
of cannabinoids
to this system so i think what's
happening is
the people who are passionate about
legalizing cannabis on the other side
there's people just as passionate about
keeping it illegal and i think that's
the war that's been fought in europe at
the moment
moving on to the last topic and again as
we were saying before we came on air i
think germany is going to be the model
for a lot of the european states
the way this structure is put into place
who are the top three companies in
germany do you think of at the moment
uh so difficult question because we have
uh
different tiers we have the medical
cannabis space
we have the hemp industry we have the
cbd industry
in the cbd industry you would definitely
have to mention
the sanity group with their brand ray
they had a couple of investment rounds
and they are very present in the german
market
with good with a lot of with a
wide variety of products when you look
at the
medical cannabis market you definitely
would have to mention
the three companies which acquired the
license for for domestic cultivation
which is aurova afria and the dimikan
and if you look at the the the hemp
sector
there are not really big players
but some very important companies like
hampro international from dusseldorf
which which this company is howling and
they do everything from cultivation to
extraction
to hemp seed oil and all the basic food
stuff
for the for the food industry for the
food industry
okay brilliant some good knowledge for
everybody there to research those
companies
last thing i wanted to ask you drone nab
and oil
what are your thoughts on drone knob and
oil
a synthetic version of thc that euro x
the german company are
creating so that seems to be where the
pharmaceutical companies are creating
synthetic versions of cbd and thc
sorry i haven't heard of that so i know
about
synthetic cbd synthetic cbd was
used in cosmetics for a long time
i haven't seen personally one product
with synthetic cbd because it wasn't
listed in the single convention
and you could use it uh according to the
european
cosmetic directive but yeah there's
there's something going on
scientific research and companies are
going for for the synthetic way um but
we will see
it's not very present right now okay
brilliant
well thank you very much for coming on
the show it's been an absolute pleasure
talking to you it's been a wealth of
information i know the viewers would
have liked it as much as i've done
hopefully we can get to touch base as
well towards the end of the year and see
how germany's moved further along the
the line the same at ireland yeah watch
out for germany this year september
federal elections and we will have a
green
green government and they will legalize
with the cannabis control act
and uh the first of january 20 vantage
for the first uh coffee shop
dispensaries will open in germany
there you go you heard that here first
kai thank you very much mate you have a
great day and i look forward to chatting
again soon
thank you bye thanks