[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to
join in this episode by jason spadophora
aka the wolf of weed street who's the
founder of principal street capital how
you doing jason good how are you
fantastic mate thank you very much for
coming on we're going to talk all things
investment and the great profile that
you've built yourself up over the couple
of years and now kind of dominating the
cannabis investing space on twitter so
i'll just jump straight into everything
and maybe we'll go from the first topic
which is many penny stocks to unicorns
do you want to give everybody a little
overview of where the game started in
the canadian kind of small shares and
where you're kind of at at the moment
with the msos in america yeah so i i
actually started in um
2013 um and this was when
um then attorney general eric holder had
given a
statement that the department of justice
was not going to um go after states that
had marijuana laws on the books
um and i was you know a newer investor
and i was like wow cannabis i'm like is
are like pot stocks a thing
um and
i went and and googled it like anybody
else and
i found like 10 companies on this uh
this website
and i ended up buying one i was my first
penny stock i ever bought
um
and it went up like 50
uh
two days later i was like oh my god this
is amazing i'm like what what did i find
like i you know i felt like a discovered
fire and then two days after that it
dropped 50
so i ended up losing 150 bucks
um and i was kind of hooked from there
um
and just kind of trying to you know like
look for these sorts of things and these
were early days you know it wasn't even
canadian companies really they were a
couple
um but not too many you know this is
before canopy aurora chronos and and all
of them
so it really was a crap shoot in the
early days
so yeah and from there
then colorado went legal
and um you know you didn't even really
have unicorns you had like
uh
stables of unicorns because you could
buy something at a half a penny back
then
and
you know watch it go up ten thousand
percent
um which to put that in perspective if
you bought a million shares of the stock
at a half a penny it would cost you five
thousand dollars and if it went to you
know 50 cents
that's a half a million dollars and
people were making money like that you
know the problem was a lot of people
just thought it was going to go higher
and higher and higher
um
and
never took money off the table and then
watched it just go right back
so you know like the
discipline in the early days um was
something that you were forced to learn
um and it's you know something that we
still have trouble with today you know
in 2022 eight years later
okay very interesting just getting that
money off the table at the appropriate
time is the key to this whole game isn't
it
yeah
for sure i've used notice to i've
noticed a kind of let's say an
underground world or reddit forms full
of cannabis investors now that are
starting to get pretty substantial like
we talked to roger forsberg aka puff
daddy he was on the show last week so
i'm starting to notice there's this
little cult
uh
gathering and crew happening on on
twitter and on reddit that's basically
uh tearing the cannabis emissions apart
and building up the kind of first tier
cannabis mso shall we say yeah
yeah i mean you know
i i love that you know
cannabis has always been a cult sector
always
you know and and we've always had our
you know call it like our teams you know
i like this company you like that
company we're gonna beef we're gonna you
know fight it out
um
and and now you've got all these these
teams basically
uh you know like
fighting the people that own the arenas
you know
called the exchanges and whatnot
um
and so
you know these people that we're
adversaries at one point are a little
bit galvanized to kind of like team up
and
and are forced to
explain like to everybody else why this
is still uh a meaningful investment
um you know the the the sector has
just been absolutely hammered you know
when it in terms of from like a capital
markets perspective um now the
businesses on the other hand have been
thriving
um which is
very hard for people to understand and
you know it's a point that i always make
that the business like you could like a
strain of marijuana from one of these
companies
um take like a med men okay like med men
is a great brand you know it's very
visible the stores are nice
um from a capital markets perspective
like a public company
it is
aids it is as close to stock market aids
it's like if aids and ebola had
a baby
that's what med men would be from a
capital markets perspective so you you
have to
um
understand that going into it and now
you see a lot of these people on the
reddit forums twitter trying to explain
that to to all these people that it's
not so much a problem with the companies
it's a problem with
um the exchanges that they're on it's a
problem with that there's only 95
percent um
or there's instead there's 95
retail ownership and only 5
institutional
which basically means that
all these stocks are being priced in by
complete morons and you know i and i say
that
all the time that i think pot stock
investors
um you know
90 of them are probably the dumbest
people in the world yeah well i think
there's a lot to be left to the
imagination if you can't read a balance
sheet or read a profit a loss sheet or
even see what kind of cash flow some of
these companies have i think that's what
seems to be happening is that the mass
or vast majority of campus investors
have no nuanced financial skill and
somebody basically been able to explain
to them look this is why this stock is
man united and this stock is real madrid
or why i think there's a lot of value
and i think that's going to be
the next let's say wave of financial
gain in the industry i see it as the
media and the info the
influencers being able to have a direct
voice to these large consumer bases as
you said some are truly some are cure
relief it all depends it's almost like a
little a tribal situation that seems to
be happening in the the
retail investor market
yeah for sure
um
yeah and you know it's also
there's a little bit of nuance in there
as well as being an investor in this
space um you know like you always and
i'm sure you've seen it where i think
that people that dollar cost average in
cannabis are always going to get killed
um meaning like they have a budget and
i'm going to buy some here i'm going to
buy some air and then i'll buy some a
little bit further down if it goes down
i just buy some more that's never worked
um you know i've always been somebody
that core trades position meaning like i
have a set position
um that i buy usually in the summer time
and i have uh like call that eighty
percent i don't touch and then with that
20 on the upswing i do trade it as a
means to grow the entire position but
also take it as almost like a dividend
uh meaning like
i'll give you a quick
rundown say i buy a thousand uh
shares of the stock at um ten dollars
and then it goes to eleven dollars well
i sell 250 shares okay so that's 25
all right well now it goes back down to
10 and i i rebuy it i don't buy back i
just buy back 250 shares i pocket the
difference which is the 250 bucks and i
save it for a rainy day um and that
served me you know also like going into
um february to the summer which is the
back half of the year and that time
period which i call the odds of march
like you're not buying you're not taking
on size um the market has
sucked since 2014 from march to summer
um you know that's when you're
uh you're not increasing your exposure
you're decreasing it and you're waiting
for that that summer low
to you know buy stuff back you know i
can and then like my last and final rule
is if anything that i own ever hits an
all-time high in february
um which is right before that march
start i sell 30 of the position
no matter what um and that's
at a minimum
so in february of 21 where everything
hit an all-time high
just doing that um saved me a lot of
grief across the board
you know so there is some nuance this
isn't you know you have to remember
these are all speculative companies at
the end of the day in a sector that is
going to be wildly different 10 years
from now
than it is right now you know if you go
back to when prohibition ended there was
like 300 companies you know now there's
10 and maybe you can name five
right
yeah now i agree the amount of
information and data and i think you
need to be consuming at your level that
people aren't just going to be able to
pick the right
solution off the bat from researching
companies to board the ceo looking at
the balance sheet profit and loss sheets
the history of the relationships that
have been had at that company i think
there's a huge amount of data that needs
to be
consumed on a daily basis to make those
nuanced decisions i'm going to jump on
to the next topic and it's basically the
wolf of weed street the moniker you have
on twitter did that just come out of the
movie and you put one and one together
and got two or was there yeah
that's exactly what happened um actually
um i was engaged at the time and my
fiancee went out with a bunch of her
friends and um
and i
just so happened to have off and i was
doing something completely different
at the time and
i was like oh and nobody's home i was
like i'm gonna you know smoke a joint
and watch some tv
and
so that's what i did and i saw a trailer
for
um the wolf of wall street
and i was like
haha wolf of weed street that would be a
funny name
and um i was like i bet somebody on
twitter already has it so i went to
twitter and nobody had it
and i was like
stoned and i was like oh just make a
goof of it and i put like a photoshopped
head of a wolf
on leonardo dicaprio's body
and
you know it's just a goof to start and i
was like man
i can talk about all of these companies
that i'm like are really scammy
um anonymously and and that's what i was
doing you know like no recourse like i
could just say whatever i wanted to say
um
and
that's exactly what i did and people
were really
uh you know responsive to it you know
they they liked it and i just kind of
like showed things and
and you know at the end of the day like
we were all kind of in the same boat
there was not a lot of information out
there
in the sector so one of the things that
i did was i was using people
um you know
via twitter to see if a lot of these
early companies were real or if they
were po boxes so i would send somebody
up i'd say hey
does anybody live in you know like
colorado springs and somebody be like
yeah i do
um okay i'll send you a hundred bucks
on paypal if you could go to this
address
um and
if it's a p.o box just take a picture if
it's not here's some questions to go in
and ask and people were doing it
we were finding a lot of companies that
were just po boxes
um so
you know from there that developed like
the wolf pack
and then and i you know i had a small
amount of followers and colorado had
gone legal
um and then one of my friends who you
know
called me randomly one day and he's like
i want you to sell all of your pot
stocks and i was like why would i sell
i'm like i'm killing it
um
and he's like uh
there's a thing there's an article
coming out on bloomberg blah blah blah
and he's like and i'm watching he's like
there's like short positions like
building up
and he's like i was like okay so and
he's like i got a bloomberg terminal i
was like what's a bloomberg terminal
and so i get off the phone with him and
my account is at an all-time high
and i was like you know what let me just
tweet his warning
and i was like you know sector takedowns
in effect blah blah blah
and uh i get up you know like
30 minutes later hour later
the whole entire cannabis market and i
think this is january 10th
um
2014 dropped 60
in an afternoon in an afternoon so i
remember my account was at like 75 000
and at the end of the day it was it
closed at like 29 000.
now because i've been looking at the
sector so hard
i had a pretty good idea where like
what the good companies were and and
where it would balance
um so i kind of divided what what i have
left into these companies and you know
everybody just kind of followed along
and then the wolf just kind of
uh got bigger and bigger from there
oh it's an amazing story if anybody's
not following i should highly recommend
that you go and get over to twitter and
follow the wolf of wall street or wheat
street um last thing before we go i want
to just touch on the true trading group
that you're a part of can you give
everybody just a little overview of that
uh organization
yeah so
um it's great uh you know during co like
this is something because you know when
we were going back and i just talked
about that first website that i went on
to find uh pot socks that was
marijuanastocks.com and that was a site
that uh myself and my two other partners
mike and adam um ended up buying
um which was kind of like full circle
and then true trading group was
um an idea
um that adam had
uh to you know basically get out of the
investor relations world and you know
make it
like an educational platform think of it
like netflix but for trading where
you know you pay one price and then you
get
um all these things you know like all
the content all the
you know courses the tests everything
all in one place
um and then during and then code would
and
you know i i
honestly like i i really didn't want
much to do with it and then
um kobet hit
and i was get i was already doing it on
twitter like telling people what i was
buying and i just found like all these
people were really ungrateful
i became a moderator there um and now a
part owner
and
we basically start with like 300 people
now we're at 10 000 with the whole idea
of like
there's a lot of things that you don't
know
um and you know there's a whole
psychological aspect to investing um and
trading that nobody talks about um
you know so
true trading group has really just
become like this this monster of a
platform
where people can can learn
um and listen to people that you know
have done it are doing it um plus have
the benefit of like you know uh 5 000
other eyeballs
out there um with all these things where
you know if you don't want to trade real
money we've got uh you can paper trade
we have like simulators
um we have
you know
live squawk so you get news as it
happens
um
and
you know
really it's just a place
where you can learn like we make you
take tests so if you want to like learn
options okay well we have a whole course
on options and you've got to go through
it and take a test and that's how you
you know that you're ready
so we set up a reward system
um you know through there
it's
yeah it's pretty cool um and you know
people can try it out for like three
bucks
for a week and you get some courses and
then you can also listen to us like
throughout the course of the day
it's not just about like getting alerts
and somebody telling you what to do
um because that that doesn't that only
worked so long right you want to be able
to make your own trades and and
ultimately that's that's the goal um and
then people stay
um for the ideas
amazing yeah i'd highly recommend
everybody checking it out all of the
details we posted at the links below for
everybody and if you're not following
wolf of walls weed street get it sorted
now jason thank you very much for
joining me mate it's been an absolute
pleasure chatting to you
thank you hopefully we get to chat again
in the near future we're going to start
keeping an eye on the european stocks
for you guys soon so there'll be lots of
opportunities coming over here with
germany legalizing now hopefully
i know i know i'm i'm involved in a
company in germany
um
so yeah we'll have to talk about that
one day too we will indeed mate you have
a great day and thanks again for your
time thank you thanks everybody