foreign
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I'm delighted to be
joined on this episode by Boris
moshkovitz Boris is their co-founder and
the managing director of Alice sana a
pharmaceutical wholesaler importer and
exporter they've been providing the
supply of individual cannabis therapies
for patients since 2019. Boris how are
you keeping today
all good thank you for having me I'm
delighted to have you all now a man
who's a Cornerstone of the European
industry at the moment it's great to
maybe get you out and give everybody an
overview of some of the things that are
happening do you want to maybe give
everybody a quick little review of how
you ended up co-founding a managing
director of Alabama
sure it's been a ride I mean we started
in 2019 we found it out of uh Zan as a
pharmaceutical wholesaler I myself I've
been in this industry since 2016
um as let's say an activist of a voice
in the industry uh why at that point it
wasn't even an industry but it was a
group of people fighting for the right
to have a medical cannabis as a therapy
so by 2017 the law came about in Germany
that was the moment when uh it was legal
to prescribe it and uh receive it
through the pharmacies and then that
time I found my first company for
cultivation
um didn't work out that tender uh was
thrown out in court so I started this
company elizana has been in the industry
since 2019 we got our licenses and since
2020 we're selling a pharmaceutical
cannabis to Pharmacy supplying patients
all over Germany there's 22 000
pharmacies in Germany and more and more
pharmacies are getting uh the hang of it
are understanding that there's a say
it's a legit and and viable uh
medicine that is being provided
yeah it seems to be Germany's going to
be the Cornerstone of the European
industry and what happens there should
have good Ripple effects across the
industry I'm going to start straight
away with the first topic which is the
pharmaceutical cannabis industry and a
pretty straightforward question where is
the most playing near pioneering in the
pharmaceutical cannabis industry is it
North America or is it Europe
I believe we do take impulses from all
over the world in Germany but the
advantage of Germany is to know that we
have started we're looking at Canada at
North America but we're also looking at
Israel where uh pharmaceutical cannabis
is uh basically all over the place in
every Pharmacy and um I would say that
we have a lot of innovation here and the
sense of providing to patients and then
just the system because we have the
first system that is reimbursing
medicinal cannabis for patients so they
apply and they get it and no matter
where they stand
um but from a research point of view I
believe that there's a lot to be learned
in the modes of delivery and this is
something that we see more in Israel
than we see in North America North
America is especially looking at the
United States it's still a lot flower
driven maybe extracts uh but um the
future is more in formulations finished
products medical devices so there's a
lot to do and a lot to be learned and
gathered and I think in that regard
Germany's can be the Melting Pot of all
influences from around the world
okay very interesting mentored Blends
and formulations there it's one of the
key things that we think is going to be
the future of the pharmaceutical side of
the industry and it brings me on to the
next topic I wanted to talk about which
is the thought of biosynthesis so you
guys Supply dranabadal which is a
synthetic THC product do you see
biosynthesis becoming a Cornerstone of
the pharmaceutical cannabis industry or
is it still a number of years away from
being perfected
look from
from where we stand we've been talking
to Partners who are investing in in that
sector of the industry and they're
investing in clinical studies because in
the end it is about creating
formulations isolating more synthesizing
um those formulations
um that we can match with indications to
do that we need the clinical studies and
that is an investor traditionally in the
Pharma industry where you can protect
your intellectual property
um and in the past this has been the
difficulty in the Cannabis industry
because there was nothing to be
protected but Brands
um so I do believe that the medical
space we will see more of that coming
and the next two or three years
um definitely more so and that's going
to happen as well as in the states as
well as in Europe
um we will be providing and that to
patients by securing marketing
authorizations licensing products but
we're not doing the research ourselves
or development but we're on the on that
end um or of the say Market access and
distribution marketing provider
okay so biosynthesis seems to give the
producer of the end product much more
protection whether it's on the process
that they create the substrate that they
use and then the potential for medical
trials coming from an already
pharmaceutical grade company is that
correct
absolutely
um I think somewhere in between what we
see is the the organic formulation so
what we call extracts and which we see
now as as oils and and eventually
vapable oils
um tinctures this is the the go-between
step
um biosynthesis will will just be
more of a scalable process and thus we
will see big Pharma getting involved and
then creating real alternatives to pain
medication and possibly other
indications that we just have to explore
secure and really reliable uh
communicate at this point there's a lot
of guessing and a lot of uh No Label
prescriptions or off-label prescriptions
I mean what the most successful product
is a pedial x which is a high CBD
tincture that is for seizures uh as a
first line medication but at the end
it's being prescribed for a wide range
of indications as an off label and with
flower we know it's it's No Label uh
prescription all together so why since
he says well just um streamline the
whole process be more uh focused and and
more clear to all everybody involved
doctors pharmacists patients and uh and
careful takers
yeah and it seems to be in the biosity
space so it's corporate the Innovative
companies we see are targeting the
actual CB1 and CB2 receptors themselves
and based on some research this the
focus of 30 of all FDA approved drugs
are are focused on receptors so do you
see that as being a new Avenue let's say
for the Cannabis industry that is
basically untouched as of yet uh for the
companies to to do more research and
development and develop products that
are going to be able to take patients to
the next level of care
um it's not an entirely new approach I
mean the the research of the
endocannabinoid system has been going on
since uh I guess the 50s but uh more
recently uh we do look not only at the
cannabinoids themselves but also at the
Inhibitors and other forms of and or
enhancers
um to uh to utilize these receptors more
effectively also in the context of other
medications because it's rarely that
it's just a cannabis therapy it's it's
often a mixed form of therapy so we have
to understand how these receptors
interact with other forms of medication
and thank you so the next topic I wanted
to jump onto was sourcing the best
products you guys are a wholesaler
importer and exporter is there a
specific process that you guys go to
just try and find the next best product
that's coming to the market or is it
generally a case of the the
manufacturers themselves have got good
marketing campaigns or have got good
Outreach programs where they're able to
find the companies like yourselves and
you can marry the two companies together
and we continue to scout the industry uh
worldwide and and that we're doing a
couple of levels on one level is
getting the best flour dried flour
because currently still two-thirds of
the market in Germany has dried flowers
and um there we had questions of quality
and we still do
um as you know eugnp in Germany is to
required quality level but at the same
time we see gcp to GMP hubs
um spread
um all over Europe and the world and
bringing in
flower at different levels of quality
and this is something where we're very
cautious of what we choose because we
have the responsibility towards the
patients so this is one
um in tinctures and extracts we also
look at the process how is it being
processed where's it coming from what's
the original what kind of biomass is
used has it been irradiated before or
not
um and then lastly what we do is to set
this we look at research we don't do the
research ourselves but we initiate
processes like inhalators uh patches
things that we believe will be an
important part in the future of the
medical cannabis world or medicinal
cannabis World
um and these are things where we Source
the right
companies the right Technologies and see
how we can Implement these Technologies
and cannabis because when you look at it
pharmaceutical we do have already
established mechanisms of modes of
delivery for other
um medications and sometimes it's just
about understanding that parallel and
introducing that to the Cannabis world
and that's let's say I would say the the
third stream of our actions in providing
the best sourced medications and
therapies for patients and then
pharmacies and doctors
we recently saw a sneak preview of some
of the German laws and I was interested
to ask you as somebody who actually
holds sales and imports this where do
you think is currently producing the
best medical cannabis flower in Europe
is it the ornamental flower up in
Denmark is it the likes of material
ventures in Malta who are bringing in
low-cost product from South America
Portugal and where do you see the best
flower currently being made because we
saw the rules that the German law looks
like you have to cultivate within
Germany that it doesn't look like
there's going to be any Imports
yeah that's well now you're referring to
the bullet um points paper of the
government regarding the legalization
for the recreational market and that is
due to the international treaties that
we have the single U.N convention and
the Schengen treaty that we're not
allowed to import for recreational
purposes and we
will have to at least for the time being
cultivate in Germany that law may change
by the time they finally come to uh to
terms with legalization but let's say it
is that way
um that's only for recreational medical
cannabis will be still imported from
around the world
um currently I believe the best
operation when you ask me in Europe
um we see very good reliable product
from Portugal again it depends who you
talk to Portugal and what
uh who your partners are we have a very
strong partner with the state-of-the-art
facility
um the best post Harvest services so we
get our product from Portugal we don't
also have products from Denmark from
Netherlands and um I believe and works
prone currently the opportunity to
import also from Switzerland eugnp the
main thing is it has to be really EU GMP
um and not just been let's say gcp grown
and then tried it packaged in a ugp
facility that's theoretically that's
enough but practically you have to look
at a couple of other aspects for it to
really match our quality standards okay
so that's a good bit of clarity so when
it comes to the medical cannabis you'll
still be able to import European
cultivated cannabis it's only the
recreational industry where it's going
to have to be cultivated within Germany
absolutely because the treaties stand
and we are already imported for the last
uh two three years um so this is a fact
that has been never challenged and uh
there was nobody who well in the right
mind would minimize the medical uh
market and uh providing to to patients
less product I mean we do have a tender
we had a tender we had three cultivators
in Germany who also provide to the
German Market at a set price
and that's fine and it's about two and a
half tons from what I understand per
year in an overall Market that has now
grown to around 10 tons of flour I think
we imported last year 20 tons but let's
say some of it has been extracted some
of it goes to other countries some of it
is being destroyed because of say end of
stability so around seven to ten tons
apparently last year were sold as dried
flower so there's two and a half tons
bedroom can there's two and a half tons
of German uh grown uh from dimikano or
nafria that leaves still at least five
tons that need to be imported
in the growing market so we see a
tendency a necessity also to enable that
and just make sure that the quality
standards are being uh
say or people stick to the quality
standards
amazing I know you're a very busy manner
when you're reaching our time so I don't
keep it too much longer if you could
predict one good thing that you think is
going to happen in the German Market
over the next 12 months what would be
the one thing that you'd like to see
happen
yeah or the next 12 months well
hopefully they will go through from
discussing uh the law to actually
drafting the law and and passing it
through the Senate by Fall that would be
exactly 12 months then we would have uh
reached a lot and established a lot and
will be at a different place but in the
meantime I also believe there will be
home grow and Social Clubs so these are
things not necessarily
um
um best for the industry but good for
the patients and and and good for those
who won't have access to the plant
yeah I couldn't agree with you more for
anybody who wants to know more about
alisana the link to the website is going
to be below and if you're not following
Boris already on Twitter I highly
recommend you do it's one of the top
voices in the European medical cannabis
sector Boris I know you're very busy so
I'm not going to keep you too much
longer but thank you very much for your
time it's been very much appreciated
thank you yeah it was a pleasure until
next episode everybody
thank you