[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i'm delighted to be
joined on this episode by yuri and
kuster who is the founder a co-founder
at the institute for medicinal cannabis
in netherlands
the imc aims to improve the provision of
information about medicinal cannabis to
patients and prescribers and to help
strengthen the collaboration in the
research in scientific network how are
you keeping today you're in
hi owen good morning i'm good i'm good
excellent
you just told me there
yeah yeah thank you very much for
joining it's very much appreciated and i
know you're mad with a wealth of
information and i'm sure the audience
are going to love this quick chat do you
maybe want to give everybody a brief
overview of how you got into the
cannabis industry and where you are and
what companies you're part of at the
moment
of course so i've joined the cannabis
industry about six years ago now um i
started out working for an extraction
facility uh very close to where i'm
actually living in environment in the
netherlands and lastly as people might
know is the agricultural capital of the
world the best agriculture university in
the world let me just
turn some of my thought off my apologies
so
we started out with an extraction
company they've developed drone
extraction technology and it's different
from
co2 but
uses basically
uh some some things are the same some
some parameters are the same so that's
where i started out six years ago
started working with different kind of
cannabis both medical cannabis from uh
from the dutch government better than
cannabis but also with
outdoor hemp so with him for cbd
extraction
enrolled into both markets food
supplement market and thc market
went on going from there and eventually
ended up
founding the institute for municipal
cannabis and working for a
lighting company where i do the strategy
so where we do provide
lighting to cultivation areas and my
expertise on cannabis and cannabinoids
makes the lighting and the cannabis a
very good fit
and we also founded the institute
officially last year in january the
january 1st 2021
a year before we started having round
tables and
just sort of organizing ourselves
and since last year now officially
in foundation
okay incredible yeah you seem to have
some great partners transvaal pharma
bedrock and fairground and a lot of
doctors and researchers so the objective
with the institute for medicinal
cannabis is to basically coalesce all
these uh
smart people with a lot of research and
data all in one centralized spot and is
the objective then to have software
where doctors around the country can
dial in or is this based on information
you're going to create papers and
distribute those papers around
a couple of things i think the main the
main
thing is what you said is cooperation so
we are trying to cooperate between all
fields of the medical cannabis so that's
doctors it's specialists it's
pharmacists it's academics but also
people from the industry it's the
government so we you need all of those
to create a good framework a good legal
framework but also a framework for
patients to actually get a product
um
one of the things we are doing now is
and we are only a relatively small
foundation it's not for profit so we
don't charge a lot of money
not at all even so it's it's it's a
we don't get paid anything as a board
member of the institute so we do this to
improve the industry and we don't
provide with thousands and thousands of
papers what we are doing is providing
fact sheets and we have the first two
ones available i think they're for
chronic pain and for
uh
epilepsy if i'm saying this correctly
and
what we're doing is we call the fact
sheets and so it's basically a sort of
summary on what is available for doctors
and patients so what is currently the
state of research on chronic pain what
kind of products are being used uh
what's the current stage just a very
factual overview no no no you need to
use this or
this is something that this counts as
evidence is very good overview fact
shoulder
yeah observative overview so we're
currently
creating those and one of the other
things we just launched is a
i don't know how this translates but
it's uh you always have this sort of v
you also have this piece of paper with
your medicines right where it says okay
this is the list of side effects you
might experience if you use this product
so uh
what's the english word for it the
yeah just a piece of paper with the
instructions so but some people these
are all it's very tiny and very detailed
and it's hard for people detrimental
effects
yeah
yeah yeah exactly what we've now done is
we create a very simple video of it it's
like a generic thing in the netherlands
which is available for all pharmacies
it's not pregnant in any way not even by
us not anyone which is just short
three-minute videos explaining cannabis
cannabis floss flour and cannabis oil so
just very simple what is it where you
can get it what does it do and how do
you use it just very simple
uh simple animated videos for people to
use which they get a qr code from
pharmacy if they get a cannabis product
and they can just view it online how to
use it and what it is just very just
providing information to the patients
that's just our goal
okay so initial stepping stone of
information for a patient or a medical
practitioner who's looking at the first
level of information
is there another platform is there
another platform because the one thing
i'm starting to notice we're actually
doing an article on software and
cannabis now over the next week and it's
the one thing i'm starting to see
movement in the european space because
it's all well and good the companies who
are cultivating and growing but if the
doctors don't have access to be able to
track prescriptions and track the
medicines and track the behavior of each
patient uh i i see that's where the next
move is coming in so are you guys
planning on building some sort of
software that allows the doctor full
access or you guys initially just doing
this says look the industry needs to
move forward we we've all come together
to help this industry move forward and
the objective is not to turn this into a
large corporation it's basically to get
the industry up off the up off the
ground and help as much as we can
yeah
definitely the latter um i have also
seen on the scanners conferences i've
seen these parties providing software
and they're i think now on startup phase
even one of our partners
is trying to set
the institute's trying to set it up but
we are as an organization really want to
remain uh a neutral objective party uh
non-commercial so so we would if a
partner of us provides a good software
that's functional and where this kind of
data can be exchanged you would promote
we prove promote it for the partner like
if somebody would reach out or experts
would reach out to us or specialists
where can i find this they would
redirect them to the party we would not
uh do this ourselves because we think
that's not our you're going to be a
facilitator and not some not a an actual
player in the industry
yeah no i think that the two uh the two
pillars there seem to can't cross either
have to be offering advice and be
willing to educate or you go for a
monetizational company i don't think the
two dollars can coalesce well they can't
go less but i don't think you'll get
taken seriously over the long term of
time i think
the way the route you guys are taking is
something that us in ireland can learn
from that look there needs to be a board
set up independent of everybody's
venture that basically helps the
industry move forward at no
cost and at no gain to any of the
members of the board
definitely i think oh look the gun
i think that's in some regards the same
as the netherlands it's not really big
there's not a lot of different parties
with a lot of interest i mean
it should be possible to set something
up there's a lot of common ground we
found the common ground here there's a
lot of common ground i'm sure in ireland
as well
we also did a
conference last year in denmark where
they invited us the institute also to
speak on what our initiative is this
year we were invited again to speak on
what we did in the first year
and
every i think every country can benefit
from such an initiative because there is
a lot of common ground and if you want
to be taken seriously also by your own
government by the by the healthcare then
you need to provide a neutral standpoint
if you come from it from a commercial
aspect
they always they just
very shortly will say okay you're just
out here to make money and egypt want to
make money
that's his own only goal and if you come
more from a patient perspective and more
from a common ground like we noticed
these things and and so for
a problem in the end was where
uh scientists had a hard time finding
a product or where do i get the product
where do you get it from we see that
pharmacists don't know what to prescribe
sorry doctors don't know what to
prescribe so they asked the pharmacist
and we just
i think every country can benefit from a
facilitating place who knows where all
the players are where the experts are we
have a lot of experts who are
affiliated with the institute we just if
they do cannabis research we ask them if
they want to be an expert
and if there's ever a topic like it's
chronic pain or ms or epilepsy we know
okay you can contact this specialist
ask his opinion maybe he can help you
setting up a research it's just really
facilitating i think any country in eu
could benefit from it
yeah no very much agreed i want to move
on now to just the netherlands i have a
couple of questions about the industry
over there do you guys produce enough
cannabis for your medical cannabis
program or do you import as well
no no we export about eighty percent i
think of the the cannabis so so baroque
has been export is the sole producer at
the moment and
there's a medical tender ongoing
to have two medical growers where
i mean better can is not 100 guaranteed
to be one of the two but it's very
likely there will be one of the two
growers and so there will be one new
party providing cannabis
uh but currently almost every all
cannabis is being exported uh our
cannabis is being
so officially the cannabis for the dutch
government we have the office of
medicinal cannabis who gives basic
basically what better can is as a
contract manufacturer they create
cultivated cannabis
for the government and they distribute
it and all the records of it are just
online findable
it's all transparent and most of our
cannabis goes to germany actually
and i think yeah germany seems to be
taken in cannabis from malta from
denmark from the netherlands
they basically have no cultivation
themselves i think they have like three
and three cultivators and they produce
a thousand or two thousand kilograms
each
another percent and uh that's not enough
to satisfy other patients so they have
to import it and they've been importing
it from the netherlands for quite uh
quite some time
yeah we previously talked to sony
murrenhout from the leather hands who
about cultivation and he gave us an
overview of a number of things so
when it comes to the product in the
netherlands the pharmacies are the ones
that distribute the medical cannabis
over there
yeah correct so you want to get
basically get a prescription from your
doctor from a specialist and then you
could go to pharmacists energy
pharmacists in the netherlands where you
can get the cannabis flower
and cannabis oil is a bit more difficult
because not all
pharmacists make the oil there's two
currently two who make the oil we are
also partners the transfal and the
clinical cannabis care where you get
your cannabis oil
okay very interesting so when it comes
to the pharmacies and let's say the
buyer for the pharmacies who are getting
the new products that are coming out
they really only have one company to
supply them with product at the moment
hopefully two within the next 12 months
is that correct
they only have one and they're not even
directly because because it's being
sourced from the government so it goes
from the cultivator to the government
from government to the distributor from
the distributor it goes to
the pharmacist
but uh
yeah basically one source
very interesting because i think over in
ireland we're going to have the exact
opposite scenario that whoever has the
class a import license will then be able
to source the best product for the
pharmacies to be able to sell i don't
think there'll be a cultivation
operation over in ireland that'll be
able to be big enough to feed the whole
industry over here
i can admit like it's not an ideal
situation where you only have one just
from a risk perspective you want to
differentiate i mean the cannabis
currently being provided by those
governments is
very good quality it's gmp qualified
flowers so it's not an issue in terms of
quality it's more of a you want a more
diversified portfolio you want more
producers to see what you can get maybe
some different strains there's all kinds
of you just want to see what's more
possible and if you think it doesn't
even necessarily need to be a better
product but if you think it's going to
be a better product from
any other producer you should be able to
uh
to get it i think that's something
how countries eventually will go to
where they also allow imports but for
the netherlands currently it's not
possible
yeah now very it's very interesting to
see what's going on in europe i
definitely think there's a lot of
movement i can see it over in ireland
over the last five to six months that uh
steam seems to be gathering behind the
germany leading the way with germany are
taking the headlines shall we say with
what's happening over there and it seems
to people are taking notice but i think
new york is going to be a massive one
for the irish people we look over to new
york and boston a good bit in new york
they go live i think in like six weeks
now or eight weeks with retail stores in
manhattan and if you've been over there
recently it's full of vans it's full of
cbd stores tic products so it's going to
be interesting to see now that the
cannabis tourism i think that happens
between north america and europe
yeah i mean amsterdam is obviously a
massive spot for for cannabis tourism
and there's still a lot coming
so that that's going to be interesting
you have the coffee shop experiments as
well in the netherlands
so there's there's a lot of things
we don't have time for to dive into but
it will be interesting how to develop i
just want to say that on the on the
german
possible legalization
that let's not all focus on just
germany and just the uh recreational
medicine is on the market is very
interesting it can be very big don't
forget that we have an approved
cannabis medicine with epitheliolex from
gw pharma which was one of the main
headlines of
2019-2018 which is currently almost like
it's forgotten by uh by the uh everybody
industry so medical says a lot of
potential so
i would really
anybody who's listening or even viewing
this like
it's not just possible legalization in
germany there are other things happening
in the street definitely as well
yeah i think any good medical cannabis
program that has chronic pain and
neuropathic pain on it is going to allow
for a huge chunk of the illegal market
to be turned legal and for a lot of
patients to be able to access a medicine
that is going to be beneficial to not
everybody but for some of the patients
it's definitely going to work so we've
hit 15 minutes already i could actually
fly along talking to you at the moment
for anybody who wants to know more about
the institute for medicine municipal
cannabis this is the website below it'll
be in the description below i highly
recommend going checking it out and
learning as much as you can
yuri and it's been great to talk to you
mate hopefully we get to chat again in
the next six or eight months and see get
an update and hopefully we've got more
news going on in europe
all right it was my pleasure thanks for
inviting me thank you very much guys see
you in the next episode
you