foreign
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I am delighted to be
joined to this episode by Lars olafson
Lars has been a CEO and Management
Consultant for almost all of his 40
years in business he is an excellent
Swedish Navy SEAL and he's currently
representing 500 people in the juicy
Fields Saga that's continuing to go on
Lara's how are you keeping today
I'm fine thank you thank you for having
me here delighted to have you on mate
it's always good to bring Clarity and
information to the audience in Europe
because there's a lot of [ __ ] and
and uh smoke and mirrors that are
currently going on at the moment so I
always get ready to get the source uh so
the information straight from the
sources moved can you maybe give
everybody just a quick overview what is
Juicy fields for the people who have no
idea about it yet
yeah you should feel started in the
spring of 2020 and basically it's an
e-commerce platform where you could
invest in cannabis plants and they were
calling it e-growers and what they have
done is to pitch from different kind of
business Concepts uh like a crowdfunding
concept and an investment concept and so
on and what they did was to pick to to
put together a concept where you're
investing in cannabis plants
okay very interesting and who are the
main players who set up juicy Fields
what territory are they based in in the
world yeah uh that's kind of interesting
because if you are looking at the
website they have had uh they said that
they had operations more or less all
over the world in South America in the
Central America in Europe and there are
some uh farmers in there in Asia as well
so so that this was from day one a
global operation uh and then a global
Enterprise
and uh and uh and uh they they they
presented a new way of investing uh in
the Cannabis industry and uh and uh and
that was the the new disruptive concept
so to say
okay so the business model was basically
getting people to invest in cannabis
Growers around the world and like a
co-op that I'll be able to spread their
money together so
can you tell me how long did this
Enterprise last
yeah well it it's
um it's important to know that there
have been a pre-planning uh process uh
at least that what I have identified is
that they have been working on this
concept for at least two years before
they started operation in in April 2020
and then the operation uh went on until
mid-july this year
2022. so more or less uh uh two years uh
two years and a couple of months that
was uh during the operation and when
they took in all their investors
and so but that the company there that
there are different companies but the
parent company actually started back in
2017 as a kind of research and
development company so that had been
quite a lot of planning before they
started operation and also a lot of
Investments because that is a very
important in this uh in this case uh
because I'm not just a lawyer I'm also
an investor in the Cannabis industry and
I invest in startup companies so you
could look at
um use your Fields like a startup
company with all the different kind of
elements a startup company have to have
a a business concept A business plan
financing for starting up operation and
all these elements
okay very interesting where was the the
let's say the parent company set up what
location and territory was that company
set up in yeah and the parent company UC
grow is a German company usually grow Ag
and then they started subsidiaries
and in Switzerland and various say uh
potentially uh
it's a bit it's a bit uh Shady if if
there is a company in in Cyprus but the
the parent company is in Germany that's
for sure
okay and how long have every people been
aware of the juicy field scam and when
did people uh kind of highlight that
look there's just something that you're
not going correctly here yeah uh well uh
that were definitely something happened
in the middle of July because all of a
sudden one day uh the website was closed
down everything was shut down uh
um emails was disconnected in Mobile
telephones was just disconnected so more
or less overnight everything was closed
down and that's when people started to
think about well what is this is this
just a technical problem uh is it's just
something temporary or have all the
people uh just left the company so that
was the the first starting point of the
process is this something that is still
going on but there is some kind of
technical problems or is it the scam and
and this is interesting because I've
been investigating investment scam for
the last 15 years and I've been involved
in the investigation and helping victims
for more than 30 of these International
Investment scams and I I and I could see
a pattern a kind of Playbook that all
these scammers are using and one of the
things they are doing and this is smart
because if you shut down everything from
from uh and disconnect everything people
realize that yes this has been a scam
but if you are leaving someone behind
and posting things uh like this in this
situation posting things on the website
that yeah this is just a temporary
problem we have had some internal
conflicts between the founders of our
company we are going to soon start up
again and you are going to be able to
refund your Investments and all these
kind of information then people are
living under hope that yes I'm not being
scammed and that is the psychology of
these scammers and they know this for
sure
okay very interesting and is there
annual returns for the companies or the
liquidity of the company where was the
com the the money outflowing to is there
a a trailer of paperwork Trail so far
I've looked this person could
accidentally the company this person
took accident yeah they invest this and
I could tell you that I have identified
something about 125
000 investors for more or less all
countries all over the world so this was
just not just them and a European
operation this was a global operation
about 125
000 and that business was done between
the investors and a the Dutch company UC
Fields be they and Yusuf is BV
they had that account in Cyprus and so
that's where all the money uh was sent
from the investors to Cyprus that would
say Lithuanian Bank also involved but
that that was just a few percent of all
the cash flow so so the main bulk of a
cash flow was from the investors to a
bank in Cyprus and the bank account was
hold by this uh Dutch company
very interesting there is a word going
around that it was basically just a very
Advanced money laundering scheme
conducted by the Russian mafia is there
any truth to that
um well yeah yeah definitely because in
all these first of all I should say that
when I looked into this and I came into
one of my clients contacted me in the
end of them of July and explained his
situation and that was one of my clients
from Sweden I should correct you that I
have now about 800 clients from all over
the world more than more than 50
countries all over the world and that
when I looked into this I saw
immediately again that the pattern that
kind of Playbook the template for these
kind of scams and all the different
elements and um and and this is uh also
very interesting because in all these
criminal activities the criminals also
use different kind of source of incomes
it's very seldom just one kind of crime
they are using this infrastructure they
have been built they have built to use
for different kind of purposes so the
investment scam of having people send
money to Cyprus to invest in in cannabis
plants is just one of a different kind
of businesses of a different kind of
criminal activities because inside the
use you feel scam I have identified also
a number of things that point in the
direction there had been a money
laundering scheme as well and the money
laundering scheme could be free or maybe
four times as big as the investment scam
in size of the the kind of money that
was involved and I should also say that
I have identified
something between 1.5 and 2 billion
euros has been lost by the investors and
I think the sum is closer to 2 billion
than 1.5
very interesting is there a specific
country that has the most amount
investors that have allows the most
amount of money or is it spread out
across the globe yeah it's interesting
to see that that top that that the
numbers are very very uncertain and what
I have uh with all the contact I have
had and as I said I have 800 clients but
I've been in contact in one way or
another me and my team we are 12 people
uh being in contact with more than 20
000 investors and that when I add up all
the different countries and uh what I've
been talking to people and the
information they have been giving me
that's when I come up with a number
about 125
000. Germany is definitely one of the
largest something between 10 and 11
000 investors has lost money a Spain is
a very large country something nine ten
thousand Portugal the neighboring
country from Spain that there is seven
eight thousand I have a lot of clients
in Mexico I have more than 60 clients in
Mexico and I think Mexico might be one
of the biggest countries actually and
France as well so so that so so there
are thousands of thousands of people in
more or less every country
it's crazy the overarching reach of this
scam you have said previously that
you're sitting on documents that
basically points the finger at certain
facilitators is there a case that some
of these facilitators were completely
unaware of what was going on at the
company or is their actual factual
evidence that would stand up in court
that when the finger has been pointed
that there is
irrevocable uh proof that they were
involved yeah yeah my legal strategy not
in just this case but in many other
similar cases is that I know for sure
that the criminals they have been
planning this for years there have been
as I said a a pre-planning process of at
least two years and then the operation
during more than two years since on top
of that and and if you have and that is
the logic if you have planned this and
invest a lot lot of money and time into
this and actually steal two billion
euros I I I I could I could be 100 sure
that they had planned the exits as well
to keep the money there is no logic in
stealing 2 billion euros and not trying
to keep it as much as possible so my
strategy is in all these cases not to go
after the criminals because they are so
far ahead and they have planned their
exit so carefully so it's more or less
impossible to find the money
so what I'm doing in all these cases is
to look who helped them who has
facilitated for them to do the sales and
marketing and that's why I'm targeting
some of the large social media companies
some media companies that have allowed
user fields to actually promote to do
sales and marketing and these companies
they cannot just say that we didn't know
they need to actually talk to people and
do some kind of due diligence of who
they are doing business with and they
should have asked two very simple
questions because everyone who is
working within the Cannabis industry if
you are a farmer if you are a producer
if you are a Trader whatever it is you
need to have a license
everybody who is handling cannabis in
one way or another need to have a
license and if you're giving investment
advices or managing people's money to to
get money and then put money into some
kind of investment then you also need to
have a license
so there should have been two very
simple questions asked to the people
from use of field do you have a license
to trade in cannabis and do you have a
license to give investment advices or
during investment management and neither
of these companies who I'm calling
facilitators has even asked any of these
two basic questions
okay very interesting so it's
facilitators from everybody from legal
advice to conferences to Media companies
to news networks the owners was on them
to ensure that they were dealing with a
reputable company and everything was a
book board yeah yeah and especially the
facilitators who was in the Cannabis
industry those who have been uh lawyers
cannabis lawyers those who has done
exhibitions within the industry business
to business exhibitions all these people
who actually have a knowledge of how the
industry works all these people I have
identified Ian I have a list of more
than 40 companies who has in one way or
another being a facilitator for user
fields to do the sales and promotion and
exposure and on top of that I have more
than 70 T people who has individuals who
has in one way or another help yusu
Fields with sales and marketing and
these are people who knows about the
Cannabis industry and should have asked
these two simple questions and how the
industry works because it's not just a
matter of not having the license the
whole concept just doesn't work there
isn't this profit margin that is
promised to the to them investors you
cannot buy plants like this and there
isn't any and buyers all the end buyers
doesn't exist they haven't sold one
single flower to Annie and buyer that is
the pharmaceutical companies
it's a very interesting case to say the
least and is it are you looking for
reparations basically from the the
facilitators to pay back any money that
they were owed or is it a case that
these are going to court and there's
going to be a settlement uh brought
against them yeah more or less in in 95
percent of these cases it's going to be
a settlement outside Court sooner or
later and I've been trying to have a
dialogue with some of these large social
media companies but I have uh just they
they had just ignore me so what I'm
doing now is to go to courts and I have
a legal strategy and it's a solid legal
strategy and it's going to be something
very very interesting from a legal
perspective because what I would like to
do is to set precedent for the future if
you are a facilitator you just have to
do some basic due diligence of who you
are working with and how you are
facilitating for these people and if
there is a damage you have to take
responsibility for this so I'm not just
claiming for the lost money I'm also
claiming for that the mental this
comfort that these people have had this
my clients has lost so much money on an
average my client has lost more than 32
000 Euros and these people all their
investors they are not wealthy people
that one of the time that what they
targeted was people who was just
ordinary people
who wanted to support the Cannabis
industry and they wanted to have the
opportunity that the Millionaires and
the billionaires had that that was they
that was the uh the kind of persona the
the set Target on so this is ordinary
people and many other people many of the
investors has lost more or less
everything they have
yeah it's one of those buyer beware for
every investor retail investor in the
Cannabis industry at the moment I know
if I've been in this industry for five
years and I know of no company that's
paying out 20 or 30X and your investment
to date even if you're based up in
California or Colorado you're still
looking at a small return on your
investment until Federation
yeah yeah absolutely and in this
industry the Cannabis industry that the
big return of Investments isn't in
farming uh as in as in all kind of
farming it doesn't matter if it's food
or whatever it is there is very very
small profit margin so so promising a
profit margin of uh about 66 within
three months that is an an annual return
of investment of about 250 that is
ridiculous that that is just so
completely mad so it should have been a
a a warning signal not just for the
investors because they the investors
they had been scammed so so cleverly but
all the all the professionals those
where I'm calling their uh the
facilitators they should have realized
this is a this is an offer that just
doesn't exist
yeah there's no billion dollar farmers
in cannabis at the moment anywhere in
the world and I think the only real
returns from this industry will be IEP
protected uh uh companies so it's been
absolutely amazing to offer to hilarious
hopefully I get to touch base with you
maybe in about six months for everybody
to see how everything's gone but let's
hope all the investors get some of their
return back for themselves and uh thank
you very much for taking their time to
do this for anybody who wants to know
more about the juicy Fields case they've
built a website that has all the
pertinent information that you can go
and peruse yourself at any time so
highly recommend checking that out Lars
thank you very much and you have a great
day thank you for having me thank you no
problem till next episode everybody