[Music]
welcome to
the next episode of kind of some view i
am delighted to be joined by
liz wald she's the chief strategy and
dude loves are good or
go there to organics how are you keeping
this i'm great owen thanks so much for
having me great to be here
i'm absolutely delighted to have you on
this is a topic of conversation i think
people are going to be
focusing on a lot more and more is the
soil and nutrients part of cannabis
i think we're going to start things off
you've had a pretty uh stellar career to
date
and haven't worked at a number of global
companies that are an expert in
multitude of fields do you want to give
everybody a little overview quickly of
how you got from
the business world to the cannabis world
real quick yeah sure
so i was fortunate to go to business
school from 1993 to 1995 and when i got
out the internet was really
just becoming a platform for commerce
and i thought hey this is going to be
new and fun and exciting i'm going to
jump into the e-commerce game and
um i was uh ended up doing some
consulting to aol and the you've got
mail days when we all got
you know magazines in the mail with
cd-roms that we would put into our
computers to get it
and then you know hook up to the
internet with dial-up um
and so i spent about 25 years in that
emerging then
industry and um was at some amazing
places you know like etsy and indiegogo
and just
really fun opportunities building global
businesses
um and then i you know was like hey i'm
kind of ready to look at something new
and being in new york cannabis was
something that was happening out in
california and colorado but it really
wasn't happening here
on the east coast but people were
starting to talk about it it was
bubbling up
and i thought you know this is going to
be a really fun
industry to be in and it's going to be
disruptive the way the internet was
disruptive because
cannabis touches everything from you
know agriculture
to restaurants to product development
branding pharma i mean just so many
different things
and so i thought hey i need to i need to
learn about this and
through doing that and networking and
meeting some interesting people and
doing a little bit of angel investing i
i found my way to good earth organics
well that's an amazing story yeah so
you're going to be able to provide a
wealth of information for the viewers
today on this episode
and let's kick off basically with the
great news from yesterday we were
talking just before we went live there
with new york going legal on the wreck
tell us as much as you know about that
to help us get our
information on that process well it's
it's super exciting i mean
you know people have been pushing for
recreational cannabis here in new york
for many years and um it's uh
it's finally gonna happen we're we're
super excited uh it'll probably take a
you know a bit of time for it to
actually come to life
but there were a couple of bills that
were um
proposed and one of them was called the
mrta
um and and that one was really being
proposed by proponents of social equity
and ensuring that a lot of the tax
revenue was going to go back into the
communities that
had really been dis proportionally
affected by the war on drugs over the
years and the like and then there was
another bill the crta
one with leading with cannabis and one
leaving with marijuana but essentially
the same letters
um that was you know really much more of
centralized control and the like and and
over the last couple of years one of the
reasons that
cannabis had not become legal despite
lots of popular support and even
legislative support
was this battle between the two bills
and it was great to see that they
finally worked it out and many of the
social justice
issues are going to be addressed and
there's going to be representation
um on sort of the committees that make
the decisions and set the laws and the
regulations so
i think overall no bill is ever perfect
but i think people are pretty excited
about what's going to be happening here
in new york
yeah i think one of new york's one of
the cities that ireland has close to its
heart so whatever goes on there where i
was very interested and known about it
absolutely and the people who travel
there so
i think next christmas or the christmas
after that should be an enjoyable uh
little uh shopping trip there yeah and i
think you know they're estimating
something like a four billion dollar
market and
you know i think the the um uh
legacy market as as we might call it uh
here
um other people might call it the
illicit market
is probably three or four billion
dollars already as it is so this is a
huge huge opportunity um
and not just in you know the city of new
york where you've got your 8 million
people and and all the tourists that
come but
upstate new york where a lot of
agriculture has grown
you know the us is still in this crazy
state-by-state patchwork of laws
and uh it could even be that we have 50
states legal and still not
federal legalization the way things are
going you know um
we think it's going to provide a lot of
jobs and opportunities
upstate in the more rural parts of new
york new york state is a
huge state with lots of open space once
you get kind of out of the uh
five boroughs of manhattan yeah now a
pleasure living in new york for two
years so it's most people think it's
just those fibers and then you kind of
can
realize the size of whole territory
let's kick on to the start of the show
and the first topic
is the story of good earth organics most
people might not have heard of you guys
yet but
those in the know will have already
known about the surge of business you
guys have happened over the last while
can you inform everybody about good good
organics and how you get it and your
story
sure so good earth organics is a
manufacturer and distributor of
premium organic soils and soil
amendments
uh soil amendments or sort of nutrients
and things you would add to your soil
and what most people don't realize is
that soil isn't
dirt you know it isn't the stuff that's
out in your backyard or in a park
um it's really made of ingredients like
coco coir and peat and compost and
and lots of organic uh nutrients of the
type that we add to our soil that might
come from
fish meal or bat guano or sea guano or
things like that and
about 12 or 13 years ago a gentleman
named roy leon who was a retired chemist
moved to this area in southern oregon
that is part of what is called the
emerald triangle and this emerald
triangle area is kind of southern oregon
down to
northern california and it's where i
call it sort of the napa valley of weed
because some of the best
outdoor cannabis is grown that the
terroir is great you know
everything about the air the soil the
humidity the
the rainfall everything in this area is
really conducive to growing
tremendous cannabis and this retired
chemist
moves to this area and you know he
starts talking to local people and
they're really interested in having a
soil
that will be optimized for really
terrific cannabis growth but also be
very clean
not have to use pesticides and
herbicides and you know all these
different kind of
chemical uh things that are that are not
natural
and that you know can leave residue and
what not in the plant
so over a few years he worked with these
local growers
to create what is now good earth
organics and our
core soil blends um and we've got now
sort of three main soil blends that are
can be used whether you're doing indoor
or outdoor or you're starting with a
seed
or you're starting with a clone um and
and they're kind of optimized for
different stages and styles of growth
and then we've added a bunch of
amendments and things to help those
things grow but
being from this you know historically
amazing growing area
where you know it's been legal in oregon
for several years um
but the people been growing cannabis in
this area for decades right so
there's a there's a lot of history to
learn from and he took his background
and married it up with the growers to
create this
really wonderful totally organic product
that's optimized for cannabis amazing i
think you covered the next topic as well
the importance of soil and nutrients for
everybody
as well it's a it's so important uh for
the process of
getting a good plant to it is sufficient
either cannabinoids or terpenes or
flavonoids whatever it is your objective
is with the plant to get
how do you see the growth for um the
market
in the us for homegrown i don't think
it's even really touched
a a a major part of that yet would you
agree
yeah no i think home grows really i mean
if cannabis it's in its infancy
homegrown grow is still you know in the
womb
so to speak like it's really really
early um
but i think you know plants are like
people whatever you put in a person
you know really affects how you perform
right you know
this excellent you know amazing athletes
don't eat a bunch of junk food they eat
high quality food and
plants are the same way you know they're
going to take out of the ground
whatever's in the ground
so having really rich nutrient-rich soil
is super important and the other thing
is
cannabis is highly tested you know home
growers are often growing for medical
reasons
and many cannabis users are growing
or are consuming cannabis for medicinal
purposes
and it's really important like if you're
a cancer survivor and you don't have
and you're taking cannabis to say help
with the chemotherapy or something like
that
you don't want a whole bunch of
chemicals in there that are going to
interfere with
whatever it is that your the medicines
that you're on
and i think home growers also they just
want a really pure
clean plant and so knowing that
whatever they're putting their plant in
is going to be pure and clean
is really going to help them um feel
confident
about their cannabis and the testing at
the state levels
is only getting more and more um extreme
like they're really able to find
particulates and contaminants and small
things in the soil
so it's becoming you know mandatory in
way for growers
to to just ensure that they're not going
to be not be failing those tests
it's such a huge financial hit
if you if your cannabis doesn't pass the
test you can't sell it you know that
that that's a major problem
so more and more and more growers are
moving to 100
organic just to kind of ensure um
consistency of their crops as well as
the high yield and all the things that
you mentioned the terpenes and
and the cannabinoids and whatnot but
just not failing the test is a big
is a big hurdle as well okay amazing and
do you see in terms of the market growth
for you guys do you see people buying
individual pots that just have the soil
in them and then they get to put the
seeds and what's the process exactly
could you describe to me for
a consumer who wants to grow let's say
four plants at home we saw new york as
legalized grow at home laws so
if you want to grow four plants at home
is there going to be a a range of
different sized pots
is there going to be individual how are
you guys going to target the exact
consumer audience so
i think we're going to see a couple
different things i think there's people
who are going to
you know they're not going to
necessarily want to start from
one seed they're going to go down to a
to
um a legal grow and they're going to buy
a a small plant that's already been
started
that they already know okay this is the
strain that i'm buying that
you know they're they're going to have a
little bit of a starting point and
um and those folks are
you know they're we're going to be able
to provide them both soil and nutrients
that they can use
throughout different stages of that
plant's growth
i think sort of the all-in-one kit
idea is is you know it's it i think once
you're kind of
past the the most novice like i've never
grown anything in my life i think people
will do their research and
they'll want to do a quality product and
if they're going to grow this cannabis
i think people will be willing to invest
in good ingredients and
you know you're there in ireland so i'll
make a beer analogy
um that uh you know if you're gonna make
your own beer at home
you're not gonna buy the cheapest
ingredients and make like
uh you know a watered-down lager
you're probably gonna say hey i want to
get really great hops and
and i want to have my malt be a premium
malt and i'm going to brew
something that's going to be rich and
flavorful and unique and all that
and i think we'll see the same kind of
approach in
in the homegrow cannabis also i think
people who don't live in a city
you know uh home grow for people who
have access to outdoors
i mean these plants are the size of
trees you know they're six feet tall
right and so it's a very different thing
than kind of a window box with the
where you grow your you know oregano and
basil and whatnot
yeah yeah no i i couldn't agree tomorrow
lastly what are your hopes for the
industry over the next 12 to 24 months
have you got any uh
things that you'd love to see happen and
get escalated quickly
yeah sure i mean short of like hey
federal legalization let's
you know remove the magic wand and get
that done
i think there's some steps that would
really help the industry lots of people
talk about the safe banking act
which um you know in a nutshell would
allow
um federally chartered banks you know
the big banks everyone's heard of
citibank wells fargo
chase these kinds of banks to directly
bank the industry
um and right now there's a it's very
challenging
for cannabis companies that actually
touch the plant
you know we're a soil company we you
know we can bank at wells fargo or
wherever
you know without too much challenge
because we're making soil
but if you're a dispensary it's much
harder for you to get a bank account and
so changing some laws around that that
would allow uh people to say if you've
got a legal business in the state you
should be able to
to run that business with with a bank
just like you know a hairdresser a nail
salon
or a you know a gym or any other small
business in that
in that community amazing i want to
thank you so much for coming on the show
we normally do the 15 minutes here for
everybody who wants to check out good
earth organics the website's there below
i'd highly recommend doing your research
on this company i have no doubt we'll
see them in europe
in a few years time not not quite soon
they need to dominate america first but
you can come invest in us now at good
earthorganics.com learn how to do it
there you go so basically any building
investors in the cannabis industry go
check out the platform that they've got
going on they're good at organics
liz thank you so much for coming on the
show i hope you have a great weekend
and hopefully we can talk together again
in the future and see how things have
progressed
thanks so much it was great to be here
cheers thanks guys
you