foreign
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the Cannabis review I'm delighted to be
joining this episode by Chris Davis
who's the executive director of incba
which is the international cannabis Bar
Association how do you keeping today
Chris I'm doing very well how are you
I'm fantastic mate thank you very much
for taking the time to do this I know
you're a busy man and do you want to
maybe give a really quick little
overview on under 60 seconds of how you
ended up as the executive director of
the incba sure yeah um when I came on it
was 2017 so uh the association was
started in 2015 by a group of lawyers
um in San Francisco that really looked
around and saw the need for increased
levels of legal services in the industry
so uh I started volunteering with incba
I was in a completely different industry
so I was in Securities litigation and
then I was in uh Finance
um really sort of liked the the industry
um had historical connections to it
through family and friends so when I
moved back to California in about 2016 I
started doing pro bono work for a few
family and friends
um you know really sort of got up to
speed with where the law was at the time
and sort of what we needed going into
the future and then was lucky enough to
apply for the position and be hired as
the executive director so
very good very good and the origins of
the agency go back to what year and what
stages for everybody who's not aware
sure yeah like I said it was it was San
Francisco so California
um in about 2015 legalization happened
in California back in 1996 so so it was
legal for quite a while but it was under
uh a not-for-profit model so we had
collectives and cooperatives that would
provide medicine to patients that needed
cannabis in order to treat you know
either for palliative care or for other
pain management issues
um we looked around and really the the
group of women that started the
association saw a need for lawyers to
get together and to speak to each other
there really wasn't a set of best
practices it was an industry that had
not really from the legal side had not
really matured right since it was
illegal at the federal level it was
legal at the state level there was a lot
of discomfort with papering any sort of
uh you know Arrangements among
individuals uh there was really sort of
everyone was allergic to putting
anything down on paper we were still
afraid that that Federal the federal
government was going to come in bring
seizure actions against individual
companies things like that and so in
order to create those best practices
three women in San Francisco got
together and they really said you know
it would benefit not only us and not
only our clients to to have everyone
sort of be on the same page about how we
should do some of these things but it
would benefit us to have the people
across the table uh from us you know
start from a place of of Education start
from a place where they knew sort of
what the what the rules are and what
they should be and how we should proceed
as an industry so it started off as a
networking group pretty pretty quickly
after that we got into continuing legal
education so
um now we put on about 80 hours of
continuing legal education each year we
do this year we have five in-person
events lined up uh one in Europe which
would make six um so we're really
excited for that one coming up in
Ireland on the 25th um so you know we've
really expanded we touch on pretty much
all facets of the Cannabis industry now
so anything from you know educating
lawyers on how to best serve their
clients to advocacy to Liaison
liaisoning with the government
um sort of all of those facets are
things that are covered under under our
Banner
it's very good and what was the first
step in towards creating an
International Association was the one
specific country from outside the states
to cut together what can you tell us on
that
yeah it was it was really interesting it
grew up organically and so there had
always been sort of an eye right it was
this uh this idea from our beginning
that we wanted to fill a space that
wasn't currently filled right and in
terms of international transactions it
really didn't exist we understood that
legalization was sort of rolling across
across the globe and
um there were a lot of lessons to be
learned from you know how we're doing
things in the United States what we're
doing right what we're doing wrong
um we saw interest
um I think one of our first
International uh uh members someone that
came to one of our cannabis law
institutes in Washington DC was a a
gentleman from Lesotho
um and so that really opened our eyes
that this was sort of you know traveling
across the globe we had a few European
members at that point and so I think we
had members from from France from
Germany from Spain and from Switzerland
and so we sort of saw the writing on the
wall that this there was going to be a
lot of utility from the international
perspective
um both from from those individual
Jewels trying to push a regulated market
on on a domestic level from wherever
they were from but then also sort of
laying the groundwork for international
transactions so
um really was an organic evolution we're
really excited that now we have our
incba Europe group over the next year or
two we do plan on rolling out those
other sort of large geographical
portions so incba Latin America incba
Africa those sort of like
conglomerations of attorneys surf
clients in those jurisdictions as they
come online and as they create regulated
markets
okay amazing the next Topic in
conversational letter to have was
basically as a compliance professional
and a business strategist for people
over in Europe who are looking to try
and write policy and have policy
influence what states would you be aware
of that have the best legal framework in
place or is there a combination of a
multitude of states where you could
Frankenstein a couple of different
policy and create a perfect policy for
Europe
see that's really the latter
um I I wouldn't say that any
jurisdiction in the United States has
has gotten it exactly right
um you know and it really depends on
what stage of the market you're looking
at as we look at the success of of
individual jurisdictions
um for a place like California right
which is where I sit
um as the markets matured it's really
we've run into difficulty because we've
really over taxed some of the entities
we've made it very very difficult for
the legal regulated market which has a
lot of benefits you know related to it
um we can trace transactions we have
Financial tracking of a lot of the
companies
um we have you know the ability to test
product to make sure that public health
and safety uh is insured as we roll out
these these products and these programs
to a wider group of consumers
um but here in California we've really
created a system where the illicit
Market is is really able to compete with
the legal regulated market right and so
although we've done some things right
there are some things that we got sort
of sort of wrong in that capacity
um you know it really is about matching
your policy goals to uh the drafting
that you put down on paper right
whenever we create a complex regulatory
system and and for most jurisdictions
this is coming out of nothing right so
we are it's a really unique situation in
which uh we're not evolving a regulatory
structure we're coming up with one from
scratch and so those always have
unintended consequences and so you know
a place like New York has a really
robust social Equity program
um that stems from those Regulators
having a specific set of policy
objectives in mind and then working
backwards through the regulations and
understanding how to draft a set of
regulations that promote those specific
policy objectives
um and it's it's a really difficult
thing to do and so really what you have
to do as a jurisdiction is you have to
understand what you want your ultimate
Market to look like right
um in Europe you know we don't have uh
the same concerns that we do in the
United States you know using social
Equity as an example there is not this
history of animus towards you know
certain sets of individuals uh and the
drug war has not been used to really you
know wage a war on on certain
individuals that we now need to include
in the market going forward
um and so you don't have that policy
goal so you'd write a set of regulations
sort of on a fundamentally different a
different basis um and so really it's
about working backward from the market
that you want to see
um you know an efficient market that has
predictability in transactions consumer
protection uh the ability to track and
Trace some of the products that are
going through to make sure that they're
not being diverted either out of state
in the United States or out of the
country uh in Europe
um and and really working back from that
to make sure that you're having a
cohesive regulatory structure that that
you know you can overlay on top of an
existing market right because that's the
other unique thing about the Cannabis
industry is not only do we not have
regulations
um and so we're creating this regulatory
structure from scratch but there's an
existing set of demand for the product
right and so in virtually every
jurisdiction in which we see
legalization occur uh it's not because
people want to you know create access
where there was no access before it's
because we want to formalize the access
we want to ensure that there's product
testing we want to ensure that you know
tax revenue accrues to the government
um and so really you're you're you're
trying to
you're trying to place a regulatory
regime on top of an existing Market that
you know to this point has been
unregulated so
um really it's a piecemeal it's a
piecemeal sort of process
um for European Regulators that are
trying to create these regulatory
structures you know it's really about
going through and understanding what
each specific legislature and regulator
wanted to see from the end product in
each one of these states right so what
is the purported uh focus of the
regulations right what is you know is it
to increase your tax revenue through
increasing the tax revenue base
um do you want to do that through
specific taxes on uh cannabis related
entities you know so do you want to have
a cultivation tax or do you want to
ensure that each one of these companies
that has been created is paying an
income tax that's more sort of more
aligned with with traditional taxation
right and so uh one of the problems
again here in California that we've seen
is that we have all these different
stages of Taxation but that takes away
from the overall tax base you know for
for a company paying into the income tax
right and so income tax is reduced
because we've made competition more
difficult because we had things like the
cultivation tax which was recently
recently repealed for for exactly those
reasons
amazing very interesting indeed and
another question do you think a
standardized testing system for the
United States when Federal legalization
comes is going to be easy to implement
or do you still think it'll always be on
a state-by-state basis surely if there's
going to be interested Commerce there
needs to be an overarching spectrum of
rules that everybody has to apply by
sure
um you know the FDA is never going to
give up so our Food and Drug
Administration right the dual federalism
problem is always going to sort of arise
um the Food and Drug Administration its
primary directive is to ensure health
and safety
um of products that are consumable
products for individuals right uh not
only consumables but also Cosmetics
they're never going to sort of let go of
that jurisdictional you know that
jurisdictional purview so we're going to
need some sort of national uh National
mechanism whereby you know we can see if
products are safe for consumption
um that being said right like what we've
seen in the Auto industry in the United
States is uh we have state by state
regulation
but we have production plans that
primarily take place in in certain
jurisdictions right and so we may have
all of our cars that are made in Detroit
but California has the most stringent
emission standards and so what happens
is those Detroit producers they have to
adhere to the California Admission
standards because those are the
strictests in the country and it's the
largest market in the country and so
really what I think I think naturally
before the FDA sort of establishes any
of those boundaries
um I think that probably we will tend
towards uh whatever one of those largest
consumer state has implemented for their
their testing policies I think
ultimately it's going to be a race to
the to the top as opposed to a race to
the bottom um I don't think that we're
going to see sort of a relaxation of
those health and safety standards I
think that we're gonna sort of pick the
state that has the most stringent
standards which at this point you know
is is sort of a you know there's a
competition but California has very very
stringent standards and so I think that
we're going to see sort of everyone
coalesce around what those standards are
in order to be able to have a national
market for cannabis in order to be able
to be eligible to you know ship your
product out of a producing state and to
access markets like California or New
York we're going to need to sort of you
know rise to the level of whatever
testing they establish there yeah I
couldn't agree more last question before
I let you go which do you think is going
to happen first safe Banking Act is
going to be passed or European country
is going to develop a recreational
Market
that's a great question
um
given the dysfunction of our Congress I
think that I think that a European
country is gonna going to establish that
that adult use Market
um you know I know that a couple are on
the cusp right now so
um you know I know that the laws in
Germany are changing very very quickly
uh I look forward to seeing what happens
in Europe
um I think that the only way that the
save Banking Act potentially beats the
implementation of an adult use Market in
Europe is if it gets you know sort of
snuck into one of the larger larger
bills that we have passing but our House
of Representatives is you know doesn't
doesn't have much of an appetite to pass
anything at this point so
um I would say that that's probably a
safe bet
um yeah yeah for us it's keep an eye in
Germany or Prague our Czech Republic
which one is going to get out of the
Golden's first so hopefully for the rest
of Europe and the global industry that
uh one of them gets assorted by the end
of 23 started 24. can't wait yeah it's
been amazing talking to you Chris thank
you very much for taking your time I
know you're a very busy man so I'll let
you go for anybody who wants to learn
more about the incpa the website is
below and it'll be on all the links no
matter what platform you're watching or
listening up highly recommend checking
the boat they're a top legal Source in
the global industry so Chris thank you
very much again for taking the time
thanks so much really appreciate it
until next episode everybody