[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review on this episode
we're going to be talking all things but
kind about cannabis storage i'm
delighted to be joined by michael joyce
who's the
director of business development for
cookie jar canadian company who've
designed some incredible new technology
to be storing your cannabis and
collecting it and inspecting michael how
are you keeping i'm doing very well owen
thanks for having me today
delighted happy anniversary cannabis
storage is one of these ones as i'm
researching the whole global industry
that uh i've yet to have anybody on
about the topic so i did a little bit of
research and delighted to come across
that the products and the digital
application that you guys have developed
do you want to give everybody maybe a
quick little overview of the cookie jar
story and how you got to where you are
now and then we'll jump into the first
topic
yeah absolutely so uh our founders are
two serial entrepreneurs and they had
developed a
an event-based
company uh just prior to the start of
the pandemic
and with all the regulations and
everything and
proper safety precautions uh the the
event-based business
wasn't the right time um they'd had a
conversation with one of our founders
sons uh who's a cannabis user
uh shortly after legalization here in in
2018 and uh the conversation evolved as
he pulled out a plastic bag with
cannabis in it
um
you know and
being entrepreneurs and
and inquisitive minds they started
asking questions and
quickly realized that
plastic storage isn't really ideal for
cannabis it allows things to interact it
allows for permeability of air all kinds
of factors that that really decrease the
quality or degrade the quality of your
cannabinoids
and it spirals from there
you know very fortunate to
live in a world where there's lots of
resources and lots of manufacturing
options
and they concluded that you know storing
cannabis in plastic is detrimental and
you can visit our website to learn all
kinds of information about that
but really the ideal
medium for storage is is glass because
it's inert
and and on top of that uv glass uv
restrictive or uv resistant
glass because uv light
further degrades thc into cbn uh so it
reduces that psychoactive effect uh that
high feeling that some people seek out
when uh when consuming
you know the the the story evolves quite
a bit um
you know one of our biggest
differentiators here is um you know in a
country where we're fully legal
but it all started out with medicinal
cannabis it's important to recognize
that
uh inspection of your cannabis prior to
consumption is is so important
so our lid is is very unique within the
industry
it is airtight but it's also built with
an edge to edge five times magnifying
glass to allow people to better inspect
their cannabis
keep it in that airtight container
without having to
unnecessarily expose it to the
environment
um you know but there's other factors
that play in here as well
you know we're
one of the first countries to fully
legalize
uh and we've been
essentially
fully illegal for for almost 100 years
here in north america
so
there's a lot of misinformation out
there
unfortunately and a lot of propaganda or
misleading statements
so a lot of
what our company is about is is helping
educate people
you know on on the importance of access
the importance of how it's produced
how it's stored is is vitally important
for the end consumer
so a lot of what we do with our our app
the cookie jar app which is completely
free and available on ios and android
is provide people with information to
help them educate themselves on the
potential benefits of cannabis how it
might interact with them
how it might help them with various
different uh struggles that they're
having
okay amazing so can you tell me one of
the things that i'm sure a lot of people
want to know about when it comes to kind
of a storage what are they they kind of
let's say the two biggest things that
are happening your cannabis if you're
not storing in an airtight glass
container what are the two big things
that consumers of cannabis need to be uh
informed about and the reason why they
should be upgrading their storage uh
component
yeah so probably the two biggest factors
will be airflow and light
so airflow
oxidizes thc which is one of the most
common and sought after cannabinoids
when it oxidizes it becomes cbn and and
just doesn't have the same effect
it is still a cannabinoid there is still
medical benefits to it
um but it's not what people are
necessarily seeking out
the second factor is going to be light
because uv does degrade thc as well
so those are probably the two biggest
factors
the third would be
humidity
you know if just like
any foods really they're susceptible to
the environment and if there is too much
humidity
uh you're more likely to develop molds
or mildews which we don't want to
consume
and if it's too dry
that dryness dries out the the terpenes
and the trichome structures in your
cannabis uh and your trichomes are
really what
contain the vast majority of of the
cannabinoids that that most people seek
out so
the top two would be airflow and and
uv light exposure to uv light and then
followed
closely by
uh by humidity
okay great thank you and can you give
the viewers an exact where about to you
guys in canada and where are your
products available in that territory
have you guys branched down into america
as of yet
yeah so we're based in ottawa canada so
our nation's capital and uh our products
are currently available right across
north america canada and united states
um
we do have distribution points in both
countries and we are
looking at expanding into the rest of
the world more more readily
okay and do you guys see a position as a
consumer storage that you guys are
mainly focused on excuse me or is there
is there a massive difference between
let's say large-scale storage for the
bulk's providers and a consumer storage
and are you guys pivoting into both
sectors are you going to stick to
consumer side of things yeah so uh
predominantly our focus is on the
consumer storage um the the legal
growers and
you know the industry level people
typically have great storage in their
facility
um
the so so our main focus is on on the
end consumer
that being said we do have some products
that are
in development we'll say
um that are more suited towards licensed
producers
for them to be able to start preserving
those you know important cannabinoids
and terpenes
earlier on in the process so that at the
end of the day the end consumer does
have a product that that is superior
okay very interesting and we were just
talking there briefly before we came
online that you guys are in a lockdown
over in canada at the moment but one of
the pluses is that you've got a legal
cannabis industry with a curbside
deliveries
what has been the biggest uh product you
see
we were reading a lot about oxley taking
a lot of the share from some of the big
providers are you seeing that uh small
cultivar taking a major share from the
big huge bullet providers as we're
starting to read from this territory
yeah very much so um you know if you
look at the the statistics from a couple
years ago
kind of the big five the the five
largest
volume producers controlled i think it
was about eighty percent of the market
um
you know now it's it's much more on the
craft side uh the the smaller growers
that are
they're doing a great job um you know
but they're really dialing in
the specifics of you know temperature
and light penetration and and nutrient
balance and ph and how long to to
vegetative growth and how long to flower
and
um they just seem to be going uh that
little extra mile um and and we are
seeing it here in canada that that those
craft growers the people that are
putting
you know the the taking the minutia of
the plant
and uh and focusing on it focusing on
the littlest aspects
they're making a little bit difference
here a one percent growth here or one
percent growth here or
improvement
and they are eating away at that market
from
from the the big five businesses here um
so it's it's it's nice to see because
there is a lot of variety coming out
um there's growers out there that are
using different grower mediums that are
a little bit more environmentally
conscious with how they're producing
you know that are working with
you know marginalized
minorities or or different aspects of
culture like it's it's really it's it's
wonderful to see because
the the restrictions here in canada have
been
lightened we'll say uh or or lessened to
a degree in in getting through that
license producer application
so we do have newcomers to the industry
quite regularly
um
but we are seeing a huge influx of that
craft growing
mentality
and
the availability of quality craft
cannabis here in canada much much like
we experienced with uh with beer
yeah and alcohols over the last kind of
decade
so it's it's wonderful it gives people
options and and ultimately
as long as they're making informed
decisions
we're happy
yeah i don't know uh it's one of the few
industries where i don't know any
cannabis consumer where if we went up
and said look here's a half an ounce of
the best weed in the world or here's two
ounces it is crap weed that anybody's
gonna take the two ounces of the crap
wheat everybody it's the one industry
where i don't think there is a low tier
market and i i don't think the the craft
suppliers will be able to cater to the
people with a nuanced taste
and uh
exact product that they're looking for
as opposed to the the coke or the pepsi
of the market
yeah you're you're very right i mean
there is uh
it's an interesting perspective here
because uh particularly here in ontario
uh you know our province
there is a huge
shift in marketing um and and kind of
the the market perspectives
so
we have something here that the
government has implemented called an
excise tax
uh which basically
taxes based on quality is kind of the
best way i can think about it so the the
better the quality product the more tax
you're paying
um
it's it's very unique um i actually i
don't know of any other industry where
where something like that happens where
you're paying more tax
for a superior product exactly
so
kind of over the last year or so there's
there's been
i guess for lack of a better better term
it's price wars
so you are seeing really quality
cannabis from a
huge number of of growers here in canada
that is
priced below market value um because
they have to do something to compete so
we're in a bit of an interesting area
an interesting time for cannabis here in
canada um you know we're we're very
lucky that our federal government is
going through an 18-month review right
now
to
[Music]
kind of look at the whole industry over
the last three years and and
re-establish things because
you know the excise tax is a bit is a
big aspect but also it's a it's a whole
new industry right so
everybody coming into it was
was very green and
if i want to use an industry term
um
you know so it'll be interesting to see
kind of in the next 15 months or so or
16 months
where
where the government wants to
kind of give and take a little bit
but right now with the price wars that
are going on
uh with so much of the
the cannabis flower specifically on the
market being undervalued
there are
discount brands popping up everywhere
so you can go and buy
an ounce of cannabis here in canada for
a hundred dollars
which is
a very reasonable price if you ask me um
but there are also
you know the consumers that that really
do care about i just want the best
quality product yeah you know i want
something that's going to do this or i
want something that's going to do this
and help me relax or
help stimulate my appetite or
help me with nausea or pain or you know
and and that's one of the things that
that we here at cookie jar are really
focused on is is helping people
understand that
cannabis isn't just used to get high um
you know it's actually
it's a miracle drug if you ask me um i
don't even like using the term drug it's
a medicine
um
you know one of the oldest in human
history
okay well on that note we've just come
up to our 15 minutes time now it's been
a pleasure talking to you michael and i
hope we get to such base again in the
towards the end of the year maybe see
how you guys are getting on for
everybody wants to know more about
cooking jar of their products come and
check them out the website is below
there and they're very sleek when uh
class design so the best of luck would
ever do in the future michael and uh
thank you very much for coming on the
show it was a pleasure and uh if anybody
has any questions you know how to reach
us take care everybody thanks everybody
for watching