[Music]
welcome everybody to another episode of
the cannabis review i am delighted to be
joined by matthew harold on today's show
to talk about some marketing and other
things matthew how you keeping
it's great to be here i want to just
thank you so much for having me
on i'm excited to talk to you it's great
to have you on i've been following your
work on linkedin it's uh some great
insights you've been providing for the
the people on linkedin so great to
finally chat to you
let's kick things off but basically you
just exploit explain to everybody
where you're at i know you're the
marketing director of good fields maybe
how you got to that position and how you
got into the cannabis industry
real quick yeah sure um you know it's
it's been uh a short but also long road
at the same time
a lot of action so a few years back i
had a major life
change i um i actually lost my father in
a bicycle accident and i
delved into guardian caretaking for my
mother
so i had a ton of responsibility i left
a career in health and wellness
and got a really close-up view of some
of the stigmas against cannabis
within the traditional and conventional
medical spheres
when my mother was misdiagnosed and i
presented cannabis as a solution they
were trying to come up with
diagnoses like dementia and then
parkinson's
and really it was adverse reactions to
the medications they were putting her on
and so i found it a bit disheartening
that i couldn't have a conversation
with some of the doctors in charge
of her care to have really something
that i saw as a productive exploration
for something that could help her
now in this time a close friend of mine
started to check in on me just to see if
i was okay
and it was sort of my escape that we
would talk about
the new vertically integrated company
that he had just been promoted
to director of operations so we'd spend
hours getting into the spreadsheets
talking about what are the problems or
challenges that they're trying to
overcome
and i got more and more interested and
he was definitely nudging me along the
way
and finally i decided to take it
seriously so i studied cannabis very
intensely
for about six months and then
just over two years ago i did a week of
training where i got to see
every single aspect from the extraction
laboratory
to the cloning the mother room the full
cultivation
experience to how it's processed trimmed
cured
packaged transported and then i started
my very first day inside a medical
dispensary on 420
two years ago that quickly led to
all sorts of opportunities promotion
into marketing
and since then i've worked with several
companies after staying there about a
year
and here we are today amazing okay
that's a pretty great story
um okay let's kick into the first topic
of conversation i think it's something
that you're going to be able to shine a
lot of light on
cannabis becoming a wellness industry do
you agree or disagree
absolutely agree absolutely
do you see much more acquisitions
happening now from the wellness side
of business into the cannabis side
it's hard to say how it's going to go
exactly i i can't speak to that
specifically but what i can
say is that the wellness industry is
very very large i think a lot of people
don't realize
that it is it's bigger than alcohol it's
also bigger than
the global pharmaceutical industry we're
looking at a 4.5
trillion dollar industry beauty alone
which cannabis has barely begun to touch
though we know
some of the efficacy of cbd as well as
there's promising results for other
cannabinoids like even thc
a in its raw form seems to be beneficial
to the skin
and beauty is a trillion dollar industry
alone and that's just part of wellness
so when we look at that we look at the
spa
scene which is considered separate we
look at all these caretaking services
there's a lot of opportunity for
cannabis to be integrated into those
i think we're at the very very beginning
yet
my personal perspective comes from the
standpoint of looking at the data for
why people consume cannabis in the first
place
and when you dig into those you see that
even if somebody is not necessarily a
medical patient they may be
self-medicating
and at the very least their reasons
typically
are all surrounding something that is
relatable to wellness and the pursuit of
a higher quality of life
okay yeah i think it's it's an exciting
one that most people aren't paying too
much attention the the capital that the
wellness industry does have to be able
to enter this space
is going to be pretty vast and when they
do finally push the button i think
there's going to be a
a big chunk of the industry brought up
by the wellness industry next topic of
conversation that is something i think
again you're an expert that and most
people haven't got a clue about
the art of marketing in the cannabis
industry again a lot of people are
barred from using social media sites
we had luke from can an la based
uh micro dose drink on they had a great
campaign
where they they more imitated to what
the effects and
the lifestyle that reflects can do you
see a lot of creative campaigns
happening like that
or do you see people sitting on their
hands and not knowing really what to do
with themselves
i think you get a mix of both right
can's a great example
um it's interesting you say that because
can
recently entered massachusetts we're
also a beverage company at good feels
so we're doing a lot in the aspect of
celebrating life and wellness that's the
essence of what we do
and across the board there's certainly a
lot of confusion now
each state has different regulations
which is going to make it challenging
for example
a distinct east coast west coast
difference
in california on adult consumption
products you can offer
promotional discounts on the east coast
here in massachusetts
you cannot offer discounts so right away
that
that shifts your strategy for marketing
tremendously in terms of people sitting
on their hands
i think you do have people that are
confused at what they can and can't do
social media is a challenge digital
advertising
is starting to open up just in the last
year or two
so i think we're going to see a lot more
creativity coming to the forefront
okay and we've recently seen new york
have legalized cannabis and we saw duchy
have their big huge billboard on times
square
and uh weed maps if i'm not if i'm not
mistaken had another one there the other
weeks
do you see that becoming a lot more
prominent across the state such as super
bowl ads and
what not where the cannabis industry is
up there with the pepsis and the cokes
and the budweiser ads
in in terms of quality is going to be in
terms of quality
um yes i think that's coming cannabis
comes from a background
very closely integrated with music art
and all sorts of um you know back in the
prohibition in the us
there's a very prominent actor that
refused
to to stop speaking about cannabis and
he got
arrested he was a very high profile
person my point being that
in terms of the quality of what we're
going to see i think it's gonna keep
getting better
there are more celebrities signing in
into the space
everyone from martha stewart to jay-z um
it's going to bring that level of
production up
and i have to say i can't wait to see
the first
real cannabis super bowl advertisement
in terms of a brand representing itself
providing something inspirational the
same way that alcohol does
yeah no i couldn't agree with you more
and how
to you guys it feels good or good feel
excuse me how are you
finding the the ability to maneuver
within each state and over you guys you
have separate state laws so
have you guys got distribution
nationwide or is it specific states that
you guys have focused on i'd be
interested to know your distribution
method
sure so in terms we're in the middle of
launching in massachusetts and we've
already had conversations
because the interest is there of whether
or not we want to be in other states
our focus is going to be similar to what
some other companies have done to be
successful which is
we're going to hone in on getting really
strong in massachusetts we want to we
are a massachusetts born company
and so we're going to focus on
connecting with our local communities
educating them on our product as well as
we want to
give back to the community our company
just converted to 100
renewable energy all of our employees
started 20
or higher that's entry level for us
and we are doing a number of other
things like converting to
all plant-based materials to set the
tone that
when we look at life and wellness it's
more than just
you as a person but feeling good about
all the things that you're doing
outside of yourself and that translates
back to your own wellness
so in terms of our strategy we're trying
to start
local with ourselves and the people
around us then over time
we're gonna look at what are the best
ways to go
state by state what i can say is it's
really important
to spend some time before doing homework
looking at that regulation at those
regulations because they are going to be
distinctly different
in some very important key points
especially when it comes to marketing
yeah due diligence i think is uh
paramount when it comes to setting up at
the cannabis industry regardless of the
territory at the moment
one of the things that actually is
pretty impressive is the way you guys do
treat your staff and some of the
policies you have i think
one of the great things about the
cannabis industry there's so many
creative people
and it breeds a certain mindset to get
into this industry in the first place
because you have to chase your own tail
there's no
clear pathway to success so it's always
great to see companies
investing in their staff and bringing
them along on the journey as opposed to
kind of profit profit profit i think the
cannabis industry is going to be a great
way to lead in terms of social equity
and
reinvest in profits into the community
the last thing i kind of wanted to bring
up at you was
it's a bit of a random one now and i
just interested to know what you do
if you had ten thousand dollars as a
startup for a marketing budget
what are the top three things you'd
recommend any startup you don't need to
go into too much detail just give the
maybe top three bullet points of what
you think 10 grand would get you
sure um i think for one starting to
you know there are a lot of companies
that don't invest in their own brand
so i think doing some research spending
some of that money
into the sweat of really getting out
there
whether it's through digital medium or
getting
in person which has been difficult to
interview people
and start testing ideas so with good
feels we went through
an exercise to really learn we we had
all these parts right
and jason who's the founder is a
tremendous person
so is his whole family his wife is you
know they think very similarly and
that's why i'm on board because i think
the same way
i think brands can can really hone in
on understanding who they are what
they're providing
who are they providing for and getting
getting that down to an essence so that
it's only a few words long
when you do that homework up front it's
gonna guide the entire marketing plan
from there i think we're in the age of
content production
so you're gonna need to have a story
whether that's investing in the time to
film and photograph whatever you're
doing before you launch
whether it's working with creatives to
to build out something that's exciting
and entertaining and delightful
for people to engage with um
those are the things that i would invest
in i would invest in
relationships also in educating people
who are within the industry
um forming a relationship with
dispensaries with retailers
holding in on-site trainings as
kovid starts to shift back perhaps to a
more normal way of life
that's going to be extremely important
and providing investing
in those materials like what's something
someone can hold
and bring home with them that's not only
going to provide them value and tell
your story
which is is inspiring it's also to
educate them
on how to have the best experience when
they consume cannabis
safety first and always about how do we
how do we make it so it's most enjoyable
and going to raise up someone's quality
of life
that's something that's always very
important to me and i think when we
exude that as a company
people really resonate they feel that
they feel that they're cared for
and that's going to be a real um
ingredient for a successful company
amazing
this has been hugely informative and a
great discussion to have with you
anybody wants to know more about good
feels the website is there below on the
screen
i highly recommend you follow matthew on
linkedin
he's a daily source of information and
positivity that's well much needed
in a sometimes a [ __ ] show of in
misinformation so
it's been great to chat you met you i
hope we get to chat again before the end
of the year
and uh we've got lots more to discuss on
a positive note
thanks for having me this was a lot of
fun i'll do it again anytime
you take care have a great day everybody
we'll be back again soon