[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i am delighted to be
joined on this episode by jason wong he
is the creative director of puffco and
in a past life a multi-talented
world-renowned musician jason how are
you keeping today
good how are you i'm fantastic made us
delighted to be talking to you on the
show puffco are a very exciting company
that i've been reading up on a lot and i
know you're at the forefront of
everything that's going on there at the
new creative sector can you maybe give
everybody a little overview of how you
got into the industry from music into
cannabis and your position at pubco at
the moment
sure
so i started out my life journey as a
drummer in a rock band in the 80s uh
here in la which was at the time the
mecca of music
especially that genre so i spent my teen
and early 20s playing in bands uh going
on tour doing the whole musician life
and um after
my 20s i uh got married and realized
that i couldn't no longer be on the road
and live a lifestyle of a musician and
be married so i decided to give up music
and
focus on starting a family and in doing
so i had to find a job and the only job
that i could find was as basically a
janitor at an industrial design company
i had no high school diploma i was a
high school dropout just a musician so
wasn't qualified for anything other than
a janitorial job so i took the job and
just worked my way up the ladder long
story short um got to work at a
broadcast design company
and uh started just learning how to uh
learning my trade and learning how to
design and doing uh graphics for
television networks
and uh did a couple of high profile
projects like the super bowl open i did
uh
the olympics 1996 olympics for uh nbc
those were two huge profile high profile
jobs and from there just my design
career took off and i was able to start
my own creative agency um that got
acquired by a publicly traded company in
and i was just freelancing around town
and heard about this opportunity at
pufco
uh and decided to see if i could meet
with them and speak to them about the
role was to to be the head of creative
and build a creative department at uh
pufco so instead of hiring an ad agency
to do all the all the creative and
marketing work uh build a department to
be able to do that in-house and that's
kind of uh how i ended up at puffco
okay amazing pretty exciting story there
for uh for
the first half of your life so for and
i'm sure roger founded the company in
2013 you guys are on the way to doing
100 billion turnover it's been a pretty
impressive story so far and i have to
admit the design of the products are
pretty amazing and beautiful and some of
the new accessories for the line for the
viewers can you tell the two different
product ranges that puffco do have for
consumers
so currently we have we last year uh for
an april fools kind of a campaign or
uh an idea we released a product called
budsee which is the first non-electronic
uh device that we put out um it's
basically a water bottle uh a bong
disguised as a water bottle uh and it
was like an april fool's joke people
thought it was a joke they didn't think
it was real um so we released it april
1st last year and it was a huge success
um so our products basically
we focus on trying to provide
the most uh enjoyable experience with
the plant so the plant is to us a
medicine or a gift that we have and we
just want to create a technology to
provide
the most uh intuitive and enjoyable and
flavorful experience uh with the plant
and that's kind of the puffco uh mission
that kind of brings me on to the first
topic i want to highlight is puffco
being the most awarded it's uh the
flavorful experience is it the the
innovation with the technology that's
done in-house what do you think is the
number one factor that makes puffco the
number one brand at the moment
i think it's um
i think it's a time we spend in the and
the
thoughts we put into every little detail
uh previously in my career before
joining puffco i did get to work with
steve jobs over at apple for about seven
years
uh and um it was about the time when he
got back to apple after he was let go
and he came back and it it reminds me a
lot pubco reminds me a lot of the spirit
that apple had
when i was working there with uh with
steve and the rest of the apple team
it's
attention to detail making sure that um
everything is there for a reason
everything that all the features all the
things that are on any electronic device
is intuitive and it's meaningful and
it's it's well thought out and i think
you know puffco has a brand and as a
company yes we're a business yes we want
to make profit but um i think you know
our main goal
isn't to turn a profit or to make as
much money as possible squeeze every
dollar out of our customers our main
goal is to provide a
very meaningful and enjoyable experience
and put it put all all our energies and
thoughts into making that as thoughtful
as possible to the consumers and i think
that in return makes up for a successful
brand because the mission is just like
if you have a career goal and your goal
is only to make money um that's all
you're going to do and focus on but if
you
learn your craft and do your job really
really well and put a lot of thought and
effort into what you're putting your
energy towards the money becomes a side
effect of the great work that you're
doing so i think that's kind of what
puffco's mission is is to always chase
innovation and not chase money and uh
you know profits and all the other great
things that happen by creating a
wonderful product and bringing it into
the marketplace um is you know uh the
the profits and the success financial
success is all a byproduct of that
yeah i would agree i think cannabis
industry is a unique industry when you
look at it from the consumer's point of
view you could have a customer for four
to five decades
if you've got a good product and the
good products are really the ones that
kind of rise their top that it's not a
case of lowest market price sales in
this industry at all whereas let's say
in chocolate or drinks industry or
whatever it might be i think cannabis
consumers are well educated they know
what's going into their body they would
sooner spend that a little bit extra and
if you can provide the perfect design
which you guys have done which i think
it's you've built a perfect by the
perfect
products but then you seem to have
stripped them down anything that wasn't
required gets taken out immediately it's
not about just building an extended
building and making sure every component
in the device has a use
yeah absolutely and even when we do
upgrade versions or we do our limited
editions um our product lines um there
we don't just put things out for the
sake of putting it out we really put a
lot a lot of thought um we have an
amazing product team we had an amazing
quality control team we have an amazing
customer service team it really takes an
entire infrastructure an entire team of
people to make a successful brand
because there's so many touch points
with it with the consumer and so many
things that need to be carefully thought
out and and really work through and i
think our biggest
asset is that we do have a very
passionate and loyal consumer base
and they
give us their feedback and they let us
know what they'd like to see they let us
know what they don't like you know we
listen and i think for
us as a brand or as a company to have a
dialogue
with our customers and not just have a
monologue i think is a very huge kind of
uh advantage that we have
yeah it's been lovely and interesting
looking from ireland at the the north
american scene you can start to see now
the top companies in each sector coming
to the fore puffco and your territory
can in the beverages industry cookies in
the dispensaries industry and i think
that's just going to become more and
more prevalent with m as over the next
couple of years so it seems to be an
exciting let's say next five ten years
ahead for what could be huge potential
for puffco
absolutely it is very exciting i think
yeah technology evolves really quickly i
think one of the beautiful things about
puffco and why i enjoy working here so
much is that we're a purpose-driven
brand we're not a brand that's just
purposefully uh strictly capitalistic
we're a brand that care about social
issues where a brand that care cares
about human equality we care about uh
all of the people that uh the shoulders
of the giants that we're standing on
people that had are served had had to
serve 25 30-year sentences in jail to be
able to you know for us to enjoy the
legalization that we have currently um
all of the things that we we do we do it
with purpose just like with our devices
i think we're very aware of um social
causes and things that we feel
passionate about and we
feel passionate about along a side along
with our community so that uh we're not
just a voice on our own but we're able
to hand our megaphone or share our
platform with those voices that need to
be heard
yeah and i think companies like
yourselves need to lead for the front
cause it's not just all about capital
gains and returns of this industry where
we're much more vested in the industry
work and as a whole and delivering
quality products to people than just
having a couple of commas in a bank
account at the end of the day 100 100
and i think you know the cannabis
industry was born out of activism right
it was a demonized
plant medicine that got a bad pr wrap
and uh you know it's starting to be
normalized i think we have to be at the
forefront of normalizing this plant and
really sharing the benefits of this
plant medicine for me personally um i
have a huge sleeping disorder um for
many many years and the doctors
prescribed me every sleeping pill every
you know
a valium and any xanax you name it i've
been prescribed to try to put me to
sleep it works it does put you to sleep
but you know your the rest of your day
is ruined after you wake up because it's
such a powerful tranquilizer and when i
got introduced to cannabis uh in cbd it
changed my world it truly added value to
my life i got off of these poisons um
it's the only thing i used to to go to
sleep and relax and it's it's been a
huge asset to to my well-being in so
many different ways mentally physically
um i feel so much better um so it's
really provided me
a a
enjoyable kind of alternative to the
prescription drugs that the doctors were
prescribing me yeah that's one of the
topics i was going to go which was from
tranquilizers to edibles because i don't
know about your journey going from there
so yeah it's great to highlight
everybody that you don't need to be
consuming a lot of tablets to get a good
night's sleep there are a number of
different methods out there if you did a
little bit of research on it it's going
to bring me on to the last topic the
perfect cannabis consumption
what do you think is the perfect way to
consume cannabis and
all the little variables that would go
with that i think um to me personally i
think that there is no wrong way um it's
just what you prefer right so um i still
enjoy every you know i enjoy a joint you
know sharing a joint with my friends uh
i enjoy taking edibles i enjoy vaping
concentrates um i enjoy every process of
it my favorite way is um you know not
only because i've worked at puffco but
the peak pro is my favorite uh way to
consume it's just so simple clean easy
flavorful i enjoy it very much um and
you know i do it at a i don't do it to
like chase you know
clouds or anything like that i do to
really enjoy the flavor of the plant
and to really enjoy uh you know good
quality hash and to relax me and go to
sleep so i think there's no wrong way i
think you have to find something that
works for you
uh whether it's edibles or tinctures or
you know the good old flower or
concentrates just find something that
works for you and then explore and and
experiment with other ones and see if
you can find something that even suits
your lifestyle or your needs better
couldn't agree with you more i know
you're an extremely busy man so i'm not
going to take up too much more your day
everybody the website for puffco is
obviously below a lot of you've already
been there if you haven't should go
check out their concert pens and their
portable water pipes they're absolutely
top-notch jason i can't thank you enough
for coming on the show and hope we get
to chat again in the near future great
absolutely thank you for having me it's
been a pleasure thank you everybody for
watching check in the next episode