[Music]
welcome everybody to the latest episode
of the cannabis review i'm delighted to
be joined on this episode by mara gordon
she's the co-founder of the renowned
company and zelda how are you keeping
mara
well thank you and yourself
i'm very well thank you very much i'm
delighted to have you on the show going
to talk about the dosing in medical
cannabis on this episode and maybe mary
you could give the viewer an overview of
where you kind of got yourself into the
cannabis industry and where you are at
the moment over the us
so the the
way that i got into cannabis to in
initially was because there was no
data
around dosing and what you were taking
and how you were taking it how much to
take for various diseases etc and so i
decided to focus on solving the the
dosing questions uh initially this was
back uh 2010 when i started doing this
and been working on collecting data and
working with patients ever since
okay great so perfect person to talk
about on this topic i'm going to jump
straight away in the first topic and
that is the art of the exact dosage it's
a lot of the things i'm sure doctors are
afraid of prescribing the medicine most
people don't want to go near because
there's a myriad of combinations that
can be actually put together and it all
depends on patient can you give
everybody a little overview on your
methods and what you think may be the
perfect dose for different types of
people
um yeah the first thing i would say is
there's no such thing as a perfect dose
for the typical person
because there is and we're all have
different endocannabinoid systems and
they all work differently with different
diseases however we have been able to
identify patterns
that make it closer to a week we call it
a target dose where you work with the
patient or you wear an individual work
towards a target amount of the
cannabinoid that they're that they're
working with
and with the understanding that they may
have to exceed it or they may not ever
make it to that high point if they don't
need it which is okay but what we do is
uh we always
look at any of the data that's out there
in the research have there been any
studies pre-clinical or clinical on a
particular disease set then
and then we're able to look from that
through our data because we have been
collecting over 300 data points on each
patient going in and then looking at
what they're using and how they're using
it and then
whether it's being effective or not and
being able to make some
some
some predictions on what the target
should be for various diseases for
example
if you
based upon the
research that's been done in the
pre-clinical on
breast cancer
there's three major subtypes of breast
cancer we look at
what is uh
where the cannabinoid receptors are
whether they're present
within these types of breast cancer and
something that we can target we know
that thc actively
activates the cannabinoid receptors so
we want to make sure there's thc we also
know that cbd also works in another way
of of
on the cancer cells through other
systems within the body as well so we
might start out a a
a ratio of one to one on the amount of
thc and cbd that the patient will use
and then based upon where their age is
we have found that there's variances
that as we get older we need less
to be able to
impact because of changes in metabolism
and changes that we frankly don't know
yet
but i always i always
stress that people need to start with a
very very low dose of the thc
maybe sometimes we have people that are
older
my age and higher that we're we're using
like one milligram to start
and titrating up very very slowly so
that we make sure that they don't have
any adverse reactions
because
even though it might make somebody feel
too activated or too
much psychoactivity at a particular dose
if you titrate slowly enough you can
avoid that and also if you stay at a
certain level long enough like a few
days to a week at a certain level that
makes you uncomfortable your body will
acclimate and it no longer will do that
so if we're able to titrate people up
that way we also know that you need more
cbd than thc because thc is much more
powerful than cbd so when you
incorporate cbd at some point you may go
from that one to one to one to two one
to three whatever higher on the cbd
as long as you have lab results that are
associated with the product and i'm
talking like lab results that show the
cannabinoid and terpene content beyond
the just thc and cbd but even with just
those if you have that then you can
calculate how many milligrams are in
each dose so that you can be very
controlled on taking the same thing over
and over again
i made some topical here yesterday just
because i'm in i'm in mexico right now
and
i didn't have access to aunt zelda's
here so i made some in my kitchen based
on the old the old style the way i used
to make it
and i wanted it to be 10 milligrams per
milliliter
of cannabinoid so i was able to take the
extract that i had knowing the lab
results that were on it just do simple
calculations and when i figured out the
volume of what i was making i was able
to then calculate out how many
milligrams of cannabinoids i had to
include in order to achieve that
i always recommend that people start
extremely slowly for example you know
2.5 milligrams as a wellness dose of thc
is often what it takes to get somebody
um to the right place if you're treating
serious diseases then it's a completely
different subject but for like something
like anxiety or
or slight pain
for a healthy person
um or somebody that just needs a little
edge to get to sleep that 2.5
may be all they need
okay would you think 2.5 would be the
same when it comes to let's say a cbd
edible we know we're going to have an
influx of them in the market a lot of
the time when the novel food license
applications in europe especially go
through so do you what what do you
recommend is the perfect dosage for a
smackdown or for an active treat
you know when you're talking about cbd
it depends on how it's derived and what
else is in there
because
cbd on its own
may make somebody feel activated you
know people talk about it not having any
you know psychoactivity is just not true
um it's certainly not true if it's a
whole plant where it's including
terpenes
and other components that may make
impact how a person feels
a lot of times the
hemp
varieties that are being grown
have
higher levels of pining in them for
example
and these might make somebody feel very
very focused or it might make somebody
feel very activated
and uncomfortable and anxious so
again i would say that if you're going
to get a a
candy bar or something which first of
all i don't i don't like that whole idea
but if you are if you're gonna get a
food product
i think keeping the whole thing under
under um
10 milligrams for that purpose is good
maybe if you have something that can
easily be subdivided uh into pieces
accurately then you can have a hundred
milligrams for the whole thing with the
ability to get ten
these are not medical products though
yeah these are well these are products
for people that are self-medicating that
are you know they have like a little
minor ailment
like maybe they just need that little
edge taken off instead of having a glass
of wine or a beer so but if you're
talking about people that are ill or
people that are really having trouble
with pain or anxiety or you know ptsd
things like that i mean they may need 50
to 100 milligrams to accomplish it
i think that people that say that they
feel a lot better from 5 to 10
milligrams i think a lot of that is the
placebo
yeah okay agreed on that can you i'm
going to move on to the next topic can
you tell the audience formal clinical
cannabis research and trials that have
happened
we know that they take it an extremely
long time could you maybe give an
overview of where the industry is at
that are their products ready to come to
market apart from the handful that
already made it over here in europe
what's the overview on that part
you know it's interesting i was on a i
was on a panel uh
last week where we were talking about
this exact topic and um
what what i am seeing is that there's a
lot of innovation going on outside of
the united states
um the united states still has so many
barriers to be able to do solid
research
and the barrier
to entry of a drug into the marketplace
from the fda is is much stricter than it
is in some other places the eu is pretty
strict too
but the but it's certainly like places
like australia where we do trials and
south africa brazil
colombia
portugal for example places like that
canada but even with that it takes it
takes years to get something through
process and millions and millions and
millions of dollars to do it
um
so
uh for example when we
uh through the lira therapeutics which i
co-founded also
when we um
when we were trialing our xenoval
product
we were able to use the data that i had
been accumulating through aunt zelda's
over the years for people that had
insomnia to be able to get a target dose
to start with to have a a better
opportunity and a more likelihood of
success um with the trial because you
know most trials fail so if you could
start out with something that's already
got somewhat of a track record you have
a better opportunity but
you have to go through everything from
uh
safety tests and then you have to go
through a whole trial of safety and you
have something called pk which is where
you have to find out what the actual
dose tolerance is so you make sure you
stay within a certain amount
and then you have to try it in small
group and then a larger group and we're
talking double blind placebo it's not
always so easy um i had a uh i spoke to
an oncology nurse one time in pediatrics
and she said how am i supposed to how am
i supposed to you know have do this
double blind when it's so obvious
which patients are vomiting and which
patients aren't vomiting and which
patients are happy and which patients
aren't based upon i mean where's where's
the placebo on that
so it is very challenging um
what i have recommended is that drugs go
through more of a biopharmaceutical
plant medicine
nutraceutical type model
of approval instead of going through the
whole you know fda
uh uh system which is it can take a
decade in millions and millions of
dollars there's still no guarantee that
you're going to get anything to market
i saw that epidiolex was just approved
in spain
it's a it's a
not a very good product but they've
spent millions and millions of dollars
in years uh gw getting it to market and
and
it's going to be hard to to catch up
with that
the one the one thing that i do
recommend is that
i'm not sure whether you have this in
ireland or whether it's uh and that is
the concept of orphan drugs
orphan diseases
and these are these are diseases that
there's not enough
people that that are uh that have been
diagnosed with this to justify i mean
there's an actual number i think it's
like 250 000 or something where there's
an actual um where there's not enough
people
for the
uh typical pharmaceutical companies to
develop a treatment for them
you know like there's not enough people
with huntington's there's really not
enough pediatric cancer it's actually
relative i mean in my world it seems
like it's constant but it's really in in
reality it's it's rare
dravet things like that these are rare
diseases and the obstacles to getting a
drug through
trialing is much faster
we did an observational study
at uh chops uh children's hospital of
philadelphia on autism looking at four
formulations there
for our hope line and um
i wasn't part of it but it was my
company that did it and uh um we were
able to observe based upon these and
that was groundbreaking to be able to do
that at a mainstream institution so
getting a drug to market
by going through an orphan
designation and then prescribing it off
label is a really good option for
getting drugs out there that's how many
many drugs get to market they get there
for one thing and then doctors use them
for many other
things okay very informative i'm gonna
end with the last topic we're nearly
running out of time you're in mexico at
the moment i'm sure the
the on off again legislation that seems
to be happening there what's your
overview of the industry over there at
the moment is it ready to explode or is
it still going to travel on for another
little while
i think it's going to travel along for a
little while um i'm speaking an event in
cancun in
november and it's a business and
technology event
and my hope is that at that time we'll
be able to sit down with some more of
the decision makers i have um i've
already been talking with with groups
that are going for licensing to grow and
manufacture
and
i'm hoping something will happen this
year you know it's a it's a it's a
complicated uh culture here
with you know the history of cannabis
obviously it's kind of funny to think
about uh people bringing now so much
cannabis from california to mexico
when you go into the country there's
signs saying you're not allowed to bring
marijuana into the country and it's just
it's just hilarious to me based upon
where we came from here i'm hoping that
in the next year we'll see at least some
regulations starting to take place
because yes it's been it's been
legalized but there's no infrastructure
yet to support it
okay very interesting we'll have to get
somebody on to further educate us on the
mexican industry over time but it's been
amazing talking to murray your wealth of
information and it's been an absolute
pleasure i hope we get to try to get in
the future sometime
anytime you my pleasure no problem
thanks everybody for watching see you
next time