foreign
by Dr Benjamin Kaplan who's the founder
and chief medical officer at CED clinic
and CED Foundation how you keep it today
Dr Kaplan I'm great Owen thanks for
having me
thank you very much very much for coming
on I know you're a busy man and we have
a very busy schedule
you're part of a number of
entrepreneurial Ventures and medical
Ventures and you've got a huge area of
expertise in boats and I've got to touch
on those towards the end of the show but
for now can we start with your book that
you've recently brought out called the
doctor approved cannabis handbook the
link will be in all the viewing and
listening positions that you're watching
this from can you maybe tell everybody
what uh motivated you to write this book
sure I mean I've I've seen the common
narrative that cannabis is poorly
understood
um the acceptance of cannabis by the
medical sort of community is is
languishing
um the the substance of course is
stigmatized um but the really the power
of evidence and research and advocacy is
is bringing real patients real relief
and it's just kind of lost on the
medical establishment
um and it seemed like the right thing to
do to to collect the patient's care
evidence that I've seen the research
that I'm doing and to share it with the
public in language that everybody can
understand
yeah and you have a huge wealth of
knowledge some of the statistics I was
coming across that over 16 000 patients
who've dealt with there must be a huge
data now that you've built up a a huge
database when it comes to the
methodology for going about gaining the
new information for the book was there a
specific way you went about doing this
or was it taken from data you'd already
accumulated
um
the medical establishment is is just
completely
left in the dark you know I think
doctors are not taught about medical
cannabis in in med school they're not
understanding the therapeutic value if
we were painting a picture there's a
gigantic hole in the middle which is
literally this the system which has the
most uh prolific signaling in the human
body and that's the endocannabinoid
system
um if you I mean if you imagine the
depth of
emptiness in the literature that we're
learning about the studies that we're
conducting the treatments that we're
providing you know
of course patients are missing you know
one of the one of the one of the systems
which causes joy in our body
um and to have that kind of as a as a
gigantic missing piece in medical care
is ludicrous
um so it sort of it became a kind of
mission on its own once I was
discovering this to share it with
everybody I mean this is something we
shouldn't be without
um and and you know listeners and
viewers might not know but
in the last hundred years is really the
only time in human history where
cannabis wasn't front and center we have
archaeological evidence going back 12
000 years that this was part of ancient
human history
um and certainly throughout the rest of
History just until you know the early
20th century this hasn't been part of of
normal dialogue but it's our human it's
a human plant
the book over 60 in different chapters
with a host and multitude of ailments
that can be researched uh and looked at
well when it comes to the future of the
medicine side of things obviously the
receptor targeting drugs and
formulations that are going to be able
to discover is that the the kind of the
big huge Market that's off in the future
that most cannabis companies will get
into or do you think that's going to be
dominated by Pharma
I mean I it's it's not all smoke and
mirrors you know the perception of
cannabis has often been clouded with
with myths and misconceptions and
skepticism but as more research has has
emerged it's clear that the therapeutic
benefits aren't just hearsay that people
are really finding benefits they're
rooted in rigorous science and evidence
and that's the underpinnings of the
traditional Pharma World they ground
Pharmaceuticals in evidence in studies
in clinical trials
um cannabis has just been going through
its own natural clinical trial people
have consumed it really forever Against
All Odds and against whatever laws told
them they couldn't and people have found
benefits I mean there are countries
where it's common to cook soup and to
drink tea with cannabis and everywhere
else people just did it because it felt
good it felt right
um so I think you know slowly the
mainstream establishment is catching up
with what people have already known
the story that was published by the
Journal of the American Medical
Association that's in your book that
noticed the increase in 65 and over age
group in using cannabis surely that's
the secret untucked Market that most
people aren't really focusing on I know
there's everybody thinks strong about
get their their modern user over into
the industry and it's not going to be
via smoking it's not going to be via
vaping Edibles they're not really
getting dosed and Emulsion Technologies
at the scale where they they should be
so surely that's 65 and over who can
have a pill for a multitude of different
ailments are that secret untapped
audience that people should be focused
on their own deal yeah it's not it's not
so secretive um you know Medicare budget
and Medicaid is close to 30 billion and
the government at least in the US but
really other governments as well are
spending so much money to take care of
our our our most sensitive populations
these older adults as we get older the
ailments of Aging catch up with us the
joints become painful the days become
longer it's harder to sleep you know all
of these things things surprise surprise
are tied to the endocannabinoid system
and if we're not looking and learning
about the endocannabinoid system if
we're not treating that we're just
treating half of half of the people we
see it's just it's it's it's it's a
paradigm without a core Mission without
a core Central piece
um the book has of course clear chapters
dedicated to to ailments of Aging
um not the least of which is cancer I
mean most of us get cancer about 40 of
people get cancer as we get older
um but creating an end-of-life plan I
mean imagine we live in a world now
where dying is this weird time most of
us you know don't have the luxury of
dying with Dignity
um it's either costly or disconnected
from our families when we're getting
sick and going to hospitals
um that shouldn't happen it doesn't have
to happen um and I think there's a way
to incorporate cannabinoid therapies and
a cannabinoid understanding of moods of
memory of feeling Joy which can make
aging less uncomfortable
do you see the population-based medicine
moving towards a more individualistic
approach or do you still think it seems
to be a one-size-fits-all at the moment
well traditional medicine it's one size
fits all you you have depression we got
this array of pills to treat you with
that's ridiculous all of us are
different
um even one day from the next you know
you might have a beautiful day or see a
beautiful movie and feel differently
um should you be taking the same
medicine which amplifies things as if
you're not changing at all that Paradigm
doesn't make sense
um on the other hand you know we we've
sort of fallen in love with this genetic
medicine Where oh my gosh if we only had
your map we would understand exactly
what works for you but that's not true
either you know a our map changes
um you know genes are one thing but the
way they're read is another depending on
your environment depending on
um the foods you eat the amount you
sleep your manifestation of of the code
is different
um so it's not so cut and dry I mean we
all wish there was a clear answer that
worked for everybody maybe because it
would be simple
but that's not realistic and and what
I've found treating patients
individually is that it's it's better
for them nobody wants to feel like they
don't have a voice in their own care
when people are empowered with care that
matches their needs their days and it
changes with life we're happier you know
we don't want to be in this sort of Silo
you know this pigeonhole of who I am and
who I should be and what I should feel
like you know people want flexibility
and freedom to be different one day from
the next
I'm going to move now on to your
entrepreneurial success that you've had
can you maybe give everybody an overview
what is the CED Clinic's mission
sure
um the seed Clinic is pronounced like uh
seed like the seed of a plant
um the seed mission is is a is a private
medical practice that specializes in
cannabis therapies and eocare that's
guiding patients with HIPAA compliant
digital health care services for
cannabinoid-based treatment so it's sort
of the the scaling of Medical Care a
doctor like me can see one patient at a
time and I can get to know them and care
about them and evolve with them as you
know their therapeutic Journey changes
but how do we scale someone like me when
medical school is not teaching cannabis
doctors are not really plugged in I
think we need a digital solution for
that that's what eocare is we're
reaching out to Broad audiences learning
about who they are what they need and
then giving them individualized care
through a digital platform
and the successful uh acquisition you
had of solar Sciences to maybe want to
give people a little bit of a story on
that so it was great to hear a success
story
sure yeah no I I'm privileged to have
that success I think solo was a company
trying to give transparency into the
system you know around 2019 we had this
Vapor crisis where people were consuming
cannabis and things
things were happening that we didn't
understand that were bad of course that
was a little bit confusing tobacco smoke
with cannabis smoke and it was also
confusing licensed regulated dispensary
products with crud that was made on the
streets by people that didn't know how
to make their products we've since
learned that street products are not
safe and dispensary products are
generally safe if they're regulated but
during that time it was important for
the public to have transparency and see
what was going on and that was what solo
was all about
and your work at Green acts Capital are
they one of the top firms when it comes
to investment in America
yeah um so green Access Capital is a
unique
fund that's raising money from
interested and knowledgeable investors
it's led by a team of really the
industry's experts in understanding how
cannabis can succeed from a business
perspective they look at new startup
companies ones that have started to
generate money but maybe not enough and
need to scale and green Access Capital
feeds that company enough money so that
they can grow and succeed and that
success is shared with the business
community of investors in the fund I
serve as an advisor just helping them
understand which companies have their
stuff together and which companies maybe
need more work or need a later look
and what are your thoughts currently
what's happening in New York do you see
the medical side of the industry just
getting pushed to the side there or is
it thriving or how your viewpoints on
that territory
um well I think New York is struggling
with the same struggles that everybody
else is is struggling with
um you know there's a shift in
perspective that leads to a rewriting of
our understanding of what cannabis is
you know some people think it's only for
medicine other people think it's only
for fooling around you know of course
anybody who consumes cannabis finds it
therapeutic you know whether it's an
adolescent feeling uncomfortable at a
party and just wants to feel relaxed or
a grown-up who's at the end of a day
wants to unwind and just de-stress these
are all therapeutic reasons
um the unfortunate thing is that people
can sell products for a low a low-cost
attract a recreational audience that
just wants the fool around and maybe
doesn't have enough money and all of a
sudden the medical industry gets washed
over part of that is because there
aren't medical leaders the medical
establishment has just completely lost
its way
um so of course they're not going to
fight for themselves
um but that's part of what I'm doing
with the doctor approved cannabis
handbook is arming the public with what
I've learned with the knowledge to
understand the value here how medical
cannabis can be applied to almost
everybody in almost every illness
whether it's treating the illness at its
at its at its sort of foundation or just
managing the symptoms of discomfort
um there's something in the cannabis
plant for everybody you just have to
learn about it
is it safe to say the best medical
cannabis companies have still not been
created yet or do you think that the
current crop of companies have copped on
to the plans and formulations of these
specific molecules are going to be able
to be an advantageous route for success
for a lot of companies that's a really
good question
um I think we haven't scratched the
surface yet most people out there
including clinicians think CBD and THC
is cannabis and those are two drops in a
gigantic bucket this plant produces
hundreds probably thousands of different
compounds Each of which has medicinal
value if we look in the published
literature you can pick off each of
those individual molecules and find
research on them you can understand that
oh my gosh Alpha pinene when I'm walking
in the forest and that that Pine smell
oh I feel like I can breathe better well
guess what from a pulmonologist's
perspective a lung doctor we see that
actually people can breathe a little bit
more easily when they're exposed to
Alpha pinene and that's one of as I said
a thousand different compounds here
there's so much in this natural Pharmacy
that we have yet to understand I think
traditional Pathways the pharmaceutical
industry is not going to be able to use
cannabis in the same way that they're
used to I think we're going to have to
develop new tools new understandings a
more natural view of how we can use
nature in medicine which I think is
really refreshing we have to sort of
turn a new Leaf here on how we care for
people
fermentation engineering seems to be one
of the key areas that could hopefully
Propel access these rare molecules and
allow for the the Blends whether that
seems to be come to fruition we shall
see yeah there's so so what you're
referring to are sort of different ways
to surface these active molecules one
way is to grow a plant and throw it to
chance organic plants grow wildly
another way you can do it is to
consolidate lots of plants and pick off
the parts you want another way actually
is to grow other vectors like yeast or
like some bacteria can actually produce
cannabinoids and these are all areas of
explanation exploration to see what
people want what people will buy and
what actually works so there's a whole
industry donning here that's
um really exciting
yeah very much so Last Thing Before I
Let You Go if there was one medical
cannabis conference in America that you
think somebody should attend what would
be your recommendation because as we
start to see with the conferences
there's more focus on the After parties
than there is on the content on the day
yeah no I'm I don't want to be a Debbie
Downer but I found conferences to
largely be commercial Ventures you know
there are a couple lectures that are
wonderful and it's nice to hear learning
there's often regulators and lawyers and
hopefully some doctors talking
um but the conferences themselves are
really an opportunity for vendors to
sell products
um so as a as a viewer as an attendee
you're kind of attending this commercial
Fest where people want your number want
to contact you and wants want you to
spend money
um that doesn't have much value to me I
tend to to speak at some
um but I quickly leave so I don't have
to deal with the crowds
um so I you know I think at the current
state of conferences I I usually tell
people to steer clear
yeah no it's a good bit of advice for
anybody who wants to learn more I highly
recommend checking out Benjamin's
website it's below and the link to buy
the book the doctor approved cannabis
handbook will be on YouTube Spotify
you'll have easy access to be able to
get a copy of the front for now Benjamin
thank you very much for your time it's
been very much appreciated my pleasure
everyone thanks for having me until next
episode everybody
[Music]