foreign
I'm doing well excited to be here and
excited to dive into the conversation
with you
hopefully we can get some information
across
so can we start real quick quickly how
you ended up co-founding eight
Revolution and your your endpoint to the
Cannabis industry please
sure so uh in my previous life I was
sales and marketing for an analytical
instrumentation company where my
responsibilities were to grow and
develop marketing channels as well as
business development relation channels
into new markets we were experiencing
oil and gas pharmaceutical food and Bev
and one of the new tasks was entered a
new market where I was asked to explore
the Cannabis market so in 2018 I set off
to MJ bizcon where my eyes were wide
open and I was ecstatic with the speed
and the opportunity of the industry and
uh fell in love with what was happening
and decided to link up with one of the
people I met at that joke Kellen Finney
who was actually speaking at the
conference and from there we decided
that we wanted to see the industry a
certain way which is an analytical focus
and we wanted to bring real-time quality
control sensors to the Cannabis industry
and decided to form eighth Revolution
okay incredible so a web information
coming from and from sector that applies
a lot of cannabis industry but can you
maybe tell everybody a little bit to Die
My podcast you guys have you've gone
great guesses I find that these are
great data Gathering tools do you
viewers yourself
yeah I appreciate that so the dime is
our is our weekly podcast where we
explore all things cannabis and I think
the dime has been the greatest unlocker
from a networking standpoint the ability
to connect with individuals and and
spend time with them and then ask them
the why behind they make certain
decisions I think a lot of times
especially in nowadays we rush to make
judgments when we see headlines but we
don't really understand the macro on the
why that these Executives make certain
decisions and that's really the primary
focus on the dime is to really
understand the true why these Executives
or these leading researchers are making
specific strategic decisions on how they
go about their day-to-day I do
okay very interesting so I want to start
off basically as new what are two things
about four different quick topics so
it's got things that you specialize in
so first is like license acquisition for
anybody looking to open up their own
business what's what's more important
for license like acquisition consulting
company like yourself or legal expertise
which Step comes first for the entire
with the church around the license
I think they work hand in hand I think
relationships are really Paramount in
this space and making sure that you get
off on the right foot is really critical
so we work very closely with a lot of
law firms where we specialize in this
area to ensure that we work hand in hand
with the clients to make sure that
everyone's operating at the same speed
so unfortunately the the de facto answer
is both
thank you very much next one is facility
design is there a specific architecture
companies uh that work now specifically
solely cannabis or do or do you really
find companies that good fine dining in
Real uh buildings and complexes are the
wearables that are for the Cannabis of
the same at the moment
uh I couldn't really hear the end of
that but I can make some assumptions on
the true direction of the facility
design and what we found is that certain
layouts and procedures help with the
optimization of the flow of the process
and just putting those necessary steps
in line allows for the operator to not
have to go backwards and to take let's
say reverse steps that are more costly
and expensive which could set back a
facility you know a large amount of
money if they're looking to take certain
steps let's say like cgmp or to do other
uh profit maximization in the future
very very good thank you very much so so
put your if you can't hear me just just
let go so this question is on equipped
selection now is this something if you
were single company only has another
Mantra would you specifically hire some
expertise is in the field working with a
kind of benefit or is it just any uh
let's say engineer or a highly
intelligent individual could move over
or understand pretty quickly what the
equipment is
I I I'm sorry I couldn't make that one
out
so let me just start this again so
equipment selection
is in in expertise required in choosing
using a quint or is it some entrepreneur
could learn to read
um that's a great question I think an
entrepreneur can can figure it out
through their own I think one of the
things that special needs for us is that
my partner kill Infinity's got extensive
background in the various different
attraction space so he's understanding
the variables on what is the end product
and then likes to work badly through
exactly what the the client is looking
to create so I think it is possible that
an entrepreneur can get their hands
dirty and do it themselves but again
selecting equipment is necessary earlier
on and and making a step like cgmp might
be overlooked or if if let's say the end
goal is differently from what we're
expecting to produce you want to make
sure that the the beginning steps align
with that end goal
brilliant and and the last one in this
topic optimization process it's one of
those big hurdles a lottery called
company come across like again is this
something that in-house Houston can be a
tank or is it always was going outside
and equities is the better and Superior
option in that process
I mean that's a great question and
really depends on the operator I think
the most important thing that we found
is that data is King and understanding
which variables are controlling that
optimization parameters and allowing
insights into real time in order to
maximize your profit is really the
driven goal so if you're not really
understanding which variables are
influencing your output it's really
going to be hard in order to lock down
that optimization what we've seen is a
big margin compression everyone's
talking about a race to the bottom and
instead of figuring out hey let's raise
our prices and push it back in the
consumer another way to approach that is
to look inwards and to figure out what
are cogs and where can we make
influences to really drive down our
internal calls so that we can maximize
our profit and therefore optimization of
that process
section I wanted to move on today is the
most interesting sect of cannabis now as
we know uh technically advancing rapidly
every year where do you see is going to
be the most directing interesting sector
of cannabis since now today and and in
five years time
wow at five years time is really hard to
tell especially with the industry and
the way it's operating now I think it's
going to be technology again I think
people are going to dig an inwards Focus
they're going to adopt outside industry
technology process analytical technology
is one that obviously with my background
I'm pretty confident it's going to move
to the space it's in pharmaceutical it's
in oil and gas it's in food and beverage
it's exactly the type of equipment that
will help consistency and product line
across state by state so that when you
do grab a product in New York it's very
similar or not close or exactly the same
as the one in California
very good do you succeed biotech
technology overtaking a large show of
the Cabbage industry district one of
these bio company biotechnology
companies have gotten their cell lines
and they're in their large quantities
that they can manufacture to specific uh
price point and an exact yield like like
the pens adults
creams tinctures oils potentially come
from the biotechnology sort of bigger
harvests more free frequent harvest the
price points Point going to be lower do
you see that and then at that scenario
any updates or do you think you think
new methods of extraction are going to
be able to keep with the biotechnology
sector
it's uh it remains to be seen I I
wouldn't feel confident speaking on that
that is outside of my expertise that
would really lead into my partner Kellen
Finney or who could expand on those but
I don't know it sounds like it's
possible but again in this space though
speed and everything is moving it's
really challenging to recognize you know
what is possible what is really going to
happen in the short and near term
yeah very much agreed what is the most
exciting thing over like 12 once you
look for seeing in in your territory
I'm excited to see how New York rolls
out their cannabis Market uh it's a big
ask what they're doing and it's a big
Challenge and a lot of the msos have
shown some frustration and we we're
interested to seeing if it's possible to
what they are able to achieve I know
some people have casted their doubts and
I think one of the things that
fascinates me most is that we're going
to get a live case study on exactly what
is possible and what is not when opening
up a massive market and limiting certain
the entrants coming in and how they plan
on rolling out that market in the next
eight to 12 months
[Music]
mergers and Acquisitions being a big
part over the decal of 18 months or it
would only be when Fair legalization
happens they will start to see am an
activity
I I think over the next eight to 12
months you might see some merges and
Acquisitions but more of the distressed
assets I expect to see some of the the
smaller operators maybe maybe pass
through and get acquired for sure to
cheat multiples I expect that to be the
case but again with the capital markets
operating the way they are I think
people will be a little more hesitant to
deploy and my understanding is that a
lot of these larger companies will look
inwards from an optimization standpoint
in order to hone in on their internal
efforts so that when the markets do move
in the other direction they're ready to
scale faster again but they've really
honed in on the internal infrastructure
but it wouldn't surprise me if we saw
outside in Industry Titans continue to
try to migrate in obviously the word on
the street right now is Big tobacco and
everyone's kind of yes or no depending
on how your strategy is and if it's good
or if it's bad it remains to be seen on
how that works but some may think it's
pretty disruptive Others May think it's
a it's a pretty opening invitation from
the joint
pretty interesting and do you think the
current selection of MMO in America are
to be the dominant versus in a few years
time or has the most successful cannabis
company in Erica still yeah
oh that one's a good one
um
give me a second to think about that
ah it depends right it depends if the US
gets locked into the U.S market because
from our understanding right now if we
haven't federally legalized it we will
not be involved in global conversations
at a World level so if we are not
partaking in those conversations the U.S
companies might be locked in and might
have to take creative approaches to
outside Partnerships we've seen Cheryl
Leaf do it we've seen a couple others
expand overseas but right now they're
pretty much like independent entities
which don't allow companies to operate
with the economies of scale that really
what the everyday investors used to
seeing from a numbers standpoint as
you've seen with these larger companies
outside of cannabis
yeah we we've seen some of the the mssos
take an interest in your Europe ready
truly leaves the acquisition of 420
Pharma being one of the latest do you
think that that uh an American aiding
companies are looking at Europe with
blinker and thinking that took it is
there for the taking or do you believe
there's going to be European cannabis
companies not only to thrive but moved
to America to take it to that market too
so for the companies that we've spoken
with directly on those questions they
think there's a ton of meat in the bone
still here in America with with major
markets still not opening up and limit
it's the capital capital they're looking
internally right now on on States like
Florida and Texas Alabama North Carolina
potentially Pennsylvania and Maryland in
the next two years so I think they're
looking internally right now with an eye
on the future but they're pretty
confident that there is a lot of meat on
the bone internally and then I think
they look for a global landscape but I I
think right now the focus is going to be
currently on internally expanding uh
locally and domestically with the focus
on let's say internationally over the
next two to five years
course interesting if you had a hundred
dollars to put on IMs I was stuck would
you be thrown in your money
oh I'm gonna make a couple people pretty
angry at that one
um there's no really good choices
um which is my favorite uh I really like
true leave
um GTI I'm a big fan of Ben Ben as well
um it's hard to tell it's still so early
in the market but there's there's
certain things that certain operators do
that I like more than others and there's
more strategic efforts that I like that
others do as well so for example
tarasen's got a very uh limited
footprint but it's very very strategic
in the markets they're attacking so
maybe over the next two to five years
there they start to rise in in growth
and start competing with the bigger one
truly if it's right now dominating
Florida but Florida is is a smaller
Market of its own in comparison to like
a global landslave so when Florida turns
true leaves numbers can be massive but
as if they open up that market then
truly's numbers might disappear so it's
hard to feel to really feel super
confident on anyone I think the craziest
part about the Cannabis industry as a
whole is that the way the Cannabis
industry operates now everyone has their
cards and think about from a card game
standpoint eventually Federal
legalization interstate commerce will
come about and everyone will have to
re-deal their cards in and then
redistribute their assets because these
vertical integration assets that are
happening now don't allow for economies
of scale and don't allow for a sharing
of knowledgeable confidence right we're
not really driving home price because
we're not able to have one massive Hub
of cultivation somewhere and then
dispersing the product elsewhere you've
got different states uh growing products
across the region which just makes more
challenges for people right you don't
have one master girl overseeing the
entire operation you've got multiple
Master Growers which leads to more
challenges and more expenses and and
more likely more hurdles and less
profits
yeah and it seems to be what 100 with
Canada we're around to this smaller
cultivars and the small backup operator
that wasn't taking a huge huge to the
shoe at the moment in the larger Korean
episodes are the ones struggling who
have fantasized about the size why is it
heals and the difficulties they've been
sold off or reflection we're doing the
at the starting four electric ago on
cannabis tourism who do you think is the
best cannabis kind of a tourism company
in the in most of America
that's a great question but I haven't
participated on any of those cannabis
tourism so I can't speak confidently on
them but I would Envision that the one
that involves education and experience
will be the one that can win and I'm
looking forward to experiencing the the
multiple different uh ones we've
interviewed and the different people we
spoke about that are excited to bring
cannabis tourism to A Whole New Life
yeah yeah so one thing I see in New York
in such a big Market because uh people
take people are restorating how much
Europe are going to go to to see none of
this is legal and the amount of Revenue
that that's going to generate we've
actually had a great chat flying over at
the time all day this is a very
informative profession for everybody
wants to know everyone's company eight
we're traveling the link is
highly recommend checking them out and
the podcast the dime Brian thank you
very very much for the time today it's
very much appreciated
yeah I appreciate you taking the time
looking forward to doing this again
we will certainly catch kill pretty soon
over the next six six to 12 months I
will have an update on both of the trees
but for now thank you very much until
next episode everybody