foreign
to the Cannabis review we've got a
brilliant end of year special for
everybody now today we're going to go
over the top five moments of global
cannabis of 2022 and to do that I'm
delighted to be joined by three of the
leading voices in uh drug policy and
cannabis policy movement in Ireland
starting open your top right corner is
Natalie o'riegen how are you keeping
Natalie oh good enjoying the Christmas
break so far delighted to hear this next
blow that is Ryan McHale from cran are
you keeping Ryan
very good thanks I'll thanks for having
us today
I'm ready you guys have been very busy
this year in Ireland and last but not
least is bread and minutes from Crown as
well how are you keeping Brendan oh good
yeah it's been a good good year so far
very productive A lot's happened and we
were good to talk about which is great
we do indeed yeah lots to talk about now
so the best thing to do is just get
started off and we're going to start off
with our first topic so we've chosen
five of the most influential moments we
think about Irish and international
cannabis and the first one we're going
to start off with is the Justice joint
Justice committee report that came out
in Ireland recently and I'm going to go
around the room and give everybody a
chance to talk but Natalie I'm going to
start with you can you give everybody a
quick couple of minutes brief of how you
saw this report and the influences it
may have
yep so the report and it's been going
ongoing for about six eight months and
myself Crane and many others were asked
to contribute to it at the time
um and the report was released just
before the Christmas break and when it
was released that morning I don't think
anybody in the drug policy field or the
reform field or any activists seen I
could have predicted what was coming out
of this report so it was a lovely
welcome surprise to see for once in
Ireland a government report that is
Progressive that is sensible that is not
just filled with prohibitionist Reefer
Madness narrative that we usually tend
to see other government documents so
there was 22 recommendations all
together it wasn't specifically about
cannabis and it was regarding drone
policy at home at a whole so I did
include some things regarding like a
safe consumption facilities and
addiction treatment and a whole a lot of
other things but the couple of things
that really stood out for me were the
fact that the Justice committee
recommended a lot more research into
not-for-profit Social Clubs so social
clubs are not new to the caliber scene
and they're operating in many countries
across Europe as it is and they have
worked well as a not not for profit uh
way of providing cannabis to people
so for a Justice committee to say that
Social Clubs need more uh research and
how would Social Clubs work in Ireland
it was a very very Advanced
recommendation for Ireland because
sometimes I do think along with many
others that Ireland can be a bit
old-fashioned when it comes to drugs
policy and I think they just don't know
what the future holds so they may be a
bit nervous so it was nice to see that
they are acknowledging Social Clubs and
the fact that these not-for-profit
Community collectors can work and have
worked in other countries and as well on
top of that which was highly surprising
was they recommended regulation of
certain drugs they didn't specifically
name certain drugs but you know the
power deducement you can kind of guess
they're probably talking about cannabis
in that regard so
for again for a government report to
come out and recommend regulation and
recommend it in a way that we've been we
know for years and we have been asking
for years like it is ham reduction it is
about taking the taking drug policy and
controlling it because drug policy are
drugs at the moment in illegal Market is
uncontrolled and that is the most
damaging aspect of them so for a report
to come out and to say that
criminalization hasn't worked
prohibition has not worked and that we
need to do something about it
is highly highly welcome and I think
Craig and Brendan and everybody else in
drug policy and Ireland will probably
think the exact probably have thought
the exact same thing when we were
reading the report that day so pass over
to Ryan I suppose
perfect thank you very much Natalie Ryan
can you give us your little overview and
talk a little bit about what kind of
came from that such as your meeting that
you guys had referring Fame and the
future workers are going to be doing
yeah so the report itself
um
it was kind of seen as great success
from everybody and I think it was
um because I think it covered kind of
all areas of drug policy and the
consultation process that the justice
department had were groups they had
cannabis groups they had a Frontline
groups and he had new workers against
prohibition under 22 recommendations
there that were extremely welcome by
other groups when we were there for the
launch of the report and all the
different advocacy groups so they're
they're all delighted and because there
was something there for everybody's
consultation is very well done but in
terms of cannabis stories about tree
recommendations that really stood out
and one of them was expanding the
medical cannabis Access program which is
is definitely needed and it's good that
that's represented there and was not
really sad and the Social Clubs and the
the allowance of of currently illicited
substances to be ground
for non-profit and then the regulatory
system the one of these aren't aren't
law yet
and it's not been unlocked but it will
be interesting to see how the department
responds and that might be something
we'll see you know when the um when the
dial comes back in a couple of weeks
time and in terms of The Minister's
response and I think when we met with
the minister this report wasn't
published yet so we didn't actually know
the recommendations but we are looking
to uh to engage forward and with the
Department of Health and they'll discuss
these recommendations that are actually
out there now and so I think it's it's a
good four-step I think and it's
extremely Progressive it's extremely
void region and if these recommendations
can make it into large and I think we
will be seeing a broad future in terms
of our true policy Clover yeah going
forward
incredible incredible so Brandon you'd
be not this I think longer than most in
Ireland what was uh what was the
feelings that you got you had from the
report that was published
um I was completely blindsided I
expected it to be the same as we'd
normally see for these reports where
often the body of the document is
actually pretty strong and they've
encompassed carefully the views of all
of the respondents but then um given
them all equal weight and in this one it
didn't it actually came out it made
strong clear recommendations for which
I'm very thankful and what's more and I
went up to the launch of it was James
Lawless who had chaired the thing was
very passionate about it he put the work
into this he'd done his diligent work
and here he was representing it so I
think that was all very very encouraging
this isn't a report that's just going to
sit on a shelf and from our perspective
those of us who wish to see change it
now takes us to a place where you know
2023 is in part going to be about
writing to our TDS to ask them what are
they doing to implement the
recommendations of the report and that's
a huge shift in terms of where we are in
lobbying
um I think the social club elements
really important and I think another
interesting thing that kind of happened
on the day actually that there was some
political except acceptance that you
can't make black markets go away
magically and you have to look at you
know reducing the harms and uh you know
that seems to have been encompassed in
this
um don't let the perfect be the enemy of
the good
and I suppose
um yeah I mean really that's the gist of
it the main thing I think about this
report as well is that it's looked at
the wider harms of drugs and it wasn't
open to us to look at just cannabis on
its own nor should we I think if we
address the social harms across the
Spectrum here we'll end up with much
more sensible policy across a right a
wide range of substances
yeah very well said very well said so
Point number one was the joint Justice
committee Report top story number two
definitely for if you were living in
Ireland was Geno Kenny's bill that he
brought to the doyle so Ryan I know you
guys you were doing a lot of work with
this and then Natalie I'm going to give
you an opportunity to speak out but Ryan
can you maybe tell us the importance of
Gino's Bill the chances of the passing
and any little pertinent information
that you'd have for the audience
yeah um so genius bill is kind of a long
time common
um I'm sure we're in the canvas space
you've been waiting for for I think
about two years and finally came in
quite a simple build that would
decriminal lawyers cannabis possession
of up to seven grams of variable
cannabis that was quite moderate it's
not I don't think it's it's the it's the
system that many of us want in the long
term and I think Jane I was aware of
that he he realizes that and this isn't
the end I'll be out I think in terms of
passing I'm not sure I'm not sure if
we'll pass and it's going to open the
air at the moment I think with the way
things are gone with with this Joseph's
report and kind of the citizens assembly
they might be looking for a more robust
system than just decriminalization so
they might actually take it another way
and but it is important
um in the sense that it's part of this
conversation that's starting to build
and Gino's Bill was introduced and
a little while back the week after labor
party introduced the motion on
decriminalization and this report came
out then a couple of weeks after so it's
all kind of building into the into the
um the national discussion I don't think
one report or one bill or one event is
going to change things I think it's it's
a it's a collective process of all these
different
um these different things happening at
the same time so I think it's positive
and what's going to come of it I don't
know if it's going to pass it might be
amended heavily and include more kind of
uh safeguards for regulation and things
like that but um it's definitely a
powerful step forward and it increases
the discussion on the kind of the
quality of the discussion in the country
yeah for sure it's part of the snowball
that seems to be gaining momentum
Natalie you were working on this
equipment if you've got a little brief
little overview of any inside
information for us yeah so Gino's been
working on to try and get something on
the floor of the doyle for over two
years I think
um and In fairness for me put a lot of
work in he got a lot of doors closed in
his face he got a a lot of feedback back
there he had to change plans about a
million times but he eventually got
their true determination and
stubbornness and putting the work in
there and what's the chances of it
passing is anybody's guess it is a
private member's bill so it is an
opposition bill so it would require the
current government to side on with the
opposition on this point which Tech
usually doesn't happen but Sherlock
Never Say Never
um but even if it doesn't pass
that's not the end of it like this the
the bill is on the doyle floor it is
going to have to be debated on the
dollar store for that to be debated
we'll also get to hear politicians and
elected TDS what their view is on this
topic they will have to stand up they
will have to vote Yes or No Yes or No
against this at one point so if nothing
comes out of it if nothing else comes
out of it we will
Force the conversation on the issue we
will get people's opinions and we'll get
our politicians opinions and I think as
well as Ryan said Geno's
decriminalization Bill uh labor put in a
motion the following week for a
decriminalization of all drugs and then
the citizens assembly is coming off this
Justice Port committee report
it's not an issue that can be run away
from anymore it can't it's not an issue
that can be just put on the back burner
and hope for and hope and pray that the
politicians will not have to tackle it
within their sitting term that they can
pass the book to the next
so I think it brings the conversation to
the floor and it forces people to have a
conversation about it if nothing else so
I do think it's an overall good thing if
it passes all the better if not we we
still have a million more avenues that
we can go through yeah as we said it's
all part of this snowball that's getting
your momentum so moving outside of
Ireland
our first two topics the first two
stories were a joint Justice committee
report Gino Kenny's bill that was
proposed there and so we all agreed when
it came to the European story that there
was only kind of one or two territories
that you choose from one was Germany and
and the Czech Republic so I think we're
going to lead into the Czech Republic
first how quickly do you think Prague
are going to be able to get this
industry open road and do you think
they're going to be able to get it done
quicker than Germany start with you
Brandon
yeah I think the Czechs have been
waiting for to do this for a long time
and I think they'll hit the ground
running
um I think they are more flexible in
terms of how they deal with and think
about bureaucracy and um yeah I'd say
they'll be able to speed for a while
because the Czech Republic's been
wanting this for quite a while
um and I think it's going to feed also
into into the wider thing both at the
European level at the national level a
lot of politicians have a lot of
catching up to do now with where a
popular opinion is both in terms of
whether drug policy in the round is
working and what people want to see out
of you know legal regulated markets
yeah couldn't agree with you more
Natalie what are you thinking is going
to happen with Prague do you think
you're going to get there before Germany
I tend to agree with Brendan I think you
will be all very surprised and Germany
may be the last ones to regulate but I
do think that they will get there before
Germany I mean their National Drug
coordinator is well clued in he he's up
to speed he knows what he's talking
about from the outside from my opinion
like he knows prohibition hasn't worked
he knows control of cannabis is the
future and is the better approach to it
like thereafter getting together a group
of representatives from all areas of
society from police Customs drug experts
the members of
um their Parliament so they are getting
all views they're not just listening to
one side they're getting the whole
package they're getting the whole views
and I do hope after this consolidation I
think they said around March I think
that they're they're a plan for a
regulated market would be finalized so
it'll be interesting to see what comes
out of this but I am hopeful well I do
think that they they have a good grasp
of what needs to be done and I think
they will power ahead with it
yeah it could be very interesting to see
Ryan do you see them being the European
leader to get going first or do you see
uh any hurdles that may potentially
happen for them I think it'd be very
interesting to watch and I think Arlo
Israel March from this for this
consultation process to kind of be um to
be revealed what's going on there
um I think in terms of roadblocks and
stuff like that I've seen there in the
nails recently Germany are kind of
getting a little bit caught up with
themselves with international law and
things like that and that seems to be a
kind of recording issue in in kind of
global through a policy reform that we
always find ourselves getting kind of
our hands toyed with international law
and I think the approach that the
Canadians and the Americans talk is
probably the best approach for us
Europeans to take and just to ignore and
move on from it it's kind of it's
notoriously difficult to try and change
those International agreements on drugs
or any International agreement just just
with the geopolitical nature of things
like that so we'll be one to watch and I
think we're definitely going to see more
of this stuff we're kind of EU or un law
coming up in was but I don't think it's
going to stop it fundamentally I think
it's just going to be a little
roadblocks along the way but it will be
good to watch the more countries that
they were the the clouds over here you
know yeah very true I think it's a
perfect scenario of it's better to ask
for forgiveness than ask for permission
when it comes to creating your own
policy of your own country when it comes
to the Cannabis industry as we've seen
with Canada and America right we're
going to move on to topic four so Story
number three was Germany's Advance with
the Czech Republic is advancements the
next one we're going to go on an
international look and Thailand has been
a very interesting story over the last
year and could be potentially over the
next couple of years with potential for
cannabis tourism that far outweighs a
lot of other territories around the
world Brendan can you talk to us about
Thailand and what's been going on over
the past 12 months well not entirely up
to speed fully with Thailand but it
seems like they sort of they've created
a bit of a vacuum in a way by repealing
some laws and leaving it there but I
think some of the pressure International
pressure is going to come from where
their tourist Falls from
um I don't see the Australians as being
too but but when the Chinese start
returning to Thailand in numbers there
might be some pushback there around
around drugs policy I I don't know I
suppose really what I'm interested to
see is how do markets develop when there
are relatively few rules and what
happens when you try and regulate a
market once it's started I think other
markets that are interested that have
come like interesting that have come
online recently is countries like
Argentina for example we don't hear much
about it but Argentina has gone both
recreationally and medically legal and
it's dismantling its Black Market I'm
not too clear on how it's dealt with its
International obligations around that
but um you know the some countries are
just ignoring the international
obligation at this stage
um I think for the US it probably hasn't
come up yet because legalization hasn't
really happened at the federal level
it's been more a case of state by state
yeah very very true there's been a lot
of interesting advances Mexico is up
there another one with Argentine
Argentina I think that where they seem
to be there well Mexico seems a bit
stuck at the moment actually
yeah
very high Court decisions that they have
to legislate but they haven't legislated
yeah yeah I think they're the closest
and the most influenced by America and I
think the the politics is having a lot
to play there whereas I think countries
that seem to be a little bit more
distanced away in South America seem to
be pushed down or pushing on without a
undue influence
yeah so sometimes it's easier to just
remove loss than it is to design new
ones but it doesn't necessarily mean the
outcomes are substantially better
yeah no I couldn't agree with you more
but if we had the greatest and smartest
people as politicians running countries
all over the world would have been their
own age for this conversation to be
taken place at this moment in time but
we've got to do our best as our citizens
to ensure that we're getting given and
delivered the best potential Solutions
and and products for uh people in each
individual countries so we've got four
we've got four uh topics that we've
touched after joint Justice committee
report Gino's Bill Germany and checks
advancement and then International
communities like Thailand Argentina
Mexico so I wanted to pick the last one
and I thought it was I've gone through a
ton of different things like you could
talk about juicy Fields Spain launching
their medical program the the check
announcement the acquisition PDD and
Columbia care but I think the big one
from America was Biden signing the
medical marijuana research bill and I
think it's going to have huge
implications in terms of dementia Moody
that gets pumped in for r d and the
amount of potential that I'd say the
rarer cannabinoids that now get
available for marketing for products so
what do you guys think of deployed
inside of the medical marijuana research
bill as one of the most important
stories Ryan I'll start with you
I think boyden's been doing a lot now on
this on this cannabis front uh This
research bill is going to open the door
now for America to be ahead of the game
in terms of cannabis research and what's
being what's going to be done there and
I know the safe the safe Banking Act
didn't go through which is something
that American people have been quite
upset about in the industry and in the
in the Cannabis space
but um in terms of research and things
like that I think America are going to
be ahead of the game they're going to be
the first ones to do it and they're
really invested in the medical Market
it's where it all kind of began for the
Americans anyways so they're building on
that there I would like to see more
stuff done on the expungement of ProAir
criminal records with with cannabis
right now it's not it's not being done
federally I know it's kind of been done
a little bit uh step by stay but I'd
love to see more doing on that kind of
going back to toilet and by now when
they decriminalized I think they
released four thousand prisoners in one
day so it'd be great to see more kind of
initiative taken on that globally
especially in the United States kind of
the notorious uh War on Drugs going on
over there but it seems to be coming to
an end thankfully yeah it's very true
have you actually friend what do you
think of the last topic Brighton signed
in the bill I think it's all progress I
think until the safe banking acts passed
the impact of U.S federal law on
cannabis is global because it screws up
with everybody's ability to use Banks
worldwide I mean it's been a huge
problem for Uruguayan is is a is a
problem still for legal cannabis
companies all over the world
um and I think there's a bit of a land
grab on at the moment from the farmer
side to see what's patentable what's
what are paint nipple products that can
be developed out of this I think um the
piece that the US is doing really badly
on and we need to keep an eye on is
drugs policy overall in terms of overall
death rates they're way way worse than
even us in Ireland is joint worst in
Europe now so you know what's happened
in the US is something that I'd be
afraid of happening here where they've
separated cannabis policy out completely
from the rest of drugs policy and
allowed the rest of drugs policy which
is the less popular bits of it sometimes
just sort of drown on the floor it's
shocking so you know this is why I think
reform needs to stay locked step it's
not about individual substances it's
about the the overall overarching the
umbrella of things that come under
substance control actually
and you know we're talking about legal
cannabis markets here but I think in
time we'll be talking about legal
markets for other products too although
perhaps much more regulated than any of
us would like to see for cannabis
yeah very well said Natalie I'll give
you the final word what do you think of
Joe Biden's recent work in the kind of a
sector
well I'm glad to see their r d bill and
the research and development the
scientific the scientific research being
able to go into cannabis
like one roadblock we always face when
you are arguing for a reform of our
cannabis laws in Ireland even or across
Europe is and I'm sure Ryan has heard it
himself from Brendan is oh we need more
research we need more research we need
more research if I hear that I hear it
in my sleep at this stage
and with this bill we will have more
research like we
I don't know the exact number anymore
because I think there's one new one
being found every week but we don't know
half of the cannabinoids that are in the
cannabis plant we do not know
the full extent of how beneficial this
plant can be from for as a valid
medicine for people so there are people
out there for years who will say oh I
get relief of this and I get relief of
that but there is no scientific research
into it so that is a block for expansion
of the mcap expansion of other medical
aspects of cannabis so for the research
and development to be able to go into
cannabis as a valid medicine it's a good
thing regardless of whether what side of
the what side of the fence you're on
regarding pharmaceutical companies
interests and in it either way it is
going to be a good thing I think and you
know it is going to feed into
worldwide cannabis reform and especially
for medicinal cannabis and its medicinal
properties for people
yeah evidence-based medicine I think is
what every politician wants to be able
to hang their hat on and they can't do
that unless you've got r d budgets and
allocation of resources to be able to go
and look at the potential of the
hundreds of Canada's uh terpenes and
flavonoids that can all be Blended
together for potential whatever it may
be the r d needs to start in the labs
with that but it's been a it's been
great running through the year guys does
anybody else else have any other topics
outside the top five that we touched on
that uh you think is worth a mention
I think this year I mean not just in
Ireland but everywhere really this year
is the year when we all need to tell our
politicians what we expect them to do
they might not agree with us we that
sometimes they won't reply but we
absolutely need to remind them that
we're here we're voting and we care
about these issues
yeah and to that aim you know Crown we
hope to have some templates out for
people to do to to follow in the New
Year and I hope other organizations will
be doing the same because there are a
lot of nuanced positions in this reform
fight but we're all looking at the kind
of the same broad brush Strokes end
goals which are you know safer societies
and happier people
yeah agreed The Economist industry is so
complex and nuanced that uh it takes
years and years of research to be able
to get yourself remotely up to speed and
yeah well I think that's a very relevant
thing I was reading somewhere recently
that when alcohol prohibition ended in
the state so it took about 10 years for
even 50 of the supply to move back from
the black market to the legal Market
we're in a period of transition we can't
expect everything to be perfect and Rosy
along the way we're going to learn a lot
some fun will be had lots of fun will be
hard money will be made some harms will
be done too and we need to be open to
that we need to work out how to remain
you know human and compassionate and
honest and fair in this industry going
forward but you know it's all positive I
think you know 2023 and Beyond are going
to be good years in game cannabis yeah I
couldn't agree with you more and what's
great is we're starting to see a real
ecosystem in Ireland take place and
everybody's sharing and helping each
other in a long way that continue
because I think we're a more powerful
force when we're all combining our
resources that everybody working
individually
yep definitely
right we'll call it an end on that it's
been a great 2022 guys and thank you
very much for your time let's hope that
2023 kicks off with a bang I know the
Cannabis reviewers got big plans for
next year for expansion on it we look
forward to seeing uh what the New Year
brands
for everybody we're going to be busy
regardless it sure is for anybody who
wants to check out more about crime's
work and all the great stuff that
they're getting on their website is
below and everybody knows if you know
the Cannabis review website you can
check up all the stories and up to date
and we look forward to a 2023 guys for
now happy New Year and thank you very
much for your time
thank you bye-bye
[Music]