[Music]
welcome to the next episode of the
Cannabis review I'm delighted join to
this episode by Greg Gasper who's the C
us weed Channel how you keeping today
Greg hi thank you for having me
delighted to have you on do you maybe
want to give everybody a quick little
overview of your position at us weed
Channel and how you came into the
industry yes so um Chief Revenue officer
currently at the US Wii channel um we
are obviously a cannabis TV station but
really built to be a global cannabis
media
platform um you know been in the
business most of my life or you know the
plant has been a part of my life um
since my teens um but formally and
professionally started in the recck
market in about 2015 in Washington state
launched one of the Premier CBD brands
that got into Dillards and selfridges as
you would know in the UK and Lane
Crawford in Hong Kong that brand was
Wildflower Brands and that position
promoted me and moved me to Los Angeles
where I ran a series of regulated
licenses there and really built I feel
like that was the um you know the
foundation of my career was that move to
Los Angeles there and my connections to
that Community where the major project
that I was leading was we were one of
the leading ease delivery Depot in Los
Angeles so that was an amazing
experience getting to work with you know
one of the Premier Tech plat Platforms
in cannabis at that time and uh that was
that was great and it was a colorful
experience and uh long story short um
the the Wildflower company purchased
those licenses um they were never signed
over so um that kind of left myself in a
strange position um in the the company
and um decided to move to Phoenix and
that's where I cut my teeth here in this
market where I'm currently at in Phoenix
Arizona getting to work um to help
launch some of the Premier Brands here
the top Vape brand in the state amused
and launching their CBD CBG Wellness
brand here and eventually working with
Shango as sales director which is a top
flower brand here and yeah so long story
long my journey was through more or less
you know touching and selling almost
every ancillary part of the business um
from finished goods to Hardware to Tech
and that's kind of what brought me here
um to the TV channel where I met Shane
um late last year and once I heard what
he had I was kind of like what how do I
join so that's what brings me here now
and thank you ow for having me my
pleasure um there seems to be a mass big
gap for a platform for cannabis media
and it seems to be a h that you guys
look Prime to be able to fill do you
want to maybe give me elaborate a little
bit on what do you think the platform
for cannabis media looks like and is it
going to involve a wave of m&amp;a activity
of the best offerings to the market and
bring them all under what umbrella like
current media would
do right so you know generally speaking
I think you know whether you're a brand
or a leading Creator or voice in the
industry
um we are at the will of the big pet
Giants the YouTubes particularly as the
host you know for you know storing that
content and distributing it mostly for
creators um from Instagram and Linkedin
particularly um you know my experience
in the wreck Market pretty jaded with
Instagram having you know dozens of
accounts shut down and banned and you
know um some pettiness of uh reporting
each other and all of those things that
happen when you're at the will of one of
these Tech Giants so again um a lot of
these creators are able to monetize the
content that that they create and
companies whether you are a direct
cannabis brand or an ancillary product
you're not able to Market your product
to reach the end consumer um especially
through paid ads you have to be very
creative and it's a fine line of what
you post versus getting thrown in jail
and all of those things on social media
so that is kind of the basis of what we
want to build here we want to be a
platform for the voice of the global
cannabis Community whether that is a
consumer you know someone interested in
learning more on the educational side of
it or a company looking to reach the
global cannabis
audience it also seems to me that
there's a massive gap for the content
creation side of this industry for such
there's so many potentials stories that
could be turned out of from this sector
like they've done with some of the we
work shows or kind of these kind of
elements there's tailes having a a a
publisher that's able to actually go out
and purchase these H shows or movies and
then sell them on to bigger
opportunities seems like a very good
advantage point absolutely so um you
know advertising partners that come to
join the channel um you know 100% of
that money stays within in the Canabis
Community one
because 70% or so of those funds will be
going towards the production of a new
show which is an asset that we will
share together as you know the ad brand
that helped produce it as now that show
is brought to you by that brand of
perpetuity and that is now again an
asset of ours so if that show blows up
we can put that on Amazon Prime
streaming or Hulu or Netflix and things
like that so so you know it's not
limited to our Network we're able to
take it to the masses we're also able to
lease content for major Production
Studios to play on our channel so um
Sony and Paramount in particular we can
pick from those rolodexes lease that
content and have it brought to you by
your favorite brand so think of your
favorite you know Cannabis movie I like
to use the example Harold and Kumar
brought or Harold and Kumar Go to White
Castle could be brought to you by White
Castle or brought to you by your
favorite brand so um the possibilities
really are endless and I think that's I
feel like part of the challenge um here
in the United States in particular is
you know I don't think people really
believe it that we're able
to yeah it as I said of all the sectors
if you analyze from the Cannabis
industry from biotechnology to
cultivation retail the media side of it
seems to be one of the biggest markets
that you could potentially get into with
the fewest competitors in it but it
seems like whoever gets in and becomes
the dominant leader now has to build the
whole foundations and the building
itself whereas cultivation could take
expertise from another industry and
bring it in I think making cannabis
media would have to involve I would
imagine a blend of either consumers or
industry expertise to be able to ensure
that the the content is as factual and
and correct as possible correct and you
nailed it because I I often get asked a
question to the effect of well who are
you trying to reach are you trying to
reach companies or are you trying to
reach consumers um you say you're a
global Channel but you're us um but the
fact is we are all that we have to reach
the consumers consumers want to know
about the brands and companies and how
it's cultivated How It's Made maybe do a
tour of the manufacturing facility or
lab I think that's important for
consumers to see from their top Brands
and plus partnering with us we want to
you know give as much Roi and roas back
to you as possible which automatically
brings the CEO onto a talk show that we
have kind of a satire comedy talk show
and you know really just crank up that
partnership as you know make it mutually
beneficial which I think is another
thing that um you know companies here in
the US are apprehensive about um and you
I will say part of what connected you
and I here Owen was my Outreach this
year to particularly the European
markets and they excitement actually in
it so on the US side you know I hear
it's like oh yeah that's amazing you
know we'll
see um sort of thing where the European
side is more like wow you built
something amazing and let's
go it seems to the move when we have a
lot of m&amp;a activity across the industry
let's say schedule three allows that to
happen the big brands that end up coming
out on top that control massive partions
of the industry it would be the most
prudent thing for them to have a large
cap capex budget for Content creation
all the Red Bull model where it's more
sense to be able to create our own
content and generate consumers as
opposed to targeted ad Billboards and
ads on TV which might necessarily be
preferential for the non-cannabis
consuming or the non-cannabis favorable
side of the the population so is that
one of the medium to long-term
strategies that you guys are saying that
okay when this does happen these budgets
for these billion dollar companies are
going to be available to actually said
write some serious checks to create some
real content because as we all know
everybody at this moment there kind of
is self-made content and the budget
behind a lot of stuff could be a hell of
a lot better once they had access to
that Capital absolutely so you you know
the long story short the answer is yes
you know the strategy is um to increase
the production value and to you
know not just the production value of
podcasts and you know news shows um you
know stock trading shows and you know
other educational and cooking shows that
we will be producing um but just
leveling it up each quarter um and you
know to your point as things go schedule
three if they do I'm not confident in
that personally but we'll see
um things will change in that regard you
already see the paps blue ribbons and
some of the big dogs entering the space
well that's when you'll continue to see
that happen and those Brands the brands
that we know that are imprinted in our
brains well they know how to Market and
they spend money on media and those
Productions and getting their voice out
there so you made a great example when
you mentioned Red Bull so I think you
know there's a lot of parallels to what
we can do with Red Bull I think you know
X Games and um you know the yacht races
and the plane races and all the cool
stuff actually that unique stuff that
Red Bull produces well that's generally
a lot of what we will be doing over here
at the channel you know um we will be
having our own sports leagues and
Esports um and things like that so you
can expect that from us but obviously
with our you know cannabis Community
Twist on it and think of it I guess
we're kind of like the the new MTV in a
way almost is a bit of our
model yeah well comedy music Sports I
think the V diagram of those three
things kind of it sits perfectly in the
middle so if you can get a global
audience viewing those three different
uh genres then I think as I said you've
got a recipe success on your hands
absolutely and yeah thank you and it's
you know um the sky is really the limit
um for what we can do and generally
speaking the vision of the companies
that choose to enter IM mediate
partnership with us is you know those
first Partners going to have a large
part in you know forming the direction
of the channel into the future and
that's why it's interesting starting
this year really again the enthusiasm
from
Europe has got me going um absolutely
because I think that um I think a lot of
companies that are eyeing that market um
you know they see huge potential right
and they see um opportunity Beyond
what's here in the United States it's
incredibly difficult again here to
Market and operate and you know I think
it's kind of the New Horizon that's
exciting and for those that are already
there you know they see advertising on a
US Channel as that bridge you know to
gain more brand awareness from you know
probably the largest legal cannabis
Market in the world so or country right
yeah no very much so um it's been
incredible talking to you and going
through the US weed channel for anybody
who hasn't visited the site yet the
website is below and in the description
wherever you watch or listen to this
podcast hopefully uh we get to touch get
Bas again in a couple of months Greg and
hear more about the future expansion for
you guys thank you very much Owen it's
been an honor and look forward to
chatting with you again soon and my
pleasure um until next episode
everybody