[Music]
welcome to the next episode of the
Cannabis review I'm delighted to be
joined in this episode by Julian tueras
who's the founder at skimy leading
consultancy firm based in France how you
keeping today Julian hey hi hi everyone
uh glad first glad to be here thank you
for for your invitation uh hello for for
your audience and uh I'm super happy to
to present what we are doing right now
in France so I think I will start for a
short presentation about myself so as
you can hear I'm
French uh I'm a faradi with 10 years
experience in canabo especially CBD so I
discovered canabo 10 years ago in
California and I bring it to Switzerland
where I start my company so uh we I was
involved so the seed to extract uh we
have our hor plant we made our hor
extract and uh then we uh distribute
this extract and we have the first one
to do that in Pharmacy in Switzerland so
this Pharmacy is Pharmacy benu it's a
chain of Pharmacy of 1,500 Pharmacy so
after this Swiss experience uh I was
focused on French market and I'm working
on French market now since two years as
a advisor from my company advisor for
pharmaceutical labs
uh so some are famous some are less
famous so I quick explain a quick uh
little quick explanation about my job so
the the first part uh what I'm doing is
uh to advise to have good quality
product which uh which is super
important at the moment uh to to have a
really good quality product so I I go to
choose raw materials producer
manufacturer I advise for example about
the low regulation I work so with uh
marketing department or um scientific
Department as well and uh and two I how
to make promotion in Pharmacy so it's a
free really 360 service the second part
which is really crucial for me and I
introduce that a bit later than the
first part it's to train pharmacist I
realize that training pharmacist it's
really uh the key for CBD success and
especially in Pharmacy because the
pharmacist miss a bit the train actually
compared to uh CBD shop or over sailers
and they are scientist and they realize
that they have a lack of knowledge at
this moment and they really want to
increase their knowledge about CBD
product and especially about over the
the counter CBD product so uh I will
start to to talk about the French
cannabis now Market in France where we
are a little quick update so that's
basically an incredible career you had
to date the first topic that I wanted to
talk about was an update on medical
cannabis in France and if you could
maybe give everybody a breakdown of what
the size of the market is um yeah where
where it's alled to be prescribed what
conditions are included and any other
perent information that you think yeah
sure sure sure sure
sure
so about French uh cannabis in France so
uh the French medical cannabis right now
so after the experimentation during
three years
uh Pharmacy will be allowed next year
for
2025 uh to deliver CBD product on
prescription so it will concern for
example like high CBD do or THC actually
what you can find uh on on the mark Mark
concern and especially in Pharmacy or
even in shop it's low CBD product okay
so this this kind of product are allowed
under two main condition so it's a daily
dose of 50 milligrams so per day and a
concentration of Maximum 20% with
sublingual oils for example so this
these two main condition are from the DG
DG guidelines it's a governmental
organism attached to health Ministry so
it's a bit better because it brings more
clarity for the market and uh we cannot
Ure CBD product low lowd do CBD product
because actually it concern six millions
people in France so uh it's a big
challenge it's a challenge for pharmacy
uh to to distribute this kind of of
product uh why because most of customers
at the moment find their product using
internet or they go in a CBD shop or
even in tobacco shop so with potential
quality issues so there's no tracability
there's poor advice or there's even not
at all advice by seller at the moment so
this this is a big problem the quality
is a big problem at the moment the
traceability of the product has a big
problem and there's a really interesting
studies about Mila or Mila it's an
organism attached to our prime minister
uh it's really important organism in
France uh about drugs and addiction and
the their mission is to fight against
drug and addictive behavior and they
made in 2023 a study about CBD product
and the result was just a catastrophe
like 80% of CBD product actually in
France are not compant they don't answer
to what they propose this is the
situation on about a French medical
cannabis right
now very interesting um when it comes to
the numbers of patience how far are you
guys behind let's say Germany or how far
you head from the UK is there a specific
number that everybody knows
of uh how far I I I don't really know
about how far we are compared to uh uh
German or or or UK uh I think we are a
bit late compared to this Market as
especially UK uh but uh we start to uh
with this kind of guideline what I told
you which now since one year I think we
the market are increasing uh I
bet it's it will increase in the next
months or the next years uh through and
I'm particularly sure about that through
the
pharmacy and do you see the one of the
areas of growth happening within France
is the discovery of formulations and
some of the big biotech and farmer
companies able to find these perfect
blends of cannaboids and Turpin to be
able to deliver a finished product to
the market so yeah maybe probably I
don't know I I don't have a crystal bow
for that but what I what I'm sure it's
like we need to to
work of course about the quality but
about for about the bu avability of the
product so I'm always looking for for
example for really good materials and
create pills or or tablets to increase
the the B availability but at the moment
if we talk about for example teint or
CBG or CBN to Pharmacy I think it's a
bit early we're at early stage of to
introduce CBD in Pharmacy so um let's
let's you have to be simple for moment
to train Pharmacy so to be simple it's
CBD okay they they are okay now with CBD
like if you talk to a pharmacist three
four years uh earlier about CBD uh they
they will they will not take you
seriously now they take you seriously so
it's a first step it's a it's a main
step that uh we are doing and and maybe
later and I hope we will introduce a bit
more uh interesting product maybe with
CBG with CBN and uh depends about the
regulation too so let's see as you were
stating one of the big hurdles seems to
be the educating of doctors and
pharmacies can you maybe tell us about
some of the work that you're currently
doing when it comes to uh bring this
forward in France yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah H how how is I told before when I
was presenting myself so one of the big
part of the job is quality the second
big part is education education
pharmacist so uh what I I'm doing right
now for example so I'm doing training
live training so tomorrow I'm going in a
city close to m city and I'm going to
train a group between 30 and 4 Pharmacy
during the afternoon so how to use CBD
product uh in the pharmacy so it will be
super interesting for them M for me um
and two I'm doing online training um I
didn't think that it would be it will be
so s successful I'm really surprised uh
and uh they they are they are super
interesting most of them are pharmacist
manager which are are coming so it's not
just the the second or third hand of the
pharmacy uh so yeah and um uh if they
realize that they have to offer
complient products and to advise a
patient uh they realize that CBD
customers need strong support even for
lowd CBD uh quality okay is crucial but
offering correct advice to patient I
realize is vital uh so for example for
example if I I tell you some training
goals I will tell you some
about our training uh it's first how to
identify good product so provide Basics
on cannabinoids to to to make difference
between CBD THC broad spectrum full
spectrum or even the the vehicles use
the oil vehicle which is used in product
um and and one of the main parts and I
realize too that uh Make This Little
Light in the brain of of the pharmacist
not to talk directly about the product
yeah like this is better than the other
okay it's one point but what they are
really interesting at the moment it's
the Uno canab system we are super
interesting so about how CBD can Works
uh in the body so uh why it's A New Path
of healing actually so integrate CBD
product into
Pharmacy recommendation uh with several
practical case are really interesting
for them to because they just hear about
cbbd okay it's too calm or something
like that may I introduce that they can
use or they can advise CBD for
inflammatory uh problems or to prevent
inflammatory problems or about immunity
and it's it's open really a large a
large possibility for them the Synergy
of CBD with other products too so they
they are super interesting to to keep
back the the market in in in their
Pharmacy and that's my goal actually
it's my goal CBD in pharmacy even low do
uh another another point where I I
really push on it it's to raise
awareness about interaction because like
okay CBD at 50 milligrams a day it's
safe everybody is C about quite safe but
you you are not um it's possible there's
some Auto medication at home and to
double or triple ver do is quite easily
and at this problem like CBD it's it's
an inhibitor of ctoom P 450 so uh it's
it could be a subject of many
interaction so that that's really the
role the role of the pharmacist to to
prevent people about that only only a
pharmacist can do that uh so yeah so we
we insist on the quality we insist uh on
uh how to advise and for me both points
are really crucial about prescription or
non-prescription CBD and about the CBD
in general CBD future so yeah I can I
can conclude that but education
education is the
key when it comes to the CBD is it just
coming from plant matter so it's 95% or
is it an applied pharmaceutical radient
where it's around 99%
Purity um it depends about it depends
about the prod of sure CBD at 99% it
will be more interesting uh uh uh than
pure CBD it's more interesting but it
depends if you if you promote
oils and you work with a broad spectrum
CBD it should be really interesting uh
about the Entourage effect so it's it's
another subject because I'm not against
this theory of Entourage effect but I'm
not pro about this theory of Entourage
effect it could be used in a bad way
like in a marketing way okay there's
probably a Synergy between cannabinoid
so it's could be interesting there's
some different canabo working together
I'm okay with that but this magic effect
like I don't really like the magic you
know magic is not it's not
pharmaceutical uh the other way what I'm
waiting really strongly it's the API uh
CBD so you have some now on the market
uh for me and they are a bit overpriced
but it will come it will decrease I bet
with the time and it should be really
interesting to to maybe to have more
quality product and I already heard
about some different CBD natural one
that the bio avability can be um
increase by two or 2.5 and I'm super
interested about this kind of product
that I can I can promote to some
manufacturer in France and then after to
create a really nice uh drug on
prescription or without
prescription it's been absolutely
fantastic I'm talking to you Julian it's
great to get an update and everything
that's going on in France I know it's
going to be a big prominent Market when
the whole medical landscape is uh is
developing and evolving over the next
couple of years hopefully we get to
touch base in about six to seven months
and see the progress that you've made
over in France for everybody who wants
to learn learn more about Julian's
company you can see the website is below
and it'll be available wherever you
watch or listen to this for now Julian
thank you very much for your time thank
you Owen it was great pleasure to talk
with you it was uh nice time I hope it
was clear even with my French accent and
uh and I will be really glad to to meet
you in in real on on 7 June for for
cannabis submit thank you yeah looking
forward to meeting you in crack place
for now thank you very much for your
time and until next episode
[Music]
everybody