[Music]
welcome everybody to the next episode of
the cannabis review i am delighted to be
joined on this year with a fellow
irishman and one of the leading cannabis
activists in ireland he is also an
independent political candidate and the
founder and host of the hugely popular
martin's world podcast martin camden how
are you keeping
i'm very good on thanks very much for
having me on again i really appreciate
it delighted to have you on the show man
you're all over the news with the
campaign you created recently um can you
give everybody a little overview of what
was the international legalized cannabis
day and the campaign that you brought
about because it was pretty impressive
the response that you seem to have got
from it
yeah i suppose uh all credit has to go
really to luke ming flanagan who is the
real creator of the national legalized
cannabis day campaign
he founded it back in 2001 um in
november 2001 november 5th 2001 when he
went about and rolled up he said to me
in a recent interview over 400 cannabis
joints and sent them to all of the
politicians senators local councillors
and media also across the island of
ireland
and that got a great load of attention
for the campaign at the time he also
delivered the cannabis plant to the then
national drugs minister uh in charge of
the drug strategy and he got arrested in
the process of doing that he never
actually got to deliver the plan to the
minister as intended but he got arrested
and following that campaign uh luke
mcflanagan told him he got over 65 radio
interviews um so for for me i was i was
this was pointed out to me that this day
it was coming up and i was just like
well this is the 20th anniversary of
that date and so i was like that's a
significant milestone and it's a it's an
event that was well worth recreating um
so myself
in a joint effort with other campaigners
here relief cannabis cafe r420 uh
supplies and the cannabis activist
alliance and we set about rolling up
over 200 cannabis joints and we printed
out a nice letter which uh highlighted
the aim of the campaign and at the back
of the letter also included was 10
reasons why cannabis prohibition should
be ended we also included within the
letter then a disclaimer and because
within with the letter included in the
envelope was a cannabis joint and a
jelly and because we had a lot of
hysteria here in the media recently
about cannabis edibles so we chose to to
include a jelly just for that
side of it but the jellies were mostly
haribo from the kids halloween bags and
there was a few cbd gummies put in there
as well but uh not too many doses
they're a bit pricey um but we sent
those then off to all of the media
across the island of our are the
politicians across the island of ireland
and the campaign was incredibly
successful within a couple of days as
the letters started arriving because we
sent them in a kind of um
in a spread out fashion we didn't post
all the letters at once from the one in
a post box because uh to be honest like
when you had a bundle of 20 of them you
could actually smell the cannabis coming
out of the envelopes because they
weren't sealed up in in any way
um so we kind of staggered that that was
what he was looking for we staggered the
post of that going out and then like
come the middle of uh the week following
the fifth of november and we achieved
what we wanted to which we got the
nation talking about
that the need for change around cannabis
prohibition uh so it was it was very
successful we also then got
out another campaigner green tea who
spoke on national radio uh on the
national airwaves as well about uh
what she's doing they're growing
cannabis for her partner who's got late
stages of multiple sclerosis so that the
campaign achieved much more than what
it's set out to do we just wanted to get
the nation talking but we actually got
got a few more campaigners out to the
forefront now and they're standing up
and speaking against this uh inhumane
prohibition of cannabis
yeah no that's a it's a very impressive
campaign and you haven't had any
kickback yet nobody's come back and said
it to yourself
no kickback it seems like the guys above
in the dial are getting more kicked back
to me because apparently they've got
like a 30 million euro security system
in place and and it wasn't effective
enough to prevent a couple of uh hand
rolled
or even to politicians again they did go
back to the old scare tactics oh my god
what if it was antrax it's like come
here don't don't compare our campaign to
to a move of a terrorist organization uh
cannabis giants and anthrax like they
should not be mentioned in the same
headline at all unless their objective
was to try to um
muddy the waters around who we are and
what we're doing you know attaching us
to a terrorist kind of uh fly no no
thanks that was a very poor journalism
that one was
yeah i think i seem to think that in
ireland at the moment here because the
politicians seem to be broken up into
maybe three or four different groups
you've got to got the the young
knowledgeable ones who know all about
cannabis now that there's nothing wrong
with it now that's a billion dollar
industry and don't want to be the ones
to put their their neck on the chopping
board but will back in industry once
it's it's got the right players involved
in it then i think on the contrast
you've got the old people the the civil
servants who might block this in the in
the department of health and whatnot
that uh are just it's like heroin to
them and it's completely uh
uneducated ill-informed opinion on
something so you've got the two of those
worlds that are happening i think it's
what's happening in between is the most
interesting one because they might have
come from that world but they're open to
learning and they just don't know enough
yet and it's kind of up to people like
us to be doing good content and doing
campaigns like you're doing to highlight
how nonsensical the current campaign is
and that they the war on drugs has been
lost long ago that this now needs to be
looked at
like every other uh country i think is
starting to pivot into it and it
actually brings me into the next topic i
wanted to bring up to you is germany
legalizing what are your thoughts on
this so far and the three uh coalition
parties that uh have come together now
to create a recreational cannabis
industry with first products being sold
within 12 months from now i think yeah
well i think that the most uh
attractive thing to me about germany's
move is their their approach
it's not to make money it's not that the
line of coffers at all it's actually to
remove the criminal body that currently
exists within the cannabis industry
with cannabis prohibited it's in control
of the organized crime gangs so the
german government have kind of
identified this as being a big problem
um in order to achieve achieve harm
reduction so for for them they've seen
the most effective way of achieving harm
reduction around cannabis is to regulate
it to control it um in a true sense of
the word control because we talk about
cannabis and all these other drugs is
controlled drugs but they're they're
anything but under a model of
prohibition so i think that's the most
attractive thing about the conversation
there within germany currently it's like
well the money is great you know they're
talking about five billion euro um a
multi-billion euro saving for the
justice department and having to enforce
this you know and having to occupy their
prison cells and all of this stuff
that's all great but what i think is
that the best part of the conversation
is that the control of cannabis that the
harm reduction around cannabis and the
removal of the organized crime gangs
from the cannabis industry and i think
it's great i hope that germany are very
successful over the next four years as
it is a four-year trial and at the end
of the four years they'll come back and
they'll review it so it's open to change
and but i hope the findings are as to be
expected which is that yes ending
prohibition regulating cannabis will
achieve what they're setting out to do
which is eliminate the organized crime
gangs we don't need these organized
crime gangs in our society there's
enough bad players out there without
creating a fictitious system for them to
exist within which is prohibition of
cannabis so yeah it's a great thing i
think that's going to send shockwaves
then across the rest of europe because
as we're having conversations here then
in ireland and those dinosaurs that you
mentioned within the ranks of our
government um it'll be much harder for
them to discredit the conversation
around this now because like for them to
say oh that's a foolish idea they can't
say it anymore because it's like well
you send a german government currently
as a foolish people that they're making
a mistake and because i don't think any
of our ministers would want to get on
the bad side of germany because they're
a big player ever in europe and so i do
think that this is a great opportunity
for us as campaigners here right now
because um the the
conversation it's going to be a lot
harder for the prohibition side to keep
up their arguments because uh it's it's
like a house of cards start their
arguments they're they're falling and uh
they're down to the bottom turnout at
the moment like if we're already they
just clean house with them and because
you know next year as we move into the
next chair in our in ireland and we've
got geno kenny's bill we've got the uh
citizens assembly coming up and so many
avenues for conversation for change to
happen um and the german stuff is just
going to really enrich that conversation
now for us and the kind of the
anti-prohibition side
yeah i think we're uh they're sandwiched
in there we've got legalization in new
york we've got legalization in germany i
think it's just going to be a slow march
in towards us and if they've got any
sense it's about replacing the criminals
with their uh refined legal industry and
uh having a bit of common sense
as they look at this the last topic i
wanted to talk to you just before you
move on to the last one it's just worth
to be saying as well that like germany
are not alone within europe that we've
luxembourg there's malta we've portugal
there's many countries now we're in the
european union looking at changing their
laws around cannabis and a lot of them
are restricted because of the
international narcotics control board
which is why germany are choosing to to
use the phrasing it's a research uh
period a four-year research period
because the international narcotics
control board would kind of control the
laws around narcotics within europe um
they wouldn't allow a country to
actually legalize uh cannabis because
that's the problem brought up by gino
kenny there recently as that would be in
violation european law but a research
project uh that's within it um but yes
germany aren't alone we've uh big waves
being made over here in europe next year
from from many countries so yeah sorry i
just wanted to get that in before you
went down to the last topic
not at all you're you're completely
right so um
the next topic that i did want to jump
in on was the first mcat patient there
was a lot of headlines recently there a
lot of pizzazz and jazz about behind all
this how much of a a
step forward do you think this is or is
it more pressing headlines and publicity
i i think it's it's a great step forward
in one sense because no patience some
you know again we could talk about the
mediterranean access program and it's
like get the most
it's a regime that north korea would our
program north korea would be proud of
because of how restrictive and
controlling it is and because
effectively you know no patients are
able to get access through you know
you've alicia marrow they're suffering
with chronic chronic pain living on
alicante and gets access to cannabis and
it does her tremendous benefit so she
won't get access under the medical
cannabis access program but for the
patients who do this is great this is a
tremendous step forward for them and
they're just tree conditions listed the
nausea associated with cancer the
multiple sclerosis but only the
spasticity associated with multiple
sclerosis and then there's the
refractory type epilepsy now all of
those patients have to have undergone
standard conventional treatments and
that treatment has to be unsuccessful
for them to be considered accessible to
this program so again that this while
having one patient on it it's great it's
a real step forward and but still
there's a long way to go for for the
patients who could benefit from this
plan and they recently added and i think
this is most the most noteworthy thing
actually outside of the the first
patient getting access is they've
actually added two cannabis flower
products now to the medical cannabis
access program one of them is a 22
percent thc variety of cannabis from
bedrock bedrocan the other one is i
believe a thirteen and a half percent uh
thc variety from bedrocan um and i
believe they've got a content of cbd in
there in the region of about one percent
as well in both flowers and but what
this does again for us as campaigners
here in ireland is it's it's more fuel
it's more ammunition for us to use to
counter the arguments of the
prohibitionists how can they tell us
that you know that the cannabis plant
that's being grown by a person who wants
to mitigate maybe the onset of their
glaucoma or something like that or maybe
to reduce the effects of their arthritis
um how can we tell them that they're a
criminal and what they're using is not
medicinal when we now have cannabis
flowers included on it you know is is
this cannabis flourish in some way
superior it's like if it is please prove
it like because i i can't see how they
can justify having one regarded as a
medicinal product and and meanwhile like
the other is like no no you're a
criminal and that's a dangerous drug
that you're dealing with there
it's um
the only one i would say with that is
what i seem to think what they've done
is that somebody like denmark has got
this ornamental flower
pharmaceutical industry so they know how
to grow a rose a million times over the
exact same way and i think this is what
bedrock can't have done is that they've
kind of given a specific
method let's say that they can guarantee
that every single butterfly is going to
be this exact percentage of thc so yeah
i think that's where they're they're
getting around the loophole but that's
not to say that homegrown laws shouldn't
be in essence and part of any law or any
industry that comes into ireland
it's a must i think for the whole
industry to be able to agree on that
yeah i think they're using maybe a
tissue culture method which might be
outside of the realms of possibilities
for the conventional gardener out there
but still cloning like cloning a
cannabis plant it's uh it's well within
the realms of possibilities for for a
conventional getter to do that and it is
quite consistent and again if you were
to end prohibition and if you had access
locally to a service that would test
your cannabis then you could see if your
if your growing program your gardening
program a home is consistent in putting
out um the variety of cannabis that you
need for for whatever conditioners that
you want um and even if it's not again
you know if you as a as a conventional
gardener you might be somewhat uh
um
trained to blend these different
extracts and you could again blend them
to make your own uh um
confine our consistent ratio of
cannabinoids there again and so again
the prohibition of cannabis is what
makes it impossible for people to do
this currently once we remove
prohibition the cannabis will make it a
lot easier i was looking at the medical
cannabis access program like and a 50
milliliter bottle of um one of these
extracts that that's currently under the
can he pulled that that recent i wanted
yeah yeah so going with the 50 ml bottle
which is the most kind of cost saving
one because if you go for the lower
bottle it's even more expensive but it
works out at um it's 450 odd euro for
the whole bottle but with the amount of
cannabinoids that are in there it works
out at being about 90 euro per gram of
cannabinoid so it's like 100 milligrams
of thc for per milliliter and there's
five milligrams of cbd per milliliter
and when you work it out you know break
to cast down like when you're looking at
just the active ingredients if that's
what you're after and going from the
cost of that per gram it's more
expensive than gold gold currently is 50
euro per gram and currently our our
government are buying in cannabinoids
that are more expensive than than gold
know per weight and which is absolutely
crazy when you could grow this stuff out
your backyard and imagine you could grow
something at your backyard and it's more
expensive than gold currently like
just fellas turning over mountains at
the moment to get access to gold like a
ruining the environment and meanwhile
you could pop a few seeds and you've got
something that's just as valuable
and more beneficial than gold because
really what beneficial is gold outside
of maybe the computer stuff you do with
it but
yeah now a great agreed grid i think
we've got a lot to look forward to now
in 2022 and uh hopefully there's major
steps ahead with gino's bill and a lot
of other things coming what's the number
one thing you're looking forward to next
year before we jump off
yeah the there's the feederboards
campaign here in ireland we're going to
launch a feed a bird's campaign again
where we're going to do some fun events
on the run up to it throughout january
our february march and just before we
get into that growing period you know
april may and june and stuff and we're
hoping to give away a lot of free seeds
to people to promote the event but the
feeder birds campaign if people don't
know about it we're just encouraging
people to use hemp seeds to feed birds
and then hopefully you know these hemp
seeds might uh sprout up a few cannabis
plants around the place which might
gather the attention again from the the
media and
get the conversation happening again so
that's something i really look forward
to again next year is the uh the feed
the birds campaign and all of the events
coming up because the calendar is really
filling up there now and for ireland and
the cannabis community and for next year
so big things to come
yeah that's great to hear make great to
hear and look forward to
all that we have got to come now in the
next 12 months ahead of us so thanks
again taking your time to come on the
show mate it's very much appreciated for
everybody you haven't checked out check
out martin's world on all the social
channels on his own youtube channel as
well it's a very very good show and very
educational so thanks again martin for
coming on the show everybody we will
chat on the next episode until next time
you