foreign
welcome everybody to the Cannabis review
I'm delighted to be joining lips Episode
by Brett wardy who's the CEO of MC
nutraceuticals how you keeping today
Brett
I'm very good good to see you
yeah you too mate thank you very much
for taking your time to do this you guys
are one of the largest global suppliers
of Canada it's a great to talk to you
about distribution and wholesale supply
do you maybe want to give everybody a
quick little 30 second 60 second
overview of how you came about being a
part of MC neutral nutraceuticals and
what you guys do
yeah sure I've been I've been in the
hemp industry since May of 2019. I first
started with a chromatography
remediation company where we just
removed THC from CBD
um that business model wasn't all that
feasible during the crash of CBD pricing
crashes
um and eventually I pivoted into my my
own holy identity I called MC
nutraceuticals and we now distribute and
manufacture the 39 cannabinoids that are
derived from hemp that are currently
available in the market we are one of
the only companies that offers every
Cannon really that is offered on the
market and we've you know in the last
two and a half years we've gained quite
the market share in the US and also
abroad where we ship to 19 countries
okay incredible so when it comes to I
was looking at the list you guys have 42
types of cannabinoids available on your
list when it comes to selecting these
cannabinoids is that outside suppliers
that you end up going and do
Partnerships for and you're kind of the
center point of this industry or are you
cultivating or biosynthesizing your own
molecules
we do a little bit of everything we are
more of a distribution so we'll contract
manufacture out with other labs that are
in local to Denver Colorado usually
um and then we do our own r d our own
analytics in-house and we also do some
small scale Manufacturing
so a lot of times we'll build it and
then have someone else go scale it
and in terms of the r d process can you
speak to that how long does it take for
you guys to figure out okay this is kind
of annoy we're going to bring to Market
obviously is it what are these hair long
as a piece of string each one is gonna
be different
yeah so I mean there's there's the uh
the chicken in the egg scenario
sometimes you know what does the market
need
um versus how long the r d processes and
then sometimes things just kind of fall
in your lap or a chemists you know make
something that's that's needed in the
market essentially so r d processes can
happen take up to a year and sometimes
they're as short as is three months uh
one of the big hurdles is standard
creation so we have to actually contract
that out
uh you know 99.99 reference standard
with an outside company and then we take
that to a third party who does a you
know third-party review on it make sure
it is what it is run an NMR and then
they'll they'll essentially start using
that for testing in the market so
testing is one of the hurdles obviously
just the basic r d all of our products
are essentially 95 pure if not 99 a lot
of times they are 99 pure
um so also just getting to that point
where everything is pure free of toxins
we run everything through a toxicology
lab that's local to us to make sure that
there isn't any other products
byproducts essentially made in the
process and then after that process
we're able to fully distribute it once
it's third party tested ran through
toxicology
um and then there there's a need in the
market sometimes you make something and
it's not necessarily needed in the
market
and when it comes to the need in the
market are you highlighting
opportunities and seeing let's say cbga
for Cosmetics or whatever it may be and
then you're going to Pivot to these
clients or is there smaller let's say
Distributors and wholesalers below you
guys that are dealing directly with
formulation companies or with Brands who
are looking to create a new product
range
you know part of part of our or my
company is is the ability to do business
development for our clients
um so our clients are always looking for
the newest best thing that's does X you
know for example way back in the day CDN
uh helps with sleep so what happens when
you mirror CBN and put THC with it you
know you have a you have a hell of a
sleep product so
um you know I think part of it's us
doing the own formulations for other
people we test it out we send it out
that's part of the business development
press product uh product development uh
so we do a lot of that in-house for our
clients you know we see ourselves as you
know you buy from us sure and if we just
want to keep a transactional that's fine
but you know if you want to have a
deeper relationship with us we'll tell
you what to do or what we think is
working on the market we have over 300
clients internally and then we probably
distribute to another
400 500 indirectly through Brokers or
contract manufacturers or people like so
we have we probably have one of the best
understandings of what sells and what
doesn't from the top down View and then
we also take feedback down from the
people that are actually Distributing
straight to stores you know smoke shops
gas stations grocery stores wherever it
is
and when it comes to you guys have a
global presence now in 17 18 countries I
think you mentioned before we came on
air and in terms of the logistics and
the distribution of these kind of
products are you so sourcing more at a
local area or is the ability to take
these across the Atlantic across the
Pacific pretty easy for a company of
your size
sure yeah so we have a distribution or
fulfillment center in pills and Prague
or I mean pills and Czech Republic's
about an hour outside of Prague so we we
said most of our product there for
inventory for what's needed in the the
EU Market the EU Market's a lot smaller
so there's only five or six cannabinoids
that really do sell so it's not a big uh
ask for us we don't have the inventory
all 42. uh so we send that over to there
and then then we can distribute it easy
through the EU
okay very interesting and when it comes
to now sustainability for the industry
moving forward as it's these molecules
are going to become more uh more sought
after and more looked after do you see
biotechnology companies filling a space
especially in the European Union where
regulations might be a little bit
stricter and they want their replicable
molecule over and over again what do you
think the biotechnology companies are
going to play in the the ingredient side
of things for you
yeah I'm I I'm not sure I I guess they
probably would call them biotechnology
companies I know there's a few already
in Europe but the U.S um and I'll just
say this because I'm from the US but the
US is years ahead of where Europe is and
we're seeing that on an economic level
um on a sophistication level regulation
level we're kind of seeing everything
we're kind of seeing I would say you
know once Delta 8 was introduced to the
market in the U.S I would say Europe's
about a year after that so you know
still in its infancy to a certain degree
where people are still kind of wondering
what it is
um you know in Europe that's mainly
hexahydrocannon which is hhc that's the
big product that we see over there
um you know so I think there's still a
lot of growing and evolution done over
there I mean we're you know I spend my
time going to Europe and educating
regulators and politicians about similar
stuff
um sorry one second lost my screen
um
so I think they're still fairly early on
so I'm not sure if someone would enter
the market because we haven't seen any
biotech companies for the most part
enter the US hemp Drive cannabinoid
Market
um once again I think there is some
which you would consider biotech
companies maybe in the water soluble
space specifically so we do see people
claiming they're a biotech company but
we haven't seen anyone biotech
large-scale Manufacturing in the US most
people that are manufacturing a large
scale were already in the you know
they're CBD manufacturers typically
because they already had most of the
equipment and the infrastructure to
build out from there
so the companies let's say the buyers
synthesize their own cell line and are
able to use Advanced fermentation
techniques they're not so much supplying
the recreational industry in the US is
that more pharmaceutical so yeah that's
that's exactly how it put it there
there's I'm sure there's some r d
companies out there there always is uh
but as far as the commercial
availability on a scale we're seeing
most of the products still being made
from you know original 2018 Farm you
know uh hemp Farm manufacturers
essentially so typical extraction all
the way to isolate and then isolates
then used to be converted to Delta a
Delta 10 hhc CBN thcv Etc
and moving on to the intoxicating hemp
derivatives seems to be the new buzzword
that I'm reading from America that seems
to Encompass all of the hhc and Delta 8
that you've been already speaking about
we we see hhc all over Europe you can
buy jellies in the regular kind of old
head store now in Dublin it's gotten so
far over here do you think that they're
here to stay I was looking at some of
the figures from Bob Holman's article on
uh Forbes that basically gave some of
the size of the numbers that these uh
these products and these are bringing
into the industry are they here to stay
as long as I have my way so I'm already
spending time over in Europe as I
mentioned and you know educating people
on what these products are why they're
safe why you should allow them
um you know the best way to describe it
is you know obviously Bob hoban's
article is a good one to reference Beau
Whitney's The Economist that's doing a
lot of work on the U.S hemp industry
who's probably going to start working on
some of the European hemp industry uh
we're seeing you know Florida has now
become the largest cannabis Market in
the world it's a 6.9 billion dollar
retail Market which passes California
and that was done in three years
essentially so I you know I think it
would be wise to at least slow down on
any types of bans such as Austria or
Switzerland or I think Finland now I
think it would be wise and for an
economic level to slow down their their
you know the other thing is safety um
with safety needs regulations so we
we're going to propose tomorrow actually
in our press conference uh in czechia uh
regulations that we would suggest would
be deemed appropriate we've also done
the same thing in Alabama Kentucky
Tennessee and now Florida you know the
the main ones 21 plus behind the counter
if you're an adult and you want to
consume cannabis I think you should be
allowed to and I use cannabis as the
plant so any cannabinoid in the plant
whether it's hht or CBN or thcv it
doesn't matter to me if it's
psychoactive or not it's all comes from
the cannabis plant at some point
um so I I am recommending regulation in
all these countries in Europe and I
believe it to be a huge economic driver
whilst we wait for regulation and
legalization of marijuana which is still
probably you know years out maybe for
Germany for full-blown legalization
um and then who knows for the rest of
the you know the European Union
um
we've also seen in the hemp industry
that
um moderate regulation is significantly
more powerful for medical patients
recreational patients any type of
patient or consumer
um then medical or recreational Cannabis
the recreation of medical cannabis did
about 33 billion last year we think the
number which we'll have in the next
three to four months so Beau Whitney is
over 40 billion for the U.S hemp
industry so keep in mind the hemp
industry has been around since 2018 the
U.S cannabis Market has been around
since 2012 roughly
um so what the Cannabis industry did in
12 years we were able to do in four or
five so we're about twice as fast as
they are from a distribution economics
perspective and then on top of that
we've expanded the Cannabis science to
include 42 cannabinoids where the
marijuana industry only does four or
five and that's not because the
marijuana industry doesn't want to
that's because they're over regulated
the point where they can't adopt and
innovate fast whether it's Capital
whether it's just regular in general
the hip industry is moving at a pace
that you just can't keep up with and
that's why I think it is here to stay
especially in the U.S the European Union
will see how fast I can get out there
and educate everybody on the on the
topic is
yeah I think uh it's got to be one of
these sectors where different parts of
the world are just going to be
completely differently uh legislated and
different range of products I don't
think there's going to be a translate
from North America over into Europe at
all I think with 2027 countries in the
European Union they're all completely
different than a completely different
needs at once but I think the the
advancements that are happening in
Germany and Prague and Switzerland are
are sign of things to come and hopefully
that uh the Czech Republic roll back the
laws that they changed and just recently
regarding CBD
yeah I think I I don't understand the
law I don't think there's actually a law
put in place I could be misunderstanding
it but then and Prague you can't or in
the Czech Republic you can't and I think
this is European Union too you can't
advertise CBD at all essentially so I
think that's more of what the Department
of Agriculture was saying which is kind
of more the same the way I understand
CBD is it's a novelty item you know you
want it you buy it there's no
information about it whatsoever it's you
know it's like a knick-knack essentially
that you can eat so I I think that's one
of the part of the the proposed changes
to the regulation is like listen you
want the people at the store educating
people on CBA CBD CBN hhc whatever it is
so they they can responsibly consume it
it doesn't matter what it is so you know
I I think that obviously I truly believe
there's a misstep by the Department of
Agriculture there or the Ministry of
Agriculture
um but that's why I'm here to try to
educate you know before before I started
talking to some of the advisors of the
Prime Minister and the health Ministry
there's there's just no one to do it so
once you start educating people I think
people start to understand the economics
the safety understand the product and
why it's important
yeah I couldn't agree with you more out
of the 44 kind of a noise that you guys
work or what are the top three in the
Market at the moment and do you think
those top three are going to change over
the next five to ten years
yeah I'll preface was probably not
um but the top one in the US is to help
eight uh for example we sell about a
thousand kilos a week at Delta so it's
about a billion doses
um so the scale is quite un pretty
unfathomable about how much just our
company does and you know there's 15 20
30 alike the US is consuming billions
and billions and billions of doses a
month which is just
it's it's great honestly to see that
people actually want this product they
want to consume this product and it
helps them
um so the biggest ones Delta in the US
the second biggest or the first biggest
in Europe is hhc obviously and that's
about the same you know we said about
500 to 800 kilos a month sometimes a
thousand on a good month to Europe so
we're seeing a similar demand there's
obviously less competition as importing
hhc there's also less people that make
hht in the US so the demand's still not
clear it's not quite as much but Delta
Eight's the king here in the U.S HCC is
the king in the EU and then
I'm trying to think of the second
biggest one
um
you know I'll tell you my favorite just
because at the top of my head you know
there is a there is a huge gap in
between Delta 8 and the next one
essentially on a volume basis my
favorite cannabinoids are CVN and thcv I
think they have the best known
therapeutical benefits thcv is now
coming down to a price where I think
people are going to start formulating in
with their Delta eights or whatever
product it is
um you know I can't make claims but CBN
let's just say it's good at night time
and THV is good in the morning so
um you know those products are have
serious promise and I'm glad that the
hemp industry was able to make those uh
at scale
um and I I foresee that those are going
to be huge products on the medicinal
side in the next let's call it 12 months
from now
okay incredible we just reached our 15
minutes Brad it's been an amazing
conversation I hope we get to talk to
you again towards the end of the year
and the European Union esteemed along
and we've got all these new countries
legalizing
sounds good I appreciate your time
thanks thanks for chatting with me thank
you very much everybody for those who
want to know more mcnuticals website is
below highly recommend checking them out
they're the top dogs in America when it
comes to wholesale supply of
cannabinoids so Brett thank you very
much for your time
yes chat soon bye
[Music]