that ireland is going to be one of the
countries that delivers one of these
global brands
and i'd like to maybe in this little
segment convince you as to why
ireland is going to be the european hub
for global cannabis companies
um i'm sure you'd agree that a lot of
the investment opportunities and the m
a's that are happening some of the
london stock exchange stuff is exciting
industry so
i think a lot of the north american
companies are definitely going to
position themselves for a european entry
at some stage would you agree
absolutely you know i have a a special
place in my
heart for ireland um i i was born in
india when i was eight
i actually moved to ireland my parents
are doctors and they they worked there
and i lived there for six years
uh and and you know i was educated
partly in ireland and then came to the
us
um and i can say you know given where um
ireland has positioned itself the only
uh english-speaking member right now
of the eu uh being known for its tax
benefits to
large corporations that have already
from other industries
utilize it as such it's a natural
natural
landing pad for the larger companies for
innovation
around this area for brand creation for
uh interaction with uh
between the us and eu um so i'm very
excited
you know i plan on making a business
trip out there and
really getting a detailed sense of of
what the opportunities are
but i think you've already got a brand
in that space ireland already has a
brand in that space and so it's all
about how do you convert that
and how do you convince the regulators
to open up
more business around the cannabis space
and that by the way is just a snowball
effect happening right now
if you look at the us and and you have
any kind of doubt
about legalization in the u.s just think
of the fact that canada and mexico
are going to be legal federally and the
us is going to be sitting there missing
out on
tax revenue dollars in post covid
everybody wants to address deficits and
any kind of new source of revenue
generation is golden
so i i always you know people in the
industry complain that we get taxed too
much
i think it's a beautiful thing to get
taxed too much right now because
eventually
the as a lobbying continues as we go
towards legalization and beyond
everybody's then going to start looking
at tax efficiency and ireland's going to
be
very much at the nexus of that yeah i
couldn't agree with you more i think
there's going to be a lot of the
services will be based in ireland a lot
of the
kind of b2b business operations will be
based in ireland
granted there might be genetics in north
america but i still think it'll make
sense over time to have
greenhouses set up in ireland extraction
facilities set up in ireland
logistic companies that open ireland so
i think it's exciting future ahead for
ireland and north america and europe in
the next five to ten years and
hopefully we get to chat about this
again in the next few months and we've
got things to progress about
absolutely i hope your regulators in
ireland are watching and they make a
move
in the right direction and uh you know
part of bar capitals
uh work is to promote and and educate
people
and and and help find the right um uh
the right uh ways to
open up this market perfect it's been an
absolute pleasure talking to nan thank
you very much for coming on the show and
i hope you get to chat again very soon
thank you and thanks for having me it
was a pleasure here as well