so i see folks posting photos all the
time in
facebook groups or on instagram or they
send me photos saying hey what's going
on in my garden and a lot of times i
can't tell from the photo
what is going on in the picture it's too
blurry and unfortunately our cell phones
just don't work well for macro
photography so
i've been using this dyno light for
years we carry it on our website it's
going to run you about two to three
hundred dollars delivered
they're depending on the resolution that
you want
but it is really the gold standard when
it comes to these usb microscopes they
it works really really well
here's an image of an aphid that i took
today uh just to give you an idea of the
quality and i want to do a comparison uh
because
you know it all starts with a good
identification but people are like i
don't have you know 200 300 to spend on
a microscope which i totally understand
so
suzanne wainwright evans my my dear
friend the bug lady
recently recommended to a group uh for
an affordable wi-fi digital microscope
this one from amazon this was 30 for
prime day and i wanted to give you guys
a little comparison so you can kind of
see the pros and cons because there were
definitely some things i came across
with this microscope
that i really didn't like and then there
were some other things that pretty much
blew me away in terms of quality so
uh let's get let's dive into it so
really quickly it's a wireless
microscope it hooks up via a wi-fi
connection which has its pros and cons
and i'll show you how that process looks
here in a second
you have your on off button here
led adjustment it's quite bright and
then this is just like a dyno light this
is how you focus the light
or sorry focus the image that you're
looking at
and then you have a digital zoom
additionally here on the back
as well it comes with a nice little
stand
and probably the coolest thing it comes
with is this cover i don't understand
why dinolight doesn't send these covers
with their lights it's a really really
nice feature
i have to keep my dyno light in the bag
in order to keep dust out of it
suzanne i think even puts like a ziploc
baggie around it too to keep the
microscope lens clean
it does come with a stand dynolite
charges extra for this however the stand
i don't really use the stand anyway
but the stand did fit for the dyno light
too so just something to be aware of and
then here's my charger it's a pretty
standard charging adapter connection
takes about three hours to charge they
say how long it lasts on a charge i
don't know i just haven't used it long
enough yet but let's go ahead and dive
into the microscope itself and then
compare some images and talk about the
pros and cons
okay so i went ahead and stole my wife's
phone and downloaded this mac c app onto
it so i can record and show you what's
going on at the same time
uh one thing about this phone is it does
require you connect through wi-fi so i
actually have to go to my wi-fi settings
here it doesn't take you to the right
location but takes you close um it'll go
in here and in order to see the wi-fi
network that i need i actually need to
turn the light on here so
let's turn it on you'll see the led
light comes on
and uh one thing i found is it's it's
pretty good in that regard like usually
pretty quickly here that wi-fi network
will show up there it is so max c
now we're connected to it
if we go back to the app itself now we
have an image
and you can see that's the image of this
cover which is a really nice feature
that it comes with that cover
snap the cover off here
drop it down here you can see now i'm
recording
or
magnifying this wood table um now a
couple things about this uh about this
in terms of user user ability that's
really nice now if i'm in a in a
outside or in a grow room it's kind of
nice that i don't have a cord to deal
with i don't have to be right next to my
phone
those are all really nice features and
then also over here you can zoom in and
zoom out
so if i want to zoom in
there you go i can see it goes up to two
times there
and then i can adjust just like with the
dynolite i adjust my
uh magnification
and resolution over here and
the the dyno light actually has two
levels of zoom that will focus this one
only has one so once you're in focus
you're kind of you're kind of there
that's the image
so a little bit of a little bit less
quality there
also if i want to take a video i have to
click over here on video
and now it's recording a video you can
only way you can know that is by looking
up here in the corner
so that's not quite as as easy as on a
dyno light either
and then the resolution i can adjust
right here i can also rotate the image
180 degrees and then i can snap photos
on here or i can snap photos on here
either will take a picture of the image
and i can go back to my photos library
and see
now
with the dyno light
you have this really intuitive button
here now yes i can take photos directly
on my computer
but it's much easier to just click this
little button here to start a video or
start a photo and so in that regard i
think the dynolite wins as well as in
the zoom but let's look at the actual
quality of this camera and see if this
is something that will work for folks
who just need a picture of an insect to
send off her id or for scouting in their
room they're not really interested in
getting that super high resolution so
let's compare the two
so here's the video of the wi-fi digital
microscope
as you can see here the quality is
pretty good you can see the aphid itself
crawling around on the leaf i went ahead
and went with video instead of a photo
because
the
image quality is going to look exactly
the same i compared them and
so you do get a high quality photo or
image and then it does have this digital
zoom where you can push these buttons on
the back to zoom in or out using the
digital
ability and you can get quite close and
get a pretty good image so overall i'm
pretty happy with the resolution on this
camera
i'll save some of the negatives for my
little summary at the end here
but the image pretty good now compared
to the dyno light here which is is now
on the screen you can see the dino light
this is the exact same leaf by the way
just a different section with more
aphids
allows you to have that second layer of
optical zoom so much higher quality i
can zoom in on the cornicle there or
now i can see the head of the aphids and
a bunch of aphids here crawling around
so
again you get what you pay for in terms
of the lens quality
with the light so i'm really really
still happy with it overall
okay so let's summarize the difference
between these two microscopes you know
with this dyno light i'm going to be
paying more but the image quality is
going to be much much higher
it's going to have customer service and
support
it's going to have updates it's
it's with a good company and i've worked
with them now personally and i'm really
happy with it
but
it is expensive and you're paying for
that quality now this
this light on amazon this microscope um
let's talk about some of the cons i
showed you guys the image and again it's
pretty good but there are some cons that
go along with it too and things need to
be aware of so one
i originally took some images and i
didn't want to share my wife's photos
with the app and
i thought i could just
share selected photos it didn't actually
take any photos or videos until i shared
all my photos
i thought i was recording photos i
wasn't recording any photos
and then i thought i would send those
photos to
from her phone to either my macbook or
to my phone via airdrop or
email or even dropbox and i wasn't able
to do any of that
it won't let me share the videos it'll
let me show the photos so if i want to
just snap a photo in a grow room really
quickly and send that photo off to
someone i absolutely can but if i take a
video
the only way that i found i was able to
share the video was to take it
add it to my iphone library
on my computer and then drag and drop it
onto the desktop and then take that file
and that file was then shareable i have
no idea why um it actually my wife's
phone during all of this ended up
getting stuck with only siri working and
i couldn't even do a reset until i did a
force quit on the whole phone i don't
know if that was related to this either
but it seemed glitchy
so
i'm not i wasn't too excited about that
you know now since i have both how often
will i be using this one um well i'll
lend this one out to friends and family
and things like that um it's
the advantage of is it's really portable
if i break it i'm not going to be
heartbroken for 30 bucks and
um if i'm out in the field and i want to
snap some quick photos this is really
nice i don't need my laptop and
everything like i do with this dyno
light for a setup so
again there are some pros and cons to it
but um
because i really like taking high
quality photos i'll probably be using my
dino light more but if you're a grower
you want something quick you're not too
concerned about the privacy issues or
some of the glitchiness or necessarily
being able to share the videos um
this might work great for you so you can
check it out i'll put a link in
the comment section there for folks who
wanted a direct link to it to buy it um
i do just full disclosure i do sell dino
lights i think i mentioned the video so
i do have a relationship with them
i know nothing about the company that
makes these uh there's just something
that suzanne put up so
uh happy growing guys remember identify
your pests that's the most important
thing before we take any steps or action
in terms of application or pesticides or
anything you always have to start with a
positive id so alright
take care