[Music]
all right so I'm at hasco Creek Farms in
White Fish Montana with one of the
owners Craig
mcvine uh get a tour of the cultivation
facility which is over in this area just
toward that and the extraction stuff and
then this is the main store but what
they're doing here is really unique and
uh yeah I'm excited to share it with you
guys so Craig welcome yeah yeah
then this is clone Island yeah and we
what do you call it the Clone Lounge
yeah and we were we wanted a little more
humid in here so we kind of like tuck it
in and that the aeroponics keep the
humidity higher nice as long as we close
it off which they seem to do better our
our propagation ratio is pretty I mean
now that it's the humidity is up it's
like 90%
95%
okay so and then
we we always address everything from
like youngest oldest so um we
transplanted this room 3 days ago three
days okay so we're still in veg in
here um there just kind of bouncing
in wow you go from an old barn to some
ra seriously upgraded Tech here
yeah so people are going to ask these
are pip rocks pip pip shelving these are
vas vertical airf flow
Solutions um we run
CO2 from a big 750 tank right into these
the fan pumps it so it just kind of kind
of rain CO2 down on top of the
plants
um and then yeah it's all living soil on
pip shelving and then we run blue mat
systems so kiss soil blue mat systems
and then these are the BIOS lights y
yeah they have a new light out they do
it's very similar but like lighter yeah
the mhm this is the uh ti2 I oh and you
guys also label your beds like this a
little
yeah we label the beds and then we um
run everything through a troll
master and then in the in the Next Room
we'll go upstairs the next room's uh in
like week four so it's a little it's a
little bigger we'll put the shelves in
the next one and go upstairs so you can
see it from from above okay great and
then uh this is how you guys using
scaffolding the access stuff yeah the
scaffolding goes right between
these and then you can move these
shelves you just unlock
them so you can work on whatever side
you
want so for you guys the limitation was
space square footage and space so you
really needed to go vertical yep we
needed to go vertical and and in the
beginning we were limited
on the uh the state of Montana measures
your canopy space
and they don't care like they'll measure
this as
canopy so if we push everything together
we can limit our canopy space so we can
like basically fit more now we have
10,000 ft canopy space so it's plenty
but in the beginning we had a th000 so
we had to like cram everything together
got it that makes
sense got going is like we measure we
try to keep 1.2 to 1.4 VPD
in these rooms and it's like I think one
of the nicest things about this grow is
that these rooms are like they never see
outside of 1.2 or
1.4d and so what are the big factors
there in controlling the environment for
you uh humidity and temperature
basically and then matching that as we
drop as we drop temperature we we drop
humidity and and you that all through uh
this troll Master controller yeah it all
runs through this how do you like the
hydro X Plus I like it
um it it works well we also we it's a
great system for controlling everything
but we use a pulse to monitor everything
oh okay to see um to basically to double
check everything that's a good idea yeah
all right
cool pretty easy we
[Applause]
can so then this is our
other flower
room oh do you want me to close the door
uh yeah let's close it grab it
okay and
then so we're a little later in flower
in here I think we're just just started
week five okay and then we can go
up are you going to run it another round
of trellis netting on
this or how do you guys typically finish
we generally at this point we probably
won't this is probably the cut off on
where we would have we might have to put
some stakes in like we rent two on that
one um so it just depends on the height
so it's I
would I would say we probably should
have ran another round of trellis but at
this point it might be be it might be a
little bit
late got
it oh that just slides in yeah these
just slide in and then they we go up
there it's so it's not so bad then
having that second level that you're
working uh no once you get these
in
um it's really easy to work up
there you just have to think about what
what your move is up there cuz once you
know you don't want to put it in and
then need to go to the other side right
away yeah so the soil's not leaving do
you just pass the plants up or put them
all up there when you go to transplant
and then Harvest like pass them down so
yeah yeah we just put them all we put
all the plants in a bin put it up here
and then transplant them up and then
when we Harvest we just same thing
someone stays down someone goes up and
we just pass them down is there issue
with the a lot of like dirt or dust
coming down onto the lower level when
you not at all not at all um or do you
always harvest the bottom first we
always harvest the bottom first yeah and
we don't really when we Harvest we don't
we don't pull the roots out or anything
so no dirt comes out during Harvest we
just cut the plants out okay um and then
we pull we do pull Roots but we pull
Roots like once everything's all done
then we pull roots
here we can go up here it's all
right watch your head
oh yeah they don't make this right here
taller big
people oh this is a cool view yeah it's
it's so this is the second level but
it's it's you're you're like right here
so it's not not yeah it's a good working
height yeah yeah and you can adjust the
Heights on these shelves all you want
it's pretty easy we just keep it here
cuz it's about good for
everybody and then we go back we we're
kind of still trying to find The Sweet
Spot of how
many how many plants per bed we run
anywhere from 5 to 5 to
11 a lot of it's cultivar
specific okay um what we're what we're
finding but now we're doing a lot of
work to figure out exactly like is it
five is it six is it 7 what's what's the
magic number to Just maximize your
canopy as quickly as possible
yeah
makesense
cool our original room we're not on um
vertical racks yet okay this is how we
this is how we first started with kiss
soil um we made these beds that we can
roll around put them on pallets so we
had some
drainage um and then these are our
original lights too which we will be
upgrading this
room uh probably this winter and then
this will end up being our biggest
room um in this facility we have all the
racks and everything
it's actually a matter of trying to time
it out cuz we're going to have to reduce
production for couple months to scale
this room up okay and one of the things
we were talking about that this is
probably a great example of is when you
so all of these beds were treated the
same the exact same and so you have
cultivars that are reacting very
differently y assuming you know we're
making the assumption that the nutrient
level is going to be the same across all
these beds they're all getting a
approximately yeah approximately all the
same but then you have different
cultivars doing basically taking up
different nutrients yeah like this one
yeah looks great doesn't need any
nitrogen y dark green if anything I
would have you know room like this I
would have said oh this is getting a
little too much nitrogen but then you go
over here and we're lacking nitrogen
have a a mobile nutrient deficiency
going on with nitrogen
so uh this is where and Craig and I are
having discussion about this today with
Terry their head grower about how do we
address these things because we only
want to do one soil test for this room
so we want to keep the soil relatively
the same not get too caught up on what
the soil test is you know at the end of
day we want let the plants tell us
what's going on but make sure that we're
optimizing Health across all of these
genetics so um moving forward you and I
talked about doing some you know light
nutrient things for the beds that are
maybe needing needing nutrients but
without changing the Dynamic of the
whole room yeah yeah so that's so that
we can amend all together and not run 30
soil tests to do it yeah and that's the
that's sort of the next step and the
other thing that we talked about that I
think is really interesting is just at
first eliminating a lot of the
variability so starting out with just
water you know not doing all the other
amending things so you can get a
Baseline and then from there really
improving and adding things uh as
needed but uh
yeah so this room's getting an upgrade
soon in terms of lighting and yep we'll
we'll probably put those new bios lights
in we we've got the the PIP shelves
already ready the vertical air flow
systems are ready we just need to um we
have to get everything out cuz we've got
a the one thing with the mobile racks is
the floor has to be completely
perfect oh so yep any like any variation
in the floor has got to get filled in so
we'll fill the floor in with epoxy and
raise it up like I don't know quarter of
an inch
probably the concrete settled
so cool thank you and then this is a
good room to to talk in because there's
so much going on in here that's
different like there's different there's
different there's really healthy looking
plants there's some that clearly need
nit nen if you go back there there's
some necrosis on the outer leaves and
they look like they need nitrogen so
it's kind of a fun one to dive into a
bit yeah we'll spend and every bed in
theory started out exactly the same
approximately the exact same
yeah yeah so we're going to um just for
people who are curious we're going to do
uh solary pH test see what that's at
take a look at the water and um check
the moisture level in the beds
and then uh come up with a plan from
there yeah
perfect um so this is where we wash and
process our
hash
um we basically freeze freeze fresh
frozen in
here and then these guys take it in
there turn it into hash and then freeze
dry
it here come in here cuz we keep it cold
party in here how's it going guys what's
going
on how you doing this is Tad this is
Zach and Tony nice to meet you
guys last night what what are we washing
right now this is the melted strawberry
nice which right on tested almost 40% we
did this is the fourth wash and we're
getting to you know not going to be um
but I'll show you what the first pole
looked like how we doing guys doing good
sir yeah this is the first pull off of
it so kind of compare the two right
there um
so
yeah nice yeah um and then the uh yeah
this melted strawberry really nice
stuff probably yielding I would guess
this is second and third P too I'm
probably going to get like probably 5%
yields but if I had to guess where we're
at what I think we're going to get quite
a limit
fat yeah Li fat man was 6 and half%
that's crazy it was that's awesome
really we have
like 585 G of cart has which most of
that is like Primo it's going to be such
good C it's going to be so full of
Turing um but you know 70 70% three I
mean there should be
like there should be like six or 600 700
cards wow sweet something like that um
maybe maybe a little bit less depends on
of that depends on how the Press goes we
don't blow anything out things like that
right on cool yeah thanks for little
humble little lab we got the AC unit and
the cool B back there keep a cold
um fill this water tank up I like to
fill it up days before washing that way
ites to get down like 40° before we even
start and then we've got that bucket
filled with ice pretty much and we're
sort of cying water through the through
the chiller and then into here and so
it's pretty pretty good little setup
pumping out the pump the waste water out
the out the wall there nice yeah very
cool well thanks guys yeah man
absolutely this is your o helps grow
some fire fire
Le right
on but it's kind of an
interesting way we do it so we take
these we roll the so we keep this room
at
60° fenhe 60% humidity okay um to get a
nice slow cure on it but these we just
roll these right into the
um right into the grow room and then we
can fill them up there and
then roll them back right into here so
we
can kind of do like full full shelves at
a time
basically
um yeah these are about dry not quite
done
yet very
cool and then these these old uh reefer
shipping containers are awesome because
they're like super easy to climate
control so you don't have issue with
condensation or anything like that no we
run a de we run a dehumidifier so we get
that we um you're able to maintain it
even we keep crazy Montana weather yeah
keep it exactly at 60 60 between that
that mini split in the back that
dehumidifier and then this humidifier
it's like almost always it's within
within less than like about a percent of
60° f 60% humidity okay
cool on that tray in there that you just
saw the uh the food grade the the the
darker green food grade stuff that we
don't really spend near as much time
watching because we're going to decarbon
put it into gummies anyway it ends up
becoming truthfully the most valuable
pch in that lab by the time we put it
into these gummies because of how many
cans of gummies in one wash can make
okay you guys use uh some unique
ingredients yeah versus the standard
indan uh GMO free glutenfree all the
keto all the things uh but yeah organic
tapioca syrup organic uh organic sugar
organic color uh
use products like juice concentrate to
color it um so it's like organic berries
have made this juice concentrate and
absolutely use so we trying to keep
everything kind of natural um I found a
plantbased uh extract um from this
company in Berkeley that we use for a
preservative um which we went from
having mold problems in the very very
beginning of like trying to figure out
if they're going to be shelf stable or
not to not having mold problems
overnight when we start using that
product it's amazing and it's 100% plat
extract super and then you guys add
herbs oh for for one of our gummy lines
yeah we have some herbs in adaptogens in
there to enhance the AM PM sort of
feeling that we're going for in that so
like the PM will have uh camomile and
skull cap and things like that and in
the daytime might have Rola and um other
upper I haven't made those in a while so
which yeah so yeah cool well since I
have you um can you tell me I mean we'll
go check it out but can you tell me
about the Canino yeah since you're the
Creator uh
yeah I just want the spel is
that yeah the Canino we were like 3
years ago we were sitting around and
drinking wine and talking about how cool
it would be to have a product that was
alcohol free CU I think it was probably
in the fall that we were doing this and
that's generally when to try to like
simmer on the drinking for a little
while and um but it'd be it's still nice
to have something like alcohol um and um
and so we sought out to do it and and
started messing around with the hibiscus
tea because it's uh antioxidant it has a
nice color of red wine kind of and so
seemed like a natural medium to go with
and uh one thing led to another added
some Botanical and got close to recipe
and then actually Craig and I went to
wala wala and picked up wine barrels
from double back Winery to try to age
this tea in to give it the
characteristics of like a Cabernet or
something um and so and I think it's not
wine but I think it's close I think it
it definitely had I I don't know I feel
like people I think people liked it I
think people were receptive to it and I
I feel like people were uh
were understood it understood that it's
not wine but it's kind of and we were
just putting it in little 1 o shot
glasses if you you know you pour a glass
of wine which I've done with family
members there that are not into cannabis
at all um in fact my mother-in-law just
quit referring to it as a narcotic which
is awesome um so but she I poured her a
glass and she tried it which I think is
a testament to the product because
there's no way she would have smoked a
joint if it was getting pter on the
table um but she was willing to have a
little glass of canabo and so it's kind
of removes that stigmatism and provides
a social atmosphere for cannabis use
which I think was a great alternative to
alcohol for myself personally yeah and
it's a little more social experience
than just eating a gummy that's that
that's my whole consumption these days
is I'm married to someone who doesn't
smoke um and so I it's not like I'm hang
out with friends so my whole consumption
these days is like a gumy before bed or
maybe going down to my basement and
smoking my puff CU or but I'm by myself
you know and I'm not you know I'm not in
a social setting with that um so yeah
absolutely and how much THC is in the
Canino we went for four to five
milligrams per glass and so this batch
has five and a quarter um we wanted to
make it approachable so somebody could
have a glass um that might be a little
heavy for some users um so just a
smaller glass but it's for for for
people General Canabis users I think
four to 5 milligrams is a pretty
approachable dosage and so in the in the
bottle the wine bottle the wine bottle
how much 21 total 21 milligram so we
went for went for four servings per
bottle so you can pour like a 6 to 8 o
glass have a nice Hefty serving and but
still only get a few milligrams as
opposed to having to do a shot that has
10 migs so we didn't want to get
anywhere near 100 milligrams in that
bottle we were 20 was as high as we want
to go honestly yeah yeah we probably in
a perfect world would have been closer
to 15 or 16 but okay yeah yeah no I I
tried it it was quite good and you know
it has a subtle cannabis flavor to it
but you really the hibiscus tea is
really what you the the Hibiscus is
really where it's at so yeah we have a
we have a lady who does tea Blends for
us at the store for has and I'm actually
going to include her in the next round
and maybe try to do something that's
more like a rosé or a white and have it
be available in the springtime as we go
into summer and honestly I think that
would probably appeal to some of our
demographic even more um than going
after a red and I think it' actually be
easier to achieve I think that she can
give some pale teas that will have that
finished product of a white wine that we
can get some of those floral because
white wine is naturally a little bit
more floraly and that kind of thing
sometimes anyway so maybe try to I don't
know we'll see we no one's ever done it
so we'll try I just love seeing new
innovative ideas so I think that was
that's very cool we'll go and we'll go
check it out in the store here awesome
excited yeah thank you
thanks now that I don't want to get too
into because there's pollen in here oh
okay but you can look in there though
it's peing yeah I was peeking with the
camera yeah and so that Center plant was
jobba the Hut a male and then um we're
breeding with lemon fat man musty
Buffalo and I think black maple okay so
we'll let those go and then we'll get
the seeds and then we'll run pheno Hunts
on
those yeah so this is our this is our
store hasco Creek Farms in cannabis
counter um the vision here was kind of
to create a much more
approachable um userfriendly
familyfriendly uh dispensary that had
other health wellness products and was
more health and wellness focused so
that's what we
did well as we're walking inside tell me
a little bit about sort of your vision
for this place so the vision was kind of
to create somewhere that um you know
your mother could go when I was my well
my mother's she's got Parkinson's
disease and she uses cannabis to help
her with that and she was she 7 years
old and she's not that comfortable for
her to go into a dispensary um and
necessarily and get her medicine so we
tried to make a we wanted to make
something that was more comfortable more
open um gave people a cooler cleaner
vibe to go
um use cannabis get cannabis and other
things they need so this is the front of
the store hasco Creek Farms um all real
health and wellness everything's been
super ethically thought out um basically
no talkx no toxic chemicals no um toxic
ingredients everything's been every
ingredient in every product in here has
been researched to make sure that
it's
um mostly mostly all from organic farms
in the US
and be corporations and other you know
good com good clean
companies very cool so it has sort of a
just a welcoming familyfriendly vibe up
front here and you I see you guys have
some some drinks and stuff that are just
yeah and like all the none of these
drinks have a ton of sugar in them
they're all you
know uh I know like this black water is
full of fulvic acid
and zero sugar z00 Z full of fulvic acid
is really good for um gut health
immunity
um kind of the all the all the things in
here that's kind of kept in line with
all the herbs and supplements and adap
all these herbs
available I saw you had mushroom powders
yep over they keep moving things they
keep moving things
around um you have a whole sleep section
on magnesium yeah sleep section mushroom
powders it's we've got kind of like a
more male section back there where it's
just you know we've got two or three
deodorants in there the cleanest de
deodorant we could find and kind of
we've tried to find the best of
everything and put it all in one place
so that people don't have to I went down
a rabbit hole one night trying to find a
find a good deodorant that wasn't full
of aluminum and other oh right here and
other things so I I appreciate that
you've done that yeah and so that's kind
of like this is the the lotions like
that the face wash and
then that's
like your our deodorant line right there
is the same and like any one of those is
that very cool and then uh tell me about
safe Farmland so safe Farmland we donate
a dollar of every transa sorry a percent
so no$ one of every sale goes to Safe
Farmland which is a 501c3 that we have
um developed that is basically designed
to kind of kind of curb development
around here and keep some of these Open
Fields as Open Fields Andor you know
keep some of these smaller Farms going
um I can't I can't don't quote me on
this but like in the 70s I think it was
like 88% of the food in this Valley was
grown in this Valley and now it's like
7% or something it's it's those numbers
aren't completely accurate but they're
close and that's
pretty um not really a sustainable
future in that people need to kind of
grow their own food at least in their in
the area they live um and so we're
across the street
we've donated 40 acres to save Farmland
that's the first big land donation I
think there's a couple more coming and
we've got a lot of people around the
valley involved and they are kind of
rallying behind it and we're trying to
over across the way develop a farm Hub
of sorts that would hopefully allow
younger organic farmers that maybe
couldn't afford a plot of land around
here a plot of land to be able to uh
um grow organic vegetables so they'll be
able eventually this will all be
Farmland Y is the is the yeah and right
now it's right now it's or it's hay so
it'll it'll maintain as a hay field
until um yeah you know we're in the
um uh
fundraising the
fundraising um state of that this right
now and trying to get more funds
together to try to save more land like
that yeah cuz you were saying like this
develop over here wasn't here few years
ago uh yeah probably I think that's you
know probably eight years old and then
oh and then there's one yeah the one
around the way is they're still building
it just that white fence y there's a big
development going in so and that was
they're still I mean they put that up in
like two the last two summers yeah
they're still they're I think they're
finishing the last two houses right now
but yeah it's beautiful out here in
Glacier National Park is just right down
this road I heard yep right through
those two mountains right in that canyon
on a clear day you could see Great
Northern Mountain through that this is
our event space um we're able to have
events out here um in this space this is
this is part of hasal Creek Farms which
is completely different from Cannabis
counter cannabis counter is its own
entity and own registered premise which
has given us a little more room in the
front to be able to have an event space
like this have you know your families
come and be able to hang out and play
soccer or bot ball and
enjoy a beautiful Montana afternoon um
and with the with the legalities of
everything keeping the two different
spaces and the two different businesses
allows us to successfully do that so you
essentially have two different addresses
here so so this is 1202 and cannabis
counter is 1200 war in Ro one address
and then we cruise over here and it's
another address so this is the event
space is technically yep the event space
is technically entirely different space
yeah very cool all right
thanks I'll start go ahead yeah so
here's the Cannabis counter side of
hasell Creek Farms right this way all
right um we try to keep a similar vibe
to the front where we've really like
ethically thought out you know what we
carry back here it's not a bunch of
different uh glass pipes and stuff
they're they're source to be clean and
um kind of good companies that we would
stand behind just like everything else
in
here
camera to work there we
go and then over here we have
our we're a A can distributor which is a
company out of a beverage company out of
Colorado actually that's hemp
derived THC low uh milligram THC
beverages so they're 2 milligrams THC 4
milligram CBD um they're just a partner
ours we don't we don't create that
there's our rosins this is actually a
this is a cheesecake that Tony made a
THC infused cheesecake oh yeah he's like
he's like the mad scientist yeah he's
having fun back there yeah yeah um and
then here's more of our these are all
our own products that we make in house
and we kind of do a
um five different categories uh that
kind of correlate with sativa and Inda
so
you know the heavy the heavy sativa
strains we put more into a focus or
socialize hybrids end up in more
socialize create relax and then heavy
Inda um more sleep generally and then we
also base that off the tpes in each it's
not the only thing we use we just tpin
as well to to kind of give you more of
an idea of what what sort of feeling
you'll get when you consume
um whether it be you know a pen a t
think sure or gummy or flour so here in
Montana you're allowed to open the jar
yep and smell it and stuff yep so you
can open that and
smell there's that melted
strawberries you guys are hand trimming
yeah all of this
mhm and then uh this is your gummy line
I know we talked about that so here's
here's our gummy line so this was our
original gummy line with these are
um
CO2 extracted um we have a daytime and
night time we sell these in twos fours
and 10 milligrams um the nighttime are
have like chamomile and holy basil herbs
mixed in with them the daytime have
ashwaganda and Rola uh mixed in and then
our newest canop our newest gummy line
is these um
these H these are hash RW and gummies so
all solventless hash RW and gummies all
milligrams and then we get the
categories by washing our own hash and
keeping all of our
um hash that we use you know whether
it's indicia forward sativa forward yeah
so we keep everything um everything's in
its own childproof container and just
give everybody a peace of
mind
um okay Cas they have kids or whatnot
and yeah that's way better I mean the
ones that we buy in this in Washington
are usually just in a yeah they give
they we we do that too we have the exit
bags but it's we've gone a step further
um and we've gone it's that way with
everything so like here's our here's our
flower you've got to line this
up to that little
thing in order to get it
open very cool I love
that same we've done the same thing with
the pens and even these I won't open
these because they got tamper seals on
them but same thing you have to push
those in to get your yeah to get your
pens open and that's all fresh frozen
live rosin
um all
solventless very cool and then this is
the and this is the canbino yeah and
then these are our Deli our bulk Deli
jars here we don't use Clear jars so we
keep the light off the Cannabis so it
doesn't deteriorate over time but it's
the
same most the folks can just tell you
how much yep so you can also just order
um however much you would like and then
we can weigh it out and give it to you
that way if you want to bring your own
jar um I don't know where they are but
we we do have jars
um where you can bring your own jar and
and do it that way here's the Canino
that we just saw heard about from
Tony yeah
great cool well thanks for the tour
[Music]
yeah