so I wanted to share a talk that I've
given at a couple of different
conferences in the past year I gave a
version of this talk at the living soil
Summit in Vegas and then just recently
in Melbourne Australia at a
pharmaceutical conference you know I
started the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast over six years ago now
as a way to bridge the gap between
academic research and actual Growers
when I first started the podcast there
were very few resources for finding
accurate information and frankly my
initial interviews were less than
scientific but rather folks that I knew
that cultivators really wanted to hear
from as the podcast evolved I refined my
podcast to be more research-based but
also included cultivators that have been
successful in the industry to share you
know their real world experiences
because as many of you know rarely does
growroom environment or outside growing
conditions reach anything close to what
we would consider be optimal there's
always going to be challenges there's
always going to be
compromises most of my interviews are
with experts who have dedicated their
lives to a very specific aspect of
horiculture or biology and I consider
them to be much smarter than me I just
try to stay open-minded always keep
learning and ask the questions that I
think most Growers would want to know
the answers to and my goal today is not
to be exhaustive on any one topic since
I've done over 130 episodes to date but
rather just give some key takeaways and
then folks can go back and find those
guests uh and listen to that particular
podcast if they find a topic that's
really interesting or they want to know
more or you can ask questions uh in the
comment section below for this
particular YouTube
talk so starting off I have to pay my
respects to Clackamus cot I met him in
in the ICM uh organic soil form I'm
still on there from time to time and uh
the biggest thing from my all of our
long conversations and um you going out
to dinner and stuff like that was I
learned that as a general range a
quarter cup to a cup per cubic foot is a
pretty good place to start for most of
your inputs if your NPK on a particular
input is higher then you probably want
to be close to that quarter cup range if
it's a lower mpk input then you can
probably be closer to a cup and there's
there's a lot more that goes into
balancing there this is just a very
general rule uh C's also famous for
popularizing the Cornell soil recipe
that recipe is uh essentially a third a
third a third so it's a third compost a
third Pete Moss and a third pmus or
perite or whatever form of variation
that you have now we've modified that in
our mixes
uh we're we we've changed that up a
little bit uh for a few reasons one
because uh we find commercial compost to
be the biggest contaminant in terms of
heavy metals uh so we've reduced that
amount to closer to 15 to 20% uh we keep
the Iration around 30% and then we'll
add in biochar Pete Moss to make up the
difference for our base mixes but um a
lot of people are still running you know
what people call CZ mix and uh doing
well with that one thing that talks
about though is you don't have his mix
because you don't have his earthworm
castings and essentially what he's
saying here is you need to formulate
around your compost your compost is
going to be your biggest variable in
determining your soil recipe and that
and that's one of the reasons that I
don't really like online soil recipes
because everyone's using a different
compost source so really important that
you know your compost Source uh when
you're when you're going to come up the
recipe because it may already be in
calcium you don't need to add as much or
maybe high in potassium and you don't
want as as much whatever whatever
nutrient we're talking about here so
that's where soil testing really comes
in handy and that leads me to my next uh
guest which was Steve Solomon Steve I I
had heard of Steve before I really got
too far into the industry Steve had
written gardening west of the Cascades
which was a really famous book here in
the Puget Sound uh in the northwest
region and when he came out with his new
book The intelligent Gardener uh the
idea really uh spoke to me because as
someone who grows vegetables I wanted to
grow the healthiest food that I could
and that was really Steve's focus is how
do we get all the minerals back into the
soil in the proper ratios and at luxury
levels so that we can grow
nutrient-dense food because if the uh
soil is lacking in calcium for example
and then we're growing a crop that's low
in calcium we're not well the food that
we're consuming is not going to happen
the calcium that we need for our bodies
and in addition if we're taking that
waste and then re- composting it and
then putting it back onto our soil we're
exacerbating this issue of low calcium
so that's where soil testing and soil
balancing comes in and that's something
that we really like to do on the U
cannabis side of
things now one thing that I want to
highlight is that Steve's soil targets
and metrics are for growing nutrient
dened vegetables uh that's really that's
a really important distinction he's not
as interested in yield and he's
certainly not talking about cannabis um
and and he that's something that he
freely shares um and and something that
we've talked about a lot so the targets
for what we call living soil for
cannabis are quite different than the
targets for um nutrient Dent vegetables
according to his
book next up uh is Gaia Palmer I did I
did a couple different interviews with
ja ja's was such a good friend um he
passed away in
2021 I I just want to remind folks that
if you have friends that are dealing
with addiction and depression and things
like that uh that you reach out to them
and connect with them as best you can uh
G had uh definitely had some demons but
he was also one of the most
intelligent and uh unique people I've
ever met in my life and and frankly kiss
wouldn't exist if it weren't for G so I
want to pay my respects there and uh I I
think his interviews are actually quite
interesting given the fact that many of
them were were he he was at The Cutting
Edge of what a lot of these things are
that we take for granted now like VPD
and bio controls and all this stuff uh
it really wasn't around in the canvas
industry when he started talking about
it and you can kind of hear that in some
of my initial podcasts with
him one of the things that g talks about
though that I think is important to
highlight is that canopy determines your
yield so whether you grow one plant in
veget for a long time to fill a 4x4
space or we put nine plants in that same
space uh if the canopies are
approximately equal your yield is going
to be approximately equal all other
conditions the same um and that's I
think that's something to think about
when you're planting out your crop
depending on if you have uh number
limitations based on the regulations in
your
area the other thing that G came up with
was this uh initially it was sort of an
80 to 120 membar for kiss soil and
that's a good starting number for most
people growing in Peete based living
soils uh We've since modified this
closer to 80 to 100 we want to be a
little bit wetter the lower the number
the wetter the soil is um we have some
guys going as low as 60 so some people
are going 60 to 80 but it's really
important to try it out in different uh
in your media and see what works best in
your uh grow space but that's a good
starting
point and then one other thing that jaia
figured out was that communal planting
has increased yield benefits so I met G
one day I was literally mixing soils in
my parents' driveway when we had the
compost tea business and he stopped by
to get some compost tea ingredients and
I just gave him some of the soil I was
making said try this out with your
plants let me know what you think I
wasn't even growing cannabis at the
time and uh he came back
uh a couple months later and really was
super interested in the soil because
that soil would just water outperformed
his program that he was running I think
I think he was running bobiz or one of
the bottled Botanicare bottled nutrients
at the time um some organic line and so
then he started experimenting with this
soil and growing in seven gallon pots
and he took all those pots and put them
in a flood
tray kind of all mashed together and and
then he and he noticed that the roots
were starting to grow together and he
saidwell why not um just put them all in
the flood tray so initially he just
filled the flood tray and then he
realized the soil depth wasn't enough so
then he increased the depth and and
started growing in essentially a raiseed
bed with pond liner uh and and that was
the most successful thing because for
those of you that grew up um in states
where it may not have been legal to grow
it was the sketchiest thing you know
trying to move soil out of your garage
or out of your basement at 3 o'clock in
the morning um you know trying to trying
to do that was always sketchy so if we
could reuse the soil and just bring in
nutrients to replace what was taken out
by the plant uh that was going to reduce
risk and reduce labor and make
everything simpler and we've since
modified this process to um commercial
facilities but that's really where it
all
started okay moving on to the bug lady
Suzanne way wght Evans dear dear friend
of mine she is the best entomologist um
INF field
entomologist um I'm aware of in the
United States maybe in the world she
works in um ornamentals she works in
horiculture she works in cannabis uh she
really knows her Pest and this is the
stuff that she's taught me through our
conversations and I've done multiple
podcasts with her and I I highly suggest
you check them out so step one it always
begins with a positive ID you need to
know what the pest is because um they
can have different life cycles and
without understanding the pest you
really can't begin to develop a a
program for treating or managing the
pest and one of the other things that
she highlights that I think is important
to realize is that pests cannot develop
a resistance to being eaten this is
important because when we apply chemical
fertilizers over time or even organic
fertilizers pest can develop a
resistance to that and if they survive
due to that resistance they're going to
be more resistant uh to Future
applications that's why we change our
modes of application so um we're not
constantly using the same pesticide over
and over again but when we use
beneficial
insects uh that's not a concern and
they're working 247 for you in your room
getting to all the places that you may
not have reached with your sprayer so um
bringing in the right beneficials at the
right time in the grow is is
huge and then this one is one that most
people know but I just want to throw it
out there as a reminder because when I
first started spraying my plants with
pesticides you know like an oilbased
spray for example and and pesticides
don't necessarily mean chemical
pesticides you know I'm also talking
about things like neem oil Horticultural
oils um you know sulfur whatever all of
these things that we use in the organic
side
there're still pesticides um you always
want to apply them at the label rate so
I was thinking okay I'm going to be
ecologically friendly I'm going to apply
my pesticide at the lowest rate I can
because uh I just I don't want to be
spraying pesticides anyway well the
problem with that is when you apply a
pesticide at below the label rate you're
allowing that plant to develop a
resistance this is that issue that weal
I just talked about so
always important to apply label rates
because those label rates are
established to give you the maximum
killing effect uh with the minimum RI
minimal risk of phytotoxicity so um you
always want to follow the label rates
and they'll usually give you a range and
you could stay at the lower end of the
range depending on how much pest
pressure you have but that's always a
good idea to make sure to follow those
label rates those label rates if it's an
EPA registered product are the law and
you have to follow them especially if
you're a commercial facility and always
make sure to wear the proper PPE as
well one other thing that she mentions I
think is important to bring up is that
it's best to apply beneficials early
when the plant canopy is smaller when
your application rates are lower and
before we get too far in flour because
if you get into flour not only can you
not really spray anything once pistol
development is started but it's also too
late if you have a big outbreak if you
see
webbing for example from two spot
spidermites you know laid in flower you
could apply beneficials but they're
probably it's probably too late in the
game at that point so it's really a
great preventative I like to do a couple
of preventive or mainit sprays and then
bring in my beneficials after I've done
a couple rounds of sprays and then
that's sort of my beginning IPM in veg
so always use the beneficials um as soon
as you can in the plant's life after
after you're done spraying whatever
whatever it is you might be spraying on
your
plants and then lastly Suzanne there's a
ton of bad information um online I see
people getting recommendations for their
IPM program from Facebook or Instagram
or forums um always good to have an
entomologist in your corner or reach out
to someone who has access to an
entomologist to make sure that you're
getting accurate information and if you
have a commercial facility
you know I I've talked to Suzanne about
this multiple times I just had this
conversation with her this week where
she went and visit a facility that was
working with a different uh consultant
who was a rep for a
insectary and basically they were having
them over
apply the beneficials and they were
spraying too many products to where uh
her visit was paid for within a month
just from what they were spreading on on
uh pesticides and beneficial insects
because their program was not optimized
uh from from from a cost perspective so
if you're a commercial facility and you
have a robust IPM program it's always
good to have a professional like Suzanne
look at over and make sure that you're
not overspending too because people do
go that route as
well and then lastly uh please don't buy
ladybugs again something I thought was
ecologically friendly um in fact they're
Wild harvested I did a whole podcast on
ladybugs and why you don't want to buy
them it's actually pretty interesting if
you want to check that out but they are
wild harvested they spread disease to
Native populations and if you let them
go outside they're probably just going
to fly away so one more thing to think
about uh when we talk about beneficial
insects all right next is Ben Hartman
this is a book that I think everybody
should read um if I owned a commercial
facility I would make all of my
cultivators and even all my processors
and everyone in that worked for me read
this book um it's all about minimizing
waste and maximizing
efficiency it's all based off of the
whole Toyota concept of lean
manufacturing Ben did a great job of
converting it into a mental model that
works for farming but really it works
for all aspects of your lives so the
whole idea is to reduce muda and muda is
waste and waste can be
um
wasted uh food that you know you didn't
get processed it could be waste in the
form of a pile of of stuff in the corner
of a of your I don't know corner of your
room that needs cleaning up um it could
be waste in the form of
uh time like you're spending time trying
like when I had a farm I would spend
time if I wanted to start a project it
might take me 20 minutes to get all the
tools I needed to start the project and
I think well shoot by the time I get all
the tools together I'm not even going to
have time to do the project so that was
a that was a waste um and then the last
waste is this mental waste this idea
that we have things that are constantly
in the back of our head that we know we
need to do and we just don't seem to be
getting around to it that's a form of
muda as well um so it's it's a great way
to just be a more efficient grower and
more efficient with your
time it's all about getting the right
tools in the right location to SA time
and
money um and I will add just a funny
story um over at Gold Leaf Gardens the
uh Nate over there had all his guys read
the book and it was so funny because one
of them was coming up to me Buddha and
he's like yo I'm I've been you know
getting into this whole lean farming
thing um my toilet paper you know we
were keeping in the garage now I keep it
in the bathroom so it's right there
where I need it when I need it um and
it's just more efficient you know and
it's just funny how we can incorporate
these things into our life to be more
efficient with our
time all right Dr yorm kapulnik um he's
with the Volcan Institute he was one of
the creators of
dinoo and uh he really changed my mind
about how I felt about micro isal
fungi so what he talked about is um and
I think this is important to keep in
mind for all microorganisms whether it's
micro fungi or Bavaria
traderma when we say these These are
sort of think of them more like
categories um in the sense that they're
not all the same product so for example
the
Israeli
dyo is comes from a very um Aid
environment so it has very good drought
Toler tolerance um it can handle a wider
range of temp so we're talking about
those abiotic conditions maybe then some
of the other um micro risal products on
the market and frankly there aren't that
many microle manufacturers most of them
are coming from just a few
sources so that's something to keep in
mind too but with Bavaria you know for
example if that particular Bavaria
species was uh discovered on say like a
grasshopper that particular Bavaria
product may have better efficacy with
grasshoppers but it may not have as good
of efficacy with say another species of
insect so to say that all Bavaria is
going to perform the same is not is not
very accurate you really need to try out
a few different ones and find out what
gives you the best efficacy now just to
further complicate all of that we found
that some companies some quite popular
um companies here in you know the
organic living Soul Space are selling
Bavaria that doesn't even have a Spore
count high enough to allow for any level
of
efficacy so you really need to know
where you're getting your product and
know that that product is that is good
otherwise you're just wasting your money
and I know this because um one of my
pathologist friends purchased it tested
it and and looked at the Spore numbers
and then on the flip side there's
another company not in the living soil
space but out there that's selling um
Bavaria and their claims for Spore
counts are higher than would physically
be possible to fit into that volume of a
container so it's not it's just not even
possible so um really important to to
look for a good source when we talk
about buying um micro
products and then one other thing that I
wasn't really aware of was that micro
isal fungi and traderma can be
symbiotic a lot of products have them in
there together but traderma can be very
aggressive but it what they found is
that the certain species can work quite
well with micro isal fungi so um if you
wanted to do a micro isal uh
application uh you know early on when
you first transplant a rooted cutting
for example or have a Seedling then you
could follow that up a few weeks later
with a trichoderma application something
like root shield and that would be just
fine uh one other note that I wanted to
add here is that U and I'll talk about
this more in my heavy metals talk but
there is research that shows that micro
isof fungi increases the uptake of heavy
metals along with all these other
beneficial nutrients so microle fungi
has a ton of benefits I highly recommend
checking out the podcast but keep in
mind too that if you're in a state where
you're regulated for heavy metals you
may want to just be careful and think
about using this because it will
increase uh heavy metal
uptake all right Don Marshall Don is a
dear friend of mine uh
he established uh the Horticultural
college at Lake Washington and he uh or
the program there and he ran it for like
30 or 40 years um I went back to school
just to take his botany program prior to
him retiring the last year before he
retired because he is the best educator
I'm so grateful to know him and I'm
working on putting together a botney
class an online botney class for folks
that so that people can take his course
online uh here in the
future but one of the things Don talks
about in his podcast I with him and I
think this is interesting and this is
where it's important to understand the
mechanism behind
why plants do the things that they do or
what the mechanism of action is from a
plant physiology perspective
because um it's all about in this case
root hair death so root hair is where uh
nutrient and water uptake occurs and so
if you are
overwatering you're going to be killing
root hairs and potentially creating
environment that's going to be better
for pathogen growth uh if you're
underwatering you're also going to be
killing root hairs now these root hairs
will regrow but the they will both give
you a similar above ground display in
terms of symptoms because they both
cause a reduction in nutrient uptake due
to this root hair death which I think is
really interesting because people look
at a wilting plant and they just oh
that's underwatered but in fact it could
be massively overwatered because they're
going to have same symptomatic
conditions and understanding why I think
is really
important and one of the things that Don
highlights is you need to be a detective
in your growth so you need to do this
first thing in the morning not at the
end of the day after you've talked to uh
you know hundred people and made a
million decisions and you're tired but
right when you first go to your
Greenhouse or to go you you know go see
your plants you need to look around the
room and say see what's going on you
know what's what's my limiting factor of
growth and sometimes it's fertility but
people always assume it's fertility um
it could very well be your irrigation
the way you're Watering your plants it
could be CO2 it could be light intensity
um all of these things all work
together and so what you need to do is
always be thinking about what the
limiting factor of growth because
there's always something and you just
need to keep checking those off and
checking those off and keep improving
things so there's no reason for example
to go buy a hype
ferment um or biological product if my
limiting factor of growth is light or
the way I'm watering um and if you do
find that one of those you know products
makes a difference then you have to go
backwards and figure out why it made a
difference what was it addressing in
terms of nutrients in terms of biology
in terms of whatever aspect was limiting
your plant's growth so just always good
to be a plant detective in that regard
um and it's something that I always
think about now when I approach plants
um in a new
situation Lee Bree Lee does not work in
cannabis either um he is a plant
[Music]
doctor independent prop consultant sorry
as a doctor at implant Health um he
works in agriculture but I really loved
his perspective and approach to uh plant
health so he loves soil testing but he
does it primarily to support what he's
already seeing feeling and smelling in
the field for example you can scoop up a
handful of soil you can smell those
actino bacteria uh you know what healthy
soil smells like you can feel the tilth
of the soil what levels of sand silt and
Clay are in there um you can see with
your your eyes visually how the plant is
responding to the fertility that's
getting so um the soil testing is really
there to support that and I think that's
important we can't rely solely on soil
testing I think there needs to be a
check some checks and balances between
the soil testing and how our plant looks
um because at the end of the day that
soil test really doesn't matter what
matters is our plants and how they're
responding um to whatever fertility
we're giving
them and then the other thing that Lee
talks about that I think is important is
um this idea that egg is not a natural
system um you know you hear people say
well no one's know putting Miracle Grow
out on the
rainforest um yet we're able to grow
these healthy happy plants um what would
Mother Nature do this idea of biomimicry
you know and imitating what nature does
well Mother Nature doesn't have weeds
they're just plants Mother Nature um has
pests you know what we would call pests
um there's in you go out and look around
your yard you'll see that there's insect
damage on pretty much all your plants um
keep there's checks and balances there
to keep things in place and what causes
those checks and balances is the level
of diversity and ecology that is there
but when we talk about growing a
particular crop which means growing one
plant primarily to the exclusion of
pretty much all others um it's not a
natural system so while we can use what
nature does we want to look at it from
the perspective of um the fact that it's
not a natural system what is going to
make a difference in the health of our
crop and some of those practices like
bringing in organic matter um you know
in mulching cover cropping um those
things make a lot of sense in an outdoor
environment indoors where we can control
every aspect of a plant's growth or
health um is it's very much not a
natural system and we want to keep that
in mind when we're making decisions
about our growth
so I thought he did a good job speaking
about
that all right Brandon Hudson Brandon
works for kiss um he does all the
Agronomy for us and
he's been growing now for oh shoot
almost 40 years I think so a ton of
experience and he's grown he's grown
with salts now he only grows Organics um
but he he just has a ton of experience
um ran a commercial hemp facility for a
long time and so um one of the things
that Brandon really talks about and
explains so well is this idea of a
dichotomus key and he put together an
article it's on the kiss website uh you
can check it out under the blog page
under learn and essentially what it is
it's a mental checklist it's this idea
that Don talked about about being a
plant
detective um all laid out for you with
mental mapping so is your problem biotic
or
abiotic you know is it caused by
temperature or um sunlight or is your
problem caused by an insect or a pest
for example um he looks at and he
explains like all the different
deficiencies that you may see from a
nutrient
perspective and then how we can address
these
things so um I highly recommend checking
it out I did have him on the podcast
talking about the dichotomus key as well
and one of the things he talks about is
just following the science you know
we're constantly learning um he's one of
the more Curious people that I've ever
met um and he's always challenged me in
that regard to keep on learning new
things and so you know he's he just did
a podcast with Mr growt recently talking
about um you know myths within the
Cannabis industry stuff like white ash
he he talks about the science behind
that um so really important that we
always look to science first rather than
what we see on social media or what um
influencers may be telling
us and then one of the things that
Brandon is really good at is pathogen
prevention and he does this by not
skiing out on um his his spray routine
um by keeping his space very clean and
staying ahead of the game on this um I
tend to be a little bit more of a lazy
grower and I'm not as good about this
sort of thing and you know it shows here
in the Northwest you have to stay ahead
of things with sprays you know microbial
sprays for example if you want to
prevent powdery mildew if you want to
prevent petritis on your outdoor crop
and Brandon's really good about that you
know staying to his schedule journaling
what he's doing every time he goes into
the grow room so he has notes and then
uh making sure to stay ahead of it so
something to think about in your
grow now as I'm recording this talk I
just recently published a podcast with
Dr Nicole goce and she's amazing she's
she's a
pathologist um she's at the University
of
Kentucky and I the latest podcast has so
many gems I this is based off of her
first podcast with me but one of the
things she talks about is there's very
few cannabis pathogens that are easily
identifiable from images you really need
to send them off to a pathologist um to
make sure that you understand what
you're dealing with so that just like
with insects so you can come up with a
prop proper plan of action um you know
recently here in the Northwest I get
this uh it looks like powdery mde this
sort of white covering on the leaf it's
not visible when in the morning dew but
after the Dew dries you'll see these
splotches of white again it looks like
pm on different places all over the
plant and I you know I looked at it
under the dino light with a microscope I
I'm not able to identify it so I sent it
off to uh Dr goce and I can't wait to
hear her tell me what it is the only
thing I can think it might be is
something related to Leaf Hoppers
because that seems to be the one thing
that's vectoring across these plants
currently it's only on my um autoflowers
it's not on my photo period plants but
I've seen it on them in previous years
so I'm excited to get it identified so I
can know how to treat it or even know if
it's something I need to
treat uh one of the other things she
shares is that there's actually two
species of powder M that can infect
cannabis and one can survive and thrive
at a 40% humidity so um it's important
to know what you're dealing with so that
you can treat it appropriately and the
reason I say this is because
traditionally we would say okay well I
need to drop my humidity down to a level
that PM can't survive well at 40% not
only are you stressing your plant but um
in the case of in case of this one
species of PM it actually can do quite
well
so this is this is important to know and
then also that these uh powdery milde
species can have a wide Host range
meaning that they and they can display
differently on different plants so that
powdery mildew on your squash um is
actually probably the same PM that
you're getting on your plants um same
with your cucumbers so it's important to
know that um because I'd always thought
oh there're all there's all these
different species of powdering mildew
the one-on-one plant is probably not the
one affecting my other plant but that's
not totally the case some of these have
pretty wide host ranges and one of the
things she mentions is that curbit tend
to uh have the same species of PM as
cannabis and that's something she
mentioned in the latest podcast so that
was new information to me so now I'm
going to be more careful in the future
with my pumpkins my squash my cucumbers
and keeping them away from any cannabis
crops to make sure I'm not going to get
em transferring across or staying ahead
of the game with my spring on on those
plants because um traditionally I will
always get pm on my squash plants uh
here in the Northwest it's rather
inevitable and then this is just always
a good reminder but whenever I go to a
new facility I always like to pop a
plant out of a pot typically in veg and
just take a look at the
roots you know do they have white
healthy roots with good root hairs or
are their Roots Brown and slimy is the
plant girdling at all because they
haven't trans planted you know in a
proper amount of time um and one of the
things is that pythium is pretty easy to
identify um it's typically only an issue
on young plants and they can outgrow it
uh but these are things that we can
start there are some things that we can
identify
visually all right Dr Bruce
bugby now this podcast uh I did do a
podcast with him but some of this I'm
going to share is new information that
came from a podcast he did with uh migro
recently and one of the things is we've
known that cannabis is a highlight plant
you know similar to Corn but it can
handle levels even higher um in the
recent trials that he did upwards of
2300 ppfd with yields continually
increasing now you have to take that
with a caveat because there are some
lighting companies out there that are
pushing more light more light more light
which is not a sustainable approach one
because it's it's it's not good for um
our environment in terms of the amount
of energy that we're using and having to
create but also because from an economic
perspective those yields may be slightly
higher but they're not increasing uh at
a linear rate so the yields go down as
the light goes above so the the economic
threshold where we want to be uh is
around 1,00 to 1300 ppfd
um when we're supplementing CO2 at 1,200
parts per million um and everything is
dialed in and I think that's an
important factor I would tend to go even
a little bit lower than this because you
have to remember this is Bruce growing
in a growth chamber this is not a
typical facility situation with living
soil where we have a lot more variables
going on so I would tend to aim for
1,000 to 1100 initially um and then you
can always ramp up but if you you are
running CO2 you do want to run higher
ppfd now um if you aren't able to run
CO2 let's say you have a home grow and
it's just not feasible then 800 to 1,000
ppfd is optimal when you're not
supplementing
CO2 and young plants can handle
highlight too this is something new that
I haven't had a chance to really play
around with but he claims a th000 ppfd
in veg is fine with CO2 supplementation
and will cut veg times down
substantially meaning we'll getting get
a lot more growth this is really
interesting I would caution people to
work their way up to this I wouldn't
just throw plants under a th000 ppfd in
veg but I think this is definitely worth
exploring um as a side note if you are
interested in lighting at all um I've
been working with a wonderful company
that's a NASA spin-off uh their company
name is bios the website is bios
lighting and I I work with them uh with
lot of um lighting proposals so whether
you need one light or you know 500
lights we've done we've worked with
people on both sides of that um It's a
Wonderful light with a seven-year
warranty um I think for the price it's
the best light in the industry and it's
what I use over in my
Grove at my house and I'm very happy
with it so just want to throw that out
there for anyone looking for lighting
just hit me
up uh Bryant Mason Bryant is another
good friend he is an
agronomist uh and some of the things
that he talks about I've done multiple
lives with him on YouTube you can check
out as well as uh interviews for the
podcast but one things that we both
agree on is that pH matters in Organics
and living soils um fortunately with
Organics and living soils the pH will
tend to fall into a a range that's
acceptable let's say 66 to
72 but if we can get that pH dialed in
into to a a good range the plant's going
to be able to put more of its energy
into other things rather than
um pH management so that's where we
always want to start with getting our pH
into optimal ranges for plant health and
too low of a pH frankly can really
increase your heavy metal uptake um
another thing that Bryant talks about
and Steve Salman's talked about this
well as well is that gypsum has a very
low solubility rating so um and a very
low salt index because of that soluble
rating so you can use a lot of it with
very little risk you know it's going
it's calcium sulfate so it's giving you
calcium and sulfur it's not really
impacting pH and so um that's one
amendment that I think you can be very
heavy-handed with and experiment with
because typically if we don't get enough
calcium into the plant early on in the
plant's life and throughout all the way
through flower it's going to impact um a
variety of plant physiological functions
and um impact our yield and plant Health
dramatically one other thing that Bryant
talks about is
nitrogen so there's research that shows
that maximum nit nitrogen use efficiency
occurs when plants use various forms of
nitrogen um so that
means we want to try and think about you
know not just using one source for
nitrogen but multiple
sources and then uh when you incorporate
carbon based nitrogen it increases
nitrogen efficiency and what he's
talking about there is things like
anything with a meal at the end of it so
feather meal fish meal blood meal all of
those come with that carbon um component
in there which will again increase that
efficiency of nitrogen some one of the
advantages we have as organic
Growers and then there's a lot of hype
around amino acids you hear a lot of
people say you aminos and they're
typically derived from soy um one thing
that Bryant points out is that all
organic products when we talk about
these different meals feather meal fish
meal whatever are either composed of or
end up as amino acids these are proteins
and fish meal for example is quite high
in protein um so in through the process
of mineralization we're we're getting
those amino acids um so he's on the
fence as to whether or not we need to
purchase um
directly amino acid products or if we
can just continue to use these
amendments because they're going to be
mineralized into an amino acid form um
through through the organic process
anyway through nutrient
cycling Dr Wendy's zelner uh this along
with Dr goce probably my two favorite
podcasts at the moment
um
silicon is uh such a fascinating element
it's highly abundant um and has a ton of
different plant benefits um it mitigates
plant stress reduces heavy metal uptake
uh there was a study actually done by Dr
Nicole goce the pathologist that found a
70% reduction in powdery mildew using
molite which is calcium
silicate it increases your heat and
drought resistance it reduces salt
stress enhances UV tolerance and reduces
sodium and chloride uptake it really is
that miracle drug that Miracle um
fertilizer uh it's the one thing that
kind of meets all of those uh all of
those standards and interestingly enough
you know when we talk about hyper
accumulators like cannabis or rice for
example if soils have insufficient
levels of silicon then the plant will
uptake arsenic through that same
pathway and Si availabity availability
varies dramatically based on your parent
material and Source uh and this is sort
of the order from most available to
least available so an amorphous form
would be something like pottassium
silicate that eggs 16h you know I think
we sell a pound of it for like 20 bucks
it allows you to make up a gallon of
liquid potassium silicate it's what's in
most of of those you know silica
products on the market just you get to
add the water yourself and save a ton of
money um and that's one of the best
forms of Si from an availability
perspective and then biogenic would be
plant-based sources of silica so things
you know silica derived from bamboo for
example would fall under that category
um that tends to be the next most
available though you do have to be
careful with um the potential for heavy
metals for example with rice
HS a lot of people like to use rice hes
well that can be quite high in Arsenic
so you do have to be careful of your
source and then lastly is crystallin so
that's silicon dioxide those are things
like
um salt or quartz for example not salt
sorry sand or quartz um that that's that
crystallin form and those are going to
be available more on a period of weeks
to months to years and probably are not
even going to be available that first or
second cycle even um so if you're adding
silica sand keep in mind that these
products are rare rarely
unavailable um one exception to this
would be dious Earth according to Dr
zelner uh it tends to be fairly
available to the plant and they've done
some research with that which I think is
really
interesting um and then this chart here
that she shared with us is a good way to
compare SI products so you can convert
them so you actually are comparing
Apples to Apples because it is quite
confusing and all these different forms
of
Si um will offer different levels of
actual
silicone and then if you are applying it
she recommends 30 to 60 PPM weekly or 20
to 40 PPM on a soil
test all right and that is the talk
really appreciate you guys checking it
out if you do have questions comment and
I'll do my best to answer them or uh
send me an email at Tad atkiss
organics.com and I really appreciate you
guys checking out and supporting the
podcast we do have a patreon channel for
anyone that is interested that uh allows
you access to the
podcasts immediately after I record them
you get the raw interviews with all the
information uh we also do monthly
Hangouts uh where we share our grows and
talk talk with other Growers um about
what's going on not just in our grows
but in our lives and then also do a book
club right now we're working our way
through teaming with microbes we already
did the intelligent Gardener and we have
a few more books on Deck uh so it's been
a lot of fun oh and then we also have a
private Discord Channel and some other
stuff going on but um yeah so if you
like the podcast and you want to support
it it's a really easy way to do it I
think it's as low as five bucks a month
you can check it out and get access to
all that stuff too so appreciate your
support have a great day