so here's the African compost with the
molasses and the name and I'm seeing
I've seen like four or five of these
really wide fungal hyphae structures in
in the sample and I just wanted to show
you this this is only a 100 times
magnification so I'm wondering exactly
what the effects the neem are on the
soil but when I added that in the
molasses you can see there's just a ton
of growth and again this is it 24 hours
this is the widest diameter fungi I've
seen any of my testing so far and
zooming in now so you can see there's
there's a ton of bacteria as well now
we're 400 times magnification
so I gotta say the surprise any quite a
bit i did not expect to find this
but I think we can safely say that the
addition of neem cake watered in
certainly not killing the microbes in
our soil seems to be increasing them
especially when I look at it with
molasses in there