okay we're back with the
African worm
castings at 24 hours with a little bit
of molassus added in now we're starting
to see some more activity here so we're
starting to get some fungal
High getting uh a strand like this uh
probably every other field of view so I
think this this were a tea I'd want it
to go longer we're at 24 hours right now
um
keep in mind that your field of view is
or through this video is a lot smaller
than my actual field of view through the
eye
pieces so let's see if we zoom in
here lot more bacterial
activity you can see it looks like we
have pretty good
uh morphological
diversity different
uh shapes of
bacteria