okay this is an African Nightcrawler
earthworm castings combined with neem
cake and molasses you can see there's it
we're still getting some fungal growth
or about 28 hours in right now this is
it a hundred times magnification we zoom
in 200 times get an idea of just how
much bacterial activity there is the
entire here's the fungal fungal hypha
but the entire slide looks like this in
terms of bacterial activity
it's just teeming
you're now at 400 times magnification
and we looked at the African
nightcrawlers without any any food
sources we didn't really see a lot of
activity so I am inclined to think that
the neem cake he's a decent food source
especially for bacteria here but it
doesn't seem to be inhibiting fungal
growth as I am seeing it on the slide or
if it is it's minor relatively speaking