this is what I think makes microscope
work so interesting so when we look at
the karanji cake now added to the exact
same compost was before that we added
the neem to I wasn't able to find any
fungal hyphae and this we zoom in here
that's just 400 times magnification you
can see we have some bacteria but
nothing near what appears to be the
levels that we had with the neem cake
but certainly more than the control and
this one had a very different appearance
the water actually turned a grayish
color it's kind of murky looking but you
can see some guys cruising around there
I'm curious to see how this will look in
another 12 hours