[Music]
hey guys Tad here with kiss Organics and
today I'm here to show you an unboxing
of the newest Light from bios lighting
this is the Luna
1750 now now for those of you less
familiar with bios bios is a NASA
spin-off founded in 2014 on the Florida
Space Coast originating from projects at
the space Life Sciences lab and Kennedy
Center to grow plants in space and help
astronauts regulate their sleep on the
International Space
Center if you haven't had a chance you
can check out my review of the BIOS
Endeavor multibar light on our YouTube
channel I've been running it in my
garden and I love how little it weighs
making it easy to hang and adjust and
the light output and uniformity is
excellent I've gotten solid yields with
good turine expression across multiple
harvests and bios uses the same Spectrum
in their Endeavor and Luna
lights today they use these discoveries
to revolutionize lighting for human
wellness and growing plants on Earth
I've worked with a lot of different LED
companies over the years and now I work
exclusively with bios for a few reasons
uh first and foremost is because I
believe they have one of the best lights
commercially available on the market in
terms of build quality you really see
that NASA engineering coming through and
the quality of the lighting they're
producing and they also have the best
customer service of any Lighting Company
I've ever worked with uh in addition to
that they have the best warranty that's
out there on the market today a 7-year
warranty on the fixture and a 5-year
warranty on the power supply but let's
Okay so let's get into the specs on the
light the light works on a range of 120
to 277 volts or you can get a different
power supply that works on 277 to 488
volts
the fixture is approximately 38 in Long
by 4 1/2 in wide and 4 in tall and
weighs 12.2 lb the power supply can be
mounted next to the fixture or further
away using a jumper cable and it weighs
7.4 lb the light is 635 Watts with a par
efficacy of 2.76 U moles per second and
a ppf of 1750 U moles per second the
housing on the light is cold forged
aluminum and tempered glass over the
diodes so you can easily wipe them down
and clean them this is crucial not only
for IPM but also to maintain efficacy
lights without glass coverings May list
slightly better efficacy but in everyday
usage I would expect it to drop quickly
as the diodes become dirty or Dusty and
you cannot clean them effectively the
light also has an ip66 waterproof rating
an ip66 rating is protected against
multi-directional High Press water so
you don't have to worry about damaging
your light when spraying and it's easy
to clean and it's the highest rating a
fixture can have bios C customizes both
the cabling and the lighting layout
because everyone has a slightly
different grow environment if you
contact me directly through kiss
Organics we can get you a custom
lighting layout that would show you how
the lights potentially overlap and what
sort of homogeneity you would have
throughout your
canopy okay so I wanted to shoot a quick
video showing you how easy it is to hang
the light because it weighs so little I
can hold it with one hand while
attaching the hangers and then the Quick
Connect cables uh they just snap in and
do a half twist to ensure a solid
electrical connection with no risk of
them coming apart it's literally plug
andplay right out of the
box all right so now we are back in the
grow room I have the lights hung up I
have the Luna and I hung it up next to
the Endeavor so that you could see the
two side by side both of these lights
are from bios and the Endeavor I'd
already did an unboxing video of that
you can check out on our YouTube channel
um you would never really run these
lights side to side by side you choose
one design or the other but I did want
to show you what they look like next to
each other now in terms of the light
itself um I'll post on the video here
I'll show you what the actual lighting
layout is but just checking it with my
par meter right now um as we start up
close to the light here we're up to 3200
uh ppfd and then as we come down now I'm
at about 2,000 right about here directly
under the light and then as I move away
we're going to see those light levels
drop as that angle changes to too so
even at this distance we're at about a
th000 ppfd here and as we move out
towards the edge of the bed here at an
angle if I angle more meter we're about
550 uh
ppfd so we're getting quite High light
levels uh with the Luna and we're
getting it with a very slim form factor
so it's not going to block any light
coming in from the Sun say in a
greenhouse and we can also pack these
closer together if you wanted to hit a
higher overall uh ppfd in your grow
thanks for watching my review of the
Luna LED grow light from bios lighting
please reach out to either myself or
bios if you have any questions or
interested in a custom lighting layout
for your garden or facility