foreign
what's up guys Tad here with kiss
Organics and I'm excited to give you the
first look at the new bios endeavor
just open the box and I'm gonna get it
out here
so we have some cords now cords are
going to be extra
separate accessories when you buy the
actual light but it does come here's the
power supply
let's take it out and get a look at it
here
foreign
okay so this new light is foldable
as you can see here
the first thing I notice is that it's
really well built I love the sturdy
construction with the aluminum it is
much lighter than the other bios lights
and uh basically we have everything we
need here with a power cord
here's a dimmer cable
and then we have the power supply which
I'll attach to the back and then the
light itself now all these things are
separate uh in the way that you purchase
the light
um
but it makes it really easy to get
exactly what you need so you're not
buying unwanted cables or extra parts
so the power supply
has these nice little clamps
fold out
hearing this will just clamp right onto
the top of the light
and snap on
I have these easy Twist on connectors
and then here's the optional dimmer
cable which I'm not going to install
right now
the light does have these clamps so it
makes it really easy if you want to
attach it directly to racking
these can extend out and that'll support
the light otherwise you can use
basically some hangers some clip hangers
which is what I'm going to do today
but let's go ahead and get this light
plugged in and set up
okay this is a broad spectrum light
with optimal photosynthesis and coverage
for a 4x4 canopy area
it's going to have 1150 average ppfd at
a foot from the canopy and 2.7
micromoles per Joule Photon par efficacy
it delivers a total of 1750 ppf
and can be used indoors in multi-tier
systems and for your veg to flower
growth you can use it full cycle
I love the glass over the diodes which
makes them really easy to clean it
protects them from dust and overspray
and will actually improve your
efficiency over time because of the
ability to clean the glass and keep this
clean in your facility or in your grow
room so my favorite thing about this
light is the fact that it's really
robustly built I love science as you
guys know and the fact that bios is
founded by former NASA scientists I
think is really cool and it really shows
in the build quality compared to other
lights on the market though I think my
favorite thing about bios is the
customer service it's been wonderful
working with them and knowing that if I
have any issues or if I need something
right away they get it done in a timely
fashion that's the great thing about
working with a small business that's
focused on delivering for the customer