this is the blue lab pulse meter I'm
very excited to be able to add it to our
lineup of products at kiss Organics and
we have the best price online this meter
is not for everyone but here's what it
does it measures moisture conductivity
or EC and temperature directly in the
root Zone with one click it connects to
the blue lab Pulse app to view analyze
and store all your measurement data the
apps available in English Spanish Dutch
German and Korean and it has a has a
built-in depth gauge to get consistent
measurements with every reading it works
in soil Coco core nutrient solution and
living soils so how and why would you
want something like this for your garden
well first off it will quickly measure
moisture levels it is waterproof unlike
the blue mat moisture meter and I love
that I can get a reading immediately
instead of having to wait for a while
between readings this means I can use
one meter and check multiple pots or
beds in in a matter of seconds to see
how evenly I'm watering or if I have any
dry spots or if any containers got
missed when watering secondly it tells
me EC EC is a measurement of electrical
conductivity in your soil which is a
good way of seeing what level of
fertility you have in your media cat
like calcium magnesium potassium sodium
and ammonium as well as annion like
sulfur chloride nitrates and
bicarbonates are all salts that when
dissolved in solution and soils will
carry electrical charges and current now
too high of an EC will potentially put
osmotic pressure on your roots and that
can be bad so it's about getting it into
the proper range and we really want a
soil test so we can determine what is
making up the salt concentration in our
soil but it will give us a rough idea of
fertility in our soil mix if we know all
our inputs and staying within certain EC
ranges typically 7 to 2.8 will allow for
good microbial activity and important
soil processes like respiration and
decomposition keep in mind that several
factors canect effect soil EC such as
moisture content soil structure and the
presence of dissolved salts as the soil
moisture increases so will your
EC and lastly I get an idea of
temperature cold root Zone temperatures
can inhibit plant growth and the uptake
of many essential nutrients like
phosphorus and too high of soil temps
can make it easier for plant pathogens
to grow I'm currently calibrating it
with my blue matat moisture meter and
we'll be comparing it with an aerometer
here soon
okay so this is the iPhone app that
comes along with it you can use it on
Android as well though the app is called
pulse again it's available in multiple
languages and essentially I just push
the button on the pulse meter itself to
connect it it connects quickly via
Bluetooth and then at that point I don't
have to keep reconnecting with every
calibration or every every photo I want
to take I just click the measure button
and then I can go in as I'm doing here
and I can add a photo to that
measurement as well as any notes that I
may want so here's a good place I can
add say the the VPD in the room at the
time um any pest pressures I may dealing
with uh when I watered um and and keep
track of all of that right here in the
app so it's a nice little kind of like
journal in some ways now this could get
complicated in a facility where you have
multiple plants and things like that but
you do have the ability to export the
data so if you had a facility for
example you could just measure one room
export that data and then keep the files
somewhere else associated with it but
since I just have using it in this room
I can go back through historically and
look at my notes and anytime you see an
orange dot there next to the recording
that tells me that I took a picture um
or added extra notes so that's a really
handy feature to quickly go back through
and look at what was going on in the
room at that time for tracking things so
again not for everyone but if you're
into Data this is a really cool tool
that uh could potentially help you in
your growth
and so you can see what I was doing here
was I was comparing the 35% moisture in
this case correlated approximately with
my blue matte moisture meter um at that
point it said I was at about 75 M bar
now I've been playing around with this
for a little while and getting a bunch
of measurements to kind of get an idea
of EC and uh moisture level and how
those things relate to say something
like the blue matat moisture meter and I
find I probably want to be around 35 to
45 5% is a moisture range um and that
probably correlates to about 80 let's
say 70 to 90 in terms of uh mbar ratings
but one other cool feature here I can
now export this data I can send it to
someone or I can save it to a file or
email it to myself and uh I think that's
another really great feature associated
with this you can configure it based on
the type of media you're using in this
case I just configured it to a mix media
for living
soil well that's it that's the blue lab
pulse meter I hope I covered the pros
and cons as well as why someone might
want to use this tool in their Garden
thanks for checking out my review and
you can go to kis organics.com to learn
more or order one for yourself thanks