um you know I guess we're getting into
more of the realm of anecdotes here but
some Growers well there's two there's
two things that I've heard from Growers
one of them is a myth in my opinion and
that's that sulfur levels like that are
uh kill soil biology and I just don't
think there's any evidence of that I
mean soil soil microbes need
sulfur um and there are certain popul or
certain species that actually prefer
high sulfur environment you may you'll
see a shift in the in the population
profile like you will with any
management action that you take um but
it definitely doesn't kill microbes I
think that comes from the idea that
there are a lot of fungicides in organic
production that contain sulfur so
something called the Bordeaux mixture or
lime sulfur like it's a it's a great
fungicide when topically applied to the
leaves but it's in a totally different
it's completely different chemistry in
those products versus sulfur in the soil
um and at 100 PPM it's not toxic it's
not costic it's not I I don't understand
the functional mechanism in which it
would kill microbes and uh I you still
see microbial action I don't have a
microscope I don't use a microscope but
you the microbes are clearly
thriving based on a number of other
metrics when you use a lot of gypson so
I do not believe that the