[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from a around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge now before getting into the
podcast I wanted to let listeners know
of a couple of things first off we have
a new Bloom booster that we've been
formulating and testing for the past 2
years it's now available on our website
and is the cleanest organic Bloom
booster on the market we also have a new
soil blend using a new compost Source
from SE Coast compost that is the lowest
heavy metals with the highest fertility
and beneficial biology of any of our
mixes so if you're in a tight regulatory
State please reach out because I think
we can help my guest this week is Adam
Arnold Adam is the founder and owner of
collective elevation in Boseman Montana
Collective elevation is one of the
largest living soil cannabis Greenhouse
facilities in the country Adam's been
growing cannabis for 20 years the last
10 at his facility in Boseman which was
designed and built from the ground up by
him and his team prior to recreational
legalization in Montana he built
off-grid Greenhouse facilities in
Montana during the medical days and has
founded Collective elevation on a
platform of sustainability utilizing Sun
Assisted Living soil practices he went
to school at the University of Idaho for
conservation biology and natural
resource ecology and worked in
Wilderness management for the forest
service prior to working in the Cannabis
industry I had the pleasure of visiting
Collective elevation last year and
filmed my tour which is available on
YouTube I highly suggest checking it out
it's one of the nicest facilities I've
ever seen in person and I'm honored that
they've been using our soils in their
green houses for over a few years now
anyway now on to the show Adam welcome
to the
show thank you honored to have you here
um can you tell me a little bit or tell
listeners a little bit more about
Collective elevation and I just want to
right from beginning suggest that if
folks enjoy this interview and would
like to see the facility that we're
talking about we did put out a YouTube
video last year when I got to tour the
facility in person that's on YouTube
already can just search for it and it's
a it's a great uh example of a wonderful
Greenhouse operation in Montana but all
right Adam take it away tell me a little
bit about uh Collective
elevation yeah Collective elevation
we're um the largest living soil
facility in Montana probably one of the
largest cultivation facilities
singularly we are the largest
cultivation facility in Montana and
um we evolved from in the early days of
Montana medical program like 2011 and 12
we were um my business partner was a
hydr grower and I was a living soil hoop
house off-grid grower I had a place out
in the boonies that was just all solar
powered and we when we started our first
Dispensary after a couple years of
knowing each other we basically saw that
uh my style was producing more Cannabis
Cup winners we were actually winning
more Awards with the living soil and
off-grid approach than we were with like
uh fancy dosatrons and and hydro and
salt-based systems and then also it was
just far more profitable as well so we
had kind of like stumbled upon this um
one of these rare win-win wins in the
world of that doesn't happen very much
in business where it's uh something is a
better product that's better for the
planet and once you have a knowledgeable
group of uh or a team you've got
something that's also cheaper to produce
and that just that's we stumbled upon
something that was uh yeah like said
rare in business and so we kind of ran
with it um and as we bought this new
facility I I also did see the
limitations of having an off-grid
facility you can't really run year round
you can't have beautiful mom rooms you
can't you just as much as we want to be
sustainable you got to have proper
electricity and a and connection to the
grid uh also I needed to be closer to
town to have access to labor so that I
could build the team of my dreams so
that it wasn't just all on my shoulders
and just you know stoking wood stove so
basically in 2012 2013 I was stoking
wood stoves at midnight 3:00 a.m. 6:00
a.m. in the fall running a trim crew all
day you know working 16 hour days with
breaks and and the whole time I was just
like daydreaming about my dream
Greenhouse we knew that utilizing the
sun uh especially in Montana and the
summer it has huge benefits to not only
like you know turpine profiles and
quality but also from a a electricity
cost so having that
off-grid background really put some
ideas in my head but I was just
daydreaming of my dream facility you
know how am I going to build it it's
going to be run from an app I'll be able
to control everything from my phone
which led us to this Wadsworth system
I'll have a team that I can rely on that
has a specialist in every category and
basically I was daydreaming and planning
um my dream facility while working way
way too many hours in the old days and
in 2017 the Cannabis industry in Montana
changed such that you had to have a
dispensary and produce everything on
your own you couldn't do any um third
party uh sales or anything like that and
also they forced us to basically have to
have a dispensary if we're going to have
a grow so we started our first
dispensary um that year there was also a
Cannabis Cup uh where we entered a bunch
of our products in the Montana State
providers cup and we really dominated
that particular competition and uh the
the rest is kind of History it also
reset the industry in that the biggest
providers in the state at that time got
set back to three patients there was
some court cases and
essentially us little guys and the big
guys all got set back to the Finish or
to the start line again and we got to
all start with three patients and once
that court case went through the people
who had a 5year head start on me were
down to the same amount of patients as
me and and we were Off to the Races and
we had a you know really good product
and that ended up being one of the best
jump starts for our our business to be
able to build so we also bought a 38
acre property here in Boseman that year
and started designing it from scratch
the very first Greenhouse we built was
just um treated lumber and kind of a
little house style that we that had
worked really well as far as light
deprivation manual light tarping on on
my old farm and we built that to tide us
over while we brought power in and did
everything and I started working on
getting a hold of Nexus which was our
first uh automated light depth system
green houses and Nexus were the first
two and now we've got two 3,000 ft
nexuses or 12,000 ft Nexus facility and
we've got another 12,000 ft NextGen
facility that we built in
2021 and we basically just started
building and because we were on a budget
and we had to build the first 3,000 ft
greenhouse and a uh mom room and
Warehouse head house connected to it
that forced us to design as we went and
while in many ways that was a hindrance
because we had to build on a budget in
other ways we were able to learn a lot
of lessons as we uh expanded our
facility and we did actually leave our
footprint um blank enough that we could
expand into it and yet learn from our
mistakes as we went and that was a huge
benefit because if you would have given
me $8 million in 2018 and said hey build
out this facility today I think I would
have made a lot more mistakes it was
actually a really big benefit for us to
just um build and design and evolve as
we go um so first we started building
the facility at the same time we started
building our team and the dream facility
coupled with what is now the Dream Team
you know the first one of the first
employees I ever hired was Danny uh on
the cultivation side and you know you've
met Danny you know his ability to
innovate and design and you know he
picked up where I left off as far as I
had lots of great ideas but my welding
skills were maybe a little weak or my
ability to form unistra
into anything in the world so like that
was the beginning of like the Dream Team
and as we moved on we grew and hired on
at the time it wasn't even Specialists
what we really learned from that was in
many ways it's better to have a blank
slate somebody without a ton of grow
experience um because a lot of times all
they've built is bad habits especially
in the days of misinformation and you
know big ego and bad habits don't make
for
um receptive uh Innovative team a good
team is one that is humble and can um
see the error of their ways or change
their minds when presented with new
information and so uh not that we don't
have some Growers uh some experienced
Growers on the team but a lot of
them they had that that quality of uh
humility and and willingness to learn
and change especially because a lot of
them came from the hydro background with
that being said they also brought some
good Innovation to my side to from a uh
dosatrons and plumbing and you know
basically
having good uh Sops and some cleanliness
and some some facility management system
so I guess that really helped form the
Dream Team uh there was a short period
where I was getting some good employees
from another facility that ran a pretty
tight ship but uh at the time my motto
was you train them we retain them
because we were nicer people and and a
lot of people really enjoyed the enjoyed
the uh living soil concept and even just
not working in indoor rooms which at
that time was all High Press sodium you
know what I mean like it it messes with
your eyes it's not as fun versus on a
nice on a 40 below winter day when it's
cloudy being in a nice Greenhouse or or
sunny for that matter and being at 80°
is wonderful and also on a 95° summer
day like today my team's in there and
it's 78 degrees and both of those things
are kind of just it's it's nice they
they appreciate working in living soil
working the way these plants have
evolved so
yeah well you dropped a lot of gems
there that I want to go back and
highlight uh first off though big shout
out to Danny he uh he's amazing um I'm
so glad he's part of your team it was
wonderful to meet him and you uh both of
your Innovation and what you guys have
brought to this to Collective elevation
is really really fun to see and uh I
want to highlight a couple things that
you mentioned in there that I think
listeners really should should pay
attention to the first being uh that you
said that you built out the facility as
you went um I think that is huge because
you know when I built out my farm
granted it was a a little bit different
type of farm you know we were doing we
had an edible nursery and we did have a
greenhouse and things like that um I
made a ton of mistakes because it was my
first time doing it and there are a lot
of things that we learned that first
iteration that as we grew I was able to
improve on and I see a lot of facilities
that want to go big and they have these
massive you know aspirations which is
awesome um but they try to do it too
fast and I think starting small and
scaling as you learn where your pinch
points are and where you know mistakes
happen and there's there's so many I can
think of and I'm sure you probably have
a pretty long list too um I I think
that's a really good idea trial
something you may find that living soil
is not the way that you want to grow
because of you know for some reason or
another or you may find that uh you know
you set have a whole facility for
Hydroponics and then decide to go an
entirely different method of growing and
now a lot of your equipment is obsolete
you know I've seen that more than once
too you know where these places will
have hundreds of thousands or even
millions of dollars worth of obsolete
equipment because they completely
changed the technology and the way they
were growing so I think that's a really
good point did you want to add anything
to that yeah I think that um two things
we also built the facility when the
gting was good in the Cannabis industry
it was very profitable from 2017 to 2020
ironically during the medical days and
because my goal wasn't to make a million
dollars my goal was to design my dream
facility because I was passionate about
cannabis that that was a perfect
combination of like not being some
corporate entity I wanted the best
Greenhouse facility in the world that's
that's literally was the core driver
more than yeah more than money or
anything else just so we could get the
perfect facility and and so that we
could grow so that basically we could
scale without ever sacrificing quality
because I knew there was some like happy
medium there and um another thing that
really helped was I have an old living
soil facility shop that's kind of my
beater car my R&amp;D facility and that has
really uh helped a lot in that I've
never bought anything or enacted
anything large scale at the farm because
it's very expensive to make mistakes or
convert over or you don't even get good
accurate tests but I have some of the
first uh Grassroots living soil 4x4 beds
that they ever made went into that
facility in 2016 or 15
and that was of the first tester of
going from uh pots or inground wooden
beds to you know like Grassroots fabric
beds and that helped like oh well what
if we had a liner on here so that it
didn't dry out on the edges so much and
that helped we can give feedback to
these companies so there's a lot of same
with LED lights we never bought a single
LED light without first running a light
in my for light rooms so I have seven
forl light rooms there and being able to
test any new things and I don't care if
That's genetics we never brought new
genetics we we never took clones into
the farm uh in the old days even now I
Almost Do all feno hunting but we make
seeds there we make fenos hunting we do
all our feno hunting there if we get new
lights we test them there on a small
scale if we get new beds new soil
additions um new microbial products
literally everything is tested at that
R&amp;D facility uh first and that is fully
indoors so it's a little bit more um
less subject to seasonal variations and
and stuff like that so it really gives
you a good control and by no means are
we uh Advanced science scientists but
it's amazing what you can do with just
experimental room and and it's you know
it's it's cheap like I said it's the
beater car that we try everything before
we bring it to the farm and that's every
every single strain that's helped our
facility so
much I love that so it's functioning as
an R&amp;D space for you to trial anything
um I was just on the phone yesterday
with a a grower in Michigan and they
were getting some uh 250 gallon totes of
hydrate and one tote allows them to do
two applications on their plants uh on
scale it's expensive um to enact
something so you have to really and I
realize if you're a home grower in a
tent you know like the cost per plant is
is not as much of a factor but I think
thinking about this in the same manner
allows you to be more efficient um you
know you can spend your money spend your
time doing other things and maybe those
other things or scouting your plants um
or maybe it's just enjoying your room
but um having to spend your time on
labor doing things that you don't
necessarily want to do um you know or or
having to make more applications of
whatever is is time and on scale I know
especially for you that just doesn't
work so having testing things out and
then also having a quarantine space
essentially is what you're using that
for for all genetics and things like
that is is an awesome suggestion we
recommend it to every facility I look at
when I see a design like where where is
your your you know your quarantine space
um and offsite is even better so that's
that's a really good point um the other
thing I want to highlight is you
mentioned that you like hiring blank
slates and I I love that I think getting
people with a Horticultural or botney
background but maybe not in cannabis
allows you to really uh shape them to
what uh you know what you want what your
goal or vision is at Collective because
I see too many ego in this industry
where people come in and they they want
to change things and add a lot of
variables and uh it makes it challenging
I think I think we can all learn from
each other but at the same time you know
they've got to be able to enact your
vision you know in a in a with a
positive attitude yeah y 100% that's
that's been crucial building that team
and and when you build that team even
having uh We've we've over the last few
years become an EOS company which is uh
that's more of a business thing
entrepreneurial operating system it's an
operating system for our business and
that that highlights a first of all
there's a accountability chart so that
it lines out who's in charge of what
particular task uh within the facility
because you don't get to this scale uh
by running everything yourself or being
able to uh micromanage every single
aspect at a certain point you have to
trust people and even if you trust them
and they're amazing you still need to
have a really good outline of their
expectations and duties and one of the
first things you do on that
accountability chart is you you write
out the seat you write out all the
duties associated with that seat and
then you find out does this person uh
get it want it and have the capacity to
do that particular task and if they
don't then what you have is a sacred cow
um and when you get to that sacred cow
mentality you know like too many sacred
cows that are basically not contributing
to the greater good not on the same path
and then also getting your team to
actually understand what your one three
and five year goals as a company are cuz
so many people they're just winging it
they're just out here surviving and and
I don't blame them because compliance
and economics and taxes it beats you
down I spend I I mean all I want to do
is go grow cannabis too and I spend 80%
of my time now doing meetings with
accountants and and you know but and my
team as well um but we have five
dispensaries and a lot of my stuff even
though where I came from as cannabis and
growing is now business and Retail and
really stuff that it's hard for me to be
passionate about so building out that
team um showing them what you expect and
that so many people are so used to like
oh I came from this other girl and we
just do dabs all day where's your dab
table are you kidding me no there's no
smoking in this facility we're we are a
a lean mean professional machine and
that's you don't become the best by like
just kind of limping your way through
life so like actually having high
expectations and uh duties and
putting people uh pairing their skills
with the seat in your company and when
it's small when you have good people
they have uh awesome positions to grow
into and as you get bigger then you know
all those seats are dialed all their
expectations are there but just like
having a little bit of intention and
getting your entire team paddling in the
right direction um you know and and at
any given time they actually know like
what our plan is and what our goals are
what our mission is a company is and um
what our values are and that no matter
what happens we're not going to break
our ethics we are a living soil
sustainable organic facility
so everything else being equal we don't
break that we don't um any time where
there's a cost benefit analysis run and
maybe there's something that's real
questionable whether it's um really
worth it ties always going to go to
sustainability in the environment if
we're using you know these new cubes
that we trial and we get 5% better
results out of them this like PR
preforma cubes which we've been recently
running the side by side with they are
they're great they're pre-charge are
wonderful but they come in plastic trays
every single one and 3,000 take up a
whole pallet instead of taking up uh a
little box versus like rocker Peak Cube
so basically having the team on board
with what your ethics are and what your
goals are really really helps everyone
helps you steer the ship away from
icebergs and and it's more important now
than ever because it's tight out there
you know in the Cannabis
industry yeah and I have to give you a
compliment there um there's very few
people that I I've met in this journey
you know through this industry that can
that can transition from being a grower
to running a running a business
essentially a corporation at this at
this scale uh I personally found I don't
have that skill I'm not good at managing
Personnel um when I had a farm as it
grew larger things got a lot more
scattered because I didn't have the the
staff couldn't see that Vision because I
hadn't uh you know elucidated it very
well um they didn't have delineated
tasks there was just kind of a list of
tasks so having that that accountability
and that
transparency and that Vision all really
well L laned out is is I think one of
the key components to a successful
company um and I I think that it's
amazing that you're able to do that a
lot of times I found with small
businesses you have to bring in someone
for that next stage of growth it's
rarely the founder that's able to
continue on because they don't have
those same skills like you could be an
incredible grower but you may not be
good at managing you know 100 people uh
they're very different skill sets so um
kudos to you in that regard um did you
want to add to that because I I was
going to trange change topics here and
start talking about uh climate and the
weather in Montana but did you want to
add anything else around personnel
before we move on um as far as building
a team um no I
mean that's that's the core thing is
just keep an open mind have good
expectations and yeah those were um that
transition that you just mentioned were
expensive lessons I'll say that it I had
to uh learn the hard way and thank God
that the getting was good as we our
timing was just at a certain point lucky
because I could do the exact same thing
I I used to work a lot physically now I
work just a lot and not physically and I
could have the same exact mentality now
and try and be doing the same thing that
I was doing 10 years ago and I wouldn't
stand a chance today you couldn't evolve
fast enough and you couldn't overcome
those mistakes so like there's some luck
involved there too um you got to really
really care and at a certain point now
I'm dug in this is my life I'm in so I'm
not like if I have to evolve to save
everything to the company like that's
what you do um but but there's some luck
there and you just recognize that timing
was crucial for us
but no that's it that's all and and I
just to add one last point there is I
think treating your staff really really
well if you get the right person um
taking care of them and making sure that
they're that you they they're sharing
your passion for the work that they're
doing and that they are uh enjoying
their life that that they're creating at
this facility I think is is a huge part
of the success and just the overall
mentality and energy around the farm and
I saw that when I was there yeah yeah
our culture is amazing and now really
has been and a little bit that was luck
a little bit of that was passion and
also because we live in Boseman Montana
so like I definitely want my people to
enjoy their life on their days off if
they're out there skiing uh or mountain
biking or camping or whitewater rafting
they're more likely to come into uh if
you're stoked on life you're more likely
or passionate about life or getting
after it you're a lot more likely to be
passionate about your job as well and so
it's a little bit harder to uh maintain
that for me now as like to some degree
the crews start keep staying the same
age and I'm I'm like uh now I've got a
family and uh you know I I have the the
core team that has come with me the
whole way but like you know there's a
little bit more turnover in trimmers and
butt tenders and whatever and
you I I'm not like having beers with the
crew or partying with the crew after
work as much as because I have two kids
in a family and I try and like so it's a
little harder to maintain that culture
but luckily I think that my team my
leadership team does a good job of
carrying that torch and that culture has
has carried us a long ways um and and
it's awesome that you can recognize that
because it's like it's essential and you
can't buy that you can't buy that magic
um something goes wrong at 4M on a
Friday you find a spot of mil do does
your IPM guy go home and tell you on
Monday or does he roll up his sleeves
stay late and and uh deal with that
problem right now before it's a huge
huge problem like you can't buy that
kind of accountability and that's where
you lay out those core values uh are
team has core values and one of them is
like accountability doing the right
thing with no one when no one is looking
and sustainability is a core value of
our company and when people know that
you can you can I mean we hire and Fire
based off of our core values um and part
of that is Passion you know anyways
that's that's all awesome no that's
great advice I love that and I hope uh I
hope other people can have the same
success in that regard too because I do
I I do I I can walk into a facility and
usually tell pretty quickly just from a
few hos and and handshakes what the
energy and the uh culture is at that
facility and and no one wants to work
somewhere where it's you know dark and
gloomy and the owner's always pissed off
and you know no one's happy with the
yields and so it all ties together and I
think creating a good environment goes a
long way to creating good plants so
that's that's a really good point about
the human component um but let you you
talk you mentioned Boseman let's talk
about Boseman what's the weather like
there year round um I think of Montana I
just think of harsh extreme climate what
uh what are you guys dealing with there
yeah it's interesting today's I think 97
degrees uh and what probably 10% R it'll
be or or even maybe a little drier than
that at the peak um we had a 100 mph
wind storm roll through Missoula last
night luckily it didn't hit Boseman or
my outdoor crop would have been
annihilated so uh we that actually just
missed us but that's touch and go um
last winter we had a week of uh it hit I
think 48 Below in Boseman 50 Below in
Montana so we have a 150 degree
differential um and that is a huge
challenge for us as far as um we have
basically of the Four Seasons we have
three distinct ones as far as in the
green houses are concerned and that's uh
you know spring and fall are very
similar as far as the challenges we Face
uh summer and winter and all of those
three distinct um phases have different
settings and parameters for the brain on
our Wadsworth and that forces us you
know like Danny's been working on like a
master facilities calendar of when do we
close up our wet wall when do we start
using in the middle of summer I'm not
using the roof vents because I don't
want bugs to come in but in the spring
and fall and winter that's hopefully the
bulk of what I'm using to vent the
greenhouse so that 150° differential
adds a ton of I would say excitement but
I don't it's not that fun for me
anymore yeah what are some of the the
key points that you like things that
that you have to deal with when you have
say let's just start since it's summer
right now what what are the challenges
and how do you overcome them with this
heat and low
humidity you mentioned a wet wall for
example yeah one of my biggest fears is
just uh power outage on the hottest day
of summer or the coldest night of winter
winter um those are those things are
very scary to me because it doesn't take
long so one of the first or best
insurance policies we finally just
hooked up a a large uh natural gas power
generator backup generator now it
doesn't run the whole facility but it
runs all the crucial
functions to limp us through uh 40 below
night at midnight for eight hours you
know I.E all the heaters and the mom
room lights and you know a couple of you
know just the the skeleton Essentials of
survival and it will also run the light
depth curtains so that I can close the
curtains and run a couple of exhaust
fans with a wet wall on the hottest day
of the year so the wet wall is
absolutely essential I mean our our
green houses are
basically 78 to 83 degrees year round
summer and winter and um you know
there's a moving Target there where
you're you're actually in the summer all
summer you're doing a cooling mechanism
so you let it get up to 81 and then you
cool it down to 78 versus in the winter
you let it heat up naturally to 83 and
then you just exhaust it so basically
you're you're heating up versus cooling
down and you're letting it rebound
naturally in the summer back up and in
the winter you're heating it up and
letting it cool naturally down and all
you can never really hit not only do we
have a ton of microclimates Within These
green houses um which is a challenge in
and of itself and something that's kind
of hard to understand or even like
really measure because usually our
Wadsworth brain system just measures a
few key points in the green it doesn't
have uh that's one of our future goals
is to have eight parameter points where
you can actually measure that
differential in microclimates throughout
the whole greenhouse and and we've made
some progress there in the past and then
like life gets busy so in the summer you
know that temperature is a huge uh issue
right now Danny's actually hooking up um
misters as well because one of our our
big goals in all of our transitional
periods from the Clone room to the vedro
um you want to Mass those parameters for
a couple of days as you transfer down so
if you've got 90% humidity in the Clone
room you want to have 85% humidity on
day one as you transplant those clones
and slowly phase it down a little bit
and then get it down to that you know
70% in the vegro well then you need to
have as you transplant into the greenh
houses you want to have a super high
humidity in there to basically reduce
any opportunities for transplant shock
so one thing in the summer that we found
now for the most part it's amazing how
living soil is so
um has it provides such a wonderful
buffer um you'd be amazed at how many
times my hoop houses that don't have
very much control at all uh it almost
seems like VPD isn't that important when
you have a big deep living soil bed
because those plants can just absorb 5%
humidity and they'll be praying I've
I've regularly outperformed my really
really nice green houses with all the
bells and whistles with a simple hoop
house and just natural summer and it
doesn't make any sense cuz your VPD is
way off but but that living soil buffers
that to an incredible degree um
but if you're talking about you know
really getting down to the economics of
it and if you're trying to shave days
off your cycle um for example we in the
Clone room they're going to spend you
know 11 to 14 days in the bedroom
they're going to spend 14 to 18 days and
then we're going to transplant them from
the bedroom into our flowering green
houses they're going to have like um 10
to 14 days in in a vegetative growth in
that Greenhouse well if I want it 10 and
not 14 I need to have the least amount
of um stress involved in that transition
so that they can hit the ground running
so little things like having misters to
you know match the proper VPD that they
were at is going to really shave that
off and and for a while there this is
actually something that David Peron uh
when we finally brought in a consultant
uh kind of helped me think before I was
always thinking um
can I afford this should I spend
$112,000 on uh these systems and he kind
of helped me think because a lot of
times I don't have anyone to B bounce
the financial aspects off of that's kind
of what the buck ends here as far as
being an owner before you're talking
about quality consistency labor
reduction with your crew but you're not
talking about like yeah the the cost
benefit analysis of it and David helped
me like all right I'm thinking can I
afford $10,000 right now for a Mis
system well if you shave five days off
of your veg cycle in your flowering
greenhouse and you've got four green
houses and you've got so basically four
and a half Cycles a year you're looking
at shaving um you know 20 days you're
getting 20 extra days of of utilization
and flowering in a greenhouse times four
greenh houses that $10,000 could equal
80 $90,000 a year you can't afford not
to do that and and just like flipping
that mentality on its head of
like oh boy I don't want to spend 10
grand right now but I don't want to lose
out on um 20 days of of productive
growth over the course of the year so
like like just changing your mindset of
how to think about these things has been
really um extremely helpful to
me yeah the biggest place I see that is
with uh upgrading lights from HPS to
LEDs people are like oh man I can get
these HPS so cheaply um and when you
switch over to LEDs a lot of times when
we do the math with some of these
Growers it's like your your savings on
the electrical bill
within two three Cycles will have
covered the cost of the lights and now
you're just saving you're just saving
money um but it's that mentality switch
like you said of you know what you're
currently doing what's looking ahead at
the future and looking at your cost you
know cost benefit analysis I think is
really important yeah that's that's a
great Point um going way back you
mentioned wet walls can you describe a
wet wall though for people who may not
be familiar with the term I wasn't
familiar with it uh you know coming from
the Seattle area it's nothing that I had
ever had to incorporate into my
Greenhouse yeah it's essentially a
radiator for a car what it does is it
it's a cardboard wall that uh runs water
uh through this cardboard wall and it
draws air across it so all of our green
houses are staged to have you know your
first exhaust fan going to go on at this
temperature and then one degree higher
your second exhaust fan is going to go
on then your third uh step is that water
is going to start your pad pump will
turn on which will run water through so
basically this is just a cooling
mechanism it's um a lot of people refer
to them of as a swamp cooler it's a you
know it's just a air conditioning uh
it's a swamp cooler is what it is so and
they don't work everywhere now Seattle
Florida you know basically the Montana
is absolutely perfect for wet walls the
higher your temperature and the lower
your humidity the more cooling benefits
you're going to get so I can have 108°
here and I can have my Greenhouse I bet
I could get it down to like maybe even
into the 60s you know what I mean I can
have a 30 30 plus degree temperature
differential just because of that wet
wall um now I think combined with
misters I know a few other green houses
here in Montana that don't have wet
walls but they have misters and they
also use shade curtains um which there's
don't give me I don't think that's the
best method but the mis's also uh
combined to help with that Cooling and
of course increasing the humidity and
getting your VPD in check but um the
hotter it is and the drier it is the
more effective your uh wet wall is going
to be but Montana is literally the dream
climate for wet wall efficacy so that
that's what a wet wall is and and it's
crucial otherwise our green houses I I
guess I shouldn't say crucial because I
do have hoop houses without wet walls
that are probably 100 degrees right now
and man they're happy too um but that's
because of living soil if I was in a
hydro system they would not be happy
with having hot Roots like that you know
what I mean um and we have found that
not having or having raised beds that
tap into the ground in in a hoop house
will really even um improve that the
more they can like the more those roots
can be cool the more they can handle
those um high temperature and low
humidities but the wet wall is is not
only crucial to our operation but it
also in increases your humidity a little
bit so that brings you closer to VPD
with that being said there's you know
too much out of the Year where I don't
stand a chance of keeping VPD and that
is like you know that July August time
where I can't get it humid enough
although if you check back when those
misters are in I might finally be there
we'll
see cool cool that's awesome um one
thing that I thought of as you were
explaining that and talking about uh the
wet wall was the um the the the tubing
that you use to to move large volumes of
Air ac across the entire beds I came
back to myig grow and people have asked
me like hey what are those tubes that
you have in the bottom of your beds and
I'm using Greenhouse convection tubing
um you actually are using a commercial
product I couldn't get that commercial
product um on the scale of you know an
R&amp;D room uh they just don't sell you
know 10 foot sections of it uh at an
affordable price so I'm using Greenhouse
convection tubing for anyone listening
but can you talk a little bit about that
the uh I think they duck socks was the
name of the company that you went with
yeah I believe that's correct um that
was another this is kind of the
beautiful uh you know props to Danny for
coming up with that because that was
another scenario where I was using floor
fans to increase air flow uh sometimes
during the winter with microclimates we
were having mildew issues and so I was
just adding more floor fans and more
dehumidifiers the first year and when
times were good I was just adding um
yeah basically oh let's put up another
dehumidifier well at a certain point you
got to stop throwing money at it and you
got to start like really addressing the
root of the problem um which is doesn't
matter how many dehes I put in here I
don't seem to be fixing this issue and
the issue was airf flow
and so at that time we had a higher
plant count per canopy we were doing um
I think 12 or nine plants per 4x4 bed
and we basically had a middle row of
plants so we had three on the either
side and then three down the middle well
we reduced our plant count we found that
we didn't actually lose any um time on
our veg cycle and that also opened up a
little aisle down the middle the idea
was that we needed a little bit more we
and we also increased our um
pre-transplant pruning or our
post-transplant pruning and our 21-day
leafing and and pruning events to reduce
transpiration uh increase under canopy
air flow and it still wasn't quite
enough it did help solve the problem but
we were still having like I think dead
spots Under The Canopy and so you know I
once again you POS the problem to the
team and Danny's like well what about
these I was like uh we were originally
thinking about putting those kind of in
the upper parts of the the greenhouse
but then they block light and there's
all these issues with that
and with our new lowered plant CR and
our increased pruning there's a
beautiful aisle right there under the
green houses it was like all you know so
Danny kind of came up with that uh cep
and design and another potential
subsidiary benefit of that is because
those uh and if you want we could post a
picture and the um and exactly what
company those are uh on this website if
you remind me I'll have Danny get you
all that information so people know but
it's also sucking up air right off the
ground so if the CO2 is sinking in there
you're actually kind of running like CO2
Rich uh fresh air through those duck
socks and you're getting nice even um
air flow all the way through the lower
canopy and I would say that took us
another a good chunk of the way to
solving our problem and it was actually
a pretty cheap and Innovative solution
that that was a that was a really nice
one it worked really
well yeah I know um going back in time
here from talking to Clack ofis cute if
when he was talking about his favorite
facility design it would be air moving
upwards from the ground up and then from
talking to Dr Nadia SAA uh Dr Green
house really the airflow expert in the
industry she had also talked about how
using uh airf flow like this so these so
picture for people who are listening
picture like a 8 or 12 in uh ducting
like you would use you know to to duct
your your house or your your grow and
then make it out of fabric or in my case
make it out of plastic with two 45°
holes angled up and then a a big 8 in or
12-in fan
moving the air through that giant tube
so it's it's diffusing a large amount of
air across across a large area Under The
Canopy uh at a very high volume but low
uh velocity um and so you don't get um
calcium issues in terms of like too much
evapo transpiration but you like you
said you're getting the CO2 pushed back
up into the stomata which is where you
want it um and it gives you it removes a
lot of those micro Pockets it has a lot
of potential benefits so I hope that
describes it and we can we can post
photos for sure yep that yeah that that
microclimate it definitely helped uh
eliminate microclimates within the
greenhouse because anytime you have a
big room it's not all consistent all the
way across it's colder near the wet wall
or the intakes and it's hotter on the
other side and you uh you know you're
going to have a harder time getting your
dehumidified air which you know
obviously isn't a this time of year but
in the winter you've got different
cycles and different needs uh summer to
Winter getting that dehumidified air
evenly spread out across the greenhouse
is a whole uh I mean that's a whole
Topic in and of itself and then like you
said uh it does it makes those Leaf St
just perfectly not so that you're over
transpiring or or getting dry spots but
also so that every plant is getting that
fresh air and hopefully CO2 enriched
fresh air because those beds produce so
much CO2 um and the the where they draw
it uh that's another thing too is before
we actually put more dehes in and before
we put those duck socks in we switched
from vaf fans to HF fans in a circular
manner that was like the actually
backing up even before any of that the
first thing we did was reconfigure our
airf flow uh with oad fans so vertical
vaf is vertical air flow and HF is
horizontal airf flow can you just touch
on that for people who may not be
familiar with these Greenhouse terms
yeah yeah so the those vaf fans they
they basically suck up in a mushroom
cloud if you were to use a fog machine
which I've always daydreamed about
renting a party fogger and just watching
the air flow in my green houses and we
never really we use our our dram fogger
but it doesn't quite produce a drastic
enough um you know it's it's not drastic
enough that we can like really uh watch
but I've always rent thought about just
getting a good party fogger and really
nailing down where there's dead spots in
your Greenhouse you know what I mean but
sucks up and through and creates this
mushroom and the idea is as the air
comes from the in our case I guess the
West the East Side the air is coming in
from the intakes and it's getting
circulated in this mushroom pattern
slowly across the greenhouse uh touching
every single leaf surface but not so
much that any single plant is getting
blasted uh HF is just like you know like
a standard uh box fan and we don't have
standard box fans of course but um
they're they're big circular airflow
fans and they're all positioned uh kind
of in a circular pattern around the
greenhouse so you've got three just
slightly offset on the north side of the
greenhouse that blow to the west and
then there's three on the east side that
blow to the East and it creates this big
circular pattern above the canopy once
again not lasting anything like a
racetrack exactly um now in a perfect
world I have recently seen a a seed
potato Farmers Nexus Greenhouse where he
actually put his wet wall below the
greenhouse his entire Greenhouse was um
metal grading uh his floor his entire
floor was metal grading so he's got a
wet wall and then you have roof Vents
and and vaf fans vertical air flow so
basically your wet wall is going in
under the floor it's percolating up
through the entire canopy slowly because
heat rises as a air flow is Heating and
then it's just going out the roof vent
and it was like oh my God if I could
redesign I might consider that you know
um it's it's a pretty neat uh concept
you know I don't know as to its efficacy
I don't have any experience with it but
it was a cool design liked it a lot
um we basically in the winter we
typically are doing a little bit more so
we have two green houses that are vaf
fans and we have two green houses that
are HF and you know there's kind of two
schools of thought there either you're
mixing and stirring it in that racetrack
pattern or you're just letting the warm
air percolate up nicely through the
leaves and then out the roof fence and
you know jur is still out they both work
neither is
wrong um but I haven't found strong
enough evidence to like convert the
other ones over from my original design
also it's a slightly smaller Greenhouse
that's another uh problem that popped up
is I built the two new green houses to
be 4200 square fet and that actually
that bigger Greenhouse that wider
designed made it harder for me to get
that dehumidified air over to the other
side of the greenhouse but if I put the
dehumidifiers on that side then that
blocks out that Southern Exposure sun
and in the middle of winter you need
every bit of sun you can possibly get um
so there's all these little uh every
time you increase your scale or increase
the size of facility you come up with
completely new problems that you
couldn't possibly have foreseen um yep
hence why it's better to build out
slowly
exactly
um yeah so one of the things you
mentioned was Co 2 let's talk about that
because you mentioned their beds are
creating an incredible amount of CO2 how
do you manage
CO2 in your green
houses yeah
so first this is a kind of an
interesting thing so living soil facil
we do have a CO2 burner in every single
one of our green houses they maybe get
used two months a year um for the most
part we rely on the CO2 that the
microbial action in the soil is
producing so when we have an empty
Greenhouse when I harvest I will get
over a thousand parts per million um
built up in there and we get super high
nighttime co2's CO2 concentrations
because that soil is producing so much
CO2 on its own um now during the day two
things in the summertime there's no
point in running uh we have an influence
set with our wwor system our our control
system our Greenhouse controller so that
when an exhaust fan turns on the CO2
burner turns off because there's no
reason at a certain point you're it's a
drop in the ocean if you have the amount
of uh exchange rate that our greenh
houses have on a hot summer day um as
far as like uh freshening the air it's
probably got new air in it every minute
so you're not um there's really no
reason to run CO2 there um and at that
point even whether the soil is keeping
up so basically in the summer we're not
running any CO2 at all um in the winter
we were running CO2 for a long time
using those CO2 burners but what we
actually found was during the coldest
month of the year in Montana when we
actually have the least um par levels
from the
sun we might be just a little underlit
with our LED lights um in the winter see
I'm trying to Stage it to the lowest
common denominator now I have too much
light in the summer and I don't have
quite enough light as if as compared to
If I Were a full indoor grow room in the
wintertime but I usually am able to
utilize the sunshine 90% of the summer
my lights are completely off and I'm
only using the Sun and 40 or 50% of the
winner that's the same as
well what basically ends up happening
there is if I run CO2 too much in the
winter time when I actually have it's
that limiting factor you know what's
that um what it maso's law the the the
bucket concept have you ever seen the
barrel analogy of there's always going
to be some limiting factor there and
yeah your plants can only perform to
their highest uh potential based on
whatever the limiting factor is and so a
lot of times in the winter when I feel
like I need the um CO2 I actually am a
little bit underlit especially for that
January February run and that's kind of
like um using nitrous when your car is a
old jalape you know what I mean you're
you're not ready to really hit the gas
and you actually end up getting some we'
we've actually Rec called you with some
problems a few years ago where I
couldn't figure out I was having some
unusual uh Fox tailing and growth
patterns and I believe it was because I
was
essentially using CO2 when I was
underlit and therefore the plants
weren't really like Max know you don't
need uh a th000 parts per million CO2 if
your par is too low uh it doesn't really
uh make sense there so we do use CO2 in
the winter but a lot of times it's
actually more that um November December
when it's sunny and spring um before the
before it heats up for the day before
the exhaust bands are on those first
couple hours of the morning in say March
April that's when we're actually turning
the CO2 burners on I haven't even seen
that much uh Effectiveness there I
believe basically I could run my CO2
burners and I could even get my
Greenhouse up to a thousand my my living
soil beds outperform a CO2 burner on co2
production um when there's a greenhouse
that's empty you can never quite tell
CO2 production when the greenhouse is
full because those plant PL are actively
uh you know breathing it as you go so
you can't really ever
tell yeah so uh I had to double check it
was it's Lee Big's law of the minimum
that's there we go that's the one you
were thinking of and and people if you
can imagine a bucket with a bunch of
holes in it and basically you're you're
plugging the holes to figure out what
the limiting factor is and so if it's
lighting don't worry about your
fertility fix your lighting if it's your
VPD then you got to fix that before you
look at you know fertility or lighting
and so all of these things are related
and you're constantly as a grower trying
to figure out what your limiting factor
is it's a really good uh perspective
when you approach a grow and it's
something I always do when I walk into a
new grow is I think about what's the
limiting factor is it the watering the
fertility the lights the VPD the air
flow all of these things so yeah that's
a good point um getting back to the CO2
though uh do you find that you need to
vent CO2 during nighttime hours in order
to not get excessively high
CO2 no I we this this was an uh ongoing
argument about four years ago whether it
was worth um what well in the winter
time is when that happens um and in the
summer it doesn't seem to happen quite
as much because I guess I just don't
know why it just doesn't really um I
guess probably because also in the
summertime we're still exhausting some
air at night anyways but but typically
in the winter
time I don't want to ever lose any of my
heat you know what I mean I don't want
to ever exhaust so I have uh limit set
with my Wadsworth system where you know
depending on the if you're in veg or
flower but so after 7 P.M I my exhaust
fans are all locked out for the night
they won't exhaust um for a while there
um a former cultivator of mine Chad
who's a really really knowledgeable guy
we were having this ongoing discussion
or maybe argument about whether we
should be exhausting that CO2 at night
and for a while I did but what ends up
happening is Technically when your
heaters run they're producing some CO2
too you know I mean so like basically
I'd exhaust it out and because nothing's
transpiring but the green houses are
still it just replaces it right away but
then I'm running my heaters and I'm just
exhausting warm air which you know our
utility bills are high enough in the
winter I never saw any evidence that a
th000 PPM CO2 at night um had any
negative issues and then watching like
um j plant speaker or argue with people
on Instagram years ago where he was like
turning them on an hour or two in the
dark he's turning on a CO2 burner so
that that first hour or two of morning
when those plants are starting to
transpire they have this high CO2 I've
never seen any evidence that like the
kind of CO2 that living soil produces at
night um has had any negative impacts to
me but I haven't done a ton of extensive
research on it because it's also pretty
costly and we have great at the end of
the day if I have a great harvest then I
don't worry about like those it's it's
only when I start to have bad
experiences that I start to like look
for the problem and if if it it's that's
never been the common denominator is
nighttime CO2 so I don't worry about it
and I don't exhaust it at night anymore
um I just assume that first thing in the
morning those plants are going to have
really good CO2 levels until the first
exhaust bands KCK
gone that's that's great I have seen
excessively high CO2 and I'm not talking
a th000 PPM I'm talking thousands of PPM
2,000 3,000 PPM of
CO2 um in some indoor facilities that uh
they were getting
weird weird growth and um the one thing
that did fix it was a nighttime venting
again indoor facility different
environment um alog together but um that
was and you know the size of the room
relative to the amount of soil is
probably a big factor there too as well
as how much respiration you're getting
yeah so volume of soil um so I just want
to bring it to people's attention as
something maybe to look for but I think
that's really great that you don't have
to do that and in your case because you
are greenhouse in the winter and you are
sacrificing all that heat you know you
you do have to make a a decision as to
whether or not it's worth it in this
case it doesn't sound like it is so
that's that's really good to hear
um yeah so I I just want to share a
Counterpoint of a different experience
but again this is why every every
facility is a little bit different and
everyone has um everyone needs to look
at their own facility specifically and
figure out what what the requirements
are there to be most successful because
it is it is always a constant uh balance
there so on one hand you need to you
want to maintain at least ambient CO2
what 420 PPM is sort of your our current
ambient air CO2 um so you need that air
flow exchange otherwise if you're not
getting enough CO2 from your beds or
let's say you're not running living soil
those plants are not going to have
sufficient CO2 especially if you're
running your ppfd at you know a thousand
or higher there's no point if there's no
CO2 in the room so there you need that
air exchange but if you're exchanging it
with really cold air and now you're out
of VPD range uh that's creating a
different problem so as a grower you
kind of have to think through these
things and really decide what makes the
most sense in your environment and in
your case it sounds like um
the environment is probably the biggest
Factor limiting factor for you because
you are forced to deal with these such
extreme conditions like how do
you I mean do you do you have a lung
room or you just force you don't really
have the ability to uh you know
condition the
air in the winter I assume in the summer
you're conditioning the air a little bit
possibly um through through the use of
your wet wall but what do you do in
terms of the air conditioning ideally in
the winter time I try and bring in as
little cold air as possible you know
like it's it's like this either for one
thing it does create a little bit of a
microclimate and some of the early
designs there so my wet wall is
completely sealed up so part of this
master facilities calendar is uh
sometime around November when the
hottest you know when you no longer have
temperatures above say 45 or 50 degrees
will go and we will put uh black white
black or you know double wall plastic
over all the wet walls um and we'll and
all the um black blackout uh breathable
walls on the other side of the Breezeway
so we also do have a Breezeway on the
exhaust side of every room that so that
I'm not just sucking all that warm air
out I'm actually putting it into the
Breezeway first um then you use your
smallest denominator fan so in the
winter time I might only use um roof
venting for my next gens and that's it
the only exhaust I don't bring any air
in I mean except for what obviously when
whenever you let air out some's going to
get sucked in but it just gets sucked in
through the cracks like you're just
exhausting hot air you're not actually
bringing cold air in um some of the
early designs of our so this is all a
staging question
so when it gets too warm and this is
there's three distinct Seasons like I
said summer fall count is one for the
greenhouse winter and summer the very
first thing to come on is our condensate
fan which is a very upper smallest fan
in the greenhouse and that's like above
the blackout curtains so
we've implemented so many different
trials to so first the condensate fan
will come on and that's way up there and
it has an opportunity it's above the vaf
fans so it has the opportunity to come
in and slowly stir a little at a time so
that you're not getting like super cold
on one side of the greenhouse and then
super hot on the other second if it's
too warm so you can you can have a zero
degree day and if it's sunny you're
still exhausting air and you're bringing
in cold air second the after that
condensate fan has exhausted its
potential which very rarely happens in
the winter you'll go to the Gable
exhaust fan that's stage two it gets to
83 degrees in the winter time Gable
exhaust fan comes on um the big exhaust
fans are now disabled for the winner you
never have to use those so when the
Gable exhaust fan comes on uh we have a
little uh ramp it looks like a
drawbridge and that's so that the Gable
exhaust fan kind of gets um jumped
essentially you picture this draw
drawbridge from a castle halfway up as
it comes in it gets kind of like guided
up into the upper parts of the
greenhouse and then once again
distributed via vaf fan so it doesn't
just sink right on and make those plants
closest to the Gable exhaust band uh
really cold um which also can lead to
like condensation and therefore Bud rot
you know when you have these really cold
um and then a really hot heater kick on
there's also um settings so that my
exhaust fan can't be on at the same time
as my heater is on and my team has to be
trained to we should be to have a
conversation in the greenhouse and
within five minutes if a exhaust fan
kicks on and then five minutes later a
heater kicks on someone on my team needs
to have that sick sense of like oh that
shouldn't be happening we should expand
our um differential you know we can make
our heaters kick on at 76 degrees or 77
and we won't have an exhaust until 83 or
even 84 if it's the middle of winter
therefore you get this nice yo-yo effect
where ideally depending on the
temperatures depending on the season the
heater will kick on and an exhaust band
will never kick on um that didn't fully
solve all of our problems we had
Wadsworth designed us a burp feature so
on those coldest days of the year where
you're not getting any sun um or you're
not getting any power from the Sun so
now your light depth curtains are
closing and it's acting as a basically
an indoor facility now and you're just
running 100% lights when those lights
actually the lights in the dehumidifiers
combined actually produce an amazing
amount of heat even when they're LED
lights and for 10 months out of the year
we really don't use heaters too much at
all or maybe a few times to heat it up
in the morning you know what I mean and
get to temperature but for the bulk of
the day our equipment is producing
enough heat that we're not venting that
it's carrying it so one of our first
steps on those cold days like when it's
we're talking 40 below during the day
and I don't care how much Sunshine we
have when it's 40 below those curtains
are closed I'm not taking that par
because I I'm heating too much in order
to to uh get that part so we had
Wadsworth and they're pretty awesome
about just like oh what's your problem
no one's ever had that before let's do
it they built us in a burp feature so
what'll happen is the curtains
themselves will burp 5% they'll open 5%
when it gets to 83 degrees or 84 degrees
and they'll just let a little bit of air
up into that upper canopy above and then
the then it just naturally um cools
because there's enough um heat loss
because it's a greenhouse
um that so that burp feature has given
us one more step in our there's a
staging process of the the lowest
minimum tool for the job so it's first
it's a roof vent then it would be like a
condensate fan then a Gable fan um and
if the curtains are closed and all these
things have override so they don't um
interact with each other I don't want if
my Gable exhaust vanand kicks on my roof
vent needs to close it means the roof R
is not doing the job we've got too much
light coming in or too much um passive
solar gain coming so and what I don't
want is my roof vent sucking my Gable
exhaust B kicks on and then sucks air
through my roof V now that could one
suck in bugs probably not because it's
winter time but also I'm not sucking air
across the room anymore I'm short circu
short circuiting all of this and I might
be just sucking air from the roof end on
the west side to the fan on the west
side and I'm actually not cooling at all
you know what I mean so so it's all the
staging system with the Wadsworth having
um parameters and set points and what we
call you know they um it's a what's the
word I'm looking for it's a a lockout
essentially uh Wadsworth will actually
program in so that like just like my
exhaust fan can't be on at the same time
as my heater if an exhaust F opens the
heater turns off if a roof vent is open
and an exhaust van kicks on the roof
vent will close so there there and it's
a series of staging and all of this has
taken years and you could take my exact
uh Sops for what my green houses are and
you could give them to someone and all a
sudden it's summertime well it's a
completely different mechanism and it's
completely different Sops or you could
give it to someone in Oregon or
Washington or Florida and none of that
would make any sense at all um it has to
be very much specifically tailored to
Montana and then Montana's Seasons
that's one of the biggest challenges we
face is that you know we have some
incredible sunlight in the summer and
incredible temperatures and then
everything is opposite in the winter and
just like um in many ways indoor rooms
controllability and and stability makes
growing easy but it also makes your
power bill High because a lot of these
guys I know are running air conditioners
in Montana in the winter time not us you
know what I mean our lights right now I
bet you there's except for the mom room
and the vedro there's hardly a light on
in my whole facility right now today my
power bill per unit is incredibly low
compared to any of my competitors here
in Montana and even my heating bill um I
think I only had a $800 natural gas
heating bill I shouldn't say only
because it's still expensive but for a
facility of this size in January when we
had a week of 50 below or a week of 40
plus below weather uh that's like
unbelievable and it shows you that my
both my light depth curtains work really
well and my equipment everyone's
equipment produces a lot more heat than
they think even when it's LEDs dehes and
and LEDs produce a ton of
heat so investing in the right
infrastructure has saved you a ton of
money and the right systems over the
last you know few years since you've
since youve build out this facility and
the other thing that I really want to
highlight is this idea of Sops because
people ask like what's the SOP for
growing you know and whether that's
around IPM or in this case the
greenhouse or uh fertility all of these
things um what you said is really
accurate you know every facility every
space has different challenges different
environment different things and so they
really need to be tailored customed to
that space you can't just take someone's
sop and run with it and think you're
going to have a successful grow it just
doesn't work that way there's no perfect
method or grow setup it's extremely
customized and part of that EOS ENT
operating system we were talking about
not only do we have Sops but we have
like a core processes uh that this this
all integrates the C the master calendar
with the core processes the Sops but the
core processes had a little bit more
room for um
philosophy and like you know like if
this then that you just uh you know
here's I just need to teach you the
concept and I also that also ties back
into having an amazing team that not
only can
understand they have the capacity to
understand like what is what are we
going for here not just this is the SOP
because the SOP changes from December to
July so drastically that my team has to
actually understand like what are we
going for here and then and then I mean
that's That's essential but yeah Sops
are very much different summer to Winter
and of course the other common
denominator there is um I had to obsess
over it for years I mean literally at
before when I was stoking wood stoves at
midnight 3 and 6:00 a.m. well on that 40
below night uh in January you better
believe if I wake up and go to the
bathroom I am looking at my app and I'm
watching that I I unfortunately can
never quite shed that and there's also
alarms built in so if the facility
temperature drops below 55° myself and
Danny get an alarm on our phones and the
alarm company actually calls us if it
gets above 88 we get a text then a phone
call um you know as soon and you don't
you want to set it so
that you know one wet wall is clogged
for one minute I don't need to get phone
calls all the time the second it hits 85
degrees but you set it just below that
parameter where it should never be which
is like I said 55 and 88 if it's we got
a problem and two of us are getting
phone calls after we get a text if
there's an issue and we're also like
prepping for during that 40 below week
you're watching the weather and we're
also putting in backups we're testing
our now now that we finally have a good
uh backup generator we're going to be
testing that but also we're going to
have staged out sunflower heaters with
propane next to every Greenhouse so that
in the off chance that the power does go
out and the backup generator doesn't
turn on you better believe I'll be there
at 3: in the morning and hopefully my
team set me up for Success cuz I'm not
trying to call them at 3: in the morning
I'll be there and I'll be lighting
heaters in those green houses and
hopefully those heaters are set there
and staged and ready that's like your
insurance policy you know what I
mean yeah yeah it's it's a lot and
honestly one of the things as a business
owner that uh is really challenging that
no one really talks about is the fact
that you never really get to shut off
even if you're on vacation even if
you're at home you know using the
bathroom at 2: in the morning you're
you're still thinking about your
business you're thinking about your
plants and uh you never really get that
mental break and I think that's that's
hard and a lot of people don't consider
that when they think about setting up a
new uh a new business like this or being
a business owner it's well and and
trying to explain that to the crew
because every day I would look at it as
I wake up and I take um basically I'm
going to get my butt kicked three times
I'm going to get three pieces of bad
news today I guarantee they could be
somewhere between $1,000 P pieces of bad
news or $10,000 pieces of bad news but
I'm getting the news and you can absorb
the first one even if it's the 10,000 or
the 1,000 you're like it's good it's all
good this was beyond your control
nobody's fault here um how do we solve
this how do we not have this happen
again but by the third one even if it's
the smallest one like all of your
ability to absorb bad news has now been
taken up and keeping your cool and and
having them understand that's also why
it's good that they know you because
they know that yeah sometimes you're oh
he's a dick today he's pissed off like
well geez you guys look of these three
things that happened to me today and I I
lost my ability to absorb it's my shock
absorbers you know what I mean it's all
good I'm in a great mood it's 9:00 a.m.
got some bad news no worries don't worry
about it but by like 3 o'clock piece
number five you're like are you kidding
me wait what happened it's so hard to
but having your crew actually know you
as a person and hopefully empathize with
that and then a little bit of that is
like actually telling them what you're
going through and of course apologizing
as best you can when um
when that does happen you're like hey
here's what was happening here's why
that happened here's what we're going to
do to fix that problem so it doesn't
happen again and now um rather than me
be responsible for that I'm going to
assign that to one of my team members
this is going out the accountability
chart and now this is your job and so I
want you to worry about it so that I
don't have to because I can only worry
about so many things um and now our team
with the evolution of our core processes
our Sops a team that truly cares and
just we have just such an amazing team
and somebody in each department that
cares and is accountable for all this
stuff but back in the old days the first
few years you could track all of our I
don't want to say we ever had anything
catastrophic happen but all of our
biggest disasters you could track them
for the first three years with they
lined up directly with my vacations the
first time I ever was in Alaska on a
camping trip out of reception literally
they it was like clockwork and and
that's no one's fault per se it was that
we didn't have systems in place and even
then the team cared but I didn't explain
to them those little things that I was
paying attention to in the middle of the
night or or even the concept of like oh
so many times the Cure is or the The
Cure is worse than the disease like oh
no we found aphid so we root drenched
everything with insecticidal soap like
wait we what now um You didn't do it we
did a new treatment on an entire
Greenhouse without triing it in a small
section
first who gave the go- ahead on that
while you were out of town [ __ ] okay now
it goes in the SOP anytime something new
happens and now at a certain point I
keep saying this and this keeps not
happening at this point my team's
probably just rolling their eyes but
like eventually there won't be any new
problems to have we'll have had all the
problems and so someone will know whose
job it is and we'll have a quiver of
options to solve that and eventually and
this is already happening as I've uh
phased into office life now I still do
my daily walkthrough every single day
but unless there's an emergency or a
large scale problem I'm into the office
and onto accounting and my team can
handle all of this stuff but back in the
old days it was two to three to four
hours of me being this now I have a
sawyer my IPM manager he's doing The
Scouting he's got the eye you can't buy
the eye you have to have the eye and the
only way to get the eye is years and
years of like developing the now I have
some people uh Jared too my the guy who
does all our soil fertility and stuff
um he came from you know a school
background and didn't have a ton of
cannabis experience but now just
recently he's been impressing Me by
finding stuff before I find it he's got
the eye now too you know what I mean
like I said you can't like um you can't
even you can teach it but you can't
teach it today you can't put it in an so
the eye has to come with time um yeah so
that's where
uh now I finally feel comfortable not
spending 3 hours a day talking to
everybody about uh theoretical growing
conceptual stuff if this then that um
that's another thing is the Instinct
that um you know if you listen to all of
the people that you've had on your
podcast you have an amazing resume of
some of the best people not just in this
industry but in the world from a science
perspective like it's unmatched
unparalleled me nor none of my people on
my team can hold the candle to those
guys' specific things but first first of
all they're willing to learn and listen
to what those guys are saying and then
there's something to be said about not
only that Steady Hand but there's an
instinct there's a this plant is healthy
and I know it and I don't care what you
say about uh if a Praying plant you guys
can argue all you want about whether
praying is bad or stressful for plants
but I know what it does to yield and I
don't really care about the science
behind it at a certain point I feel and
have seen and know the results um and
that's something that you can't really
like um
College doesn't teach that that standing
in a room with someone and being like
does it feel too humid in here you
that's like a feeling it's that six
sense it's that magic the ninja [ __ ]
that you cannot buy or or train into
people except by spending tens of
thousands of hours in a greenhouse and
and overcoming all these problems and
that's like my
team either they're there or they're
almost there I
hope yeah I love that uh and I think to
a team member that finds a problem and
then brings it to you along with some
potential
Solutions is worth a million times more
than a team member that just comes to
you with a problem um as as a business
owner that is priceless um and you may
not go with their solution and they need
to be okay with that because you may
have more information that they may not
have access to or you may have
experience in your facility that you
know they haven't had but being able to
talk it through with them and for them
to be able to bring insight to the
problem that you don't have is
absolutely the I think one of the most
important uh aspects of a of a team
member you're 100% te and then you you
have to have people obviously who are
smart competent and you know have common
sense but then even teaching them how to
think uh with that mentality and and
even throwing that throwing those
problems back to them like all right
well there's no easy solutions but yeah
come to me with these Sol just exactly
what said that's super essential is and
it also is empowering to them because
now they're not going to come to you
next time with just a problem they're
going to come with a couple of solutions
like you said you don't have to do it
but you've now empowered them uh
retrained them how to think and and
eventually they've already walked
through this system this process that
you've done a million times and and now
they do it without we don't even have to
bother him this time because he's busy
today because we only have three options
and it's either it's because of the
Season or the severity of the problem
but we know that this is our go-to this
is our first step this is our second
step if this problem progresses and then
this is our third step and they and then
hopefully as long as you're evolving
your Sops and core
processes you should write that new
problem in every time that is an issue
you got to like um not only fix it but
what if that person is um incapacitated
for a day what if they're sick that day
like you got to have like you got to
continue to evolve your Sops they don't
just stay put you have to to update them
regularly yes yes um all right the last
thing I want to touch on in this call is
the praying leaves thing because I think
um I I had no idea I was opening such a
can of worms and basically what happened
for people who missed it is on uh
Instagram I posted a photo of one of my
plants and it was praying what we call
praying leaves so let's call it a 45
degree maybe 60° Leaf Angle an upward
trajectory and I was I was speculating
that this might be a less than optimal
angle for like a solar panel for you
know photosynthesis and why would a
plant do this uh and everyone uh not
everyone a lot of people jumped on me
for that saying you know praying leaves
means your plant's healthy it's it's
related to uh the turer the pressure in
the leaf in the stem that creates that
angle and I wasn't arguing that it was
bad I was just trying to get behind the
mechanism of what might cause it and
basically what I learned in that process
is that many of the mechanisms around it
related to like hydrology and and things
like that are actually quite positive so
it can be a sign of a healthy plant but
I also have found that it may be a sign
of low CO2 and that plant is trying to
raise the leaf angle as a way of getting
more uh CO2 to the stomata or um I've
seen it with plants that are quite
unhealthy with tissue tests that show
they're very low infertility yet they're
still PR pring uh which just I think I
think the big consensus I came to was
that it's not
necessarily um there's many there's many
modes of action that can cause this
turgidity in the leaf many of which are
beneficial and many of which could be a
sign of plant stress so I think my big
takeaway was it's not necessarily a good
or bad thing it's a thing a plant does
in response to certain environmental
factors many of which are beneficial
some of which could be detrimental
but um yeah yeah I didn't mean to throw
you under the bus or open it was a good
chance to explain it yeah I just want to
like yeah sometimes because every grow
is different and everything you
know the soil doctor cannot give me or
you for that matter either exactly a
recipe for what my plants need in my
specific area at a certain point and
also if you bring in somebody who's way
more knowledgeable they can only do so
much if your plants don't have Baseline
Health well okay there's like 10 steps
we got to do before we even get to there
what are we going to progress but the
point is like there's no one gun quiver
there's no uh prescription to that fits
everything and sometimes I have to take
stuff that people that are far more
knowledgeable than me tell me with a
grain of salt like this plant might have
uh this this and this deficiencies and
you can tell because its leaves are
yellow but that doesn't mean the soil is
deficient that just actually means that
we underwatered it this last week and
it's not available you know you see all
this like we'll sit there and argue to
we blue in the face about what's wrong
with this plant and actually it's dry
you know could uptake the nutrients in
the soil that's a good point so I've
already taken a lot of your time I feel
like we could we could talk for hours I
would love to get you back on because I
just made a list of topics of things we
didn't even get to like fertility
irrigation drying curing genetics your
marketing and branding and also your IPM
those are all things I would love to get
uh a little bit of insight from you on
because I think what you shared today
was really great well and if that's the
case I'd love to uh get the team on
there because so my IPM manager has now
taken this picked up where I left off a
few years ago and not that I'm not um
involved in the weekly meetings and
conversations of what's going on but
he's really you know Jared has taken the
soil prescriptions and the soil tests
and he's taken it to the next level from
where I left off uh Danny obviously has
always taken the design engineering and
and um in Innovative nature of
facilities design
and not that him and I don't go back and
forth more than anyone on what we're
doing but uh he's really got I if if
we're going to do that I'm happy to
bring on different members of the team
or even parts of it uh you know what
what Connor's done in my propagation
Department uh what Alejandro and and
Kyle have done for the uh leafing and
harvests and efficiency and reducing
touch points and stuff like that and
then just all of them are I mean if you
think about it like Connor takes more
clones in a month than I've ever taken
in my entire life and yet you know I've
now grown I guess I don't know if you
don't necessarily give me credit for it
but tens of thousands of pounds of weed
but I haven't taken a clone that's not
true I do at my R&amp;D shop a little bit
but you know the point is like each of
my teammates or team members have done
each of their individual tasks a hundred
times more than me now and the only
thing that I do is
like keep tabs and stay informed on it
so if we want to get in depth on any one
of those topics I need to like bring on
the team because that's how you evolve a
facility like this is by letting and
just like any good businessman will tell
you you hire people that are better than
you and I'm not even saying all of them
were better but they are now holy cows
they're you know these guys are are you
know like I said they're snipers they're
rock stars and
they've got a lot of practice and I but
I would love to talk about like the R&amp;D
facility because I do a lot of cool
breeding projects and honestly a lot of
this other stuff is kind of it gets
monotonous compliance and the world and
stuff
all yeah people get into growing weed
because they think like oh I Love Weed
let's do it and it is it's exciting it's
fun but like there's still a ton of
repetition um my R&amp;D facility I still
get excited about going there every
single morning and check in and it's
still fun I still get to do the parts of
the job that I love cuz it the it's hard
to quantify or make that facility pencil
out even though it's pretty cheap to run
you know I might spend 150 or 200 Grand
a year with you know the salary the
power the rent
everything but God it puts a smile on my
face just like doing new breeding
projects and making seeds and and seeing
new fenos and and and also it doesn't um
beat me down oh we had a hermy and that
whole room got seated
Ah that's what it's for blast it you
know what I mean it doesn't you know
versus catastrophic failure in a large
scale Greenhouse so yeah uh I'm happy to
continue this conversation but I would
like to maybe bring on the individual
team members to give them their credit
and also so that you can actually go
down the rabbit hole um just even you
can't keep track of every single
treatment and every single thing at this
scale I I mean I can give you the
overview and the master calendar and I
can do everything but my people have now
really taking it to the next level and
and that's where you got to bring them
in or do like 15 minute segments with
each person or something of that nature
I I would love to set that up that would
be great yeah I mean it's been it's been
a pleasure working with you um over the
last few years and I don't even know
when we first started talking but um
getting to come out and see the facility
meet the team meet a lot of the people
in the Boseman area and the community I
I loved the community there when I came
out and the fact you were you know you
gave tours and everything and really are
opened it up to even competitors to come
and see what you guys were doing I
thought was really uh really
commendable thank you we appreciate that
and that that's a step in the right
direction too we have a right now we've
got a living soil Alliance here in
Montana so uh that's kind of a all of us
living soil Growers trying to band
together
to uh educate the consumers so that look
if you're shopping at the co-op but you
don't care what's in your
weed you you just don't know any better
if we can educate the consumers to uh as
far as I'm concerned and for a while we
used to have that same mentality of like
Secrets let's keep everything guarded
let's not tell everyone what we're doing
and then for after a while it's like you
know what first of all imitation is a
form of flattery second if the whole
world grew with living soil Su grown
cannabis Well we'd all be better off
from a carbon footprint standpoint and
so would I be jealous about that hell no
I wouldn't um Might Sting for a second
because someone copied you but then
you're like no what's that's not what
this is all about this is all about like
sustain my my degrees are in
conservation biology natural resource
ecology Wilderness management I was a
Wilderness Ranger for 10 years like this
is a core tenant a principle of the
foundation of this company was
sustainability and it's easy to forget
that when you're drowning in compliance
and day-to-day and bookkeeping and all
the nonsense but every once in a while
you do remember that like man that's a
that's a founding principle of our
company so first of all I'd love to do
that again if you're ever back in
Montana
um and I was talking about just doing
that having like a living soil Alliance
day and doing the same thing and opening
up the
facility and also you know what it it it
took the edge off for so long all of our
competitors we were just competing
against each other but like yeah let's
bring it in we are a community we're all
facing the same struggles like let's
talk about them and and it's liberating
in a sense like hey here's the problems
I have today look here's a spot of
mildew here's what I'm doing to address
it here's what I've done in the past to
address it
uh not be like don't tell anyone that I
had some mildew oh my God you know and
of course as you know when you post that
stuff online then the closet Growers
come out in full force about I'd be more
worried about that purple stem if I were
you it's like ah gez man go back to your
closet I'm just trying to do a good
thing here and that's the LED lights and
it's hard for me not to take it
personally because I care so much but at
the same time
like you don't have to worry about the
chatter of the closet Growers you just
do your best but but for us to like uh
We've scaled to this level and as far as
I know as far as I can tell we haven't
lost a bit on our quality now I don't
think we can continue to scale that
another thing we got to talk about is
um how many rooms you can have
efficiently to have a high utilization
rate like just facility design man
there's a lot to that um anyways we
could talk about this all
day well I know you're busy um so I I
super appreciate the time we had today
uh and I will uh absolutely reach out
thank you thank you Tad we really
appreciate everything you do for the
community and yeah shout out we also
still use Kissle Organics for our veg
soil and we have done some side by sides
there and we have a large ribbon mixer
here and I I will say that um as much as
it stung uh your soil just tromped all
over my soil when I was making it so I
don't even like to say that I
begrudgingly say that but props to you
for and what you've done for the
community we really appreciate it
everyone here everyone in Montana just
uh think so highly of what you've
brought to the community just by this
the same thing you're educating us all
by having these aesome guests on your
show so it's an honor to be here thank
you