[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of kiss organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge if
you're enjoying these podcasts please
take a moment to subscribe to our
newsletter on our homepage to stay up to
date on the latest podcasts product
announcements and videos I'm hoping to
make a lot more videos this year to
highlight some of my favorite new
products soil test kits and various
projects around the farm that I think
would be helpful to gardeners now this
week's podcast was a fun one some of my
podcasts can get more technical or
science focused however for this podcast
I want to talk too directly with a
grower to get some hands-on experience
and knowledge from someone in the
industry I had the honor of sitting down
with my good friend Nate Gibbs owner of
goldleaf Gardens a tier 2 producer here
in Washington State this podcast was my
first attempt to the video podcast so if
you're listening to the podcast and
would like to see the video version you
can go to youtube.com
I will also have some extra content to
support some of the ideas we discussed
as well as more footage of origins the
dispensary next door to where we shot
the podcast and if you want to see more
of what gold leaf is doing you can check
out their website at wwlp.com or on
instagram at at gold leaf gardens 420
now this podcast was a little bit
trickier to record because we did we
shot the video in a coffee shop so it's
a little bit echoey but I did my best to
edit the audio and make it the best we
could but I apologize in advance for the
quality of the audio on this one however
that being said Nate was a great guest
and I had a really fun time sitting down
with him so I hope you enjoy the content
of the show alright I'm here today with
Nate Gibbs doing our very first live
video podcast here in Origins they're
opening a new coffee shop right behind
us that's not open yet it'll be opening
soon and there
is a recreational cannabis shop next
door it's really cool it's it's a new
way of sharing and showing cannabis and
I'll take you guys over there with the
camera afterwards at the end of the show
if you're watching on the YouTube
channel now Nate here is a tier to
cannabis cultivator here in Washington
State he grows organically and is
someone that I met quite a while ago but
what Nate's what they're known for is
with gold leaf gardens is having the
highest quality top-shelf cannabis here
in the state and we have some samples
here which I'll zoom in a little bit of
some of the products that they produce
yeah but Nate can you talk a little bit
about your history and tell us a little
bit about how you got into growing
cannabis originally um yeah I have to
think about that the you know it's it's
you know we're grateful for for where
it's come to now you know just to being
in a place like this you know out here
in public with it you know amazing
beautiful stores you know or our
products displayed on the shelves and
you know on TV screens and and you know
just to have the sort of environment to
be able to showcase you know the work
that we're doing at gold leaf gardens
and and polarised racks and lyric ana
gars it's just it's a long long
unimaginable way away from from you know
the the dingy five foot high basements
that we were starting off in you know a
decade ago but you know here we are so
now let's talk about when we met so when
I met you it was working in
collaboration on a potential project a
friend I was looking to set up and you
at the time
100 light facility yeah on the medical
side you were running and so I can you
talk a little bit about that probably
yeah you know I mean I'm gonna skip over
a lot of details but you know kind of
starting from just the early grassroots
cooperative patient to patient care
provider model here in Washington State
you know one person growing for a couple
of patients in their basement we you
know sort of moved from there into you
know opening our own dispensary where we
worked with a collective of growers and
a larger collective patients eventually
that we outgrew our home grow operations
and moved into our first warehouse which
like you said was about a hundred light
warehouse and that was a that was a big
step you know at the time you know
Washington state laws were still a
little bit ambiguous we were taking a
you know sort of progressive
interpretation of the laws and and you
know that point you know nobody knew you
know day in day out if you were gonna
get shut down and everything seized or
if you were positioning yourself to
become part of this burgeoning you know
legal markets that was uh that was
beginning to to become you know
legalized so so I think we met at that
time we were we were looking at how we
were going to transition from this the
medical days the medical model into the
recreational model and and everybody was
ambitious and the future was you know
very optimistic and and there's a lot of
big money going around to finance very
large ambitious projects so we were I
think we were working on something that
you know was probably 10 times as big as
we ended up landing it with you know but
um the best thing that happened from
that was really meeting you we were
beginning to come into our own as
organic growers you know sort of
following that path from just you know
figuring it out on our own to
you know starting to realize that was
the direction that produced the best
products and was most in line with our
values but we didn't really know what
we're doing all right so tell me a
little bit more about how you learn how
to grow yeah time you know back then
there wasn't a lot of information
available what was your what was your
source of information what is yeah well
there was not a lot of information and
there's a lot of misinformation you know
you know at the time we were you know
nervous about even logging on to
computers a search for for info I mean
it all felt that illicit so we would go
I remember I'd go to the they used
bookstores and get these old tattered
copies of you know and Rosenthal book
how to grow cannabis and we you know
there's a small network of people that
you know we would we would share ideas
about what worked or what didn't and and
then there was you know the the local
hydroponic store which was sort of this
you know hub of where growers would go
and and you know cross-pollinate ideas
and you know yeah ironically you
couldn't tell anybody what you were
growing but everybody knew and you sort
of had this little dance you had to play
but I mean I remember I would I was so
you know I would I try everything you
know I would literally if there was a
new product on the shelf that offered to
boost my yields or boost my my flavors
or or fix my mites or anything I mean we
I think I tried everything and that was
about the time I
I ran to keep it simple which was the
exact opposite philosophy I had I was
keeping it complicated but well it's
because we had completely different
upbringings yeah in ways that we ended
up around cannabis so for me I had no
experience with the plant I grew up with
my parents owning and
in landscaping business so I was around
plants you know my entire life but never
cannabis so for me I I'd never been to a
hydro shop the first time I walked into
Hydra shop I was like what are all these
products and it was it was really
intimidating for me I had never seen you
know fertilizer was like a bag with a
label there were no three numbers on it
yeah and three numbers there was no like
hot chick in a bikini
yeah these fake monster plants and I've
never seen the word bud so much in my
life
yeah but I I was my dad's and my mom
sold their nursery and leased the land
out to the company they sold it to and
when they did that my dad decide you
want to start a compost tea business so
this was like way back in like 1999 when
that whole industry was just starting
out with dr. Ingham and so he had this
this compost tea business that was going
and we I came back from Australia and
started helping him out and he'd get
these phone calls from guys to be like
yeah I got you know 20 tomato plants in
my basement and it took me a little
while you know I was like how these guys
really like their pasta sauce so I
figured out what they were actually
growing and I started googling compost
tea and found some forums online but
even with the forums you know you're
right there was a lot of misinformation
I mean there still is but on top of that
it did feel a little holistic it was a
little scary you know when yeah what
direction the industry was heading and
then like you said we met and at that
time I had been working and learning
about soils and just getting into
cannabis myself and started working with
giant Palmer you know you know in
regards to testing out different soil
recipes and seeing how we could grow the
plant more organically and without all
of these other products and so Jaya was
really instrumental in that
and it was it was quite a journey you
know it was it was a lot of fun getting
to learn about an entirely new plant and
learning how to grow indoors it's
totally different than growing outdoors
and and and the higher value of the crop
sort of allows you to to really
experiment with inputs that I you know
just don't make sense if you're if
you're actually growing tomatoes or
you're growing you know cabbage or
something and so I think it kind of
opens up the whole of the realm of like
you know well if we can absorb these
these input cause you know we know how
to really maximize this plant you know a
10% yield in a cannabis harvest you know
could be thousands and thousands of
dollars right and so so you're think
that's part of what drives that the
cannabis nutrient market of you know
trying to always sell you more and more
some of which works and yeah what's does
it yeah it's right at all when we
originally were working on the soils
that I thought was really interesting
was the goal initially was not a
commercial application it was to create
a product where a cancer patient or a
medical patient could walk into a Hydra
shop and rather than getting hit with
all of these you know bottles and
nutrient lines and this craziness they
could just take a bag of soil and walk
out the door and water their plan and
then Jaya was able to start figuring out
some of these commercial applications on
scale which is sort of when we met you
and you were doing some of our first
trials too with the product uh-huh and I
know there was a learning curve there
and like some you know it didn't work
quite as well as you wanted initially
yeah but well I mean we were skeptical
just because you know it was such a
different thought process than what we
had been sort of accustomed to in terms
of buying a lot of bottles of you know
off the shelf we had a I think you you
know you remember we had a really
complicated recipe yeah you had this
this piece of paper I remember yeah five
milliliters of this and three
milliliters at this on the fourth day
and then
eight algorithm you know I was insane it
was the craziest nutrient I've ever seen
and your plants look great like yeah you
know you guys were really good growers
and I think that's an important aspect
of well I think you know what was
happening because it was you know we
were successful I mean at the time you
know and you know you couldn't tell me
that I wasn't growing the best cannabis
then which I wasn't
but yeah the you know we had so many
things going I mean I would talk to all
these people and they'd say oh that you
know the secret ingredient is
you know roots accelerator the secret
ingredient is this bud booster or this
and that so I would you know my logic
was well if I take everybody secret
ingredients and it's just gonna have to
be awesome right yeah and and but it's
you end up coming out with like you know
pretty good results but because we
weren't very scientific about it we
couldn't tell you what it was that was
leading to that right and what was just
more things we're buying I know I was
spending a lot of money I had a very
complicated recipe well there's a lot of
redundancy and as you taught me
there's a lot of bottles of things I was
greatly overpaying for because you know
it might have been them now now I look
back it's you know guano's suspended in
water but it's you know fifty dollars a
bottle instead of you know the dry
inputs you give I four dollars of
dollars of at least five of the bottles
you had had the same seaweed product and
right yeah yeah for sure so let's talk a
little bit about that transition so you
did some trials with living soils and
decided to commit your new facility to
that method of growing with the goal of
reusing the soil you know cycle after
cycle with minimal amending amending
yeah can you talk a little bit about
what your facility looks like now and
how you set it up yeah
well I remember when I was you know kind
of modeling out the the new facility
which was you know more than twice as
large you know just taking our nutrient
costs and putting on paper taking the
way we were doing things you know ended
up being very expensive and I was
starting to have to think about you know
the scalability of our processes and and
it was really opportune you know when I
met you and Jaya and and you said you
know here's this you know here's this
way of growing plants which is going to
require you know which is gonna let the
plants dictate what they need and
instead of as much you know you know as
much of the growers you know
manipulation of the of the you know
nutrient systems and and then that would
allow us to you know 10 mm of plants
right because you know we're you know in
a short period of time in a few years we
went from you know a few dozen in our
basement to you know we have four or
five thousand in our garden anytime so
you know you can't do the same things
you can't give each plant that seemed to
have retention so so I think that's that
was you know you know we're the light
bulb started to go off but also as we
were going through these trials with
sort of that as the end goal you know we
realized we're growing some of the best
product better than we had been
you know and your yield wasn't
necessarily any larger at that time was
it you know I don't think it was you
know significantly larger but it wasn't
it wasn't worse
I would say the quality was was better
and also to you know we just found the
overall health of our gardens began to
kind of just tack in a different
direction part of you know being very
hands-on with the nutrient regimen also
meant we're really hands-on with our
sort of our IPM program you know we're
using a lot of we're spraying a lot of
things and treating the soils and
treating things above the ground and and
running to a lot of problems you know
we'd have a you know I have a lot of
issues and and once we sort of you know
really let the you know built a good
living soil environment the plants
became happier and I think their natural
immunities began to be come fully
actualized and we just found ourselves
fighting a lot less problems so I get a
lot of emails about blog post I put up
with actually a photo from your facility
Rhian reusing soil so you use you've got
you got a bunch of plastic pallets in it
like blue plastic pallets which is great
because they're a lot easier to clean
and you know they're not gonna harbor
disease like a wood pallet wood and then
you had a custom-built fabric pot I
believe made specifically for the
pallets with the ID and then they're on
racks so they're raised up so you're not
bending over the whole time you talked a
little bit about like what because you
how many rooms how you have them set up
yeah so you know we have so our soil
beds you know which might be kind of a
modified version of you know what you
know you and I have kind of designed
there they sit on food-grade pallets and
then on top of that we had a geo pot
design us a fabric bed that fits exactly
on that pallet you know part of a great
thing about pallets for anybody
designing a large facility is there you
know a lot of material handling options
you know warehouses house pallets
forklifts everything certain knows how
to their affordable you're not eating
the wheel you're not recreating the
wheel exactly so we kind of use that as
our standard you know unit and from
there we have a soil bed with with with
you know kiss soil that we reimagine
we'd ever throw it out and and in each
bed we'll plant six plants and then
they'll have sort of a independent
trellis system per bed so we'll we'll
use you know sort of a scrog type of
training - for those same six plants
that share that bed and that trellis so
you're you that's just for your flower
room so your vegging in a separate room
in smaller containers yes and
transplanting into the beds for their
final yeah so so we have one room that's
you know one the four hundred square
foot room that's dedicated to all of our
propagation they'll spend a couple weeks
in there in smaller plastic pots and
then they'll move into one of our seven
production rooms each room has 50 beds
and we'll plant six plants per bed and
then from you know sir well 300 plants
and then um and then they'll live the
rest of their life cycle in that room
for about we'll give it about a week of
transition time in that room just
because they're going under something
more intense lighting we found that
that's a good amount of time and also
when we harvest we try to turn that room
over and get plants in there within a
day okay so for for reusing soil you
know we had to really figure out how we
can thread the needle harvest our plants
get our inputs back into the soil
transplant in there within 24 hours
I remember move it into the next floor
so you're first doing that yeah we have
to play around out a lot you know we
were trying to put all the nutrients
back in right at the beginning of the
cycle and it was just causing this tool
to heat up from the amount of microbial
activity was going on so what you guys
sort of figured out was okay we can put
some nutrients back in then and some
organic matter but then we'll also top
dress nutrients yeah throughout the
cycle and to to allow that to allow you
to get that immediate 24 hour return
when you could start planting back in
yeah it's really you know
you know if you have that downtime to
let that those nutrients you know heat
up and cook in there you know you lose
that production time so you know and and
if we sort of load it up the soil all
the way and transplanted we notice
there's a lot of transplants stress so
we found you know we we re amend a
little lighter and then we'll use top
dressings and water in a few things and
you know put some things into the
compost tea as we brew them so that they
can be integrated into the plants life
cycle throughout so you're not just
doing water you're doing other things we
do other things yeah a lot of compost
tea some some foliar applications you
know you know micronutrients and and
some you know like some top dressing as
well and you're always experimenting
with new things that's one of the things
that I really like to encourage with
growers and one thing that you and I you
always tell me too is you're always
trying out new things and seeing how
they do with a control and I think
that's the important aspect of it yeah
you can actually see is this one change
making an improvement or is it making
things worse is it worth the amount of
time and money I'm gonna spend on yeah
and that and you know one nice things
about you know growing at scale with a
lot more plants a lot more beds
everything being uniform the rooms all
being uniform is that it allows you to
dedicate you know small amount of you
know your canopy to these experiments
without really impacting your overall
production as much you know if you're
you know when we only had you know when
I was only growing 15 plants if I wanted
to try something 2 to 5 plants you know
enough for a decent sample size and it
didn't work out you know it really
impacts you now if we wanted to try and
experiment to one or two beds you know
if they maybe don't get quite the
returns or the the results we wanted you
know we're still able to absorb that so
you know it's hopefully leading to
improvement year over year I think yeah
so one of the so one of the challenges
with the style of growing they're doing
with reusing the soil is the fact that
you're not able to
fully sterilized the soil or clean the
media and so insects and diseases are I
think you're at higher risk for some of
these things and that's one of the
criticisms that I hear from traditional
agriculture and horticulture with the
style of growing can you talk a little
bit about some of the ways that you guys
deal with that and what you've you know
some of your experiences um I actually I
want to ask you a question about that
but the you know so I mean you know an
outdoor farm you know in a greenhouse
per se unless they're in containers you
know they're also not you know removing
the entire field right I mean this seems
to be something in respects to a you
know a container type of system indoors
you know I guess you know overwintering
outside we don't have that going on
indoors so yes there is definitely that
issue but yeah that is a challenge you
know I think that we don't have the we
don't wipe the slate clean in between
rounds where everything's removed and
sterilized and started over that being
said you do keep your facility very
clean yeah absolutely yeah you're you
know disinfecting the room just not the
soil and the beds themselves right I
think that's important it's not it's not
messy when you go into gold leaf you
know yeah I mean as much as you know
being able to have soil you know it's
not like a laboratory level hydroponics
facility like some of them I I've been
into we still have we're still trying to
promote a very you know environment that
or you know life is proliferated and and
you know encouraged you know on the soil
level
you know robust you know microbial
environments you know around the leaf
surfaces as well so you know sterile is
definitely not our end goal at any point
but but cleanliness is is important
absolutely
but with with you know with you know
perpetually you reusing your soil
it does force you to you know really
think about your environment the
sustainability of it over time and your
modes of your modes of pest management
you know you can't you know you can't
apply any type of product that's also
going to damage the the beneficial
you know microbes and insects in your
environment so you know we use a lot of
beneficial insects for example and you
know a horticultural spray that's meant
to knock knock out pathogenic insects is
also going to kill our good guys and so
we have to you know you know what I
think you know we're ultimately working
towards is is just the the right balance
of you know biology and our rooms you
know you're never going to eradicate
something all the way but you're gonna
you're gonna keep it under under control
to where there's a good economic
threshold and you know and when you kind
of have the right pieces in place you
find that you know the gardens would
sort of tend to themself and do is
Mother Nature
you know intended well when you compare
it to outdoor so the thing about being
outdoors in the field is you can still
get you know this these pathogens where
they you know overpopulate they're
always around just like they are in an
indoor facility people that say there
might free over there I just I don't
believe in you I think that's really
really hard to achieve and maintain but
I think you are able to maintain them at
a low enough level through a good IPM
program to where they are very
manageable yeah and having those
beneficial insects there I think is huge
in protecting the plant and having good
microbiology in the soil you know on the
leaf surface and
the thing about outdoors that's so nice
is you have that diversity of predators
that already are naturalized to that
environment and indoors you just don't
have that so I think the ability for
these pests are really proliferate
across a mono crop in an indoor
environment is a lot greater and when we
talk about greenhouses or like
horticultural operations I've gotten to
see more and more of those over the
years they are running you know they may
have a thousand different you know a
different varieties of plants and things
that all have different insects and pest
problems so they feel like the only
solution is to spray some pretty heavy
pesticides and sterilize everything but
well yeah with the been you know whether
like for example our beneficial insects
and we found you know I think
everybody's still trying to learn how to
you know these worlds converge mean
cannabis is so you so new but you know
we found that some things that work on
you know other crops for that same path
just aren't really taking hold you know
developing breeding populations and
things in in our rooms and so it becomes
sort of economically unviable they keep
using them yeah I found other things
that just sort of take root and get
established and just become part of the
you know the environment and you know so
that's that's just been a lot of
experimentation you know yeah well do
you have a favorite a favorite insect or
what I like to add your room that you
wanted to share with listeners you know
I mean I the Rove beetles right you know
they're a little expensive on the front
end but we you know III don't know
remember the last time we reintroduced
them but if you scooped up a handful of
our soil or I mean they even crawl they
crawl everywhere you find them you know
all over your facility well you have
them in the in the only compost - how
are they coming in for lowly compos okay
so yeah yeah and so you know those you
know they seem like apex predators as
far as you know that you know bugs go
and so you know I think you know
definitely if you don't have those
established in your organic soil
facility you know those those are those
are
good partners that have in there but but
yeah and and just being very
prophylactic and proactive right I think
kind of wheeling it back to those early
days it was get a problem look for a
solution try it doesn't work go to a
bigger gun until your present the
nuclear option and and and now you know
you have to be extremely cognizant about
not letting a problem you know flare-up
so you're constantly screening your
rooms are looking constantly screening
your rooms and you know one of the
hardest disciplines I think is to for
example spend money on on IPM for
problems you don't have right and yet
it's you know when you go back and study
all of you know I'm you know your notes
you realize you spend much more once you
have a problem and you have to fight it
that's a really good point and so and
then you you don't even think twice
about staying the money you have to do
it it's crop loss or it's been you know
hundreds or thousands of dollars on a
solution so you know when things are
going well you know it seems a little
hard to say oh I really have to you know
be disciplined in order my you know
hundreds of dollars of beneficial
insects and keep introducing them in the
room but then you realize we haven't had
a problem in six months or three months
and and and so you know I need to keep
up with that you know and I think that
once you're able to get from a you know
sort of a knockdown or a combative you
know yeah cycle into more of a
maintenance cycle that's when you know
again it actually does get much easier
and you know so less stressful less
stressful yes you got you got to keep
you got to keep investing in that part
of your Gardens if you're if you're
gonna especially are going to be you
know uh reusing soil you know keeping
some other plans that are you know never
never clearing out your mother room so
you're always gonna have you know some
some plant there so so there's there's
so many aspects to cultivation besides
just growing the plants one of the
things that you and I have talked about
more recently is the whole idea around
lean far
oh yeah and I know you have a lot of
experience with lean manufacturing and
then I was like read this book yeah and
you've sort of embraced that and your
facility Lobeck he talked a little bit
about that experience well yeah I
wouldn't I don't know if I would he
might be giving me too much credit I've
always been you know interested in the
subject and you know just always
thinking about you know running running
a production business you know looking
for for the right strategies you know I
I've always you know been very
interested in how how to sort of take
that these methods that work you know
I've given you know like Toyota this
great advantage over its rivals and yeah
and apply that but I always had a hard
time connecting the dots you know it
always kind of thought the ideas made
sense on paper and so when he gave me
that book by Ben Artman I was like there
it is you know somebody somebody smarter
than me finally connected the dots and
I've been you know so we've been going
through a process at our place of
removing waste you know and then just
really analyzing doing a lot of deep
reflection on on every step every touch
is it necessary does it add value or
does it not and it's amazing once you
sort of take inventory of that you know
how many things you do in a day that
aren't adding value to you know to your
customer at the end of the day
and you say why are you doing it you
know and so it's it's a transfer
transformation process that I think is
gonna be going on for a long time but I
you know I think it's it's really the
right direction especially as this
industry becomes highly competitive you
know now you know the the prices of
cannabis here in Washington State and
you know from what we've seen in other
states you know are falling getting much
closer to you know representing their
manufacturing costs not you know this
sort of artifact of what they used to
cost in the medical market or on the
street before yeah you know I mean we
grow some of the you know highest in
cannabis in this market but you know an
eighth of our flour doesn't cost much
more than what I was paying for you know
in college 20 years ago oh my god is
that work you know so you have to be
efficient and there's no rolling of fat
you're not taking that money home it's
the government that's even worse that's
the customers paying the same thing we
were 20 years ago you know we get we get
rid of that so yeah you know it's you
know it really you know I think if
you're not running a lean operation a
very smart operation then it's hard to
make money right now and I think I think
you know that's just the reality and so
yeah it is a slow process I've been
doing it at my on my farm you know
getting the employees to work on paying
attention to what they're seeing around
you know how we can keep the property
cleaner and how we can improve the our
processes because a lot of what we do is
just so time-consuming yeah and I know
we I know we can do a better job and I
know we haven't even thought of all the
ways we can do a better job so it's one
of those things it's not it's not so
much an end goal as it is just a journey
right and I'm really I'm really enjoying
it it's definitely changed the way we
run our farm and my and our business
and I'm glad that it's you know yeah
it's a Kaizen it's that that improvement
you know that 1% improvement you know
it's not you're never gonna get there
they're just gonna try to constantly you
know carve away at what doesn't need to
be there and aim towards this this
purity of you know pure value right
which is more of a you know something to
aspire to then probably something you've
ever actually achieve but you know in
that pursuit you end up becoming you
know becoming better at what you do and
yeah you know and and you know one of
the one of the traps I think we've seen
like in you know probably all farming
and it's starting to apply to cannabis
is that you know one direction people
take it is to just grow larger and
larger yeah and yet you'll see
large-scale operations that have taken
on a ton of debt to get there not
necessarily being more profitable right
and that seems that seemed interesting
right where's that economy of scale but
I think you know these type of lean
methods can be applied to a very small
operation or a large operation yeah but
either way you need to you know you need
to be very disciplined about how you're
running know for sure and I know for me
I've been a lot happier since we started
implementing this stuff because the
mental cost of all of this waste was
just weighing me down like walking
around and seeing project after project
that need to be completed or just mess
after mess that we left behind it's like
it was exhausting
yeah so just getting the stuff off the
property it was so nice yeah it's still
it's a constant battle yeah oh yeah it's
been great so changing directions we've
been talking about cultivation so far
but as you well know that's just one one
aspect of cannabis cultivation I mean
there's you could be the best grower in
the world right now here in Washington
State and still be failing just because
there's so much more to creating a brand
and a market share and interest in your
product yeah and key I want to talk a
little bit about your sort of your
company philosophy and the morals that
you guys stand for but before we do can
we talk a little bit about branding and
marketing aspect of things right um yeah
you know I mean it's you know the if
everything's important now and you know
it's all tied together to those two
things are really close for you what you
guys are doing yeah absolutely you know
I mean I think we were a little bit
ahead of the curve in just realizing
that you know cannabis is gonna kind of
turn from this sort of you know
anonymous you know anonymous commodity
to you know something that was gonna you
know look a lot more like like products
you see on the shelves in other
industries so you know kind of early on
we stuck our neck out and came up with
the name gold leaf and started branding
our product and at the time and say the
Medical dispensaries you know you
usually go in it was kind of like a like
purchasing bulk supplies you know at you
know at an old general store you know
you have these jars and here's some some
strains you don't necessary know who
grew them or anything like that yeah and
so we came out kind of with a jar with
our logo on it and it said you know this
is gold leaf weed you know this is you
know for better or worse this is this is
where it's coming from and um and so we
we kind of rode that into you know into
the the market and now of course that's
how all products are sold but it's it's
really important you know I think
because now in Washington for example
you know all the products need to be
sealed and kept behind a you know
usually behind a glass counter behind
the bar so for the customers you need to
really develop a trust with them and and
so you know having strong you know
branding and marketing to kind of
reinforce that those company values is
is essential and
can be an incredible grower you can have
the most coveted strains and it can just
fall flat for you because you don't have
that piece in place which yeah I know a
lot of growers in Washington right now
our producer processors as they're
called here are struggling to get into
new stores and get their product so
whereas I know you guys can't even keep
up right now with the number of stores
and people that want you and want to
carry your product and a lot of that is
due to customer demand people have come
this you know signify certain traits
with the brand gold leaf and I think you
know I won't touch on that some more but
I think such a big part of that is
you're the culture you've created there
you know in the community that you guys
have and can you talk a little bit about
sort of so I know a little background
here it's kind of unfair but I know you
guys are for the started off like a
bunch of Hawaiian guys yeah coming out
of what Kauai I think you said yeah you
know I mean I'm from Oahu most of our
you know all of our growers are from
kawaii and okay yeah we you know we have
a we have a it's you know we kind of
identify as a Hawaiian operation you
know obviously we have you know we have
all sorts of folks there but there's a
you know we embrace that spirit of Aloha
you know regardless of where you're born
from or you know what your ethnicity is
it's it's that's our value at the end of
the day and you know you know what what
that what does that mean you know it the
word has a lot of different meanings but
it means love you know and and so just
from the love of the plant to you know
the love of you know each other the
family you work with and your community
and you know growing up in a you know
unique place like Hawaii you had a real
tight communities there was a social
responsibility and that sort of you know
manage how everybody interacted with
each other and you know it just seems to
you know it's just how we live our life
and and organic growing kind of falls in
line with that as well and so you know
that's that's sort of how we run our
think our company internally and it it
is struck a chord with with
pull up here you know yeah it sounds
really you know it sounds cliche but you
know there's people want to know the
story behind the brand and you know the
yeah I think it's important yeah it is
and it's not you know it I think there's
substance to that you know I mean people
you know you you have this dollar in
your wallet to spend and you can choose
how you want to spend it you know
there's some folks who hate give me the
most potent weed for the cheapest amount
of money I can spend and we've you know
there's nothing wrong with that but
that's not the customer that that seems
to you know be supporting our business
and you know there's other ones who say
you know it's a good product but also
too I just love the way that you know
you you guys you know run your business
you know are good responsible members of
the community you give back you you grow
things responsibly when you you know
there's no rule that says you have to
but you know we know we trust we trust
your cultivation practices we know you
take care of your your employees and and
so you know at the end of the day I mean
that that adds up to to those those
those sales you know which is important
so yeah and your guys are passionate
about what they're doing I mean well you
know so my growers you know and I got to
give them credit because you know it it
all starts with them I mean without them
then the rest of business is you know
there's no foundation and and they're
almost all you know brothers and cousins
they grew up on this really you know on
a farm in a really small town called
Koloa an island of koi and you know they
grew up growing vegetables you know
sustenance farming they would sell there
you know they go with their folks down
to the farmers market and sell what they
didn't need and and you know that's
that's where they came from where they
were really relying on their land you
know to provide for their families and
so you know now you know what they've
kind of you know migrated up here and
you know the fact they're sort of able
to do that but in this in this different
market I think is something they're very
very proud of and and it's and it you
know shows in the product you know but
but they take a certain pride in the
gardens and I know this is a cultivation
science podcast but you know
just there's this one thing I haven't
been able to to sort of like quantify
scientifically and it's it's you know
just as love and this passion for for
being for your work and it just it it
shows up in the flavor and it just shows
up in in the the product at the end and
so you know I don't know how to
replicate that I just know we have
something really special and and we're
just trying to let the world you know
kind of see it and you know decide if
that's that's that's for them you know
yeah I mean one thing we haven't
mentioned either is that your facility
is fairly far south of Seattle so a lot
of the guys live in Seattle even I think
in North Seattle in some cases yeah yeah
and are driving all the way down to the
facility which is you know how many
miles is that well yeah it's in Olympia
Washington and you know it's about a 60
mile drive each way and I I mean we have
most of our employees and they make that
drive both ways every day you know in
traffic you spend hours there getting up
and you know crazy hours oh yeah
definitely the opportunity to work a
part of this community
yeah and and you know everybody has a
shared shared you know sense that we're
building something special and yeah you
know you know to come from a small place
and be able to make your mark and you
know going to these stores and and and
you know hear the stories that you know
there was there was people that were you
know genuinely had their their day or
their lives improved by you know by your
products I mean that that's the kind of
thing that makes that drive worth it you
know and so so yeah we're just blessed
and and you know wouldn't do anything
else so what are some of the things that
you do at goldleaf you know for or with
your employees that helped build that
sense of community yeah we
I mean even even something as simple as
you know on Friday we you know we all
stop work a few hours early and barbeque
and it's just become this tradition you
know that I don't know how it started
just as long as I can remember we've you
know we break a little early on Friday
and we everybody has a potluck and and
yeah that's kind of a Hawaiian thing you
just you know everything you know kind
of you know orbits around food and
community and and it's just you know
it's a special time where we're able to
you know just reflect and and you know
have your team together and something
that's not work-related but well yeah I
mean it's it you know it's the the
barbecue everything you know it's it's
such a small thing but yet I think it
just helps everybody remember that like
yeah we're this you know it's this team
we have a we have a greater goal and you
know we're happy to work together so
when I first started running kiss we
would have staff meetings we're not all
working at the same time to where we can
do these sorts of barbecues and things
but we're working on more team-building
events and those opportunities to be
together outside of the you know outside
of the workplace and not talking about
work like my farm managers birthday was
last night and you know over half the
staff was there you know other people
the guests we're leaving in like the
staff was there hanging out because they
enjoy each other's company and like some
of the some of the people have taken
trips to Iceland together or live
together or have moved across the
country and it's like those moments of
community I think are so amazing and
when I first started looking staff
meetings I was like oh my gosh this is
cut account I was calculating out how
much this is costing me per hour that
we're just sitting there and you know
people are asking questions and I'm like
20 man-hours I yeah like this is a lot
of money that we could be spent doing
other stuff but as I matured as the
leader or as a business owner I realized
just how important this aspect was that
people feel like they're being heard
that people have time together that's
not spent being you know stressed or
working and that everyone gets along and
likes each other is so important
and work environments can go a lot of
different ways oh yeah I mean I know
there's a lot of places where it's like
I don't want to see you till Monday
morning I can't get out of there fast
enough um yeah but uh but but yeah you
nailed it ed I mean it's it's um I think
it comes down to a sense of purpose
right and and like you know you have not
every job at gold leaf is you know is as
glamorous as the others but I think that
it's it's important to you know you know
sort of develop that and everybody that
says you know it's like there's this um
you know quote for the stonemasons and
it says you know we cut humble stone
must not forget we're building
cathedrals right and it's like you know
even if you're just trimming and I
totally butcher that quote by the way
but you know the whether you're trimming
or you're packaging or you're delivering
you know everybody realizes that this is
all part of that you know that that
customer experience and I think you know
there's so much to be learned from from
every person who works there right like
you and I we both you know wear a lot of
hats or running our businesses you know
we're not always down in the trenches
you know at least for myself I should
say you know I can't you know I'm not
always you know and there's there's
weeks I'm not even in the gardens as
much anymore because I'm have other
things to attend to and and you know
fine you know the person with you know
maybe one of the most homeless job you
know at our at our farm will have
insights into that part of the process
that I wouldn't be able to come up with
you know and allowing them empowering
them to say hey you know okay why don't
you make this improvement this isn't
about me telling you how to do a job
it's you know it's me finding the right
people who want to improve this company
in any way they can and so giving them
some some Liberty which he knows takes a
certain amount of trust and but you find
I think you find overall that when
people do that you know that gives them
a sense of purpose say wow I've improved
this product I've helped my company
everybody benefited from it
I think that that sort of really yeah
you did told me another time we're
talking about one of your trimmers you
kind of told me a story around that you
want to share that with the listeners
was that which one was that I mean ice
probably it probably has to do with you
know Sano and you know he's our longtime
trimmer but yeah and you had offered him
other positions in the company yeah but
well yeah I mean I've had a you know a
awesome kid he's been trimming for me
for just you know years and years and
you know I you know he's definitely
earned the right to you know move into
like you know different jobs but he just
kind of has this this old soul and this
this this you know desire this this how
should I say this affinity for it kind
of you know there's one the
craftsmanship you know and this one
little thing he does he takes his one
job of trimming which you know if you
you know trimming for the cannabis
industry is you know some people think
it's like dishwashing in the restaurant
industry like it's where you got to
start and yet you know he takes so much
pride in in trimming a perfect flower
and I think you know what he's told me
is that you know I mean these growers
they put in so much time and energy from
from taking a clone and and all the way
through it's it's growing life and you
know the harvesting and the the curing
and you know he it's his job to give it
that final manicure that the you know
that's you know your customers are gonna
see and he that pride he hasn't that one
simple task really embodies oh you know
just how you know how we try to view
everything we do so it's great and and
you know he's I know he might be a
trimmer forever and and you know it's
it's but he enjoys what he does you know
he absolutely absolutely you know you he
has purpose in his work and and he's
quite talented that he's good at what
he's doing absolutely and you know what
simple task and I pay him well to do it
now I said you know I'm gonna continue
to promote you but you could still be a
trimmer right because he's earned that I
want to take care of folks but if his
you know calling is to do that one final
detail it's like detailing a car before
you put it on the lot you know it might
not sound as cool as a guy engineering
the car
but you know at the other day that
customer is gonna want to see a nice
shiny car and that might be what makes
him purchase it yeah and he understands
that and I think that's sort of that's
that's definitely a you know an example
for how we try to do everything there so
let's talk a little bit about what where
we are yeah and sort of a little bit
about the coffee and some of your
products and how you guys brand your
your stuff for listeners yeah I mean the
where do I start so yeah we're here you
know origins coffee shop it's adjacent
to origins recreational cannabis shop in
Redmond Washington we've worked at them
for a long time and we love that they
sort of are thinking outside the box
with how people are interacting with
cannabis as a whole and with the brands
in general you know and it's a it takes
a little bit of creative thinking to be
you know to make in this market so so
you guys partnered on this this coffee
mm-hmm and ki talked a little bit about
where we're starting you know at the
actual origin of the coffee itself yeah
why you're why you're doing it yeah I
mean you know it's the two things we
consume the most of his coffee and
cannabis picker as well get in
businesses both but uh you know I was
I've been thinking for a long time I
mean I drink a lot of coffee and there's
a lot of restrictions on how I can you
know really market and advertise my
cannabis brand you know just sort of
what's socially responsible and and you
know it's it's an adult product and even
the state sets some limitations on how
how and where we can advertise obviously
you know I'm thinking about our brand
you know eventually moving into you know
possibly other states and you know
internationally one day so how do I
begin to export that you know if I can
ship
my products across state lines you know
and so the coffee just seemed to be
something that sort of embodied a lot of
you know similar similar values so we
partnered with a roastery on the Big
Island and there they work with a
cooperative of Kona coffee farmers other
coffee farmers in Hawaii you know small
farms small family farms organic same
values we have and so hopefully now you
know if you get a Buy or you know get a
bag of cold gold leaf coffee and it's
excellent too and you know we made sure
that make sure hey if we're gonna put
the name on it's got to be really good
you know and and so hopefully you know
you maybe you try the coffee and you say
wow you know what's behind this brand
and it's like oh hey they also grow they
also grow herb and maybe I'll check that
out so just just a different way of
thinking about the brand as a whole you
know eventually perhaps it expands
beyond just cannabis into more of a
lifestyle and you know culture yeah and
then you guys are known for your flower
yeah that's really what's you sort of
staked your mark on but you also produce
other products as well yes so beyond the
flower you're also he talked a little
bit about the lyric ana gars and some of
the other products you created to sort
of diversify in this market yeah so we
you know we you know we start off pretty
much strictly selling flour we partnered
eventually with concentrated maker polar
ice tracks and we do solvent free
concentrates so hash rosin and that's
been really great you know we've been
winning some awards for that it's just a
very pure process that involves no
chemistry and so we figure why are you
gonna grow your your your flowers
organically and then you know process it
with with you know hydrocarbons and you
know other solvent so it's a it's a
solvent free you know constant
concentrated processing
and then we put them all together into
the categories and so this is actually
one of the smaller ones we call this the
cannery low but it is a basica cannabis
cigar and it it's it's our flower then
it's wrapped in a layer of the
concentrate and then we take the fan
leaves from the plant so instead of a
tobacco wrap it's you know each leaf is
meticulously you know placed around that
and cured and dried the whole process
takes months and you end up with this
you know kind of work of art yeah
they're beautiful yeah yeah all I'll
post some photos and stuff for listeners
on the podcast page but then also I'll
show some of the videos that you've you
shared with me because one of the things
that I just want to mention while we're
talking about marketing branding that's
so important is marketing branding is
not just a t-shirt or a hat or a coffee
bag it's the sort of collection of all
these things to create identity and a
culture around what you're doing it's so
important I think that people have an
idea of not just where these products
come from but how they're grown and you
really have to marketing and branding is
is a holistic thing and that's one thing
I'm learning you know it's not as easy
it's just running out and buying a
hundred t-shirts yeah you have to create
that social media presence you have to
create that understanding of what you're
doing and that recognition so that so
when someone sees that t-shirt or that
coffee or that hat they can say hey that
signifies this you know quality
community you know Aloha
whatever whatever you're going for with
your product I think that's important
yeah and that's something that I know
that origins has worked really hard on
too and so I will I will do a video tour
and there that will have on YouTube as
well that we can share with people so
they can see how some of the more
innovative reck shops are doing things
here in Washington yeah
you know it's I think all I can say
about its authenticity right if you you
know have a strong sense of purpose in
what you know why you're doing what
you're doing
you kind of build your marketing around
that it'll you know it'll it'll work out
well for you I think if you're trying to
put out a message that doesn't truly
represent who you are then it's it's
just gonna kind of fall apart and but
yeah you know you gotta you got to
approach it from so many different
angles and and you know it's exciting
times because there's so many platforms
now to get your message out you don't
have to throw a ton of money at it like
the hard dollars like you did before you
know taking out magazine ads and
billboards and and all of these these
cost you can be very creative and you
can use people to to spread the message
I think that nothing's better than you
know like firsthand recommendation you
know and and so those are those are
things that you know you try to
cultivate as much as possible yeah
that's a really good point about being
authentic because we nowadays we're just
bombarded with messages all the time and
marketing and I think people even at a
subconscious level at the very least can
tell when a message is is fake or not
authentic so that's a really good point
well is there anything else that you
want to touch on today I really
appreciate you taking the time to chat
in yeah no thank you I appreciate it you
know and and you know thanks again I
always appreciate your your help with us
sort of coming into our own as organic
growers and you know we're you know I
think I definitely know we wouldn't be
who we are and and and how we are if it
wasn't first in over you know
opportunity to run into you at that
transition time so so that's been great
no it's been good and I think it's
important to collaborate with people in
the industry and I know you and I are
always learning new things and when I
learned something new related to soil I
think matter would matter for you I'm
calling you up and when you discover
something you know you're sharing with
and I think that's how we all stay
competitive you know with absolutely you
know and I think I you know I can't
stress that enough I think there is um
you know there's there's there needs to
be more unity you know the cannabis
industry you know as things get
competitive you know the the gloves come
off and it can a key
you know everybody's kind of fight for
their own but I don't think it has to be
like that you know you look at other
industries and like-minded brands and
come together and and there's a lot
there's a lot to go around so yeah
looking forward to the next chapters as
well
all right thanks yeah you've a she ate
it alright thanks that was Nate Gibbs
owner of goldleaf Gardens a tier two
producer here in Washington state known
for their top-shelf flower and organic
methods if you're local to Seattle Nate
will be back at origins coffee shop in
Redmond Washington on 4/20 this year for
a luau with his crew from 4:00 to 7:00
p.m. so stop on by and say hello
don't forget that there is some video
content to go along with this podcast on
the podcast page at WWE sorghum XCOM or
on our youtube channel under K is
organics you are listening to the
cannabis cultivation and science podcast
I'm your host Todd Hussey thanks for
listening
[Music]
you