hey Jim how's it going good to get to
chat with you again good to talk with
you today are you doing I'm good I'm
good I know we've talked a lot off air
but I wanted to record a video because I
know there's a lot of people that have
wanted to hear from you and hear what
you've been up to I know personally
you're less involved with the cannabis
scene as you used to be and you've been
getting more into mushrooms but do you
want to just kind of fill people in on
what what's been going on in your life
sure I thank you for asking I had we
were able to pay off our house a few
months ago and I don't know I just
decided to remodel and I got rid of
we've been here 17 years and got rid of
17 years of junk it's just amazing I
mean I went through 17 years of computer
equipment like why did I buy this you
know so it's been kind of a semi
approach to minimal as my efficiency and
and I really got really really tired of
being involved on any level at the
Cannabis scene so I contract my growing
to somebody that I trust outdoors and I
get extremely nice yield of high quality
flowers and that everybody go have a
good time and just for needing some
recreation I guess you'd say and I
really enjoy growing things still do I
got involved in growing mushrooms and
working with a fellow that you would
know I think is set it and forget it
organics on Instagram and so we worked
through some different recipes and for
the substrate and actually is
interesting one of the books that I used
was organic mushroom farming and sarra
remediation by gentleman from North
Carolina and it was the first how to
that actually mentioned things like you
know earthworm castings rock dust so I
kind of felt a kindred hey I'm back home
you know that's pretty cool and so yeah
it's been really fun and growing your
own food and as well as the medicine on
the lion mane and what you would know as
maitake some in the northwest refer to
it as hen of the woods but there's
several turkey tail and other mushrooms
that we can grow that have long
established histories is terms of
medicinal out primarily out of Asia
China and Japan and then of course the
the food the culinary mushrooms are
really exciting to grow like oysters
which are the easiest mushroom in the
world to grow and that one I would
recommend people start with so they
don't get some stumbling blocks I mean I
wouldn't start out with growing lion's
mane for example I probably do mushrooms
and then kind of work up nice especially
for the outdoor gardens we can use wine
caps and so not only are we growing food
but it's also doing some wonderful
things with the soil in deconstructing
the carbon sources that are in the so
maybe like luck for example well you
know it's better night it you create
soils a lot of potting soils have a lot
of wood in it wood chips so by using
mycelium we can deconstruct that and it
just adds to the human of the soil you
know the nutrient profile so it's
win-win
you're not only improving the soil but
we're also growing viable food good
source of B vitamins and protein what
have you now a couple things a couple
questions I had because I am NOT a
mushroom expert I love eating mushrooms
I loved the interview with Paul Stamets
that on the Joe Rogan podcast that was
sort of some of this stuff around like
lion's mane creating new neurological
connections in your brain and it's right
or ways that people are using fungi
which is incredible and I've always had
been a little bit I think there's a term
for it and I might have it wrong but I
think it's Micah phobic yeah oh yeah yep
the sense of like going out my brother
for example will go out and harvest wild
mushrooms and that makes me really
nervous not knowing what I'm gonna be
consuming me just because the dangers
associated with them and learning how to
do support prints and things like that
so I always heard that you need to be
have very sterile conditions to grow
mushrooms and you need you need to be
very careful and it can be so dangerous
because some of these mushrooms are
toxic so mm-hmm it's almost like there's
this fear-based thing around mushrooms
that is sort of more the public opinion
that doesn't sound like is really
accurate no and and culturally that
phobia whatever we want to call it goes
back millennia I mean this isn't
something new what I suggest people
consider is that for example Paul
Stamets up at fungi calm he sells a
sponge so the the part of the process
that requires the sterilization and
almost lab conditions will say he's
already done it i fact they sent you a
link this morning in preparation for
this for several varieties of mushrooms
that you could buy with confidence and
this font is it's already colonized with
the correct whether it be hoisters or
what are these guys shiitake and
probably whatever and there's other
there's other sources too so for people
that are concerned I mean I'm not gonna
go walk around there were Civic
Northwest go well I think that's a I
mean take a class you know there's the
American Mike
the association that has branches and
state organizations I know one or two in
Washington you know it's kind of fun you
get out with a group of people and an
expert and you know it's if you're going
to do that I would suggest taking a
class and do a lot of reading with books
that have and try to get the digital
version so it's on your iPhone or
something so you can do some
identification
now some of them you're not I mean
obviously you're not going to confuse
the lion's mane with a toadstool sure
and some of the other ones that we find
growing on the timber itself like reishi
but and those you buy the plugs they're
already inoculated you drill a hole and
you insert the plug in away you go so
that's probably the path of alleviating
some of those concerns but I am with you
when people send me pictures look what
do you think this is how do we want an
operative opinion I don't yeah I
wouldn't be cooking needing it unless
you know that your drunken
brother-in-law is coming over something
maybe that we always start with a
positive identification that sounds like
absolutely yes that's claimer to throw
out there to people absolutely and and
barring that until you feel comfortable
then I would buy spawn inoculate air
colonies gives me colonized medium more
often than not wood chips and but I know
for example Doug at Northwest red worms
he used to grow oysters the white
oysters the standard one I guess you say
in these plastic bags that you hang from
the rafters so it's got pretty nice
analogy uses a medium oh newspaper and
coffee grounds
that's excuse me I know they saw a video
out to find it for you but the guy grew
it on old tennis shoes
I remembered this is really an important
thing I think in this whole discussion
punch I was here before plants which
preceded the animal kingdom and they're
gonna be around long after the insects
are gone
I think the role that one of the most
important books a person could read I
think is I think you read you have a
copy of this mycelium running hi Paul
Stamets and I think that's that should
be like the primer for anybody to get a
grasp of how much Punjab the role it
plays in our world sure yeah other
primary decomposers so when you say an
old shoe or coffee grounds they're gonna
be one of the things that's really
efficient and breaking down carbon oh
absolutely
now go ahead well no I
for example the a popular one would be
straw okay so you got a good source of
lignin and carbon whatever I start
thinking it through the eyes you know
like wait a minute
what are they doing in Asia so I looked
and rice hulls well for me it's a lot
easier messing around rice holes and
getting a bale of whatever you know
because like just run up the
concentrates and get the stamp like you
buy you know was it okay they sell by
the pound or fifty pounders by cubic
feet but it's a lot of rice holes for
you know under 20 bucks I tell you that
and so that's really inexpensive and I
don't have to mess around with straw you
know trying to bust up a bale though I
have done some work with another
gentleman and we used bales of straw
that we picked up from a feed store and
put some of the colonized spawn use that
to then inoculate the
and yeah it's not so so you're working
with call a nice spawn but I know
essentially what you're saying is you
don't need sterile media to grow that
spawn out based on right
actually what you want is okay the way
that that I was taught and we use
pasteurized substrate not sterilized and
we're gonna go back to your expertise in
history with dealing with microbes in a
soil in a soil mix so we don't want a
completely sterile medium because nature
abhors a vacuum right so you're gonna
get contaminants whereas if you
pasteurize it you're still leaving and I
really dislike using this phrase but
this is a popular one you leave the good
guys there the good microbes there in
the pasteurization which just simply
means you're soaking the material in
water between 160 and 180 Fahrenheit for
a period of well I'll go with hour hour
and 15 minutes and that is going to give
you a clean substrate but it's not going
to be sterile and so especially if
you're growing most popular because it's
the easiest one to grow the most widely
grown or the oyster in a good way
they're very invasive so once it gets
that substrate they take over and that's
a good thing so just like you know we
deal with our compost teas you want to
put add the correct aerobic microbial
colonies which will keep the anaerobic
colonies at bay or destroy them what
have you so it's still the same science
that that isn't different and that makes
it because you can go to Amazon right
down for under $20 get a cardboard box
with a moister mushroom start in it and
you open the box ever said it know what
you get to watch it grow over the next
several days so that's I think is really
cool because it gives people thought
well I can do this if they're
manufacturing this and wherever and
shipping around the country I mean
they're good repeat business so
obviously it's not some big you know
feat to grow it and that would get dead
good two-person confidence to buy the
colonized spawn from Paul Stamets and
others some for that you want to maybe
grow in a like a plastic tub but other
varieties you'd want to put out your
garden like the white caps those but the
wine cap is actually one of their
nicknames is soiled Buster so if you
have really hard soils you know you know
what I'm talking about rather get out
the El Toro roto tiller yeah we can use
this and it plus it's then gonna give
you crumb which you know more about that
than I do the importance of crumb the
Lukey methods control microbiology in
our soils and it's just fun you know
especially it's a really good learning
I've been working with people adding
spawn to their worm bins so we're gonna
raise the fungal level in the
vermicompost and while we're doing that
we're gonna be able to harvest some food
how are you doing that if you're not
pasteurizing the worm bin because that
would kill the worms well because worm
vermicompost in the very nature and it's
ecosystem is very I would only use the
word antiseptic but it's a very clean
medium we adulterated okay and I'm not
suggesting that we want to grow and
straight worm castings I'm not but
that's a very
very pure medium to start with and so if
a person just took really quality
vermicompost and I've done this myself
and mixed it about one part compost to
three parts vermicompost with the three
parts of rice hulls which I did
pasteurized not sterile and then added
just some kelp you get tired of hearing
this but kelp mean a company and malted
barley to the substrate because the malt
fungi are enzyme engines and we already
have several hundred year history of
using those very enzymes created by
barley in bread baking it's what they
call diastatic malt that's added to the
dough to increase the activity of the
yeast so what's yeast like Easton's a
single-cell fungi
so I decided huh I wonder if this will
do anything for the ones I was trying to
grow it sure did oh wow this is really
cool so here's a product for 80 cents a
pound that you I added to a substrate
recipe and set it forget it organics
he's been doing a lot of work with on
substrate recipes and trying to use
things that are would be easy for people
to locate like core even coconut core or
Spagna peat moss and things like that
but we're trying to use everyday not
trying to make it some exactly because
it doesn't need to be you know it trying
to keep it easy yeah for people to
understand and I don't you know there's
there's some good books out there and
one is a not exactly the most exciting
name but it's called mushroom
cultivation and it's strictly about
outdoor gardens adding different
deities of edible mushrooms that we can
use and not only to improve the tilt in
our garden plots but also provide us
with a good viable protein source so for
vegetarians and even vegans this is a
good alternative for meat free diet
people like yourself just yeah I like to
taste them so yeah I actually what
sparked this cuz I knew he were doing
this journey in doing these experiments
with various mushrooms and things like
that I went over to my mother's house in
Fort Lee Lowe and she had gone to the
local farmers market and picked up some
fresh oyster and they were phenomenal
her on them it was a little bit of a
meaty flavor almost right a little bit
like chicken but different I don't want
people to think everything's like but it
was good and so much healthier you know
just that other than the price because
they were expensive oh yeah they were
they were great so it made me think
about ways I could start growing these
at home and learning more about it
because I really I really did enjoy it
the one one way is to use go over to a
Home Depot or whatever in place like
that hole all murders flows and the tubs
their storage tubs the club the like
Rubbermaid that kind of thing you could
use those even and we didn't pan out
then you know he'd still have a storage
cover you know just mix oil or whatever
you know something like that but yeah
just you put substrate in there find a
recipe that you're comfortable with that
makes sense to you and it's hard for me
to envision how anybody could really
fail with something like the oyster
mushrooms they're just that easy to grow
okay it started a hundred years ago at
after during World War one in Germany
and out of necessity feed the people
and then after in the 20s and 30s it
spread like wildfire throughout Asia so
that it became a it's a major crop in
China and India because you can produce
a lot of protein and you don't have to
it's not like trying to grow an exotic
plant like say orchids you're not gonna
break the bank we're talking about you
know growin mushrooms this is really
like a poor man's hobby which appealed
to me you know I spent enough time and
effort money on growing and thinking I
did to grow cannabis you know or
something so this is really uh and it's
almost instantly you get you've seen the
results of your work in a couple of
weeks okay so I like you know so let's
say I wanted to try going I stir
mushrooms I know you've talked a little
bit about this process all right you
said they're the easiest so take me
through all the steps from beginning to
end you know like going to the website
ordering this flooring what should I
have at home before the spawn arrives
well you want to have your substrate
ready and the beauty is that
commercially some of the things that are
used to grow oysters are really
intriguing like I said you know a good
friend Doug over at North West he was
using newsprint and coffee grounds yeah
I mean Wow
and not only that not and not just
getting one crop in one cycle you know
what they call anyway is there like a pH
range though so here's here's the thing
when you say coffee grounds in newsprint
I think that's not gonna a very nutrient
rich source for these mushrooms which
makes me wonder if these mushrooms might
be a little less nutritious than if I
had grown the
and it's in a higher hired nutritive
that's a really really good question and
one that I can't give you a specific
answer to but I have wondered the same
thing so one of the reason I bought the
book organic mushroom farming is that
that issue is addressed to some degree
by instead okay remember when you first
showed up at or we did I mean I'm about
the same time over it I see mag yeah I
remember how much bad information there
was okay sure
oh well imagine that you'd been there
ten years earlier okay about how bad it
could have been well that's where the
mushroom forums are now I mean it's
appalling I mean I read things like well
yeah you want to add limestone because
you need all those minerals let's see we
got calcium carbonate
what what exude treants are we talk I
mean if I want nutrients I use basalt
okay yeah something very nice is calcium
yeah you know I mean and kelp meal yeah
probably the richest plant on the earth
so I have a kelp story to tell you but
just just to simplify things so
basically you're saying for a substrate
that that's what you have to have ready
and then you're recommending starting
with something I think you mentioned
rice hulls or yes that's your carbon
source sure yeah that's your carbon for
I mean you can use straw that's more
traditional Strife probably cheaper but
I live in you know the city and I got a
drive 15 miles to a feed store and then
God knows how you know the whole Bureau
at least with the rice holes that I get
from concentrates are organic so cross
your fingers you know with rice hulls I
worry about arsenic levels potentially
being an issue right from a heavy-metal
perspective right let's just talk
organic strawberry so let's try and find
a source of organic straw you would in
the tub you would you heat the water to
between a hundred one hundred eighty
degrees and keep it there for you said
at least an hour and 15 right to make
sure that we've pasteurized it yes and
then what happens then do you need to
get the spot on it right away
well what you think you're gonna uh you
want to drain and squeeze out is much
like remember fungi are for many many
decades it was taught at university is
that fungi were a subset of the plant
kingdom and we now know that's
ridiculous
yeah they're closer to animals in this
regard they use oxygen and expel co2 so
you want that substrate like our soils
in this regard you want it moist but you
don't want it drenched
and so what I do is I just get I got
some 100% cotton pillowcases put this up
straight in there and just squeeze it
and you know keep twisting and twist and
get as much water and then let it hang
maybe for a day it's not no it's not
like okay we got a rush I mean you want
to be take caution of course and then
when you'll know the consistency you
want it so that it's what's that word we
use and so low me okay that's what
you're looking for so air passages and
then you dump in your spawn which in the
case of oysters they're probably I'm not
sure what mr. Stannis is using but let's
say it's chips wood chips or shavings or
what have you I found it easier in my
experiments to use organic sorghum or
Milo whatever term and it's really
inexpensive because it's it's a
feedstock you probably feed it to your
chickens there it's part of the mix of
your chicken mash whatever it's called
and because sorghum has a shell like
corn popcorn if you will we have found
that to be easy to inoculate colonize
but yeah I mean you're kind of wide open
whatever so you're mixing that in with
the straw yeah and then you're adding
neem and kelp and rock dust to that yeah
well I just sprinkle it in just a little
bit like about like what I did with soil
you like say a cup of mean two cubic
foot okay a cup of kelp now there's a
funny that's an interesting one in
studies that I downloaded from India
using neem and carranza not only did it
suppress the contaminants as the term is
used it increased the yield curve factor
on the fruit that they were actually
wanting to grow in this case it was a
stirs and which sounds well if it's a
fungicide yeah but it's not a I want to
get into that whole thing it's like
silliest conversations in the cannabis
scene but so just out of Hawai night I
started adding kelp or excuse me an
email to the recipe the substrate and I
saw the same thing a suppression of
contaminants and an increase in the
yield of the the target fruit that we
were trying to see now one nice thing
about oysters is they're they have a
very distinctive look so you can feel
pretty confident absolutely that you're
not getting something some contaminant
in there well the contaminants are
usually that's kind of like soil
remember we used to talk about on the
Cannabis boards that if you see the term
was mold I think if it's this color
you're fine if it's that color you're
not so fine and so blues and greens you
don't want to see the white is you know
we're we're dancing right well it's the
same thing in the substrate you know you
start seeing green and just call it a
day and toss it oh they're talking about
mold it's not actual fruiting mushroom
caps you're saying if you see mold
growing in the yeah it's it all has to
do with color you're gonna you're gonna
see white which is what you want it's
like just like in our soils we didn't
want to see what Pink's blues and greens
memory serves me correct I only ever saw
white so I'd never concerned myself yeah
do you have to poke holes in the
pillowcase or will it actually grow
right through the cotton oh no I just
meant I use that to get as much water
out
the substrate as possible so you're
growing it in you then put it into a tub
yes and then I you drill some two inch
holes for ventilation and use that tape
that if they use on bandages it you can
see through it but it has wilt like
microscopic type holes in it use that to
cover that that blocks contaminants
getting into your tub okay they say I
mean you bite it you know any by where
you get your prescriptions you know
drugstore it's just that that tape you
use the wrap around your bandage how's
that you want your bandage to breathe
right like how that's tape or first-aid
tape yes at first aid yes yeah it's not
not the heavy-duty stuff just it's I
don't know three dollars for a three
hundred feet or something there okay so
anyway you drill these two inch holes in
it again we're back to fungi you need
oxygen so you need good ventilation but
you don't want you want to have a way to
block the bad guys from getting in there
yeah do you need to put a fan or
anything on this no no I mean I've had
some other interesting ideas going into
a Quarian store and looking at some of
the stuff they used to create air
bubbles
it was long skinny I'm thinking I said
well you know he'd build a frame out of
those put that on the bottom with an
arrow I mean is this is open to a lot of
Investigation and the beauty is that
it's not gonna break the bank it's not
like let me try this thousand dollar
super-duper light from you know we'd be
growing wheat or something and bite it
when I didn't work I didn't you know I
didn't pay off I mean this is like a
poor man's hobby I guess you can say so
how long from the time you inoculate
this or into the straw and you get it
into the tub how long until we'll start
seeing mushrooms with the oysters
because of how and I mean this in a
positive way how invasive they are ten
to twelve days and then it's just like
you know you're cutting constantly and
getting
I mean this thing goes on for several
weeks that's why
so the you don't really grow cannabis
you know you're looking at three months
before well how do you know how to pan
out how'd those seeds work right well
you don't have that here I mean this is
like instant gratification almost
they're as close as you can get to
instant gratification yeah that's and
the other thing is with the oysters
sometimes when you're bored look at the
variety there's like 22 major varieties
and some of them are just I mean they're
pieces of art you could hire a
professional photographer and shoot them
and sell postcards of it I mean some of
the exotic blues and pinks and all kinds
of neat colors there's something like I
believe I'm quoting Paul Stamets oh I
want to be careful here at all I'm
misquote but something like 15,000
specific varieties of fungi that are
cultivated either by intent or you know
what have you and the amount that
freaked is fairly limited I mean for
example morels
everybody likes morels right that's
actually the fruit of ecto micro hazel
that's why we get them at the base of
trees that's the fruit from that variety
of fungi I just found that really
fascinating and some grow in decomposing
logs on the ground some grow on living
trees like reishi you that's where you
ought to find those and when you buy
like say logs that are already pre
inoculated the big one is the ones from
Japan shiitake yeah so you get this log
it's a for a disc discussion we'll call
it sawdust
Hill together bound by a resin of some
type that's been inoculated with the
spores and so it's a one-time use but
that's an easy way to get started - just
for the gratification part of it you
order it and they're not expensive see
order a log and you grow some mushrooms
or and it just gives you a sense of
accomplishment well I did this you know
so that then leads you to some that
maybe are a little bit more challenging
yeah I think that's what I'm gonna start
with here there's a local guy who makes
them he makes a few different products
and so I can get the logs from him oh
absolutely I mean you're up there that's
why Paul Stamets is domiciled up there
I mean vasilich North West is one of the
epicenters of well let's use the word
mushroom foraging how's that there's
just a lot of opportunities many were
native and some were brought it you know
just to sort of the human race moving
around and things but yeah that would be
if you know somebody that's putting
together into shitake blogs that would
be way cool just to have it in your
store yeah and people come in to look
what I did you know kind of thing and
yeah we had one actually set up and this
is funny so one night our security alarm
started going off and we couldn't figure
out what it was the whole thing was
covered there was movement inside our
farm store turns out what had caused it
was one of the mushroom logs had
released spores and in a hoofed and then
the spores had hit the camera well past
the alert to go off so we went down
there was no one there but we figured
out after the fact that we'd put the
mushroom lock too close to the camera
yeah I mean there's I've seen some
videos of time-lapse yeah it's the most
fascinating
it's the
has anything that I've ever been
involved in is this Lucas learning about
especially for myself was medicinal
mushrooms the the cordyceps and the
lion's mane it would actually though the
Lions meow there's one for you if you
get and you can find them here in the
northwest because this is foodie central
right Seattle in Portland so you get
take fresh lion's mane you cut them into
steaks and then you treat it like
lobster or crab and that's what it
tastes like just spread some butter on
it with some herbs and then grill it I
mean what a great what a great you say
you and your wife are having a dinner
party you want to impress people well
here's a non meat meal that I've
prepared for you and you could do some
things with well maitake would ear
moister 'z I mean you can really create
some really wonderful now where I come
in is I'm a real big bread baker yeah so
I like making artists and pizza dough's
and then using mushrooms on that not
with a ton of cheese either the you know
you want the flavors to come through of
these wonderful things that we grew in
our gardens but I could see it like at
your farm having like an exhibit area
for the children to see mushrooms
growing and how they're harvested and
then might even turn into a profit
Center you know I can have company pick
a mushroom or something you know well
yeah we've tried inoculating some logs
but we didn't have any one that was
really staying with it it makes bright
success right I think that's important
with any living organism so I'm hoping
to try again once we get the farm you
know
well you're right you're right around
the corner from Paul and his operation
so you know picking up the I don't know
if he has will call or whatever but even
shipping you're gonna have it there the
next day and he's and his staff are
really good about answering
questions and I mean I might even learn
to the substrate business I got a couple
guys that I would be interested in
talking to you yeah yeah my wife and I
have been taking the lion's mane and a
few of the other prodigy all Stamets his
company they've been they've been great
it feels good to take something that's
healthy and safe yes yes I use it I buy
a different product but he he worked for
cost ounces an extractor for over a year
and then set up his own business down in
Ashland yeah in Southern Oregon and he's
got one product all his products are
fifty dollars a pound and so your
prescription or the dosage is four grams
a day so that's a hundred and ten days
worth a pound I mean for $50 it's
cheaper than supplements and yeah pawpaw
stuffs is expensive but fortunately we
had a wholesale account because sure
were retail establishments so we a lot
of a staff and stuff we'll get an
employee discount is able to sure the
one he the general I can't remember his
name but anyway he has one that's ten
varieties and they're different
primarily I don't we shouldn't have said
that but a lot is from China and have
they used in traditional Chinese
medicine for centuries grown here just
originally written yes right for people
oh yeah right exactly well like I was
telling you yesterday a friend of mine
his wife is is Chinese and they have a
little boy and they're in China right
now visiting grandpa and aunts and
uncles and what have you so one of his
wife's uncle's is owns a growing herb
traditional medicine store
Thank You Carrie okay here you go
apothecary right like you in Chinatown
that you'd see in Portland OR sale so I
gave a
us to all the Chinese names I said see
if you can get these dried and then we
can do I'm this isn't as complicated as
I'm making it sound but we can do a
Jurassic Park thing and get that those
those spores are reactivated so that we
can produce them and grow them yeah but
like some of the ones they're really
beautiful mushrooms like turkey tail
that's a big medicinal one and cordyceps
which is written those fascinating of
all um I think that's the one that will
actually eat insects that's correct
or it's the zombie yeah yeah yeah
because it will cause them to act it
actually affects their neural function
that's great it's tough it's really
fascinating yeah and yeah when you get
into the world it's like what's really
cool about it is it hasn't been
bastardized yeah and I don't know that
it can because my ecology is a is a
really big universe to go play in and
there just aren't that many Paul Stamets
around that's the reality of it yeah are
people who can explain the big picture
as well as he does and so you're not
gonna see well you're never gonna see a
canna con for mycologist okay okay yeah
you're not gonna have there's a song
from it like almost 55 years ago from
the Rolling Stone and the title of it
you know it's all you need to hear is
it's the west coast under assist the
under assistant West Coast promotion man
and that's what I was looking at an
upcoming event in Portland in August
like who is going to be there and it's
the first thing I thought it was that
song by the really you know button-down
you know selling the dream but I don't
think that that is there really going to
at least and well my life I may be in
your electrum I don't think you're gonna
see that happening it would be it would
be I would really blow my mind if it did
that you would see that the whole thing
would get turned on its head yeah yeah
well who knows I mean cannabis sure has
changed in your lifetime quite
dramatically you know it's really funny
is that I was thinking about this the
other day in a conversation with a
friend we go back to when Lyndon Johnson
was president okay as far as their
friendship so we were there before it
started I mean on this level they're you
know just 70 people lighting up or
whatever you know we're supposed to say
getting stoned and so I you know we
lived through the whole thing and
watched it morph into what it whatever
it is you know now and it just boggles
my mind that and one year prices could
drop 80% I just I mean there used to be
a time where you could grow some pounds
you know you shuffle them off for 3,200
and you know it was a nice little edge
unto your income I suppose but not
probably as many as you have I've been
to a few wreck farms or were you gonna
call him yeah and my first thought was
man you guys are in trouble that's a lot
of plants I mean look what are you
thinking you know I mean I would want to
grow 4,000 tomato plants without a big
crew and I don't know scaling is a
definite is a definite challenge that we
deal with
I still like dealing with people that
you know spits in the sunshine and
I'm just an old curmudgeon I don't buy
into this garbage about no indoors the
best station that isn't but you know he
is afraid of being high you know when I
started when I started when I started on
this journey my first crop went to
ground 43 years ago and the word
sensimilla hadn't even been popularized
yet so we didn't know we were done just
you know got and chop down some weed man
and the scene straight out of Thailand
and India and Sri Lanka what-have-you
and then it started in late seventies
early 80s the name game started out of
California course all these wacky names
and then in the late 80s when the two
first of the two major seed companies
today what you would know as sensi seeds
was they had a catalog called the SSS C
super sativa C Club and in their
listings they gave credit to several
seeds that came out of the Northwest
from a group called sacred seeds there
was a reason that Williams wonder will
look on a map and Williams organ and
wonder organ on the opposite side of a
valley downs of it are the main one of
their would he call it I guess the
forerunner of any of their strains is
the Afghani hashtag one number one
Afghani number one well that was one and
they this is they're giving him credit
and they're Catholic so obviously it's
true they bought that from sacred seeds
and then the other big catalog was I
can't think of his name but anyway the
seed bank and he hooked up with Sam
skunk man so that's where you got the
haze
and Northern Lights came out of British
Columbia the BCG a British Columbia
Growers Association and that whole thing
but that's when I saw it changing we
don't want all those imports man we can
no we'll make it better because I know
this guy that's got this really cool
I'll fill in the blank and I can cross
it with my fill in the blank and then
the seed thing was on I never imagined
that it would get the insanity that a
mate Peyton Manning push I mean really
if Obama push I mean come on and I'm
looking at a book right now that one of
the authors is Victoria Hayes I'd like
to see the birth certificate on that
before I buy into that one hmm but you
know you know i mean the whole grabbing
people's genetics and in a copyright or
whatever that scam is like you know if
somebody actually I had about four
people tell you know they got some of
your genetics and I said yes a lot of
cares I don't care you know doesn't mean
anything he'll get bastardize or the
first person that buys it because you
know I got this guy he's got just a
special cush from Anna wherever got
pimple Texas man you know we're gonna
cross that and make it super strange I'm
still waiting for that super extreme but
you know so far I retired from the
business and said yeah okay it didn't
happen I've been waiting for 40 years
but I haven't seen it yet I still don't
I don't believe that American breeders
for and not a criticism just a statement
of fact
will ever hit the levels of several
hundred years of hand selected seeds
from places like Sri Lanka and Thailand
and other places that's all we don't
have that sense of longevity or in terms
of
seeing the big picture it's all about
immediate results you know okay here's
an example one of the biggest developers
of dahlias is here in Oregon the Dahlia
farm down near a few miles south of me
and I go to this show every year and the
family's been growing dahlias and breed
them since the twenty Sol's you know
ninety over 90 years and I'm talking to
one of this grandsons or whatever and he
was telling me this took seven years you
know to develop this and this one you
know blah blah blah I said ah man you to
get some weed growers in here and these
guys can crank out a a new strain and
matter of a month or two so you need you
need to pick up the pace and he just
shook his head he said yeah whatever I'm
just saying that you know there's I I
don't sense this what are we gonna leave
the next generation you know 200 pushes
I don't know or or whatever they are
yeah well there's this the idea now that
using you know science science we can
and genetic markers we could identify
within a particular strain or cultivar
varietal what you know say for example
that specific marker that's associated
with helping with epilepsy so reducing
genes if we can identify that and we can
increase the you know the particular
cannabinoid that helps with that and we
can grow out you know 200 different
phenotypes and identify within seven
days if it's male/female what what
percent of that marker it's going to
it's going to Express then we can really
quickly make decisions and and and make
changes that would have taken a regular
grower you know generation and cycle and
cycle the to actually know so that to me
is both scary and exciting
but I hear what you're saying and I do
agree with you that we like we don't
have the same relationship with this
plant that we that these you know
indigenous cultures that the treat it
like sacred medicine had and that they
did there was I think much more
spiritual and I don't want to just throw
that out it's not I don't think the
cannabis plant is just a chemo var or
you know a particular expression of
these chemicals there's more to it than
that you know and maybe that's just the
spiritual side of me thank you
no I know it's it's look we've had what
eighty-two years of insanity since the
1937 law was passed at the urging of
DuPont and other big chemical companies
and you know the campaign politically
publicly has been it's Obama it's just
it's it's unreal all I'm suggesting is
is that the deal that started in the
late 80s with this you know there's
something magical about my strains
better than your string I think was to
the detriment of the plant itself and I
used to have a tagline on might when we
were before social media when we were
doing forums you know once you take the
whoop down to a chihuahua there's no
going back and I kind of think that's a
little bit where we're at well no that's
a lot where we're at it Tomatoes why is
it that we want to grow heirlooms well
we want flavor and color and and robust
plant right yeah we're sick
Roma's and tomatoes on the vine as they
call it you know this man right in the
store that store yeah yeah you know they
last the longest well I was in the
produce industry for several years and
yeah your biggest concern is what they
call legs from the time we pick it how
long
optimum time to get it into a
distribution center you know and so you
were probably uninterested hopefully but
in the 90s Calgene was a big project
that involve Monsanto UC Davis and they
were going to create the tomato that had
the longest shelf life or something by
replacing one of the DNA or RNA whatever
from using a potato so as they were just
stumbling around with genetic modified
plants and the publicity against it and
the media it just killed the project I
mean look up calgene sometime and it was
a mess and it was a harbinger of things
to come I think I don't want to eat
frankenfood I just trust the people at
Monsanto as much as I do law enforcement
you know I don't need your goodwill I
can figure this out I know where to get
Tomatoes seeds
I don't need your garbage and what the
average consumers walking into what's
that there's a lot there's a line from a
song by Grace Slick that said I don't
care if my lettuce has DDT on it as long
as it's crisp okay and that's kind of
where we're at as a society well yeah
but the tomatoes are so pretty well yeah
you see those lights he put in there
that hit you know this the special
lighting the
look and so it's frankenfood and all you
need to do is go to a mall and look at
the level of obesity that has struck our
children
I mean diabete to diabetes used to be an
old person's disease that's what you got
like in your 50s or 60s from well being
a [__]
you know drinking too much yeah I laugh
at that because I know you're battling
at my dad's battling it so I think well
yeah I mean you know we didn't make good
decisions you know I mean let's get
honest here
but to see children it's not just talk
they've locked 2025 years off their life
expectancy and I think that's just
horrible and you know if we treated our
dogs like we treat our children we'd be
arrested if you gave a dog a cup of
coffee and uh you know Winchell's donuts
the morning for breakfast
somebody had probably come in arrest you
for ld2 animals but you know you do it
we put you know cook machines in our
schools how are you gonna have a
thriving human being with all that junk
going in their bodies from the time they
get up til they go to bed oh and then
that's add in the let's sit in front of
and play whatever the latest in a
computer game is on there or worse or
worse now we'll know you have to walk
you can walk around with your phone and
play you know I don't even know the
games anywhere so I don't really care
what those fungi I think fungi will
bring I yeah I know it sounds corny to
some but I tomorrow delved into this
over the last two or three years I agree
with Paul Stamets that if fungi will be
what saves the human race from it so I
that I sincerely believe and like your
you just had the experience of eating
fresh oysters the other day that would
not be a hard diet to acclimate yourself
to I mean you could say you know I could
do without me if I could have this
quality of protein yeah I could see
moving towards our plant it's not a plan
to get my idea an on meat diet yeah and
I think I think it has a really big
important role to play I can know like
from your own experience that taking the
taking but using the oysters excuse me
the lion's mane and and whichever ones
you choose the cordyceps like I said it
might my recipe that I get is equal
parts by volume or weight well I'm not
sure it doesn't matter anyway Rishi
cordyceps and lion's mane and I think
that's a really nice balance okay I'm
not promoting it just I'm sure that
there are other people offering the same
same type of mixes and what-have-you and
if I get those mushrooms or when I do
get those mushrooms from China I'll be
more than happy to share those spores
with you I even have an electric stir
plate you know for mixing the spores
with the honey water and all that stuff
for inoculation and oh cool so we we we
emptied our house out have you seen that
book about how to the Maria Connery
condo book yeah well basically we
stripped this house clean furniture
everything gone Wow
one was I wanted to do the floors right
and it's a lot less money if they're not
having to move furniture around yeah so
part of it was so part of it was an
economic consideration but you know
since we've done that I haven't bothered
you'll get a lot of furniture I got a
couple Nordic recliners that was pretty
cool so I'm not a minimalist you know
I'm not going to sit in here
the Adirondack chairs from Walmart or
something but uh I just thought you know
owning a bunch of stuff is really a
downer I don't know is then you gotta be
responsible for you know yeah and you
have to maintain edit yeah tell somebody
about it oh that's really cool you know
it's like I had a friend of mine he was
really brilliant in high school and he
got a scholarship and went to Harvard
and then about a year after he graduated
Harvard he began a downward trajectory
alcohol and you know whatever other
drugs I remember one time he said if he
goes you know the people are still
really impressed that I went to Harvard
I said yeah but I don't know so what you
know write a book or something I guess
you know my years at Harvard I I don't
know
this last year getting ready to fully
retire and you know unloading the house
payment that was really liberating it's
like all I got to do is come over $300 a
month for property taxes here that's
great
that's like I paid more than that when I
got a high school you know rent having
300 a month so yeah it's pretty cool I
mean I don't know I just I don't feel I
need the other than toys you know I mean
some is another camera I want to get
because I know right well I really want
to learn
just for my own pleasure I guess is how
to do video editing on the iPad yeah and
there's and there's a really
professional work being done
I compete with that but just to see the
challenge there of mixing audio tracks
and with the video that I shoot and yeah
it's you know it's fun it's a lot better
than I got powdery mildew what should I
do in your case I'd take a machete and
take it down and hope you know for
better luck next year
yeah okay I mean I'm glad I'm glad
you're doing well and I'm glad we got to
talk about mushrooms and minimalism and
cannabis a little bit and I think it
would be really cool as we were doing
this I was just thinking in my head
it'll be cool to come back on and not
talk about how to grow psilocybin
mushrooms necessarily but to just talk
about some of the effects and usage and
some of your experiences I think would
be cool to share in a separate interview
if you're open to it yeah I am the only
thing making really I mean you know my
first experience with psilocybin was C
1968 so that's 51 years ago I want to
give it all away but I just want to say
that the micro dosing became a really
big part of this transition and what I
would use in your life huh
recently in your life yeah I start I
went to see Paul Stamets give us talk in
September about what nine months ago in
fact that was when I sent you that was
from that presentation and so I thought
hmmm I want to give this a shot so I did
and so I started October 1st and so
that's what eight and a half months now
and the one thing that I can say is that
when somebody asked me well what did it
do for instant clarity and that to me
was the biggest gift I could have ever
been given at this stage of my life
and had such knowledge been out there 10
20 years ago I would have anyway I'm not
I don't sell things and so it matters
not to me but I just know that people
who are suffering from depression
long-term hardcore depression that well
my daughter for example she died after
struggling for 12 years with she was
finally diagnosed as schizophrenic 12
years you know it was a real tragedy and
I just wonder if that could have been
helpful yeah and if we just get rid of
this silly social and political crap
about how we treat different situations
one is that for example end-of-life
that's a hard thing for anybody to deal
with you know you're given a diagnosis
you know you're gonna be you know tidy
up your affairs and so research at John
Hopkins and other major research have
found that administering these
psychotropic mushrooms help people make
that bridge psychologically so that it
isn't just doom they can put things in
perspective and why wouldn't we want to
do that for our friends our parents or
anybody I mean why wouldn't we want that
available or at least research it
correctly research not I don't know you
I listen to dead or Jimi Hendrix you
know kind of thing so uh yeah I guess
that if I had
soapbox that would be it that we need to
change and I'm involved with the group
here in Oregon trying to get it on the
ballot next year not to legalize not to
even decriminalize just to allow
legitimate research that has been done
at Harvard and John Hopkins and
universities in Asia and Europe and what
have you and so if we can bring the
freeze I like you know put some adults
in charge okay they don't have an agenda
trying to promote you know ABC mental
health services or something yep yeah
pharmaceuticals what I used to call it a
state bombed pharmaceuticals I always
thought would be a really good name for
a cannabis company so but in a serious
sense I mean the way that we're treating
our our citizens and our friends and our
family is it's really horrible
I watched my daughter go through every
prozac and I mean I can't even name them
all sure yeah and I just saw this
downward you know watching your child
die over 12 years was well it's not
something that I would want I would wish
I'm like I don't have enemies but I
would wish on nobody you know we have to
do something better I don't know that I
don't know I don't have the answers I'm
not a medical doctor don't pretend to be
but what I do know is that what we're
doing isn't working and how is your
father he's good he's uh he's
semi-retired now I mean he's got a whole
bunch of projects going on around in
there out on the Olympic Peninsula now
they actually had a whale wash up on
their Beach a grey whale this last my
goodness well
seeing one of those in person was crazy
so we went out there for that they got
to they were able to move it fortunately
because the thing stunk like you would
not believe as it's not proposing or the
famous video from the 60s when they blew
one up on the organ beach oh I heard
about that oh my god yeah I don't know
this is gonna slow news day but yeah the
we we go to Kate Mears for well watching
here in Oregon and to see them moving
north or south even at time of year
whatever yeah it's pretty uh they're
pretty incredible creatures I don't want
to take away from that I mean I ideally
it never would have washed up on the
beach but since it did we took the
opportunity to actually get to see it up
close absolutely uh yeah yeah I was
wondering this one one final thought you
know the life I'm not trying to get into
anybody's religious beliefs whatever
certainly not that but if we could agree
that life came from the ocean and the
former plants I think that's what it's
so remarkable about kelp kelp meal in
its purest form like the form that you
use and I used to pull it out of the
ocean dry it in the Sun and chop it up
yeah there's so much benefit there not
just the plants yeah I mean that's a
given you know for uh agriculture and
horticulture but taking a capsule a day
is remarkable of beneficial and it's
better quality that we get Acadian see
plants material yeah it's coming out of
clean water cleaner water than I would
want to necessarily do the Pacific with
all the tankers and what-have-you moving
cross it but uh yeah I started taking
kelp caps just uh I'd have to re weigh
it but it's probably a little bit more
than maybe a little bit more than a gram
a day and I saw because I when I got
this puppy from my good friend said it
forget it organics he gave me this
bulldog puppy and so I went to this we'd
be cool
holistic I love that term holistic pet
center and they had kelp meal yes I'm
reading the label it's the same variety
that we use in our soil mixes and look
the price was $18 a pound well because
they big rounded finer I mean I can live
with it you know so I started giving her
a teaspoon in the morning with her meals
and then teaspoon at night with her meal
and all the puppies that came out of
that same litter most of the puppies the
gift-giver test sees those puppies and
you say man without a doubt your dog is
the biggest the strongest healthiest and
so talking with a rep from ASL to trade
show one time he said look Jim he says
you know we love you guys but if people
quit using it near so we wouldn't even
mention it at a stockholders meeting you
know you guys are nothing which is you
know truth
the majority of kelp is used in
biomedicine
for human and animals but you want
stronger
whatever it is horses dogs livestock
kelp meal my chiropractor has draft
horse he's got like 20 of them talk
about a weird hobby I go do you write
them you can't write crap horses so what
do you doing them because he's just
beautiful to look at
anyway we were talking to in yeah and
guess what it's part of their diet
includes rock desk and kelp meal huh I
just found that really fascinating so I
turned him on to using concentrates
because the selection and quality price
and then I got him off of glacial rock
dust and over to basalt and you know he
he was really impressed with the changes
that he saw in his but anyway so there's
more in commonality with plants and
animals than we probably want to address
or can't address yeah you know I think I
just trying to interesting when I
started adding it to my mushroom
substrate hello wow this is really cool
I mean this is like and I want to get
back to you on that question because you
asked a really legitimate question that
I cannot find a definitive answer can we
tweak the substrate and increase
whatever properties is we're looking for
we want to a more meat like flavor will
say in a oyster mushroom can we
manipulate that with the sub just
because you can draw it on newsprint I'm
sure we can and we just don't have the
research on it yet no we don't I'm
positive that it would change the
flavors and I mean that's that's what
happens with all vegetables I don't see
why the pathways good fungus like yeah
and so that's something that my friend
and I have really been focused on is
trying to bring some of the practices
that we've been doing for several years
in the area of soil mixes which one of
those can we bring over here to this and
make see a benefit a viable benefit yeah
and I and I think that we we are but you
know it's kind of like you already know
I don't want to sell substrate I mean
sure I don't want to listen to
you know well I got a run for today
alright man you so much we'll have to
walk the talk kelp at some point cuz I
got some stuff I want to share with you
and then I'd love to talk to you about
some of these psychedelics and just okay
just talk experiences and some of that
so good it's again soon man thank you
very much thank you have a good one
correct
[Music]