yeah so as you can imagine this is the
most sterile environment on the property
so our head of extraction uh he went to
MSU and got his uh plant science degree
um so he kind of started off with this
but then you know he as the company grew
you know we got he got pulled more into
the extraction side and there wasn't a
whole lot of time for him to do this so
um probably a few months ago we just uh
hired a girl from MSU um with a plant
biology degree so she's kind of coming
in under the his ropes and he's kind of
teaching her all the nuances of the disy
culture lab and she's kind of running
with it right now so we're excited to
actually you know get somebody in here
who has the time and you know knowledge
so is the main purpose uh just to speed
up your propagation or is it to get
cleaner cleaner are you trying to
cleaner plants address something in
particular yeah um so I would say
definitely cleaner plants um also kind
of like a you know genetic Bank you know
we there's a few strains that you know
aren't selling much at the time being
you know we can kind of keep them on
reserve in here for a while until maybe
one on do another run of it and see if a
great yeah yeah so um but yeah yeah so
it's actually you know looking pretty
good um yeah you can inside there
okay this past uh winter and summer um
we did some breeding of our own and are
really trying to get a strain that um
finishes really early um because as you
can imaginea Montana you know weather I
mean we can have you know snow in middle
of September you know I've seen snow end
of August before um so some of our
breeding projects we actually harvested
about you know I would say four weeks
ago um which was really exciting um for
us so how big were the plants uh you
know they're they're nice you know they
weren't huge but you know and some we
started a little bit later than others
you know some were about this big and
some were about this big that's great
yeah so I mean and all that's going to
go towards uh just biomass for
extraction right now until we kind of um
get the ball rolling and kind of get
everything honed in a little bit more on
the genetics side there was uh quite a
bit of
variation um so yeah so I'm excited for
next summer that'll be cool to kind of
hone that in but um yeah all right very
cool thank you TI culture
lab that's in a 40ft container out here
yep yeah we love the shipping containers
out here they're pretty
nice