[Music]
so when they bought this land probably 5
years ago the only thing on this
property was this barn out here and the
big wooden structure and that was an old
grain silo um so there wasn't water
there wasn't any power and it was just
kind of a wide open field so oh wow all
of this has happened in the last five
years few other things like Alpha Beta
the first thing we built has now been
taken down yeah yeah the original
Greenhouse that we had kind of built uh
that's nice though because I just Vis
visited Paradise Organics you know and
they're retrofitting into a building so
you have all these you know things are
not necessarily where you want them to
be and that's really common yeah in this
and there was there still is a lot of
that here cuz I mean there was so many
different stages of this build you know
first it was the little Greenhouse that
we built with just
a generator and you know plug in power
tools and dig borrowed us an
extension the first lifts when we were
building we didn't have
power Char Ros extens she's a sweetheart
to for us to move in we originally going
to put it in the back field but the
first Outlet to get power was like
$40,000 just to bring it in and we were
like we had enough money for half of
this Warehouse building in that Nexus
and that was our first because
everything before that was the Old Farm
which was just hoop houses off grd most
sustainable Farm but comes with some St
wood stes at 3 a.m. yeah
yeah so yeah and you can see this is was
kind of like the start of the second
stage was this back half and then the
other Nexus that's connected to this
and then it was the third stage was that
building so we added another 3,000 ft
onto that and the fourth stage which
where we're going to now is uh we built
this as soon as we heard or as soon as
recreational passed in Montana yeah um
this was our project you know Danny does
all the facilities he's you know doing
anything that a breaks down or designing
any of the plumbing anything like that
uh but we also have Jared who does all
of our flowering green houses we've got
Connor and Woody who manage the
propagation Department which is Mom's
and then we've got Sawyer who does IPM
so they've kind of taken it a little
further than either of us originally
just because at the scale you are
specializing so each of these beds rep
represents one of our Banger strains
that we replicate and continue to grow
you'll see that we're in a system right
now we're in a complete revamp to make
our mul layer something more sustainable
um and hopefully reusable um it what's
really caused this was having shortages
and cocoa and and we knew we wanted to
eventually over the time over the years
we've done uh living mulches You Know
cover crops we've done wood chips but if
you do two wood chips four runs in a row
with these year round green houses
you're going to get obvious problems
with potentially nitrogen robbing it
doesn't break down we want to evolve to
a system where we're either using
something reusable that's roll up and
put and you can put it back down or
we'll rotate through cocoa one time that
gets stirred in uh wood chips one time
we've played around with recycling our
own hemp fiber but all that does is clog
up wood chippers
so we're in R&amp;D on both scrog systems
mulch systems and what's our third uh
Rock for those the two those were the
two ones I thought we had one more um
for
R&amp;D those are the main things that we're
still like trying to develop something
that's scalable reusable and works well
um first of all we'll if possible we'll
scrape some of that mul that wood chip
off that's why we'll only use wood chips
once a year I don't ever use them in the
mom room because wood chips come from
outside at a nursery and we ain't
messing with that that's why another
reason why we kind of like Coco but wood
chips we'll use them and you'll see them
in our in our hoop houses uh great thing
because we're only running one run a
year in there and those wood chips
aren't uh haven't been a factor at all
at the end of the season but I think
when you're getting four Cycles a year
or four and a half you're much more
likely to have that issue and so the big
thing we do is we don't use wood chips a
lot um we'll only use it maybe once a
year Coco was our tried and true even
though it was kind of expensive um it's
a
byproduct and it just get stirred right
back into the soil when we amend so
we'll test these pretty frequently
usually two weeks for Harvest in the
greenh houses uh as needed for these if
there's any issues or when he's sending
soil tests in um Connor will take core
samples of all this and send those in
too um otherwise this because it's
consistent that's one reason we don't
have Mom room in a greenhouse is
consistency year round this is one of
the only like year round air conditioned
spots that we have and it's just so that
we don't have to hit a moving Target
with varying light intensities and
temperatures and humidi where Mom room
needs to be consistent so when you
remend your soil testing and then mixing
the nutrients and the cocoa for M layer
back no will Top dress the uh it'll be
after the re amending yep so we'll top
dress put the craft mix down uh
sometimes we'll lightly stir that in
sometimes it'll just kind of stay on the
top and get watered in depends on if
it's caking that's based off soil test
the soil tests uh you can see Jared's
soil calculator if you want he's kind of
made his own version of
you know all those other ones um and so
we'll amend based on those obviously mom
rooms a little bit different uh
prescription than the flowering rooms
we'll top dress that essentially craft
mix just a series of of all our base
amendments then we'll plant um and we'll
put the cocoa on after and then the mom
room gets all handw watered everything
else has irrigation okay so then at the
end of the
cycle the plants
testing soil is the soil staying here in
this room and then like I see him with a
shovel over
there trans see have you already dug in
some nutrients yes but let's go ask
them how's it going
Woody how's it going good this is Tad
hussy he's uh Tad how's going he was
just asking if you have already uh
amended this uh bed as you're doing your
top as you're doing your planting so
yeah we just started like a chart we
numbered all the beds so we can keep
track of like monthly for how often beds
are needing food so these these beds I
just PL out of them today so the new
ones that are going in are the ones that
were here got amended a little over a
month ago so we're going to just add
some as we transplant them today to
start them off and add some in there I
can see you have some yep it's it's just
a fish meal and gips
Cy that's all you needed yeah yeah
that's kind of what we've been
as Amendment it's most
nitrogen in the mob room it's
like they start to get to Green don't do
anything if they start to get test and
we can top dress craft mix any kind the
cycle based
on we usually don't do any Leaf tissue
tests or anything like that not that we
haven't but
um doesn't seem so you're removing all
of this biom yep I'm not sure is this
the old moms is what you chopped out of
there or is
this so he just killed something that we
don't need so as we sit down every month
and plan out our next planting Cycles
maybe we have too much in inventory one
thing's not selling we'll balance that
maybe we have moms that have only been
used one time or not at all hopefully
not at all if we've done our job right
uh or hopefully not not at all
so
yeah how do we get them how are you
supporting them Danny made these unist
Strat because I I ran into this problem
trying to do pallets and tray and then
the plastic Palace just oh yeah handle
the weight the wheel weight yeah yeah uh
so uh unistra is my best friend uh I
mean since I've started growing uh about
eight years ago uh I've just started
using Unistrut for just about anything I
can it's so versatile easy to work with
and there's so many different uh types
of bracketry
huh yep yep throw your tray on there and
then so all of our uh so all of our beds
uh in our green houses too uh we built
you know pretty much a very similar
design uh except for they're not on
Wheels yeah that's look great I love how
clean you guys keep in here that drain y
having that drain is awesome
yeah so these were actually just plugged
yesterday
um so
yeah so they'll obviously top all the
moms move it into here it'll spend uh
you know usually approximately 14 days
sometimes 12 um until we are rooted and
ready to go at that Point they'll get
moved into the bedroom the reason we
obviously bring you into the tissue
culture room first the mom room second
the Clone room third and then we'll go
to the bedroom um it has more flow as a
harvest system and what we're doing is
we're following if you picture this grow
as a river we always start at the top of
the river Upstream top of the stream at
the cleanest spaces and we move through
just assuming that your oldest plants or
your harvested plants have the most
potential to be what we would consider
unclean um so it flows better with the
grow and the Harvest than it does with
the tour because we end up zigzagging
our our greenos are all staggered three
weeks apart and so we'll start at the
most freshly planted going to the most
uh soon to be harvested at the end and
those will it'll all flow according to
their age
class so you're just using these look
like Costco shop yeah actually these
lights were um we got a bunch of these
lights with the tissue culture La kit
okay so and we just had a bunch of
extras and we were like ah and this has
been enough light for them uh yeah we've
noticed if we give them any more light
they tend to Yellow out a little bit
harder so they definitely liked you know
less light from what we've been seeing
we've tried a few different of uh you
know you know the Lux LED lights the
Clone lights um you know a few different
you know your typical you know single
t5s and then you know these been
actually working pretty well for us all
the looks where we're getting yellowed
out in the middle um and maybe it's just
cuz you know we could probably DW that
in and feed more
but this is this why would you uh
Advance anything past or buy more
expensive lighting when this is just
done the trick so perfectly for
us and then are you dipping the cuts in
anything y yeah uh zerall zerall and I
want to say a panic for a dunk and as
far as a rooting hormone oh God we've
gone through everything what are we
using right now well currently we're
using the uh the Athena rooting hor oh
really y so we've tried every single
thing possible including nothing had
just about as good of results yep we
rotate through we used to do aloe a lot
of the things that we used to do that
were more
um k&amp;f didn't scale that well at least
not an effective Manner and so we've
kind of like phased out certain you know
even what we found is we can get away
with less te's we used to be just you
you can imagine this scale what kind of
te's we're brewing and we've kind of
spend doing less and less of those and
I've seen no negative results from that
either so
yeah so this is a bedroom these are all
en rolling tables we usually do 6in pots
this is where we found um we used to
make all of our own soil for the whole
facility and this is actually where the
most impact for us has been for kiss
soil is what we found we cannot make it
and have the same we showed you those
pictures uh a couple years ago of like
the side by sides and it was noticeable
at scale a couple times in a row and at
that point we started buying kiss every
time for our veg soil uh even though
obviously we don't have huge soil needs
once our living soil systems are in
place I mean at this scale there still
quite a bit and that's part of why we
use six inch pots um we can almost get
just as good a growth in two weeks two
to three weeks in a vroom and two weeks
it V in the greenhouse be letting them
tap in before flipping with our four
green houses you end up having a harvest
every 3 weeks so if these spend two
weeks in here you always have three days
on either end to clean run or if
something ever gets pushed you've got a
little bit of a window we do have
another bedroom for spring planting
season that's the same size and we'll
use that if we need to but generally
speaking we're trying to have a high
utilization rate on our vedro high
utilization rate on our clone room and
our system is all planned pretty much
perfectly for where we're at right
now so this is our first round of an
experiment with a new multilayer that we
were hoping to be reusable we can
already see there's some flaws in this
this is a recycled hemp fiber that Danny
found yep okay
um so that a lot of well a lot of the
people are using this for micro greens
and whatnot but there's a company out of
Canada uh Terra fiber that makes a lot
of these mats uh for as far as weed
suppression um for micro greens um
erosion control um so I kind of thought
it'd be kind of fun to test it out as a
mulch layer um what are your thoughts on
it right now uh right now you know I
don't know if we'll stick to it I don't
know if we'll go back to it I mean it
was kind of a really cool thought uh in
using it um I don't think it's going to
be very easy to pull them back out of
the beds after the round is over and
then reuse them we need two runs to be
competitive with the price of Coco it
looks like it'll just pull right out but
those roots are going to grow into the
bottom with a bunch of soil there's no
way you're rolling up that much and then
how are you going to pressure wash it in
the winter there's some rubber stuff but
I'm a little bit worried about like
leeching that we could you know like
rubber matting so this is a mat yeah yep
just rip open oh okay and then also I'm
concerned that it's going to do what
Pete Moss would also do which is hold a
lot of moisture on the top and kind of
become a sponge and instead of like just
trapping it it's going to actually
evaporate into the air which defeats the
whole point that's why we're pretty well
deed up for for winter runs in here and
that the
main the main reason for this then is
just moisture retention yeah y That's
your biggest thing battle here in the
community y okay is we don't want it a
in the air that could then promote uh
Milo or just battling making our
dehumidifiers uh work excess but also
what we'll find and we'll show you in
zone three there is when we don't have
any mulch you start to get exposed roots
a little bit of compaction and you're
way more like it's so much harder to
read that um first of all soil moisture
because the Top's always dry and you you
get Dy off in those that top surface
layer you'll start to get uh a little
bit more yellowing at inconsistent times
or a little bit faster it's it's it just
becomes harder to read it it you lose
your stability when you're evaporating
that much soil and and you're more like
just have Regional uh attrition you know
certain leaves will fade out a week or
two before you want them versus that and
the beauty of Coco was it could just be
stirred in and game on I mean I love the
idea of a mulch but what I struggle with
is when I want the biggest the biggest
thing on scale is being able to re amend
those BS quickly and be able to just mix
whatever it is into the media Without
Really changing your
physical yeah so I could see where Coco
might work for that because
yeah it's not very sustainable and
that's kind of what we're looking for is
a more sustainable you know long-term
users that we can reuse it's sustainable
in that it's a byproduct but not in that
we have to ship it here and it's
footprint on it is is pretty terrible
and we're trying to revisit all these
things and find um coste efficient
Alternatives besides just as as this
Market gets more and more competitive
first of all having a living soil system
is going to be never having to replace
this soil after and oh by the way these
two greenh houses are all kiss soil um
yep yep this was the big order we put in
with you yeah and uh what we found is we
got these finished out two months before
recreational was launching and typically
we would have uh built our own soil and
we had prepped to do that we were not in
a position during Harvest to do that and
then after testing it in the bedroom and
seeing what happened it was like we
pulled the trigger on you know scale and
Bo Bo we haven't looked back as far as
that's concerned yeah I think you saw
the lights just kicked on yeah what was
that about this uh Wadsworth system that
we have which is our control system
there's a light sensor right there that
blue thing and because it's cloudy out
so these uh LED lights are all dimmable
so obviously it's cloudy right now uh
typically these are only one week into
uh they've been they were transplanted
one week ago so they're still just at
the end of their shock phase this is the
first day that the curtains the lights
have been open all the way and or the
curtains have been open all the way and
the parameters just got turned up just a
little bit to like four 500 par so
that's why these are now kicking on this
winter we're going to drop these lights
actually a little bit because they're
dimable we maybe went a little high and
a little under lit a little conservative
on three three Cycles a year this is
great with all the supplemental Sun but
if you have a cold cloudy
December we're maybe just a little
deficient on light we called you last
winter when we had that issue and I
think
between the CO2 two burer being kicked
on at a time when they were already
underperforming with their power levels
and we uh maybe were a little actually
deficient on our soil tests yeah
whatever M and the humidity was really
high because we were it was Winter and
you end up getting high humidity in the
winter we're always battling that that's
why there's you know quite a bit of
there's more than my all my vehicles
I've ever bought in the humidifiers in
this facility you know what I mean and
that's for largely three months a year
the rest of the time we're running super
efficient you know and I mean Montana is
a great climate for wet walls with our
you know warm dry but not too hot walk
down there and take a look at that
absolutely so this is Danny and this is
a great example of where we all like
design out big systems and we wanted to
maximize our square footage in canopy so
these greenh houses are actually 4200
square feet those other ones are 3,000
if I were to do it all over they'd all
be 3500 we'd have instead of having six
rows and four rows we'd have five in
each one they'd have perfect consistency
but this is example where what we found
was with our dehes back there not
blocking light we were starting to get
mildew in the winter time on the front
rows where we were maybe having not as
good a cycling at that time we had baf
fans or uh yeah vaf fans Not HF fans
yeah so what we
did in this size we have them on the
other one because they worked just fine
here we weren't being able to stir our
air well enough so we added everything
we could so we started first we added
more dehumidifiers then we added uh we
reconfigured our air flow uh then it was
summer and we didn't have any problems
and we thought we figured it out then
last winter we added these and now what
we're doing is we're flipping sooner and
throwing shorter canopies especially
during that winter month but we're going
to have to drop the lights in order to
do that so we
are we'll never have a problem again I
know
[Laughter]
it we solved every issue
so you can see these have already had
their uh transplant Leaf up they've been
uh uh these have all been pruned from
the bottom um one week in we've been
really good at avoiding transplant shock
you can still see the remnants on a
touch of saggy leaves but overall if
they had even a little bit of micro
yelling at this point I wouldn't be
concerned uh these beds are like rehab
to them even if they were to get
unhealthy which we don't let them um
they tap in and and two weeks later we
flip
CO2 levels Elevate at night yes with
this much soil in room yeah oh yeah that
that's we
don't in the summer um depends if they
get too high uh we will have you know
some on occasions uh fans will kind of
burp the greenhouse um and kind of
maintain there but um they don't go up
too too high
um empty Greenhouse in an empty
Greenhouse yeah yeah yeah
um but uh no they generally will come up
to about you know anywhere from 600 to
700 ppms at at night now the well the
interesting thing though is an empty
Greenhouse will outperform these beds
with no plants to suck up all that CO2
will outperform that CO2 burner all day
long we can get it up to like 12 and
1500 on an empty Greenhouse right after
we've turned the beds or uh amended in
new microbes
and for the first year now there's a
little bit more volume on these green
houses but there's also correspondingly
more soil our beds that we made that
were more mature outperformed CO2 Wise
from a CO2 production standpoint
significantly over the kiss Organics now
I haven't seen any dramatic differences
I think it actually has to like the soil
almost produces more CO2 or or our
sensors are off but for a long time the
kiss Greenhouse is empty would only get
up to 600 00 and the nexuses would get
up to 12 13400 at night about that
actually yeah pretty interesting
um so all these floor fans too it's just
max air flow that we cannot get enough
as long as it's not blasting on the
plants wet walls um perfect for this
climate we are hot we're dry you use a
wet wall in Florida you can't get that
but first of all we hardly ever have a
day over 90 anyway
one or two a summer and we could get
this 20 or 30° cooler than ambient
anytime we want we've never been too hot
unless a breaker blue or a you know what
I mean and if we do get alarms four or
five different cultivators will'll say
oh it's too hot in zone four what's
going on uh here you can
see the green houses now these lights
are reading on different Cycles what we
found especially in these North Green
Houses was the winter sun was getting
blocked on the south two rows so when we
programed these lights I had these two
put on his own in those four so they'll
actually read and I can set them
differently um it's less applicable to
the South Greenhouse but especially in
that North Greenhouse those lights will
be running 24 hours a day even or not 24
12 hours a day and on a sunny day the
north for Rosa lights will just let the
sun take over as needed and the Shaded
sections of a green us so we can really
micromanage accordingly with our
settings and of course now we can do it
from our phone with the Wadsworth system
you can have every single parameter
you've got outside you've got Zone 1 2 3
4 temperature humidity um your power
levels your
VPD and your CO2 levels right now on a
day like today or in the summer we won't
run CO2 burners at all because it's just
it's a fart in the wind but uh this big
change here is that instead of the old
days of having to stoke wood stoves at
midnight 3 and 6 a.m. now if I wake up
in the middle of the night on a 40 below
night in the middle of
winter I can look at get this and just
make sure that everything's okay and
there's no
emergencies yeah Green Crack that's
sativa leaning this is Don Fuego this is
a strain that we bred out of two of our
Legends which are one of our bestselling
Cannabis Cup winning strains which is
donni burger and sweet and sour which is
strain we bred ourselves and this is the
baby of that and so we're trying to
always stay ahead of it we proved it
over in my shop this is only the first
commercial run we've ever done of it um
and we're pretty excited about it new
release coming up Don Fuego but you can
really see strain specific sativa time
as you walk towards the more indas
you'll see that short that stacking
they're way further along eventually
we're going to plant just green houses
of sativas just green houses at indas
but we actually like that Harvest
spacing right now for the size of our
cruise to be able to do a a 5-day
Harvest and I can even spread it over 10
days depending on my timing but
eventually it's going to make more sense
for perfect utilization of veg and clone
rooms to have
uh 70-day green houses and 60-day Green
Houses we don't have significant
problems and we stick to our system we
don't go looking for them too much I
can't tell you how many times people
have brought me a uh immature aphid or a
winged aphid and everyone loses their
[ __ ] and more often than not the living
soil system handles any pests you're
usually able to get through it
and we don't if we did our job right all
up until there as far as bugs are
concerned
either we don't have to worry about them
or the ones there are are so minimal or
so minuscule that uh launching a war
halfway through flower when we've got
more green houses coming has in fact
done us more good than bad we have
insecticidal soap root drenched plants
and more bad than good or so more bad
than good thank you we have incal root
drenched plants because of uh soil
aphids that people told us were roote
aphids that weren't and we just about
fried a whole greenhouse and it our
treatments have literally done more
damage when we go aggressive out of our
comfort
zone uh and do more than a small tester
we do more damage than good so we don't
panic and and like I said if you put
that soil in a microscope someone
professional is going to tell me there's
something to be scared of in there well
I mean the health of the plants tell you
everything another interesting thing to
note uh Golden Goat very specifically is
one of our best prayers in This Kiss
soil and I believe a lot of it is our
light it tends to get this light crab
cloth I think we reduce our
transpiration by not having as intense
of light um and and but for the longest
time I was like maybe this kiss soil is
like too rich or I I couldn't figure out
why my best prey and strain had it's
subtle but it's there and I think it's
our light intensity this dropping of the
light uh we're just slightly out of our
perameter and this is one of our
indicators also because it's a short one
it doesn't get quite as much light to
say Donnie Burger you
know this greenhouse though a little bit
smaller we typically have way less
problems with mildew or anything of that
nature um oh here we go right
here freak Show it's got seeds in
it that's also the first thing that's
going to Herm if you have it um I used
to think that some of our oldest strains
would get that and that they did have HP
but they I haven't ever seen any
significant impacts from that
specifically and furthermore uh I have
brand new fenos that we just pheno
hunted and they'll randomly do that on
the second run in a green in my shop
so I don't know what it is never tracked
it down doesn't actually impact that
much but it is a curiosity that
everybody who's known their salt has
always wanted to blame on HP Lon and
it's not been the
case so yeah four strains one two three
four or is there five five strains in
this green house these are actually
pretty lower test some this is one of my
favorite strains smell that forbidden
fruit it's so that living soil really
brings out those
turs um but it tests 16% it's one of our
that good but I think we're about to win
Award with the joints supp from it so
that's why we're growing this is
to
absolutely that's why Donny Burger which
is 33% gets grown in every single
Greenhouse even though I between you and
me hate to grow it it's the worst
linkiest least producing finicky little
thing you've ever seen it's not that bad
but it sucks Danny what's your favorite
cult oh boy uh honestly the forbidden
fruit the forbidden fruit it's uh it's
I'm not personally a big fan of high
testing you know THC um my those days
are over for me uh I would much rather
you know to have a higher turpine
profile and just you know still be able
to function golden goat's my second
favorite it's got that it's Island skunk
I mean just smell it it smells like it
belongs in Hawaii you know um and this
this is a sativa one not a particularly
Frosty she's late to the party on um but
it's a legend and stood the test of time
even though this is only like a
22er she still stays on the shelves cuz
this is a Montana cult classic
absolutely a legend
strain so we'll go from basically it
gets harvested it all gets wheeled in on
um dry flower
hangers so we've reduced a whole bunch
of touch points on this Farm by just the
Harvest crew will hang it in a dry flow
on these dry flow RS right here okay it
used to be what is this this is a dry
flow hanger these are amazing and here's
another uh interesting this goes here uh
dry
power company let me get oh my camera's
going okay dry fler that guy's awesome
he made these originally kind of for
hemp um this has been a game changer for
us as far as reducing touch points at
the farm it used to be that you would
Harvest put it in a bin bring it over to
somebody at a station
they would take it out of the bin they
would Leaf all their plants it would get
stuck in another bin brought to the
drying room hung on some sort of screen
system so each branch had to be hung
manually by hand and then when they go
to take it off after 14 days they got to
unthread out of the netting or ropes
while with this you reduce all those
touch points they harvest it they leave
it right there they stick it on a dry
flower rack it goes onto here which gets
pushed in now then you just take the
whole thing here and the real Beauty in
the system it used to be a giant straw
you touch every Branch one more time
here you take this half you throw it a
bin take this half you throw it a bin
you literally can just strip these down
then it can be [ __ ] process we Rel
three entire touch points with the dry
flower system it's and you can now fit
just as much room we have every kind of
infrastructure you can imagine you know
and I've tried with winches on racks
that raise the whole thing as you load
it so you don't have to be up on a
ladder and dry FL it's like the [ __ ]
when you get a product that you really
love that makes your life easier it's
totally worth promoting it and then
another interesting thing this is where
there's so much space in this industry
for renovation and Innovation is that
when we first ordered these they would
send these aluminum uh sh lengths of of
light because of shipping cost and it
was more than the price of the dry flow
hangers which is what I want was these
metal things well Danny was like look if
you just cut Danny clipped them all and
he made them work on unistra and then he
told dryflow hey instead of having to
spend twice as much on shipping just
send everybody these and make it
Unistrut which is available at every
Home Depot and you already know Danny's
love for Unistrut yeah so then they
custom made notches for us which I just
found out they stopped doing but I don't
know why because that changes his whole
game now you I mean there can't be very
much money in just giving all of it to
shipping like it's way easier to ship
thousands of these than it is these long
lengths so just those little things of
like don't use some aluminum prefabbed
specific size thing use a readily
available building material that is at
every you know and so so these are all
this is off right now but you can see
there's air flow air
flow air conditioner humidifier
dehumidifier it's got all the things to
keep it at 60% in these 60 uh degrees
and Summer and the winter even with
seasonal
fluctuations so this is the same thing
except for they just took this down
bucked it now it's going to sit here
while it waits to be trimmed so this is
where we'll put all of our flour it'll
uh basically it's been it's kind of
curing now it'll be trimmed sometime in
the next week
um get a little more in here same deal
waiting for bucking um it just sits in
these bins um closed up this is one
whole Greenhouse in here yep that's one
green
house mostly
anyway yeah so this is where we process
all capsules carts um and sometimes
package pre-orders for wholesale um this
is a capsule brand that we're just about
to release in Montana it's uh going on
people's shelves here probably within
the week and it's finally just Master
packed out and ready for uh retail ready
sales um it's a niche in the market that
isn't what represented it's not a huge
portion of the market but there's nobody
in that space so awesome and we already
have a big following with our capsules
and we already had all the Machinery so
it it makes perfect sense to be a
non-threatening third party brand that
is available on other people's shelves
now I heard here in Montana in the
dispensaries they call it dly style
because they just throw all the buds in
a jar and you not necessarily branded
that's only a few dispensaries actually
uh typically speaking like we're all
prepackaged now but we try and do that
in a fresh manner because it's just the
way the regulations have uh pushed us we
used to do deli style and some people
still do it's strain by strain you just
get a big jar and you pick what you want
and they weigh it out in front of you
you know and does that make it hard
though as a cultivator to build a brand
if you're a grower because they're just
throwing in jar they're not necessarily
promoting we typic we'll do two types of
wholesale one is packag and branded and
the way we avoid that is it goes in our
packaging before it leaves our facility
and then you don't have a choice um and
it kind of depends on which Market we're
in if it's a market we're already well
represented in we don't need to uh get
the brand or maybe we have something
that's starting to get 6 months old and
somebody wants to White Label it as
their own um in which case it's yours do
what you want with it but consumers are
looking on the shelves now for
Collective elevation because you've
built 100% we're uh as far as Montana
goes we're a reasonably renowned name
for our just even our open source
information of like just the cultivators
know who we are and now that those
cultivators are actually out selling
their capacity they're coming to us
often times first which is it's crucial
that's the future you know you have to
be retail ready and
[Music]
branded