so it's Adam Arnold Collective elevation
um we're in Boseman Montana is where
we're based out of our dispensaries are
in uh but Billings Missoula and Boseman
as well tell me about Collective
elevations since this is you know your
your company yeah well uh this was all
founded
from being passionate about growing
cannabis since essentially I was a
little kid and so
initially what happened when Montana
started allowing legal medical marijuana
uh I purchased a farm that was
completely off grid out in the middle of
nowhere and went with hybrid just just
basically hoop house facilities you're
just running one or or pulling tarp
light dep and I learned a lot uh my
business partner Carl at the same time
was an indoor fully Hydro salt-based guy
and at the end of a couple of years we
were just friends at that point a couple
of years we saw that one of us was doing
significantly better on our yields and
overall just profitability and the other
one was and then still getting winners
off and so we saw the potential of
living soil and and what it does for
plant Health uh the problem with the
offgrid facility even though it was
extremely sustainable was you had to
make up for that with a ton of work
stoking wood stoves carrying water just
a a lot of the tea tanks were trash cans
and carrying five gallon buckets 100
yards so there was so many
inefficiencies in that off-- grid style
and waking up at 3:00 a.m. stoking these
wood stoves I was always dreaming of man
what if I could see this on my phone
what if I had a greenhouse that could
run all winter and you didn't have to
worry about it and so that sparked what
is the modern iteration of our our
current Farm um as soon as 2017 legisl
legislation pretty much cemented the
Cannabis industry in Montana as being
around a stay and not subject to
shutdown and lawsuits that was the first
time we could really invest um in
anything more than a rental because we
didn't know that if it wouldn't get shut
down entirely so at starting in
2017 we started building this out and we
built it out in about four different
phases um learning as we went and just
always trying to troubleshoot and evolve
to have the best most efficient system
we possibly can so this is the biggest
as far as I know growth facility in
Montana let alone living soil um and
that all evolved from both seeing the
potential of plant Health uh the quality
we started winning cannabis cups in
Montana really early and we saw that
living soil was outpacing our Hydro at
the time
and then of course you take into account
cost Effectiveness and once the labor
the initial soils in the the labor
savings Alone um all the dots were
finally just pretty connected it was
apparent over a series of years that
this style has chops um for both quality
is so rare in life that you get a win
win win that's better for the people
better for the planet cheaper to produce
and that's not really a thing that
happens in business very often usually
one of those things has to be sacrificed
and we stumbled upon something and we've
just kind of been running with it ever
since so even
though um you're organic that's that's
almost just a perk on the commercial
scale because of the you're you're
finding it's actually cheaper less labor
um and has all these other commercial
benefits on scale that make it
worthwhile and Organics is well that may
be something you're passionate about
it's uh it's sort of like an added bonus
on top of all the other absolutely I
mean if we can if we can be more
sustainable than everyone else then and
that is a core premise of our our
mission statement as a company um that
being said it so that was actually why
we started down this path we just
realized that there was these secondary
benefits of of also a better product
that turned out to be cheaper and and
then a few other things that happened to
us like our local grow store shutting
down a few years ago now since we've had
sparked us to getting Trailer Load you
know filling up semi- trucks worth of
amendments and doing it once a year and
planning ahead and just trying to scale
in every way that we possibly could
before the rest of the industry uh gets
to that level beating them to
Market so uh tell me tell me your name
and your role here at Collective
elevation um so my name is Danny James
um I am the facility manager SL
cultivation director sometimes um you
know I do most of facility maintenance
uh design um you know uh do a lot of the
construction and you know figuring out
how new systems can be implemented or to
make things more efficient and um better
for the company as as a whole ni see you
wear a ton of hats and kind of solve so
many hats yep I uh I dabble in you know
minor electrical I do all the plumbing
for irrigation systems tank setups uh pH
injection systems um yeah I do
fabricating I do yeah I do jack of all
trades really now were you a grower
before you uh yes yeah so I have been
cultivating cannabis for about uh eight
nine years now
um started off growing in a fourcc car
garage for a local dispensary um and um
that plants were on cinder blocks and uh
plastic trays and since after that uh I
went to a Coco Hydro setup um with a
dispensary here in town uh spark one and
I was there I would say I learned a
majority of my you know cultivation
practices and whatnot um through them
and then uh so it was a very different
transition coming from a super sterile
you know plant environment using cocoa
substrate Hydroponics salts you know
mixing up batch tanks and then coming to
like the whole living soil you know kind
of organic you know way of things so it
was a fun transition and I don't think I
could ever go back to growing in
Hydroponics
yeah yeah so last question I'm I'm super
interested in the Unistrut tray
TBL cuz I need that at my house yeah I
will have to draw you up some plans are
you welding the unistruts um so the
trays that you were interested in uh for
our mother room uh that all of our two
4x4 beds are on those were not welded
together um they make Universal kind of
brackets that you can Bolt together all
of the Unistrut and kind of make you
know whatever shape and length and width
you would want nice okay and then you
know just using the casters you know if
you get a the right size Caster that is
you know can
withstand I think the casters on those
trays were about 350 450 lbs per per
wheel um and we do you know uh a wheel
on each corner and then two in the
center of a 4 by 4 by8 tray okay so it
can support a lot of that Center weight
yeah I love that there's a lot of really
cool Innovation that I see just little a
huge difference yeah yeah and that's
kind of my uh that's my my forte is I
love yeah both my parents are Engineers
um so I kind of and I I didn't
necessarily go to school for engineering
but I have that mindset of like looking
at things in a different way and seeing
how I can kind of accomplish certain
things on my own very cool yeah all
right well thank you yeah thank you uh
can you tell me a little bit about about
yourself and what your role is here yeah
um I'm Jared um I'm our one of our
cultivation guys I'm doing most of our
uh fertilizer management nutrient
management um a lot of our irrigation
stuff so just kind of monitoring all our
green houses like throughout a daily
basis and stuff and just working amongst
the other Crews and everything kind of
get everything done um yeah so we just
toured the facility um so I I'll share
some video of that and we can look at
the irrigation and things but tell me a
little bit about your your process for
maintaining the soil um a lot of testing
so we're every run we're testing a
little bit before Harvest kind of making
our amendments based off of that um
looking kind of trying to see what we're
deficient in um putting together a good
like fertilizer plan that's going to
meet our needs while not giving us too
much Surplus we don't want to be
wasteful so kind of meeting our needs
without getting into too much Surplus
within our soil um a lot of monitoring
post of our post our first amendment um
especially throughout kind of our veg
time just monitoring our plants for like
their nitrogen needs and everything um
we'll do some foler testing if we feel
like we got something going on for the
most part our soil testing is kind of
our good uh standard go-to to kind of
check out what we got going on in the
soil
um for the most part we're using dry
amendments um we try to use those over
like kind of liquid feeding at all um
and we don't really have any liquid
feeds but for the most part dry
amendments usually kind of mixed in the
first like 6 in or so of our soil um
okay so a lot of the standard kind of
organic uh products we're trying to use
a lot of
um we're a lot of like fish meal some
fishbone meal we use like gypsum sulfate
of pot as kind of all the and then
you're uh addressing any fertility
things that come up with keas or liquid
yes so if we do have any like kind of
for the most part we've been lucky
lately to where we've been getting into
a Groove where we haven't necessarily
seen as many like kind of later growth
deficiencies um been doing a good job of
kind of getting to our nitrogen needs
early and everything and same with our
other uh nutrient needs but if we do run
into those issues we're doing some top
dressing or some like liquid feeding
through like our micro tees where we'll
put if we're looking like we're nitrogen
deficient we'll use like some fish
hydraulic within those uh those teas or
we can do some like nutrient soaks as
well um but yeah for the most part we're
trying to kind of cover our bases
earlier pre-planting so that way we're
not running into those issues where by
the time you're seeing it into the plant
it's been a few weeks or it's been a
week or so already that the plant's
deficient so kind of trying to
preemptively take care of those issues
rather than uh Wai and seeing them and
then responding but yeah very cool yep
sweet thank all right
thanks