hey guys
tad here we kiss organics and I'm making
this video because I see people posting
photos of their plants online all the
time and asking what's going on and you
see advice across ranging across the
board from at cal-mag to add molasses
you have a nitrogen deficiency but
really we don't know
and that's where soil testing comes in
I think soil testing is critical and
everyone should be doing it in their
gardens now most people are familiar
with the Logan lab standard soil test
this is a male like three test and
there's a bunch of different tests out
there and a bunch of labs but I'm just
gonna explain the comparisons between
these two to keep this video short now
may lick three tests tells us everything
that's in the soil so it'll give us our
cation exchange capacity or micro and
macro nutrients it's not a hundred
percent accurate but it gives us a good
range now the disadvantage of that test
is it doesn't tell us what's actually
available to the plant that's where
things like Tichy testing and a
saturated paste test or now this new kit
from soil savvy this soil test is
something I've been doing a lot of
research on lately and it's very very
easy to use so let me show it to you
this is the entire kit it's got a return
envelope so you're not paying for any
shipping to send the sample back which
is awesome
it's kind of scoop it's got simple
instructions and this is the whole kit
right here what's in here is a special
synthetic resin or an artificial root
and what that does is it slowly pulls up
ions over the course of five to seven
days and this is tells us what's
actually available to your planet right
now now the way you use a kit like this
is keep in mind everyone's room is
different everyone's growing different
cultivars and strains everyone's using
different nutrients and has different
microbes cycling nutrients in their soil
so let's say you're having the best crop
you've ever grown two weeks in the
flower well you can take a soil sample
at that stage of growth and that will
give you a benchmark for future growth
now let's say the next time around
not skidding the same results well if
everything else is the same you can do
this well savvy test and see oh well my
manganese levels are lower this time or
I have too much iron and then you can
make real-time adjustments this is gonna
help increase your yield this is gonna
help with plant health and plant growth
it's an all-around win so in combination
with the Logan lab test which is going
to give us everything that's in the soil
with this soil Saturday test which tells
us what's currently available to plant
it allows us to have a really good idea
of the nutrient and mineral profiles of
our soil the other way you can use this
test is let's say you want to know how
quickly a given application is actually
becoming plants available or how much of
it is becoming plants available well
let's say for example you put out some
high peak guano and you wanna know when
is that phosphorus actually becoming
plants available well you could do a
test a week out and say okay this much
phosphorus is now in a form that the
plant can take up so it's a really
really easy simple and fast effective
way of testing your soil I will be doing
a full podcast episode just on soil
testing in the near future if you're not
familiar with the podcast it's called
cannabis cultivation in science and you
can check it out right on our website
kiss organics calm and it's also
available on iTunes youtube stitcher all
the major platforms the last thing I
want to say about this soil test is we
do have it available on our website
right now it's $30 with free shipping
regularly $35 so if you wanted to try
this kind of testing and compare the
results this is a great way to do it and
I've also included a soil test of the
Logan lab test and the soil savvy test
right there on the product page of the
exact same sample so you can see the
differences that you're getting in these
test results it's really interesting so
check it out if you can't find it just
go on to kiss organics that's kis oor GA
and ICS comm type in soil test into the
search function it'll pop right up
alright thanks for checking out the
video happy growing