one uh one last question I had for you
that was sort of unrelated but one that
I I hear debated by Growers that I think
you could answer uh fairly readily is
this idea of rizosphere pH and the
importance of pH um some organic Growers
don't really uh don't use pH as a tool
because they say that the the soil's
ability and the microbes ability to
buffer is so great that it's less
important how however uh some of us like
myself feel that well there is an aspect
to that by optimizing uh pH in in
rizosphere and in the soil we're
allowing uh for these the plant to have
less stress and to make these
um make it easier for the plant to
uptake nutrients um yeah what what are
your thoughts on this and how do
microbes help in uh sort of that pH and
risos feere
relationship yes pH is very important h
under high pH if you really want to to
absorb if if you really want your plant
to absorb enough iron for the
chlorophyll to have a good color and
photosynthesis in in in the leaves uh
you please make sure that the pH will
not be above uh seven and a half even
lower than that
uh you know 68 or something like this if
you have a low PH then your plant will
not be able to absorb some of uh the
goodies that is being needed for for a
good crop uh so this is something which
should be kept in mind uh my
recommendation is uh take a nutrient
solution with a high buffer capacity and
that will helps you uh to
overcome those uh situation in the
ReRe so is it safe to say that the the
risos spere plant risos spere
interactions and the risos spere itself
is is highly complicated we are still
learning a lot about the soil microbiome
in relationship to the rizosphere
and by having the pH within uh a range
that is more optimal for the plant all
we're doing is making it easier for the
plant to access nutrients which will
potentially reduce plant stress and
allow it to put more energy into yield
and growth and protection yeah those SCT
yeah