so what you've got Anatomy right here on
this apple if you can make anything
out is this is this is the buds scale
scars from last year so it has grown
this much all the way to the end this
year the farther it gets away from the
farther the apical marem gets away from
last year's growth last year's growth
starts to grow Spurs and that's how you
encourage Spurs on apple trees is
letting the apical marasim get away get
farther away and so these are all fruit
Spurs right here right here and so this
tree will grow fruit Spurs and so next
year this will have fruit on these spurs
because a Spur by definition is a
shorten compressed stem and it's really
built for fruit production and built for
fruit weight and the mistake people make
is they see this big Chute coming they
pit they cut it here by cutting it here
it removes the apical dominance and
these guys say oh look we're going to
sprout we're going to sprout we're going
to sprout well once it sprouts you don't
get any Spurs so the way to encourage
spur production in fruit trees is to let
it grow because once a Spur once it
forms a Spur it always has that spur so
now I could go back and I could cut it
to here and these spurs would not turn
into vegetative shoots they would stay a
spur and you would have spur growth
you'd have stocky growth and it would
support that and you get away from this
type of growth see what should have have
happened here or what will happen here
eventually I should have thinned these
but also these will be cut back so that
this can be strong enough to hold all of
Weight like this and not let it continue
to hang down like that