for what you were dealing with I'm going
to guess without seeing it was probably
onion thrips onion thrips biology is
very similar to Western flour the adult
flies in female she inserts her egg into
the plant tissue it's in there a couple
days it hatches out starts cruising
around they have asymmetrical mouth
Parts they kind of more I didn't to use
the word Rass but they kind of like
damage the cell surface there um and
that's why you get
that white silverish kind kind of color
to them because they're removing the
chlorophyll and if you look they're
through when they're in their early in
Stars basically toddlers And even
teenagers they're they're kind of
yellowish clear but you can see the
green chlorophyll from the plant in
their in their gut and you know they
poop it out this kind of greenish color
from the chlorophyll but they're going
to cruise around and feed and this is
kind of and it it you know I always hate
to say things because people take it
like oh my God that's it's black and
white but no it's not but generally
onion thrips tend to feed more on
foliage Western flour thrips yes they
can feed on foliage but generally they
are more of a flower problem because
they really like pollen and so Western
Flower thrips are what we see a lot in
pansies and we see them in patunas and
we see them you know in lies because
they have a lot of pollen onion thrips
tend to be more Fage feeder and so when
you're growing cannabis guess what you
don't have present pollen so um and and
I think people because they they don't
do their due diligence and take the time
to ID which I don't expect Growers to be
able to tell species of thrips apart you
know that's my job that's extensions
jobs you know people that that can do
that stuff um but people guess and they
do the matching photos online and you
cannot just match photos of what Western
Flower thrips and onion thrips
necessarily for ID from a distance you
have to look at the length of the hair
on the prot nooms you have to count in
tenel segments you really have to get in
there but but but but the good thing is
generally for onion thrips and Western
Flower thrips the management is
basically the same because the biology
is the same you know they're they're
young they're eating on the plants then
they drop to the soil to pupate and then
the adults emerge back up where it gets
sticky is when you're dealing things
with like Ayo thrips who do not drop to
the soil to pupate it's also a much
larger thrips the predatory mites can't
take out Ayo thrips so you generally
have to spray for oino thrips but when
it comes to onion and Western
flour the the BIOS work really well the
predatory mites and all of that when it
gets into chemicals um Western Flower
thrips have more resistance issues than
onion thrips um but that's not something
canos people necessarily have to worry
about because those kinds of pesticides
you're not going to be using anyhow
so how do you feel about the SF nematode
sski approach following up you know a
couple days after a a couple suffoil
applications so you can spr would you
critique my yeah so um suff oil is fine
once suff oil is dry you can reuze your
predatory mites but if you're going to
do like you know two or three sprays of
suffoil x two to three days apart yes
that's smart to wait to release the
predatory M from an economic standpoint
I generally go with cucumeris more
because it's a lot less expensive and it
works just as well um in cannabis on the
thrips as sworski does sworski tends to
be you know a little more expensive um
so but no I think that's that's a
perfectly fine program and using you
know your sticky cards uh you know to
monitor I think is a very you know good
good tool for that so yeah I'll give you
I'll give you a that so one thing you
mentioned was how they eat the
chlorophyll mhm so one of the ways I
just Scouting For thrips when you see
that like I always called it like the
shiny leaf surface yeah is how I see it
like it just has a different gloss to
the leaf where the damage is is that
unique to thrips because I to me thrips
damage looks very specific compared the
other things and one of the things I
look for is that shininess along with
where damage is lace bugs can give you
that kind of look to um now lace bugs
aren't a big problem in cannabis but it
has lace bugs have been reported in
cannabis but it's not a huge economic
issue I mean it's hard to ever say
always but generally also um you know
spidermite damage sometimes can look a
little similar um but they don't have
that silverness but I don't always see
that silverness with thrips damage but
you do see it that's good to know