[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge just a friendly reminder for
folks who enjoy the podcast content and
want to support the podcast we have a
patreon where we do a book club Hangouts
and share private content that we don't
share on social media we also offer a
wider range of products ranging from
living soils LED lighting beneficial
insects organic fertilizers and
professional Consulting on the kiss
Organics
website my guest this week is Julie Gres
Julie has 18 years of experience as a
biological scientist prac IED in
laboratory greenhouse and field research
as well as technical service support for
the integrated Pest Management industry
she's been with bioworks for 5 years and
has previously held positions at BASF
Becker Underwood and Iowa State
University now on to the
show Good Morning Julie thanks for
coming on the show
today thank you very much Tad for having
me yeah I I felt so fortunate to have
met you at a couple trade shows now I
know you're a good friend of Suzanne way
W Evans who's also a good friend of mine
and she speaks so highly of you so I'm
very excited we managed to agree on it
figure out a time to get you on the
podcast well thank you very much yes
Suzanne is a um a fantastic friend of
mine and we talk about everything
um professionally but also uh a lot of
personal stuff too so uh we are we're
very good friends and uh yeah it's just
it's just great to um uh to be here and
you know in addition with Suzanne you
know we
we the other good thing is you
know we talk a lot about um challenges
that Growers are are having in the field
and we bounce ideas off of each other
and we'll look for research together to
solve particular problems and so we're
very much uh a team in that sense in and
trying to come up with the best
solutions for
Growers yeah let's let's give listeners
a a quick intro into your background and
how you came into this role at
bioworks so I've been with bioworks uh
since June of 2019 so what that's
for um about four years I think and I
should have done the math on that it's
been a little while since I looked
but um so right before covid and at
bioworks I I started off as a bio uh a
biological program manager responsible
for the our our insect management
portfolio and last year we had a uh some
rearranging of our Technical Services
Department and I switched roles to a
technical services manager and so I am a
more uh General
instead of just focusing on the insect
side of things I also help uh Growers
with the disease management and plant
nutrition to a um a lesser extent it's
definitely not where my strength lies
but I can speak to it a little bit but
diseases and insects are where my
passion
lies I so in terms of what I do as a
technical services manager I uh we have
a tech emails and phone calls uh hotline
that we always have someone on there
paying attention to any calls and emails
that come in and so I help out with that
and we also go and visit growers in the
field I am also I work also very closely
with our regulat
at
marketing research and development um
departments internally to bring new
products to the market and improve on
the products that we currently have in
the market so I wear a lot of hats in
that sense and uh help out where I can
and when I can but my main my main
priority is working with the Growers and
helping them solve disease and arth pod
issues that they're dealing with as far
as uh my history prior to bioworks I was
with
BASF and I was in seed Solutions so I
mainly did a lot of work on corn
soybeans wheat and cotton um but I had a
research Greenhouse where
I uh uh treated seeds and then planted
those seeds into the greenhouse and then
infected those plants with soyan CIS
nematodes or with a corn rootworm to see
how the seed treatments performed on
those insects so it was still insect
focused even though it was in seed
Solutions
BASF bought the company that I was
working for originally called Becker
Underwood and I was with Becker
Underwood for about six years and with
BASF for about seven years uh at uh
Becker Underwood I was in quality
control Regulatory and uh I was also a
nematode field development specialist
where I worked specifically with the
beneficial
nematodes very much doing the same thing
that I am doing now but focused
specifically on beneficial nematodes so
I do have a lot of experience working
with um many of the nematode species
that are commercially produced and used
by Growers so that um that's pretty much
me and a
nutshell great great and for folks that
are listening if if you are interested
uh you can also check out the podcast
I've done with Chris Hayes and Michael
brownbridge who are both also at
bioworks um and offer a really unique
perspective around uh talking about
pathogens and and insect control and PES
management things like that so those
podcasts were recorded a while ago so
people can check that out uh well why
don't we start off talking about
nematodes since you do have a background
in this now I myself have only used SF
nematodes and I tend to say SF because I
always mispronounce the name uh maybe
you could start off talking a little bit
about SF nematodes and what they treat
and because I I found them to be very
effective and then maybe what other
commercially reared nematodes might a
cannabis grower consider in their
program excellent questions so SF stands
for Steiner
neopel and Steiner Nela is probably one
of the most common nematodes that you
buy and it it it
is often considered
a a specialist in in in some fly species
and uh it is very commonly used for
fungus net management
uh Steiner melti is also used for thrips
management so thps Pupa that fall um
free Pupa and Pupa um and it's important
to note that not all thrips pupate in
the soil so if you are going to
use nematodes Steiner nlti or Steiner
aaroc capsi for management of thrips you
do need to make sure that you identify
the thrip species that you have and
confirm if that thrip species is in fact
pupating in the soil because if it's not
you can throw all of the beneficials in
the soil that you want and it's not
going to work because they're pupating
on the plant thrips are an interesting
species in that they are sort of an
intermediate between a complete and an
incomplete
metamorphosis the pupa uh still kind of
have uh legs and if you poke them they
can actually still move around which is
unlike what you would think of when you
think of a pupa so that's why we kind of
consider thrips as you know an odd an
odd ball in that it has this odd uh
intermediate stage so that being said um
that's why the pupa can sometimes will
stay on the plant because again um they
still have legs to to grip onto the
plant so there are a few species of
thrips that do um continue to pupate on
the plant the one of those being EO THS
are a good example of a thrips that
would pupate on the plant now something
like an onion or a Western Flower thrip
onion probably being the more common
species in cannabis and hemp are often
um pupating in the soil if you have a a
really thick um say flow or Bud
sometimes you they may get um stuck in
those and not come out and and pupate in
those but for the most part they're
going to drop to the soil so then you
can use beneficial nematodes there are
also a couple of other um soil based uh
beneficials uh such as stratal leaps and
deloia which are um uh predatory might
uh in the case of stratal elaps and
delosa in the uh is a beetle in and uh
they do fly at night um so I know that
delosa isn't something that a lot of
cannabis Growers use because they might
not want to get that um in their
bud so um with that being said there are
a couple of beneficials that are used
for fungus net management one of those
being C mfti and I will tell you that
there is research uh uh probably the
most research has been done on Steiner
nlti and Steiner carpo capsy and Steiner
carpo capsy it it can also be used
for management of thrips and fungus
snats um there is research that suggests
that both of those are are uh okay to
use um traditionally we use Steiner
mlti um because we have seen really good
management um with that nematode species
and it can be um both of those species
are fairly robust
nematodes
um so basically what happens um is if
you were going to use nematodes for
management of say let's say fungus Nets
really fungus Nets or thrips say you had
onion or Western Flower thrips and you
have fungus Nets which is very common
these are very very common insect
species that
um uh happen almost ubiquitously across
all
operations and so if you were going to
use Steiner mfti you
there are a number of companies that
sell
nematodes
and they can come in a variety of
formulations uh that's a um a much
longer conversation that you know if we
want to go down that path we can but
basically there's a number of
formulations and uh a number of ways
that the ne nematodes may come to you
some times they come in bags Sometimes
they come in trays um but in almost all
cases it's either crumbly or more of a
sugar cookie batter
consistency and you'll want to keep
those in the refrigerator because those
nematodes are in an infective juvenile
stage and all of them that you receive
are infective juveniles um all of the
other life stages are going to occur in
an insect host so those infective
juveniles um they're only
uh way to survive is if they find a host
so they're very driven to find this
host and if they don't find a host they
die
because they are a an a Very a very
specific life stage in the in the
beneficial nematode life cycle where
they are free living meaning that
they're found outside of the host all of
the other life stage ages of the
nematode or inside the host so that's
important to know because this
adaptation of the infective
juvenile uh they retain the Mt from the
previous um uh juvenile nematode and
that sort of creates this jacket um on
the nematode that helps it when it's
outside of the host um prevent uh or at
least decrease the chance es of quick
desiccation or drying out um so it kind
of creates this jacket of of protection
um and in fact it may also help with
compatibility because we've got a lot of
compatibility results out there um with
a number of the nematode companies will
provide compatibility with tank mixes
that you can apply with the
nematodes and um nematodes are are
fairly compatible with with a number of
um
chemistries and
Biologicals can you give an example of
something that you may want a tank mix
with a nematode if you're doing an
application there the more common ones
maybe in
cannabis so another pest that is
commonly found in cannabis and hemp is H
the rice root aphid and the rice root
aphid uh is is is a tough one to control
once you get it so um um obviously
sanitation and quarantine are incredibly
important again um we don't want to
necessarily go down that rabbit hole
unless unless we want to
but if you were uh many Growers use enop
pathogenic fungus for management of rice
Rapids uh enop pathogenic fungus H genus
species Bavaria basana
iseria um uh for most sosia uh
C the iseria has now been renamed by the
way to um Corps so if you see
Corps uh it is now the new ice area but
you'll see it sometimes interchangeably
but the new language is Corps um so
aeria Corps there's also a number of
meisum uh which is another enop
pathogenic fungus
um so those are the three
main fungal enop pathogens that are used
by Growers and each one of those are I
mean they're good products there's a
number of companies that sell a number
of these products um sometimes the same
genus species uh but different strains
and they're all uh pretty good at uh
management of various soil and folar
based insects so to get back to your
question
Tad you could tank mix if you also had
rice root Aid you could tank mix your
nematodes with a uh one of the Bavaria
met isums or cep species and then you
would be targeting
more more pests basically um then
sometimes those are going to work
synergistically together um so for
instance
the uh enop pathogenic fungus and enop
pathogenic simply means insect killing
by the way um and sometimes n the
beneficial nematodes although that's the
easier way to say it technically they're
antipop pathogenic nematodes so both of
these are insect killing fungus and
insect killing
nematodes so you could tank mix these
two species um you may get additional
benefits in management of your thrips
and the fungus Nets um these enop
pathogenic fungus are typically not
that um uh that specific so it you know
we often have labeled pests but uh you
can
get additional efficacy um by using some
of the endom pathogens so that would be
um one obvious one I know that uh Aid
duratin is a good one to use with your
enop pathogenic fungus H or the enop
pathogenic nematodes there's often
Synergy or um additive effects I know
that not all cannabis Growers will use
Aid duratin insect growth Regulators in
general are a good thing to pair with
nematodes and fungus because it will
slow down or stop the life cycle and
which is incredibly important if you're
dealing with
aphids uh or other arthropods that have
very fast life
cycles because the
fungus takes typically 24 to 48 hours
to adhere to the surface of the cuticle
to germinate to put out the osori which
is the infection body that creates the
metabolites and pressure that punches
into the insect's cuticle um and then
that hyy goes down into the the insects
hemil or blood and then kills the insect
um so that that process to get into the
insect typically takes 24 to 48 hours so
let's say you apply uh one of the the
fungal-based
um
products any aphid that mols within that
24 to 48 hour period may not be killed
because they are shedding off those
spores and they don't move around very
much aphids specifically so they're not
going to crawl around and get more
spores typically so what you apply
initially is often times going to be
what you're going to Conta them with so
if you can slow down the insect's life
cycle with an insect growth regulator it
will very very commonly uh have higher
efficacy when targeting pests like
aphids thrips white
flies
so just to make sure just to reiterate
you're saying using a product like
something that has Aid dirting it's like
it maybe like aagard or azamax it's
brands that I'm familiar with I'm sure
there's others out there on the market
market so something AER Jackson based
and then looking at a Bavaria product uh
you obviously with bioworks you guys
have botanigard um I'm also familiar
with bioceros is another uh Bavaria
product potentially um people could look
at and then uh combining those two along
with an a nematode and you specifically
SF nematodes or Steiner name carpo
capser if I said that somewhat close
um very close Okay that's really
interesting so if we one thing I wanted
to touch on with you and we talked about
this a little ahead of time uh was this
is something that I learned from from
Suzanne that I think is really important
to highlight and that's that that these
different
species uh are within let me back up
within like Bavaria let's take Bavaria
as an example of this um bioworks
through banag guard has a very specific
species of or or strain of of Bavaria
bosana and that's what gets commercially
reproduced they discovered it um and
then and it has very unique special
properties to it um and that's why it's
so successful because it can survive in
a variety of different media different
temperatures um but it's going to be
different than say the product from
bioceres or another company it's going
to be a different um strain or species
of fungi
also B Bavaria basana but getting to the
idea that not all Bavaria is the same so
just because you and this is the same
for micro risal fungi this is the same
for as far as I understand pretty much
all of these um beneficial microbial
products and so uh Growers may want to
cons rather than saying Bavaria doesn't
work or Bavaria does work they need to
find a specific they need to try maybe a
couple different brands to figure out
what works in their environment
depending on what sort of you know
biotic and abiotic factors they may have
in their grow in their cultivation
facility or space um is there anything
you want to add to that or or touch on
in in regards to
that uh yes I uh I have a number of
things to add so first of first I want
to mention that botanigard is no longer
sold by bioworks it's now actually nope
it's fine it's it's it's now marketed by
op however this year we are planning on
launching our
own product and we hope to do that at
cultivate um we're still waiting on our
EPA registration which um should be
should be soon so with that being said
um so let's talk
about a few of the products that are on
the market there is tanard which is a
Bavaria bassiana strain ghaa there is
bioc cerus um that is uh a N3 strain
there is velifer which is ppri
strain
um and then uh th those are the main
ones at least um those are the ones that
are uh that come to the top of the mind
uh are are strained that that we are
going to be commercializing is also a
Bavaria basana so all of these are
Bavaria basana species and but they're
different strains so what I'll say about
that is often times uh all of these
different strains have
[Music]
been isolated initially from an insect
so researchers in the field they see
these Mast or um uh fuzzy bugs that's
all the mycelium and the spores that are
produced and they take those MOS insects
into the lab and they culture them and
you know since they were on a bug in in
the field is that something that's just
advantageous fungus or is that something
that actually killed the bug so they
will take those spores that they get
from their culturing and try to infect
other bugs and if they kill then it's
likely that it is an emop pathogenic
fungus and you know again there are a
ton out there these are just the ones um
uh and there's a lot more that is known
than is commercialized um for a number
of reasons mainly you know are these
particular fungal strains capable of
being mass produced and not all of them
are so for instance um with the
botanigard being a
GHA uh GHA actually stands for
grasshopper a so that was isolated
initially from a grasshopper um some of
the other ones
um uh uh nfly noly is another one that's
a c uh oh that's Corps though so um
iseria uh so I'm getting a little off
base
but similar concept so let's just
continue on with the Bavaria so um all
of the these different Bavaria were
isolated from different insects so so
sometimes we can see improved efficacy
on uh say the tarnish plant bug uh I I
think um I'd have to go and look how an3
was isolated I want to say that was from
um a plant bug but um again I haven't
looked recently so don't quote me on
that but um you can have strengths and
weaknesses from all of your fungal
strains
so often times I will tell Growers that
you don't necessarily have to use just
one you could have a couple in of of the
fungal strains in Your Arsenal uh
within the same genus species um but you
could also have within the same gen um
in a different genus so Bavaria iseria
Corps or meisum so you could rotate say
a Bavaria with uh a Corps or a Bavaria
with a meisum and again each one of
those uh
individual
fungal genus species and strains are
going to have different strengths and
weaknesses and so you can have uh
you you can get potentially more out of
your endom apathogenic
guard and I just completely spaced in
the moment um but that is that I'm
excited that bioworks is going to have
their own uh product or Strain coming
out very soon I look forward to hearing
about that I currently have in my indoor
garden I have the granulated bioer
product as well as their liquid um
product and
so I I would suggest for Growers the the
ones that you listed is a good starting
point for people in terms of looking for
uh
commercially produced high
quality options um and I only say this
because I know there's some other ones
out there that you that um Michael
brownbridge has tested with in
conjunction with Suzanne that either um
I think it was it was a metan product
that had claims of spores that was
higher than physically possible to fit
into a container um as well as another
one that had Spore count so low that
there was no way you could get efficacy
with it because I know you can Source I
could Source Bavaria from China right
now I could buy it get it shipped in and
sell it um but it's not probably doesn't
have the same EIC or quality that we
would want to use in our garden as well
as potentially containing heavy metals
other microbial contamination and other
issues so I would just caution listeners
to make sure you you go with a a company
that's done a lot of research and has a
good reputation in the industry for
these specific
products excellent
point
the so in addition to everything that
tad just said so the products that I've
mentioned so that's the the the the
botanigard the BIOS serus valer
botanigard um uh the lard
m52 um uh the isera or Corps products no
fly isid so on and so forth those are
all EPA registered Environmental
Protection Agency and in order to get
registration you have to have a lot of
uh uh Eco um pschological
toxicity um and uh to know how it's
going to um behave or break down in the
environment and if there is any harm to
say humans and it it goes through all of
that testing there's also a lot of
quality testing that goes on to make
sure that quality standards are met when
these these fungal products are
produced
and uh lots of data that went behind
find knowing that these particular genus
species and strains are highly
efficacious to the pest that are labeled
now when you bring in a product from
China or from you know some of these
other countries that are
offering the uh these
microbes there is no guarantee that what
they say is in that container is
actually in that container Tad mentioned
microbial contamination um there could
be human pathogens in those formulations
they've come from overseas and um
probably not refrigerated and so as
those spores die off it could uh then be
a breeding ground for bacteria and other
fungus and so who knows what you're
applying so I would as Tad mentioned
uh
be very cautious um about bringing
something like that into your facility
um use the EPA registered products they
may cost you a little bit more than the
ones that you get but you know it has
valid
um data behind it backing it and um you
know that you will get a good result
where you you don't have that with the
um off-market uh not off-market but um
black market um microbes which we
sometimes call them they are technically
Black Market because they're not legally
allowed to be sold in the US but they
are and that's the other thing and
that's the other thing yeah you also
mentioned about formulation and I think
that's important to mention with the
endopath uh fungus specifically so
there's granules there's liquids and
there's wable powders so those are the
three most common formulations with
probably the wettable powder typically
being the most commonly used and I would
say that that's probably the most common
because well it's it's got a lot of
proven efficacy but it's got really good
crop uh tolerance profiles too wable
powders um are very crop safe
typically um the other one that's
probably the second most common is a
liquid and that can be in a typically an
oil-based formulation you don't want to
have water in your formulation because
that will make the spores germinate so
uh in oil that has very low water
content um think honey basically you
know you that honey has very low uh uh
water content um oils typically have
very low uh water content so you can
formulate in oils some some of those
formulations are going to be uh
Horticultural mineral oilbased um and
some of those are going to be seed uh
seed oilbased
um sometimes you'll see that as a uh OD
oil dispersion sometimes it's an es um
uh emulsifiable concentrate or
suspension um but basically those are
liquid formulations and those are really
really good formulations to use
especially Outdoors because you have
some rain fastness with that that you
typically don't with a wettable powder
um so there are strengths and weaknesses
now you want to be careful by putting
oil in say the roots so if uh or or the
media where the roots are um because you
don't want to suffocate the roots and um
there are some formulations um that are
labeled for drench and in which case
that's something that that you may get
additional efficacy with so make sure
that that it's labeled for the
particular application that you want to
do um but the the the the liquid
formulations are are are are
excellent in that in addition to the
efficacy you get from the Fungus you
also get additional efficacy from
typically Suffocation um so you get a
couple of different mode of actions with
the oilbased formulations the last one
that I will mention um is the granular
formulation
and we had them on the market and then
for a while we didn't have them and now
they're starting to come back again and
I think the granular based formulations
are of En apathogenic fungus are
fantastic especially if you are
targeting insects in the soil indoor or
outdoor because basically if you when
you pot up your media you are
incorporating these granules into the
media and now you they're basically
landmines in there and those those as
insects um come into the soil profile or
moving around potentially in the soil
profile they'll encounter these these
balls of spores and get um uh infected
with them as you water those spores will
also disseminate throughout the soil and
the other benefit to having a granular
formulation in the soil is especially if
you have a lot of um microbes in your
soil you know we talk a lot now about
regenerative soil and um you know having
all those microbes in the soil that that
um have a a healthy soil environment
with all of the things that you could
have in those soils you can also have um
potentially depending on what's in there
um uh uh in in
inhibition um effects so uh so something
that may cause uh Bavaria or you know a
fungus to not germinate
so with that being said with a
granule the granule typically has some
sort of food associated with it whether
it is um a a rice grain that that Rice
is is no longer alive so you don't have
to worry or a mill
um those seeds are no longer alive but
it's food for the fungus and so by
having that food source available as in
in that granule the if there are
microbes that are now competing for
resources in
Space by having that food source in the
granule you actually
get um uh that um fungus is able to then
out compete many of the other soil
microbes at least in its General
vicinity so that um you can get
increased efficacy um it's also
longevity wise um if you did a wable
powder drench um and there are studies
uh there's a study by um
uh oh um trying to think of uh out of
Vermont there was a study that was done
um where the researcher did a drench um
of wable powder versus the granular
formulation and they they got good
efficacy from both but they found that
longevity wise the granules lasted a lot
longer than the wable powder um because
again the target insect in this in that
study do you remember um you know what I
don't remember what the target insect
was I think they were they uh it
actually it might have been
thrips um and Tad I can get you that a
copy of that study if if you're um yeah
I think listeners might find that
interesting um I know that like from
talking to Suzanne one of the things she
was most excited about uh which got me
excited was using the granule
formulations uh and I specifically like
I said I have the one from
bioceros that would be used for uh
treating rud Aid now I don't have rud
Aid in my garden currently but I am
incorporating a little bit of the
granules in at transplant yes rudit are
the worst um as a
precautionary you know uh preventative
for like thrips and I I believe it works
on fungus Nets as well um so uh it's
just a
easy formulation to work with and that
idea of increased persistence or or also
the idea that when when you have a pot
that has holes on the bottom knowing
that those root aphids can reach those
holes at the bottom it's really hard to
get spores all the way down there and
good efficacy when you're doing a drench
uh so I think this is where these
granules could really shine as as a
formulation option for folks um I I
would love to see these companies and
I'm gonna I'm GNA throw bioworks under
the bus here too I would love to see
them come up with smaller sizing because
um it's so hard as a hom grower uh you
know whether for my vegetable garden for
for my um indoor garden to find products
in sizings that make the sort of sense
that I can use them um it it's really
tough I I hear you and we do get that
question quite a bit and so these
commercial
formulations again because they're EPA
registered they have very stri uh strict
label language
requirements
and uh personal protective equipment and
you know very strict use requirements
and reapplication intervals and because
of all of
that it can be
more uh challenging to sell that to the
homeowner or the small grower
because uh they don't they may not have
the understanding that the label is the
law and that's why oftentimes in say
Home Depot you still have products um
that like seven that you can buy off of
the shelf that have a these same active
ingredients that we use in commercial
operations
however uh if you look at the active
ingredient
concentration it's very often
significantly less than what you would
get in um you know these EPA registered
products that are sold to large
operations so that's part I think of why
you don't see as much um of of the
companies supplying to homeowners now
with that being said there is uh I don't
know if there are uh Distributors that
do cater to homeowners and smaller
Growers and uh do offer smaller pack
sizes um or you know not case quantities
so there are some options out there just
remember that if you're going to be
using a microbial or a live organism
like a nematode or a fungus or a
bacteria that if you're buying those off
say Amazon or something like that you
you and um the the manufacturing
companies don't know how those products
necessarily have been stored or if
the shelf life has been you know expired
so you may get expired product now I'm
not saying that you will but I'm just
cautioning you that if you are going to
buy a live product please consider going
through a distributor that is reputable
in in the sense of they know how to
handle store and ship these live
organisms so that means that you get the
best possible product um that will kill
the you know the arthropods or diseases
that you are targeting um cuz a dead or
a dead nematode or a
dead uh fungus or bacteria is not going
to control your pest populations so it
is important on how it's stored and
shipped yeah that's something that
Suzanne's really drilled in my head on
the insect side you know we we now offer
insects through biob uh but we ship
everything overnight directly from the
insector so we never touch it and I know
on the insect side some folks are
repacking into smaller quantities for
homeowners which is nice but that can
also impact the quality and efficacy of
the actual product when it arrive so I'm
glad you brought that up and one thing I
learned with nematodes and maybe you can
validate this or or tell me it's wrong
but essentially um the reason these
quantities are so high with the
nematodes is there's sort of a critical
mass like kind of like a compost pile
there's a minimum needed to keep to
maintain the viability that we want um
so that's why they're sold in these you
know fairly
large quantities is that is that
accurate so with nematodes there is a
ton of research out there on a a a
plethora of of
arthropods
and the
the research
TP that has been conducted are using a
quantity of nematodes to kill said Pest
and so the rates that were recommending
for for nematodes are based on Research
results and I would say for the uh inv
vitro uh produce nematodes or nematodes
that are produced in say
fermentation those uh the rates for
those types of nematodes are typically
in the 1 billion nematodes per acre rate
sometimes sometimes less sometimes more
again depending on the species of pest
that you're targeting so uh uh I'll use
uh for an example um
there is a a
nematode uh
uh I would say lesser known but still uh
very commonly used called heterotis
bacteria for it is a nematode that um is
very commonly available and can
work uh better on say beetles it's a
good Beetle
um uh nematode speci species
so there are a couple of Beatles on the
label so Japanese beetle is one that
many of us are familiar with and those
beetles uh the grubs
are easier to kill than say a uh
European chaffer so with uh a
a um a Japanese Beetle we're going at a
billion NE half to 1 billion nematodes
per acre versus a European chaffer that
may go up to four billion per acre so
the reason why you see differences in
rate or often again goes back to the
research in um uh
how uh how many
nematodes um were required to kill that
particular Best pest um so a nematode an
infective juvenile you apply via spray
um broadcast is best um dripper can work
but you have a single point um and those
nematodes then need to go out from there
so it can can still work but you need to
provide the moisture for them to move so
um it contacts a your uh let's say the
Japanese beetle grub and that and you
know really insert pest here it you know
I'm using beetles as an example but um
so
so if that particular pest does not
recognize that nematode as uh as
self then that you you only really need
a couple of nematodes to get in to
overwhelm its immune system um nematodes
also carry a bacteria and um in the case
of Steiner nemma they regurgitate that
bacteria and it's actually the bacteria
that does the killing of the it it it it
um multiplies and then the nematodes are
actually eating the bacteria um and uh
uh that the was killed by the um the
bacteria so the um and then heter rdus
nematodes actually defecate or
regurgitate the um bacteria into the
insect
so you need a couple of of nematodes to
get in say that Japanese beetle to
release that bacteria it it it may not
recognize that there is an invasion
going on and pretty soon it goes through
septicemia blood poisoning because of
the bacteria and it
dies now let's say the European chaffer
it does recognize the fact that oh I am
being infected by nematodes and it will
launch a uh an immune response that is
much stronger so you have to have a lot
more nematodes being applied to the soil
in order to
overwhelm the uh the that particular
insect or in this case grub immune
system to kill that insect so that's why
you see uh the difference in rate um
with nematodes um and again typically
with the rate um being around a billion
nematodes
per acre now obviously that's per acre
so um sometimes uh on labels you'll see
that more in the you know per thousand
square feet um but if you work that up
to acre it's going to be in that um
General
vicinity H that's really interesting I
wasn't aware that it was the bacteria so
the so the
nematode it take me through that the
nematode penetrates the grub the the the
skin of the grub essentially and then
deposits the bacteria and then the
bacteria reproduces and then it reats
the bacteria is that essentially what
you're saying that is essentially what
I'm saying so uh for Steiner Neman
nematodes they have to enter through
Natural Body
openings and so that's the mouth the
anus and the
sphericals and but but uh then once in
they release the uh the bacteria they sh
shed that that jacket that we talked
about earlier they release the bacteria
and then the bacteria kills the host uh
then the soup that is
produced from
the uh the um the death of that insect
will be the um food source for the
nematodes to go through a couple of um
Generations
of
nematodes inside the particular host the
larger the host the more Generations the
smaller the host the fewer Generations
so um once food starts to become limited
that next generation of nematodes
instead of going into the next juvenile
stage will then um once the food is is
um limited will go into the infective
juvenile state
and that's the stage that leaves the
host in search of more
hosts so that's basically the life cycle
of um General life cycle of the nematode
um that would go for both Steiner Nema
as well as
heterotis I will tell you though that
heterotis
nematodes also have uh a hook on uh the
end of their um their nose or their or
their um body and uh for insects with
very thin cuticles they can actually
direct penetrate into uh say a grub
because a grub would have a very thin
cuticle and so you have direct
penetration which may be why we see it
being a little bit better for say grubs
than say a steinera would be that would
have to go through the mouth the anus or
the
spicles then there's also I mean if you
want to get into um there all the the
different nematodes um we've talked
about three so we have uh Steiner neli
we have Steiner narbo capsy and we have
uh heterotis bacteria for the other
really cool thing about nematodes is
they have different foraging strategies
so starting with
heterotis they are what we call a
cruiser and they are a very active
nematode um you put them into the soil
and they go crazy using up their energy
um until they find that host or they
don't and they die um or they continue
on their life cycle in a host um so
they're go go go nematodes then we have
Steiner Nema uh carpo capsi that have a
um an ambush foraging strategy so
they're a nematode that has been adapted
to the surface of the soil and you find
them in the upper soil layer and the
soil surface and they're going after
more of your mobile insects that are
going to be on the soil surface or in in
that that upper layer and what they they
can do this thing where they can
actually lift their bodies up off of the
substrate and they sort of wave around
and if they sense a host that's coming
either through vibrations or through
volatile cues that are given off um by
the sex and they sort of curl themselves
up into a a ball and they can flick
themselves at their host to improve
their success into contacting that host
that's called nictation um and that's
done by our Ambush nematode so if you're
going after a pest that is a Surface
pest um you might want to you know pick
steinm Corp capsi because in addition to
what I just said they are also a little
bit more desiccation tolerant and
sometimes also heat tolerant um John
Sanderson from Cornell who just retired
did a study on these nematodes um and
found that carpo capsy is a little bit
more heat tolerant than say Steiner neli
now finally Steiner ofel is an
intermediate so its inter its foraging
strategy is somewhere in between that of
the cruiser and the ambusher um it's
also a very very large nematode um
whereas steinon narpo capsy is a much
smaller nematode and so uh you can have
Steiner
mlti um uh sort of hanging out or
cruising around for a host so um
typically you'll find that in the upper
soil profile but typically much lower in
the soil than say that of carpac capsy
and your heterotis nematodes with it
being very active um has the largest um
Range where you may find it throughout
that soil profile that is a little bit
more in um potentially in nature
obviously when you're growing in pots um
the type of media does have a big impact
um the more uh dense and um I say uh
compact the soil the harder the
nematodes get through that but if you
had say a cocoa choir um that's uh or a
peep based media or mixture as many of
us do uh that is a a really uh an
excellent uh media to use beneficial
nematodes in as well as the um
beneficial fungus that we talked about
that's also a good media you can also
use nematodes and fungus in say a rock
wo
um or uh Oasis um however the spores
don't live as long and the nematodes
will often get pushed out from
subsequent waterings so you do have to
do more frequent waterings uh I'm sorry
more frequent applications in that type
of media than if you were in uh the the
um
um soil lless based media and um um
those type of of Medias so um yeah that
was really interesting because I I was
going to ask ask you how the heck do
these nematodes survive if you know most
of their life cycle is inside an insect
how are how in nature are they surviving
and is there any way we can apply
that you know knowledge to say an
indoor you know environment CA
environment where we don't have you
we're trying to kill off all insect host
and then I assume the persistence is not
great in terms of these these nematodes
surviving beyond the initial application
very
long what um what what are your thoughts
on that and then I have a couple other
nematode questions since we we seem to
be going down the the nematode and
timathy rabbit hole here and I'm GNA
have to have you back on I think to ask
you the actual bulk of the questions
that I had originally planned for this
episode so let's just stick with the the
nematodes for now um what what are your
thoughts on
that so
nematode
survival
so the the the the biggest factor I
think in nematode survival is to make
sure that you give
them enough soil moisture in order to uh
not only survive but move in that soil
profile you don't want to have uh say a
lot of flushing and a lot of
um uh of that water that that the
subsequent waterings where you have a
lot of water that's coming out the
bottom of the pot after you know a
nematode application because you could
be pushing them through especially if
you have say a pure cocoa choir that's a
pretty porous media and um you you could
wash them out
so um you know think about your
waterings obviously you still want to
water but not to the point of a lot of
run through through the pot
and um in terms of
survival as as long as they have
moisture and you don't dry it out
they're they're going to do their thing
they're going to search for hosts and
either find them an infect or perish
because they only have um as they are
feeding in the host uh they are gaining
the lipids or the fats that they need in
order to find a host
and so they only have a finite storage
of their um of of their
um um lipids so once that's run
out it the the nematode no longer has uh
energy to move on and it will die so the
faster those nematodes can find hosts
the better which is why doing an app you
know a Broadcast application to you know
get those nematodes all over in the pot
um and then down from there um is
generally a better strategy than doing
drip irrigation and where they get in
one spot and then they have to move out
from there they will but it will take
longer to get to those you know outside
um areas of the pot where a lot of the
fungus Nets are um so just uh that's a a
good application tip
um did I answer that question or
uh uh a couple things so what was it
again I think application method is
important to probably touch on like um I
I had to lean heavily on Suzanne for
this um and I know you're looking at
this at a very much larger scale but I
know that there's other you know there's
people like myself that are also using
them in home gardens or house plants or
or situations where um you know we don't
we don't have a nematode bucket like
that cool product from drram that's
going to keep everything agitated and
stir without heating it up and killing
the nematodes so uh I help them develop
that system oh you did oh Julie that's
so cool I had no idea yes so if you're a
commercial facility that's using a lot
of nematodes absolutely check out the
the nematode Bucket from drram it's a
very cool product um it looks very
simple but it's actually quite
complicated because you're trying to
keep them in suspension evenly but also
not allow any extra heat to end up in it
correct and yes and may I mention that
it is not just used for nematodes but if
you're doing irrigation injection uh you
could you could put your enop pathogenic
fungus in there you could do your
nematodes you could do many of your
other applications and it h there is a
swirling Factor but you can also turn on
uh air that will that will increase
the the um the oxygen in the water
nematodes aren't aquatic So eventually
they do drown especially if you don't
have agitation they fall to the bottom
of the tank um they're all still
consuming oxygen in the water so if they
don't have oxygen then that's a that's a
really uh good way to kill them also
cold water holds more oxygen than warm
water and so it's very important to keep
those Solutions as cool as possible
and apply them as quickly as possible so
that those Solutions don't heat up over
time so I actually just did a a podcast
interview I haven't released yet uh
it'll come out before this one but with
uh less over at dram talking about
dissolved oxygen specifically because it
is an important topic and and yes
temperature plays a huge role in
dissolved oxygen capabilities of water
um so what I did and you can correct
this but essentially I took the
nematodes out of the fridge I let them
warm up a little bit in the room for a
couple hours I then added some water to
a just a watering can because I just to
give you an idea I have two 4x4 beds
that I use for a sort of a test Garden
here at my house um I I filled up a
watering can a little with a little bit
of water and then I added the nematodes
stirred them all in added a little more
water on top um I made sure that water
was just comfortable maybe it might have
been a little bit too warm now in
retrospect I might have been able to go
a little bit colder but I also didn't
want to pour a bunch of cold water on my
soil knowing that I have plants in there
that you know you don't want to shock
the plants with cold water either so I
then applied it took me about five
minutes to apply my nematodes just
stirring and dumping out making sure to
cover as much of the surface of the soil
as possible and I so I did this last
cycle in the room and I had I knew that
the the Clones that I had came in with
thrips not a lot but there was some
damage and the grower who I got them
from uh pretty much warned me he's like
oh by the way I did not know but I gave
you thrips so he um so I I I released
some um some Ro beetles uh I believe
some strats and then also the uh the
nematodes and I did not see any thrips
damage throughout that cycle um but in
regards to nematodes how is that is just
a a real
basic application method for home
Growers are there any also are there any
sprayers that we need to watch out for
when we do if we were to put it through
a sprayer rather than just the water and
can method so I just threw a bunch of
question probably for your uh for your
um homeowner or small grower based
application equipment um you know proba
it it shouldn't be an issue like your
simple Venturi type um water
displacement sprayer like a um like a
hose end sprayer that's a pretty good
method um for applying beneficial
nematodes um it's going you know it it's
a little bit harder to control the
amount that you're applying in that type
of system um so you want to be aware of
that but um that's a good system
basically the the biggest thing to be
aware of with nematodes temperature
which we talked about
um uh if there are filters in the system
that the nematodes will pass through uh
they tend to get caught up on filters of
50 mesh or finer and so uh during the
nemid application you want to remove
those filters um or put in a larger
filter
size um so that they don't get caught up
and Shred uh and also PSI um the
pressure uh you just don't want to go
over 300 PSI as long as you're below 300
PS which typically isn't a problem then
um the N Hood should be fine basically
you know in the system they're subjected
to a lot of pressure and if say it's
above 300 and then they go through the
nozzle um and they go from very high to
very low pressure uh that that is is uh
detrimental to them so as long as you're
below 300 psi should be fine um and I
would say the last thing is you don't
want to have like a Mis nozzle on there
you want to have a nozzle that
that's large enough that you have um
since especially since we're applying it
to the soil typically so um uh you want
to have a larger nozzle on your um your
sprayer so that those NDS can freely
pass through and get into the soil with
the moisture that you're applying now
what about a onetime pass through like
an impeller pump like a sump pump if I
had like a 50 gallon garbage can filled
with water and I added the nitot to that
and then applied that through a hose-end
sprayer with either a a very
simple you know spray gun on the end of
that hose or even just my thumb and
finger over the end like how how is that
as an option so I actually did a study
uh back in my Becker Underwood days
where I uh did a the difference between
no
agitation air irration uh and basically
the buge pump um so an impeller that is
swirling the water around and
uh obviously the the the worst option is
the no agitation because everything
falls to the bottom um if it takes you a
while to apply that the nematodes are
all sinking to the bottom typically your
intake is at the bottom so all of the
nematodes get applied first and very few
nematodes get applied at the end of the
cycle so you have you'll have um an in a
a bad distribution of the nematodes in
the grow or wherever it is that you're
applying those
nematodes so that's that's the worst
option so if if it's the difference
between having agitation and not have
agitation uh so with the bilge pump and
the irration obviously irration was
better and you had a much longer
um uh the the nematode stayed viable in
that solution for I think it was an
eight hour period that I did the test
and I was doing um I was taking samples
at the top of the solution every hour
for eight
hours so with the BGE pump um and this
was in a five gallon bucket um it did a
really great job of keeping the
nematodes in solution and within that
first four hours the nematodes still
looked good but that BGE pump um that
you put into this into that you know in
my case it was a five gallon bucket it
is working and that BGE pump will start
to heat up the water over time so it I
in the study that I did in a five gallon
bucket uh the recommendation was 4 hours
or less so if you can get those
nematodes applied within 4 hours um
using that buge pump um the nematode
should stay viable assuming that the
water temperature is generally staying
cool um can we throw a number to
quantify cool though like uh 60
65 below that what what are you thinking
in terms of
temperature top head great great
question
and
uh let me I got oh wait no it's over
here so uh I would I would guess around
60 would be a good Fahrenheit would be
a good temperature range but um what
what are your thoughts on
that
so nematodes are going to be happiest uh
in the environment um their ideal range
is 54 to 86 Dees fhe and and so if once
you sort
of if you're heating up that water
slowly um and not say beating them over
the head with the um you know with an
impeller it it's it's probably going to
be
okay um and there's an easy way to check
on that uh which is pull the nematodes
out uh take a sample of the solution and
look at the nematodes um with a a hand
lens or more or or better a a dissecting
microscope if the nematodes are still
squiggling around um it's a pretty
pretty easy way to tell um if they're
viable or not and if they're not they're
basically pencils if you see a bunch of
pencils uh bad things have happened so
um and that's what I saw with my study
when it got past that 4our Mark in the
buge pump I also measured temperature um
I do have a document on this and um I
would be happy to share that with you as
well showing the pictures um of the
nematodes and and whatnot um from this
test and so I'll get that to you but
basically um after that 4-Hour Mark the
nematodes started going to pencils and
so our recommendation currently H is um
under four hours for a build um impeller
type pump um sometimes with irration by
itself it's it sometimes depending um
let's say you just have a single Stone
in a five gallon bucket and that stone
isn't very big it's you're giving them
oxygen but you're not necessarily
getting good agitation so with the dram
bucket uh they have both swirling motion
uh as well as irration so in your
particular operation you'll just have to
do some testing of your particular setup
to see if the nematodes are surviving
that um application and if you start to
see pencils then you know start
switching up um apply it faster uh uh um
apply with you know cooler water to to
begin with um that sort of thing but you
can start to troubleshoot and figure
fure out ways that work best for
you great great so it sounds like a
onetime pass through an impeller if we
were to use it to do an application
should in theory be fine but we could
test it by just taking a look at the
nematodes on the other end that's that's
great correct well we've already been
talking for a while I didn't like I said
we didn't even get to the I really
wanted to talk about EPA shield and sort
of what you're seeing in big issues on
Pest Management or pathogen side for in
cannabis so I I would love to get you
back on to talk about those topics
uh sometime here
soon I would love to come back I know we
didn't even get to talk about oils which
I think was our main goal other than
talking about nematodes and uh enop
pathogenic fungus which I think we
covered uh quite well and um so if you
wanted to to have me back I would be
happy to come back and talk about some
of the differences between you know
Horticultural mineral oils versus the
essential oilbased products the 25 BS
the difference between a 25b product and
an EPA product um all that good stuff um
so Chad I would I would uh I would love
that if you wanted to have me back all
right well thank you Julie I really
appreciate your time today and I will
reach out talk to you
soon all right great thanks Tad
[Music]
that was Julie Gres and you are
listening to the Cannabis cultivation
and science podcast if you like the
podcast please leave us a rating and
review and give us a follow on Instagram
and YouTube and don't forget at kiss
Organics we have a wide range of
products we offer on our website ranging
from soils amendments beneficial insects
soil test analysis and Consulting thanks
for listening