[Music]
Welcome to the Cannabis Cultivation and
Science podcast. I'm your host, Tad
Hussy of Kiss Organics. This is the
podcast where we discuss the cutting
edge of growing from a science-based
perspective and drawn top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge. My guest this week
is Bryant Mason. I've had Bryant on the
podcast a few times in the past and he's
one of my favorite guests. Bryant is a
certified crop adviser who specializes
in organic cannabis nutrition. He has
spent the last eight years working to
combine precision laboratory techniques
with data science in an effort to
unravel the complexities of cannabis
soil and crop nutrition. Along with his
work on soilless media, he also helps
outdoor cultivators around the United
States with nutrient management and
cover cropping. If you would like to do
soil testing, help interpreting a soil
test, or interested in an online course
on these subjects, his website is
www.soildconulting.com.
And if you want to save $100 on his
course, you can use the discount code
KIS Organics, all one word. I've taken
his course and was recently going back
to review some of the content. It's
excellent and I highly recommend it for
anyone wanting to do a deep dive on
cannabis fertility and reusing your
soil. Now, after recording the podcast
with Bryant, he had a couple of points
he wanted to clarify. So, there is a
short addendum that I added in at the
very beginning of the podcast. Now on to
the show on and talk a little bit more
about some of these topics that we
covered in the podcast. Uh let's just
dive right into the first part which was
where we discussed uh Logan Labs. And
one of the questions I'm seeing from my
most recent post on social media is do
we need to retest? Uh are these tests
that we got during this period um which
we'll get into a little more detail with
here as you listen to the podcast. Are
these um are these tests erroneous or
can we still utilize that
data? It's a great question. The
majority of the data on those tests is
totally accurate. For one thing, the
soil report, the what I call the
standard test is is accurate and most of
the paste information is is accurate or
fairly accurate. What I've been telling
growers at least in the period of time
where um sulfur chloride and a few of
the cations ions were elevated
is really if your plants look good and
you're not seeing any problems related
to salt stress then there really isn't
any need to retest. You can just retest
at your normal interval and uh you'll
see the updated more accurate data. So,
uh, just take those numbers with a grain
of salt. And in terms of the
interpretation, if you're seeing really,
really high numbers, I would suggest not
leeching and just sort of ignoring them.
This is something we talk about off air,
but essentially this is a good rule of
thumb. Anyway, so typically if we see
high EC, high soluble salts from I know
you listed sulfur. I'm thinking more of
like chloride, sodium, um, nitrates,
then you'll typically recommend leeching
the beds to reduce those numbers down to
a better level to reduce osmotic
pressure on the root system. It's just
easier for the plants to take up
nutrients.
However, if your plants look great and
you're not seeing that reflected what's
showing on the test reflected on in your
plants, um what's your recommendation
then?
Yeah, this is a good nuance to cover uh
because I have thresholds at which I
recommend leeching. And the idea is
we're trying to optimize
uh even if the plants are relatively
healthy, if we can reduce the osmotic
stress to the roots, you can have better
healthier plants that are higher
yielding. But there's a there's a line
between what's operationally feasible
and the marginal improvement in in plant
health that really has to be an on-site
decision. So if your plants look healthy
and you're very satisfied with the
production, then then you may not need
to leech even when there's a leeching
recommendation. And that's just really
sort of a of a a grower decision. Now, I
I'd say that if you if you see any poor
plant health or negative symptoms, then
I would absolutely recommend leeching
when levels are high. So, there isn't a
magic number. I mean, we have thresholds
where, you know, if you were 300
chlorides, we would recommend uh
leeching 300 ppm. However, if your
plants look great and you're not seeing
any visual symptoms and leeching is is,
you know, obviously a lot of work, it's
a lot of water. It's labor intensive.
It's uh material intensive in terms of
the amount of water you have to use. Uh
you don't necessarily have to do that.
There is no magic number that above that
number your plants are going to look
like crap and suffer or below that
number your plants are going to be
amazing. Um, it's really
just what we've seen based on looking
at, you know, hundreds if not thousands
of these soil tests and sort of where we
think that this this level sort of
exists. But it is a very arbitrary
number. Well, yeah. And the and the
reason that there's not a a hard and
fast number is because the
um the
osmotic problem gets worse when
evaporation rates are higher. So high
temperature, high air flow, high
radiation is when the plant needs to be
uptaking more water. And so oftent times
that higher EC is preventing it from
doing so. And that's when you start to
see issues. So the the environmental
conditions are are going
to in many ways determine when the
plants are actually suffering from
osmotic stress. And so that's a number
another reason these numbers are a
little loose. Now if you're in the
winter and it's temperatures are
depressed or the radiation, you know,
your um PPFD is a little lower, your
evaporation, your total evaporation is
just on the lower side, then you might
be able to get away with quite a bit
higher levels of salts. So again, it's
it's have to And I want to also add that
there is the possibility of sampling
error here where if a small amount of
fish bone meal or alphalfpha meal or
whatever organic amendment gypsum ends
up in your tiny sample that could
dramatically skew your results and and
show numbers that might be higher than
what's actually in your soil or
reflected in your soil because one of
the things that you mentioned in this
podcast is later on is that soil is not
homogeneous. we we think of it as
homogeneous but really it's it's not
homogeneous at all even with these
potting soils. So um through no fault of
the lab uh potentially the results could
be skewed just from from
sampling. Yes, that that so I I I
sometimes have that concern with
nitrogen because it's on the the soil
report and the scoop size is quite
small. But when it comes to most the
soluble salts, I'm looking at them on
the paste report and the sample size is
a cup. So it that does help eliminate,
you know, a small chunk of one thing or
the other because the sample is quite
large when we're looking at the paste
test.
Um, but it's a it's a it's a valid point
to consider. And yeah, I mean, when we
were talking about pH reactions, that's
really where there's these very small
there's there's a nonhomogeneous soil.
So there's small pockets of low pH, high
pH. The ryosphere is different. There's
not the bulk soil pH is is a bit of a
misnomer in the sense that there's just
many different pockets of I think that's
a good transition into the conversation
that we had on the podcast about
nitrogen and there was a couple things
that you wanted to go back and clarify
around that that topic. Do you want to
share that?
Yeah, thanks. I I we hung up after the
initial podcast and I thought, you know,
my my answer to your question on how
nitrogen amendments affects pH wasn't
totally precise when I thought about it
more. So, I just want to clarify. So, we
talked about the nitrogen conversion
process. When nitrogen mineralizes from
organic nitrogen to ammonium, um there's
a slight increase in pH because the
ammonia combines with a hydrogen ion to
create ammonium. Uh so that consumes a
hydrogen ion and that will therefore
increase the pH. Then in that second
part of the nitrogen conversion process
when ammonium goes to nitrate um there's
actually a decrease in pH and that's
because it goes to nitrite and then to
nitrate and in both of those steps uh
hydrogen ions are released. So that's
going to acidify the soil. Um, and so
the
the there is a a slightly acidifying
effect when organic nitrogen converts to
nitrate. Um, I said that there's a
there's a a net zero effect in the pH
change. And so technically the nitrogen
conversion process acidifying but um the
reason that I generally don't see a pH
change in living soils is uh because
there's also the influence of of the the
characteristics of the amendment that
you're using. So for example when
alphalfpha meal mineralizes there's a
number of base cations ions that are
contributing um that are contributed to
the soil that more than offset the
acidity contri contributed by the
nitrification. Now other amendments and
I use this example to you is cotton seed
meal. Not that many people use
cottonseed meal. It contributes a lot of
sulfur and not many base cations ions.
So it can have a strong acid acidifying
effect. Um, but both of these are sort
of independent then from the nitrogen
conversion process. So there's the the
pH effect from nitrogen conversion and
then there's the pH effect from the
actual characteristics and the chemistry
of the amendment. And both of those are
different and that's ultimately what's
going to determine the net pH change
when you apply a nitrogen amendment. And
what I see generally is is not much
change in a living soil. The other
reason is living soils have more
buffering capacity. So if there is
slight downward pressure or upward
pressure uh from the amendment being
applied, the soil is often buffering
that and there's not a huge change. Uh
but you know there's always exceptions
and it I think a lot of it depends on
the rate of mineralization and the
quantity of amendment being used and
then like I said the which amendment. So
you're saying essentially something like
fishbone meal is giving you more than
just nitrogen conversion. It's also
giving you calcium or magnesium or or
these other cations ions that are going
to put upward pressure on pH. Therefore
sort of neutralizing the effects of this
nitrogen cycling that's occurring from a
pH perspective.
So I guess my the reason I asked this
question what was I was thinking in my
head and I didn't fully explain this was
if I already have a a freshly mixed soil
where that nitrogen is in the form of
ammonium and in my head I'm thinking
okay that's going to be if anything
raising pH slightly um because it's
showing as ammonium and my pH is 62 61
when that ammonium converts my pH is
certainly not going up. If anything, it
may drop a point or slightly um
depending on how these other factors
come into play and like you mentioned
the buffering capacity, but my
expectation is that pH is is is going to
maintain or drop and it's already low.
Um, so I like to wait to take the soil
test after, you know, wait for that
nitrogen to cycle. And I do sometimes
see the pH drop a little bit because on
the flip side, when I have a very high
pH, you know, uh, if I were to test the
soil right away and I'm 73, I might see
it drop down just slightly. Does that
make any sense?
Yeah, it does. And we have to keep in
mind that uh these con this conversion
process is actually happening
simultaneously and there's you're at
different steps in the process you know
depending on the different particles of
nitrogen. So um when ammonium is is
elevating yeah you're seeing the pH go
up but at the same time there's also
ammonium going to nitrate that's putting
pressure down. So you can never really
pinpoint what's going to happen next.
And I think what you're saying is
accurate is just wait just wait till it
cooks or mineralizes whatever you want
to say and and uh sort of levels out
wherever it's going to end up and that's
when you want testing. And one other
thing you mentioned later in the podcast
just for folks that you didn't mention
just now is that there is this organic
pool of nitrogen and you'll explain more
about that later in the podcast but I
for people who are just listening I
don't want you to think we're ignoring a
major source of nitrogen here in this
conversation. We're just hyperfocused on
this one aspect of something we didn't
quite elaborate on.
Cool. Uh, and then there was one other
topic that you wanted to just offer some
clarification around. I'll I'll be
honest, it's not uh I'm not as informed
around environmental controls and some
of that. So, I'm going to let you just
kind of explain explain that.
Yeah, I was I was just sort of
explaining a scenario in which it's
possible to cool your greenhouse by
venting even if the outside air is
warmer than the inside of your
greenhouse, which sounds it's completely
counterintuitive. It sounds impossible,
but you can bring in warmer air and it
can actually cool your greenhouse. And
the reason that's possible is
because temperature changes when there's
a a change in total energy. So, in other
words, um the temperature of your
greenhouse will only change if the
enalpy increases or decreases. And
enthalpy is a is a combination of
temperature and relative humidity. So,
let's say it's super hot outside. It's
like 97 degrees Fahrenheit and very dry,
20% relative humidity, and you're in and
your greenhouse is slightly cooler,
maybe 95 degrees Fahrenheit and 40%
relative humidity. If you vent, the
temperature in your greenhouse will
actually drop because there's a
reduction in enthalpy. So, this is just
one very niche example of what I was
explaining has been um kind of blowing
my mind as I as I go deeper into the the
science of energy balance and and
ventilation. Well, thanks for clarifying
those uh points and coming back on and I
hope folks continue to listen as we
start the rest of the podcast here.
Hey Bryant, you're you're a popular
guest. Thanks for coming back on the
show today. Thanks for having me again.
I'm excited to be here. Yeah. Well, um,
for people who are unfamiliar, please do
go back and check out the previous
podcasts that I've done with Bryant if
you want to get an idea of some of the
things we've already talked about. But
we have some new topics for today. And
let's just start off talking about uh
Logan Labs a little bit and lab testing
in general because
um just to throw it out there, I know
you found some inconsistencies
uh in the test results starting around
in August and I had seen some things too
on my end that uh were were often we had
both reached out to Logan. We reached
out we talked to each other about this
and some other people had reached out to
us. Can you just give us a little more
context of what was going on and where
to go from here? Yeah, sure. Like you
said, in August of 2024,
um I saw a a number of tests that were
all very elevated in sulfur on the
saturated paste test, so soluble sulfur
and abnormally high levels. And I pretty
much within a day or two uh I told the
lab and this type of thing happens
occasionally and
uh the lab is very responsive to this
type of feedback because I'm looking at
so many tests and I'm one of their
partner aronomists and so they jumped on
it and they brought in what's called an
ICP technician. And ICP is the uh
advanced piece of equipment that
actually looks and determines nutrient
concentrations. And the technicians
serviced the instrument, calibrated it.
Uh they went through multiple sort of
steps in QC, but unfortunately the issue
seemed to persist uh for for a while.
And I've just been thinking about it and
working with them slowly throughout the
months. Um, and it took a while to
figure it out, but ultimately, uh, I can
just tell you, we can jump into what was
going on. Before you do, can you just
talk about what the issue was that we
were that we were all seeing on our test
results? Mo mostly elevated levels of
sulfur but also slightly elevated levels
of chloride and a few of the cations
ions calcium, magnesium, potassium,
although those were uh less so than than
sulfur. Now with that higher sulfur and
chloride number, the soluble salts
number was therefore a little bit higher
because that's one of the components of
soluble salts.
So what that led to was not necessarily
an overlication of anything but rather
an underlication in certain instances
because as as someone writing
recommendations I would see high levels
of sulfur and so I started for example
suggesting potassium silicate instead of
potassium sulfate in some instances. Um,
I also use what I call a governor in the
soil doctor tool algorithm. Like a car
has a governor that prevents you from
going too fast. Um, I essentially stop
the use of gypsum and potassium sulfate
above very very elevated levels of
sulfur. So in really high EC situations,
some of the recommendations didn't
include gypsum or potassium sulfate. And
then the final thing which we've
discussed is uh in some instances I was
telling growers to leech their soil. So
essentially to flush the excess levels
of chloride um sulfur and I guess sodium
as a as a fourth cation I didn't mention
out of their soil to reduce the EC to to
reduce those levels. So those are the
the substantial things that were
happening in the recommendations due to
these elevated levels. Now, uh to be
clear, that wasn't happening in all or
even most of the recommendations, but
definitely in some instances that was
happening.
That that's great. And I also want to
add a couple just a little thing more
context here. So, and you already know
this, but for folks who are unfamiliar,
um sulfur in general is a pretty safe
uh mineral in the sense that high levels
of sulfur are not really uh having
negative impacts on your plants. You're
not going to see a sulfur toxicity, per
se. The issue there is it's going to
raise the EC or the soluble salt level
of your soil and potentially lead to a
little bit more osmotic pressure on the
roots, making it harder for your your
roots have to work harder to pull
nutrients up um versus uh a slightly
lower EC. So that's the issue with
sulfur. Now, with the chlorides, I just
want to emphasize that um for folks that
may have had to may have been given a
flushing recommendation that that
doesn't mean they were, you know, you
were at zero chlorides or 100 chlorides
and all of a sudden it's reporting 400
plus chlorides and you're you're having
to flush. These are probably test
results where you were borderline or on
your way to needing to flush anyway. So,
it's not the worst thing. Um but
obviously not ideal either. We want to
be as targeted and accurate with these
tests as possible. I think that's really
well said, especially on the sulfur
front. I'll also add that
um for years I've been trying to figure
out how to organically push calcium and
potassium levels
high without spiking the EC in the
soluble salts which is a very difficult
challenge because we're using large
quantities of just gypsum and potassium
sulfate in some instances langite a lot
of sulfur containing amendments.
So to your point, sometimes leeching is
a really great thing because you're just
sort of pushing levels down. And also
when I saw this, I changed my
recommendations a bit, my thresholds,
adjusting certain leeching thresholds.
Um, and so there was, you know, some
self-correction along the way because
this has been going on for several
months. Um, but anyway, that's that's a
little background. So let's let's talk
about what the actual issue was and how
that relates to Logan and if it's even
specific to Logan. Yeah. So and this is
where I've spent a lot of time is is not
only figuring out the solution but just
sort of putting the solution in a in a
larger framework of is this Logan
specific, is it lab specific, etc. So
what happened is Logan actually has
really vigorous quality control. they
they re-calibrate their ICP every 20
samples, which is far more than most
labs. Some labs do it twice a day. Some
labs do it every hundred samples, but
every 20 samples is very rigorous. And
when they do that, they use uh what's
called a standard, which is a
calibration solution that's provided by
the ICP company or technician.
And unfortunately, they were sold a
standard solution. The high-end, they
have a low-end standard solution and a
high-end solution to tell the machine
what's low, what's high. And those are
are known values. And the high-end
solution, they were sold a bad solution
that was overly concentrated. So, they
were calibrating that ICP machine to the
wrong standard because they were sold
the wrong liquid solution. And that's a
really tough thing to figure out because
they're continually recalibrating.
They're cleaning everything. They're
they're troubleshooting everything, but
the but the the known standard that's
supposed to be, you know, ground truth
is was off. Um, and so unfortunately it
was just calibrating to the high side.
I'll mention that any soils that were
low that so usually traditionally top
soils um anything that's low in in
soluble salts really didn't have this
issue because that that lower standard
was
accurate. One of the reasons I love
Logan and working with Logan is they
participate in um something called the
NAP, North American Proficiency Testing
Program. I believe there's 150
participating labs and it's a quality
control level between labs.
So they do a quarterly blind or double
blind statistical evaluation of soil,
plant and water samples. And there's
essentially, you know, they they're
given a a sample, they run it, and then
this NAP program tells them how close
they are, how precise they are to the
known levels, and they compare it across
150 labs. and Logan always has an
extremely precise score. Um, so to me
that's always given me confidence with
Logan. The problem is those samples are
top soil. They're low in in nutrient
concentrations. We're working with
Petebased medias that often were really
pushing nutrition and EC quite a bit
higher. So they were they kept passing
NAP, but that's because it was on that
it was it was a low concentration sample
and we were seeing these issues in high
concentration high EC soils.
Yeah, that's a great point. And for
those unfamiliar as well, u with with
ICP uh machines, you know, we're talking
parts per million here, parts per
billion in some cases. So, they're
extremely
um I guess accurate in that regard. Now,
when we're talking about such small
amounts, there's just greater uh
opportunity for sampling error and for
other things too to keep in mind. So,
um, one of the things that I always try
to emphasize with the growers we work
with is if if we have a test result that
is just really far off the standard that
we expect it to be, then we can always,
you know, we can we can always ask Logan
to retest it or we can assume that maybe
something got into that sample that
contaminated it. Maybe there was a p
piece of like fishbone meal for example
that was undissolved and ended up in
there and suddenly our phosphorus levels
are just through the roof and our pH has
dropped dramatically or or you know
something like that. So it's always good
to take these tests I think with a small
grain of salt. I think they're the most
useful tool that we have agronomically
for making uh data driven decisions
about our garden and about our soil. But
it's still not perfect and it's it's
never going to be perfect. And then on
that note, I think, okay, well, so Logan
had this issue. It wasn't really their
fault, but unfortunately, it it
happened. Um, what about switching to
another lab? Well, this could have
happened in any lab. Um, so it's not
necessarily unique to them in that
sense. And, um, if you were to switch
labs, like I know that's something, you
know, you and I talked about like what
what does that really look like for a
grower? The one thing it does mean is
you're really you're starting over. um
in a sense you can't take your old Logan
tests and then um correlate them with
your new tests at the the other the next
lab you go to you know and there's so
many labs out there so whatever lab you
go with you kind of need to stay with
because these test results don't it's
like apples to oranges I guess so I just
wanted to share a little bit more around
this idea also anything you want to add
yeah I want to add one thing which is
that this these issues actually happen
at all labs
unfortunately. Yeah. And you just don't
know. And so the the reason I've
personally committed deeply to uh Logan
a is for because of what you're saying
so I can really calibrate to one lab and
have a very extensive database
uh that I'm comfortable with, but also
um I can see these issues. I'm I'm so
familiar with the data, their process,
the people in the lab, everything that
when these issues do arise, I can see
them and identify them very quickly. And
um this is, you know, part of the even
though it took a long time to solve the
problem, I I was able to help them solve
that problem. And so it's sort of it's
been a sort of a mutual and
collaborative process. And if you go to
another lab and you're just doing, you
know, let's say one to even up to a
hundred tests per year, you're not
you're not going to see that. And so
you're not going to know when issues
arise. So for me and the growers I work
with, I think there's actually a major
benefit to being deeply in committed and
involved with one lab's data set. Um
because at least I know what's
happening.
Yeah, I I would guess we see probably
about a thousand tests a year. I'm
guessing you're significantly higher
than that with the number of growers you
work with. So, you do have this database
that builds up over time. And so, um,
yeah, if you suddenly see a 20% increase
in in your soluble salts across all your
tests starting on this date, that's a
really good clue. And I know you're
working with Logan for instituting, you
know, even more additional controls.
Yeah. To hopefully catch these sorts of
things in the Yeah, let me mention that.
So that the you can recalibrate the
machine over and over again, but if it's
still giving high levels, what does that
mean? And so I actually went back into
our database. So internally,
um, we anonymously put all the tests
into a database and then we essentially
ran statistics looking at the average
levels before and after August of 2024
and that the trend was clear
specifically with sulfur. We also looked
at the variation between months, etc.
those statistics. And so we're I'm
working with them to actually institute
another step of of QC where they they
look at their own internal database and
they just see how close it is
monthtomonth or quarter to quarter.
Um especially when these when these
issues arise, they can just look
straight at the straight to the database
instead of continuing to try to figure
out the the equipment malfunction.
Yeah. Yeah. And if folks have questions
about this, uh, I'd say feel free to
reach out to me. I assume you can reach
out to you, Brian. Um, or or even Logan
directly. Uh, but this issue has been
corrected as of what date? Mid-Marchch.
I don't I'd have to go back and look at
the exact date, but yeah, if you see,
you know, if you have a test and you're
thinking, why is chloride 450 ppm? It's
so that doesn't make any sense to me.
It's always been quite a bit lower. and
your test with result was before
mid-Marchch, I would assume um you're
fine. You could probably if they still
have your sample, they could rerun it
for you. Um but
ultimately, anything after mid-March
will be accurate. Um and I think I've
gotten some questions around, well, is
is it how can I still use these tests?
Absolutely. I mean, I would just look at
specifically sulfur and chloride with a
grain of salt.
Um, and you can assume, you know, on
average looking at a few thousand
samples before August of 2024 and and
about a thousand after. The other cat
ions are uh there's a lot of
variability, but let's just say 25%
elevated. So, it's not going to change
your management decisions very
dramatically. Um, and you can still use
the data and most of the data is still
very good. So, that's sort of what I
would say. We wrote a lot of really good
recommendations with very small things I
mentioned that um may have been
different, but the data is still good.
Just take it with a grain of salt.
And and the good news in this is if
anything you might have underapplied
nutrients, which is always
uh vastly preferred over overapplied
nutrients. Absolutely. I would have and
I if I saw the trend go in the other
direction where I was seeing things
weight artificially low leading to
excessive high application rates I would
have taken much more aggressive action
because that's such a higher risk. Um
but instead we kind of took the slow
route didn't didn't sort of overreact
and and figured it out over time. I also
just want to say that I think you and I
both are huge believers in transparency
and that's why we're actually talking
about it. We want we want people to know
this because ultimately I feel like that
is what builds trust and credibility as
opposed to covering things up which
again is kind of what happens in other
labs. They see internal issues and they
fix them but they don't really say
anything about it. So I think we were
both eager to actually talk about it.
Yeah. Yeah. And I want to be clear
because there was there were a couple
growers who reached out to me directly
and I was not aware of the full solution
until very recently um within the last
oh couple weeks. So um what what I what
I knew prior to that date was I had
reached out to Susan. We had we had
scheduled a meeting. We went we went
through tests. We went through sort of
their protocols and how they do these
tests which was
um which you know was was really
interesting and I learned some things in
that process uh which was great but uh
you know they hadn't changed any of
their staffing they hadn't changed any
of their procedures and so if you had
talked to me prior to you know our
conversation Bryant you know a week ago
whenever that was I would have told you
that like as far as I know I'm not aware
of any issues and this is um this this
is where we're at with it. But we we
have seen some inconsistencies with
higher numbers. So, I just want to throw
that out there because I I do know that
there's some people that have been
pretty vocal about this on online and um
yeah, it's a little bit of vindication
for them, but also I want to make sure
that we're approaching it in a way
that's solutiondriven, I guess, so we
can all continue on. Uh great. So,
moving on, you brought up uh you
mentioned nitrogen, and I just want to
talk a little bit about nitrogen. I'm
going to I know we have a list here
we're working off. I want to jump around
a little bit. Um first off, before we
dive into your your topic on nitrogen, I
wanted to say, can we talk a little bit
about how nitrogen cycles and how we see
it on on these soil tests and its impact
on pH? Because
um what we know that that nit that the
cannabis wants nitrogen in the form of
nitrates for the most part and when we
first add compost when we first mix our
soil so soils we're going to see a low
nitrate number and a you know high what
we would consider a high ammonium
number. Not high relative to the nitrate
number. Ammonium you know maybe like a
three or a six or something like that.
How does that how does that cycling
process really work and what is the
impact and implications for a grower?
Great. So for the most part growers in
living soil organic growers are are only
applying organic forms of nitrogen. So
nitrogen in the form of proteins and
amino acids. But let's just say soybean
meal, alalfa meal, blood meal, all these
are actually full proteins. The biology
in the soil
mineralizes those organic forms of
nitrogen into smaller and smaller
organic compound. So they take a
protein, they turn into amino acid, for
example. And uh the plant actually can
uptake those organic forms of nitrogen.
And um it's not the primary form of
nitrogen that's uptaken even in organic
soils where you're just feeding amino
acids and organic compounds, but it is a
a plant available form of nitrogen
that's very very beneficial when the
plant does uptake it. And that's
typically skipped in the scientific
literature because most the I'd say 99%
of um studies use the inorganic forms
which are ammonium and nitrate. So in
our systems the plants we can assume the
plants are uptaking a certain amount of
organic
nitrogen. So once it's turned into
organic nitrogen a different set of
biology transforms it into ammonium very
very quickly. uh in a in a warm moist
soil. This these this transition happens
very very quickly. Um and then a
different set of of bacteria convert the
ammonium into nitrate. So nitrate is is
the final uh form all of the organic
nitrogen we apply to the soil eventually
ends up as nitrate. And it's a pretty
quick transition from ammonium to
nitrate as well in again with the
conditions we're talking about. So, um
you can sort of see where your soil is
in that mineralization process based on
that level of ammonium, that middle
step. The weakness of soil testing is it
doesn't show us the entire quantity of
organic nitrogen in the soil. We're only
seeing those final two pools of
nitrogen, ammonium, and nitrate. So you
can sort of gauge how much nitrogen is
in the soil just based on ammonium and
nitrate and you can see how mineralized
it is based on how low ammonium is and
how high nitrate
is. So I hope that makes sense. I mean
essentially what we're doing is we're
just throwing nitrogen into the organic
bucket and the biology is transforming
it pretty quickly into the nitrate
bucket. So when I see
ammonium let's say over two or 3 ppm I
can assume that there was some sort of
nitrogen previously applied fairly
recently and it's still moving into
nitrate. Um it is true that you you
definitely so let's say we were in a
hydro system and you fed
100% ammonium ammonium sulfate or
something versus 100% nitrate. So, um I
don't know, let's just say calcium
nitrate. The the cannabis plant
absolutely will perform better uh in the
nitrate scenario, but the soils we're
working in again, they have a lot of
access to amino acids and small organic
compounds. The ammonium tends to be
pretty low. The nitrogen or the nitrate
tends to be pretty high just because
that conversion process is happening so
quickly. So, you know, in organic
systems, you're not actually you don't
really have much control over whether
the the nitrogen's in the ammonium or
nitrate form other than time. You can
wait longer and it'll all convert to
nitrate.
Yeah. A couple other things around that
that I'd like to add is so we so we have
this organic pool of nitrogen that's
it's essentially tied up within the
microorganisms within the organic matter
within these fertilizers that we're
adding and it's being converted or cover
crops that are breaking down. All those
things are going to have nitrogen that's
going to slowly be releasing. It's then
this is the organic pool of nitrogen
that we can't really measure as
effectively. Um, and that's what you're
referring to there. And then it, you
know, converts to ammonium like you
said. Now, ammonium,
uh, and this is where I want to get some
some clarification from you. Ammonium
would put upward pressure on our pH,
whereas nitrate being an ani would put
negative downward pressure on pH. And
where I see ammonium levels on soil
tests is typically when people mix a
soil and then send it in for a test
right away or when they add compost or
organic matter that's not fully
composted. And the implications of that
is our our our nitrate nitrates and our
nitrogen recommendation is just going to
be a little bit harder to dial in.
So, ideally what we like to do with our
soil tests is we we mix the soil, we
wait two to three weeks in and let me
emphasize in warm conditions, if I did
this in the winter in a pile outside,
that nitrogen's not converting at a very
quick very fast rate and it's not going
to it's not going to switch to nitrates.
But if we wait, you know, two to three
weeks and then send in our soil test,
the result we get back is going to be
more accurate in terms of our nitrate
levels, which will allow us to make a
better decision about where we're at for
nitrogen. And I would assume, and this
is where I want your clarification, I
would assume our pH would be a little
more accurate, too. Um, I know you and I
talked about this, you didn't feel like
it it changed pH as much, but I have I
feel like I've seen that a little bit on
tests. I don't know. Yeah. So in a in a
living soil there's a well first off
there's way more buffering capacity. Um
and also these transitions happen
quickly and sort of u non-homogeneously
in the soil to a certain extent. So yes
in theory if you put down a large
application of a fastreleasing nitrogen
source that first conversion will drop
the pH. So, if you tested in the middle
of um like you amended the soil and
immediately took a test, you might see a
dip in pH, especially in a soil that's
sort of doesn't have a lot of buffering
capacity. But typically, if you wait a
few weeks, a a drop a drop or a raise,
wouldn't you see a raise from Well, so
you would see an increase uh at first
and then a drop. So, so, but again, I
don't actually see that be in in most
peakbased soils. I just don't I I can't
even think of an instance when I've seen
that. And I believe that's because I'm
telling people to to wait um and to let
the full conversion process happen. And
I also just think that uh I'm not even
sure in most soils that that is that
visual. Maybe a couple um ten of a pH
drop. Are you seeing significant pH
drops? Like the soil's at a 68 and it
drops to a 55, that type of thing.
It's hard for me to say because I don't
see enough tests like in a row, you
know, right? two weeks apart or three
weeks apart to where I can really say.
But I do see a tra I I do worry that if
I see a high ammonium number and I know
that's converting to nitrates and I'm
already at a low pH uh you know 63 or
something, I'm worried that that pH as
those nitrates mineralize could
potentially drop further. I know you're
less concerned about that, but I just
something I was thinking of. One thing I
do want to highlight though that you
said is that we're we're these soils are
not homogeneous. We're acting like soil
is homogeneous. It's not. There's all
these different pockets of phes and
mineralization and nutrient
availability, microbes. Um, and I just
think that's important for people to try
and keep in mind. It's really like it's
like visualizing space. I don't feel
like we can fully Yeah. understand it.
Um, but also the other thing with this
nitrogen conversion, especially when we
add nutrients to the soil, if we add a
large amount of
fertility, we really have to treat it
like a like a thermopilic compost in the
sense that that soil potentially is
going to heat up uh because the bacteria
is reproducing so rapidly as they get
this food source. And the concern with
that is that um it's it's going to make
it inhospitable to plant roots or less
hospitable to plant roots. So that's
another reason when I see a higher
ammonium number, I say, "Okay, let's not
plant yet. we need to let the soil cycle
a little further um to allow this
nitrogen to convert. Make sure the soil
temperature is good um not too hot so
that nitrogen Yeah. I think when when a
soil heats up it's it's just tons of
cellular respiration happening with the
the bacteria primarily and they're
actually consuming a lot of oxygen. So
my my fear is you're just you're
planting into a low oxygen environment
because the microbes are are using so
much oxygen. Um, and as you mentioned
previously, definitely a really young
plant isn't going to want a high
ammonium nitrogen environment. So,
waiting is
preferable. Um, but I just want to
emphasize when you put in an organic
nitrogen, the the net change in pH
should be zero. So, yes, you're going to
get you're going to get a fluctuation
boop boop. But that con conversion
process is quick. It's super dynamic.
And so to try to manage the pH during
that blip of time uh doesn't make sense
to me because it should start at seven
and end at seven for example.
Um now if you were using an if if you
use an a nonorganic form of nitrogen
it's
different. So but we're primarily
talking about organic amendments here.
Yeah. Yeah, I guess the context for me
is more like I see a soil test on
freshly mixed soil that is a low pH,
high ammonium, I worry that it may drop
a little further because we don't know
where we're starting with that mix. Um
whereas like you said with remendment
with nitrogen, that makes that makes a
lot of sense. That's really useful. Now,
one thing that you also uh wanted to
talk about was why nitrogen targets in
living soil that's being used multiple
rounds might be different than other
cultivation. Yeah, this is this is
something that I think is an important
point that I've thought about a lot
honestly for years.
the a soil fresh out of the bag. Um, you
know, my target level of nitrogen, which
is should should totally be based on the
soil volume per plant, the length of
time the plant is in the soil, um, how
much supplemental feeding is done, etc.
But generally speaking, 100 to 150 ppm
of nitrate nitrogen, low ammonium shows
that the soil is fully mineralized.
That's a really good target number.
Every time I test a fresh kiss soil,
it's somewhere, you know, approximately
in that range. Um,
also one nuance here. F testing a fresh
soil out of the bag is going to be less
accurate than testing a soil after it's
been through a round. It's just always
less homogeneous even if you mix it
super super well. But point being, if
you're somewhere in that, let's say, 100
ppm, 125 ppm range, that's a lot of
nitrogen.
What happens though if you use the soil,
let's say 10 rounds in a row, is every
round you're applying more organic
nitrogen, more alphaalfpha meal, um more
compost, more granular poultry manure,
whatever.
And the majority of that nitrogen in
that in those amendments and that
compost does get broken down within a
round, but a lot of it remains because
of two things. The carbon to nitrogen
ratio and the particle size. So if you
put in a big wood, if you put drop a
wood chip into the soil, that's going to
take a fairly long time to mineralize
and to to decompose in your soil
compared to a tiny little particle of
blood meal, which is really really high
in nitrogen, low in carbon, and has a
small particle size. So as you put in
all this organic nitrogen over time, not
all of it's releasing, and you start to
build this reservoir of organic nitrogen
that's releasing slowly. And so over
many rounds, you actually have this this
large reservoir of nitrogen that is
releasing slowly that we're not seeing
on a soil test. And so in general, I
think growers who are who are on
multiple rounds in the same soil can
start to lower their nitrogen target
well below 125 ppm. Um, and I've gotten
feedback from growers who are in, you
know, around 25,
uh, that that my nitrogen target is
feels a little too high in their soils
and that they're actually getting really
good results with, uh, and their plants
are are finishing at a at a coloration
they like, a greenness level they like
with much much lower levels. And I just
think that's because they have 25 rounds
of alphalfpha meal application that's
still slowly mineralizing. So for
example in aronomy you assume that 50%
of a compost would become available in
year one 25 the next year
25% the third year. So we can sort of
think of it as that if there's sort of a
staggering release rate across some of
these amendments.
Yeah, I would expect release rates to be
faster in soilless media because we
have, you know, more biology
uh warmer temperatures and controlled
environment agriculture, you know,
indoors. But I think the principle of it
absolutely just think of that 50 2525 as
a principle and not as as a as a rule to
follow in in the soils we're talking
about.
Uh yeah, I don't know have a lot to add
to that. I think that's really
interesting and I think that's a very
good point and we do, you know, we see
the same thing.
Um and the nice thing about nitrogen is
it's pretty easy to add and it's pretty
easy to visually see symptoms of. It's
it's the easiest
deficiency well and maybe even toxicity
to really uh see in your plants. And too
much nitrogen, you're going to you're
going to have issues. You're going to
see the the clawing. you're going to see
um you know lower yields potentially
greater pest pressure. So really having
proper levels of nitrogen is is
important. And then if you need to add
nitrogen um I mean fish hydraulicates
probably my favorite quick liquid feed
that's affordable and not you know
you're not buying a a marketing branded
product I guess. Yeah absolutely say
that's one of two options I love. I I'd
also
um say that to me the the
best the be the best way to create your
own internal nitrogen targets internal
meaning in your own operation is to is
to just judge your plants at harvest.
Did they fade too too fast and too early
or are they too green and too
vegetative, too leafy at harvest? and
and look at where your nitrogen is and
kind of adjust from there. Um, I tell
people this all the time where it's
like, I'm going to recommend a certain
amount of nitrogen to hit the the
nitrogen target, but ultimately you
should be reading your plants like you
said. And I think just where your last
round ended is is the best metric for
that.
Yeah, my last round, which I shared on
Instagram if people want to see, but um
I felt like I finished a little high in
nitrogen. So, I'll I'll go through get
the test, get the recommendation, and
then I I'll probably take my nitrogen
target and adjust it down by Exactly.
That's exactly right. And
then, but I I'll still work off the same
target and then I'll just lower it and
then I'll see how that round goes. And
if it's if it's still high, you know, if
it if it's high, then I can adjust it
down further. Or if it starts to get low
and I find I have to apply something.
The other thing, you know, you could
look at is is blood meal would be
another pretty fast um nitrogen source
that you mentioned. Um so yeah, you can
just make adjustments like that. I think
that's a really good point.
Um, something that's not on your list of
topics, but something I wanted to talk
about because I've been thinking a lot
about it lately is is rock dusts in
living soils. I know um certain mixes
like the Coot mix for example recommends
pretty high levels of rock dust and
people are always worried about getting
their trace minerals.
Now my lately the way I've been
approaching it is one, you know,
particle size is king here. The smaller
the particle size, the sooner these, you
know, these rock dust will become
available. But the amount of time it
would take for the microbes to break it
down for, you know, any sort of
weathering
and
mineralization is not a timeline that I
want for like production cannabis. Um,
just because it's such an unknown
variable. And then I worry that all of
these rock dusts are bringing in some
level of heavy metals. And I'm just so
hypervigilant about heavy metals these
days with um you know working with law
facilities that are regulated for it
that I'm more inclined to lean
towards sulfates or um you know just a
tiny amount of rock dust, a tiny amount
of kelp meal. Um I don't know what what
are your thoughts on I know I'm throwing
a curveball here.
never recommend rock dust or kelpmeal in
cannabis production primarily for a
concern around heavy metals but
also I do not see them as a replacement
for micronutrient sulfates and when I
say micronutrients I'm talking about the
five essential micronutrients iron
manganesees zinc copper and boron there
are dozens of non-essential trace
minerals that are brought in with rock
dust and kelp meal
um that the plant doesn't need but in
theory would make it stronger, could be
a bio stimulant, could feed biology,
could make some kind of expression
happen. But personally, I've I've used
rock dust and and kelp meal for over a
decade in my own growing, and I've never
seen um amazing crop responses or any
I've actually never seen anything from
rock dust. I've seen stuff from kelmeal,
but kelp meal also has a little bit of
nitrogen in it and quite a bit of
potassium, so it's tough to know exactly
where that response is coming from. Um,
but in general, you apply you apply
these products for the non-essential
trace minerals, you're never going to
get a high enough quantity of the five
essential micronutrients from those
products. So, they may help. They may be
bio- stimulating. They generally don't
hurt except when they're used in high
quantities. You can run into issues with
heav heavy metals. So, I'm not adamantly
against them, but I think that growers
often want to skip the the micronutrient
sulfates, the iron sulfate, manganese
sulfate, soluble, that type of stuff,
and use rock dust instead. And it's just
not a a onetoone replacement. Um, and
I'll also mention that growers don't
like the micronutrient sulfates, which I
sort of understand why intuitively if
you use them and you look at them, they
they just don't feel that natural. So to
put them in a living soil feels weird,
especially copper sulfate, it's got that
weird blue color.
Um, and but generally they express that
concern around sulfur. you're
applying orders of magnitude more sulfur
with the use of gypsum which is not
villainized in cannabis production to
the same extent the micronutrient
sulfates are. So,
um, if you're trying to you, you know,
minimize sulfur, you really have to sort
of eliminate gypsum and potassium
sulfate and langite and epsom salt way
before you eliminate manganese sulfate,
which I'm recommending at two teaspoons.
Um, just very tiny quantities, just a
couple grams in an entire cubic yard of
soil volume. So uh yeah I don't that's
why I don't recommend
uh rock dust
and when you are getting trace minerals
from your compost fraction in your soil
too that's probably and all the other
amendments from bone meals and anything
from the ocean has a huge amount of
these trace minerals uh you know
alphalfpha meal all it's got it all in
really small quantities and generally
the trace minerals that aren't essential
if they're going to work, if they're
going to do anything, they're needed in
extremely small quantities anyway. So,
you should be in these soils that were
amending heavily and that have tons of
compost, there should be plenty of these
trace minerals.
Um, now that said, I may be a little bit
of a hypocrite because before I planted
a thousand trees on my farm, I
definitely threw in a little bit of
of just small small quantity of rock
dust. Um, but, you know, that's mostly
because I just had it lying around and I
wanted to use it. It I I would not bet a
dollar that it's actually doing anything
to my trees.
People can disagree with me and that's
totally fine. It's just I'm just
speaking to my own experience here.
Yeah, I did some trials when we were
remending uh or creating our nutrient
pack and I had with long conversations
with Coot back in the day, we did some
trials at the local horiculture college
and one of them on his recommendation
was high levels of rock dust for the
remendment with the idea of getting
these trace minerals and basically there
just was inadequate fertility because
there there there was no available
nutrients in it and um so we've kind of
we've kind I've kind of moved away from
rock dust philosophically for the same
reasons you're listing and I just
thought it was I thought it was an
interesting topic because a lot of
people have been asking me about
azimite. I mean, yeah, sorry. I think
kelmeal definitely does. Kelmeal has all
kinds of bioimulating effects um and
hormonal effects and like I said, it has
nitrogen and a lot of potassium. So,
kelme is a more complicated topic. Uh
it's also much more
available. Um, but it but to me the the
the rate, you know, the dose makes the
poison and the rate, for whatever
reason, kelpmeal rates in cannabis
production are just generally too high.
Uh, you're also bringing in a ton of
sodium and chloride if you apply it in
really high quantities. So, less is more
with kelpmeal. I'm not as clearly uh I'm
not anti- kelpmeal. I just think you
want to watch the quantity. Also, just,
you know, there's a lot of arsenic, so
if you're getting tested, you don't want
to use it in high quantities. Um, and
any bio- stimulant should be acting in
in a very low
dose. What one note to add to all this
is if you do want to play around with
these micronutrient sulfates, uh, I
would highly suggest you don't add
anything without a soil test to go off
of. And if you do add anything, we are
talking minute amounts because you can
absolutely screw up your soil with
toxicities by adding too much. So, um,
and you really have to know what you're
doing because like soluble for example
is significantly stronger than borax.
So, if if you screw up for some reason
and grab soluble on a borax
recommendation, you can way overdo your
boron. So, just be careful playing math
scientist with micronutrients. There's
also a spectrum within them. you know,
you can apply quite a bit of ferrris,
you know, iron sulfate, but um not so
much copper or boron. So, and what my
just to kind of run through it, when I
use micronutrient sulfates, I dissolve
them in water. I add a carbon source of
some kind. So, typically that's um a
humic substance, like a dissolvable
humic acid or
molasses. Uh and
uh maybe to go back to this
conversation, a kelp is a a source of
carbon. So, just a touch of of kelp. Um,
and then I and then I always apply it in
water because it's distributed more
evenly than you never apply them dry.
So, I I inject it into my irrigation
system.
Um, so anyway, that the theory there is
you're you may be chelating a little bit
with a carbon source. You're also
buffering it biologically a little bit.
So you're giving the microbes something
to eat with it. So you're, you know,
when the the microbes consume the carbon
or the sugar source, um, they may be
incorporating those those micronutrients
into their bodies. Um, and that's a
that's a that remains that keeps those
micronutrients in a more plant available
form longer because they you're
essentially taking an inorganic salt and
turning it into an organic form. Um, and
the the issue with some of these, like
iron sulfate specifically, but a little
bit manganese sulfate, too, is is redux
matters a lot. So, most of if you just
drench iron sulfate straight into a a
soil with a pH over six or 65, it'll
immediately oxidize and just rust, turns
to rust, and it's not plant available.
So, trying to chilate specifically iron
or put it into a more organic form will
keep it available longer.
That's a really great point around iron.
Yeah, thank you for reminding folks of
that. Um, yeah, I just I just take like
for I recently did a manganese sulfate
application. I I just mixed it with
water and then applied it over the top
of my beds uh with a just a sprinkler
can even. But I I haven't I hadn't
thought about adding a little bit of
molasses or some other carbon source in
there. So, I might have to experiment
with that. That's a good idea.
Um okay moving on then let's talk a
little bit about uh
transpiration in plants and what role
that plays in sort of yeah fun so it's
you know I I think about nutrition a lot
and I look at a lot of tissue tests
we've been talking about soil and I I
really look
at a lot of tissue tests next to soil
tests and it's always bothered me a
little bit that they're not perfectly
correlated. And so I spend a lot of time
trying to understand why if you have
great sufficiency and balance in the
soil, it doesn't always translate into
the right sufficiency in plant leaves.
And I've always known that the the
biggest reason is is transpiration. Um
although there's other factors, too.
And so I've I've gone into sort of the
the science of what causes transpiration
and it there's a lot of misconception
um in
horiculture around what drives
transpiration. So for example, you know,
I've always thought like
VPD drives transpiration rate, but
that's actually not uh that not quite
accurate. the if you really dive into
the physics of plants and energy uh
energy to the leaves drives evaporation
from the leaves and so that's radiation
energy and convection so air movement
warm air um and and then
sunlight and that that is ultimately
what's going to drive the rate of
evaporation out of leaves and then the
final thing to note is the stomata have
to be open so relative humidity does
play a role in that. Temperature plays a
role in that, but ultimately it's the
it's the differential in vapor pressure
inside the leaf versus outside the leaf.
Um,
but ultimately you're you're you're
changing your evaporation rate based on
the total energy hitting the leaf.
During the day when the lights are on or
when the sun is out, the the majority of
that energy is
uh radiation. It's from light. And so in
a sense the uh VPD doesn't actually
matter nearly as much during the day. It
matters more at night because convection
is the only source of energy driving
transpiration. But during the day, light
intensity and whether or not the stomata
are open are the key variables to to the
rate of transpiration.
Um, so anyway, I'm kind of going too far
into the weeds here, but if you think
about how plants uptake
nutrients, sufficiency and balance in
the soil absolutely matters, but the but
the rate of evaporation out of the
leaves is is the second thing that we
don't quantify, we often don't really
think about, but is ultimately going to
determine how many nutrients are moving
into the plant. Um so for example I just
see really poor
uh correlation between calcium and boron
immobile nutrients in the plant tissue
and how much is in the soil and that's
totally because of transpiration rates
because they move with Exactly. So, as
soon as evaporation stops, you're not
getting calcium uptake. And um maybe not
in indoor environments as much as
definitely in greenhouse environments.
Growers don't think about nighttime
evaporation, but as soon as there
there's tons of heat emission coming off
of the plant leaves, and so plant leaves
cool down, especially when they're
exposed to the open sky at night. And so
the the leaf temperature can drop.
You're not getting any radiation. And
evaporation can essentially stop at
night, which is a major problem for
creating weak cells at the top of the
plant, increases disease susceptibility,
but also just stops nutrient transport.
And you want nutrient transport
happening 24 hours a day. So there's a
number of issues around evaporation
um that I think about.
So I've always thought of it a little
bit differently in the sense that um
evapot transpiration is being pushed
by
VPD as well as um air flow across the
leaf surface because that higher levels
of air flow if you have a plant near a
fan and then you start to get that that
uh leaf tip burn essentially is is a
lack of calcium um that's developing is
because the plant can't evapot
transanspirate fast enough to
accommodate the amount of nutrients that
are going up through the leaf and so
it's not pulling up calcium um fast
enough to allow for that is is how Nadia
Dr. Greenhouse explained it to me. Um,
and I thought that was really
interesting. And I do see plants, um,
and people, you know, people could do
this experiment, but essentially if you
put a plant near a fan, um, it's going
to dramatically impact the level, the
water needs and the amount of evapot
transanspiration that's occurring in
that plant versus a plant that's further
away from a fan that's not getting the
same air flow. Yeah. So air flow will
will increase that. So there's radiation
energy and convection energy. And so if
you increase air flow, you're increasing
the convection energy to the leaf, which
will increase the evaporation rate.
Absolutely. The problem with what you're
seeing is the leaf probably can't keep
up with the rate of evaporation. So it
closes its stomata because when it
experiences water stress, it'll close
its
stomata and the then the only way for it
to to maintain energy balance is to
radiate heat. So the leaf temperature
will go up and you can start to see uh
you know burning issues essentially. And
so the issue there to me with is with
excessive um air flow is the stomata are
closing.
H you know here it's really interesting.
So the way I've
always Oh gonna say like when I see
issues on plants the first thing I look
at too is is watering and VPD because
those are which is another way of
approaching this transpiration thing
that you're talking about is this idea
that is there
sufficient water in the media in the
soil for plant roots to take up and
transpire and then you know what what is
the humidity in the room that allows for
these sorts of transpiration to occur.
the mo so relative humidity
um matters a lot in terms of the opening
and the closing of the stomata but what
I always I always thought and this was a
misconception that low relative humidity
would increase
transpiration so if you dry out the air
it'll increase transpiration in other
words if you increase the VPD
transpiration will go up
like the plant would like the plant's
trying to compensate So it transpires
more. I mean, this is what you people
say. If you increase BPD, you increase
transpiration. But I but for what I I
wouldn't see that in the tissue data
with calcium. And it turns out that this
isn't necessarily true. In fact, in
certain instances, a high relative
humidity creates more evaporation
because a high relative humidity can
open the stomata, allowing the plant to
actually evaporate water out. So it's
not a humidity matters but it matters
because in part because it's opening and
closing the stomata which allows for
evaporation. Um so when someone says VPD
growers usually think of temperature and
relative humidity on you know on the
chart
and it's not necessarily the right
metric to determine stomodel opening. Um
you know again temperature and relative
humidity matter but the the the air
vapor pressure deficit in itself
doesn't. So if you know
growers that what what really matters is
leaf temperature and so I think a lot of
people um have heard that they should
use a leaf temperature adjustment and
that's that is the key to keeping
stomata open and closed and anyone who's
transitioned from an HPS to an LED light
knows that. um you get wildly different
results if you keep the VPD the same and
it's because there's a change in leaf
temperature. So the key here to really
understand evaporation rate to really
understand if the stomata are open and
closed is to is to understand leaf
temperature and to use leaf temperature
to do the BPD calculation.
That's really interesting. Yeah, it's
it's kind of been difficult for me to to
to learn because I'm having to relearn
and it's it's like there's these certain
principles that I've always held as this
is how it works and um it's taken me a
long time to to try to understand these
new concepts um around
evaporation because it doesn't really
work with my existing sort of my
previous learning around how it worked.
Um, but now that I'm sort of
understanding the the opening and
closing of stomata and evaporation rate,
it's it's helping me immensely in in
sort of understanding how these
high-tech green houses are are managing
their environmental conditions.
Yeah, I'm gonna have to reach out to
Nadia for
a, you know, more of an explanation or
more discussion around this topic
because I think it's really interesting
and I I don't want to say that I fully
understand everything you're saying here
in regards to it. I'm still processing
it. But I think that's uh I think that's
interesting and that's what I love about
plants
and you know aronomy and all of this is
I feel like I never stop learning or
being challenged by by new concepts or
new ways of thinking around things.
Yeah. Yeah, definitely. I mean there's a
it's it sort of a whole world of plants
are like these incredibly
complex systems. And so and what I think
the hardest part for me in understanding
is when you change one variable you
multiple other variables change
simultaneously. So um that's sort of
what makes it complex.
Yeah. So on the topic of tissue testing
just to stay on that topic you mentioned
some stuff around
um sampling. Yeah. you know, tissue
testing. Further, there's a few things I
just want to communicate to growers who
are already tissue testing or or
thinking about it, which is
the the need to test. There's a couple
things you it's important to test at the
right time in a cycle.
Um there's because as you know, Tad,
that the plant will transllocate
nutrients late in the cycle. So,
Usually there's, you know, after sort of
the plant stops stretching, the flowers
are stacking, the the majority of the
assimilates are going toward the flowers
and there's less leaf growth. And so
certain immobile nutrients are going to
accumulate more and more and more in the
large fan leaves. Um, and other
nutrients that are mobile are going to
be moved out of the fan leaves and moved
into the flowers where they're needed.
So after about week two of flower and
more so after week four, but I like week
two as the target time to tissue test,
but after week two, three, four, the the
nutrients get really odd on a tissue
test, and there's not an easy way to
analyze the results of the tissue test.
So, I I'm I've received so many tissue
tests on cannabis from like plants at
harvest and it's just I I can't even
make a recommendation on it because the
calcium levels are skyhigh and the
nitrogen is low and there's not really a
target level that we're looking at. So,
I think it's really important for
growers to to um tissue test before week
two of flower. you can tissue test and
veg um really anytime before
then you know week one week two you
could go to week three probably but
after that it's it's really unhelpful
data um so that's the first thing the
other thing is the size of the leaf
really matters because like I said
calcium will accumulate in the larger
leaves the older leaves I should say so
if you're taking fan leaves um three or
four notes down you're going to get a
much different number than if you're
taking the new small leaves at the top
of the plant. And so you can think you
have low calcium because the leaves that
you're pulling are too small, too young.
So it's it's really important to stay
consistent and to make sure that the
leaves that you're pulling are are fully
expanded large leaves.
Um, I like a couple nodes down just the
the first leaf on a branch that you
think is, you know, mature. And then
whatever you choose, you stay consistent
with that sampling protocol. And those
are the two big mistakes that people
make. And I I always feel bad because,
you know, this is a lot of time and
money that people are spending sampling.
So, week two of flower, fully expanded,
new growth.
So, I I I think those are good points. I
like the idea of tissue testing for the
data that it gives us. I think it's
expensive relative to soil testing for
managing fertility. And I've actually
used tissue testing a little differently
in the sense that later in flower. So,
so if you want to use tissue testing as
a as a agonomic tool for dis, you know,
data driven decisions, then I think week
two makes a lot of sense. But where I've
used it is I have a plant, let's say
week five, week six, and something's
going on and I can't figure out what it
is. U I'll do a tissue test and then
that'll tell me, oh, this reflects, you
know, what I thought I was seeing
visually and then I have a better idea
of what a visual symptom for that
nutrient is. and then I make sure to
address it on the next round. I'm not I
can't I don't feel I can use that tissue
test to
make definitive decisions about my
fertility applications the next cycle.
But it it's like a one more piece of
information that supports what I'm
seeing. And so just to clarify, are you
sap testing or are you tissue testing? I
don't
know. Tissue. I haven't gotten into SAP
testing for a few reasons. I think it's
really interesting, but my concerns
around it are the cost, the fact that
the databases are not really publicly
available. They're all sort of internal
to these labs, which I struggle with as
a you know, wanting more transparency
there. And then
um yeah, the fact that it's a number
that's going to be changing so much um I
would just need to be really I feel like
dialed in with consistency on testing.
That being said, I do think it's really
interesting and I think it has value. I
just I haven't personally gotten to
where that's one of the tools that I'm
Yeah, similar. I I What are your
thoughts?
I like I like to just say start with
tissue testing. It's $40 a test compared
to, you know, um I think 75 to 100 for
SAP testing. You also have to get the
sample to the lab sooner. It's got to be
on ice so that the cost ends up being
more than double when you're sap
testing. It also in my experience
doesn't help to see a single SAP test at
any random point in the cycle. It should
be done like every two weeks. So then
you you're looking at a much larger
expense. I also
see I also totally agree with I struggle
with the lack of
um yeah transparency. I mean new age has
has has become my go-to lab, but I've
been working with SAP testing before
they were around and I've just continued
to have issues. Also, you're getting
recommendations from the lab, and I tend
to disagree with a lot of these lab
recommendations, especially around high
chloride. So, yeah, I have a bunch of
small issues with sap testing, but at
the end of the day, I just think the
lowhanging fruit if you want to test
your tissue is to get a $40 tissue test
at week two of flower. Just start with
one. There's research established target
levels, multiple different um researched
levels that are all pretty similar. And
so, that's just like an easy
interpretation. It's 40 bucks. Y you do
it once. Stop testing I I do use in um
in large production systems where let's
say a a 3% increase in yield makes a
huge difference economically. Um yeah,
layering in SAP testing on top of tissue
testing makes sense. Um but it but
honestly how I've used it is to do
tissue testing, do sap testing, and they
the idea is you're just trying to to
validate one you're trying to validate
the test to really pinpoint to be extra
super confident when you're targeting
nutrients just because it just gives you
more confidence uh in that that
application is going to um be the right
one. So, for example, I use it in
orchard crops a lot because we're
talking about just huge swaths, huge
applications. You know, if you're going
to if you apply, let's say you apply
potassium, that could be, you know, a
$10,000 application. So, you just want
to have as much data as possible to back
it up. Um, but yeah, I mean, I would be
concerned about tissue testing that late
because I don't really know what the
numbers are supposed to say. Um, you're
always going to see deficient nitrogen
at week eight, for example.
Yeah, I don't I don't use it so much for
nitrogen that late, but but more just to
see if there's a trace mineral issue or
if what I'm seeing visually matches with
like what deficiency I think it is is
reflected on that test. And again, it's
I don't use it very often as a tool. I
I'm more focused on soil testing at this
point in time, but I I absolutely
understand and especially in things like
hydro, I think it makes a lot a lot of
sense. Um, and I will just say as a
shout out to New Age and Scott. I've met
him a couple years now at uh the soil
summit and he's a great guy. I always
enjoy hearing his talks. Um, I think
it's really interesting. It's just not a
technology that I've really um yeah, I
mean I I have sent SAP samples to the
Netherlands for years. I've sent them to
to New Age. Um, and actually I did some
split tests last year for people who who
do want a SAP test. And actually the
results in in stone fruit um between New
Age and Nova Crop Control in the
Netherlands were were very similar. So
um no need to send them across the ocean
if you're going to sap test. I think New
Age is the way to
go. Great. Well, we're running out of
time, but I I wanted to talk to you just
briefly or not so briefly. We'll see how
it goes about um sort of your new
philosophies that you've been exploring
around cultivation. Now, for those that
aren't familiar, you have a course um
through your sole doctor website that
you've had for years now. I've audited
the course. It's it's wonderful. For
people who want a deep dive in soil
testing and want the ability to really
understand those results and read their
own tests and make their own
recommendation, this is the best
publicly available tool uh for folks. Um
you can check it out on the soul doctor
website. But um yeah, working on
something new. So I've spent almost
eight months the last eight months
deeply studying greenhouse optimization.
So I've been learning the principles
used in some of the world's largest
most high-tech green houses, the Dutch
glass houses, where they're just
achieving unbelievable yields and plant
health, like sweet pepper plants that
are 10 feet tall, just loaded with
peppers, and just really
um amazing results.
And
uh so with all this, I'm sort of
creating this this program that will
teach professional growers principles of
what creates general plant balance uh in
a greenhouse or indoor growroom. Um and
the techniques and tools to achieve, you
know, this kind of performance depending
on what level of technology people have.
So this involves the use of various
different technology as well as sensors
and automation to improve facilities.
Um, and so I'm developing it for
commercial growers who have some degree
of control of their environment. So
unfortunately outdoor production, you
don't necessarily have much control over
the different conditions. Um, but I'm
trying to take these principles that are
used in the highest tech autonomous
green houses and apply them all the way
down to like low tech high tunnels. Um,
so from sort of CA all the way to low
tunnel or low tech high tunnels and
green houses. Um, and the content has
traditionally just been for these really
advanced green houses, but I don't see
why some of these principles can't be
applied at to every level of grower. And
so I'm trying to that's kind of my
inspiration behind it. It's kind of a
Robin Hood scheme to to take this
amazing information from these big
companies and universities and change it
a bit and apply it to multiple different
contexts and and present it as
succinctly as possible. So that's what
I've been working on doing. It's been
it's taken a long time. It's a lot of
learning for me. It's also just a lot of
content and research to go through. Um
but most of this is content from um
Bahaning University in the Netherlands.
there's some professors there that have
really innovated how to think about
greenhouse production. Um, so that's
what I've been working on. I mean, it
goes through like a lot of the the the
scientific balance of plants. Um, and
then it goes into sort of the the goal
of the grower and different checklists
uh and how to measure things, what to
measure, different tools for creating
balance. So if you're in a greenhouse,
um what kind of materials to be using in
your greenhouse, diffusion plastics,
high pressure fogging, AC, and then I go
through most of the course is actually
going through scenarios. So I'm trying
to connect the principles to a ton of
real world grower situations. Um so can
you give me some examples of these
principles that you mentioned that are
in the course just so we can have a
better idea can flesh out what you're
what you're describing? Sure. Um so one
of the scenarios that I discuss
is is around disease and how to reduce
the susceptibility of disease.
Um and so traditionally, you know, we're
thinking a lot about humidity and air
flow and air movement.
Um, I really talk a lot in this program
about how to prevent free water on the
leaves, which is often one of the root
causes of disease, either plant cell
damage or condensation. So, while
relative humidity does increase risk of
condensation, condensation can also
happen at relatively low humidity
levels. Um and the final thing that can
cause disease is a weak plant which is
almost always from an assimilate or a
photosynthesate imbalance in the plant.
So soilborn diseases but also above
ground diseases always happen when the
plant's natural immune system isn't
powerful enough to fight back which is
often due to an assimilate imbalance um
or an assimilate deficit really. So a
steady production and consumption of
assimilates leads to steady root growth
and and steady um root exodation. And
this is what feeds a healthy microbial
population. So if your microbes lose
their primary food source, they won't be
able to defend the roots nearly as well.
So that's sort of where I'm kind of
coming from from an assimilate balance
standpoint. Um, and there's a number of
different techniques that you can use to
balance assimilate consumption and
production in the plant. Production
being photosynthesis. And one is looking
at your average daily temperature
compared to the DLI. That is like a
really really powerful steering
technique. Um, and just it's a it's a
really great way to keep the production
and consumption of a similant stable on
a 24-hour basis. So that's an example.
Um, and then going back to disease, I
talk a lot about how to prevent
condensation. Um, and depending on the
facility, for example, in green houses,
I mentioned you get a lot of heat
emission at night. So, I talk about ways
to to make sure your plant temperature
doesn't reach due point using climate
screens um and other other means uh
increasing air movement. How to increase
air movement. So, um I I've mentioned
this too. love your convection tubing in
the canopy. Um I'm also doing a lot of
experiments with vertical air fans, so
like Vflow fans. Um and trying to create
air flow into the canopy. And then
finally, temperature swings. And that
can happen through, you know, all kinds
of different things. So, I've talked a
lot about ventilation optimization and
how to sort of manage your your vents
and how to ventilate your greenhouse to
avoid temperature swings. Um, and like I
said, condensation can happen at
relatively low relative humidity.
So, I talk about how to how to determine
your ventilation. For example, growers
should be using absolute
humidity, not necessarily relative
humidity, to determine uh ventilation.
There's this really sort of wild example
that always confused me. You can have a
um let's say an outdoor temperature
of
like 68 degrees Fahrenheit, 20 Celsius,
and 85 relative humidity. And
um if it's if it's warmer outside with a
lower relative humidity and you vent,
you can actually
uh cool your your greenhouse because the
enthalpy or the energy outside is lower
than inside. So there's all these
fascinating examples of where
ventilation um should be toggled with
absolute humidity instead. So things
like that, just tons of scenarios on how
to manage the environment inside a
greenhouse. You were able to I mean,
first of all, this is fascinating and I
know it's a it's a little bit of a
different direction for you here, but
I'm really excited for this um and to
learn more about this course. Uh do you
know when it's do you have an
approximate date for release or is it
still you know I'm trying to finish
something this year but uh I have you
know I'm still working extensively with
growers on nutrient management. I have,
you know, a large farm I'm managing,
especially in the spring. There's a lot
of work and I just have a lot more uh to
dive into. So, it probably won't be done
for several months, but late late 2025
is my goal. I I was going to say I so
wish you were able to make it to the
cannabis cultivation and science
conference in Bosezeman this year
because uh Collective Elevation where
we're hosting it has all of these
things. They have under a hamp air flow.
They have uh they have the vertical
airflow uh fans and all of these
different things working. And I'm Adam,
the owner, is so excited to have Nadia,
Dr. greenhouse come out and walk as part
of the workshop, walk through the
facility and point out everything and
and talk about how they may be doing
things right or wrong or optimized
because airflow and humidity and VBD is
such a complicated
uh topic and it's so misunderstood and
it's one thing that I I know it's one of
the things I'm least confident in myself
uh when it comes to cultivation
practices. So, um, yeah, I really I know
you were one of the first people I
reached out to, and I know you're busy,
but I was really hoping, uh, you'd be
gonna make it. If things change, it's an
open invite, obviously. Yeah, I'm sorry.
If things change, I'll absolutely let
you know. I would love to see that that
facility. Is it is it um fully indoor
with supplemental lighting or are they
NextG houses in Bosezeman, Montana with
they do have light depth capability, but
you know, they're growing in what, like
20. I'm probably under exaggerating at
negative 20 and then you know in the
winter and then all the way in the
summer when it's you know it can be in
the 90s or higher. So they deal with all
types of climates there and they're able
to grow year round which is and grow
healthy plants. It's pretty awesome.
They're the largest living soil producer
in Montana. um they may be one of the
larger ones um greenhouse ones that I'm
aware of in the country and they're just
phenomenally good people and good
growers and it's it's cool to
see you know I I am fascinated with
these mixed environments green houses
with supplemental
lights because there's so much more
potential but also they're they're
they're also much more difficult. you
really have to be good. Um because the
the the sun and the variability, you're
still working with the variability of
nature. So, you're not just setting your
the your lights, you're like having to
to sort of adjust and move on the fly to
varying radiation levels. Um and also
even cloud coverage. So, you know, for
example, at night, you're going to lose
a lot more heat with an open sky versus
cloudy sky, and you have to adjust. So,
it's a very technical and fascinating
form of culture. I'm sure they'd love to
have you out even if you can't make the
conference. So, uh, yeah. What What day
is the is the the greenhouse tour? The
5th. September 5th, there's going to be
the tour as well as the workshop with
Nadia, uh, going concurrently at the
same time as a workshop with Suzanne
Wayright Evans, the bug lady. She's
going to be doing a workshop, too. So,
Okay, cool. Well, maybe I can try to do
some kind of strike mission. I'm in the
it'll I'll be right in the middle of a
massive peach harvest that's like high
intensity and high consequence. So
that's why I'm not really able to make
it. But I'll I'll keep it I'll keep it
in mind, Tad, and I appreciate the
invite and um we'll see if anything
shifts. Awesome. Well, I really
appreciate your time today. I always
learn a ton when we get to talk and it's
always a lot of fun to have these
conversations and people ask actually
quite a bit like when am I going to have
you back on the show? So, I really
appreciate you coming back on and
sharing. Yeah, thank you. And I' I've
loved, you know, watching you grow this
podcast and grow your business over the
years. It's it's it's been really
inspirational and I really appreciate
what you've done and I really appreciate
you having me on and our relationship.
So, just thanks goes to you.