[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discussed
the cutting edge of organic growing from
a science-based perspective and drawn
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge our
guest today is Nelson Lindsley of poetry
of plants you can check him out on
instagram under poetry of plants Nelson
has been cultivating cannabis for over a
decade and working in the industry for
over two decades over the last three
years he has consulted on cultivation
sites in Washington Oregon Colorado
Pennsylvania and California Nelson has
been on the podcast before it is a
popular guest I wanted to get him back
on here to talk about an upcoming
project we are working on as well as
cover a range of topics ranging from
bottled nutrients so I'm excited to have
you back on the show to talk about well
a few different things so let's start
off telling listeners a little bit about
our new project sure can you can you
tell them about the dope history podcast
and what that really is all about yeah I
can the dope history podcast is going to
be a collection of narratives from
individuals that have been in the
cannabis community in cannabis world for
the last what 30 40 years all inclusive
so what we're doing is highlighting
particular journeys and narratives of
individuals that have built the
foundation for the cannabis market that
we have today so Nelson I will be
co-hosting this it's gonna be called the
dope history podcast you can go to dope
history com2 check it out and I'll have
all the information coming out on with
links on the podcast page for this
podcast but this is purely a labor of
love it's something that we're both
really excited about doing together as
project just to share some of these
really really amazing stories so our
hope is people while they're you know
working in their room or sitting back
having a joint they can just hear some
of the history around this plant and
some of the things that people have gone
through to get us to where we are today
great story like if there was a campfire
it would be perfect but we can't do that
digitally right yeah for sure there you
go
so just something something to chill
listen to and kind of understand what
we've gone through with this plant and
our culture and and some of the laws and
the way you know some people have given
up so much or gained so much by
cultivating or transporting or being
related to this plant somehow
spiritually connected yeah I mean we
have stories on there from my guys that
were kicking it in the 70s and 80s and
some pretty amazing stories a lot of the
history of you know the psychedelic
movement even you know and and where all
that came from
on earth it's pretty wild awesome well
let's not give it all away
so all right they're gonna have to check
out the podcast so let's get into this
podcast though I'm excited to have you
back John and thanks for having me I was
trying to think of topics cuz you and I
have conversations all the time and they
just ramble on and they all seem pretty
interesting to me but I was trying to
think what what could we focus on today
and one question I wanted to ask you was
do you think bottled nutrients are still
relevant today are they something you
know within the cannabis industry that
are maybe a sort of a dinosaur and in
some respects or do you think that
they're improving and really are the
future of cannabis cultivation so you
the I'm gonna throw a curveball and I'm
gonna say mmm maybe maybe not and I'm
gonna say that because number one I'm
not a chemist
number two I'm learning more about the
formulations and what I'm so if we're
talking about
we'll talk about the synthetic type
fertilizers right because it's - it's
almost two different worlds for organic
inputs you know what would you can local
side note is the fish hydrolysis
considered a bottled nutrient I don't
know that's a good question I write it's
not it's not a big not buying a brand
though you're buying a product so I
would say no that would be like saying
you know ammonium nitrate is a bottle of
nutrient well I think we're talking
about a delivery system right is it and
if we're talking about a delivery system
we're saying a bottled nutrient is the
fertilizer mix with water and so we're
we've credits you know a lot of people
well we've talked about it you know
buying water shipping water doesn't make
a lot of sense you know economically or
operationally but what I've learned is
that it's with synthetic nutrients if
you are gonna be super anal and exact
about your percentages sometimes you
have to have it pre-mixed by an actual
chemist to get it a hundred percent
accurate is that needed for production
not really
I don't think so some people some people
think so some people want it to be
perfect and what I've learned when
you're scooping out your water-soluble
blends bag of fertilizer is that every
single one of those minerals has its own
specific weight and how that bag of
fertilizer is mixed up and then when
you're scooping it into your reservoir
you may or may not be getting the actual
correct combination of minerals that you
think you are based on how you're
scooping and how you're measuring so
that's where the little caveat to all of
it is so if it's being blended for you
beforehand you know exactly how much
calcium how much magnesium how much iron
and that's all done by weight by the
chemist into the bottle nutrient now I
do not think that most bottled
fertilizer companies cannabis fertilizer
companies are I mean I might get in
trouble for saying this but
don't think that they're really going to
that level of detail when they're making
their fertilizers just because I've run
tests on it and I've you know I'm not
gonna name any names and we talked about
this before but I've seen wide variety
wide ranges of differences in the
minimum and maximum of the fertilizer
levels so are those products those
perfected bottled nutrient products out
there I don't know I haven't really seen
it I know that there's some companies
that are working on getting better at
that but for right now I would still
lean more towards the water soluble
fertilizers although there are some
associates of mine who are having their
fertilizers mixed by some specialists
and are working on creating you know the
perfect cannabis fertilizer whatever
that is so is our bottled nutrients dead
I think in this current iteration yes I
think there's room for something else to
come out of it but I don't know if it's
going to make sense at scale does that
answer your question yeah it was a bit
of a loaded question I'll be honest I
mean I've been a pretty loud critic of
bottled nutrients in general for quite a
while now trying to get growers to just
read the label and then look at the
ingredients and sort of formulate their
own now that being said when we talk
about synthetic nutrients and some of
the aspects yes we do need to
continually feed the plant nutrients we
can't expect all of our nutrients to be
in the media and you know even as
someone who sells living soils and water
only soils I do think there is benefit
to continual feeding I think that the
plant will actually thrive and do a
little bit better if you are able to
give it a little bit of nutrients
throughout the cycle but that being said
I think we give bottled nutrient
companies way too much credit in terms
of you know quota QC and quality control
and the innovation that went into the
products that they're creating I think a
lot more money
time probably went into their branding
than it did in to the actual formulation
of the product in a lot of cases I agree
well can I want to say one thing about
just a little side note so I've got I've
I finally had the opportunity now that I
moved out of LA to grow some plants
outside and I for my indoor plants I
still use the synthetic blend and and I
add my organics in but outside I do not
use any bottled nutrients at all anymore
I just I've used some of your soil which
has been fantastic and I'll make a
mended soil and I just feed of water and
I have gotten to the point where it's so
much easier just to do it that way and
the product that comes out and the
health of the planet is better than
ninety percent of anything that I grow
indoors and there's so very little that
I have to do I just have to you know
have a nice soil blend that has the
right proper fertility and you know I
talked to coot the other day and dude
turned me on to a couple little things I
can add into the soil and it's just been
amazing to see what you can do without
having to go to a synthetic fertilizer
and I would more you know say that I'm
I'm moving into this place where the all
natural Sun grown there's just a joy to
it where you know I don't have to be
screwing around pH meters EC meters and
all of that and it's it's just easier
and I have less problems why is that
different under the Sun in the light
indoor light artificial light I think it
has to do with power of the way this
this planet was was built just a little
side note on that because I don't think
we've talked about the fact that I've
been moving away
you know I am almost looking at indoor
cultivation now I mean there's a lot of
indoor cultivation but a moment was
looking at an indoor cultivation is more
of an RD space and less of a space for
commercial production just because how
much easier it is to be growing outside
well that makes sense where you're
located down in California but up here
Washington especially in Western
Washington near Seattle we just don't
have the weather it's really you're
rolling the dice as to whether or not
your plants will actually finish
depending on how the weather is come
October so maybe you know maybe moving
towards you know Auto flowers is a
solution to some of that but yeah I hear
what you're saying I mean outdoor is
great it does bring up other challenges
like the weather and you don't have the
same levels of control but you do get
all the benefit of unlimited root space
and beneficial and predatory insects
just naturalizing in your environment
there's in sunlight like there's a ton
of benefits to it for sure I'm still I'm
still putting the plants in pots I mean
forgive me
so I'm still making my own soil you know
working on the you know I've got some
hemp plants in the ground and that's
been going well but I still like I still
am leaning towards growing cannabis and
pots so I can control the amount of
amendments that are actually in the
substrate oh man see I'm I'm the total
opposite I will put a plant in the
ground 99% of the time the only times I
don't recommend going into the ground
are if you have really bad moles and
foals or things that are gonna eat the
roots and kill your plant that way or if
you're in a floodplain where your water
table is so high that it's an issue but
from coming from a nursery background
growing up on a plant nursery with my
parents you take two plants and you put
one plant in a container and you put one
plant in the ground even if the ground
soil is somewhat subpar that that plant
in the ground is gonna outperform the
plant in the container 99% of the time
it's amazing for some of the reasons I
just listed you know I would love to see
you do an experiment take two plants you
know you don't even have to do a soil
test of your soil I mean I don't know a
lot about your soil but my guess is if
you put one in the ground and put that
same you know it's another clone in good
soil shoot put it in our soil and run
them side by side and see how it
compares yeah I mean
that makes all the sense in the world
and not just what that just has to do
with the amount that the roots can grow
right there's no limit limiting factor
yeah root space isn't like you said
isn't a limiting factor
inaudible environment yeah the the soil
typically has you know pretty good
microbial life you're gonna have it's
gonna have more soil structure and
there's just there's a lot we don't know
honestly going on there too but in
general you know like I have mulberry
trees at my farm and I have some in
containers that have you know been root
BAM now that are probably 2 feet tall
and I have the same mulberry tree in the
chicken yard that is now 15 feet tall
and part of that is because we have it
up potted our mulberries appropriately
to get them to the size they want but a
lot of it too is once we put that plant
in the ground and just it just took off
and waterings another thing there too
because when you're in the ground you
don't you don't need to water as much
you sort of have a natural mulch the
plants able to pull up water out of the
soil a lot more efficiently than they
can out of container so a lot of
benefits even an even a clone because
the clone is lacking a taproot well yeah
all everything I'm saying is under the
caveat that once once the plant is
established understood yeah that's
that's a good point
now since we're talking about sort of
random things I kind of wanted to change
directions one of the things that you
posted on your Instagram a while back
related to flushing and yeah and organic
plants do you want to kind of summarize
how that discussion went and sort of
what what your thoughts on it because I
think we have a similar view I mean it's
yeah I just you know all everyone's been
flushing cannabis that I know for the
last seven to 14 days of the life of the
plant so prior to harvest practices to
deprive the plan of nutrients and just
give it water
and the thought behind that was that it
created a better quality product because
you were flushing out the nutrients out
of the plant and I here you know I'll go
online and I see a lot of people talking
about that and it just didn't make it
didn't make sense like I didn't
understand how you could how pouring
water into the plant would remove the
nutrients it with that mode of action so
the way that it was being described and
talked about seemed to be incorrect to
me and so I put a couple posts up
actually was a repost for another guy
that had a very excellent description of
what actually was going on and I
suggested that we stop calling it
flushing the plan started calling it
starving the plant and that's you know
removing the fertilizer you know then
you've got various things that happen
and the plant starts using its stores of
energy and you know you start getting
nutrient deficiencies essentially is
what it is what it really looks like and
in that deficiency there's I think
there's a stress response that happens
that may increase the cannabinoid
content and terpene content as a defense
mechanism or as the death throes of the
plant as it's realizing it's not getting
anymore food it's you know kind of ended
at the end of its reproductive cycle and
that's what's actually creating the
increase in quality a lot of people talk
about it having a taste you know that if
you don't flush that you're gonna get a
poor poor tasting product on the smoke
and I don't know if that's the direct
result of it either people discuss about
chlorophyll like you're flushing out the
chlorophyll that doesn't make sense to
me and it just seemed like there was a
scientific brat an unscientific practice
being put into place and being claimed
as a scientific practice do I understand
everything that's going on when we flush
the plant at this moment no I'm still
learning and figuring all that out as I
you know go talk to other you know PhDs
and people that know a lot more about
culture than I do and I talked to them
about this flushing the plant thing they
just kind of chuckled and laugh and say
what are you talking about they've never
even heard of that before
and I don't have to explain to them
what's going on and and then they have
to decipher what I what the common
understanding of it is to what's
actually happening and there hasn't been
a ton of research done on flushing the
plant just because there aren't a lot of
other industries that do that there
aren't a lot of agricultural crops where
they're actually flushing the plant now
one thing I will say on that is cannabis
is an amazing bio accumulator of
chemicals and minerals so perhaps giving
it that water allows the can of cannabis
plant to release something that they
viable accumulated that could affect the
quality that would be the only thing
that I could think of that would that
would support this quote unquote
flushing terminology so here's my take
on it now one thing especially in you
know when you're growing in mineral
salts is you can have a buildup of salt
content in your media and you can also
have excess nitrates in your media and I
think that by removing those by flushing
the plant or you know removing them out
of the media by adding excessive water
you can improve the quality of your
final product so I think there's a few
things going on now in organic soil you
don't have a bunch of ionic nutrients
just hanging out in the media and you
typically don't have a buildup of salt
content so it doesn't really make sense
to flush your plant for the same reasons
there's no there's no excess nitrates to
remove but that being said does as you
said you know starving or stressing your
plant create a stress response that
somehow we're going to improve the
quality of the final bud well maybe but
I you know I've seen a lot of great
organic growers that don't flush their
plants that have produced really really
good high-quality you know what I would
consider top-shelf cannabis and
top-shelf flowers so I to me of what
flushing is a bit of a myth now if we
want to
are looking at creating stress responses
in cannabis plants at various stages of
growth and how that may affect you know
cannabinoid levels or turkey and content
in the plant itself I think that is
something that we can study using
science and research but I don't think
that flushing is really the right like
you said the right terminology or really
what's what we what we want to do with a
plant I would challenge people to go
ahead and if you are growing an organic
soil go ahead and try flushing one plant
and see compare the final the final
flower and I don't think you'll see an
improvement personally but that's that's
my take how do you flush your own
organic and organic I mean you're not
really when you're feeding are you
talking about feeding the plant organic
inputs through a solution or any
organics because when I have an organic
soil I'm very rarely feeding it you know
any kind of fertilizers a solution all
of its kind of art either mixed into the
soil or top trust so how do you how
would you flush or that's what I don't
understand how would you flush an
organic plant and I can get that if you
have like a pretty fairly inert low ecc
substrate and then you're trying to
flush out or purge those nitrates I
still don't understand how that affects
the taste I don't understand how that
works when people make those claims but
how would you flush an organic plant
well so here's the argument as I
understand it so if you want to take a
media soilless media that is potentially
high in nitrates and you remove those
nitrates by adding a lot of water that
plant is going to have less nitrogen to
take up therefore it's going to have
less chlorophyll production and
therefore it's gonna have less green
less green in its leaves and potentially
maybe have less chlorophyll overall when
you smoke it I guess that would be my
take on that from an organic soil
perspective you're right you're there's
amendments being added or ingredients in
terms of nitrogen that's not in a plant
available form and so that has to be
processed by the microbiology and the
soil into
nitrate or into ammonium but essentially
that may be what some of that may be
washed out through a flushing process
but it's it's not at excessive levels in
general now from a farming perspective
and agriculturally you always add
nitrogen in the spring because of the
heavy rains that you get will flush it
out of your system so they don't even
test for nitrogen and a lot of times on
the soil tests because they just assume
that your soil is going to be deficient
now that's when we start when we're
talking about agricultural land now we
talked about soilless media indoors when
we're not getting that excessive water
addition we could have a lot of we could
potentially have too much nitrogen or
too many nitrogen amendments so there is
a balance there I guess but it's not
something that I think you're correcting
with the last week or 14 days of your
plant's life it's something that you
need to be managing throughout the
entire grow cycle as you sort of balance
and manage your soil yeah I'll I'll use
flushing if my if let's say I have too
much of a dry down period on my medium
the EC is gonna climb and that mine
might not be suitable for bird whatever
stage of growth the plants in so
there'll be times if I made a boo-boo or
I made a mistake and I've got to correct
that and I use flushing to you know
clean out the medium and kind of reset
the medium for proper plant growth but
I'll still flush with a small amount of
fertilizer because I'm not trying to
starve the plant in the middle of its
cycle just to kind of get it back into
balance so well I will use that practice
but at the end I you know at the end of
the cycle I've mean I've done I've done
it where I flushed it 14 I've flushed I
flushed a lot you know thinking that
this is what you're supposed to do and
that this is gonna create quality flower
and about two years ago I started to
slowly bring down the amount of days
that I would give it water because and I
might you know what I'm gonna cut this
down when it's ready and I'm not gonna
starve it until I think it's ready
and I'm at a point now where I'll give
it water for two or three days and cut
it down and and I don't notice and no
one else who uses the
flower notices that it tastes funny or
has too much of you know some residual
something or other in it and I think
that the taste issue has more do
properly drying the product and allowing
it to cure is what I you know in in the
ash burning you know a lot of people say
well the ash is burning black that means
it wasn't flushed well I don't that
doesn't make any sense to me if the ash
is burning black it's either too too wet
or there's some other chemical that was
sprayed on it that's my thought on it
what do you think I am NOT a cannabis
consumption expert so I'm gonna not
weigh in on that one okay got it
have you heard have you heard that
conversation before I have I have but I
don't have enough experience honestly
like I know coot for example will tell
you that anything that was grown with
chemicals to him tastes like a burned up
rubber tire and he can just tell right
away if it was grown using mineral salts
I don't claim to have any level of
sophistication around well frankly
anything wine or cannabis as much as I
wish I had a better palate I just I
really don't so I'm gonna stay out of
that one but one thing I did want to
bring up relating to flushing before we
move on to the next topic is some of the
concerns around it too so when we stress
our plant we may get a good stress
response but we're also opening it up to
more pest pressure we're increasing the
humidity in our rooms potentially which
can lead to more chanting you know more
opportunity for certain fungal pathogens
like botrytis or powdery mildew so these
are some of the dangers I guess or
concerns around excessive watering or
any sort of any sort of practice that's
gonna create a stress response yeah I
wouldn't I wouldn't say that you would
be watering more often if you were
flushing
you don't want to you know drown the
roots right so III don't think that your
your latent load which is the amount of
water that's in the air or the
transpiration the water that's being
transpired by the plant should go
whether you're flushing or giving it
just a regular solution for the last two
weeks I would say that the any stress
response at the end of a cycle if you
have an unstable genetic it could cause
the plant to hermaphrodite which is what
I see often is is flushing the plant
caused the plant to hermaphrodite I
don't know Minoo that I we have a lot of
unstable genetics on the market right
now and you know one one faux-pas can
create banana pollen sacks you know so I
I would yeah would suggest everyone do a
trial like you said but with whatever
methodology they're using try flushing
in in on one or two plants and try not
watching on one or two plants and really
give it a fair you know blind taste test
or an analysis so one thing that you
mentioned a little bit ago we're talking
about outdoor plants was not using your
EC or pH meter anymore on your outdoor
plants and there's a reach recent
discussion online about whether or not
you need to ever pH your water if you're
growing organically or with organic soil
and I have a pretty strong opinion on
this but I was gonna let you go first
if there's any you have any thoughts on
the subject or I'm happy to chime in and
start the discussion yeah I think the
first thing you need to do is check your
before your feeding your plants any of
your water you need to check you know
get a water test done and make sure that
it's suitable for plant health you know
I lived in LA for a while and sometimes
the pH was all over the map and not
within that suitable for growth range
which you know from how I understand it
is somewhere between you know five five
and seven five so if it's around there I
don't know if it's that important
because the soil will do a lot of the pH
buffering for you so you know indoors
it's a little bit more it's a little
trickier when you're especially when
you're dealing with
Media and that's where you do have to
pay attention to it but for a and I
don't know how you feel about it so we
haven't talked about this but I've been
having great results after checking my
water it's around six eight to seven - I
know where it comes out and I haven't
really made any pH adjustments and I
don't notice any nutrient deficiencies
in the plant but I haven't gotten this
leaf tissue test done on my own my
outdoor plants so I'm just basing it off
of what I can see well you have pretty
perfect water I mean that to me
six-eight is is pretty pretty good yeah
yeah and what I was hearing is people
have water as high as 8 or 81 and to me
you know people are saying no don't
worry about pH in your water you don't
need to do it no matter what the soil
contains sufficient if it has good
microorganism levels and diversity it
will buffer the pH for the plant in the
rhizosphere which is correct
like you said soil does have much higher
buffering capacity but I don't think it
if we want to talk about optimal plant
health and plant growth we want water to
we want to be watering with things that
are within optimal pH ranges - I don't
think we get it throw the pH pen
completely out the window we need to
still know what we're starting with and
that's something that well we were
getting into an argument with with these
guys because they didn't we didn't agree
so since this is my podcast I get to
share my opinion which is we do need to
know what the pH of our water so you
always need to start off knowing you
know what's in your media what's in your
water because you can't develop a
fertilizer schedule or in a fertigation
program until you know those two things
because you just don't know what you're
starting with and I think that's so
important it's something that Travis
Higginbotham mentioned in the last in
his podcast that I just released and
it's something that I think everyone
needs to think about so I own I own a
percent agree with you on that I mean
you need to know what your starting
inputs are otherwise if you have an
issue or you have a problem with the
plant health and you you didn't collect
all the information for everything that
you're putting into the plant
you're not going to know how to address
the problem and again you know like you
said there's
arranged for growth that that's pH
that's humidity that's temperature right
photo period you know I think that's a
did I miss any I mean that's pretty much
right around work we need to pay
attention to this kind and you know
fertility so or soil fertility so if you
don't know what you've got going on
there then you're flying blind so yeah a
hundred percent of grief but well if the
if the water coming out of the tap is in
the suitable range and you're doing you
know some kind of you know infrequent or
frequent weekly testing or daily testing
to make sure it's if you're like on a
well it shouldn't slide too much but I
will say one thing if you're on a well
and I've seen this a lot if you are on a
knew if let's say you let's use a
hypothetical situation that I've seen if
you buy a property and you're gonna got
your cannabis cultivation license and
you're gonna start growing and you get a
water test on the well and it looks
great but you haven't really hit that
well yet you haven't really started
pumping water out of that well make sure
you're doing frequent tests on that well
because what I see from a lot of well
from a lot of wells all around the
country is that after that well starts
to get you start pulling water out of
that well start using it
it'll you'll start seeing iron filling
up in the filters and I'm seeing across
the way and people just keep going ahead
they have got their D chlorinator
sediment filter which is doing nothing
and they get these high super high
levels of ferrous iron and then they go
back to their water test and they did
before they actually started using the
well and they're like well my water
looks fine
well you need to be doing frequent water
tests from your well water or municipal
water to understand what's going on you
can't just do one water test and expect
that you're gonna be golden and I see
that tad I see that all the time and
then they have plant problems and then I
go check the filters and the filters are
orange with like ferrous iron and clay
covered all of them and I'm like guys
but what's going on here where's the
water test when was the last time you
had a water test and like oh we had a
water test a year ago here it is I'm
like well that's not what your actual
water is anymore
and there's a great guy I'm gonna give
him a plug and hopefully he doesn't kill
me for this but Dan David Berlin over at
hyper logic is one of the best you know
water purification water masters who I
will I send pictures of these filters
all all the time to Eman you know we've
kind of kind of like oh here we go again
you know tell them to get a current
water test so I just wanted to put that
out there that's very important to be
constantly testing your water as you're
using that water source
yeah farmers from an agricultural
perspective will know that their water
is going to change throughout the season
and so they they make adjustments
accordingly and you know for some of the
reasons you mentioned and just some of
the seasonal changes with excessive
rains you know bringing down things out
of the mountains and stuff like that and
erosion so good point good point so
let's get into we haven't even talked
about some of the stuff that I really
want to talk about which was this new
trial that you're setting up yeah let's
talk a little bit about that some of the
some of your findings the reasons why
you did it
let's talk about some of the aspects of
your trial in terms of controlling for a
variable that may not be perfect yeah
yeah so I started working with LED
lighting what was it you know three or
four years ago now and I worked with a
lot of the initial kind of subpar LED
fixtures that were out there and then
fluence came around and you know had
some good results with it but also had
some challenges like everybody else did
in making the transition and now we're
kind you know none of you know fluence
really was the trendsetter and turning
the you know making the paradigm shift
to some extent on you know really
looking at LED lighting as a excellent
choice or solution for indoor controlled
environment lighting now you've got a
lot of other companies that have jumped
on the bandwagon you have a whole market
I mean you go to some of these trade
shows and it's like a city of LED
lighting and I've you know I've been
primarily working with the fluence
lighting
and seeing some started seeing some
interesting results and different kinds
of results from other lighting companies
that were developing different ways of
delivering the photons whether that may
be spectrum or footprint or you know
additional features so I reached out
about six months ago to other lighting
companies that had I had seen some
interesting results from or I had heard
from other consultants or other growers
that they were having that they were
having you know good results from and
are happy with the fixtures and I wanted
to you know kind of do a an imperfect
trial and see if any of these other
lighting companies be willing to kind of
go up against what my standard has been
which has been in Spider x+ primarily
and also for me to see whether we know
where we're we're out on the market of
LED lighting and where they're certain
company is doing better things and other
companies and hopefully putting this out
publicly will improve everyone's product
that they're putting out and provide
data to the consumer and also perhaps
look at I mean so the way that I have
the the trial set up it's a fairly small
little lab space and so I've got kind of
a canopy of lighting above with LED
lighting get fairly close to the canopy
so even though there's going to be some
bleed over into the other light areas
we'll still get a good idea because I'll
be able to put fixtures fairly close six
to twelve inches away from the light
canopy some of that bleed over though
for me is interesting because the
fixtures have different color
temperatures or different spectrums and
there might be something interesting to
happen and that bleed over so I'll be
reading the color temperature of the
canopy in these certain areas and
collecting data on you know the
differences around the canopy that's
underneath these lights one of you know
there's a so right now I've got the
Spyder X plus Spectre and the BIOS
lighting the gi2
and then to Vipers cuz I always have
people asking me what's better the viper
or the spider I tell them it has nothing
to do with the the using the spider or
the Viper has more to do with your
layout and your design than anything
else I like the Viper X plus a lot
because it's it's a single bar that's
fat and covers like mmm like a 4 by 3
foot footprint fairly well and there's a
lot that you can do around that light
whereas a spider kind of takes up all of
the space above the light and I see a
lot of these companies modeling their
fixtures off of that architecture
lighting architecture and I don't know
if that's the best lighting architecture
for indoor cultivation because a lot of
times people are just designing these
lights thinking about the light canopy
but they're not thinking about
everything else that's involved in an
indoor growth space which is environment
least surface temperature the way that
the air is moving how the lights can
work with the environmental equipment a
lot of people are just kind of thinking
like we need to get this amount of PP FP
over this amount of square footage and
to some extent that can be great but
I've we're seeing a lot more of these
vertical moving systems or these
vertical rack systems that move and they
open up and you have one aisle
so it's modeling out of a roll-top bench
but just going up vertically so when you
start cramming all these lights and
plants together into this home position
where you've got rows and rows of these
plants and there's not a lot of air
movement people have been having a lot
of challenges with that so looking at
how now the lights being these lights
like the spider X plus is being
repurposed for these vertical moving
systems I'm also thinking about how the
architecture of the light can fit that
model to allow for more space or for the
environment and environmental control
which has been a serious challenge for a
lot of the people that are using these
LED vertical moving rack systems now the
other thing that I've been looking at is
that I have noticed that certain
varietals under the fluence lighting
will that spectrum
or whatever reason they'll just get what
I call tired after a specific amount of
light or duration of light even at the
lower ppfd so let's say between 200 and
300 ppfd in veg after 16 hours of light
the plants you know a lot and I've seen
this in multiple grows and I you know it
could be something else but it's can you
know I haven't collected enough data on
everything but I have seen consistency
with that with other individuals online
where the plans just certain plants
certain variety and they start to droop
like they've had enough and it's time to
turn off and it's time to go to sleep I
never saw that really under
high-pressure sodium lighting or ceramic
metal high light lighting I have seen
that from the get-go with the fluence
lighting I'm had to make adjustments and
then certain things became more
important like vapor pressure deficit
and V PDV pressure differential and then
adjusting the intensity of the lighting
and really having to work very hard on
keeping the plants healthy so the
photosynthesis continues transpiration
continues now I I think that that has
something to do with the spectrum of the
light and the color temperature and I
think there might be a little bit too
much of something and not enough
something else
so part of what I've what I've done is
I've looked at other lighting companies
that have different spectrums and tried
to compare to see if it's something with
with the lighting now I will say that
you know right now I'm using the bios
the bios light in the trial so it's it's
really the spectre light is pretty close
to the fluence light as far as spectrum
and design it's a little egregious to
some extent how close it is the BIOS
lighting is kind of its own beast it's
been it was developed by you know a NASA
scientist which is kind of cool because
I'm all about space travel and s and all
these kinds of things
sidenote and i have been vegging i have
plants vegging under the bios lighting
and plants the same gelato strain
vegging under the fluence lighting and I
have noticed off the bat right now that
the color temple ants are enjoying the
color temperature a little bit better in
the vegetative state
the BIOS lighting at the same ppfd
without getting that tiredness now I
don't know if that makes the BIOS
lighting spectrum better for vegetative
oh and whether that's gonna carry over
and I'm gonna see a benefit in Flour
because I've had fantastic results with
the Spyder X plus and flower but it does
it does make it a little bit easier for
me when I'm when I'm not having to deal
with the plants getting stressed out
from having too much maybe it's too much
red I don't know so you know those are
my early findings right now and you know
I'm gonna be making some more videos on
that and posting that up on Instagram
and on YouTube and I will say one thing
that BIOS light is really heavy it is I
think it's like 40 or 50 pounds and that
is not that is not a one-man job hanging
that light whereas the spider I can hang
that light one-man job on that the BIOS
light you're definitely need the GI to
at least you're gonna need two people to
hang that light just a warning
I was surprised on our IV it is and the
so I like the spectrum on the BIOS light
but it's heavy and it doesn't have the
same radiant cooling design that the
fluence light has so the top of the
fixture gets very hot like 140 150
degrees so just keep all that in mind so
there's positives and negatives to both
fixtures so far from what I found
okay so a couple of thoughts here you
talked about that one could you say that
maybe the fluence light has a
potentially better spectrum in the sense
that you could shorten your your photo
period because the the plants reaching
it's it's DLI or the amount of light
that the plant can take up in a given
photo period sooner so maybe you could
take an hour off of your vegetative
period and still get the same growth
rates I yeah I like to veg under fluence
lighting for 16 hours of light in 18
hours
of darkness so yeah that is a benefit I
don't know if it I don't know if it's
comparable if it that creates more
growth or not but you're not running the
lights for two additional hours I have
I've told that to a lot of people and
that a vast that have asked me about
I've seen this tiredness thing as well
and I said well switch to 18 you know 16
hours of light and 88 hours of darkness
and a lot of people are hesitant to do
that because it's been kind of the
standard to veg for either 18 6 or 24
hours but I'd say if you're using the
fluence light tribe edging for 16 hours
that was actually their initial
recommendation when they first put out
the light and it a lot of people weren't
willing to do that because they were
afraid that the plants were gonna flower
yeah you're getting closer to that full
photo periodic response I'm really
excited to hear what Travis Higginbotham
comes up with over the next year as he
gets sort of more entrenched and
experienced in his position he was our
last podcast interview and I really like
what his knowledge and what he had to
say so off to follow up with him again
on that one
so that was one thought that my other
thought is if a light is getting really
hot doesn't that mean that in a sense
it's less efficient at converting energy
into photons and I'm not I'm not
criticizing this light it's just
something just I'm just talking out loud
about I don't know a lot about lighting
so yeah yeah so wattage no so no matter
wat ajiz going to create a specific
amount of BTUs alright so if you have
600 watts you're gonna have 600 watts of
heat alright in that heat
I think it's the you know for every watt
you multiply that times 3.41 BTU or 3.14
BTU forgive me if I get the before and
the one mixed up and then that's what
that's how you figure out how much heat
which is which the engineers call
sensible load is going into the room for
the fixture so it doesn't you know that
has to do with any electronic device
right any electronic device any any
device that's powered is you know that
amount of wattage is going to it it's
going to create that amount of heat and
now when we this is something like
people get confused about so just
because you're running
an LED doesn't mean that you know so
let's say you have 600 watts of LED
lighting and then you have 600 watts of
high-pressure sodium lighting they're
gonna produce the same amount of heat
all right the difference is that from
the 600 watt high-pressure sodium light
you're only getting let's say 400 or 500
ppfd so 400 or 500 you know the amount
of photons that are being produced
that's usable for the plant it's like
400 or 500 whereas with the LED that's
the same amount of wattage you're
getting a thousand or 1100 so it's
producing the same amount of heat but
more usable light does that make sense
yeah so in theory you could use less
lights which would in which would also
lower the amount of heat being created
in a given room and get and get the same
amount of ppfd for as of the 600 watt of
high-pressure sodium
correct now why is there so much heat
coming off of the BIOS light that has to
do with the architecture and has to do
with the way that they heat that the
light is the light is designed to handle
the diffusion of that heat all right now
BIOS it seems like BIOS has opted to go
with more of a waterproof kind of very
heavy duty design which I can understand
why they would do that whereas you know
they have you know four big chunky bars
you know and it's in a series and then
you look at the fluence light and
they've got eight bars and the fluence
light has these fins that you would see
there you know the radiant cooling fin
so it spreads the surface area to allow
for better heat diffusion of the
fixtures so there's more surface area
there it's the same thing you'd see
unlike I'm on one of your ballast or any
kind of power source or there's a lot of
wattage going into something or a lot of
energy going in something they they
create those fins you see it in computer
equipment as well and that allows for
greater air movement over the surface of
the equipment to allow for better air to
you know heat dispersion in diffusion so
when you're when you're measuring you
you know you get your little laser
thermometer and measure the fluence
light it does a very good job dispersing
that heat into the environment so as
long you know what I think about is
being able to control the room
environment and if I have just ambient
heating it's being dispersed I mean that
eat is now being spread around the
volume of the room so it's easier to
manage it's easier for the equipment to
you know cool that room whereas if you
have hot spots which is what we're
trying to stay away from in cultivation
where we have these pockets of heat
pockets of humidity pockets of coldness
we don't want that we want it to be
consistent so that's the only thing that
you know like oh you know that and
that's that's one of the positives of
having an LED fixture is you get that
you can you can you're looking when you
look at your ambient temperature you're
really kind of seeing you know what's
close to what your canopy temperature is
and then when you have a high pressure
sodium like it's going to be very very
hot under the bulb because that's where
a lot of that heat is coming from
and we'll say the BIOS light the heat is
being thrown up to the top of the
fixture and when you're below the LED
diodes it's not anywhere near as hot but
you still have that hot spot above the
light so if you've got really tall
ceilings not a big deal but in this lab
I don't have tall ceilings and I'd say
that you know the fixture was heating up
the ceiling which was about a foot and a
half away
you know I'll you know was 20 degrees
higher than I was getting under the
fluence light so fluence has done a
really good job in figuring out how to
disperse that heat and you know that's
it's kind of my little analysis and all
that well I'm excited to hear your
results that's really cool what you're
doing thanks man me too
I'm super grateful for all the lighting
companies that have been open to doing
this because I know that you know
everyone everyone wants you they don't
want anything I'm not I'm not trying to
do any damage to any of these companies
at all it's really just trying to be a
give a fair test so we can look at
what's positive and then all those
companies can kind of come back and use
that data to improve what they're doing
because they're all doing something
that's fantastic and unique and exciting
and it's it's all this is just going to
lead to more efficient cultivation
methodology
and I'm all for that so the last thing I
wanted to talk to you about was sort of
your experiences with the different you
know facilities and grow operations that
you've been doing consulting on what are
you seeing out there in California right
now I am seeing a lot of fat if that
makes sense
so seeing a lot of waste I'm seeing a
lot of a lot of cultivators and farms
struggling to make the transition over
into a commercial business framework and
not having a lot of time to do that
because things are moving lightning fast
and it's chaotic and it's very very
difficult and what worked for the last
10 to 15 years doesn't really work
anymore because the margins have gone
down and I remember a few years ago
listening to Bob Hoffman who's one of
the largest basil growers in the United
States talked to a bunch of cannabis
growers and he said hey guys guess what
your margins they're great now they're
not gonna last forever enjoy it while
you can because it's gonna go away
sooner than you think and that's what
I'm seeing happen right now but people
are still cultivating and growing
cannabis there the cost to produce a
pound is still above $500 on average and
we have an oversupply in California much
like what's going on in Washington
Oregon
even though Washington and Oregon have a
much further developed recreational
market than California does but people
forgot that California has been
producing a lot of weed for a really
long time and now all those people are
having to pay taxes and you know there's
a lot of taxes probably too many taxes
and they
haven't really figured out how to reduce
their cost of production I would say
that some people have started to you and
it's beginning to happen but they have
to do it faster and they have to take I
you know take a cue from large-scale
agriculture to some extent if they're
trying to do these massive farms and
really try and reduce costs so I see a
lot of waste I see a lot of money being
spent on things that aren't maybe needed
and improper planning to understand what
you guys are gonna need on the OP X
moving into these grows they're kind of
going about it the way that they've been
going about it for the last ten years
and a lot of people are failing a lot of
people are hurting because of it so what
what do you see is a viable solution
like if you were starting a grow or
helping someone that was starting a
grill how do you go about analyzing
efficiency and and finding ways to
improve that well what I recommend
everybody begin with is a quote unquote
plant program so what I'll see happen a
lot of times is people will start out
with a rough idea of what they want to
do in their space and then they will lay
on top of that space a thought that they
can do more than is actually possible so
every space that you're working in you
know whether it's outdoors whether it's
a greenhouse or whether it's an indoor
cultivation space it's gonna have a
limitation on how much can be produced
cramming more into that space is
actually going to reduce the output than
if you met then it than if you were to
meet the space with where it's maybe
operationally tuned so one of the first
things I like to do is sit down and look
at the space and create a layout and a
floor plan for where every plant is
going to go and then base expectations
on what's going to be produced on what
the space can actually handle so once
we've established that floor plan now
this is assuming that you have
your areas or rooms already kind of
mapped out then after that then we look
at what the current equipment is in the
facility or the Specht we talk about
what we're gonna spec for the equipment
but a lot of times I'm coming in and
doing audits on facilities that were
already built and they were poorly
planned from the get-go
for whatever reason so what we we have a
lot of times reduce people's
expectations and what they can pull out
of the space by looking at what the
space can actually handle so we'll go
from plant count to what our equipment
sizing is and then we'll figure out you
know the optimum amount of plants that
can be in each room based on keeping in
a controlled environment based on what
the equipment can handle and then we'll
come up with a flow for where the plants
begin you know in the facility whether
they're starting as a clone or a seed
and where they're going to end and we
map out every part of that process and
then essentially run a digital form of
the operation to give that client or
give the farmer an idea of the path of
his grow room and every every expandable
every supply that's needed to get that
plan from point A to point Z a lot of
times people are just kind of winging it
and what happens when you wing it is you
waste a lot of time a lot of money and a
lot of labor so the first thing to do is
come up with a plan an operational plan
in a plant program and have you know
manage your expectations of what you're
gonna actually produce out of the space
you know whether your nursery or whether
you're producing for flour there's gonna
be a limit you can't you know if you
have enough space for 10,000 clones or
5,000 clones to be produced per month
that's all you're gonna get you're not
going to get any more than that unless
you expand your space in an intelligent
way so that's a lot of a lot of what
I've been doing now is looking at that
analyzing why there are fail points
and offering people solutions and a lot
of that has to do with reducing what
they're trying to do within the
limitations about getting real within
with the limitations of your farm so
what you're describing is very similar
to what Ben Hartman was talking about
around lean farming or lean
manufacturing in terms of setting up and
really understanding workflows
is that correct yes yeah his book is
awesome and I bugged you for a while
there I was like you need to read this
book yeah so know that I was doing I was
I would say that I've worked with some
engineering companies on the
pre-production that's involved in
planning out these gardens but after
reading that book it really helped me
turn it into something tangible after
the plan was finished and also
understanding how to really think about
how you plan your garden you know a lot
of people are just starting with like an
empty rectangle and they're trying to
fill it in with as many plants and as
much canopy as possible also you know
just because you have a twenty thousand
square foot building doesn't mean you're
gonna get a ten thousand square-foot
canopy out of that there's a lot of
space needed for the actual operations
plant movement all these kinds of things
so a lot of for the first three years of
you know doing some of this facility
design I'd work with the owner of the
building and they'd be like we got a
twenty thousand square foot building
let's put a 20,000 square foot canopy in
the building and it's like where are you
gonna take a [__] you know it's like
people aren't even thinking about that
so yeah that book was a huge influence
on how all these things kind of work
together and the lean farm man that's it
so you know amen thank you for turning
me on to that book and thank you for
that podcast great podcast well I think
people just needed time to spend time
planning time spent planning is not time
wasted in fact it's probably the most
efficient thing you can do and I'm a
culprit of this even now I don't have as
much sop or standard operating procedure
established as I should because
realistically when you're running a
business or running an operation like
this you need everything to be
standardized as much as possible so the
employees know have expect know what
their expectations are and at the same
time have a resource that they can go to
to understand what they should be doing
and why they're doing it too and that's
something that you should have already
thought about hopefully in a perfect
world before starting your business but
that's not what happened in my case not
even close but we're working towards
that you know yeah a lot of I think
that's the kid I think that's the case
with most people also the other thing is
a lot of times people write an SOP and
they spend a lot of time and money doing
that and then they get their garden belt
and then no one follows it
so the spxl has to make sense and it has
to be applied to what's actually going
on I see that all the time I'll see like
a manual that manual just gets dust that
are all over it no one's actually going
and using it and you've got operators
that coming in and kind of doing their
own thing and setting their whole rules
and and that might be that's a kind of
interesting thought twos like the SOP
manual the best way to be creating best
practices I think that SOP manual is
there to kind of be the backbone the the
history of how the building's gonna be
operated but then what gets put into
practice in the business should be
simplified we've even talked about you
know having there be a you know I pad in
the room that has just the videos on the
iPad for every part of the process for
someone to reference because so many
people are learning things off of
YouTube and online streaming services
maybe our SOPs should be geared towards
how people are actually learning these
days less people are you know learning
and my I mean I could be wrong but I
think most people OTT of people are
learning through online services and
podcasts like this one and YouTube and
you need to learn something quick it's a
lot easier to have it shown to you then
have to go through and read the
directions and hope that you're reading
it correctly and then translating it and
to reality so maybe we need to be
looking
and how we structure our SPS depending
upon what we're writing as a before of
course but maybe there's a better way of
having these best practices displayed
for the staff so that's something that
I've been kind of playing around with
maybe perhaps turning poetry of plants
in into an instructional company where
there's videos online to show every part
of these processes for different steps
it's something that might be interesting
that's funny cuz for me I tend to move I
tend to not like videos as much I like
hearing things you know obviously with
having a podcast that's something I
enjoy but I love to read and I love to
read things and see them visually that
way but if it's something complicated
you know like putting together furniture
it would be a great example having a
visual guide like a video like you said
is it's pretty handy you know or maybe
it's like mixing up fertilizer that's
something that is pretty easy to screw
up off of a set of written instructions
so I I think that's a great idea
I do like that yeah and yeah every
everyone learns different too right so
some people are better at reading and or
listening or watching I mean so maybe
you have to have a combination of all
three you know to really have it make
sense and the staff can access it based
on how they prefer to learn you know
make it easy for them yeah that gets a
little controversial in terms of what
they've come up with in in education
around research and learning but we
don't need to get into that that was
sort of something that I did with my
master's degree but oh really
yeah I want to get into that can you
briefly touch well the basics would be
that you know this idea of sensory
learning that some people are auditory
learners or some people are visual
learners they found when they actually
did a lot of research on it it didn't
really play out quite as well as people
thought so there is something to have to
having different modalities of teaching
in terms of the way you explain or teach
a subject but no one no one is a single
modality in the way that they learn they
don't just learn
from an auditory perspective or from a
visual perspective or from a sensory
perspective so it's it's a little it
gets a little more complicated than that
I guess but it is interesting and I do
see you know younger generations being
much more focused or more interested in
watching videos and learning from videos
than prior generations like like myself
I guess well I you know my IVA I have a
nine-year-old son and we you know we do
a lot of Legos and if you look at the
Lego instruction manual it's like step
by step with the picture and with the
direction of how this is getting put
together even something I mean and
anybody can figure out how to put
together a Lego for the most part so
maybe there's a combination of those
things like we were talking about just
something where people actually can
access the best practices and the
standards and and they know what the
standards are because a lot of times
we're walking on the facility and it
people don't know and they just end up
you know they get shown it once or twice
and then they end up creating their own
method and dad you know maybe that could
be a better method or maybe not but
that's something for the operation
manager and the operational management
to decide not a new hire so I just see
these kinds of things where it's you
know back to what we were talking about
as far as lowering the operational costs
improving quality blowing the cost of
production and really taking a cue from
other companies that have been
successful and that's what I would
recommend if you're a cannabis
cultivator well you know a lot of people
are touring a lot of canvas farms it's
not the place to find the best
information on agricultural best
practices like go to a real farm go to
you know now I wouldn't say cannabis is
not real farm but go to an agricultural
farm or produce farm that's dialed in
that's successful see if you can get a
tour of their facility and see how
they're doing their processes because
those are the processes that are going
to be applied to cannabis in the future
matters
ooh yeah I see a lot of reluctance from
people saying that you know the
horticultural world or the agricultural
world doesn't understand cannabis and
has frankly been a little bit arrogant
towards cannabis because it has been a
black market crop in a plant to grow for
so long but at the end of the day
there's so much more research in science
that's that we have this existing body
of work to pull from if we look at
what's going on you know in commercial
greenhouses and what's going on on
commercial farms and how they're
establishing workflows and how they're
processing plants yes cannabis is a
special plant in a lot of ways but I
think in the way that we cultivate it in
most cases I mean there's some things
around photoperiod and such and in
nutrients but overall it's it's another
plant and I think people get too caught
up in sort of this spirituality around
the plant that they don't that they they
aren't willing to embrace some of the
knowledge that's already out there or go
in search of it when when they could
yeah I I think that's I think that's
because they're afraid that's what I
think I think it's scary because it's
not where it's moving into being and
becoming an actual business and less of
a lifestyle and that's a lot of people
don't want to let that go and I get it I
understand that but and and maybe that
might be true big AG doesn't know how to
grow cannabis yet I I would say they'll
figure it out at some point and maybe
they won't figure it out to the point
that you know how to take away the
experience and the artisanship that
these cannabis farmers have developed
because they absolutely have I mean I
haven't seen too many people coming from
big AG that can grow the same level of
flower that people that have been
cultivating and working with the plant
for 20 years because it is it does
become like playing an instrument right
you you're doing it for so long you
develop six sons you develop a skill set
around it but that's great now let's
figure out how that artisanship that you
amazing cannabis cultivate
have developed in the last 10 years 20
years 30 years can now be applied within
the agricultural format so go meet those
people become friends with them see if
you can you know in you know bring them
information they don't know about so
they will be open to show you guys what
they're doing and how they're able to
reduce their costs cuz you're not gonna
have an opportunity to cultivate
cannabis if you're still spending six
hundred seven hundred dollars to produce
a pound I mean you won't be able to
survive so we have to just let those
take off the armor you know let's have
an open conversation about this being a
plant the stigma is going away and let's
figure out a better way of cultivating
it so the people that I've been working
with the plant developing the
artisanship that make it so special can
stay in the game and that's really what
I try and help people out with and I'm
learning how to do that everyday and I'm
learning from the PhD greenhouse manager
that grows you know microgreens and I'm
learning that from the humble farmer
that's using KNF living soil
methodologies I mean there's something
about you to learn from all those people
and and then you just work on merging
those worlds finding the similarities of
where they all can meet and improve
there's no ceiling to how we can improve
how we cultivate plants at this point
like I don't see the ceiling I think
there's so much more to what so that's
the real challenge that is how do we
scale these methods or how do we scale
an artisan farmer in order to stay
relevant as this industry blows up that
is a great question and I would go I I'm
gonna reference a lot of what been
talked about in lean farm is we have to
scale the cannabis farm we have to know
what the consumer wants to buy right so
scaling is gonna be partly connected to
what we're growing and what we're
growing it for and I don't think we
really know what that is yet I think
that's being developed
and why I'm saying that is I'm seeing
that flowers becoming less valuable on
the market than all the derivatives
right so seeing a lot of eight pens a
lot of you know hash and derivatives and
variations of hash becoming more popular
and more convenient for consumption than
having a jar of flour
I love cannabis flower it's always
number one for me I mean I've it's
something that I love the experience of
the flower love looking at the flower I
love smelling the flower but a lot of
the new people that are coming online
they don't want to go around smelling
like a flower and also they maybe prefer
the different delivery methods so
thinking about that and we have to think
like well what is the percentage of the
flower gonna be look what is the retail
sales a flower going to be as we move
forward is it gonna be 70% 80% of what
it's kind of been or is it gonna be more
like five to ten percent of the market
so if it ends up going to where I think
it's going to go it's gonna be a much
smaller margin on the market and we're
gonna be moving towards these
derivatives then it doesn't and it
doesn't matter as much I hate to say it
but doesn't matter as much is if you're
producing like these really crazy
looking flowers so if that's the case
then you know because those crazy
looking flowers those amazing beautiful
flowers take a lot of energy a lot of
time and a lot of money to produce and
if people aren't willing to pay a fair
market price for them and they're not
gonna be around and that's kind of you
know what I see if it takes if it costs
$600 to produce a triple a beautiful top
shelf pound of the most highest level
flower and you can only sell it for $700
just like the cost of producing it or
$800 then it then that flower is gonna
go away until it can command a higher
value and what we're gonna see is large
scale or large scale operations where
it's not as the focus isn't necessarily
on the aesthetic of the flower it's
going to be more on the chemical
concentrations that can be
produced and how much of it can be
produced so answering your question if
we're looking at a derivative market and
we're producing candidates for a
derivative market why are we applying
the same methodologies and costly
methodologies of producing very very
high quality or close to the high
quality flour if it's just going to be
turning your derivative in the first
place so a lot of people haven't thought
about that in my in my opinion my humble
opinion they've designed these massive
facilities have cost a lot of money and
then over half or 70% of all of what
they're producing is being turned into
some kind of derivative so if you are
planning your cannabis business and you
want to grow flour god bless you I love
it
keep it going if you have a brand behind
you even better you'll probably be
successful more successful about it your
brand has any kind of market share but
if you're just getting into this really
think about what percentage of your
sales are going to be flower sales and
if you come in same conclusion that I am
which is that it's going to be lower
than all the derivatives then build a
facility out with economies of scale in
place and focus on producing biomass
that can be turned into derivatives
which requires a lot less input and
energy than it does if you're growing
four flower kind of roundabout answer
but does that make sense yeah we're
definitely seeing that here in
Washington people moving towards more
concentrates and moving away from flower
in a lot of ways which I agree with you
is a little bit unfortunate but it is
the reality of where the industry is you
know now you can get cannabis sugar and
canvas gummies and cannabis chocolate
and pretty much any of them you know I
and you have no idea what that plant
looked like no you have no idea what the
plant look like you don't know what it
was grown grown with you don't know the
quality of the flower all you really are
getting are these constituent
cannabinoids essentially so yep who
knows and that's a little scary to me in
a lot of ways just because you look
we've already talked about this we don't
know about
you know pesticides we don't know about
heavy metals yes there's some testing
going on around it but the regulations
have not cut up with the with the laws
in a lot of ways so I guess we're just
gonna have to wait and see how it all
pans out but there are people still
growing high quality flour out there you
know I know quite a few but it is it is
getting tougher and tougher so the
market is changing yeah and I don't want
those people to I'm saying this not
because I like the reality of it it's
just the reality of it and there are
some amazing cultivators that I'm hoping
it will swing back the other way
and then we'll you know at some point
when everything's kind of calmed down a
bit
there's gonna be a clearly defined
market for boutique really high-quality
anibus flour but please if you grow
really really really awesome epic flour
you are valuable and you're important
and you're special and that's that's an
art form in a craft you use your head
though make smart business decisions so
five to ten years from now you can
continue to grow that flower and that
might mean you have to be a little bit
nimble on what you want it you know with
where your direction where your
trajectory is out with where it should
be to survive because this is survival
mode for most cannabis companies right
now unless you've got hundreds of
millions of dollars behind you and and
you can afford the crazy burn rate so
please if you are one of these craft
growers and I see you all I see these
flowers all the time and I love it I
don't want to see them disappear figure
out how to survive think about a
longer-term plan and thinking about you
know what you might have to pivot and
grow lower quality product that's gonna
go to derivatives just to be able to
keep the business open that is not
anything you should really stress out
about you should just be like okay this
is what I have to do right now trust
that it's going to come back around the
artisanship will survive but that's only
gonna survive if the art that the
artists continue to produce if they all
get out of the game because it's too
tough then what are we gonna be left
with so please you know make smart
business decisions be okay
hey with yourself no one's gonna judge
you if you've got a grow flower for
derivatives for whatever reason just
keep going please stick around because
the art that you've brought to the
Kansas community is so important and it
would hurt if all of those people
disappeared and we just had you know
massive hedge funds growing and you know
mid grade product and that was all that
was available that would I mean that's a
possibility that's definitely a
possibility and it could be like you
know the beer industry where it took
like 30 40 years for craft beer to come
out to come back into the fold and I
would just say let's be smart about it
to keep to keep the artisan growers
around I think it's really important
well I know this podcast is cannabis
cultivation in science but I almost want
to have someone on to talk about
marketing and branding because you
should I want people to survive these
like artisan growers like you mentioned
the only ones I know of that are really
thriving right now or succeeding are the
ones that have really really strong
marketing branding and so they've
captured you know a certain demographic
of their of their community that is firm
believers in what they're doing and
they've been able to share the message
of how they're cultivating with a larger
audience and unfortunately that's so
important for companies nowadays and
it's something that I've had to learn
the hard way myself with my business I
was spending way too much time arguing
obscure scientific references with other
people online when I should have been
marketing my business I would be a much
more successful businessman right now
and part of starting this podcast was a
way for me to get some of my message but
also a greater message of what you know
the philosophy of people that I believed
in or had access to you out to other
growers so they won't make the same
mistake with their businesses that I did
so yeah you know learn learn from my
mistakes too in that regard and really
invest in that as much as much as I hate
marketing and branding and I have to be
careful because my fiancee is a
marketing director here I don't think
she listens to all my podcasts but it's
not something that I'm terribly
passionate
and you really have to find someone that
is that's really gonna take your
business to the next level if you want
to be successful because there's so many
aspects around social media now we're a
global economy and it's so important
that we reach out beyond just our local
area and people really find out what
we're what you're doing so even if
you're limited to a particular state
with your cultivation getting your
message out there too is wide of an
audience as possible is only going to
help you be more successful absolutely
absolutely
and just that not to that's a skill
that's another skill set and not and
that's that the thing is sometimes the
some of the best growers in the world
they don't know how to do that you know
and it's it's gonna be a challenge and
you know maybe there's some kind of a
boutique grower farm management company
that could emerge out of all this that
could help organize organize and create
a channel or a free way for a lot of
these boutique growers that just want to
grow so they can continue to be
supported successful as long as it was
done in an ethical way in a responsible
way and it wasn't some crazy you know
we're gonna control and own everything
that you're doing kind of thing is I
think it's important that people still
feel the sense of freedom that they had
when they were cultivating and in the
black market I mean there was a freeing
it was a free feeling to be in there and
not not that I was all a good thing
right like get people spraying a bunch
of crap and all the plants and
everything but being in that space where
you're kind of outside of society and
you're creating you got like wings that
that are so large no one can see and
there's something about that that is
inspiring and then once you get put into
the system and the structure and you've
got all these boxes you have to check
off it can limit that creative
experience well maybe there's a way of
still creating that creative experience
inside of the structure maybe something
that can be discussed at a further date
and you know I mean you can kind of
you have some other industries but it's
hard yeah I know for me with my business
trying to hire outside help with
marketing became really really expensive
and really challenging and I wasted you
know thousands of dollars on this in
terms of getting hiring the wrong people
are not getting what I thought I was
getting out of it or investing in
avenues that were just not you know
we're not productive so putting money
into you know maybe ads wasn't the right
wasn't the right revenue source or for
my business and these are all trial and
error things and it's really really
tough for a grower especially someone
without a marketing background to figure
all of that out and get into the
industry and figure out whether they
should be putting their money into
marketing so that it's the most
effective and a lot of that's data
analysis and requires having a lot more
information than the average grower is
gonna have you know we're fairly
insulated in what we do so there's a lot
of challenges around marketing and
branding and maybe I will have to have
someone on to kind of talk about that if
there's an interest if there's an
interest please people reach out shoot
me an email let me know if you're
interested in me talking about that with
someone but I know we have a lot of
other people that are just cultivating
for themselves or on a medical level
where they don't really need or want
that information to so uh yeah I think
there's a good friend of mine who always
said that everyone in the cannabis
business you know up until recently has
been doing business but they haven't
been in business and now we have to be
in business we can't just be doing
business so all that I think all that
information and coaching on that and is
really important and how it applies to
the cannabis world and how it's being
shaped you'll be great
yeah well thanks again for your time
today was there anything else out of my
budget cover before we sign off no it's
pretty good I'm just I'm excited to to
get to work you know to follow through
and continue on with this this podcast
that we have coming up with dope history
podcast and you know really looking
forward to this next year it's gonna be
a lot of fun that was Nelson linsley
from poetry of plants you can follow him
on instagram at poetry of plants that's
all one word and you can follow us at
kiss organics that's with 1/s you can
also check out his website at WWE a
plants calm he's an excellent consultant
and his team can help with facility
design operational training and state
applications the dope history podcast is
going to be an amazing project and
something we are both really excited
about it's taking us longer than
expected to get it published you can
follow along at dope history podcast on
instagram and WWE history com the
narratives we've heard so far are really
fascinating and the history behind this
plant and the effect its had on our
culture and the people involved in
bringing us towards legalization is just
incredible you are listening to the
cannabis cultivation and science podcast
I'm your host Todd Hussey don't forget
that there's more information articles
available on our website and blog at WWE
and XCOM and if you enjoy these podcasts
please take a moment to leave me a
review on iTunes or whatever platform
you're listening on and send me your
feedback and suggestions through our
website contact page thanks for
listening