[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge before starting the podcast
just a friendly reminder to check out
the podcast page at
www.is organics.com just click on the
learn tab then podcast and if you want
access to podcasts as soon as they are
recorded along with additional content
and video we do have a patreon account
we also do book clubs Hangouts and have
a private Discord channel for members
the kiss Organics website also offers
Consulting a variety of soil amendments
lighting fixtures beneficial insects and
the highest quality commercial soils on
the market we carefully research all the
products we offer in manufacture to make
sure they are science-based and meet our
standard of quality for this week's
podcast I had the honor of interviewing
Dr Nadia asaba also known as Dr
Greenhouse she is the president and
founder of Dr Greenhouse an Agricultural
and Mechanical engineering firm that
specializes in the design of HVAC
systems for indoor plant environments Dr
Saba has her PhD in agricultural
engineering from the the University of
Arizona's controlled environment
Agricultural Center and she is a
licensed mechanical engineer in the
state of California for over 20 years
she has dedicated her education and
career to helping Farmers control their
environments allowing them to grow crops
indoors in green houses and in
facilities that would otherwise be
impossible or impractical to do so now
on to the
show to the show hey Tad thank you for
having me yeah I'm really excited to
catch up again with you I I know it's
been a a little while since we last
chatted uh what have you been up
to well it's the new year um and you
know with every new year we think about
you know what what the year before
brought us or didn't bring us and what
we um hope the the next year will bring
so I've been thinking a lot about the
trends um in our industry uh in 2023 and
2024 and and looking ahead and and
trying to predict or you know consider
will some of those Trends continue into
2025 um I recently posted a Blog about
my predictions uh today um my podcast
episode going into a little bit more
detail on my predictions and Trends um
it posted today um today is January
21st and you know we're just we're
looking ahead to you know looking
forward to more Greenhouse projects I
think that's one of the biggest trends
that we have seen in the industry across
all the crops that we work with you know
growing indoors is really energy
intensive and um you know the P
Piper is is asking to have their you
know their dues paid in in a sense and
it isn't always panning out it's not
necessarily a profitable business and so
finding new ways to you know increase
the bottom line increase those margins
and actually first off just be
profitable or at least Break Even which
a lot of Growers haven't been able to do
um or it's been very marginal and so you
know there's only so much you can do to
increase your rate of growth and your
your yield and your output and so more
and more Growers and operators are
looking at how do we cut costs um and
you know energy is you know 30 to 50% of
uh Growers cost uh depending on where
you are and depending on what your labor
situation is um and so you know we're
seeing a lot of that as well as you know
a lot of interest in Automation and AI
though what I will say is a major Gap in
the industry is is data um you know
people aren't necessarily collecting
data or they might be monitoring with
you know some of the the monitoring
systems that are out there but it's not
actually being recorded or downloaded
anywhere so you know you're kind of like
kind of guessing I mean you have a feel
for it on a day-to-day basis but you
know that doesn't necessarily mean that
over you know the course of a of a full
you know Harvest cycle or a full year or
or a season um you have more of a gut
feeling than the data to support
decisionmaking so um you know we're
we're hoping and encouraging Growers to
implement you know more robust systems
even again if it's not tied into
controls and it is still monitoring like
just get a monitoring system that
actually records that data so that we
can then even help you analyze that data
if you don't know how to do it um but
yeah it's uh you know 20125 is going to
be an interesting year 2023 and 24
already were I mean honestly the last
five or seven years were interesting
right I mean we had covid and then we
had inflation and supply chain issues
and I mean and 280e is drowning the
Cannabis industry and over Supply and
it's just like okay how do we sort of
course correct here so honestly that's
what I'm up to is just thinking about
the course the path you know forward and
how Dr Greenhouse can fit into the
success um of of Growers you know
production goals and profitability goals
and you know work life balance and you
know all all of those things so um
I guess that's what I'm up to thinking a
lot that's great and for people who are
unfamiliar the podcast is called the
doctor is in and you can find it on all
major platforms uh Nadia's website is
drg greenhouse.com and she also I I use
this uh fairly regularly is your VPD
chart and your VPD app so there's an app
you can download from the App Store it's
free and you can put in your VPD and
it'll tell you where you land when you
enter your your um temperature and your
humidity um so a couple resources for
folks now your area of expertise is
probably the area where I feel the least
competent because it's so complicated um
I have a I have a bunch of questions I
want to cover today but let's just start
off with talking about um what are your
sort of initial considerations when you
walk into a new grow space like what
goes through your head because I
realized like with the the variety of
ways that people are growing from you
know an indoor tent a 4x4 tent to a
garage to facilities indoors to green
houses and you see all different shapes
and sizes um and not even that just
different ways that fans are configured
and airflow in and out and sealed and
unsealed like this is a very complicated
topic what do you what do you think
about though when you walk into a new
space from an environmental perspective
yeah I I mean thank you for this
question I mean one trend of 2024 is
that I was visiting a lot of sites all
over the country um both green houses
and indoor to really help Growers and
operators improve the conditions of the
facility that they already have rather
than helping investors right figure out
where to spend their 20 or $30 million
we're like okay how can we spend a few
hundred, to improve the asset that we
already have and one of the areas is
always climate control and you know the
the the two most challenging areas in
terms of managing the environment has
remained the same for 10 or 20 or 30
years I've been doing this for 26 years
now um is air flow and humidity control
it doesn't matter the facility it
doesn't matter the crop
um those are the two primary concerns uh
and I'm so happy that more and more
people are actually shifting away or
maybe they're figuring out the
dehumidification question and are asking
more and more about the airf flow
question I think I told you earlier I
was just at a mushroom conference and
talking about airflow mushroom Growers
are challenged with good airf flow um so
that is the first thing I look for quite
honestly is I am looking at your airflow
devices whether that's a duct whether
that's a poly tube whether it's a fanc
unit sitting in the corner of your grow
tent you know whether it's fans blowing
on your plants or not blowing on your
plants um that is always the first thing
that I'm looking for in fact I was made
fun of many years ago I'm I'm a both an
agricultural and a mechanical engineer
um and you know I've studied HVAC a long
time and I walk into any room and I am
looking up at where the diffusers are um
where the return registers are where the
equipment is um because I know that
that's going to affect how I feel down
here and the same is true with plants um
and so that's the first thing that my
eyeballs go to probably are the
circulation fans do you have them where
are they positioned how many do you have
are they you know blowing in the right
direction are they fighting against each
other because they're pointing in 17
different directions that is not even an
exaggeration I've walked into some green
houses and indoor Farms where fans are
pointing in multiple directions not
working together and just I mean it's
chaos um and and so that's one of the
first things I'm looking for is how are
we moving air in this space and how are
we getting air into this space are we
using outside air or is it 100%
circulation is it overhead is it under
tables all of those things because
airflow is you know you can have the
right size HVAC equipment it can have
the right capacity of cooling and
dehumidification you know for an entire
grow space whether it's you know 500
square feet or five 5,000 square feet um
you
know you can have the right capacity but
if you cannot get it to where the plants
are um who cares right it's just going
to circulate on itself um and and it's
not going to do a lot of good so how do
we distribute that conditioned air to a
space so that's one of the first things
I'm looking for the other thing I I
notice right away is the layout of the
room the plant density you know how tall
the plants are the different ages if you
have multiple stages of plants and you
know a lot of times right you you have a
one room or you know that is dedicated
right for the next eight weeks eight to
10 weeks of growing out say a a cannabis
flower plant um and uh and so all the
ages are the same but their morphology
is different right all the you might
have multiple strains in that room and
so you have short plants you have tall
plants you have medium plants right you
have more squat plants or you know more
narrow plants and you know
how how are those
plants uh configured
relative to each other you know I mean
there are some rooms I walk into and it
looks like a wave right because it's
like you have small plants next to tall
strains next to small cultivars next to
tall cultivars right and so it's just
kind of all over the place and when I
think about again airf flow I'm thinking
well are those tall plants
obstructing airf flow to get to the
shorter plants right or are the shorter
plants creating just like a Channel of
air in between the tall plants right
depending on on how it's going and so
you know I I look for uniformity also in
crop morphology um and it doesn't have
to be uniform necessarily but it kind of
you know if if we can design a room both
the plants and the air distribution
system that works together as opposed to
in opposition of each other or
obstructing each other um then you're
going to have more uniform conditions um
you know you're not going to have these
hot spots or or you know stagnant
corners of the room because air will be
able to move freely within that room so
those are kind of the first two things
of course I'm noticing if it's single
level double level right like sort of
what kind of crop style or or cropping
system we have I don't pay as much
attention to irrigation and the
substrate and cropping system it is
important um especially if you're
growing say in you know living soil you
might only be watering once every couple
of days um and so the the Dynamics of
water vapor and evaporation in that
space might be different than if you are
growing in rock wool or cocoa core with
drip irrigation right and and those
those systems are meant to drain and you
might be irrigating multiple times a day
and so we would expect a different
evaporation profile in those rooms um
and so that is interesting uh and then
the other thing that I look for is is
there water
everywhere and not necessarily because
of irrigation but because of
condensation and condensate collection a
lot of Growers have dehumidifiers in the
room or fan coil units in the room and
they are condensing right that water
vapor um out of the air through the
dehumidification process and too many
times we see overflow of the drain pan
you know just spill water spilling over
onto the floor or into the corner of the
room um or we see you know that um you
know the the drain pipe off the
condensate isn't designed correctly uh
and so it's it's it's backing up and
clogging up the the drain pan or you
know the ability to drain to the to the
floor or whatever um and and why that's
important to me I mean it's it's a lot
of things on an AG back perspective it
means that I'm not
controlling the water balance in the
room as well as I want to be because
rather than removing that water vapor
from the room I'm now just reintroducing
it to a spot on the
floor right so now I have to re-
evaporate it that that takes extra work
to do that right like to re- evaporate
the same water over and over because
it's not leaving the building uh so to
speak um so that's one concern the
second concern is you know that is a
place where algae can grow bacteria can
grow mold can grow and so now it becomes
a contamination risk for our Growers
right and for those plants that's not a
good thing and the third thing is a risk
to to people who are working in that
space right because now that becomes a
slipping Hazard not just on the water
but now that slippery algae right I mean
I think a lot of of people have had that
experience um where you slip on that
that that green water and you know woo
kind of got to catch yourself as you
skate across um and so you know I I
noticed water uh on the floor and on
surfaces um because that's what we're
trying to control through
dehumidification um and so when I walk
through a site a lot of times that's the
thing that I point at that the
maintenance guys come right away and fix
um and so honestly I really have fun
doing site visits and and and visiting
facilities because there's always
something to point out that can be fixed
right there on the spot you know Growers
kind of become blind um you know they're
so fixed on the plants and on nutrient
recipes right like these are really
great things to be focused on that's
what they should be focused on um but
they you know become blind to the
everyday things that are happening or
may not realize what the risk or what
the consequences are um and on and on
that note the last thing I'll just say
is is I look
for where air is entering or leaving
where it shouldn't be um you know
whether it's a greenhouse or an indoor
facility you know sometimes we see that
the building the structure isn't sealed
well you know the the seal around
diffusers um or penetrations through a w
isn't sealed well and that's where heat
and humidity can come into your space
that's where heat and humidity can leave
your space in an
uncontrolled manner um and again that's
not great for you know for HVAC control
and what we're trying to achieve with
our heating cooling and dehumidification
systems um but it's also an energy drain
on your facility because you know you're
if you're in Minnesota and you're
leaking out hot humid air right that
just more heat that you're going to have
to add into that Greenhouse um because
there's a hole in your wall um or if
you're in Arizona right hot dry air is
going to come in to one corner or one
you know spot in your room and you're
going to lose control of that room so um
you know looking at the Integrity of the
space looking at the space itself and
looking at all the air devices um it's a
lot I look I notice a lot of things
that's good that's good and I know you
you kind of already answered my next
question but uh was there anything you
can elaborate on in regards to the most
common mistakes you see in regards to
environmental control or air flow you
mentioned fans pointing in the same dire
or opposite directions kind of battling
each other um what are yeah what are
some other things that you see as just
common grower
mistakes on on on this topic
yeah I mean I think one of the most
common mistakes is not thinking about
how the various pieces of equipment and
systems are going to interact with each
other right so you might have an air
conditioning unit sitting on the wall
over here you can see my hand over here
um and then you might have an
oscillating fan on the wall over here
and that oscillating fan is blowing
towards
that uh that fan coil unit that air
conditioning unit sitting on the wall
well that air conditioning unit is
trying to blow air away from itself
right and and to the center of the room
while that oscillating fan is trying to
blow air towards the center of the room
in the opposite direction and now you
know you don't get good airflow or good
conditioning anywhere in the space right
like you might have good air flow near
the fan but it's you know crappy
conditions and then away from the flan
where that fan coil unit is you might
have really cool dry air over on this
side of the room but it never makes it
to the opposite wall um and so you know
that's just kind of one example or where
your heaters are located in a greenhouse
you know if you have an HF fan pointing
at the heater you know the heat is just
going to blow right back on on top of
the heater rather than being carried
away from the heater and into the
greenhouse and over the plants
that's probably the biggest thing that I
see is look you know can you move this
fan over here um or can you know we
can't can we ta change the direction of
of those fans um you know rather than
blowing in that direction can they blow
in the opposite direction and turn it
around um that's one of the biggest
mistakes that I see is just not
really paying attention or knowing how
to sort of
facilitate um conditioning the space
with the fans that you have for example
the other thing I mean you know I'm just
going to stick with fans for a
second one of the big sort of biggest
head slappers that I have oh man I'm
like allergic to something sorry my nose
is itching like crazy okay one of the
the biggest head slappers that I have
when I walk into rooms is when I see a
HF horizontal airf flow fans
um and vertical airflow fans or vaf fans
in the same space operating at the same
time so here you have these HF fans that
are trying to blow over the top of the
canopy um and then you have these VF
fans that are trying to you know suck
air from the bottom of the canopy and
kind of distribute it over the top
can I can I pause you first something
with just some real quick definitions
for folks who may not be familiar with
this terminology so you're talking about
horizontal air fans or airf flow which
is where a fan that's your typical
oscillating fan that goes back and forth
or sitting there pushing air I guess
horizontally so it's really easily
defined and then a vertical air flow
those suck air up um is that is that the
best way to describe them I'm picturing
kind of like a a a nuclear bomb
explosion that shape mushroom cloud
shape actually that's a really good
analogy yeah okay okay yeah
um yeah all right so keep going sorry I
just for people who aren't familiar with
this it's confusing I know I didn't
understand it and I still don't fully
understand it so yeah and you know I'm
glad you brought up oscillating fans as
part of sort of the HF horizontal
airflow fan Community um uh you know HF
fan
yeah are really designed to to move air
horizontally and usually over the top of
the crop um you know so you see them
sort of suspended from the trusses or
you see them hanging on the walls um and
and so yeah it's a horizontal uh motion
of air vertical air flow fans really
come in two Styles but the most common
one that I see um are the ones that like
you describe kind of like mushroom cloud
they suck air from underneath them and
then as they go through the fan then
they blow air out the top of them and
over the top then sideways so in some
ways they act they have a an a
horizontal air flow a trajectory as they
leave and then that air then filters
down in and under the plant canopy and
then gets sucked back up so it kind of
creates like the circular motion around
the canopy and so if you have have both
fans that are blowing horizontally and
fans that are blowing vertically what is
the direction of air flow you're going
to get in the
end it sounds chaotic to me and and this
leads to another question so the main
reason that we don't want air crashing
into each other is is the main reason
just because you end up with
microclimates you just don't get good
homogeneity um absolutely that's a big
big reason um yeah you you just get air
kind of banging into each other so you
get these erratic areas of of high
velocity and low velocity and no
velocity um and so it's like creating
hot spots but of of air motion you know
and then you might have air that's
moving upwards downwards sideways
diagonally um and so predicting where
those spots are going to be is really
hard but also that's not the point right
the point is to create homogeneity is to
create uniformity um in hopes that you
know your crop is all going to grow at
the same rate and with the same quality
if now if you have you know a high
velocity area over here and a low
velocity over here those plants are
going to grow very differently um even
if the temperature and humidity was the
same um it's kind of like a windchill
factor right like you can be outside and
it's warm outside um but you you know if
the air is still right you're so much
more uncomfortable than if there's a
breeze right or if it's windy and so it
it helps to basically pull heat away
from our bodies when it's windy the same
idea is true um with circulation fans
and uh and plants is that if you have a
high velocity then it's going to pull
more water vapor away from your plant um
which is going to stress your plant
potentially um and and require it to use
more water um to you know to deliver
nutrients and to keep it you know Lush
basically um and then if you have an
area of stagnant um air flow then your
plant might not have Appo transpire
enough and then it doesn't move
nutrients at all to the tips of the
plant and so you might see Leaf Tipp bur
and I know we've talked about that in
the past Tad is is leaf tip bur and so
you can see that under both conditions
really high velocity or really low
velocity um
and so the goal is to get sort of a
medium velocity everywhere um in the
space so that's one of the biggest
mistakes is when I see a combination of
fans you know I've seen oscillating fans
and vertical fans oscillating fans and
then those horizontal fans that are kind
of you know position in a racetrack um
configuration and then I've seen all of
that with also under bench fans or you
know underbench air tubes and my
question is always what are you trying
to accomplish with with all of these
fans right and and the goal and and what
so many Growers say is we want to see
the plants
dance I don't
know where that term was coined but I
don't necessarily want to see plants
dance I want to see maybe a little bit
of movement but if plants are dancing
then chances are your air velocity is
too high and you're going to stress the
plant okay oh my God T you know uh
what's interesting about this is as
you're saying this I want to go in my
girl room right this minute and change
some things that I've done
so I am doing glad that under I am doing
under canopy airflow at the moment
through a greenhouse convection tube uh
and I have because my room is so my
exterior air is so cold and I can't
condition it well I don't have a lung
room necessarily I'm trying to limit the
amount of air exchange that I have into
that room so I'm supplementing CO2 and I
do want to talk CO2 uh as well because I
think that's an interesting thing um
that people don't
necessarily talk about enough so I I am
supplementing CO2 into the air tube
which then pushes it up um when it does
supplement uh and I'm about a thousand
PPM CO2 just to throw out a number um
and uh my I really like the underair
canopy um or under canopy air flow
because I'm getting getting a larger
volume of air moved for in um at
probably I guess a lower velocity and
it's pushing the air up into the stamata
so I'm getting CO2 delivered where I
want it uh which is great but then I
also have an oscillating fan that was
above the canopy but now that the plants
have grown I'm thinking about it it was
hitting the canopy and I was seeing less
growth on the side where the fan was so
I turned the fan off and now I'm
thinking I need to take it down and put
a fan to get air circulation around the
room cuz I probably have stagnant air
everywhere else that the under canopy
air flow is not hitting um I know it's
hard to describe these things uh without
a visual but I think these are the sort
of sort of things that you should be
thinking about as you're thinking about
your your grow space and I'm just trying
to think it out out loud as we're going
through it yeah yeah yeah I mean I I
love it when Growers come up to me and
say Hey you know like I heard what your
recommendations were on air velocity and
I adjusted my fans you know to to hit
that range and it's so much better and
what I usually expect is that they're
saying that it's too low that you know
they had too low of a velocity but I
think I've had more people tell me that
they figured out that they had too high
of a velocity um and that once they turn
down the velocity of their fans or
removed some fans or reconfigured them
you know so they weren't beating up
their plants that their yield just shot
through the roof right like their plants
just thrived so much better by not you
know just knocking them over with wind
and you know when it comes to cannabis
the ultimate goal at least in the flower
room is to produce flowers when when we
have a high air speed what that does is
that triggers the plant to bulk
up and so it's going to put more of its
resources into increasing its stem
diameter and beefing up its you know
it's its stems and pedales and leaves to
withstand you know this high wind
velocity rather than putting those
resources into the flower so we're
stealing from the plant um or from the
flower production when we have these
really high air velocities so you know
for all of you listening the the target
is 35 to 1 meter per second which is
about 200 to 350 feet per minute um as
soon as you start going over that I mean
it's not the end of the world but what
we don't want to see is double that um
because your plants are just going
to you know be more vegetative than
being uh reproductive
generative now you shared a really
interesting Gem of knowledge on my
Instagram a couple years back in regards
to a photo I'd put up about a uh I was
doing these trivia questions where
people try and guess what's going on and
and in this photo a fan had fallen over
and was just blasting this one area of
the room and so these leaves were
damaged uh can you can you talk about
what was actually going on within the
plant and and evap transpiration because
I thought that was so fascinating yeah
sure um okay so when plants take up
nutrients usually with with every
nutrient except one it move they move by
osmosis so they go from an area of high
concentration at the root Zone um to low
concentration which is you know within
the plant itself and so that's how most
of you know these
chemicals that's really what they are or
molecules move through the plant the one
exception is calcium calcium does not
move through osmosis it actually gets
carried by water so um if if the water
moves too quickly through the plant
because you have a high demand for vapo
transpiration um then that calcium will
get left behind um and we get deposited
to the ends of the plants to the the
tips of the leaves if if Appo
transpiration is too slow then the water
isn't moving fast enough to carry the
calcium to where it needs to be before
it becomes deficient so that so you can
see a phenomenon called Leaf tip burn
where the edges of your plants of of the
leaves on your plant get crispy right
every grower has seen a crispy Leaf even
if you buy Lettuce H you know in a
clamshell for instance at the grocery
store you might see brown tips on the
leaves that's a Calcium deficiency it's
not rotted there's nothing you know
necessarily wrong with that plant it
just doesn't have calcium at the tips
and so it becomes crispy um and you know
that that was your trivia question was
you know what's happening to this plant
why am I seeing these you know Brown
edges you know to the tips of the leaves
and you know it kind of looks similar to
a nitrogen deficiency where you get
yellowing tips right and and other
nutrient deficiencies but it's that
brown crispiness that we're looking for
if you can touch the tips of that plant
and it kind of
crunches then that is leaf tip burn um
and that's a Calcium
deficiency and so let me just back up
for a second because I know I've used
the term evapo transpiration and maybe
not everybody knows what that is so a
plant moves water and nutrients through
the process of transporation up from the
roots and to the rest of the plant um
and so transpiration is literally um uh
that that motion that movement of water
and nutrients up and through the plant
and what drives transpiration is this
term VPD or vapor pressure deficit which
we
uh Tad mentioned we have an app so that
you can uh figure out what the right VPD
is or what your VPD conditions are based
off of the temperature and humidity in
your room um and I like to call VPD the
pressure on a plant to transpire so the
drier it is in the space the more water
is going to want to move from the roots
and out into the air um and so when you
have a high VPD
that's a dry room or dry air and your
plants will transpire a lot more moving
water very quickly at a very Rapid Way
rate through the plant if you have a low
vapor pressure deficit that's usually a
high relative humidity then the pressure
on the plant to transpire is much lower
and so water and nutrients move much
more slowly through the plant now if if
you for instance are only watering once
every two or 3 days and you have a
really high VPD which means a low
relative humidity it's it's high and dry
I call it high VPD and dry uh room
condition then your plant is going to
use a lot more water to to push out into
the room and what you might notice is if
you have a really dry room that your
plant over time might actually start to
wilt because now there's not enough
water at the root Zone in order to
support the pressure on the plant to
transpire that water pull it up from the
soil into the roots through the plant
and out into the air and so you might
find that you need to water more
frequently if you have a high VPD if the
relative humidity is really low and
that's why you know what's one of the
things I love about transpiration is
that for non-woody plants like like
cannabis for example turer pressure is
what actually holds the plant up and
turg pressure is created by the movement
of water and by the water pressing
outwards on the cell walls and that's
what holds your plant up so if your
plant starts to wilt then that means you
don't have enough transpiration to
literally hold the plant up um and so
you know one of the ways that you can
actually conserve water is by lowering
your vapor pressure deficit by
increasing your relative humidity
your plant won't demand as much water
and guess what it also won't demand as
many nutrients so you're going to
conserve water and you're going to
reduce your nutrient load um or your
nutrient demand for the plant regardless
of what type of Growing System uh you're
using uh and and you can train a plant
very young even you know at this sort of
small veg mini veg stage to be sort of
drought resistant if if you start the
plant with a high relative humidity it
will teach itself to conserve water and
then you can carry that through for the
next two to three months um with that
plant uh until you harvest it um and and
not require you know such a low relative
humidity I will say happily that one of
the trends I have seen in the Cannabis
industry is a movement away from 75
degrees and 50% relative humidity as
people are switching to LED are
realizing there's not as much radiant
heat so they have to raise the
temperature of the room and Growers are
learning that maybe we don't need such a
dry condition um maybe we can raise that
relative humidity and they're seeing you
know increases right 50% 100% increases
in yield because they're allowing
themselves to run a humidity closer to
65 or 70% not a lot of Growers are doing
that but the ones that are um are
reaping the benefits I would
say yeah yeah I am seeing more people
running higher humidities and I think
it's great um yeah couple of thoughts
one is that uh what you were describing
in the uh Leaf scenario is that some
minerals will move through the xylm
which is where water moves and some
minerals uh move uh predominantly
through the flum and uh minerals that
move through the xylem would have the
effect that you're describing so
potassium would be another one too with
that leaf tip uh scenario that you
described um for people who are uh
familiar with the botany side of things
I just think that's really
interesting uh I I just did a post on
root hairs talking about how root hair
death is really the reason that we see a
limitation whether overwatering or
underwatering what we're doing is we're
killing rud hairs and that limits the
plant's ability to uptake water uptake
nutrients and so that can have yeah
Downstream effect similar to what you're
describing so there's a lot of things
that can create the
same uh visual symptoms from totally
different environmental conditions and I
think that's fascinating and the better
we understand the why behind that the
better we can be as Growers so I love
that you were able to share that um the
the next question I have for you is
because you brought up turg pressure I
got absolutely
roasted uh a year or two ago because I
made a comment I was watching my plants
and they were doing what people call
praying which is essentially let's call
it a 45 degree Leaf angle okay and I I
made the comment I was like this Leaf
angle to me looks to be like suboptimal
from a solar panel perspective we're
trying to get the most light from a
let's say a static light like indoors
and our leaves are at this angle it
seems to me like if they were flatter
they would get more light so why why is
the plant doing this and people were
just like you're an idiot's turer
pressure and I okay yes I realized that
turer pressure is determining the leaf
angle but why is the plant doing it
because I've seen very unhealthy plants
do this that were nutrient deficient
that had less than optimal fertility or
other conditions
um one of the hypothesis was that it was
because the plant was trying to access
more CO2 because it was a a CO2 or maybe
it was a CO2 I think it was a CO2
deficient
environment
um but yeah you you're looking at me
like you may have some thoughts on this
so I I'm gonna shut up now and hear what
you have to say well those are all
interesting theories um the CO2 one is
actually very interesting but really
it's to protect itself um from um you
mention mentioned you know maybe a
highlight condition and that's exactly
what it's doing is that if it is growing
in a stressful environment um where it's
maybe really dry or there is a nutrient
deficiency what it's trying to do is
protect itself from collecting more Sun
than it can use and then being photo
bleached right or um becoming even more
nutrient deficient because it's trying
to keep up with the rate of
photosynthesis
that it could be doing um with the par
that's available and so in that case if
you're growing if you have LED lights um
and you have dimming controls and I
would turn it down um so that the plants
don't burn themselves I mean there are
some plants I'm actually curious about
some of the purpling Cannabis I don't
know if anyone has tested this but you
know like if you look at like red kale
or red leaf lettuce um that red pigment
is anthocyan and uh the sci scientific
Community um basically agrees that that
is the plant's own
sunscreen uh that that red pigment only
gets activated when the plant is exposed
to ultraviolet light and so it produces
its own sunscreen it doesn't have to go
out and buy some beach bomb or you know
some I don't know uh why can't I think
it must be winter cuz I can't think of
any uh product names for uh
sunscreen yeah uh and so that's probably
what the plant is doing is protecting
itself from um overproducing right it
from overc consuming itself um because
what will happen kind of like what
happens with humans if we're nutrient
deficiency deficient then we start
pulling from our bones right we start
pulling uh protein from our muscles and
you know we deteriorate ourselves to
keep our vital organs going and so the
same will be true for plants is that
they're going to pull from wherever they
can to keep their basic functions going
and that's just going to perpetuate the
cycle um and so what plants will do um
in some cases is that they will pray
they will close their leaves so that
they aren't exposed to so much sunlight
so that they're not sort of forced I
guess um to photosynthesize I don't know
if they have another mechanism I'm sure
they do um to slow or stop the
photosynthesis process um
but for
you're back there you are there you are
okay I didn't know what
happened I kept talking I didn't I
didn't notice you were looking at me
slowly until I finished
talking now you're back again okay do
you think you got that recorded what I
said I don't know because it is
recording
locally so hopefully okay yeah if not
then we'll come back praying plants
another time well I have other questions
about it actually so I'd like to
continue because I know we're going to
get a lot of push back on what you said
okay but you don't know what I said do
you well you were well I caught some of
it so basically you were saying that it
was a plant response to limit light due
to other environmental
stresses yeah basically so that it can
reduce or slow its
photosynthetic rate um and one of the
things I mentioned is that you know
plants will kind of do what humans do
where you know humans if we're nutrient
deficient um we'll start pulling right
nutrients from our bones right calcium
from our bones protein and amino acids
from our muscles right and so our body
will start to deteriorate in order to
keep our basic organ functions working
right and so plants might do the same
right if they are you know really active
and you know are photosynthesizing more
than they're in environment or their
nutrients or water can support them um
then you know they would start pulling
um from various places to keep their
basic functions going but plants have a
mechanism in order to protect themselves
from that which is to you know close
their leaves so that they're not
exposed um you know the chlorophyll is
not exposed to to photosynthetically
active
radiation okay that makes sense to me
except for to play Devil's Advocate we
also see plants
pray um
typically when uh well at night they'll
tend to droop and then they'll perk back
up you know when the day starts uh so
that light level increase um or that
transition from night to day we'll see
it or if we do certain nutrient
applications or on really happy healthy
plants so for many Growers I would say
the standard of a healthy plant is when
they do some sort of application or
intervention and the plant leaves prey
um so I feel like there are multiple
variables or mechanisms that can cause
this Leaf angle and some of them are
quite positive potentially and some of
them may not be but that we can't
necessarily use it as a diagnosis to say
this is a healthy plant or this is a
unhealthy plant I don't think so yeah I
mean I don't know that I would consider
a Praying plant healthy or
unhealthy um you know it might just be a
protective mechanism that could just be
temporary that is doesn't necessarily
indicate it is temporary yeah exactly
that it doesn't necessarily indicate
that there is something um systemically
wrong with the plant or or how you're
growing the plant um it also you
know could be that the plant is
protecting itself I mean I I'm just
thinking about in California poppies
like close at night and then open during
the daytime and I think one of those
mechanisms is to protect itself from
from frost um and from insects and from
other you know uh environmental hazards
um at night um when it's not active uh
so I could see that being you know
something the other thing is you know if
if a plant is praying at night it could
be a a
respiration uh mechanism so you know
plants are respiring all the time and
you know are only
photosynthesizing during the day and so
photosynthesis exceeds the rate of
respiration during the daytime hour so
we see you know um an an excess of
oxygen getting produced during the
daytime but at night time we actually
you know see more carbon dioxide getting
let off um by the plant at night uh
which a lot of people are concerned
about like oh my God my CO2 levels
increased at night is that unhealthy for
the plant no there has been no
scientific research to say that high CO2
levels at night are bad for any any
Horticultural crop so don't worry about
that and it's a natural process because
plants are always producing CO2 they're
always resp spiring um and so it could
be that that shift from
photosynthesis to respiration as being
the dominant process might also be
affecting um the sort of preying
mechanism that plants do um even at
night so also it could be a water
conservation uh mechanism uh you know I
mean yeah the ston are on the bottom of
the plant so that might seem
counterintuitive but again if we're
slowing the rate of
photosynthesis um then the stata don't
have to work as hard uh and so you know
then they they might be more closed you
might think they're more open but they
might be more closed um yeah I I like
the theory of increasing access this the
amount of access to CO2 maybe at that
angle for air flow purposes um but also
other people said maybe it's an actually
an increasing the amount of light that's
able to penetrate into the canopy so
you're actually getting increased
photosynthesis by having that leaf angle
because you're getting more light access
to more canopy um I don't know it was
interesting topic I just kind of wanted
to hear what your plants are so smart
we're still learning too and that's the
fun thing about uh that I love about
what we do is we're always learning new
things um so I do have some other
questions I know I kind of got off topic
there with that one um
let's talk a little bit about Energy
Solutions because one of the things I
see and this is something that I am
dealing with so I'll just give you a
real world example as a way to kind of
maybe bring it together for Growers so
like you know I mentioned that I'm in a
room it's mostly sealed because I don't
have a good lung lung room so if I'm
bringing in air it's it's pretty cold
air this time of year so I want to limit
that but then I also want air exchange
and my room will get too hot so now I'm
evacuating my hot air to bring in cold
air but then I'm losing my CO2 that I've
generated with either from the plants or
the soil or through artificial means so
it's this dance of like how do I
maintain the temperature and humidity
that I want in my room and the proper
air flow and the proper CO2 to match my
light levels uh but at the same time um
keep you know so I don't want to put
for example my temperature is now too
high I don't want to have to put in an
air conditioner which generates more
energy just to lower the temperature
with the heat that I've intentionally
created um do you see this on a you know
on a larger scale say commercially where
people end up uh essentially your
equipment just fighting
itself equipment is fighting itself all
the time whether it's CO2 versus Heating
and Cooling or it's cooling versus
dehumidification um or it's heating
versus
dehumidification um I mean that it just
is kind of the nature of the Beast
because for one you know we're asking
equipment to
manage energy within the space which we
call a load um that varies over time it
varies from hour to hour it varies from
day to night it varies from week to week
right and so we're asking equipment to
do all this
work and and find the right balance um
so that we can hit our temperature
humidity CO2 light everything targets um
so you know on your specific
example when it comes to carbon
dioxide and conditioning a
space one trick that you can do is okay
so let's say you have a it's a beautiful
day let's say it's like 65 outside and
the relative humidity is like 30 or 40
or
50% and you know inside you're trying to
maintain it to be 80 and I don't know
65% relative humidity so you know that
you can use that outside air to cool and
dehumidify uh your space and so you're
like oh great I don't have to turn on an
air conditioner I don't have to turn on
a dehumidifier I don't have to turn on a
heater and I can just ventilate this
space but you're like but I also want to
enrich this space with carbon dioxide to
hit you know a, or 1300 parts per
million I'm just going to dump all that
CO2
outside right
trying to keep up with with how much
happening is usually first thing in the
morning so when when the lights turn
on and your plants wake up if you
enrich that room with carbon dioxide for
that first hour or two before you need
before the plants are transpiring really
hard before heat really builds up in
your Greenhouse or in your grow um then
you can still get a really big benefit
from enriching that space with CO2 for
just 30 minutes to a couple of hours um
in fact a lot of research with other
Horticultural crops has shown that just
by by enriching for the first hour
before you vent has an increase in yield
for example Tomatoes of 10 to 15%
% just for that that's a short period of
time and if you think about it it's it's
like your plants when they wake up are
taking this big Breath Right like think
about when you wake up right I know I
catch myself every morning it's like I
know that I'm awake when I take that
that big gulp of air in the morning I'm
like okay I'm awake I'm ready to go now
that I've done that um and it's the same
is true with your plants your plants are
going to use the most CO2
right when they're first kind of waking
up and then you could do the same at the
end of the day right um as maybe you're
turning down your lights um and your
plants are still photosynthesizing still
transpiring even after you turn the
lights off it takes about 30 minutes for
your plants to acclimate um after you
know the lights turn on or after the
lights turn off and so you know stata
don't just instantaneously open and
close it takes 15 to 30 minutes for them
to do that so you could even after you
turn off the lights and there's still
all that energy in the room and the
stomata are still
open enrich with CO2 pump that room with
carbon dioxide and get it into those
those stomates um and a you know they're
going to be slowing their photosynthetic
process but you're going to be giving
that CO2 to kind of boost give it a
boost um so so that's one recommendation
that we give to everyone is look before
you turn on those exhaust fans before
you open that economizer or or let in
outside air enrich with CO2 but then
turn it off and you know unfortunately
our you know ambient CO2 levels are
increasing all the time and so you're
still going to get a good you know
you're never going to deplete um uh your
room of carbon dioxide um if you're
using fresh air you're just going to be
limited to whatever it is outside which
right now is about 400 parts per million
which is you
know more than maybe we want it to be as
humans yeah I want to uh I want to just
reiterate so you were saying that there
is research to support this idea of just
adding
CO2 for the first hour of the light
cycle and maybe again the first hour of
the dark cycle and seeing increases in
tomatoes that's that's a big one right
there for people especially in green
houses or other environments um
one thing I would add if you are
bringing in outside air just a friendly
reminder to filter it um yes or use
something to limit the intake of
pathogens and insects I know you
recommend uh M filter uh versus a HEPA
filter do you want to just touch on that
really quick sure sure of course um so
all you really need is a MV 11 filter to
filter out mold pores and everything
bigger than that and so you know
everything bigger than that is going to
be pollen insects right dander dust um
and so but really what you're probably
most concerned about are insects and
mold spores and a Merv 11 filter is
plenty what we usually recommend for an
air conditioning system is if you can
put two filters in series with each
other one right after the other a merate
filter um which will screen out the
insects and the Dust dust and the pollen
and the big stuff um and then a MV 11 or
13 filter after that which can then
focus on filtering out the smaller stuff
like the mold spores um and so that's
all you really need uh for your growth
space and and just to touch on why not
HEPA filters HEPA filters are designed
to filter out very small um particles so
viruses and bacteria are are good
examples of that and all plant viruses
are Soil and Water born they are or or
by surface uh they are not Airborne
they're spread by so if you are using a
HEPA filter thinking that you are
filtering out viruses and bacteria
that's going to infect the surface of
your plant you're not um you what you
are doing is maybe helping you know um
filter out virus is uh for your staff um
so the cold virus the corona viruses and
flu viruses aren't circulating around
but that's not going to help your plants
at all what's going to help your plants
is having good water filtration um and
good you know hygienic practices of of
cutting and pruning and and managing
your
plants okay one last CO2 question for
the podcast um so for people that are
not
supplementing
CO2 how much air exchange do we need cuz
I think of people who have for example a
grow tent and maybe that air is just
sitting in that grow tent and
circulating and because they don't maybe
for Odor Control or just the way they
have set up they don't have enough maybe
they just have a passive air intake into
the space um what sort of
limitations like I know with my room if
I if I don't if I don't bring in air
I'll get down into the 300s for CO2 and
I have to assume when I'm down in those
levels that my plant is struggling to uh
grow efficiently given the light levels
being at 900 a th000
ppfd um I'm not I'm not maximizing my
growth potential there and coot too
would be the limiting factor so if we as
we move to you know a more sealed
environment how important is that
supplementation
yeah I mean wow there are this is a very
multi-pronged answer s okay no well it I
mean it depends on so many factors you
know first off it depends on how many
plants you have right I mean do you have
one plant do you have a thousand plants
right because that's going to affect how
much CO2 those plants are going to
sequester and use um and and so that's
the first question this second question
is how old is your plant right a younger
plant is going to use less carbon
dioxide than an older plant um and so
you know just those two factors alone
have a big impact on how much um CO2
enrichment you need or you know just
with the rate really of what the rate of
CO2 uptake is by the plant so you know
how much either you know ambient 400
part per million air you need to add or
how much you know enrichment you need uh
what the rate of enrichment needs to be
to achieve say a th parts per million um
but then there's other factors right all
the environmental factors we're pushing
plants with high light levels we're
pushing plants right with maybe higher
temperatures um and so those two factors
um light and temperature um affect the
rate of photosynthesis so if you have
really high light and really high
temperatures I say really high
temperatures Maybe that's 83 or 85
Degrees um and you have you know 1,500
ppfd um as your your light levels you're
going to be pushing those plants a lot
harder than if you're at 800 ppfd and 75
degrees um you know set point so you
know the rate of CO2 uptake is going to
depend on both the environmental factors
and your plants uh so I can't really
answer that um spefic specifically but
you know it's a case- by case basis I
guess I would say I don't really have a
good rule of thumb um except to say that
usually if you assume one air change per
hour which is very low this is like
barely doing anything this is basically
just having a a leaky room um that's
usually enough um to manage uh or
maintain CO2 levels um you know for the
majority of plant growing environments
and so one AC has one air exchange of
between outside and inside air per hour
and so the way that you figure that out
is you you know you measure the square
footage of your space and then you
multiply that by the height of the room
and that's your volume um and so you
want one
volume to turn over with the outside air
replenish with outside air every hour
again so if you if you exchange one
volume of inside air with outside air
every hour that's usually enough to
maintain you know ambient CO2
levels
and okay this is my absolute last
question so when I didn't know we were
gonna talk so much about CO2 but I don't
mind it's great yeah no and well this
isn't about CO2 this is more just about
so if you were if if a company were to
reach out to you or facility what sort
of services do you offer around these
sorts of things so like what does that
process look like I and because I've
been in some some of these meetings with
you as just on the side listening in
sort of a thing
um what sort of services does Dr
Greenhouse offer for facilities what's
the range yeah so you know again we are
you know mechanical and agricultural
Engineers so and that Focus really on
environmental control we don't do
irrigation we don't do lighting there's
a lot of you know other special spe
Specialists uh in those areas including
utad um and so you know we really focus
on the air on the aerial environment
around the plant uh and So within that
one thing that we do almost on every
single project whether we're designing
it all the way through to get a building
permit for your new facility or just
doing a peer review or a gut check of
equipment that you're thinking of
installing in your grow room uh is a
load calculation and so I mentioned
earlier we you know we call it you know
the energy that's in the room we call
the load uh the cooling load the heating
load because that's what we're then
going to remove or add back into the air
with our HVAC systems so the very first
thing is we calculate how much heating
cooling and dehumidification or
humidification
you need based off of what you're
growing what type of Lights you have
what your irrigation rates are you know
all these sorts of variables um so that
then we can help you pick the right
equipment the right size equipment the
right type of equipment again if you've
picked out you know a dehumidifier and
maybe an air conditioner uh and you want
to make sure that you got the right size
um we can calculate what the right size
will be and tell you yep you're on the
right track or uh you might want to you
know bump the size up a little bit
because it's not going to give you
enough dehumidification at your
conditions um you know or it's way
oversized uh because you know you
weren't sure or the engineer wasn't sure
because they've never done a grow room
before and so you know you can save half
the price if you just you know get the
right size equipment which is not going
to just help you with the first cost
it's going to help you with the
operating cost because you're not going
to be running right bigger equipment
that has a a larger electrical or gas
load um or demand so you know that and
and we're we do that we do that level of
work for everything everyone from you
know 500 square foot you know small
grower to you know 50,000 100,000 square
foot uh you know fancy indoor facilities
um and we've saved our clients probably
millions of dollars um just doing those
those two things uh beyond that we're
hired a lot to help with air flow and to
help with CO2 enrichment so we can
actually you know calculate how much CO2
your plants are going to use so that you
know how much you need to then add if
you want to enrich the room with
CO2 um so we can get you dialed into
that number as well so you don't have a
you know bigger tank outside than you
need or you know that those canisters
are going to be enough uh and then you
know on airflow we've been called a lot
more uh recently on helping with airflow
design and improving the air flow
situation in indoor grows green houses
you know and you know if you are growing
in multiple
levels which I'm sure a lot of your
listeners are growing in two or three
levels whether that's for clone or veg
or flower you know I mean it gets really
complicated once you start working in
three dimensions how do we get air
moving down below and up above and
through right I mean those are basically
the the three variables that we're
trying to to manage with airf flow and
you know there are some um prepackaged I
would say pre-fabricated systems out
there for you know
multi-level uh uh grow racks and
I wish they were engineered a little bit
better um and and so we've actually come
through and and and helped Growers to
improve on those systems um and we've
also custom designed those systems you
know and and the thing about that you
know like if you think about like you
might spend 20 or
$30,000 installing like an inra um air
distribution system
that you know was designed to make your
dance dance but they're only dancing in
the middle they're not dancing at the
ends because it wasn't
really engineered I would say and so you
know like you think you're saving money
because you're not hiring an engineer or
consultant like us to you know to to do
the calculation and the analysis to tell
you how much air flow you need to move
from end to end to make sure that it's
picking up the right condition of air at
the other end of the rack um to size the
ducks or that plenum that's running from
end to end um but in but again we save
our clients a lot of money by doing that
because we get it right the first time
again it's not over engineered we know
exactly the fan size the duck size and
we have
relationships with duct providers who
will design that duct to our
specification if we say we want an air
velocity at the plant level of 75 m/
second that's what we get from end to
end and so you know you don't have to
hire a consultant later to fix something
that you thought you were saving money
on early um in the in the design and
construction process and you
know I have a grower you know we have a
client that we did that it was a single
level we specialty custom designed this
fabric duct system worked really closely
you know what angle do we want the the
air to leave what velocity do we want to
achieve as the plants are growing from
small to big you know and can we hit all
angles um on that plant and when they
first started it up that's all they did
they just you know used the fabric ducks
and I walked through and like oh my god
it feels amazing in here just you know
when you walk into a room and it just
feels like butter like you just know it
feels right right you don't feel a wind
tunnel you don't have air blowing on you
and then it's not like stagnant and
weird over there it just felt so good
and then they got a new grower and that
new grower was like we need fans and
they just installed fans and now the
room is in chaos because the fabric
Ducks were designed to do what they were
supposed to do and as soon as they inst
fans just like I was talking about the
vaf versus HF fans it created a
chaotic situation above the plants and
so some plants got a lot of air other
plants didn't get any air the fabric
ducts were just kind of you know that
air was just getting kind of like
swirled around without ever hitting the
canopy you know and so I I
um asked them right I uh encouraged them
look turn the fans off in one room and
see if it's any better and they did and
it was but it's really hard sometimes to
convince a grower who is used to doing
one thing who didn't maybe have this
system right in in their previous grow
so you can't really blame them because
they're not familiar with it they
weren't there when we designed it all
together and so they're like hey this is
missing right you you asked me like what
do I see when I walk into a grow room I
bet that grower walked in was like what
the hell there's no fans in here how are
you moving air around right and they
didn't ask right they just you know did
what they did and um and so now they had
to hire me back to fix the problem that
they didn't have in the first place uh
so um anyway you know we we want to help
Growers get things done right the first
time uh you know like I said I've been
going to a lot of facilities this last
year helping to um permanently fix
Band-Aids right cuz so many Growers have
put Band-Aids on top of Band-Aids we we
know that situation um or to invest in
the right control system or the right
fan system or or reinvest in air
conditioning because let's face it after
five or six or seven years like those
units have reached their end of life as
we've pushed them to run every day
through snow and and you know humidity
uh and so you know we're being asked to
hey you know we had this air condition
system we are able to get through it
wasn't great now we want you to come
back and give us the right thing as
we're considering replacing the old
equipment um and so you know if we can
get into these facilities and help you
earlier um the better it's going to be
for you in the end because you're not
going to be banging your head against
the wall like why isn't this working I
don't have the support I you know my
equipment is over cycling and I'm over
and under shooting all the time right
I'm seeing these spikes in the morning
and spikes at night when I turn the
lights on and off um we can help you
manage uh those those variables so that
um it just makes your day easier I I
mean I hate it when I walk into a grow
facility and that's what the Grower's
job has become is just sitting in front
of a computer screen watching the
temperature and humidity levels
fluctuate in you know multiple rooms and
they're trying to like you know flip
switches and turn dials you know whether
that's you know uh literally or
figuratively at the at the computer
screen or whatever um you know trying to
manage it on almost like a minute by
minute basis yeah that's maddening right
so um the equipment is out there the
control systems are out there to to do
the majority of that work for you so
that you can focus on what it is you
want to be doing right which is playing
with nutrient recipes playing with
lighting recipes trying new cultivars
and strains right like I mean the fun
stuff about uh growing plants growing
cannabis so yeah I I just want to say
really quickly like I found you over a
decade ago through canacon because the
the speaker that was the expert on HVAC
came in and he was referencing you for
all the research that he was sharing so
I was super excited to go to the source
and meet you and I'm really just
grateful that you're willing to share
some of the information that you have
with Growers and uh yeah I hope that we
can catch up again soon but thank you so
much for your time today thank you so
much Tad I always love talking to you
you always have great questions I love
going on tangents because they're always
relevant and I know that you talk to a
lot of Growers who have these questions
so I really feel like when I talk to you
I'm I'm speaking to your audience to to
Growers out there because um you're
you're just sort of translating right
you're just sort of I tried my best yeah
exactly so thank thank you for the
opportunity again to to talk about
this cool