[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation in
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge my
podcast this week is with justin mcgill
justin is an owner and head grower for
legit farms a legal cannabis company in
the recreational market here in
Washington State I want to do this
podcast with Justin because he has been
growing in living soils longer than
anyone else I know and he was
instrumental in helping me in testing
out various ideas around soil mixes soil
testing and reom ending in beds this
podcast is less about the proven science
around concepts but more so the tips and
tricks he's picked up over the years as
he's learned from cultivating this plant
my hope is that will encourage other
growers to experiment and try out some
new ideas or offer some suggestions that
may spark other innovation not only that
but justin is just a great guy and a
good friend it was fun to catch up with
him on about what he's been learning
since transitioning into the rec market
and scaling some of the things he was
doing on the medical side from back in
the day anyway onto the podcast
hey Justin welcome to the show hey Dad
thanks for having me yeah I mean I've
known you for I think we were talking
about it before the show like since what
2011 2010 I met you and I mean you came
to my wedding we've become good friends
over the years and definitely talked a
lot about growing cannabis you want tell
a little bit about how we know each
other and in your background yeah you're
being really modest we discovered your
soil and then we just took off and he's
great success yeah I've been growing for
I think since 2003 is when I first tried
hanging a light up and sticking some
clones under it and I eventually I tried
a lot of method
eventually found myself doing just top
top feeding nutrients over cocoa and
using botanic airline and getting a
decent result like pretty okay quality
and everybody was happy with things but
my best friend Jaya he was like I know
you can do a lot better and I was
struggling at that point with like some
pH issues and stuff and so long story
short my buddy started getting involved
and he's got a mycology background and
he's just as you know he's he's pretty
darn brilliant and I had the
construction pedigree and just pure love
of cannabis to really motivate us to
take it to the next level so he started
getting involved and we decided to get a
house together in Seattle and that was
right around when I met you because Jaya
he told me that people are getting big
yields on compost based soil and just
adding water to it and that that was a
typical grower I pretty much laughed at
that but we had built a really nice
scene in our basement and and I think
Jaya had met you because he was doing
some compost or some research on compost
tea and you were like hey I just made
some soil you want to try it out is that
kind of how it went yeah I was literally
in my parents driveway rolling a compost
tumbler around with the first few
batches of soil I was trying out at the
time and when Jaya showed up and we kind
of hit it off and I sent him home with
some soil too because I wasn't growing
cannabis or anything at the time and he
you guys were kind of the first the
first testers of I guess what's now
turned into or become kiss soil in a lot
of ways yeah yeah so yeah Jaya took that
soil back to our place and I'd had a
strain called grapefruit for four years
that was pretty good but we'd never
really figured out how to grow it right
and we can't remember what we did I
think we probably stuck like seven
gallons of your soil or something a
smart pot and we planted grapefruit in
there and it was it was picture
a grapefruit just towered above the
whole crop is a big beautiful buzz
everywhere it was it was it was the kind
of thing where we didn't really need to
discuss it even it was just a matter of
wow how do we get all this soil in our
basement and the first thing that we did
was we had I can't remember if they're 5
or 7 gallon smart pause but we kept
pushing them closer and closer together
we built one big drain table that they
all sat on and we kept pushing the pots
closer and closer together and we could
clearly see that the roots were growing
through the smart pots into the other
smart pots and so when we harvest we'd
be ripping these things apart and that's
when both Jaya and I were like man we
just need to put some slides on this
thing and make a bed out of it and
meanwhile my little house in Arlington
had some grow trays that were already on
tables and listed up so we just threw a
bunch of soil in there and gave it a
little experiment it was not deep enough
but it worked really well and then we
put walls on our table down below in the
Seattle house and it was so productive
and it was so easy to operate and and
the quality of the bud that we were
growing was just amazing and we just ran
with it from there
so you started you started making these
beds and I remember when we first
started talking about this and then came
around with the idea of reusing the soil
and keeping it in the room because it is
a lot of Labor especially back in those
days when you're moving it out of a
basement and trying to you know at that
time be a little more discreet how how
did the whole reusing the soil go I know
there's been ups and downs throughout
that process as well yeah now that was
that was purely Jaya because he was
convinced that we could amend it with
the proper amendments and and get it
reusable again just like you would in an
outdoor garden or a greenhouse or
something like that and at the time we
were both kind of like man we don't know
why anybody isn't doing this which is
funny now looking back on it but yeah
pretty much we just seriously went about
amending the soil and
using it and it got to the point where
some of the soil we had I think there
were some soil that had gone for seven
years before we ended up replacing that
and the soil test would get really
really weird the salt levels and all
that like I remember you looking at soil
reports like wow how is this how is this
even working but we were still getting
good quality and decent rates or I'm
sorry decent yields but um as you know
eventually we we got this plant
parasitic nematode called the root-knot
nematode and I actually got that myself
down the road when when we had the
program in a lot more places really
stepped up and we were reusing soil all
the way through the system too so we
would plant we would plant a plant in
soil and veg it would go into flour into
an amended bed and then that same soil
that's in the flower beds as we plant
the next round into there the soil
displaced would go right back into our
bedroom right back into our propagation
space so that little closed-loop system
of just recycling and recycling and
recycling in my opinion that's what got
us the root-knot nematode it's also very
likely that we've literally caught it
you know that we got it from somebody
and it wasn't around before but we've
all got varying theories on it but I
kind of feel like it's something that's
around and if you provide the right
conditions and promote it enough you get
to to toxic levels as soon as you have
the toxic levels of this nematode it's
almost like you should just burn down
your facility it's like it is so hard to
get rid of so once that happened that
was when when I quit reusing soil in veg
so now as a bedding plant goes into a
flower bed that is amended soil the soil
that comes out of that bed that's
displaced by the next round coming in we
discard that now and that's to just to
reduce any likelihood of something
that's collecting in the amended flower
beds into making it back to propagation
and I use the analogy of a river
like propagation as the headwaters
bedroom is like you know the the upper
mainstream and the flower rooms are all
like the estuary or whatever you want to
call it and we try to at the farm really
not bring anything from downstream back
upstream and right now I I haven't done
it yet but I found a lab that will test
for the root-knot nematode part of the
trouble with that without guys all you
you can't see it until you see the signs
of it and once you see the signs of it
it's way too late so as you know we're
still amending your soil like crazy and
maybe getting a little better at it but
but we're trying to we're trying to do
whatever we can to to avoid promoting
that root-knot nematode and so I'm
pretty excited about having the ability
to test it and that should be able to do
that pretty soon here that'll just
determine how long we run the soil so I
would like to know if the interesting to
see what levels of the root-knot
nematode are acceptable or if it's just
any sign of it is it's instantly over
but that's where we're at with that yeah
I want to talk a little bit more about
some of the technology you've used over
the years and what works for you and
what doesn't but since he brought up the
root-knot nematode let's talk a little
bit about that so in I I received some
clones from you back in the day right
after you got this because I wanted to
do some trials trying to come up with an
organic cloning solution and I remember
my plants they just look sickly they
never grew you know and this is like
after a month they really hadn't grown
much at all and it was until I pulled
the plants out and looked at the roots
that you actually do see these nodules
on the roots oh I think I have a photo
of it somewhere I could share but what
were your experiences in terms of
symptoms for this particular nematode
yeah you're you're gonna see well when
it's a really small levels gosh you will
see your plant health be affected you'll
have like one plant in a bed that
doesn't look good it looks sickly and
you can tell that it's that it's nothing
above the canopy that's doing it it's
identical to the others and so this
plant will look like it'll have it'll
have chlorosis and the leaves and stuff
like that it'll look like it has a
serious root issue and so when you go
ahead and grab that plant and pull it
out and pull out real easy and it almost
looks like there's a bunch of perlite
stuck in your roots those nodules or a
bunch of round balls on the roots I
think it is what we would call gulling
in a tree you know when a wasp or
something lays an egg and the oak tree
builds a big ball around it that's
exactly what happens in the roots and so
the roots grow around the nematode and
at that point the nematode now has a
permanent home and it is inside your
root system and also when we went as
soon as we pull up a plant and we see
signs of the root-knot nematode that
just means that entire facility needs
its soil replaced and we have not
discovered a way to sanitize the beds or
the room to avoid it coming back and I
think that speaks to its larvae and how
small it is and how durable it is the
larvae can last for three years dormant
and essentially it's dust so you know
what grow rooms look like and stuff it's
pretty hard to get them to that clean so
how have you tried to treat I don't even
try to variety of products to sort of
maintain the levels below an economic
threshold I know you've completely
cleaned a room so it's not like you just
pulled out the soil and brought in new
so you guys scrubbed and bleached and
really cleaned what have you done to try
and control this particular pest well
we've just researched products that that
treat for plant parasitic nematodes and
I don't know surprisingly there's not
that many I guess and we I guess we
haven't found anything that that that
seems to be very effective where we've
gotten the roof not never toe
and when we replace oil and sterilized
facility we seem to get about four or
five crops without it and it and it
doesn't doesn't seem no matter what
products we use we've been using
venerate which is it's just the it's
like majesty from maroon Bioworks and
that targets on on plant parasitic
nematodes but it also it's a biological
but it also kills beneficial insects too
and that's what we were finding was most
things that were going after these plant
parasitic nematodes are also going to
kill the rest of our beneficial insects
which with the living soil I think is a
really bad idea it's just what as soon
as you're been officials are gone you
generally have a host of issues of other
of other plant pests let's see here we
have a theory that the stern EFL ta
which is uh it's known as nemesis two
from BASF but it's a it's a beneficial
nematode that targets thrips and fungus
gnat larvae but it seems like when
you're using that you don't have the
root-knot nematode problems like
actually we used to we used to add these
beneficial nematodes and I think it was
turning a filthy eighth but I'm not sure
before we got the fruit Mountain emmitt
ode and actually the root-knot nematode
we got when we had quit using applying
beneficial nematodes so there's still
some mystery to it and if there's
another product we use is called doTERRA
or something like that and there's yet
another product that I just have not
been able to get it's called Melek on WG
it's from syrtis but it's a frozen
fungal product that's hard to ship and
and recently what I've been using in the
program is is from Bioworks it's as a
rack and it's mold techs and that and
that focuses on plant parasitic
nematodes
being safe with most beneficials so yeah
that's kind of where we're at at this
point so let's talk a little bit about
your IPM program and protocol so I know
when you enter your facility you're
putting on booties that are clean to
help prevent some of that transfer and
making sure that your clothes are clean
and you I know you especially I've been
very diligent about making sure when you
move from one location to another or
outside of your your your rec grow it
legit north that you're not getting
exposed to any other pests if possible
your clothing or anything like that now
what sort of things are you doing in the
facility itself to help maintain you
know control pests and things like that
um well since we were just talking about
the nematode and I just touched on a
little bit ago with the analogy of the
river and upstream and downstream that
that that's one of the main things is
just make sure your tooling your
equipment your own bodies your personnel
aren't going from flower rooms with
amended soil back into bedroom and
propagation and then just you know
little things like trying to treat the
ground is a place of no return
you know something falls on the ground
or something that is now dirty try try
to try not to let things hit the ground
anyplace that could potentially have
dust and dirt that is untreated or
unsterilized as potential for that to
harbor that guy there so it's it's a
real challenge because you've got you've
got personnel and you've got a facility
that likes with disability that we have
is it's a renovated egg farm and it's
got pretty rough concrete and stuff we
did the best we can with all of our
floor coverings and stuff should make it
to make surfaces that we can sterilize
and clean but it really just comes down
to the traps at consistency and
cleanliness and everybody understanding
what the goal is that we're trying to
achieve so it really takes everyone on
the team working together on this to
maintain it and you don't currently
believe you have the root-knot nematode
in your facility but you're just very
diligent because it's something that
you've dealt with in the past it's just
such
just such a devastating pest yeah
absolutely devastating I mean we in
theory based off what we found in the
past we can amend your soil for I mean
he's easily five years and so the cost
savings of just amending that soil and
not having to replace it and besides
this the cost of the soil is just the
actual physical process of removing it
it's it's huge and also we build a lot
of biology in the soil that's wonderful
if we can keep it yeah can you tell me a
little bit about your process sort of
from from clone to harvest I want to get
into a little bit of the technology that
you guys use in the rooms but can you
just take me through I think you have
sort of a unique cloning method and some
of the stuff that you've sort of figured
out the little tips and tricks that make
make legit what it is I guess
yeah I'm very proud of the cloning
method once again Jaya when we were when
we were still partnered up together on
an operation he he told me he told me
once he's like hey you know rooting
hormone he's like like you know you
don't really need that I was like what
what are you talking about that that's
crazy talk it's really expensive you
know and so I just thought well okay
let's see here I just quit using it and
sure enough I just took a little longer
and then I'm not sure how exactly it
happened so I was I I actually asked you
you know what do you recommend for for
propagation you're like oh I like these
Oasis cubes and so I tried the Oasis
cubes and I really really liked them
they worked really well and I would put
the Oasis cubes in a tray and put the
dome over it and then rip the vents off
the dome and then just water those trays
right through the dome you saw me do
that once and you like laughs you
couldn't believe what I was doing right
so I I was doing that and it was working
pretty darn well
but then when as soon as I started
having people work for me they wouldn't
really understand like have you
water this dome I don't know how to put
the right amount of water in it and
stuff and I'm actually Buster that you
met crazy Buster he just started poking
much holes in the tray so you could
water it every day and let the water
just go through it and that really
helped that was the ticket so now we put
those Oasis cubes in drain trays put the
domes on them rip the vents off the dome
water through the dome we basically keep
those domes at like 90 to 100% humidity
to the point where they're almost
molding but that's what really makes
them route well and then of course one
of the main keys is you're taking a
cutting off of a really healthy plant
that's probably the most important thing
but we will take that cutting we'll
stick it in there wasted scoob's will
drench them every day with water run it
real high humidity in there and we will
add nothing but water no rooting hormone
and in about two weeks they'll start to
root and and they will continue to root
and like one of these last like last
month we took 260 cuttings and only four
of them didn't root and so as long as
you're not in a big rush like if you
don't need your cuttings in ten days
then you don't really need the rooting
hormone and it's a more affordable
program and we've just had really good
success with it so the timing on it
works out for you
yeah so in medical days we would we
would take a cutting off of a plant that
was going into the flower room and then
that cutting would be would become our
next generation and now getting into
these just these more productive rooms
that are sealed with co2 and everything
that timing wasn't working out so we
switched to moms so we've got a whole
generation of plants going into a flower
room we just pull out the genetics that
we want to keep and we keep those aside
as mom's and I think right now three
weeks later three weeks and the flowers
when we take our cuttings and they're at
what we feel is an appropriate size when
when that crop is done and the next
rounds going in now can you talk a
little bit about that extra room that
you created you're willing to talk about
yeah
that was a little brainchild of Jaya and
I so I was just talking about the dome
and that dome is I mean I think it's 90
percent humidity and maybe even more
when you when when a plant roots in the
dome and it's and you're gonna pot it
into it we pot we go from the dome into
a three and a half inch pot when you
caught it it it often will wilt and I
think it's as those roots are our first
learning how to uptake nutrients it's
kind of a hard thing to do and you're
taking it from a dome which is very very
low VPD to a bedroom which has a little
higher VPD and we created a transitional
space kind of an incubator an in-between
zone from a dome that's ninety percent
humidity and maybe eighty degrees to a
bedroom that's seventy percent humidity
at 70 degrees so we just picked a middle
ground at about eighty eighty-five
percent humidity and t5 lighting so it's
real low infrared and we put all these
freshly potted plants into this into
this room and normally we'd get you know
probably forty percent would wilt for a
couple days and then pop back and now
they just don't will so it's really cool
so it doesn't affect our routing success
but it affects our our propagation
success from there and then as soon as
they are perky and standing up in that
room we pull them right out and
introduce into the bedroom and what size
containers are using in the bedroom
using two gallon pots right now so we'll
go from the three-and-a-half inch tall
pot to a two gallon pot and and when
that plant of approaching maturity is
right when we want to get it into the
flower room so so it's not running out
of water
it hasn't its roots haven't hit hit the
point where they think they're starting
to coil and stuff like that so it's
still really in its stride how long do
you think that process is in terms of
amount of time as well as height of the
plant
approximately yeah well we take that
cutting three weeks in the flower
and it takes a couple of weeks to root
and then it's got about four weeks after
that to outgrow its during a half inch
pot get into a two gallon pot you know
grow into that soil filling us that we
can easily transplant it and so it would
probably at that point it would be it
would get to about maybe a little to
eighteen inches tall or maybe even two
feet some of the taller stuff so what I
would call like a smaller medium size
plant okay and from there you're taking
it and transplanting it directly into
the flower room which has beds on has
rolling beds and the soil that you're
displacing from the soil coming in just
the amount of space it takes to plant
the plant that's leaving the facility
and not coming back yeah currently yep
but now that I've got this lab up north
and Blaine what I'm going to do is I'm
going to take samples from all this
display soil and I'm going to test it
for the nematode because if the
nematodes not there we could just use
the soil again and or or use it for
maybe and maybe outdoor production or
greenhouse production or something
that's yeah but in theory if it doesn't
have a nematode there we could put it
right back into flour I'm just a little
bit a little bit trigger shy yeah tell
me a little about your flower rooms
because I know this was sort of your
opportunity to design something based on
your experience from your medical days
yet I know you were also limited on
budget so it's not your ideal room I
know there's some things that you would
want to do differently but what were you
able to kind of come up with based on
your your limited resources and the
space what the space was Lao yeah um
once again I got to give a bunch of
credit to Jaya
I mean well to my own credit I was
building a wood bed a wooden bed that
has slope to it and Pont and it's
wrapped in pond liner and has a drain in
it and those beds work really well but
they're not basically efficient they're
stationary they have aisles as you know
you don't want piles when you're
lighting up a whole room
so Jaya did an experiment he used
fluence LEDs but he built wood beds just
like mine but he found a track and a V
caster they can mount on these beds so
all the beds roll together so basically
you can go all these beds and have a big
continuous block of canopy and then if
you need to go in and service your beds
you can slide them apart and get in
there he hit some amazing numbers some
of the best numbers we've ever seen out
of that little that little rig that he
did in a garage and so I just took that
idea and with one of my partners who the
is a steel expert master machinist we
designed a metal rolling bed and a
former employee of his made them all out
of a small shop and these beds are 19
feet long they're about four feet wide
inside dimensions and they have four
legs and those legs have thousand-pound
8 inch v casters on them they're really
stout and by thousand kind of mean they
can hold a thousand pounds one of these
beds holds it up two and a half yards of
your soil so in the neighborhood of four
thousand pounds or something and you can
push these beds and you can move them
yourself on the track hindsight now is
that you know you're in a room maybe
you're spraying that's the worst
situation is a floor slippery and you're
trying to move these four thousand
pounds rolling bed and your feet are
sliding that's the one thing that I that
we need to modify or change on the next
design it's some sort of a mechanical
way to move the bed belong and we were
thinking about even like a wheel at the
end of it that you just turn and it has
a little beer driving those own but that
that was a huge game changer
that made these rooms so productive by
having that much soil in the room and
all that tight together so I didn't
quite hit the numbers that Jaya did with
the LEDs in that garage but we're
getting over three pounds of light
untrimmed right now since since we grow
fur
for a pre-roll joint we don't really get
I don't necessarily get trim numbers we
do trim everything but I don't know what
that is so I mean that's been that's
been the goal for a long time like a lot
of growers trying to hit that magical
three pound of light number yeah and
then you're also so you're using
double-ended HPS which I know is not
your optimal setup but you had a ton of
them available to you yeah I already had
some of these double-ended lighting at
the AC de it's it you can air-cool just
the hood itself and out the bulb which
makes it good for a budget grower you
just you do a lot more ducting you got
to put in a whole air system to air cool
these lights but then you can size down
your AC substantially which is a huge
money saver so yeah that's exactly what
I did up there when I was buying the
lighting you happen to find they were
clearing out this AC de ballast that has
the ballast attached to it the hood and
ballast all attached so we got our
lighting for that whole facility for
cash like eight grand or something like
that which is almost unheard of and it
allowed me to do about at least 33% less
AC than most people do but probably
about half as much air conditioning as
most people run and it's working it's
working pretty darn good those lights
you just got to run them really high and
we we have them fixed stationary we
don't move them we let the plants just
grow toward them yeah I know ideally you
want to switch to LEDs but the cost
difference just wasn't something you can
do at the time but what are some of the
things you've learned with this new room
cuz I know this is your first time with
a sealed room first time was with
rolling tables I know you've been using
blue mats now for a while and you're
quite familiar with those I think I put
a picture up on our date on our
Instagram from one of your your beds a
while back in terms of the blue mat
setup but take me through some of the
fits and starts in terms of what you've
learned from from sort of this new
environment as a grower yeah one of the
first things is like
well how much tea humidification do you
need like our bigger room that you just
were up there looking at it's 1100
square foot room maybe a little under
900 square feet a canopy but there's 28
29 yards of soil in there and so if you
do typical calculations for
dehumidification it gives you a start
but I kind of had to just almost just
pick a number of dehumidifiers and try
it and I went with quest I've had great
success with him in the past they have a
really good reputation and that was one
of the challenges with sizing those guys
and did pretty good right off the bat I
can't remember I have a theory four
pints per square foot but it's not at
the top of my head right now but
basically that big thousand square foot
room has for quests 225 commercial units
but that dehumidified perfectly so what
about air flow and air movement around
your room I know you ran into some of
the challenges your first cycle with the
plants getting too big in terms of
growing more than you expected and also
getting transplanted a little late as
you're getting set up can you talk a
little bit about how you've sort of
dialed that in over the last few cycles
yeah so up until now been running
smaller rooms basements garages bedrooms
all that kind of thing and oscillating
wall fans are the standards there but
once you get into a really big room all
those oscillating wall fans they just
create a bunch of turbulence and they're
not able to effectively penetrate that
core of the room the the middle so I
took a stab at horizontal airflow HAF
which is the kind of the standard of the
greenhouse industry and it's just it's
exactly like this like it states
horizontal air flow so you're what
you're doing is you're you're creating a
vortex and you're moving all the air in
the room in kind of a cyclone and you're
just trying to move a big wall of air
not necessarily very fast you're trying
to move it all and stir it in a circle
so we got a bunch of HAF greenhouse
and I started off with just a handful of
them kind of spected out the way you
would a greenhouse and we fired it up
and it was clearly not enough and so we
kept throwing more fans at it all in a
spiral and we got it we got it moving we
got the big wall of air moving in a
cyclone there's kind of an eye to the
storm but it's pretty good but then yeah
like you were saying I came into these
rooms not you know not really knowing
how to run a real big room like this so
I came into him with a lot of plants and
pretty big plants and I raised I got the
lights up to 100% real quick
I'd really dumped in co2 on I'm trying
to really hit it out of the park but
ended up kind of breaking the bat
instead the plants all took off and got
real leggy
and you seen the rooms you know the
lighting stands at about 12 feet the bed
span is about 3 feet some of our plants
you know ripped up there and kissed the
lights and so as soon as you got as soon
as you have varying heights in a canopy
and you're trying to do horizontal
airflow
those are like mountaintops in your wind
and it just it stopped our airflow in
some areas so then I got then we got
crazy heat right where we would have a
short strain next to a tall strain we
wouldn't be able to mix the air there so
I we we got better at at getting
appropriate sized plants in there and
the right number of plants and and then
using the right amounts of co2 to not
get the rapid growth when you don't want
it and to get the rapid growth when you
do want it and that is really help that
horizontal air flow works during the
process I also learned about vertical
air flow the Vossler mandi flow fans
probably the most well-known from that
that style and it's basically a ceiling
fan that blows straight up into like a
toroid type shape so basically what it
does is it it pushes air upwards that
spirals around and and then comes back
up which helps get co2 to those
timan under the leash and I think the
[__] I'm curious to try vertical
airflow to see how it compares in the
horizontal or slow some people really
really square by it but if you can get
your canopy at the right height not too
tall and consistent the horizontal
airflow works pretty darn well and I
think that leads us into the next thing
you were maybe going to ask about with
the co2 I've been I've been using
atmospheric co2 air exchange rooms ever
since Jai and I had the house in Seattle
in 2011 so I it's kind of embarrassing
but I was going into rec without without
real deal co2 experience though I just
started dumping co2 and the rooms right
off the get-go and the plants just went
bonkers and just stretched for the light
so now what I'm doing I following the
guidelines of some other growers and one
of my partners to help me out a lot and
we ease them into the co2 now that first
three weeks we just eat them in we don't
want rapid growth in the first three
weeks we want them to root down and get
all established in the bed and I think
about the end of week three you're
seeing you're seeing little buds and you
know they're not going to stretch too
much at that point then we start giving
them the real high levels of co2 and and
do that for about three weeks and that
puts you around the end of week seven or
week seven ish and that's when we start
cutting it back for for the last two
weeks which really helps them plump up
and finish which we thought that was a
miss for a while which is funny now but
no it really works well but you know
what the big thing was and you'll find
this interesting because it involves
your soil is when you amend the soil or
even brand-new soil when you put 28
yards of it in the room and you seal it
the co2 that it produces is substantial
to say the least it is I'm pretty
amazing so I had put in an air system an
air exchange system to to specifically
deal with high nighttime co2 levels as a
way to evacuate it but I just didn't
really I'd never wrapped my head around
what our high levels and why do we want
to avoid it
all these things so I was I was having
these problems with plants just not
finishing and getting so skinny and just
really woody and big and weird I mean we
grew some amazing buds it was kind of
cool look and you saw one of those crops
but it wasn't finishing right it wasn't
getting the profile we were looking for
and everything and I was talking to Jay
about it and he told me that a lot of a
lot of people experienced what they call
night growth with high co2 levels at
night which is which is something that
you don't want and I'm not I'm not
exactly sure on the science there but as
soon as I started evacuating nighttime
co2 and getting it down like definitely
under a thousand ppm or maybe even
closer to 600 or something as soon as we
start evacuating those nighttime levels
our plants started finishing at a better
more of a proper rate and then as soon
as we lowered the levels in the first
three weeks it got rid of that crazy
high growth and then cutting the co2
back at the end allows them to send us
real nice though with learning all of
that that's made these rooms really take
off now
and not and we can predict the growth
that we're going to have and so it won't
affect our our air flow and everything
and these lights are so powerful if they
let the plants get too close to the
light it's really hard on them it's
they're just they're so hot yeah can you
throw some numbers around for co2 in
terms of ranges that you like to see
yeah well first of all like we would go
into a one of these rooms at night after
the beds are freshly turned and you'll
see 30 400 ppm co2 at night in the room
which some other growers would probably
be like oh my god dude what are you
doing but uh that that just shows you
how much co2 comes off of these beds
they're like little reactors so by by
running basically I've run air exchange
every 15 minutes I've got I've got 15
minutes on 15 minutes off of air
exchange all through every dark cycle of
these rooms and that keeps the co2
levels anywheres from 500 to 900 ppm at
night it's really hard to get the levels
low
when we first amend because they're just
producing so much co2 but that's also a
time when a little bit of excess co2 I
don't think it's so bad you really don't
want that co2 in there when they're
budding and trying to finish and then
when you do kick on the co2 what levels
are you shooting for well I'll just go
back to the bedroom dip so so
atmospheric co2
I think it's 350 parts per million or
350 to 400 somewhere in there that's
what's outside in the environment so
we'll run our bedroom at that if we're
trying to keep it low or keep it kind of
moderate growth but if we want to step
it up and get things growing faster
we'll go up to six seven hundred or
something in bed I don't I haven't gone
any higher that than that in the bedroom
because it just hasn't been necessary
and then when the plants go from veg to
flower we try to match every condition
we can as close as we can so we'll do
we'll do a similar co2 level we'll try
to get a similar amount of a light value
of our lights dimmed and everything and
humidity and temperature and and then we
will we'll go for those levels for the
first three weeks
and right now I'm six to seven hundred
parts per million of co2 you for those
first three weeks and then as soon as we
see those flowers developing then I will
step it up in two days to 1250 1300
something like that for first four three
weeks straight and then step it right
back down to about 650 something like
that and those are some levels that my
partner with a lot more co2 experience
than me gave me to work with and and it
we just we just grew to the most
beautiful crops that I've ever been a
part of and and that was a big part of
it yeah I love that you're always
learning and tweaking and figuring stuff
out as you go I think that's I think
that's the what makes a good growers is
that you're constantly improving and
learning and making changes and things
like that so that's great that's the fun
part too
if that's it's like I'm a gearhead also
and that's like the tuning alright I
feel like and and that's the part where
we really get to in
act in interface with the plants in the
room that's part of my passion in this
too is I really really like when biology
meets machine and they work together in
harmony and that's I love that about our
drones a interesting mix of everything
from creepy crawly insects and beautiful
green plants to like you know huge HVAC
systems and dehumidifiers and ducting
and industrial things and I also got a
real big kick out of us remodeling and
renovating an old egg farm you know that
was really dilapidated but we were
totally able to polish it up and make it
work and I think we impressed even the
landlord and some of our partners that
we could do what we did and what most
people saw the tear down building yeah
no it looks it looks great in there it's
it's fun to come visit when I get the
chance one other question that popped up
in my head while you were talking about
was VPD I know this is something that
you learned about and again give a lot
of credit to joy here for a lot of this
sort of as you were growing and you kind
of came up with the phrase swamp mode at
one point as you're experimenting can
you talk a little bit about what you've
kind of like figured out because I've
had like legitimate scientists come on
that have PhDs in airflow and air
movement and loud what they share is
obviously really interesting and
important and it's the basis for a lot
of information but what are you what
have you figured out just sort of you
know hands on the ground as a grower
over the years with your experience with
all of this and what VPD chard are you
using okay I'm glad you asked those
those are good questions kind of the the
way that we're all taught to grow
cannabis is humidity is your enemy and
you're just trying to keep your humidity
down you're just rammed down your head
that just drive your humidity down so
you made it - maybe causes mold just get
it down get it down get it down so I was
like oh okay well I'm pretty good at
building me their exchange rooms with a
lot of dehumidification and we can get
our humidity really low which my little
group our little group we just we didn't
think that the humidity played an
important role we didn't realize the
role that humidity might actually play
so you asked about swamp mode so it's
funny story there was I was growing my
partner Buster was growing and then Jaya
was also growing at this time this is
this is an area of our I feel some of
our greatest innovation because we all
had our little experimental rooms that
we could run independently and share
what we were finding so Jaya
he's our brain right he's all over he's
in the venues that you know about where
people talk about things and read
scientific documents and stuff so Jai is
learning all about VPD and what does he
look great for pressure deficit and
there's charts and doesn't really know
how to apply it yeah but he's like this
is the big thing this is a big deal okay
it's another acronym well meanwhile my
partner Buster who he's just the
absolute character you've met him he's
one of the only people I know who could
somehow have his exhaust system off for
his room have all of the lights on and
flood the room somehow this guy did that
so all the lights are on but the exhaust
systems off and the room is flooded so
he accidentally swamped his room okay
and so the and and so what what I call
swampy is you know it's upper 70s and
it's anything over 70% humidity in the
upper 70s that gives you that swamp
feeling like you just got off the plane
and the East Coast or maybe even Hawaii
and you hit that wall of air you can
really feel it well that's what Buster
did he accidentally he accidentally
swamped his room and got it up in the
high 70s and humidity but what he
noticed was all of the leads started
standing up people call it praying but
all the leaf started standing up really
that was firm he was like that's
probably a good thing so long story
short jaya was all was learning about
BPD online and and humidifiers and that
they had some applications we had only
heard about dehumidifiers for growing
and now we're talking about humidifiers
and then Buster is now that he's now
that he's flooded this room and seen
what the plants did now he's spraying
his wall
and spraying the floor down with water
to get the room to stay high humidity I
mean he's running his hose in front of
oscillating wall fans and letting the
water to spray across the room it was
absurd but then but meanwhile I'm mr.
powder mildew you can give me any strain
and I'll probably get powdery mildew on
it and I can Buster you know he's had
trouble getting his plants to root
really well and stuff and I was pretty
good at that so I was giving him plants
for his grow and I would often give him
these plants but by the time he got on
there covered in powder mildew and and
then they would go to his place and
within a week or so all that mule due
had turned like grayish Brown was gone
and so we started learning well I didn't
it's funny because Buster was working
for me he didn't tell me at the time
that he's doing his experiments because
I would have said dude you're crazy stop
it but meanwhile he's doing these
experiments and I started to notice I
was like hey what's going on I'm giving
you a powder Millie plants and the
powdery mildews going away and I think I
walked into one of his rooms without
telling him once and I felt the humidity
I'm like what are you doing he explained
it and claimed swamp mode we started to
put it together that by running really
high humidity we were able to get rid of
Tyler mildew which was just that blue it
was blowing our mind and meanwhile Jaya
is explaining what VPD is and how a
measure of BPD is a way to kind of talk
about what we're experiencing here with
the relationship of temperature to
humidity so now Jaya gets with
humidifiers and little you know whatever
we call them a controller for the
humidifiers and we started experimenting
with humidifiers and so over the next
couple of years we would we got some
over some big numbers some big quality
we also push the limit too and rotted
out almost entire crops running to high
humidity but this began kind of the the
journey of understanding BPD and how to
experiment with it and then eventually
now we've actually got some some
theories that we stick to yeah you would
asked about a VPD chart
I I have a have an Instagram screenshot
vijaya sent me of a VPD chart I'm not
even sure whose chart it is but it's um
it's another living soils grower we've
noticed that other living soils growers
are using VPD ranges that are right in
line with us so there there isn't
necessarily like a VPD range for
cannabis it's really kind of based on
the opinion of the grower I would say
because you see VPD charts and you're
like oh my gosh I would never do that
and then we've got this chart that were
that we're looking at right now that
really goes along with what we're
finding so I'll send you that chart that
you have it but ok it's uh it's like VPD
levels in veg I think in the upper 8 to
9 you know somewhere around there and
then flower we start to dry it out a
little bit more and the VPD level comes
up a bit like maybe a point and a little
over a point somewhere in there so I
would say that's on the wetter side of
what cannabis growers somewhat agree on
as VPD ranges for cannabis but let me
say this the when you when you give them
low VPD you get some of the some of the
most some of the fastest growth you've
ever seen but when you get into those
VPD ranges you're also you're also in
the territory that mold and mildew also
really likes so you start to find a
balance of where the plants really
healthy but also the mold and mildew
just can't really take ahold and what
I've recently discovered which once
again talking about it makes it seem
kind of like it should have been obvious
but your VPP is a relationship of
temperature to humidity so let's say
we're achieving this VPD number we want
to achieve this VPD number during the
day well if your humidity if your
temperature is dropping in your room
five six degrees at night your humidity
needs to drop an appropriate level to
achieve that same VPD so this is
something that I've discovered in the
last year here and started switching out
all my control today night controls so
we now pull the humidity down at night
in direct relationship to temperature
and that really helped that really
helped with the last little bit of
powder mildew I thought I was I thought
I had graduated powder ability master's
class here a little while back and it
came back and schooled me again and
that's when I learned about this running
lower humidity at night which is things
real obvious now but at the time it
wasn't and and now we once again are
knock on wood we are a hundred percent
powdery mildew free without you know we
don't do any sulfur burning or
vaporizing and we spray a real minimum
of sprays and you can just tell by
looking at the plant you know when
you're getting the in the VPD range that
you want to be in you just see these big
glossy dark green beautiful waxy leaves
and that's also directly related to how
dialed in your blue mat system is like
you can I can go into a room and look at
the size of the leaves and tell you
whether there's automated watering
system or not well let's talk a little
bit about blue mats since you brought it
up I know with the rolling tables you
had to be a little more creative with
your solutions there because the the
lines aren't staying still and then you
also I was just up there and I didn't
realize how much you like the protective
caps that go over the sensors for people
unfamiliar with blue mats you know I've
done a few podcasts on them already and
Ben Higgins who I just interviewed he's
working we have the results from a
recent trial on blue mats versus some
hand watering in the goldleaf facility
that we're hoping to put out soon but
what are your experiences with them and
sort of how did you design your setup
okay let me let me back it up just a
little bit so Jaya's got a grow in
seattle and i'm back up in arlington
we've we've we've already done our
communal project together an hour on our
own and i'm going to visiting his bean
and checking it out and I'm a total
stoner I'm a cannabis lover consumer to
the core and Jaya is a look not so much
little lighter weight he's just more
passionate about growing plants when
culture and organic methods and all that
so anyways I'm going to his house and
I'm looking in his basement you've got
some stuff hanging up in there I'm just
blown away the trichomes are huge and
the leaves are huge they are so
beautiful I can't grow cannabis that
looks like that and he's just all casual
and nonchalant like oh yeah I was
trained annealed very well I'm over it
and I'm just blown away it was cookies
and cream I'm just so blown away and
that that's what ultimately got me to do
blue Matt I'd already had a blue meth
system purchased and a lot of it was
built I just hadn't put it in yet I was
mainly after it just to free up my time
so I didn't have to hand water anymore I
had no idea that when you especially
with your soil when when you automate
the watering on that soil you unlock it
it's absolutely incredible so I at that
point from that point on is when I just
became a huge proponent of blue mat and
yeah and also another thing when I blue
matted my first set up and this is
pretty common had it all set up and had
some of it was over watering some of the
drippers were definitely over watering
but Jay and I noticed those were always
the biggest plants in the room so and
that's when Jaya taught me that nitrogen
is up take about when it's in solution
basically when it's in wet so if your
hand watering all the time and your
plants are drying out they're not able
to uptake those nutrients at that point
when they're dry so you're literally not
glowing and then yeah like I was saying
we would we would get these plants that
would be much bigger than the rest of
the plants when they're over watering
and that's when we started experimenting
with with with running the blue Matt's
become even wetter excuse me so the like
the blue Matt moisture probe measures an
EM bar so zero would be sitting in a cup
of water over 200 is I think that's a
wilting plant 80 to 120 m bar is
recommended for cannabis and that's
where we started but now we adjust it to
where we're down to like
forty to sixty and sometimes even a
little lower than forty and that's where
we're getting just the most rapid growth
and and helps it seems like oh wow I
didn't even know you were doing that
actually what I've seen for cannabis is
is 140 to 160 I think range they
actually liked a little dryer holy hell
oh yeah that's but you got to figure it
depends on the media too so yeah you
know that's that's a factor I so I think
for like cocoa growers and things like
that they actually wanted a little bit
dryer I don't really know cuz that's not
my my area of expertise either but I
didn't I had no idea you were getting
that wet either in those beds yeah so
moving into the big wreck farm up there
we were doing blue mat and we were
running dripper chains off of a sensor
so one sensor would would give us a zone
that was about two feet wide by maybe 16
inches long or something like that a
little down five drippers and you have
to it and yeah you have to build those
little dripper chains well setting up
the REC farm jaya told me all about the
what's it called IRRI grow the drip tape
so instead of a chain of drippers have
five dripper chain now we can run 12 and
a half feet of air broke off of one
sensor so now our zone is like god it's
almost four feet long by 2 feet wide so
we have 10 sensors in one of those big
giant beds which normally we have like
20 or something so much easier to set up
and it looks like it water's better
instead of a dripper emitting a little
circular watering mark and having five
of those now we have this big snake of
drip tape leaving a nice big wet swath
right there yeah and then yeah you
mentioned the little cap so if you're
familiar with blue mass there's a sensor
that sensor has a dial on the top of it
and that is your primary source of
adjustment that is it and those
adjustments are critical and what we
found at the REC farm was well we
discovered this a while back but it
wasn't an issue until the REC farm is
that you come in and do a big prune a
crew comes into the prune
they are likely to knock one of those
little one of those little sensors
adjusters at the top and then the next
morning show up and got a LIGO flood so
we got all the little protective caps
from blue mat I didn't know that they
made that
and we popped them on and they popped on
so aggressively that it caused often you
have to come and make little minor
adjustments to your blue mask if
someone's was set up and so we've come
in to make an adjustment and we couldn't
get a cap off the sensor so we would
totally disrupt the sensor which is not
good you want the sensor planted in the
soil and very stationary so we just took
a utility knives and we scraped off the
nubs on those little caps and that did
it that's perfect and now can we go
through we digest the whole system we
put all those caps on and with the
exception it's a minor adjustment
we're good for two months of production
there it's it's amazing and you probably
saw our bed we have them plumbed out to
a like a little one and a half gallon
bucket or something like that so we
don't have much buffer capacity for a
for a leak and I've got some of the best
flood stories I feel like of anybody
including that wreck farm I tried a new
blue mat product it was a little
quick-release thing and they blew off in
the night and I had an eight millimeter
lime dumping water in the facility all
weekend long it's the biggest blood I've
ever seen I calculated like it's like
3,000 gallons or something I got some
good videos I'll show you yeah that the
beds roll quite a bit I decide so I
mounted all the blue mat the ceiling
that's always the way I like to do it
and then you drop it down off the
ceiling I like to run the poly for all
the long runs and then run the silicon
for anywhere that we have to touch it
regularly cuz it's really nice to work
with
so all those main lines run across the
ceiling and then drop down to the bed
and then I just made I made their line
long enough that the bed could move
about four feet in each direction yeah
yeah that's great and then so you're
putting that in right after you
transplant you're flowering crop in and
you're kind of cleaning them and
and re re soaking the sensors or
refilling them right before yep
I used to be lazy and I would just take
a sensor out of one crop and throw it
right back into the room the next time
and it just doesn't work like that
they lose a little bit of water inside
of them so you really do need to clean
them out and pop them back off every
single time and if you do that
they will work perfectly every single
time and Jaya really he really did all
the ground work on the blue net figured
it out and made it super easy for me to
come in and just put it into place on a
real large system yeah and then one
other thing I wanted to touch on really
quick is your trellising your beds and
pruning them pretty aggressively at
least to maintain your canopy at a
certain height can you talk a little bit
about the the trellis process yeah a lot
of growers do staking which is very fun
I mean no matter how you're trying to
support your plants that's won't it's
very frustrating and difficult to do
because of the just the the difficulty
and the scale of it
so our beds have vertical I call them
pickets just it's a vertical post that's
designed in the bed and those are about
every every five feet and that just
helps support the trellis net and so we
on a like a shorter strain to a
medium-sized plant will do two layers of
trellis an initial layer to train them
with and kind of spread them out and
then that second layer on a trellis net
is going to support all the buds from
literally falling over and then our
taller streams we we have to put a third
row and in there but with the with the
vertical posts already there it makes it
real easy just slide the net down we
like the big grid six inch grid and we
the via cloth the woven stuff a lot of
people like the monofilament stuff we
reuse ours over and over and over we
don't cut them try not to at least and
that's huge that makes it great so the
buds are all they will grow right into
that net and they're supported all the
way to the end and so as you know the
beds roll so
sometimes you roll them and they hit
another bed kind of hard plants are all
moving around but they're all supported
in the trellis net I can come in there
with the DRAM and spray them really
aggressively and I don't have to worry
about anything falling over it works
really well
you mentioned the DRAM sprayer I know
you have a favorite you want to share
that yeah the DRAM BP 4 which is just it
means 4 gallon backpack sprayer but DRAM
make an incredible sprayer we were
turned on to it by another grower that
we met through you who's a very skilled
and he he recommended it to Vijaya and I
and we got ourselves some drams and were
so blown away I was just talking to you
earlier about it but you get the DRAM
and then you need to get this at
aftermarket Lance for it it's
telescoping and has five heads on it
that atomized the water so with that
DRAM and that telescoping Lance I mean
you could spray a fruit tree and an
orchard with it it's incredible you can
go through a room like one of mine and I
can like my big room generally takes at
least eight gallons was to spray it so
to to backpack loads and I can do it in
about probably 45 15 minutes or
something and that's moving all the beds
myself too so the DRAM with that with
that atomizing Lance you can really
effectively spray with a backpack
sprayer we experimented around with some
other what an atomizer like a stationary
atomizer
I think anybody's use one of those knows
below it Doug Fir tree over with one of
those things the DRAM was just just
right yeah and you wouldn't want to use
that for compost tea I just want to
throw that out there for listeners just
in case because that will damage the
microorganisms but for a lot of your
other sprays where you want a smaller
droplet and really good coverage that
it's a great sprayer yeah yeah you don't
want to run anything through there that
has particulates in it so those little
atomizing heads they can only they can
only take you know a pretty really small
particle yeah so I I know we haven't
even talked about legit north really as
a as a company do you want to talk a
little bit about about you guys and and
where you're where you're going to the
future anything like that yeah yeah I I
was a medical grower from from from the
very beginning right through to the very
end and I just I kept on growing I was
hoping to get into wrecks like a lot of
people but also heard a lot of horror
stories too and me personally I'm a very
accomplished builder contractor grower
but that's it and to have a rec company
and brand you need the whole you need
the whole thing you need everybody and
all these key roles so I kind of didn't
think I was gonna get into rec and long
story short one of my my main guy who
works for me one of his best friends
happened to work for who is now one of
my partners at this big machine shop
which is across the street from my house
which is funny unrelated and this guy
was a part of legit
he's one of the founders of legit or I'm
sorry he's one of the one of the owners
of legit it's the two founders are from
Oak Harbor and he basically he just put
he just put in a word with this guy and
said hey I know these guys that grow
some really amazing stuff and they're
looking to get into rec and it just so
happened that the legit team they had a
farm up in Burlington the farm that
you've been to that I know have they had
that license they had that site they had
it all secured but they weren't able to
get it going
they had to move to Raymond because just
because of laws and at the very
beginning of rec it was it was hard
getting getting local municipalities to
get you off the ground so anyways they
had this farm up there and they were
they weren't really able to use it so I
got invited in to to bring my whole
system and crew and set up in that and
the old egg farm up in Burlington there
and and they made me a full owner with
them and so it was all very
it was great the way it all the way it
all played out and the guys that it's a
it's a great group of guys there's five
of us and we're all local Northwest guys
and we are we're owner funded we run our
own Grove it's all of that right there
and these guys
I love joking and saying that I'm the
drummer of this band
I'm also the most recent person to join
with them so they already had you know a
whole brand and a whole company built
and they did it all around a pre-roll a
pre-roll joint they were they were
really unimpressed by the pre-roll on
the market and had the idea to make this
infused pre-roll but unlike a lot of
other companies they decided to make it
with premium indoor bud I mean from top
of the plant to the bottom of the plant
all the best stuff goes straight into
the joint and so that's what they were
doing when I met him and they were just
starting to gain some traction and by
the time I got the burlington farm built
the brand was really was really getting
off the ground and they were ready for
all the product that i was able to grow
up there so that marriage just came
together really really well and they've
been taking good care of me and yeah the
rest is kind of history it's a it's a
tough battle in the rec world it's
nothing like the medical babes or the
good old days it's it's all about your
team and it's kind of an endurance run
and how deep your pockets are and all
that but I'm really really happy to have
a family with these guys and they do all
the stuff that I do not know how to do
so there's another grower and there's
another farm but it's the two farms and
the wholesale team that does everything
yeah I had one last question for you
that I forgot to ask I realized and it
was around the idea of amending the soil
and soil testing so as you mentioned at
one point you'd use soil for up to seven
years by recycling it what's your what's
your current way of amending the soil
right now in terms of how how are you
are you digging out the beds are you top
dressing are you doing any sort of
fertility besides on
the blue mats there he talked a little
bit about that yeah we we used to just
kind of just throw nutrient packs at
your soil and we had just varying rates
that we felt were effective and then and
then Jaya got us using your fungal
compost and the holy mountain compost as
biological inoculant I guess you know to
keep the diversity there and we did
pretty well with that for a while but
now getting up into the rec farm and
where I can really focus and get soil
tests on every room oh sorry actually I
want to back up a little bit for a while
we were doing more of a top dressing not
necessarily top dressing we called it a
the cobbled 1/2 turn we would we would
use the same amendments which is your
nutrient pack of perlite two different
types of compost we'd mix all that in
but we would only till the bed halfway
down and we were leaving what we were
calling just a biology layer down low
and we quit doing that when we got the
root-knot nematode because because the
nematode is inside the roots any root
and leave in the bed you potentially
leave live nematode in there so we quit
doing that and we till the beds all the
way down all of it at the bottom and
yeah two types of compost and the
nutrient pack we we've been getting the
soil test and I spend them all to you
because I don't know how to look at the
photo desk and you've been recommending
different things you've cut our calcium
inputs and now our phosphorus too and
we're just we're kind of a we're trying
whatever you'll tell us we uh we're
right now our issue is our pH is high
right so we're trying to get that down
we had some success with with a sulfate
of potash
yeah the potassium sulfate was something
that was useful when you had a deficient
aciem deficiency and one of the things i
found with the the may like three tests
is that
so when you start hitting what they're
saying target range for potassium it
means you're low so you actually want to
be above that in my experience and so
what you buy you adding in the potassium
sulfate was just the fastest way to get
the potassium levels back up and I think
you commented that you saw quite a quite
a difference with that application that
you did yeah we did we really did I
didn't really know how does I just I
kind of had to guess on an amount to use
and we really lucked out because you
said according to that soil test that we
hit the level pretty appropriate but
yeah we applied that and it seemed like
a matter of days when we had a major
rapid growth but that was also at the
same time when I was dumping too much
co2 at the wrong times too so all that
rapid growth was really neat at the
beginning and then it created the
problem down the road and you tease me
about this how I'm always telling you I
got the best coffee and you don't hear
from me in it it didn't finish and got
too tall
yeah no I mean that's great I appreciate
you being sort of that guinea pig in a
lot of ways throughout the years and
helping me learn and have a facility
that I can work with hand in hand and
making these improvements and yeah you
mentioned the agricultural sulfur we're
trying to figure out how to lower your
pH a little bit right it's it's
constantly a process and you know I'm
sure some people will listen to this and
be like man what are these guys doing
because you're sharing some of the like
mistakes and vulnerabilities and things
but I think that's how we learn as a
communities is you know not everything
is a textbook and not everything is a
research lab and you kind of do have to
figure out some things in the field and
figure out what works for you and your
facility and yeah I appreciate you
sharing some of that you know it's oh
man yeah absolutely I I couldn't have
gotten to where I am without a whole
bunch of people all doing this together
and all sharing every single thing we
found you know giant and Buster and you
I mean you and Jaya I feel are the the
innovators and I'm the person who gets
the who gets the wonderful honor of
putting it into action and yeah I mean
and I want to say also like right now
our soil test the pH is really high and
things are locked out right like if you
were looking at the soil
you'd probably say oh you're having a
little trouble but then you walk into
the room and it's like holy moly so I I
can't wait to when we build another room
to get the new soil in there and to
apply everything I've learned see what
we it yeah I appreciate you being that
guinea pig and helping us figure it out
so uh thanks for that and thanks for
coming on the podcast today to kind of
just talk about your experiences it's
great to not only talk to an old friend
but also get to just share you know what
it's like in the field versus what you
see you know on paper or on the internet
and and frankly social media nowadays
everyone puts up all their best photos
and things you don't talk about it
according to the the internet no one has
ever dealt with rude a foods and fungus
gnats in the cannabis aphid and all
these other things that are just a
reality in like yeah almost every
facility or grow room I visit you know
yeah you look you learn so much when
you're having trouble you really do and
also you know I'm I'm always really
flying that flag for living soils I was
a I was a very classic typical grower
when I first heard about this compost
soil and water only soil to me it was
like yeah right and now I'm so
passionate about it mainly because I am
such a cannabis lover but when you grow
any living soils and we've got these
trace minerals and and and we've got the
soil food web it's built up as we can
and the biomes or you know diverse the
the product is incredible the the the
flavor profile the terpenes the
robustness of it just the overall health
and vitality the plant is incredible I
look forward to more and more people
using leaving soils indoors and
experimenting with them because we still
have a lot to learn and I mean we get we
get huge numbers and we get great test
scores which is I really attribute that
to the to the soils and because you only
need to add water you can use glue mat I
feel like it's that one of the most
brilliant watering systems ever created
it's so amazing it works so well it's so
consistent it's so reliable yeah look
let's get more people involved so they
can figure out how to amend it yeah and
we are and we are constantly learning
that side of things and it's funny
brought that up I just wanted one last
act out I was I was talking to a guy
yesterday out of Canada and he had a lot
of experience growing in cocoa and wants
to be organic but it's getting really
really good yields using you know an A
and B part to part with cocoa and his
small containers automated irrigation
wants more of a pharmaceutical
environment for his for his growing
operations or his facilities and we're
talking about pretty large scale here
and as we were talking I was like you
know I'm obviously a if anyone who's
listening this podcast who knows me
knows I'm an organic guy that's my
passion
you as well but it was hard for me to
try and persuade this guy that he should
switch over to living soils when he's
having the success he is looking at more
as you know a sterile environment and
something that's very easy to replicate
now yeah
with living soils yes we are saving a
lot of labor with the watering and with
the with the fact we're not moving as
much material in and out of our
facilities so it's a lot more
environmentally and sustainably friendly
but is it
I wouldn't necessarily it's easier and
there is a learning curve to it you
can't just expect that you're gonna
switch over and get the same yields that
you were growing hydro I think and you
know if you want to go multi multi level
multi tier with that I think it's really
challenging with the wait I haven't seen
anyone successfully pull it off on a
commercial scale so if you're trying to
go vertical then it may not be the best
option either so yeah it was it was fun
to talk to the guy and I hope that they
you know are open to experimenting in
fact I may try and bring him out to your
facility sometime to show him what that
looks like but it was it was just kind
of it was kind of an interesting view
because there are so many ways to grow
this plant so I don't want to just say
that these other ways don't work but
that there but rather than you know for
you and your facility this has been
really successful and I know others have
had success with it
because it it's not popular within the
within the agriculture community you
know yeah we're a huge minority yeah and
and all the other methods are known to
work and known to give consistent
product inconsistent yields and for a
really typical grower I don't want to
say the guy you're talking to the
typical grower but you know somebody who
uses very typical methods to start
talking about living soiled it's kind of
like jumping off a cliff
these guys are used to sterile rooms
there's not a single thing flying around
in there anything crawling and one of
our rooms you know we've got a whole
bunch of beneficial insects in there
we've we're encouraging this biology
where they're trying to make it sterile
so it's really a different it's getting
used to a whole nother program but the
beauty of it is is when you have when
you've got all of your predators
established and stuff you can you can
get one of these pests that will shut
down a hydroponic facility and we can
take it in stride
I'm not saying obviously that we're
foolproof you know we've got some pest
issues right now but with the living
soils you get a real big buffer because
we have all the habitats there to host a
population of beneficial that's always
there it's great and every once in a
while we'll just we'll buy some more and
throw them in to make sure they're doing
well yeah well thanks again for your
time I know you got to get he actually
have to get out over to the farm here
soon
but I appreciate you taking time to chat
and hopefully soon I can make it back up
to see him yeah and I'll probably learn
a bunch more in the next year so I'll
come back on and correct a whole bunch
of things I said all right sounds good
Justin have a wonderful rest of your day
thank you thank you go ahead
that was Justin McGill head grower and
legit farms North you were listening to
the cannabis cultivation and science
podcast
I'm your host tad hussy don't forget to
check out our website at
www.extracareanimalhospital.net