[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of kis organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and draw on
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge our
guest today is Tim we'll stir the
microbe organics some listeners may know
him better as microbe man from his
helpful posts on many internet forums
Tim is a longtime friend and colleague
who has taught me much of what I know
regarding microscopy and evaluating
compost teas I consider Tim to be one of
the foremost experts and researchers on
aerated compost teas and microbial
amendments in North America Tim also
founded WWE logical Gartner org a free
forum for gardeners as a wealth of
information
I am honored today to have him on the
show we have Tim on here today one of
the the first things I would like to
talk to Tim about would be to hear a
little bit more about your background
regarding growing cannabis in Canada you
have a pretty unique history there I'd
love to hear a little more about that
style of growing and how you did it if
we could start with that that'd be great
sure okay I guess starting back around
1995 or so is when I kind of more
seriously got into growing growing
cannabis starting with outdoors and then
slowly moved it indoors and a couple of
years after that I ended up having an
association with the BC compassion Club
Society which provides strictly
medicinal grade cannabis - at that time
it was around 1,500 to 2,000 patients
now it's way up there who knows but at
the beginning we just started out doing
basically what everybody else was doing
with the pots you know like a five
gallon pot under the high pressure
sodium lights and then
at the end of the the when we harvested
we would just dump the dirt out and use
it in the vegetable garden or something
like that and then it just started
occurring to me that this was kind of
stupid to be wasting all that so we
graduated from there to to just starting
to remix the the media as we went along
each time adding some more compost to it
and I should mention too that we had
also started out just using typical
chemical mixed fertilizers checking the
EC TPMS and and all that stuff and we
sort of had started at the same time
graduated after that when we just
started using compost and some more
natural fertilizers and and at the same
time we had been expanding our outdoor
gardens and in the outdoor gardens we
you know we didn't mix anything up every
year we just left it like a as if it was
a vegetable garden and the the plants
outside we're doing just as well if not
better than the the indoor plants so so
then I thought why don't we we just try
to move outdoors indoors and so we
pretty rapidly graduated to using bins
and I guess that would have been around
1999 or 2000 something like that the
problem being with with the bins is that
they take up so much space and you can't
move them around erm and so so then we
just got the idea of building bins which
could be stacked on top of each other
with with the lip sort of facing out so
there was a little space to get into to
to plant the young plants the Kotik
rooted cuttings into and just hung three
high pressure sodium lamps in the
in the center and have the four boxes
stacked high and I'm I guess around
seven seven stacks or something around
the lights we just stopped doing any
digging up of the soil just let it let
it be and you know at first I thought
this you know there's no way this is
gonna work but we experimented with with
one set it worked fine we just top
dressed in between harvests we would
inoculate with fermentations like IAM
fermentations and that sort of thing we
did the only prepared thing we were
using then was fish hydrolysate other
than that we just made our own own
compost keys with that system we just we
would allow the the plants just to grow
up over about ten days to 14 days then
we would just change the light to the
12-hour cycle and then start flowering
them so the the whole turnaround time
was close to 60 days sixty-four days
something like that the plants were only
18 inches tall approximately when we
harvested them but we doing it like that
we got the same yield as we were getting
before where we were going these larger
plants and over a longer period of time
and so we ended up getting actually a
higher yield that way anyway that I
don't know if I described it exactly
perfectly or anything but ask any
questions about that yes I was wondering
what size were these bins that you're
describing in and also what was your
media in the bins that you kept reusing
yeah okay so the bins were about 30 36
inches long and 14 inches deep and at
the bottom they were about
probably 10 inches wide and then whether
you sloped out to about 14 inches at the
top and making the initial mix you know
we found overtime with experience after
we started the other bins is is fairly
important we tried to have a combination
of things that stay in place for
drainage for a longer period of time you
know over the whole but the life of the
soil basically so so we use things like
fine gravel and pea gravel and that sort
of thing
for that component intuitively I I just
thought let's use as many different
colors as we can whether that make sense
scientifically who knows but just in
keeping with the human diet that
supposedly if you eat a variety of color
things you get a variety of of minerals
and nutrients so that was my idea with
that and then then of course we mixed in
stagnant peat moss and and topsoil from
outside and vermicompost that we raised
ourselves in in just in a big heap and a
barn full of worms can we talk about
that to YouTube yeah yep you have a
unique form a composting style and you
I've seen the microbial results of your
your vermicompost and it's it's always
fairly superior to pretty much
everything else I see I'd love to share
that with listeners too okay well um so
then do you think I finished off the
other the mix there satisfactory I mean
but it I know it's um my way of doing it
is quite different and and and really I
count on the the soil coming to life and
and having a life you know that's
ongoing so the the microbial population
is stay
in there and doesn't get disturbed and I
think that's really what contributes to
the success of the whole thing and I
should add to that as far as pests go
like insects that chow down on the plant
and root suckers and stuff like that we
we were really fortunate in that when we
brought in some of the topsoil and and
the vermicompost from basically outdoors
we also brought in some rolled beetles
and they they were just indigenous to
the area and they basically kept the
pests in balance it was just amazing
that that we had success that way but in
addition to that we had also we bought
some humorous and some / similes and
both of them we also had another room
where we had 18 hour late going all the
time and both of them multiplied on
their own why I don't know exactly I
didn't give them anything special to eat
or anything like that but especially the
humorous just propagated like crazy so
whenever we needed them in another room
we would just dig them up and take the
minute and move them around so and and I
should mention that the the longest time
that we had those bins going without
mixing up the soil is was 7 years and
the other ones were about 5 years and
they would they they just got
interrupted because our our contract
with questioned by the authorities and
we had to sort of shut down but with the
vermicompost we had two different
methods that we used for that one like I
said we're was just done in a big heap
in
a small barn that we had built for that
purpose and we we piled up
horse manure that we got from our field
and we usually pick out the stuff that
semi dried out and and mixed in some
sawdust and and straw sometimes but it
was almost all horse manure and with
into that we would mix some wheat brand
that was very cheap to buy it the
livestock supply store
some alfalfa meal at no greater than 5%
because I found out the hard way that if
you put too much elfelfa meal in it the
nitrates just killed worms and we also
put in some peat moss into that and that
I didn't say kelp meal yet did i kelp
meal as well so we we put in as much
kelp meal as we could afford to at the
time but it which wasn't very much
because it's a more expensive as an
ingredient and but the important part
with that is that we we left it for a
long time
so basically our worms were neglected
you know it we didn't we didn't harvest
it out on a continuous basis so my
opinion is that because the worms were
sort of forced to keep on Reed I jest
interject every little scrap they could
find instead of having new food new food
new food new food given to them they
produced a superior quality and our our
vermicompost was not typical looking
like the castings that you see in the
bags that was sort of real gooey gummy
stuff anyway and then the other the
other method is that we use the same
basically the same
greetings accept added kitchen scraps as
well and raised them in in big plastic
bins but also subjected them to you know
staying in there for a very long period
of time our method of harvesting the
worms out was to use those plastic mesh
transplant trays we would just fill them
up with the worms favorite food and
cover that over with wet newspaper and
then lay them all over at the top of the
the worm pile they would crawl up in
there and then we would just snatch them
off and then gradually throw them all
into a big bin and then come in with the
tractor and clear clean the barn out
obviously we also scooped out some of
the worms and the castings of course so
one of the things you've talked about
already was just the importance of the
microbial communities in the soil as
being the most critical factor for
allowing you to have the system where
you could go five to seven years without
disturbing the soil
could you give listeners a little
background into the microbial loop or
living soils as as you call them yeah
sure okay so first off you know with a
living soil there's uh you know microbes
live air are quickly so that there are
some microbes that have evolved to
function close to the surface of the
soil and some halfway down and some way
down at the bottom you know where there
could be rocks or whatever and so the
ones that are at the surface are the the
ones that decompose things the fastest
and scientifically it's called the that
treatise fear where detrás [ __ ] all that
branches and leaves and everything fall
on there and so they have at their
disposal all kinds of fuel you know they
can use
the oxygen which is abundant nitrogen is
abundant you know light even that some
microbes use is is there - if they need
to so that's why that's the fastest area
that things are degraded and then and
then the the altered component of what
was degraded is then passed down to the
next set of net microbes etc etc etc so
that's sort of a sort of a basis of of
why you wanna leave your soil intact and
then you know if you're outside or if
you've quit some sort of rocks or
minerals at the bottom of your soil mix
then possibly you have the the mineral
microbes that will therefore pass some
minerals up the scale instead of down
the scale the as far as the the actual
nutrient loop goes the biggest players
in that are are the the bacteria and
archaea I should take a minute to say
that our ki lump in with bacteria
because they're absolutely indiscernible
if you're looking at them with a
microscope and for many many years
we've we've thought that that it was all
bacteria that we're looking at it's only
been in you know the past twenty years
and you know getting more and more that
people are discovering that archaea are
everywhere and that maybe they are just
as or even more responsible for the
mineralization of nutrients but anyway
so I put those together bacteria and
archaea they process organic matter or
minerals and then they are consumed by
towards OA and in the protozoa group the
the two important ones in in our soil
that we're looking for flageolets and
naked amoeba and so they
they use only 10 to 40% of the energy
that they intake from eating those other
organisms and the other 90 or 260
percent is expelled in an ionic form
that's directly available to the roots
of the plants that's really an economic
thing for the plant because then it
doesn't have to expend as much energy to
to gain nutrients you know that would
take us into another topic to talk about
route exhibitions but I don't know if we
wanted to get there quite yet but I
don't know if I explain that as simply
as possible but to put it in a nutshell
the the protozoa eat eat the bacteria
and poop out I own that the that the
roots can uptake that are already you
know in a form that that is available to
them yeah no that's great I think the
way I usually explain it is when we're
putting out Miracle Grow or any kind of
you know chemical or ionic nutrient
we're directly feeding the plant that's
coming in direct contact with the roots
plant grows when we put out organic
fertilizer like alfalfa meal or kelp
meal we're not directly feeding the
plant but all this microbial interaction
is what causes these nutrients to be
changed into a form that the plant can
then uptake yeah true but that's that's
exactly what happens and and you know if
we're if we do get into this a little
bit the the bacteria archaea and fungi
that that initially degrade the the
nutrients of organic acids that they
excrete for that purpose and the the
plant roots have the exact same organic
acids that they utilize or vary
very similar anyway for to to release
nutrients as well
that's how how plants could do it
without the the organisms there to cycle
the nutrients you have some of the
nutrients which are stored in adhered to
these organic matter or clay particles
are you know stored as as we everyone
knows as cations and they have certain
net positive charges a lot of guys
talked about how you have a certain
balance of soil and along comes another
charge and lo and behold the the the
nutrients is is released from the
organic matter or the clay and is that
then available to to the root but it's
it's it's not a hundred percent that
simple or maybe it is simple but it it
also occurs from its it's caused by the
organic acids I talked about so if you
have say you have like calcium it's got
it's got a plus two positive charge so
we've learned that that it is released
by by hydrogen so if we look at you know
one of the organic acids say citric acid
which is very common it has eight
hydrogen bonds on it so if you consider
that those if you divide the two into
the eight we get four so that means that
the citric acid could release basically
four units for want of a better word of
the calcium nutrient and so these
organic acids are actually really
by the roots and by the microorganisms
it isn't something that just happens
because of having a certain mix in your
soil at least in my opinion
so do you follow what I mean or is that
too crazy so these these organic acids
that are produced both by the plant
roots as in the form of an exudate or by
these micro microbes in the soil you're
saying is what is what's essentially
making these various plant nutrients
available to the plant in an ionic form
it yeah it is actually what releases
from the where it's stuck you know the
cation exchange capacity right where
it's stuck to the organic matter or the
clay particle so that it's the trade of
the hydrogen atoms that make up that
molecular structure that actually
releases equal amount of nutrient from
the positive charge caddy on sure so so
so it's it's it's still it's the roots
of the plant and the microorganisms that
are making that happen that's why I
would say it's important in your slow
mix to have microbial microbial a active
media meaning adding in vermicompost or
having a high quality compost fraction
in there as well as a good peat moss is
a good way to increase that nutrient
cycling yeah absolutely
and like with peat moss it's got a
really high CEC so it it has a large
capacity to hold nutrients which are
then available on an ongoing basis yeah
so the plant can control what nutrients
become available
by the exudates that's feeding to the
microbial populations in the rhizosphere
as well as the organic acids it's using
to break down some of these nutrients
itself is that correct yeah basically
it's kind of um it's complex beyond
complete simplification but in in my
mind I sort of simplified it in in the
that the even though the the roots can
excrete these organic acids to get the
nutrients themselves they can also
excrete amino acids and sugars that
attract certain bacteria to them and so
then by attracting and feeding those
bacteria the the bacteria increase
vastly in population very quickly and so
that stimulates the protozoa to come out
of their cysts to exist and then they
begin dividing so as the bacteria
release the basic nutrients that we
talked about with with the excretion of
their organic acids and then the the
protozoa began feeding on them they
basically multiply the amount of
nutrient that would have been available
to begin with so so for the economy of
the plant it makes great sense that it
has released this energy in the form of
the amino acids and sugars to start
feeding these bacteria to begin with
it's it's almost like when you watch a
compost tea developing right when you
you start it up and then you feed it
some molasses or whatever food stock and
and the bacteria are the are just about
the first thing to begin multiplying and
then because of that the existence of
all those bacteria
it stimulates the protozoa to come out
of their cysts and to begin to divide as
well so it's kind of the same thing as
going on but it's in in the soil so
let's talk about this before anyone
takes this concept and starts dumping
sugar all over their other plants can
you explain a little bit more about
maybe a little bit about molasses and
different sugars and then also what
happens when you put too much and what
happens when these bacteria reproduces
too rapidly if the bacteria produce too
rapidly
you mean in in the soil or do you mean
in a compost tea I want to save compost
tea for just a second I'm talking about
just in the soil
I I'm kind of leading you to a question
but I think you're gonna get there so
what happens if we add let's just say
too much molasses into into a soil
what's gonna what's going to occur I'm
not really sure you know I can't say and
I don't I don't know what too much is
but I'm too much of anything is not good
and so I would I would just guess that
if you put too much molasses in there
you'll get an overabundance of bacteria
and they may end up eating everything in
sight it depends on what you have in the
soil to begin with you know because
molasses is a food for fungi as well as
bacteria so it does make some sense to
to just apply some diluted molasses
occasionally to to soil they use
molasses I don't know if you know about
this but if there's um like an oil spill
out in a wilderness area they they pour
diluted molasses into the soil to
stimulate the the bacterial population
that will consume the oil I didn't know
that yeah what I was getting at is you
have the potential for the the bacteria
to wrap to multiply so rapidly that they
could actually create
temperature increase in the soil around
the root zone which could cause the
plants to suffer or that the bacteria
could be more efficient and accessing
that food source to where it could pull
nitrogen and other nutrients from what
the plant could access yeah that that's
a possibility for sure that's kind of
what I was I was trying to get at just
caution listeners yeah well you caution
with everything the same thing can
happen if you if you put mix like
woodchips or something
into your soil ones which ships that are
not composted or aged the same thing can
happen the the bacteria and maybe fungi
will use up all of the available
nitrogen in an effort to to degrade that
those wood chips and so then they they
lock it away from the plant that's why I
don't like the idea of of burying things
down in the soil for the the plant to
come upon sometime in the future or
whatever because that that's always a
possibility for that to occur if you put
some sort of raw organic matter down
there that that is not stable are you
talking about Hugo culture beds are you
talking about the layers that I've heard
some of the like the revit recommended
with the true living organics Oh some
some yeah the the layers sort of thing
the spikes um some guys say that they
they have great success if they put a
dead animal at the bottom of the pit
before they plant and stuff and and
sometimes that works out great you know
it's just it almost seems like it's
happenstance that sometimes there's a
lock-up and sometimes there isn't I've
been caught for sure with my pants down
with that one by by mixing stuff in too
soon okay so let's
change direction a little bit here and
talk a little about soil testing so I
know that certain groups like in the
past I've heard some people claim that
if that all the nutrients we need are
already in soils we just need to add the
right microbial populations
they'll make these nutrients available
well there's other groups that will say
hey if we get the right mineral content
and balanced in the soil and everything
is you know the soil is mineral e
balanced then these microbes are just
gonna appear and start reproducing and
then we'll have optimal soils can you
give me your sort of taken experience on
all of this well I don't think that that
every soil everywhere will produce
whatever you need just because it has a
good microbial population there may be
certain soils in some areas that you can
say that about I'm in the the group or
maybe by myself where I think it's
important to include as many diverse
nutrient components as you can within
reason and and that that's why you know
we we used you know so many different
things in our soil mixes like the
different we would Cakes stone from one
area and and use the vermicompost and
that sort of thing and that's what I
think is is necessary I haven't bought
into the whole balanced soil thing
because the way I've been looking at at
the way that plants and microorganisms
work together to acquire the necessary
nutrients sort of goes against that in
in my mind because I think what you're
saying when you say if you have a
balanced soil and then all of the it'll
it'll cause this to release that and
this will be available instead of being
locked up and it sort of goes against
the plant being sort of having an
influence over its environment
and as if it's just something that's
being held up and sucking up nutrients
whereas I I think it really does work
kind of the way I described that the the
plant is working in concert with the
microorganisms and the organic materials
that are around it and those can be you
know organic matter can be compost
vermicompost powdered rock minerals clay
powders whatever which so that's why I
like to put you know within reason as
much as I can but but balance it as far
as the soil being able to breathe and
drain and that sort of thing at the same
time I hope I answered your question a
lot you did and you didn't so the
physical properties of the soil totally
agree with in terms of the amount of
porosity drain inch aeration when we
talk about a soil though let's say you
have a soil that is deficient in calcium
that that calcium has to come from
somewhere yeah absolutely
so there is something to balancing the
soil and saying hey I just did a soil
test this is obviously low in calcium I
need to raise my calcium levels up to X
whatever that level is that you want to
set it at I totally agree with you in
terms of the fact that mineral balancing
is just certain people's best guess
whether it's you know Kinsey Solomon
you know Michaelis Terra all of these
guys are just you know carry reams
they're trying to guess at what they
think is optimal for plant health for
various crops but we don't we don't know
there just hasn't been enough research
it seems like to me on in that regard
yeah well so I I haven't said that you
shouldn't have calcium or you shouldn't
have all of the components possible what
I am saying is that they they should be
there but they don't necessarily have to
be there
in in the certain ratios that someone
has delineated sure yeah that's that's
all so and sure you could end up with
some soil that's deficient in calcium
and then sure you need to add some
component and it's going to supply the
calcium absolutely
so you're saying don't get too caught up
or freak out if your potassium is not at
three to five percent of your CEC or
your your calcium is not sixty to
seventy percent and all of that sort of
thing yeah right but that's what I mean
yes
whether I'm I can't say that I'm a
hundred percent right but that's that's
how I grew but definitely you you know
you try to include everything that you
can and and it all depends on an
individual circumstances some people can
afford to send a way to Timbuktu for
whatever ingredient right others like
where we were we were on a farm ninety
miles away from the closest town and so
we used what was at hand
and and made what we could make lucky I
guess we we did have all of the
necessary components existent in the
materials that were around the area we
talked a little bit about soils and you
talked about the importance of these
microbial communities in this soil the
way I met you was actually through a
discussion board hosted by Jeff flow in
Fell's on aerated compost teas and I
consider you one of the foremost experts
on the continent when it comes to this
subject so I would love to kind of dive
in a little bit to that if you have time
right now to discuss a little bit more
about what aerated compost teas are what
they are not and what you what you would
recommend for people that are just
starting out in using compost teas
okay so what is aerated compost tea it's
basically a water base that's got air
being pumped into it and house and it's
being agitated and compost is added and
the agitation extracts the
microorganisms that are existing in the
compost or vermicompost and a food
source is provided that feeds the
bacteria archaea and fungi that are
existent in your compost and as they
multiply that stimulates as I said
before the protozoa to come out of their
cysts and begin to divide and multiply
as well so over a period of time the
population expands and reaches a sort of
an approximate ratio where you have lots
of but you can see if you use a
microscope lots of bacteria and and
protozoa the protozoa
are eating the bacteria so that's when
the nutrient cycling is occurring and
it's at its peak and if so that's your
purpose for using the compost tea that
is the time to apply it now what's the
window when that generally occurs for me
36 hours is pretty safe if you have if
you're not using a microscope that's a
good time people talk about different
recipes and making a fungal tea opposed
to a bacterial tea and anyway it doesn't
really work that way as far as recipe
goes all the way you can have some
influence with the recipe it's more the
timing so obviously if you want to have
straight bacteria
in a tea it's it's going to be in the
first probably 12 hours that you want to
use it however if you do have fungi in
there in your compost it's going to be
growing at that time as well so yeah I i
I've never successfully managed to have
a compost teeny that was either fungal
with no bacteria or bacteria with no
fungal if they both exist in in the the
compost use they they pretty much grow
at the same rate at least in in what
I've done so so if if that's what you
want then you want to probably use it
between 12 and 18 hours but it's it
after 24 hours is usually when the
protozoa reach their their peak or come
start multiplying I should say and reach
their peak at 36 hours and so if you
want a nutrient cycling that's that's
when you use it as far as methods of
making compost tea we made everything we
made everything from you know one liter
Brewers up to 1,200 gallons we had
straight air stones we we had you know
others that were copies of what other
people had made with the air going down
a cylinder that had the compost in it we
used Venturi's which are made with water
pumps and air lifts and air lifts are
the most successful way of doing it
first for sure
as far as agitation and as far as
dissolved oxygen
you know there's mathematical papers
that illustrate an airlift can up the
the dissolved oxygen capacity tenfold
from from an air pump that's just
blowing into air stones anyway
should I get sidetracked there and
forget what I was saying or what no I
think that's I think that's interesting
and I just want to I want to reiterate
that when Tim says that he's tried all
these Brewers you're also you've also
looked at them under a microscope and
you spent hours and hours in your
laboratory it's not a matter of you just
looking at a bucket of brown water and
saying oh this looks good or throwing it
on a plant you're actually spending time
looking on slide after slide and
examining all of these teas yeah we took
the pH and the TDS and everything every
single brew I've got several notebooks
still full of all of the notes from
there and took the dissolved oxygen
readings of course and temperature the
whole works I want to back up just a
little bit one thing you were talking
about with this bacterial dominated or
fungally dominated teas i would just
want to make it clear when we talk about
a tea that's fungally dominated they're
still going to be a ton of bacteria it's
not like that like you mentioned briefly
but the bacteria is not going away and
vice versa and it's really the brewing
length that controls that more more than
the recipe right absolutely
great so I just wanted to clarify that
and then let's talk a little bit about
what happens when you brew perpetually
or you brew longer than 36 hours because
I know this is something that certain
companies in the industry are promoting
that you and I feel rather strongly
about already so let's talk about what
happens on a microscopic level well if
once you go beyond 48 hours is pretty
much a maximum before the ciliates
usually at cilia start taking over the
whole thing it sometimes it's the
flageolets but in my most of my
experience cilia start coming into play
ciliates
are the larger protozoa that are
sometimes an indication
that there are some anaerobic bacteria
in the picture because that's their
favorite food like if you go up to 72
hours or even beyond that you just end
up with a ciliate soup I've got some
video footage that you know I don't know
if I ever showed it to you but it would
it blows my mind it's just like the
whole slide is just teeming teeming
ciliates it's just amazing if there's
someone who has perpetual breuer going
in in a store and then selling tea to
customers I mean that's possible to do
but every 36 to 48 hours
you really should reconstitute it and so
that means put in some more compost and
put in some more feedstock but what
happens is that once you do that you're
gonna have to wait for you know 24 hours
for it to basically go through the whole
cycle that it goes through to come back
to being a useful product again so if
you're if you're a perpetual Brewer and
you're selling tea you know pity the
customer that comes in after you've just
added new stuff to your brew they're
gonna get something that the dissolved
oxygen hasn't had a chance to build up
and the microorganisms haven't been
properly extracted or multiplied they're
gonna get a totally different product
from the customer who gets it at 36
hours
so that's what's wrong with perpetual
brewing if you're doing it for yourself
at home and keeping track and you have a
microscope or even you just want to
experiment you know go for it but if
you're selling it to somebody that's
that's just not very kosher you bring up
a good point though I found it was very
challenging to try and maintain good
Caribbean diversity and biomass even
when adding food stock and using a
microscope beyond you know 48 hours so
when we were doing those trade shows
together for example where we had the
microscope when we had a brew going and
we would pull samples and add food stock
and try and maintain the brew even with
a microscope and looking at the samples
every I don't know 15 20 minutes it was
still very challenging to maintain that
compost tea and I didn't really feel
like we did all that effectively yeah no
no it wasn't very good no you're right
yep so I totally agree with you that's
why when we brew and at our farm we will
just tell customers compost tea is
available on Saturdays and that's when
they can come in it'll be brewing
throughout that day they can get us they
can get get something to take home and
then we'll shut it down discard whatever
we have and start over again for another
day sort of thing
yeah that's the way to do it so some
some Brewers are putting there they're
saying they can put compost tea in the
fridge have you have you heard of that
one there's a company oh yeah yeah
there's all kinds of stuff on YouTube
these days so I just want to say that
that doesn't really work very well
either I don't know what your if you've
experimented with refrigeration or any
of that sort of thing yourself yeah we
we did put some in the fridge when we
were doing all of our experiments and
stuff and it it wasn't worth a damn the
the microbes basically just die or go
dormant and they don't come back again
unless you you know you might get them
back again if you add it into a compost
tea and brew it over again when we did
have to store some tea we did it with
removing removing the the compost
because we it was in a case where we had
it in a bag so we could remove it and
and then aerate it and the longest I
kept it that way was over a period of
three days constantly aerating it and
even then it you know slowly degenerated
in what you say
about putting it in the bottle you know
that make reminds me about you know when
people send a sample to to get tested
the whole thing is going to change
during the shipment so by the time it's
tested if if you're trying to say well
this sample was taken at 12 or 36 or 40
hours by the time it's looked at at the
lab it's not gonna be that time anymore
it's gonna be 50 hours or however long
it took to get there and it will have
transformed I don't know if I should say
this but I had a client who was in a
bind that he had a customer a big
customer for landscaping landscaping
deal who insisted that he would not
contract with him unless he had a good
test result from a lab so he asked me
what what he should do and so I said
well just brew for eight hours put it in
the bottle and ship it and by the time
it gets there it'll be good and so
that's what he did and it was perfect
and he got really great test results and
got the contract yeah I think that is a
challenging aspect with the whole idea
of testing and it's really expensive and
I like to point out to people who are
doing those types of tests that not only
does it have the challenges that you
just listed but you change one thing
about your brew that snapshot really
doesn't allow us to make useful
decisions in the field in terms of how
to improve our compost teas in my
opinion and that's why I think having a
microscope is so useful if you if you
really want to get into that aspect of
growing one thing I do want to bring up
that you kind of hinted that there is I
don't want to discourage growers from
experimenting with compost teas and
trying them out on their plants and it's
really hard it's really hard to truly
screw up yeah
it's very difficult to make a bad
compost gene yes I tried the adage of of
having an anaerobic stinky tea and
jumping it on a plant that I want to
kill and the plant actually loved it so
anyway one thing I wanted to bring up is
is recipes that's something else I've
sort of learned in my old age is that
I've seemed to get just as good results
from just using vermicompost with
molasses and you know I do have the
recipes that are on my webpage that a
lot of people just they say that's what
they use they stand by it it's great and
all that but you know all power to them
and and if they like it stick with it
but but for me I found that I stopped
including all of the things like rock
phosphate and kelp meal and and fish
hydrolysate and just stuck with the
molasses and and vermicompost and got
exactly the same microbial population
growing in in there so sure yeah we use
a product that we call our microbe
catalyst with ours as a food source not
because there's anything wrong with
molasses but just because it's a dried
granule and molasses is hard for us to
package and ship but when I owe a lot of
my microscope testing I actually used
molasses and you showed me that and I I
will say I do really like to use organic
alfalfa meal in addition to molasses and
vermicompost as part of your recipe when
I use your recipe but just the molasses
in vermicompost works really really well
- yeah well molasses has got a bad rap
somehow well I I think it all started
with some testing that was done in two
different labs one was a USDA lab
another was Canadian agricultural lab
and they they were you know trying to
show that ecoli would grow in aerated
compost tea and they I can't remember
exactly but I think both of them had
some sort of setup where they were using
jars with air stones which is okay you
know just for experimental purposes but
they they also in inoculated both both
labs inoculated with e.coli and so if
you put a coli into an aerated liquid
water and and give it food like molasses
of course it's gonna grow you know 13 um
any any kind of bacteria is is going to
grow so that that's what I thought was
very flawed with it and and it actually
you know within the in people's minds
became so serious that I I think it was
uh what what's the organic branch of the
USDA called the NOP yeah when they had
the compost tea councils part of that
and and they because of those lab
results they said you shouldn't use
molasses in in compost tea out of all
this fear-mongering about ecoli growing
and so it just that a lot of people are
saying never use it because of that and
it's just uh in my mind just a kind of a
silly knee-jerk reaction and and as you
know you know it it it feeds fungi just
as well as it does bacteria so it's it's
a very useful food stock to use yeah I
would say that's one of the the myths
that you sort of help dispel or
challenge over the last decade
another one is foaming I know when I
first got in the industry everyone was
talking about how you need to have a
good head of foam on your compost tea
like it was a beer or something you were
able to show from looking under the
microscope that that really wasn't the
case yeah well both things are still
rapidly running going by rumor
everywhere and it can't Lee I have to
keep repeating that but it doesn't
necessarily mean anything but I don't
want to keep you for too much longer
here Tim really appreciate you taking
the time today and maybe we can do a
follow-up interview to kind of hash out
some more of these topics here in the
future thanks Tim don't forget to check
out Tim's website WWE COO of organics
com more information microscope videos
and images he is the inventor of the 50
gallon microbe you later and the 5
gallon mini microbe you later both
currently available on our website he
also has a microbe identification DVD
that helps farmers and identifying
various microbes under the microscope
available on his website for only $40
this DVD was very helpful to me because
the microbes don't hold still on the
slide so it is much more useful to see
video than still images you can also
read more about Tim's theories and
research regarding root exudates at wwg
cool card Norg a free forum hosted by
Tim and myself you are listening to the
cannabis cultivation and science podcast
I'm your host Todd Hussey stay tuned for
future podcasts from leading experts
around the industry don't forget that
there's more information articles
available on our website and blog at WWE
Scott and if you enjoy these podcasts
please take a moment to leave me a
review on iTunes and send me your
feedback and suggestions through our
website contact page
you