[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
i'm your host tadd hussey of kiss
organics this is the podcast where we
discuss the cutting edge of growing from
a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge
our guest this week is my good friend
suzanne wainwright evans
also known by many as the bug lady she
is an ornamental entomologist
specializing in integrated pest
management suzanne has been involved in
the green industry for more than
25 years with a primary focus on
biological control and using pesticides
properly
she is a graduate of the university of
florida with degrees in both entomology
and environmental horticulture
she has worked throughout the united
states and internationally consulting to
greenhouses
nurseries landscapers and interior
escape companies
she is the owner of bug lady consulting
now in business for over 21 years
now on to the show
hey suzanne welcome back to the show hey
i'm super excited to be here
i love chatting with you and i love all
your peeps
yeah no i'm i'm excited too and i think
we have some wonderful topics to go over
for today starting off with talking
about
some new products and innovations that
have happened in biocontrols
since the last time you're on the show
yeah there's some really new exciting
things happening and it's not
often that we get new products and bio
control because the bio control industry
and right now we're going to talk more
about macrobio controls
which are your mites insects and
nematodes they are
heavily regulated by the usda you cannot
just rear bugs and ship them around
so we typically don't get actually
new species of beneficials which you
know we don't have any new beneficials
at this time but what we have is new
technologies
for the current beneficials that we have
and there's this new product um
for applying nematodes which i'm super
excited about it's it's still
really really really new it's actually a
product out of
germany and the manufacturer is a
company called
e nema don't say that too fast
because you'll say the wrong word um but
e nema um has been making nematodes in
germany for quite a long time
and they were trying to find a new
application methods for nematodes
right now when we apply nematodes we
generally drench them or sprint them
across the soil surface and then they
settle into that top portion of the soil
and they're really good right now for
especially
fungus gnat larvae western flower thrips
onion thrips pupae which are down in the
soil
which is fine because those are right on
the top of the surface there
the question is how do we manage pests
that are
lower in the pot and
what they have come up with is basically
a slow
release nematode system and actually
when you look at the product it looks
like small tapioca pearls that you've
soaked in water
overnight it's these little balls and
they're kind of spongy when you touch
them
but in each one of these small balls
there's about
1600 nematodes and
the the idea is you take this product
and then you pre-incorporate it into
your
media so that then you'll have nematodes
completely homogeneously mixed through
your soil
and it can stand up to the soil mixing
process
and then over a series of several weeks
you have nematodes
slowly releasing out all the way through
your media
so that again you have better
distribution of nematodes
as well as uh
higher numbers in the soil because of
the ability to slow release and to come
out of these little pearls
that they're in and the pearls are
very safe it's not any crazy chemicals
that you're going to find they're
basically made of water sunflower oil
there's some calcium chloride emulsifier
and there's sodium alginate in there so
you know they're all things that
that are not going to be toxic to your
soil and
it's a really interesting novel way uh
to apply nematodes again it's brand new
to the market
um the distributor for them is going to
be bio
b uh which many people already know
because bio b
is in a large uh infectory in israel but
they also
sell here into the united states and so
again they're going to be
distributing this product
yeah i'm looking at it right now on the
website here they do like look like
little tapioca pearls
this would be nice for reasons of if you
had a pot
with drain holes on the bottom i assume
you're more likely to get any fungus
gnat larvae that are
in you know infecting those areas is
that kind of what you're
you're thinking one of the things i'm
looking i think it will be interesting
to go back
and please do not run out people and say
nematodes control root aphids
in a petri dish we know nematodes can
get
inside of a root aphid but they've never
worked
in a growing situation where you just
apply nematodes
and the nematodes infect the root aphids
and control them
mainly because your root aphids are too
deep into the pot because again most
nematode drenches are right on the soil
surface
i think it will be interesting to look
at if
incorporating nematodes can help with
suppression
of root aphids i'm not saying it's going
to work but these are the things we have
to trial
look at and test and maybe even you know
a combo program
of an intimal pathogen pre-incorporated
with you know the nematodes to see if we
can you know go after them for multiple
approaches
so again this is brand new we still have
to do a lot of testing
the other thing that i'm interested in
about this is for the small home grow
because if you um
most nematodes come in larger packaging
and once you open the package you really
have to use
all of it you don't want to store
nematodes if these
would come in a cup and could be stored
in the refrigerator for you know a
several week period which from my
understanding from them they can be
you could open your container and again
if you only have three or four plants
and you want to apply nematodes to the
soil surface or even
dibble holes in your soil surface drop
some of these in there and
cover them you could do multiple of
applications of nematodes
through the crop cycle where
traditionally when you buy the images
you have to buy them and apply them
and it can get very expensive to buy
these large packagings of nematodes and
use them all up
this way you could do small applications
of them because there is research done
showing that low-dose regular
applications and nematodes work better
on fungus nests and coming in
really heavy and then going without an
application and going in really heavy
slow low doses are better
can you back up a moment and talk about
uh what
what specific nematodes one would want
to apply
i mean i think you're talking about sf
nematodes here but
um if you could kind of explain that and
i'm not even trying to pronounce them
i'll let you handle the pronunciations
but
i don't want people to think that like
they can just go online and google
nematodes and think that they're going
to have
you know i know it's specific to a given
pest so
well and and there is some crossover so
the main three nematodes that we work
with currently
in the u.s are synonymous lta and that's
i mean that's the majority of the market
mainly because in
research it is shown that performs best
for fungus net management and for
western flower thrips pupa in the soil
there's also a bacteriophora
which um is also used but a much smaller
percent and then carpo capsai
bacteria four is typically used more for
beetle grubs
but bacteriophores still can infect
like fly larva but it's not the best at
it
and carpo capsai is used a bit more for
things like cutworms
it also can work on flea
larvae in the soil outside
but that doesn't mean that other
nematodes
there's lots of crossover but the
research basically picks the one that
works
the best again it's not like
bacteriophorum carpal capsule
won't do anything for fungus management
it's just
celtia's been the best and there really
hasn't
um been a lot of looking at the
different species and nematodes
for potential for root aphid because
again of the problem
rudy says go really deep down on the pot
and the nematodes just aren't reaching
down to where the nematodes are when
they're just top dressed
so this new form of application could
potentially
if research plays out show better
root aphid suppression possibly yes and
i still think i still think you're going
to
need to do it in conjunction with again
a microbial product of a very
is something along those lines but since
we
don't have you know a magic bullet at
this
point for root aphids we need to use all
the tools possible
and this may have potential for that
again the product is is
they just basically launched this
product at the cultivate show
two weeks ago so it's going to be a
while before we have some u.s
trials done i do know
the research entomologist dr steven
authors who's a good friend of mine
who works at bio b is
doing trials with this product
so we should be hearing some stuff later
this year
potentially but i definitely think it's
something worth
looking at and testing pricing i am sure
this is going to be more expensive
than just regular conventional nematodes
but
if it's a situation where
you can incorporate this and then you
don't have to apply again
for x amount of weeks where you're
normally applying nematodes weekly
it could be a labor cost savings but
that only comes in if you're a larger
grower or in a larger facility
again if you're a home grow four or five
plants it's not going to be
you know that much of a cost savings
because your labor is not that intensive
yeah i look forward to learning more
about this that's really exciting
um yeah oh and and the they
then you both the product i believe
right now is standing in a philty but
they do
have the potential to do uh bacteria for
or carpal capsule
in this technology too
cool cool well i look forward to seeing
uh seeing where that goes here in the us
as it becomes more available
yeah me too uh all right so what else
is going on in the biocontrol world
so if any of you have spent time with me
over the last bajillion years my
favorite predatory might of all time is
persimilis
i love persimilis i if i was a tattoo
person
i would have a persimmons on me but i'm
a needle weenie so that's not gonna
happen
so um that's why i keep telling for
those of you that know
kelly vance at beneficial inspector you
know he's got like an insect sleeve
i keep telling him those are my tattoos
on his body because
i just well i could too uh i struggled
getting my ears pierced a second time
and now i completely regret it
because i'm just such i just don't do
needles but
persimmonless is absolutely amazing for
those that aren't familiar
for semelis is a predatory mite it's a
tropical species
and what it's known for is feeding on
two-spot spider mite
it's really got one job and that's what
it does
so it's been used really heavily in
greenhouse vegetable production through
the decades it's been used
very heavily in strawberry production
especially in california
there's a lot of persimmon production in
california for that very reason
to meet the demands of the uh strawberry
producers out there
but several decades ago um that's this
was the first
commercial beneficial i worked with in
the 90s
was persimmonless and using it in
tropical foliage for spider rank
management
it works amazing you put it out
if there's spider mite eggs immatures or
adults
it eats them but if there's no food
source they die
so it's kind of a double-edged sword i
don't know if that's
uh right but if you are
let's say a landscape kind of person or
a vegetable producer
you kind of want your predators to hang
around
and and have them on the plants if you
are growing
for ornamental purposes you're good with
your beneficials dying because
you do not want to send any plants to
market with anything moving on them
so the palm growers are okay with all
the beneficials dying off
because even though they're beneficial
most people cannot determine if
something is a beneficial a pest
or indifferent which most things you see
are completely indifferent and benign
um to uh from an agricultural context
um so you would release them they'd pass
away
of starvation because they everything up
so typically on a persimmonless program
you're releasing about every two
weeks well bio b in israel
um has come up with a new
rearing system for them normally how you
rear persimilis
is you have to grow a ton of spider
mites
and then once you have a ton of spider
mites then you go sprinkle some
persimmonlus out there
and then the persimilis multiply and
multiply and multiply and then when
your whole population is almost
persimilis you harvest them
you put them in bottles if you're a poor
spider mite that survived
and you're in that bottle with ten
thousand percent list you're not even
going to make it very long because
they're going to eat you up
and you get the product and then you
release it
what bio-b has discovered is that they
can
raise these predatory mites
on essentially
the egg of another mite species called
carpoglyphus
and it can reproduce off of it
so basically instead of having to raise
all these spider mice which have to be
raised on plant material but
carpalglyphus
they don't have to raise on plant
material they harvest their eggs
and then basically the eggs are like
little protein bars and they just feed
them to the persimilis
so it's a more efficient way of raising
them
and with that technology what they're
able to do
is then take sachets which
sachets that are used for other mite
systems are very different than these
i'll
talk about that in a second but they put
these carpal glyphos eggs
or dead mite eggs in a sachet
and so basically you've just set up a
sachet with a pile of protein bars in
there you put some persimilis in there
and then they've got two kinds of
persimilis
they have what's called the the speed
release product
which they say um if you just put that
out it just has persimmons in there in
about five days all the persimilis climb
out
so basically it's it's a speed speedy
release to get them on
but if you get what they call the uh
with it the brand is percy plus
but if you get the classic percy plus
sachets
right now they think one of those
sachets will release about 300 mites
oh up to about 12 days so you're getting
almost two weeks of release
those of you that are used to working
with cucumaris and swarsky sachet you
know those last four to six weeks
that's because in those you actually
have a breeding system you've got
mites in there that are breeding that
are feeding on fungus that's growing on
brands so it's self-sustaining and these
systems
they just put the the dead mite eggs in
there and so
there's no mice to be breeding in there
so when they run
out of the mite eggs
your breeding system's over but it still
can give you two weeks of release
and this can be important for crops
that you do not want carrier on and you
know cannabis is
one um anything that's got those
trichomes you don't want to see that
carrier stuck all over the plant
and even you know like a petunia and
calibrachoa crops
you know things like that where you have
the heavy trichomes on them and if those
are going to go to retail you don't want
to see carrier sprinkled all over it
so this is going to give you that option
for that now this persimilis you can buy
in bottle form 2 not just the sachets
but when you open the bottle and you
look in you're gonna be like what
these are persimmonless and if you've
attended in my workshops i've said it a
million times
you cannot use color solely as
identification because we have different
color morphs
insects and mites colors can be slightly
different depending on their food source
and this percy plus when it's reared
on these mite eggs the persimilis are
clear
they're almost like a milky creamy color
they are not red
and if you ask anybody what colors are
prosomalis they're going to be like oh
they're bright reddish orange
when they're red on this set on this
different diet they look completely
different they're the first time i saw
him it was like
totally freaky um because it's just i'm
so not used to seeing persimilis
like transparently creamy color
what's interesting though is once they
start to feed
on spider mites then they'll turn
their red colors so there is a little
potential here that these could be a
diagnostic
scouting tool that if you put out all
these clear colored mites
and then you start seeing them turning
red they're finding spider mites
somewhere in your crop
um so beware that there's a lot you have
to understand about using
the percy plus persimilis over
conventional persimmons
the other thing you have to be aware of
is
when you buy conventional persimilis
which again amazing products out there
um when you buy them and they're in the
bottle there has been no food in there
when you buy the red traditional
persimilis so when you release them
they are hungry it's like if you know
you were locked in a room for two days
fasting when you get out man you're
gonna be ready to eat
so when you release the traditional red
persimilis
and i watched this i i'm sure some of
you heard me talk about i
over my cove invocation i had for a year
sitting at home
i raised a lot of spider mites and when
i released the traditional red
persimilis on there
man they are right on it because they're
so hungry they go
right after the different life stages
and they just tear up the persimmons
when i release the percy plus they're
like oh yeah look there's spider mites
over there let me just saunter around
and kind of get settled in
because since they've got food in the
bottle and the sachet
they don't come out of the bottle
starving
so um that's not necessarily a bad thing
because if you have a very very low
spider-man pressure or you're doing it
as a preventative
if you can release these pre-fed mites
and you're going to be releasing
all life stages in those you're going to
they're going to live longer on your
plant so they can cruise around looking
for mites longer
the red persimmons you get those are all
adults you're getting
but they're going to be starving so the
way at this point i kind of see it and
and things may change
you know as we use them more in growing
facilities but if you have a current
mite problem
you've you've suppressed it with a knock
down spray but you still man we've got
mice up there
i would definitely at this point go with
the more traditional persimilis
but if you're being preventative um and
lots of my growers are man they're just
putting persimmons out every two weeks
it's that basically do not have a spider
mite problem this percy plus may be a
better way to go
because they're going to live longer on
your plants because of becoming pre-fed
yeah that makes sense um so when you say
doesn't have a problem does that mean
they aren't spotting any spider mites in
their grow or they might only see like a
few
in a given area like if you
walk around yeah very low pressure
thing is is with my ornamental growers
in florida
there is no such thing almost as low
pressure down there
you know because when you're outside
growing you you
it's extremely warm you don't have a
winter freeze
that's where you have just such intense
pressure you know some of those guys in
florida you know they could be spraying
for spider mites every three days
where they typically are releasing every
two weeks for some of us but
if you're an indoor grow you don't have
a history of spider mites
you know your pressure is going to be so
much lower
down there or up there or over there
wherever you are
that this may be a better choice for you
but if you've gotten spider mites into
your facility
by bringing in cuts or an employee
clothing or
you know somebody did something you know
um and you've got a problem you know the
regular persimil is probably the better
way to go
but again talk to me in six months
because this might
change you know that's the one thing
about bio control
stuff i said even three to four years
ago we know more now and it's not true
anymore
and you know that's why we've got this
concept we need to keep learning
and trialing and testing and and push
ourselves
so that we can improve these programs
and get smarter
yeah i mean that makes a lot of sense
and i know you have some exciting stuff
uh hopefully coming down the line too
that's not quite at
this stage you know there's always
things innovation happening so that's uh
that's wonderful to hear
yeah no it's great to see it here i mean
for me i mean well i get excited almost
over any bug thing but
to have like this handful of new stuff
this year it's
it's really exciting um to have new
innovations and new ways to solve
growers problems
um you know so and i'm happy to see
because
you know biobee's been very forward
thinking um
and uh they have some really uh cool
products that
and one of the things which i posted
about on social media if you saw
they basically made pokemon cards for
all the bio-control agents
which you know i love stuff like that
man
i went at the hemp show man i was right
there and i'll take one
one one one and i snagged myself an
entire deck of them and i was out of
there there was no way
i was not getting a stack of them and i
talked about them at the show
and then bio b got back to me and
they're like oh my god after you talk
they said their booth was like rushed
because
everybody was down there trying to get
these cards and they gave
every card away they had and now they're
getting a request for them
but i think it's a great idea because
it's a quick reference card
on the beneficials you know quick
temperature how do you release and
things you need to know
and again it's really cool like in a
pokemon format
yeah no that's that's fine i this is
totally off topic but i was just talking
with uh
ben the other day about how all the
stuff that we saved as kids that we
thought would be worth something someday
uh like baseball cards are not worth
anything and all the stuff that
no one really saved like pokemon cards i
guess
are worth thousands of dollars so go
figure
you never know well i look at it as
if it was sold to be a collectible then
nobody played with it and so there's
lots of it
if it was sold to be played with and
then the kids all destroyed it
that's what the valuable stuff is
because not many of them exist
very true very true um well i want to
talk about methods of release but is
there any other
like new products or innovation you want
to cover before we get into that
yes and after i told you i would be
short about all this stuff i'm trying to
add
some kind of that's fine um
so banker plants you know the
this is more of a regular practice and
vegetable and ornamental production
it's slowly creeping in here and there
in cannabis
i have not really seen it executed
extremely well in cannabis yet because
some states won't even allow
banker plant systems to be used in the
growing operations
but the idea is as i mentioned before
you're releasing all these beneficials
if there's no
food they starve to death and some of
the mites things like cucumbers and
persimilis they're not that expensive
but when you get into parasitoids um
and these are the tiny little wasps that
control aphids
it can get expensive if you have to
release them over and over and over
again
so there are these programs for using
plants that you grow aphids on
and those aphids will not attack the
crop you're growing
but it basically so when you release
your parasitoids if they don't find
any aphids in your crop you're growing
they can go to these banker plants find
loads of aphids
lay their eggs in the aphids there and
then those eats those parasitoids emerge
and then go out so you're actually
building a population
in your greenhouse and many ornamental
growers do this they start these
programs early spring before the aphids
even show
up and so they're rearing the
parasitoids in their greenhouses on
these banker plants so when they even do
show up in the spring they've got this
whole army
of parasitoids already there waiting the
program that most people know about and
you've been dating my workshops we've
talked about it
there's a banker plant system for
affidavit colemani
colemani is a parasitoid that controls
and i'm going to give you like the air
quote smaller aphid species
we know it does green peach aphid really
well it does cotton
melanated really well and it absolutely
will parasitize
the cannabis aphid the fordon cannabis
the one that everybody's having problems
with
don't go running out and think this is
the magic silver bullet it is part of a
program
its cousin parasitoid affidious
irvine which is physically much larger
it controls
larger aphid species like um
it does potato aphid it does
phospholipid
it also does the cannabis
aphid and it's interesting that the
cannabis aphid
um when you start looking at
the parasitoids that have been collected
out of it there have been several of
them
and luckily three of them are
commercially produced
at this point um
so the idea with the new banker plant
is you can grow this larger aphid
on it and it's the larger aphid which is
a p
aphid and it is grown on fava beans
so the new banker plant system that's
coming to market raises a phidious
irvine
on the fava beans with p aphids the one
we have been using
is barley with the bird cherry oat aphid
and raising afidius
colemani so now there's two banker plant
systems that allows you to raise
two different parasitoids because the
coal money
typically is not going to go over and
parasitize the p
aphids and the afib the larger
parasitoid the irvine is not going to go
over and parasitize your bird cherry
oats necessarily
again there can be a little crossover
but for the most part
the irvine system is still very new this
is the first year am i growers have
tried it
in ornamentals we've had a few
challenges first of all the p85s are
super cool
because they're giant and they've got
these beautiful long legs i absolutely
love paving
but if you look at them and give them
the side eye they drop off the plant i
mean
it's i mean you touch the plant they
drop it's a behavioral thing so if you
go to move banker plants
are the the pieces on the fava beans
and you knock them your aphids are going
to fall off if they're on rolling
benches that get banged your aphids are
going to fall off
so it's been a bit of a challenge on
keeping aphids
up on the plant also they don't like
extremely warm weather
and that can be true for the aphids on
the banker plant for the smaller
parasitoids um but i do think there's
potential there
to build up a colony uh build up build
up a bunch of these
parasitoids in your cannabis facility
that both will go after cannabis aphid
so that's something new i don't know any
cannabis growers
testing this yet but um i think
it uh it it's something we're going to
have to look at and see if it's going to
work in those systems
so if i'm a grower what am i buying am
i like raising these you know barley
plants for example
and then buying the aphid
the pafid or how did how does this work
okay so for the smaller aphid banker
plant system
you actually buy it's a it's a
basically a rockwool i think it's rock
wool or oasis you get a cube
and it's barley's already growing on it
and it's loaded
with bird cherry oat aphids which don't
freak out if some of the bird cherry and
oats get onto your cannabis
because they can't live on it but
growers are
not physically going to be able to tell
bird cherry oat aphids apart from rice
root aphid they look identical
but birch area days it doesn't live on
cannabis and
the root aphids don't live on barley
so um it's it's they they're not moving
back and forth
um but you buy the actual plant when it
comes
to the larger avid plant banker system
basically you buy p aphids by the gram
that are shipped to you and so you have
to have your
fava beans or pea plants already growing
for
when the aphids arrive you just
inoculate them on the plant
and they go nuts on those plants for
facilities that are open to the outside
um this is another really great thing
about these david banker plant systems
is it not only does it raise these
parasitoids
it can also provide food for a lot of
your native beneficials
that move in we often find
like lacewing larva on these plants we
often find
surfed flies on these plants and that's
just because they've come in from the
outside
and are utilizing it as a food source
but that's fine
because it's the immature life stage
that's eating the aphids
they're going to pupate there and then
you're going to have a new adult
in your facility that can go lay more
eggs
okay so for those listening i confused
the two um
so the pafid does not go with the barley
uh i said that right the p aphid goes
with a fava bean
or pea plants yeah and the bird cherry
odi that goes on the
barley plants great and then
once they're smaller aphids the ones
were bigger and since we're talking
about banker plants the other one
is aureus and uh
um purple flash pepper or something
similar i realize
we're not talking about uh we're talking
about pollen sources at that point
i believe but that would be another
potential banker plant to mention for
folks if we're talking banker plants do
you want to just
spend a minute on that yeah that's
exactly what you said
it's you use a pepper plant to basically
provide pollen for aureus aureus is a
minute pirate bug
it's an excellent generalist predator
it's mainly used for thrips management
but also feed on spider mites and other
soft bodied insects
in outdoor hemp and hemp and cannabis
production i find it naturally occurring
this little insect loves hemp and
cannabis
the problem is indoors when you're in an
indoor
grow you can release them in there
but you don't have pollen for them
really to feed on because they have to
have pollen to be able to reproduce
you also have to have a minimum of 12
hours of light throw that into
but um the idea is this pepper
plant then provides the pollen for the
aureus
honestly any of my cannabis growers that
have tried it i find
the little shriveled pepper plant in the
corner of a bench being neglected
um that's the hardest thing is
either do banker plants or don't you
can't half-ass it
you have to commit to it you have to
have somebody in charge of it and
generally they don't get watered and
dried up and die
i see it all the time so don't half-ass
it and say banker plants don't work
unless you truly commit to it
um and do it correctly how
far away from your crop can they be
would be question number one and then
question number two is
it sounds like you said in outdoor
situations you don't necessarily need
banker plants where would a greenhouse
fall in that
depend greenhouses we are using them in
there
just to up our pollen because you can
still get outdoor
environmental pollen in a greenhouse
especially
you know if they they the vents open and
things like that
um but it just it's really going to
boost their numbers in there because
we're even using these
um and i have you've been against some
of my talks metro line of greenhouses
we're using these peppers alyssum and
these other banker plants
outside uh with mum production because
mums themselves
um when we're growing um at a growing
facility it's just all green it's all
vegetation and there's no pollen there
and so we're adding these even outdoors
uh to encourage the aureus to stay more
locally
uh to our plants even though pollen can
blow in from the environment we're
really just
concentrating at their form so we still
i mean we even use these banker plants
outdoors okay you're just not you are
getting more pollen it sounds like
outdoors so it's not as
absolutely there was a study done
looking
at swirsky inside of a greenhouse
and then outdoors on a pepper crop
and they provided swirsky
supplemental pollen because you can
actually buy cattail pollen
from like biobest to supplement feed
what they found is indoors uh in pepper
production it made a huge difference you
really got an increase
in um the numbers of swarsky
and predation on thrips and everything
outdoors adding the pollen made no
difference
because there was enough pollen already
just in the environment
and how far away can these plants be
you know for aureus i guess specifically
well it kind of depends i mean it could
be pretty far
the thing you have to look at and think
about is so when you go
into ornamental and vegetable
greenhouses um
they're not giant wind tunnels a lot of
cannabis facilities it's like going into
a hurricane it feels like
and so you have to think about insects
trying to fly
and move around in that i mean the winds
like that move your pest
amazingly um also but
if you don't have super high winds
you know if you i mean the aureus can
travel
huge distances but if you have a heavy
wind it's going to be hard for them to
fly
upwind so you may need to put more
plants
at the head of the direction your wind
is coming from
um but you know you're not
solely relying on these for your control
they're a supplement to it
but i would say of all the cannabis
facilities i've been at the distance is
not too far
and if you look at again what we're
doing outside you know we're doing these
over about i think about 10 acres
outside
putting these banker plants and dotting
them around
so it's not going to be a flying's not
going to be an issue
for obsidius colemanian affidavits irvi
and aureus in a greenhouse they fly far
enough
trick of grandma who we do not have a
banker plant system for
those are the egg parasitoids for
caterpillars they can't fly for [__]
so you have to do a ton of release
points for them
okay i guess i shouldn't have used that
word
they can't fly for for for
whatever you get my point um
any you said there's no banker plants
for them
um so you're just talking about when you
release them you have to
have a greater yeah you can't just like
open a container in the middle of your
greenhouse and let them fly out
you can kind of do that with like the
the aphid pairs of toys lots of people
do they just open the bottle set them
out and let them go
you really want to get them as close to
the plants as possible but just
you know walk out your door and look at
the landscape
if parasitoids couldn't fly any kind of
distance
how are they going to survive you know
insects have to be able to travel a
certain distance in order to be able to
find a food source
so in the most grows it's not going to
be
an issue where they're not going to be
able to get around unless you have these
again hurricane hurricane-force winds
pushing them down to one end of the grow
okay uh so any other other products
innovation things to cover before we get
into methods of release
um well one thing i do want to mention
um
and remember i'm not paid by any of
these companies you know bug lady
consulting is completely
neutral on all this i'm just bringing
information um but basf
has released and unfortunately they were
really going to promote this
last year but because of cove and it
didn't really get rolled out
um a bellafur velifer
is an insecticide that contains bavaria
bossiana
where it's a different strain that's in
than what is in botana guard but tana
guard contains the gha
strain the bavaria basiana and velifer
is the ppri
5339 strain so it's a different isolate
so if you're finding you're using
one bavaria product and you're not
getting the results you expected you may
try a different strain and different
formulation
to see if it works better in your
growing system
um because again you guys all know
that there's differences between the
cultivars of cannabis
you know it's there's differences there
well it's the same thing too
with these microbials there's different
strains that perform differently under
different conditions and target
different pests
and so you have to find the one that
works for your particular growing
situation
what's interesting about this product is
the oil
it is in has proven to be pretty darn
safe i haven't had anybody burn plants
with it
except when somebody tank mixed velifer
with suffolk you cannot mix two oils
together
you will absolutely burn your plan
please do not do that
but just straight up velifer as a
contact product
for foliar things like thrips
white flies if you use it tank mixed
with an igr can be really good with
aphids
uh and one of my growers has been
looking at it as a drench for root aphid
and the photos they showed me have been
pretty impressive
is this going to be the be-all magical
answer for rudy aphids
no but it may work better in your system
than some of the other products so i
definitely think
it's worth looking at and what's
one thing that's really nice too that uh
casf has done
is they do have available from them
compatibility
with bio control agents so let's say you
are releasing
you know cucumaris or using persimilis
and you want to spray velifer and you're
like hey what's this going to do
they actually have a chart available
that will tell you about compatibility
with it
so which is it's super useful to have
because
most pesticide companies don't provide
that information
for folks that want to look that up
velifer is spelled
r v-e-l-i-f-e-r there's more information
on the basf side about it
just want to throw that out there um you
know
you kind of did a perfect segway into
microbials and one of the things
i know we want to talk about methods of
release or i did but
one of the things you wanted to talk
about was contaminated
non-epa registered microbial products
so why don't we skip to that topic first
since we're talking about
you know miticides insecticides um
uh from a microbial perspective
so yes maybe i planned that segue there
for you because i was gonna make you
talk about this
yeah and you did highlight this but
before we get in i want to highlight
this one more time
so when we talk about you know
trichoderma
bavaria basiana even mycorrhizal fungi
or
any of these microbial products they're
very strain specific so you can't
you can't just say oh i'm going to apply
bulvaria or i'm going to apply
trichoderma that's not that's not enough
information
they're all different from different
suppliers different growers and so
people need to differentiate and know
exactly what they're getting and that
kind of leads into what you're going to
talk about here so
take it away right so um i've worked a
long time with these microbial products
and when we say microbial
um mostly what we're going to talk about
right now are our
fungal products uh fungus that
um the entomopathogenic ones are ones
that kill insects
so this is what you know i'm mostly
interested in not as much the disease
management ones
but on in in the united states
if you make a claim that your
product controls an insect or might or
kills
anything it has to be epa registered
unless
you're making what i call the salad
dressing products which
are basically made out of essential oils
that are on what we call the 25 b list
those are the non-epa registered
products so
that means those products aren't
aren't registered through the government
but with the government figures is how
here's a list of
inputs if you want to make a product you
know you're not going to kill yourself
you're not going to poison the
environment and
are letting people bring products to
market that way that's why when you
get um some products on the market
you'll see there's no epa registration
number
if you ask them for any trial work they
really have no data
my my favorite thing to see is when they
actually spell insect names wrong on
their labels
you know it's it's a lot of um
unproven products so
what people are trying to do is sell
microbial products not as pesticides
but as either soil inoculum or just not
cleaning anything so that they
feel i'm not saying this kills insects
wink wink
nod nod and we're not going to give you
any directions
then the epa can't say anything's this
we're just going to sell you metarisium
or we're just going to sell you isaiah
or hercitella or bavaria
or claim it's a soil inoculum because
the inoculums are
not really being regulated because in
the past
we weren't really using um these
microbial
into a pathogens as soil inoculums
but now there's research that has comes
out like with bavaria basiana
the active ingredient in and the tana
guard
velifer bioceras that there is some
um inoculation to the roots with it
so what people are trying to do is bring
these microbial products to market
and scoot around the epa which i will
just tell you right now
you are taking you are taking such a
huge risk
doing that because the epa products are
highly regulated i mean they test them
to make sure
that the purity forecast all this kind
of stuff and you can get all that
information from the company if you talk
to them
these non-regulated products and where i
keep finding this is i walk into a
cannabis facility and i'll see just like
a bag laying there and i'm like what's
that
and i this one situation the guy's like
oh well i bought that at a cannabis
trade show
and it has like something you would
print at home
like a shipping label and it just would
say like you know one tablespoon per
gallon
the product that we collected um
out in oregon at a facility we took it
and the grower had already been sprayed
this spraying it that particular product
um that he'd already been using in his
facility
actually contained a human pathogen in
it um
and he wasn't aware the other thing
that's very concerning
is when you get these products without
any pesticide label they don't tell you
about a protective equipment
if you buy again any of the microbial
products the
the bavaria the botanic guard the
any of those you're gonna have to wear
respirator because
even though bavaria is not a human
pathogen you probably shouldn't be
breathing it
these contain no warnings like that so
the growers don't think they have to
wear
proper protective equipment a ppe that's
required on federally regulated labels
and this particular product the pathogen
that was in there was aspergillus
and growers are freaking out all the
time about failing microbial testing
and aspergillus is one you are
absolutely fail
for and here it is being sprayed out
on the plants by this product um i was
contacted
last year maybe earlier this year by a
grower
in vermont who asked me for directions
on how to use medirisium
metabolism is the active ingredient in
met52 but they had just purchased
medium and i'm like well what's on the
label and well there is no label
and so i asked where they got it they
sent me a website and it's a product
that was coming out of china
again not epa registered and all it was
is it just
you know was labeled as medium so
we sent that off and that particular
product
um contained a camera was like 15 or
25 different other fungal and bacteria
in that product in addition to the
metarisium
and the metarisium that was in there
had an extremely low what they call the
cfu colony forming unit from what they
claimed was in there so even that little
bit of metarisium in there
less than 25 of it was viable
so if you're you know here this person
was just going to spray it
no protective equipment and didn't even
know how to
spray it they could have easily if they
have breed this stuff you know who knows
also are you gonna fail your test
are there plant pathogens in there that
can cause
problems um i was at another facility
recently
and uh they had ordered medarisium off
of alibaba
um i those two samples are getting
tested right now
and i've also been ordering samples from
other companies
that basically won't make any pesticidal
claims
but they're selling like bavaria basiana
and again they're trying to scoot around
getting the ep
registered where the stuff again has to
be looked at
because there's such an appetite in the
cannabis industry for these products
and i think all these growers that have
bought this up
do not realize the risk they're taking
with buying these products
because they really don't understand
that really this stuff needs to be epa
registered unless it truly is
a soil inoculum and is not being applied
for use for insect management but
typically
soil inoculum rates are way lower
than the insecticidal killing rates for
these entire pathogens
so even if you buy a legit inoculum and
spray it
thinking it's going to work with
insecticidal the rates are going to be
too low
really to get what you need for it to do
it's super scary to me because i'm
really concerned someone's getting up
really sick from this so please please
please
when you're going to buy any of these
microbial products
bavaria isaria i know medarism is nearly
impossible to get unless you're ordering
it from china through like alibaba or
stuff
you know just i wouldn't do it think
about the risk
um if you do it send the product off to
a lab to have it tested
i'm going to make a social media post to
show you guys
the plates that came back
from this medium product being plated
it looks like a four-year-old sneezed on
the plate and all
the different stuff growing on the leafs
on the auger surface it's disgusting
no product should look like that
those are all really good points one
other thing i want to bring up too
is the risk of heavy metals you don't
know what
form of carrier they may be using on
there that could also lead to having
creating issues down the road we don't
know if there's any carcinogens involved
i mean i understand why people want to
skirt
these epa regulations because they're
really
really difficult it's very hard to get a
product epa registered and that's why
the 25b list is so convenient for a lot
of companies um
on the you know on that side of things
but
you know you don't get the level of
research to know
um or the level of regulation so you
don't even you don't know if the
product's gonna be as effective as
they're claiming
and then you don't know if the product
is as safe as they're claiming
because even with some of these 25b
products i'm not convinced
that they're things that are totally
safe i mean time oil
for example and some of these other ones
i think still have
can be applied at concentrations that i
wouldn't want to be
you know breathing or around necessarily
um
and then when we talk about these
microbials uh you know
you're trusting the company and i don't
and that company may be trusting another
company
and at the end of the day it's something
that i just think i agree with you the
risk is is way too high go with an epa
registered microbial product
if you're going to use it especially if
it has pesticidal
effects and if you
you know people are all like you know
don't want government regulation if this
doesn't prove to you
why we need government regulation over
these products i don't know what will
convince people because this is exactly
why because again you someone could
potentially
die from one of these products because
you don't know what's in it and that's
why
i mean you could say buyer beware but
this is why we have the epa
is to stop bad products like these from
being sold because
again this this whole industry has
sprung up basically because the cannabis
industry i do
not find any of these products in
ornamental or vegetable production and
never have in past
but in the last two to three years this
has exploded
in the cannabis industry if you are
going to buy
medium isaiah
bavaria you want to make sure the
product has an epa registration number
it has a true label on it that
tells you the protective equipment you
need to be wearing
um it should tell you you know when you
apply this product how long before
you can go back in i'm finding
the cannabis industry you're not reading
pesticide labels i was a at a facility
not too long ago that they were applying
bt uh israelians
for flight management everybody knows
about that the problem was the product
they were using
and they were drenching their indoor
plants with is
for outdoor use for ponds
it was a completely wrong label no one
had taken the time to actually read the
label to see
one where we're applying this is it on
the label
and you cannot use outdoor products
indoor just like some indoor products
you cannot use outdoor
because the inerts are different this
was not designed
to be drenched on plant material also
the pests fungus masks weren't even on
the label anywhere
for what they were doing and it's just
completely the wrong
label and this is a legit legal license
to grow
but people aren't understanding
pesticides
and how to use them properly you guys
don't want to be the one that the epa
makes an example out of because it's
going to happen because
the you know ornamental and vegetable
production facilities and even canvas
facilities are inspected and you don't
want to be the people that are using
the wrong illegal stuff in your facility
so read those labels
make sure that you know
it's epa registered and also you should
be able if you have a question
pick up the phone and call somebody any
of this microbial weirdo stuff from
online
you're not going to be able to reach
anybody that can give you good solid
information like
biosafe bioworks bsf any of those guys
you can always reach people there
to answer your technical questions about
these products and how to be safe about
applying them
and just a friendly reminder there's a
different bt for
caterpillars than there is for fungus
gnats so
make sure you're looking at that when
you're buying your uh
bt and there's actually two different
caterpillar streams
oh okay well there you go there's a
zowie and kerstaki
and there's also a strain for japanese
beetles there's a bunch of different
strains of
bacillus thuringiensis floating around
you have to make sure lock and key
system
you got to get the right one for your
past
which leads you back to starting with
identification as the very first step in
any of this uh just a friendly reminder
on that
[Music]
i listen when you talk suzanne i pick up
things it takes me a little while but
i'll get there
well i mean anybody i mean besides
knowing
i love harry potter bugs and star trek
id
is probably one of the most important
things i've preached in
my life you have got to id what your
problem is before you treat
you have to yeah and i know i've tried
to send you photos of things like aphids
in the past and you're like i need a
better photo i need to really see those
genitals like you really
dive in because you can't necessarily
tell things apart without you know very
specific
key indicators and that's why i guess i
just realized more and more how
complicated it is to get the right
identification because you've already
talked about how
you know there's different parasitoids
for different different aphids
it's not a it's not as simple as
a one-size-fits-all with a program
no and i'm going to tell you right now
cannabis growers if there is a mite in
your soil
it is not australolapse schematist
every might picture that is getting put
on social media everybody's like oh it's
stressed it's strep
no it's not if you put out a bunch of
strats and you had a ton of food for
them yeah possibly
with any living soil with any compost
anything like that
you're going to get decomposers in there
that's living soil living soil has
living things in it you're gonna see
mites in there
and they're helping decompose things and
it's not a black and white you know is
that my good or bad
there's a lot of them that are you know
indifferent they're just living in the
soil they're not hurting the plant
they're not predatory
and there's tons of them in there that
do that and you cannot
just take a picture with your cell phone
and post it on facebook
and expect someone to id there is nobody
that can do that on this
planet mites are really hard to id
let alone soil dwelling mites where
there hasn't been a ton of research done
let alone cell phone images anytime
you know i'm working with my id most the
time i have to send stuff off and the
stuff has to be slide mounted
you've got to look at all those details
on there so
you know it's very complicated
that's all i can say and facebook is not
going to give you id
answers on that stuff so maybe the short
answer is if you see a might
uh on your soil you don't need to
necessarily freak out unless you're
starting to see
excessive amounts of them where their
populations are just exploding or if
you're seeing plant damage
i i so when it comes to soil mites and
cannabis
and so far i nor anybody else
that is a trained entomologist have seen
bulb mites in cannabis even though again
people are seeing their bald mites in
there
um bulb bites in bulb crops
can be a problem but any soil dwelling
might
i haven't seen cause any economic
problems in cannabis
now you could have root disease and you
don't realize it
and then these secondary mites move in
that are
eating your dead decaying roots and
people think they're the primary
they're just a secondary showing up and
taking advantage of decaying plant
matter
where normally it's a pathogen that's
the initial
problem and that can be very hard to
tease that all apart
but i haven't seen any mites in cannabis
production to this day
in the soil that have caused any
economic loss in cannabis
i think that's that's good information
yeah thank you for sharing that
um you're very welcome the ones that i i
see the most of in living soils
would be the um
uh it's isopods i believe and then
springtails where i see
explosions of populations those are the
two things i've had people reach out to
me with
um where they just see massive massive
amounts of growth i don't know if you
want to touch on either of those
since we're talking well the interesting
thing about springtails
is it's not one species they're multiple
species so
if you're an aetherium grower in europe
springtails can be a pest and feed on
your roots there
and actually um there have been
some agricultural losses of seedlings
out in the field terminal which crop it
was again from springtails feeding on
those
but that's not what we're seeing in
cannabis
and again there's multiple species of
springtails
so yes can springtails be a pest
yes but have we seen them be of
a problem in cannabis to cause economic
damage
no that's why you have to be very
specific about your information
um knowing the crop where you're located
all these different kinds of things
i have not gotten into springtail
identification good lord that's a whole
nother
i'm sure there's some springtail nerd
somewhere on the planet that'll be more
than how to
happy to help you with id um
but for the most part that's not
anything i worry about the only thing
in the soil from an arthropod kind of
standpoint
that you need to worry about is fungus
mass
because they eat your roots they vector
pathogens you just don't want them
around
and those are very manageable if you
treat them correctly i mean beneficial
nematodes are amazing at controlling
them when you get a good quality product
you apply them correctly there's also
the beetles there's mice there's all
kinds of things you can treat them for
and rude aphids rudy birds are the the
oh my gosh
you're not going to sleep tonight
because you have root david's because
they're very hard to manage
but other than that i mean there's some
weird things you know we've had fire
ants
you know feed on cannabis you know we've
had some cutworm situations
we've had a few root knot nematodes um
and we have this new situation with um
the tobacco ring spot virus that's
vectored by nematodes
that is um just been found
in a crop and that's vectored by plant
parasitic nematodes
completely different than beneficial
nematodes but for the most part
um there's not you know the the
the foliar pests are probably going to
take you out before any of the
the root pests um you know again in hemp
outdoors we've had a few weevil issues
uh and the soil line but brood aphids
are the ones that
you know are really the only thing to
freak out about in the soil from an
indoor growing perspective what about
excessive
levels of isopods you know roly-poly
bugs
pill bugs whatever you want to call them
because i have done that
oh my gosh yeah but it's not super
common
but it self-inflicted too much organic
matter in your soil
um because you know the american way if
a little something's good more is better
and the populations just build and build
and build
and i've absolutely seen them eating the
plants
i've talked to people that they're out
there vacuuming them out you almost
honestly kind of need to change your
growing system because you're just
sustaining them
by having too much organic matter in
your soil
great thanks for talking about that um
all right so on to a little bit you know
i know we've been talking for a while
now but can we just quickly go over
methods of release
you know you kind of highlighted a
little bit when you talked about sachets
but there may be people that don't even
know
you know what a sachet is so um i don't
know the best way to approach this if
you want to talk about a few different
insects or if you just want to pick one
beneficial insect and then talk about
the different ways it could be released
and
why that's important well let's talk
about
let's okay let's talk about two
predatory mites and then we'll talk
about nematodes because i think those
are the things that i see screwed up
applied incorrectly the most so let's
jump back to persimilis
um persimilis there is so many ways to
apply for similas today
traditionally back in the 90s it would
just come in a bottle and you would
sprinkle it out on the plant and there's
a lot of that still going on today
but depending on plant shape depending
how you grow if you sprinkle
over the top you're going to lose a lot
of those persimilis to the floor
i really cringe when people say oh just
pour the persimilis at the base of the
plant they'll find their way up
you know if my mom's taking me to the
mall i want her to drop me at the mall
not six blocks from the mall because
it's going to take an awful lot of work
to get to the mall
put them where your pets are think about
it you know get them as close as
possible
and so the the next progression um from
those bottles
on the persimmon list is actually the
vial with the nipple top again
been to any of my workshops you've been
to any of my classes
you guys have all of me talk about this
in fact i'm holding one in my hand
right now dad as we speak because i keep
it on my desk here
um it's a bile about the size of a roll
of quarters and it looks like
uh the top of a ketchup bottle you know
the nipple top ones when you hold this
persimilis will
run up to the tip of it and then what
you can do is you just
walk along and touch the plant and
persimilis goes
right out onto the plant and will start
feeding that way you can see how many
mice are going on your plant
there's no waste in the floor there's no
carrier on the plant
it's very neat it's very clean i it's my
favorite way to apply persimilis
and it's been around a long time but i
swear i feel like this was made for the
cannabis industry even though
you know we've been using it in you know
the interior landscape we're treating
palm trees and malls and things like
that we've been using this
product for decades so this application
method is a really good way to apply
them um now again we have
in the past we've never had persimmons
and sachets now
we're going to get these sachets
that have the quick release uh you know
as much as i like biob i'm not sold on
the quick release sachet because
honestly
i'd rather instead of having a sash
hanging a sachet on every plant and then
dealing with sachets
for the quick release i'd rather just
use the vial and walk down and touch the
plants
but the slow release sachet may have
something there
even though it only lasts for two weeks
and traditionally you only apply
persimilis
every every two weeks so you kind of
have to look at your economics
if you want to hang the sachets out for
two weeks or again you want to come
through with the vial every two weeks
you're gonna have to look at your
situation and see what works for you in
that
now we are starting to see more
drone releases for outdoor they've been
doing it in strawberries and citrus
and now parabug has been working with
beneficial insectary out in california
doing outdoor drone releases where they
put the persimilis and the drones and
they fly them out
and and drop them and that's basically
kind of how you would do
loose mites um for production
out there now we're going to talk about
cucumbers which is a different predatory
might again i love cucumaris
not as much as persimilis but it is a
freaking workhorse
what's nice about it is it has a white
host range
not only will it gobble up onion drips
western flower thrips
it will destroy broad mites it's heavily
used in ornamental production to prevent
broad might damage on a lot of crops
if you're one of my consulting customers
you're most likely using cucumbers in
your program
because it's a cheap easy insurance
policy
against these pests i just mentioned in
addition to we know it will snack on
spider mites
and spider-man eggs out there so um it's
a good
general mite to release it doesn't have
that same
fast running up behavior like uh
persimilis does
so you cannot get it in the release vial
so you have to get the product
loose um loose
or in a sachet but the loose product um
again i'm not super excited about
putting it over the tops of plants
especially cannabis plants that are
large
because you're going to lose a lot to
the floor now in plug trays like if
you've just stuck
all your uh cannabis uh cuts
into like a 10 20 flat before you put
the jiffy dome on
you could just sprinkle in there lightly
you know a tablespoon or so
of cucumbers which i highly recommend
because you have to start your bios
in propagation do not wait people you
have to start them then
it's pennies to treat then and again
it's going to start
feeding on all those pest problems then
before they have a chance to build
when your plants are that small it's not
that far for them to walk
now the sachets which we've talked about
you can also do those in propagation
and you can use those on the plants and
the cucumbers comes in that sachet
the slow release sachets they almost
look like tea bags and either come with
a hook or they're on a stick
there is a breeding colony of cucumbers
in there and
mites will slow release out of a pinhole
in there for four to six
weeks and the advantage of doing that
is if you hang these in your cannabis
plants instead of having to come through
every week or every other week to
lose sprinkle cute camaros and
everything get it on the floor make a
mess
you just have a naturally slow releasing
population coming out and it works very
well
you can absolutely use those sachets in
propagation
but you know the propagation cycles are
pretty short
so oftentimes if you stick them in there
and then you're going to be
transplanting in you know
two three weeks maybe uh don't
give me all kinds of complaints about
that's not your time
on average because everybody roots
differently and different sizes and
everything
but you know here you put that sachet in
and let's say if you're you're stepping
up the plants
in two weeks now you've got the sachet
that you still have several weeks
still left on it you can either put it
in new propagation trays or you can just
step them
up with your crop because you want to
make sure you get that
full use out of the sachet but these
sachets on the plants have really been a
game changer as far as
labor savings and also having that
consistent slow release
and if you've got these sachets you can
absolutely come through
and spray with products like impede
stuff oil
x um any of the the batana guard the
velifer
and since the breeding colony is
protected inside that sachet
even if the product you use like suffolk
is non-selective it will kill predatory
mites
so it will kill them on the foliage when
you're spraying but it
those mites are going to start releasing
still
out and so once your soft rolex is dry
any of those mites that emerge
after that are still going to continue
to be able to live on the plant
so you can spray and it doesn't disrupt
the releasing in your system
as long as you're spraying with products
that are somewhat compatible with
biocontrol agents and
generally in cannabis and organic
production we are
those release sachets
have really been a game changer on
releasing
the other release thing i want to talk
about are beneficial nematodes
in fact i was just about to post on my
facebook page which is uh for bug lady
consulting please don't send me personal
friend request to suzanne wainwright
because that's
where i you know do my cat's dog and
star trek and harry potter stuff
bug lady consulting is where i put the
links but basf has done a really good
video on how to apply nematodes and i
see a lot of people
saying they're applying nematodes for
fungus snack control and not getting
results
i think because they're not applying
them correctly
there's lots of different ways to apply
nematodes
and you have to look at your system for
commercial production
the most standard way to do it is people
mix the images up in a five gallon
bucket
and then they use a dosatron to apply
them out so they get even dosing
um through the crop and that video uh
that gin berg did
explains that which is explained exactly
how to do it
for smaller facilities or home grows
typically people are buying sponges
because you can get smaller counts on
those
and you have to wring them out and
things like watering cans and then you
water your plants
but you have to make sure that your
nematodes are about the same temperature
as your water you're mixing them in you
need to have that
pretty close together you want to make
sure you use them up as soon as you mix
them because nematodes can drown in the
water
you don't want to let the water heat up
because that
that can do it also um
with your nematodes too again
i really like people to buy direct from
the insectaries
so that you're getting the the freshest
the most viable product as possible
because sometimes the distributors you
don't know if they've stored the
products correctly
or how long they've even had the
products
so does that kind of give you an
overview
yeah did you maybe i missed it did you
talk about ones that come with carriers
well all the well i don't say almost all
biocontrol agents come with carriers
um and even like cucumeris you can buy
it
in vermiculite you can buy it in brand
there's different carriers for different
situations
typically if you're dealing with like a
legit bio control company
they'll know what you need if you're
ordering blindly off the internet you
know who knows what you're going to get
um yeah i guess like i bought um sorry
like it looked like a spice shaker you
know this was
10 years ago now when i had thrips
and uh so i was shaking out these
you know it looked like they looked like
little granules
um onto you know the
my vegetative plants at the time
i i just didn't know if you want to
touch on that method of application well
you're probably you're probably putting
out cucumaris and you again you're
probably losing a lot to the floor that
way
what you should have done is once you've
got your tube
you lay it on its side for a little bit
you never want to stand bottles up
always lay them on their side
and then you roll it slowly to
reincorporate the mites back in
then you should open the container and
then you should have been able to get
what they call release
boxes they're basically these little
square pop-up boxes with a hanger on
them and you hang them in the plant then
you walk by with basically a spoon
and you would put a tablespoon of that
in these little boxes
and then the mites over the next day to
two days will slowly climb out of those
boxes and onto the plant so that way you
get all your mites on your plant
and you don't have carrier everywhere
yeah i did
i did have carrier everywhere and uh i
didn't know you 10 years ago so
i have an excuse but now you do that's
true well i think the sachets just make
so much sense
um so so tell me if this is right so if
it's really bad
pest problem you'd probably do a knock
down spray and then follow it up with a
release
or with sachets when do you lean towards
and i realize that every situation is
different and i do want to highlight
that
but as a general rule when are you doing
more of a quick release versus a sachet
option
for um you know a lot of these insects
i look at how long before the crop is
being
shipped shipped or harvested i look at
population density i also look at
threats from
other pests that may show up that we may
have to treat for and how is that going
to interfere
with our other program but if you
start in propagation when your plants
that's when they should be the cleanest
you can go in with low rates and again
in those those plug trays you can use
loose product right there now if you use
an arrow cloner again you probably don't
want to dump carrier all over the top of
that because that's going to make a mess
and that's where um you know
using sachets may make better sense um
again i it's like ideal when people root
in
you know 10 20 flats because if you
sprinkle it on and they just land
on the the service uh surface of like
the glue plug or the rock wool or
whatever they're using
you know it's there's so many plants
right there they're gonna bump into them
um and that's when i would use the loose
ore
if you know if you're uh even though i
realize most of growers are going to be
cannabis growers but if we're growing
let's say
basil pot tight on a growing bench and
it's a four inch pot we may broadcast
over the top of that
because the plants are touching and it
makes a canopy and most the mites
are going to end up on the plants and
not losing them to the soil because
i actually look at leaf structure too
plants like crotons it's a tropical
foliage plant super big wide leaf
we literally use an orchard air blaster
to blow mites out
because they've got big leaves that can
catch the mites and then it slides them
down towards the center of the plant
and they don't fall through you look at
a cannabis plant that's really
especially they've been
thinned out they're open they're leafy
and if you blow mites over the top of
that they're just going to kind of fall
through and fall right to the floor so
plant structure makes a difference too
on the
on deciding how we're going to be
releasing
okay so we're already running a little
long but i want to put you on the spot
here
can you answer two things in the next
two to three minutes and that would be
um one why it's important to
uh vet the entomologist that you work
with or
or let's just say not even use the word
entomologist because i'll let you touch
on that but
the um i guess
ipm expert that you work with or
consultant
and then also uh why every environment
is different and there's no
there's no perfect answer that works for
all situations can you just
i know this could be a whole nother
podcast but i i wanted to get this in
because i think it's important if you
could just touch on those
uh really quickly right
so um so again my background is a bit
more in the ornamental
market where there's only a couple of us
that are consultants there aren't very
many and when you're a consultant you're
a consultant
you don't have other revenue streams and
we've gone to college for this
and do that once i started working a lot
more in the cannabis industry and i
discovered everybody's a consultant
and i would ask people you know what are
your qualifications
and literally well i grew weed for a
year so now i'm going to be a wheat
consultant
and i think it's really important to ask
if someone is giving you
advice or identifying something for you
look at what their qualifications are to
be giving you this information um
because
i'm finding there's just so much bad
information being given out
and people can say whatever they
want about their background i mean you
can call yourself whatever i could call
myself a zoologist
you know but i didn't go to school for
that and i
i think it's important to dive into
people's backgrounds did they go to
college
or these specialized areas i understand
you could be a very good
grower without going to school i get
that but when you get into these
specialized
niches of entomology or pathology
or nematology the reality is you need to
have gone to school for this
and and worked in the field and kept up
with
all the scientific information because
if not
if the people you're getting information
from don't you're gonna end up getting
bad information
and you know unfortunately i've learned
um and it's been frustrating for me that
cannabis is kind of a social media
popularity contest
and the reality is is i'm sorry guys i
don't have a ton of time
to put up all these flashy social media
stuff because
i'm out in the field working i'm working
with growers i'm
you know doing experiments i'm
photographing things
um that's why i rely on you tad because
you basically kind of are my social
media
to get me out there because i just don't
have time for and i always say
if you've got all this time to be on
producing all the social media content
how are you actually working and doing a
job so i mean just just
buy or beware on the information you get
out there
check you know what people's
qualifications are linkedin's great you
can see
how many jobs they've had where they've
worked and that kind of stuff
and to answer a question on environment
um
it's just like uh ever let's just think
about it too with medications
actually covet vaccines perfectly lots
of people have gotten the covet vaccine
we've all responded differently
same thing with biocontrol agents you
put them out they can respond
differently in different environments
where it may work here
where it doesn't work there so when
you're
dealing with living breathing organisms
there's so many variables in the
environment
we have to test and see which one is
right for your conditions i mean
i have a pretty good idea for because of
doing this like 30 years now
the good starting point um and
we're going to tweak it from there but
um
the environment you know workflow
you know is there a soybean field
outside your facility
or are you next to a building you know
all these kinds of things
play in to how we formulate your pest
management programs and my goal is for
my growers to have
solid environmentally safe and cost
effective pest management programs
because if your program's not
cost effective you're not going to be in
business then you're not going to be my
customer anymore and i need you guys to
stay in business so i have a job
yeah that was that was great i want to
touch on a couple things
first of all i think that if you are a
large facility
you could potentially save them money by
dialing in their program
or decreasing the amount of pest damage
that they're having
they may be buying too much of a given
a given product or maybe there's a
better product out there that you could
recommend
but every situation is so unique as you
mentioned you know varying in
temperature humidity
stage of plant airflow all of these
things that uh it really does
uh require a lot of experience and
background in order to make a good
recommendation
and on that note i know i'm gonna get
pushback on the fact that you know you
don't have to go to college
to know something about about a thing um
i guess i'm the perfect example of that
when it comes to my background
since my background's in special
education but i did get a master's
degree
for what that's worth um but i do
i do think there is a huge advantage to
going to school
now for those people that didn't go to
school or didn't have that opportunity
you know there's there are wonderful
people in this industry i think kelly
vance is a great example of that
but he has a lot of uh experience as a
large
greenhouse grower prior to ever getting
into insects and then spent a lot of
time doing work with insects
but be aware that you know you'll even
see variability within these insectaries
in terms of the level of knowledge
that they have or these companies
selling insects i've seen some of the
recommendations
on there versus the ones that your you
know you and i have talked about them
and sometimes they don't really
line up as well so really do vet
um your information and make sure that
you're optimizing it for the
health of your grow and and doing
research on something
doesn't mean googling it uh you know i
see this
growers like well i've researched this
like well how did you research it well
you googled it
there is so much bad wrong
information i mean again i could write a
whole book on bad
pest management information on cannabis
on the internet
or a coffee table book on the wrong
identifications
of things on there because again i don't
know all
insects i try my best and i'm trying to
improve
constantly by learning doing more
rubbing shoulders with you know the
systematists that are specialists in an
area and and all that
but i don't know everything and as
growers
you have to be good at lots of things
but in a way i don't don't yell at me
but master of none in a way
because i don't do fertilization i don't
do irrigation but you guys have to be
able to handle all that
leave it to the specialist when you're
getting down to the very specifics on
some of this that we can help you with
um and i will say ted i did have one of
my
consulting customers in las vegas
contact me a week after the visit
and they said that in the changes they
implemented just from my being there to
one day it already
paid they saved so much money it paid
for all my
me coming out my consulting fee travel
and everything
for what they saved it was such a huge
money saver for them and that's what i'm
trying to do
um is have a good program but yet be
cost effective and you know for me
environments the environmental issues is
the same thing my goal is to reduce
pesticide use
i don't want people to be exposed to
them and i don't want more pesticides in
the environment
absolutely you know if you're hiring a
consultant for
anything they need to be able to provide
value and you have to be aware of what
that value is prior to ever
having them out i've had people that
want me to come out and see their
facility and you know a lot of times
they'll be like hey you know maybe a
zoom call be better
maybe i'm not the right person for what
you're looking for
but you know like in your case if you
step into a facility a lot of times
you'll see things that they might not be
able to put in a call or an email and
you'll be like oh my gosh
you know hey you're storing this product
wrong or oh geez you need to have a
some sort of uh you know ipm protocol
for going into this room that you don't
have established right now
these little things can save thousands
of dollars
hundreds of thousands of dollars
depending on the scale and so um
that's where a consultant can make a big
difference and getting the right
consultant because there's no
there's no list of consultants out there
in the canvas industry
and there's no ratings it's really um
it's really your job as the grower to go
out there and vet them and make sure
you're getting the right person for what
you want
absolutely being on on site is critical
because you're absolutely right um
and again i i if you call me and ask me
about disease
you know my answer is it doesn't have
six or eight legs i don't deal with it
but
tad you know from knowing me if i don't
know about it i know who does
and i'll get you connected with the
right person that does know
about that area of specialty that can
help you then
absolutely yeah that's that's the
biggest thing and that's one thing i'm
very grateful for too is like that
network of people because if it relates
to insects i know
i can get a hold of you if it relates to
you know pathology or disease
i can talk to you i could talk to chris
hayes over at bioworks you know there's
there's there's uh dr greenhouse nadia
who's just amazing when it comes to
airflow
and things like that so you know having
the network
is almost more important than your own
personal knowledge in a lot of cases um
when it comes to consulting i found or
just
being able to find answers for questions
all right well
and this is an advantage to me being
like an old person because i've only
ever worked
in the horticultural industry again i've
got almost over 30 years in the industry
my husband's been in the industry even
longer than i have and between my
husband and myself
i think we'll know almost everybody in
the industry and if i don't know the
specialist
he knows the specialist so again i i i
have no problem passing people on to get
the right people
and you know it's like even if like a
eggplant person honestly calls me and
they're like hey we have a commercial
eggplant production
greenhouse i'm going to pass them on to
a vegetable specialist for greenhouse
because i
try to stay out of vegetable production
for pest management i know
my areas and i know when to hand them
off you cannot be a master of all
i think that's a great uh that's a great
way to end the podcast since we're
already going a little long i know you
and i
love to chat anyway so uh for the sake
of the listeners let's uh
let's call it a day and i hope to stay
in touch with you
and get you back on here again soon
well thank you very much for tad having
me it is always a pleasure
i love talking with you um and i
appreciate you
giving me a platform to get my message
out there
absolutely all right have a wonderful
rest of the day and i will
talk to you soon alright thanks
[Music]
that was suzanne wainwright evans also
known as the bug lady with bug lady
consulting and you are listening to the
cannabis cultivation and science podcast
i'm your host tadd hussey of kiss
organics don't forget to check out the
podcast
page at www.kisorganics.com for links to
the websites and topics we covered in
the podcast
just click on the learn tab then podcast
also if you haven't already
please take a moment and leave us a
comment or review on whatever platform
you listen on
i do take the time to read them all and
appreciate the feedback
you can also follow us on instagram at
kis
organics to stay up to date on the
latest podcast releases and information
thanks for listening