[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge before starting the podcast I
wanted to let listeners know that I plan
on adding more interviews of Growers
this season while the original intention
of the podcast was to bridge the gap
between academic research and real life
cultivation I've done a wide variety of
interviews over the years and I think
it's important to hear how Growers are
dealing with real day-to-day issues in
their cultivation facilities as we don't
typically get to grow under perfect
conditions and control for every
variable so while these interviews might
beight slightly less scientific and may
contain some personal experiences and
anecdotal information my hope is that it
will spark new ideas research and help
Growers deal with real life scenarios
that they may be facing as well and grow
the community in the spirit of this my
guest this week is Matthew Butters I met
Matthew when he emailed me and we
started corresponding I went to tour his
facility which is about 2 and 1/ half
hours away from me and after the tour I
decided I wanted to have him on the
podcast Matthew serves as the Director
of cultivation at Smoky Point
productions and Waypoint Ventures a
prominent i502 operation in Washington
state leveraging his expertise in
cannabis cultivation he has a rich
history of successfully developing and
leading cultivation teams in various
settings worldwide Matthew is driven by
a commitment to achieving sustainable
production of top tier cannabis on a
commercial scale reflecting his passion
for excellence in the industry now on to
the
show
all right hey Matthew thanks for coming
on the show today Tad thanks for having
me it's it's really a true honor to be
on your podcast I can't say enough good
things and how much I've learned from
just listening to you and your esteemed
guests well I appreciate it so I I met
you uh recently in person at Smokey
Point productions your current facility
that you're working at uh can you just
give us a quick background about uh sort
of who you are and and what what you're
doing in the industry
yeah absolutely so I started out as a as
a home grower jumped around um from from
grow to grow just learning as much as I
could from each one being a sponge
absorbing as much as I can from each and
every you know Mentor or colleague that
I had um and I ended up here at Smoky
Point couldn't be more thankful it's an
amazing company to work for and yeah
excellent
opportunity so I I thought it might be
interesting for Growers uh because some
of my most popular podcasts are um are
ones when we're talking to actual
Growers because and that's who people
want to hear from so uh one of the
questions that I had was um as you
started your sort of experience in this
industry let's let's kind of go back to
where you started and maybe a few things
that you learned kind of each stop along
the way so someone can kind of have an
idea of what it takes to become the head
grower of a you know a pretty large
facility
I would love to yeah so I started just
humble beginnings as a homeg grower I
always had a very intimate relationship
with the plant it helped me on my
personal Journey tremendously and so
started growing plants at my house and
dove into that um and it was really you
know people putting out information just
like yourself and uh I know one of your
guests Jeff lenells he really sparked my
interest for organic cultivation
um with teaming with microbes and that
series and so just reading every you
know little tidbit or every book that I
could and trying to suck up all the
knowledge that I could and then test it
you know in real time whether it was at
my house or at the grow was just my way
of stepping up and using each
opportunity as a learning
experience um taking advantage of every
Mentor or consultant that I could and
just you know growing alongside the
plants no pun
intended so you said you started off
just with hom grows what what did your
first hom grows look like um how what
style of growing were you doing yeah so
I actually uh would uh do a whole room
so most people would do tents I think is
how how they would do it I would turn
whole rooms into a grow and I loved all
types of plants not just cannabis so I
like all plants with ethnobotanic iCal
significance or you know historical
significance with humans I think that
cannabis is an amazing amazing plant but
there's a lot of other plants out there
too so um I grow all types of plants
from you know even tobacco Nicon Rustica
um
to all all sort cacti all sorts of
plants at my house so I turn entire
rooms into into grows use back then it
was HPS that was your only option i'
kind of lined everything in plastic and
have like a little pass through area it
was
pretty um kind of state-of-the-art for
back then for being just in a house
right and so I had a lot of cleanliness
protocols that I still had and I was
growing in soil at the time and just
learning as much as I could and then
testing things real time there a lot of
trial and error a lot of killing plants
to be honest um yeah were using like a
nutrient line or were you mixing your
own soil back then how were you how are
you approaching it I was buying uh
pre-made soil mixes and then uh testing
different amendments you know just like
the the teaming with microb stuff I i'
used basically worm castings and teas
since the beginning of my cultivation
career I was using uh fish ulion and
humic acid so I I started off on the
right foot honestly um and I got this
information from other Growers who Who
provided me with that um little secret I
guess um it's kind of the secret sauce I
think um that I've been using almost my
whole career is is a combination of uh
fish hydrolysate and humic acids and and
kelp right on uh and just to highlight
for folks fish Emulsion is very
different than fish hydrate so um you
want to make sure one is going to be
high in nitrogen the other is going to
be high in phosphorus so just be aware
that they're two very different products
um when you when you talk about uh
starting off with a hom grow then and
then getting into to you know more of
the commercial side of the industry
where did you where did you kind of go
from there and how did you get your
first
starts it was just uh friendships and
relationships that I had with people
which are really everything back in the
day before before the industry was
really solidified it was who you knew
and and the relationships that you had
we only worked with people that we could
trust and I ended up giving one of my
dear friends uh I would save all my
colas like my best colas for my best
rounds I would keep in jars and just
have them like on a shelf kind of like a
display and I'd crack into them every
now and then if I wanted a little
special treat but um I gave a a nice big
Cola to a dear friend of mine who was
well connected in the industry and he
referred me to uh one of his connections
by uh Newman Lake which is on the border
of Washington and Idaho and so I got to
step in there as kind of like a
consultant and just a a labor hand
honestly I helped with everything um
whether it was pruning and defoliating
or watering and I learned as much as I
could from the other guys there and also
just provided the knowledge that I had
and it ended up working out pretty
well so you kind of
started sounds like kind of right at the
bottom of the industry um just as a as a
laborer and uh kind of worked your way
up uh so you went from growing you know
relatively small in these rooms to to
seeing you know a pretty good level of
scale it sounds like on the commercial
side what was what was that like what
were the big differences between you
know growing in your house versus
growing you know on scale
commercially it's a totally different
Beast just to be forthcoming about it
it's a totally different Beast um when
you're at your house you can do
everything yourself which is awesome
because you could take all the care that
you want on you know just a small
handful of plants and make them perfect
whereas on scale you have to think about
costs you have to think about Labor
inputs um like what's what's the true
value added from this action or this
input and and really analyze those types
of things also any problems that you
have or imbalances or pests or anything
like that go zero to 60 like really
really fast where it's much more
controlled in a smaller
scale So based off that I would think
the keys to growing you know
commercially like what you're describing
there um you really want to have a a
robust IPM program where you're really
scouting because you do have so many
plants and then you also can't um you
can't afford to use a lot of these
marketed hype products um just
because just because of the cost on
scale they're just not practical is that
kind of the main thing s you got it you
got it and like early identification of
any of those things is going to save you
a ton of money down the road um and also
just being preventative out the gate is
going to save you a ton of money so
whether it's beneficial insect programs
or or your crop nutrition whether you
can do soil tests to to be able to
anticipate things that are coming versus
you know waiting until those um
deficiencies or disease or anything like
that is you know at a later stage and
identified on your plant um if you can
catch those things before they manifest
into something pretty bad is going to
save you a ton down the
road yeah that Mak that makes a lot of
sense um and
so I mean I kind of want to get into
that but I also just want to move on a
little bit too to where you kind of went
from there uh keeping this a little bit
more chronological and then we can come
back to some of the uh pointers and tips
so like
after after being in Eastern Washington
um if I remember correctly I think you
moved on to Europe is that
right uh yeah well from there I went to
a big row and Airway Heights Spokan area
uh we did awesome there outdoor race
beds uh and then some some big hoop
houses as well uh we did we did really
awesome it was a tightnit group of
friends kind of living the dream
honestly from a cultivator perspective
when you could just manage a grow with a
few guys looking back on it now it's
really just like this dreamlike almost
romantic situation it's like just ideal
um and we crushed it just like honestly
if you have a group of guys who are
mission driven and everybody's bought in
like and just willing to do what it
takes you're going to succeed in that
situation so we did really really well
from there I went to
Okanogan um a little bit and these are
pretty harsh harsh climates Okanagan is
a little bit even more extreme where you
have uh you know really hot temperatures
dry dry Summers and then at night
especially towards the fall they can get
really really cold and those cold spells
can really you know Spike the humidity
and cause some issues there uh we did
really really great though got to learn
to Stage my outdoor crops based off of
flowering time uh put in some
autoflowers for an early season spring
Harvest that's going to be able to
maximize your outdoor season basically
as many chunks as you can split that
harvest season into is really going to
maximize your dry space which is always
a a massive limiting factor for outdoor
grows and so from there I got the
opportunity to uh get my foot in the
door into Europe yeah well well let's
talk real briefly about that Okanagan
experience in the sense of drying and
curing so like you mentioned everyone is
running outdoor crops there uh because
of the climate and you have a very clear
end date in sight where the weather
changes um how were people effectively
drying and curing such massive Harvest
and you already touched on one thing
which is you know breaking it up into
more Harvest by doing an Autoflower
season first um that would reduce you
know that would give you an early
Harvest when not everyone else is
harvesting um but then also um shrink
your Harvest a little bit I would assume
for the for the second round over the
summer what what were your pointers
there yeah so um with those early
Autoflower harvests they're they're
super crucial so not only can you bring
down that Harvest but you also can uh
House of product for sale at the
beginning of the year which is really
you know a revenue driver for a lot of
outdoor Farms where typically they don't
have and um most of the Farms out there
are probably doing large larger scale
garage pole barn setups without a lot of
equipment or infrastructure to help
regulate the internal environment um
it's kind of typical with an outdoor
grow we were fortunate enough though to
have two uh completely indoor
dry rooms where it it was totally
climatized it worked really really well
when I dry I try to really remove 50% or
so of the total moisture content of that
flour within about the first 48 Hours 24
to 48 hours to really reduce any chances
of pathogen growth or anything like that
that may occur during that drying stage
and then for the rest of the phase
ideally the rest of that two weeks um
you're going to go low and slow you're
going to drop your temps increase your
humidity and just try to slowly slowly
uh kind of balance out and homogenize
out flour because at the beginning the
outside of the flow May dry out quicker
and you may have some moisture that's
trapped in the inside so going kind of
low and slow as I like to say it's
really going to help balance that out
and pull it out um so we would work with
two week intervals and have that for
kind of these Harvest blocks and work
with
early uh short photo periodic varieties
to bring down after that Autoflower
Harvest um in in earlyer mid September
and then have a late September block and
an early October block by that time you
usually have a a cold snap that is
either snow or it's Frost or whatever
and so you only the most hearty
varieties are going to survive past that
point so that you could get maybe a
later October Harvest as
well okay so yeah so you're harvesting
you start harvesting pretty early but
because of the massive amount of plants
that you have you're kind of breaking it
up based on how the cultivars finish so
you want like a wide range of finishing
times it sounds like so you can you can
do that um how how did your product then
compare to all the pole barn folks that
were you know having at the mercy of the
environment and in their curing rooms
you know what what were the big
differences I may be a bit biased in
this regard because it's my product but
um to be totally honest I thought we
grew some really really amazing product
um you know it's going to typically in
those pole barn setups you're not going
to have the tarpine preservation it's
not going to carry through it may smell
a little bit still like like chlorophyll
like some grass or some hay some of
those off flavors and Aromas may still
be present in there whereas if you have
an optimal dry and curing time you're
going to preserve more of those volatile
tur beans you're going to have a a
better flavor a smoother smoke and just
a a better overall experience in the
final
flower and you probably have less risk
of pathogens too I would say as well
those are all good points yeah all right
well moving on then so now uh you're
you're off to Europe uh tell me a little
bit about that that experience that was
that was an experience so I'm truly
fortunate and blessed to be able to have
done this so I got to go to Eastern
Europe in Macedonia for my first uh
operation over there it was an intro
into do gacp and GMP like real
pharmaceutical grade type of production
and Manufacturing which is kind of
probably where the industry will be
headed at least as far as a medical
perspective I think that we over here
should be landing in more of a food
grade standard whereas over there
they're doing a pharmaceutical standard
um and we can get into the nuances of
each one of those types of things but
basically the gacp is good good
Agricultural and collection practices
and this is just going to ensure uh it's
going it's going to really try to
ensure that you have homogeneity within
the batch so there's not too much
variation as far as cannaboid or tpine
um it's going to monitor your inputs
it's going to make sure that your Sops
are all in place so the idea is that if
you have a patient they can actually
like set up Doses and things like that
whereas you know over here if you eat an
edible you never know what you're going
to get you may be you know not feeling
anything and you may be in a spaceship
in your room at the light toop you never
know as a side note are you seeing a big
difference in variability and Edibles on
the market here in Washington um or is
it pretty well standardized it's pretty
well standardized at this point at at
this point but again we are now to the
point where we're able to maintain those
higher level of Standards here at at
Smoky Point we have an amazing kitchen
staff commercial kitchen and just
absolute top-of-the line Edibles with
consistency all the way through with
award-winning chocolates and savories
and sweets I can't say enough good
things about the team over here but um
if you're a user you probably remember
the Dark Ages where you would get a
cookie and maybe take a bite of that
cookie and never know what you're gonna
get yeah you're getting a cookie and
like a Ziploc baggie and they're like
only eat this much of it yeah and
I'm I have to be care careful I think
everyone has that edible story though
maybe one day we'll I'll share mine on
air I want hear yeah yeah so uh what was
the so what was the setup in Macedonia
like um you talked a little B about the
GMP thing I I'm quite familiar with it
actually uh I'm on the board for a a
company in Australia and it's been
really interesting learning about that
side of things um but for the for the
sake of the podcast let's talk a little
bit more about the the cultivation
aspect like how are they growing what
scale are we talking about here um yeah
yeah share your share your Insight there
I'd love to so uh we started indoors um
just on racks like LEDs a standard setup
and then we would uh veg veg them out
and we called it an interim room but it
was a standard veg room and then we'd
put them outside and just to be totally
clear I just got this company kind of
started um
at the beginning stages of their
development I helped them write Sops and
I helped them get through the licensing
process um they were fully licensed and
we were starting to cultivate by the
time that I had left there but I had
never finished any uh flowering Cycles
or anything like that with them we were
in the stages of uh water Tre treatment
build outs uh Greenhouse build outs and
we were running living soil in
pots um it it quite a cool setup and but
I was just honestly offered a an amazing
opportunity from there that I couldn't
turn down in Portugal so I kind of
jumped
ship okay okay so you ended up in
Portugal and uh you want to touch on
that I'd love to move on to Smokey Point
yeah so Portugal is just the best the
best opportunity ever it's an amazing
country amazing people amazing food can
say enough good things about it I got
started there with a pharmaceutical
company at the totally ground floor of
everything before the land was even
purchased uh so we got to come out the
gate kind of setting things up the right
way which was awesome so we chose the
land we set up an outdoor kind of an R&amp;D
plot and a pretty large scale Greenhouse
the total property was about 105
hectares so this was a real large scale
grow um where we're talking Acres or
hectors instead of uh square
footage and yeah just an amazing
opportunity we were running living soils
we got to do a custom soil formulation
with a big European uh soil
provider uh worked with them with the
soil tests to make little changes and
and tweaks as as we saw those come back
and how that soil was performing in in
its
environment and yeah I got to do really
amazing things with amazing team I
surrounded myself with people who are
much smarter than me and uh set up a
real great opportunity there
so were you going directly in ground or
were you in uh were you in pots in the
so uh in inside we were in pots then
outside we were in like uh windro style
raised beds with with Furrow so we took
the tractors through we hired a lot of
local farmers to create those beds for
us and then we set in uh drift tape
and yeah we just amended it and drip
tape and and water only for the outdoor
and relied on the
soil okay so it was uh when you say wind
rose then you were you're putting in big
trenches of of potting soil with living
soil and then the plants were growing in
in those trenches kind of thing is that
what you're talking about yeah sorry
maybe I Ed the wrong term there so we
were amending the soil adding organic
material to it gypsum and then balancing
out any nutrient imbalances that we saw
and then doing a light tilling and then
creating those
beds okay so you're actually growing in
the native soil there correct got it
okay yeah that that makes sense to me I
I always encourage folks to use the
native soil if they can if they can pass
for heavy metals if they don't have a
high flood flood plane there or and if
they don't have any burrowing creatures
like gophers and things that are going
to be causing big problems then it's
better to go right into the ground for a
ton of reasons for sure moles are always
fun to deal with but luckily there we
were good on that front um the soil was
a little compact but we added some
gypsum in there and it really did help
actually um create some of that
Aggregate and create some of that
drainage balance out any of the the
calcium problems that we were seeing and
help with some of the salinity factors
as well I think so that that gypsum
helped quite a bit um we had to add a a
little bit of sulfur as well to to lower
the ph but not not too much the native
soil was really good pretty much out the
gate
there awesome awesome um so now you've
grown it sounds like mostly outdoor at
this point on the commercial scale and
you got this
opportunity um if I'm remembering things
in order to come over back to Washington
at Smokey Point is that is that the next
stop that's the next stop I I should
clarify that um at a few of my
operations in the past we had some small
scale indoor operations um just just a
few rooms at each spot but nothing like
we have at Smokey Point all right well
so I met when I met you uh I think you
shot me an email and we started chatting
I I remember how um and then I came up
to Smoky Point and met you in person and
and took a visit of the facility and and
I'd been up to Smokey Point before so
Smokey Point's been around uh since the
beginning of 502 they actually had a
company called the Clone Zone which was
really smart by the the founder uh Brian
leade who I who I knew through the
industry at the time um essentially
right when um we went legal here in
Washington on the rec side uh they
already had a a company providing clones
and so he was able they were able to
provide clones to the ma the vast
majority of the industry legally because
people were having trouble sourcing
genetics um from what I understand they
withheld some of the certain Cult of
ours for themselves that they grew
internally so then they had sort of
unique genetics on the market that no
one else was putting out because
everyone else was putting out all the
other stuff they did and it was just a
really um it was it was a really uh
ingenious way of approaching the an
Emerging Market you know in a legal
state that I think was really profitable
for the company at at the time um I
don't know if you know anything about
that time period because you weren't you
weren't around yet but um
yeah I I can talk about more but is
there anything you want to
add not so much not so much I know that
um since then the Clone Zone has really
evolved and has become our research and
development and breeding
facility yeah and when I met Brian he
was working on he was having issues with
his compost te Brewer um and so he
wanted me to come up do some microscopy
and figure out what was going on and so
I did a little bit of Consulting on that
side um they did one run in I think five
gallon pots using our soil with uh
chemical you know nutrient salts over
the top and I I when I came up there the
plants look phenomenal but they end up
going back to a purely uh salt program
just because that was what they were
more comfortable with um and I kind of
lost touch with them over the years
until you reached out saying you were
working at Smokey Point because I know
the company went through a few different
iterations
um over that time period and uh yeah I
was excited to come back up but I have
to say when I first visited Smokey Point
I was blown away by the the
thoughtfulness that went into the
infrastructure and I hope to show a tour
of this soon um but it was one of the
best managed and cleanest facilities I
I'd ever visited at that point in time
um so yeah I mean bring me up to the
Future what what is Smokey Point
now so I love to hear that you know
coming into a facility with good bones
makes everything so much easier on me
and my team and so that that's really
awesome that they did you know move
forward with that thoughtfulness just
with the infrastructure so that is
really great we have tried to continue
that as much as as possible just that
level of cleanliness I think that we do
this better and more thoroughly than
probably almost all of our of our
colleagues in in the industry so for
example when we cycle a room we
remove uh all of our tables our
irrigation lines get rolled up they get
flushed out and and cleaned off and
sanitized every single surface gets
sanitized we remove every light off the
ceiling it gets wiped down every surface
gets touched sanitized every line gets
blown out every filter gets changed uh
and then finally following that is a
fumigation of of just like hydrogen
peroxide atic acid just to make sure
everything is is totally sterile and
we're not cross-contaminating or
transferring anything onto the next
cycle for me it's very important that I
know that my Cycles start off you know
100%
clean so you don't feel like that's
Overkill you want to make sure that
there's nothing in that
room that's correct contaminate yeah
like especially when we're talking
spores out out here on the West side of
Washington as you I'm sure are well
Weare uh powdery Milo btis these are
these are serious issues that we deal
with as cultivators in these high humid
environments and so to to ensure that
our crops have zero powdery Milo and
zero buritis going to our customers um
it means a lot to me and it and it is
you know at the Forefront of my uh
priorities absolutely so how are you
cultivating now what's the methodology
that you're using in the in the facility
yeah so one of the first changes that I
made coming into Smoky Point was
switching over to a living soil um and
this one's a custom soal formulation
same same type of deal we try to develop
it a little bit over time um and so
we're going into that we do regular
organic soil drenches um we add in the
fish emolion we add in some humic acid
fic acid amino acids enzymes we do some
calpin veg uh with f fulvic folar sprays
uh with some calcium to make sure that
we get get the meet the calcium demands
of the plants in living soils with a
little bit smaller of containers it's
really difficult to keep up with calcium
demands of the plants and so I have to
really monitor you know my my temps and
humidities and and my soil moisture
content and my calcium levels pretty
carefully to make sure that those
demands are always met um but we're
trying to be as as sustainable and
organic focused as possible we're not
perfect and I'll just you know totally
admit that and
but but we're doing our absolute best
especially considering the difficulties
and the challenges of our industry and
our Market it costs a little bit more
for us to
be like let me use this as an example so
some of our jars that we use uh for our
habitat line we have a habitat premium
line that we launched um in
2023 and so this is going to be our top
shelf flower and all of our jars are
made from recyclable glass are joint
tubes are made from recycled ocean
plastic um these are some really cool
things that I think that are steps that
we're taking to try to uh you know just
be as sustainable as we can but it costs
us a lot more money to to do
that and so if we switched our entire
company over to this it would probably
not work out um but we do have that
offering for for people who are you know
just
uncompromising um Quality and
sustainability focused and so we do have
that offering for
that so you you mentioned you're you're
in uh living soil you're not actually
using our soil I want to clarify for
folks this is not an advertisement for
my company because you're not uh using
any of my
products um and we've we've we we had
conversations about ways that you might
be able to you know reduce inputs or
potentially um you know change some of
your your fertilizing practices to to
save costs you know and reduce the
number of touches and applications which
is something I know you're you're always
looking at and experimenting with which
is I think really important in in any
facility um you're that you're always
you know striving towards Improvement um
but overall like
um I I I think one other thing to
highlight is that so you're what size
container are you in let's start there
so we started out a little bit bigger in
a 7 gon but I had to reduce to a 3
gallon just due to the nature of the
competitive of the of the market I'm
trying to reduce costs as much as I can
and so we went to a three gallon
container I could still see um the the
same amount of quality and I can kind of
I know with living soils it's a little a
little bit different than a typical like
cocoa based media or something with your
dryb backs but it works out really well
for us where I can almost have this
hybrid approach of crop steering which
is kind of unheard of with a lot of
living soils and beds and stuff right
most people are doing that in Hydro
application or or those types of
situations um to
where so we installed an automatic
irrigation system and I can drip into
that and then my hand waterers come
through and just make sure everything's
totally balanced and even and I do
multiple shot sizes similar to a
traditional crop steering program so
that I can monitor my soil moisture and
keep it more in that goldilock Zone with
smaller shot intervals or sorry smaller
shot volumes with more intervals so that
we can maintain kind of that goil lock
Zone throughout the peak periods of the
day and then watch our dryb backs
overnight so you're not allowing you're
you're reducing the amount of dryback or
variability in your soil moisture
overall which is a lot harder frankly in
a three gallon pot the smaller the
container the harder that is for
sure it's pretty difficult for sure I
wouldn't want to go I mean I definitely
wouldn't want to go any smaller than a
three
gallon and I know some people are going
to be listening this they're going to
say well that's not living soil because
the pot is size container is too small
and you're also not reusing the media
and that's probably something we should
talk about too is to what went into that
decision and that thought process um so
you are having to bring in new soil
every cycle uh why and why why do you
choose to do that in your facility we're
not reusing our soil we're trying re
reusing our soil right now because I
have concerns about viruses and viroids
and so we we know that Popa vroid is in
very high concentrations in the root
Zone and so my concern is that if we
chop and even if we pull out the bulk of
that root mass that maybe there's a high
viral load and whatever Roots may be
remaining in there and if I don't put it
through a thorough composting process
that maybe some of that vroid could
transfer over to to the Next Generation
and I'm not saying that we necessarily
have the vroid but most people have the
vroid and it's very prevalent in our
industry and I want to make sure like I
said that my Cycles are are starting off
clean and are clean and are the highest
quality as possible and I just don't
want I want to mitigate any risk of
transferring viruses or viroids off to
my next
cycle yeah and I can imagine in a three
gallon container don't have a lot of
media relative to the the route to Media
relationship is is probably there's
probably not a lot left at the end of
the cycle by the time you pull the roots
out I would think um so there's not as
much to recycle either I I I don't know
what what do you think about that and
like I said we we are triing this
currently to where I am uh cutting it
with new soil so like for example a 3:1
ratio of used soil to do soil um that
this is the trials that were running
right now and we're actually having some
some pretty good results my my my next
step is just to make sure that we do
thorough pathogen testing and make sure
that that nothing you know weird is
happening yeah I mean that that would
there's a lot of Labor that goes into
bringing in and cost associated with
bringing in new soil um filling the pots
getting them into the rooms getting them
out of the rooms there's also a lot of
Labor that goes into recycling the soil
and contain ERS which is one of the
reasons a lot of folks like beds but I
can totally understand the vroid concern
and why you guys have gone down the path
that you have um but I think it's
interesting to talk it out so people can
kind of hear the thought process behind
it for sure me
too so um I don't think we've even
talked about exactly how large Smokey
Point really is um so folks can have an
idea of what we're what we're talking
about here what what scale are you guys
so we're tier three tier three is the
largest um license that's available in
Washington state we also have the clone
z license so the rolling Farms license
is our spot at at Smoky Point and then
we even are bringing over because the
LCB recently redefined what their
definition of canopy is which is really
unfortunate for almost all producer
processors in the state right now um and
so we actually have to relocate our
clone Zone license over to Rolling Farms
just to make sure that we're staying at
maximum capacity over here it's it's not
like necessarily a bad thing because
this whole last year I've been able to
uh have the opportunity of of breeding
at the Clone Zone and doing research and
development and at this point I have so
many seeds and fenos to test and Hunt
that I could last me like the next three
four years literally of pheno hunting
and stuff over at rolling farm so I'm
just absolutely stoked to be able to to
use those seeds and those genetics that
we were able to develop and test them
out at rolling Farms all right so so
throw out a number here how big is
Smokey
Point uh well the rolling Farm's license
is for 30,000 foot active canopy and
then the uh clone zone is a tier two
which is going to be 10,000 squ foot
active canopy and you're you're maxing
that out more or less correct at this
point yeah so 30,000 square feet of
flower and canopy um what what does a
typical room size look for you look like
for you uh it's about we we have 960
plants I have 80 tables 12 plants uh a
table they're about 4,000 square ft
rooms um yeah with with almost a
thousand plants in each room and I have
nine of those we're on weekly Cycles so
it works out really really well this
goes down to the bones of the facility
they designed it really well around the
flowering times of the plants to where
if we have nine rooms on nine week
Cycles every every week we we have a
crop you know and so we're cropping on
Tuesday dayss we're cleaning on
Wednesdays and we're filling on
Thursdays and all of that cleaning that
I said that that these guys do um is
done hyper efficiently and these guys
just you know bust their buts it day in
and day out to be able to reduce our
downtime and and maximize our
production so a lot of that having a
really good staff having a motivated
staff and a happy staff and then also
having really good
Sops um I got I got a taste of that when
I came by the facility uh can you talk a
little bit about what you have just on
the on the door of every room absolutely
yeah absolutely so I have my first first
I have my irrigation cycles of each room
so we we implemented our drip system as
I said um and so all of those schedules
are posted on the door so that my
waterers can really understand you know
when those irrigation Cycles are and and
where they're going to have to
supplement by hand also I have my
um kind of kind of our our crop work
schedule so we we fill a room and we
stage a room we properly space those
plants on the tables which is super
important to maximize the canopy a lot
of people will Overlook that but just
putting the plants in the right spots
and making sure everything is evenly
spaced out is is really going to help um
and then we set our drippers we do our
lowers which is removing all the lower
portions of the plant that aren't going
to receive adequate light or produce
anything anything substantial we remove
all of that so that the plant can focus
its efforts on on maximizing a grade
flour we're going to then come through
and we're going to Trellis everything we
LST low stress train everything we don't
do any serious tying down or anything
like that we just I I tell my team to
put one Cola in each 6x6 inch square of
trellis netting and if I can have you
know a big a big branch and a big Cola
in each one of those squares I consider
that canopy maximized and so that
schedule by the day is is posted on
every door and I just have my team fill
that out and the lead will go over and
check it check that the task has been
done so the SOP is super important but
so is um the training on that sop so
that everyone's totally on the same page
and those tasks are getting done
efficiently and then also that the lead
is checking up that those things are
getting done in an efficient manner and
there's sign offs and dates so that
there's accountability for each task so
I have that and then we also have REI
signs and so we go above and Beyond on
our REI signs and REI is a restricted
entry interval and this is something
that whenever a pesticide is applied it
doesn't matter if it's a soil drench or
if it's a folar application or anything
like that and REI still applies and so
there's a duration of time where you
can't enter that space so let's say for
example we soil drench with something
like boaria
basana um that's going to have an REI of
I believe four hours and all this
information is going to be provided in
the label and all the information on my
signs comes directly from that label and
we follow those to a T and so I even put
if um for early entry workers who have
to enter that space before that REI is
up um I I State the PPE requirements for
that early entry you know we State when
we finish the application in this case a
soil drench so we're just literally just
feeding the plants um B basana which has
multiple effects but all but primarily
as a a insecticide uh for soft bodied
insects in the red zone and so
we um are going to State those so that
anyone even someone like yourself who's
visiting those areas can feel
comfortable and safe and and understand
that you know this product was applied
or the last product was applied in that
room and and what are the requirements
to enter that
space I was so excited to see that that
is super important and I think it gets
overlooked in a lot of facilities un
fortunately um but I can't stress enough
how important it is to follow the
instructions to a te on a pesticide
label even if it's something like
Bavaria because this is why we're
running into pest resistance this is why
people are getting pesticide poisoning
in egg um you have to have proper PPE
you have to follow the REI and um so
yeah I I want to commend you guys for
that um I think it's it's really really
important so I'm glad you I'm glad you
touched on it appreciate that
uh one other thing um that that you and
I talked about was that uh as an
employee because of those Sops being
right there um if someone walks up to it
you know there's no standing around
because someone can always figure out
what the next step is and what they need
to do um it's not dependent on the
person it's dependent on the room and I
think that's another thing to highlight
do you want to touch on that at all uh
sure yeah absolutely so and then all
also so we have multiple rooms as I said
so all
do blue Mock and I have multiple people
doing blue mock my IPM will do IPM
related blue mock my fertigation lead
will do you know crop nutrition related
and soil moisture content and all that
kind of stuff they'll check for all
those things I'll check for everything
um and then we'll go through and set a
priority list and we'll put that out to
the entire team so that they know you
know even though all these rooms maybe
for example let's say multiple rooms
need Trail list I we'll set a priority
list on which room to get in first and
then as soon as they go to that room
they just look at the list what what
what's checked off the list what's not
and they could Jump Right
In awesome and
uh in regards to the the facility itself
I know that there's some limitations and
challenges um with the infrastructure I
mean there's a lot of things they got
right but what are what are some of the
challenges that you face um with with
your building you just just the shape of
the building and
everything um let's see the shape of the
building so we have have a a a large
Warehouse that has um basically a shell
within a shell so we have an internal
structure built with drop ceilings and
stuff like that inside of a larger
structure which has its benefits for
sure um as far as like insulatory
capacity you know that that shell
actually helps um with a lot of things
but with a drop ceiling you can't hang a
lot of of weight from that ceiling so
one of our limitations for example is
the weight bearing capacity of our
ceiling and if I wanted to deck out that
ceiling um with like 200 You Know topof
Thee line LEDs it's going to weigh a lot
um those LEDs weigh substantially more
than a traditional HPS and so to swap
over for us would be pretty difficult
and so I guess um the things that we're
doing to maximize our production with
that is is first and foremost making
sure that those lights are are at the
proper spacing and distance from the the
plants I think this is super important
to make sure you're not wasting photons
um and you're maximizing you know that
the crossover of the light to to
maximize your homogenity at the max
canopy height to make sure that all the
plants are getting the right amount of
light and the right Leaf surface
temperature you're not wasting photons
on the lights or or the corridors as
much as possible and if you're
maximizing you know those light levels
for for what you got and your Leaf
surface temperature and then everything
else can kind of fall in line there um
by you know just adjusting your room
parameters as far as temperature and
humidity to also help with those kinds
of things um I like a leaf surface
temperature about two degrees cooler
than our rooms we run our rooms this is
something cool that I've implemented
since I've been here at least I think
it's cool hopefully you guys think it's
cool um I run I start our rooms pretty
hot relatively I think hotter than most
HPS Growers because as you know with an
HPS you're going to have a higher Leaf
surface temperature than if you're
running with an LED so people who run
LEDs have to increase their room temps
to get their Leaf temps up to the right
optimal level so that you have the right
transpiration rates so we run right
around 80 82 degrees U for our room
temps in the first weeks of Bloom and a
higher humidity right so to optimize
that VPD the vapor pressure deficit it's
super important to make sure you're
maximizing your transpiration rates and
your nutrient uptake and all these
things and so from there will slowly
drop it down throughout the cycle and so
I'll lower the temp lower the humidity
step by step kind of in tandem right you
don't want to lower your temperature
without lowering your humidity or your
VPD will get out of whack and then it's
going to mess your transpiration rates
increase pathogen pressure all these
types of things and so we slowly step
down our temperature and humidity to
where when we're finishing at the end
that temperature is pretty low around 70
degrees and in a pretty dry environment
and so what that's going to do is to
make sure that you're not off gasing um
Turpin so the turpins are really
volatile and they're going to um off gas
and volatize at a higher temperature so
for us to be able to preserve those we
drop our temperatures pretty
significantly in the last couple weeks
of flour it also helps accentuate some
some of those pigments like anthocyanins
and
carotenoids um make it make like
increase some of those secondary
metabolites um in the end of flour and
preserve some of those turpins so that's
a kind of a cool little environmental
hack I'd say to be able to maximize the
quality of the flower that we're putting
out that's interesting yeah I haven't I
haven't um heard of anyone do it exactly
that approach um or or lay it out so
eloquently um interesting enough uh I
couldn't remember the word antoin in my
last interview with
uh with that with a Cornell researcher
and it was it was bothering me so I'm
recording these back to back so it's
it's thank you for triggering that word
for me
um yeah so uh your what is your light
level at at canopy it's pretty low so I
but I I recently have been lowering all
of them so I'm about at 700 at Max
canopy right now which is super low for
the industry um in my opinion this is
going to compromise yields a bit but as
far as overall flower quality our flower
quality has is just an absolute another
level from where it was two years ago
and I would implore anyone who tried
Smoky Point flour in the past and we
have a pretty large consumer demand and
and following but if you haven't tried
us recently I I just have to emphasize
that you gota got to give us a shot
because our flower quality and our
actually our
extracts if you don't mind a a Shameless
plug
Dad yeah well no I think it's great so
youve you've made little changes that
have improved the quality of your of
your
flower and plant health over the last
two years is really what you're getting
at which is which is wonderful and I
think um on that note when you're when
you're talking about um your lights and
the fact that the light levels were low
I think they were even lower than that
before you before you lowered the lights
obviously were so so knowing that and
you know and still trying to run a
production facility you can't add lights
because of the weight issue with the
ceiling um I I think it's just a
highlight that on a commercial scale
there's always challenges that you're
dealing with that force you to have to
step outside of what is optimal
necessarily like obviously you know and
if you could wave a magic wand and have
a th000 ppfd uh that would be great but
a lot of times there's reasons why
that's not realistic whether it's budget
whether it's you know in this case the
weight of your ceilings and so you have
to learn to adapt and adjust you know
your other environment environmental
parameters or other things in order to
be in order to stay in business on a
commercial scale and that's just
something that I I kind of want to
highlight for folks because I think
that's just the important reality of of
this you know of growing on scale
absolutely and there's things that you
can do like that like lowering lights
that really don't cost you anything I
mean the the yo-yos that that we bought
to lower those lights sorry I call them
yo-yos but um they they really are like
pennies to the dollar and but to get the
linear yield increase that you're going
to see from increasing your ppfd is is
going to be
huge and I think on that note when we
when we talk about um the light being
the limiting factor
here it wouldn't matter so much you know
how much you addressed fertility and
these other aspects if your light levels
are so low that they're just not the
plants aren't able to photosynthesize
what they need to in order to really
grow so so one thing that you and I have
talked about is how you're always
looking to make small changes as you see
or identify what you think is the
biggest limiting factor of growth in a
given room do you want to kind of touch
on that absolutely yeah so it it comes
down to to costs and everything as well
right so there's other things that you
can do like like just monitoring your
soil moisture as you know is one of the
most crucial aspects and so one thing
that we did was install um Grill link
controllers and soil moisture sensors
and it's not a massive investment to be
quite honest and the you know the
results that you get from being able to
use an analytical tool to get a precise
calculation of your soal moisture is is
really really important and also for
example your environmental controlling
equipment if you
can um if you can get these things
communicating with each other so that
for for example if you have heaters and
air conditioners or air handlers in your
rooms and they're set on separate
thermostats and maybe they've been
running in your facility for five six
seven years um when's the last time
those thermostats have been calibrated
is everything totally accurate and so is
any of your equipment competing with
each other and if you can get it to make
sure that it's communicating through a
central controller and it's all being
controlled together it's just going to
increase the efficiency of your room and
your equipment as well to save you on
that overhead
expense now you've had some other
challenges with the with the
infrastructure um either due to scale or
due to the the building you know the
infrastructure of the building itself is
there anything you want to touch on
there in terms of small changes that you
made whether it's in harvesting curing
um oh I'd love to yeah I'd love to so if
I can touch on harvest harvesting and
curing and drying I think that's kind of
overlooked a lot of people just focus on
growing growing
growing and uh you know even the best
the best grower in the world who
produces an amazing product that product
could be ruined really quick if it's not
dried or or you know stored and cured
under the right condition so I can't
emphasize this enough um that's one of
the major changes we revamped our entire
dry room and for example this is
something that's uh got a huge cost
benefit we implemented uh polyc
convection tubing so you might see this
stuff in green houses in but we
implement it into our dry room and all
this basically is is like a a plastic
tube that we connect to a Max fan and we
hang it from the ceiling and put it
right above our drying racks and so
instead of having fans or like
oscillating fans that most people will
have in their dry room so we have our
our dry room laid out so where we have a
hanging rack and another hanging rack
next to it but in between those two
hanging racks we have a convection tube
that goes uh in parallel to it from
above and gently gently blows air from
top to bottom and then extracts from the
bottom and so you have this almost
laminer air flow effect where none of
the flow is being you know bombarded or
blasted with with air directly rather
you have this kind of soft gentle stream
of air that's going in between the
drying
flowers um and providing a more
consistent and homogeneous you know
drying condition for the for the flowers
yeah I was experimenting with that uh I
I saw that in your facility first
actually um I wasn't even aware that it
existed it's a I I call it Greenhouse
convection tubing it's the same thing if
you Google that term you can find it
online um or if you go on our on our
social media accounts on Instagram you
can see some photos from my grow um I
put it as under canopy airflow as a
there's a company called duct socks that
makes um a more robust version of this
out of a fabric material material um
that you hook up to a fan and then it
pushes air and you can so I was using it
for underc canopy air flow and this was
a really cheap way of of experimenting
with that um in at my grow and I so far
really like it I think it I think it's
working really well to get air um
underneath to improve my air flow so
yeah I appreciated that I learned
something new and uh yeah I'm enjoying
that experiment I am so glad that I
taught you something Tad because You'
have taught me so much over the years
that's that's awesome yeah so it's been
it's been a fun experiment um running
under canopy airflow because it's
something I've always wanted to try but
uh there W there weren't a lot of
options for a home grower I mean there's
stuff on scale but like um yeah this was
like 30 or $40 and I massively overpaid
for what I got but uh it gave me the
opportunity to try it out so I'm still
seeing if there's a way I can offer it
to folks more affordably because it's
it's literally just a plast itic bag
tube that's like anywhere from let's say
8 to 12 in in diameter and it's got a
couple holes in it with a hole punch is
spaced out so that it's just putting
that air out more uh passively so you
get a massive volume of air at a very
low air flow rate which is uh really
nice um for a lot of reasons and I think
it's interesting that you're using that
in the in the drawing room you're also
using um to to plug
a company that I've seen now in a couple
different uh facilities um you're using
those uh drying uh hangers I don't know
what the brand is or what they're called
you want to you want to go ahead and
give them a little plug I can yeah
absolutely dry flow I can't say enough
good things about them so um these guys
are making really high quality drying
racks and it makes stuff really really
easy for us so we have these mobile
racks on you know really high quality
aluminum racks um we've been using these
kind of since I've been here
we're still using the exact same setup
you know nothing like super uh durable
very easy to clean you can't really ask
for much more than than what these guys
are providing I think they're out of
Oregon sorry if I that I I'm pretty sure
they are too and I don't know the guys
uh I've only seen it now in a couple
facilities you guys in Collective
elevation but I love the Ingenuity
behind it like you said super easy to
clean you harvest and put it on these
they look like kind of like massive coat
fers for lack of a better way to
visually describe them um and you just
put the uh you put the branches or the
buds directly on there to hang them to
dry and then you can just wheel that
right into your your curing your drying
space exactly and then we have like some
permanent uh poles let's say that stay
in our dry R so instead of you you
definitely can just wheel those racks
into your dry room what we do is we you
know we saved on the budget we only
bought a couple of those racks which
worked out really well for us so we
transport the sticks which is what the
coat hang let's say coat hangers are are
hanging on WE transport those with the
racks and then we just raise up the
entire stick and hang it on the poles in
the dry room and then reuse those two
racks so we only have two rolling racks
for our entire facility and yeah can't
say enough good things about
them I mean that's just such so much
better than trying to throw it all into
a bunch of totes and carry it down to
your drive room I mean that's so much
harder on the flow
yeah I mean there's it's just a really
good solution if folks aren't aware of
it um cuz I hadn't seen it in in a lot
of facilities until recently so I just
you know maybe everyone knows about it
but if not it's just something people
should consider it minimizes touches too
right so we're like literally just
touching the stem when we chop it we
hang it one time on that hanger and then
we don't ever you know have to
reposition that plant until it comes out
of the dry room which is really
convenient too yeah well um anything
else you want to touch on regarding the
harvesting drying curing side of things
if I could say one more thing yeah um we
implemented also this bearing uh Barrel
curing protocol which I think you got to
see which is kind of cool um I think
that most producer processors should be
doing this a lot of us are but some of
us aren't so I would just say you know
and we're also doing uh moisture
readings daily on our drying flow so
that I can adjust the parameters of our
dry R to make sure that it's always in
the optimal conditions because when it
comes down I want to make sure it's at
the perfect um moisture
content sorry I know I've had some
technical issues the last couple of
podcasts as I've been trying out new
software that's why this podcast ended
so abruptly I think I've got it all
smooth out moving forward though but
that was Matthew Butters and you are
listening to the Cannabis cultivation
and science podcast
if you like the podcast please leave us
a rating and review and give us a follow
on Instagram and YouTube and don't
forget at kiss Organics we have a wide
range of products that we offer on our
website everything from soils amendments
beneficial insects soil test analysis
and Consulting thanks for
[Music]
listening