[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of kis organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and draw on
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge I hope
everyone had a wonderful holiday and I'm
excited to be back making podcasts for
2018 we have a great lineup of guests
for future interviews ranging from the
latest in lighting technology to soil
testing permaculture lean farming
outdoor cultivation and much more this
podcast though is about a subject that
many people probably don't give a lot of
thought to but it's important aspect of
cultivation here with me today is
William Evans
I met William actually through Suzanne
Wainwright Evans the entomologist from
my last podcast when we were talking off
air she said you have to meet my husband
and we started talking about what he
does and it seemed like a perfect fit
for the podcast William has been working
in the horticulture and nursery industry
for over 20 years and brings a wealth of
experience to the table this podcast is
not the most glamorous of subjects but
one that deserves some attention today's
podcast is all about containers while
I've been a proponent of planting
directly into the ground when possible
this is not an option in many situations
and propagation is best done in small
trays or containers William will share
with us how containers can dramatically
reduce transplant shock improve worker
efficiency increase plant health and a
myriad of other benefits we also talk
about how the wrong container can cause
major issues resulting in poor growth
route girdling and even the potential
for your container being a source of
contamination without further adue
though here's our interview okay hello
Ted hi thanks for taking the time to do
this today I really appreciate it so I
wanted to talk to you today about these
fertile pots sure can you give me a
little bit of background into how you
came across the product and your history
with it and then a little more about how
it's made my personal history with it
was
I was working for a distributor that was
selling them in Pennsylvania a long time
ago in another lifetime it seems
fertility that's been manufacturing
these pots since 1960
so it's it's over 50 years now they've
always been manufactured on the east
side of France the reason that the
factory is there is because they're made
primarily of spruce fibres and the the
forests in the area there have a lot of
spruce and so the the the factory is
competing with companies that are making
firewood and timber and pulp paper and
things like that and they they buy the
the firewood they buy the logs from the
local wood cutters and then process them
there and make them into pots so these
pots are made of spruce are there any
other ingredients in the containers
themselves there is a little bit of peat
about 20% or so it fluctuates a little
bit there and there's three to four
percent limestone that's in there to
buffer the pH of the pots there is a new
version of these that's being introduced
which is a peat free pot which is a
hundred percent wood fibers there's a
couple different blends of wood fiber
but again it's it's primarily spruce
fiber and there's some maritime pine in
there as well but then again it's it's
it's all wood fibers that's the that's
the main thing so it's probably easier
to refer them as a wood fiber pot and
these pots are a hundred percent
biodegradable absolutely yeah there's
there's nothing synthetic in there
whatsoever and they're approved for use
in organic production too I believe yes
both versions are armory listed the
organic materials review Institute
that's in Eugene Oregon they put you
through a pretty rigorous process of
examining where your raw materials come
from how they are sourced how you
process them etc in order to be able to
get an armory listing which army
listings will certify that you are
approved for use in the National Organic
Program run by the USDA it doesn't
necessarily mean that your product is
organic it means that your product is
approved for use in organics there's a
big distinction between an input and an
output as far as the USDA is concerned
fertile pot will be considered an input
and it must be approved for use in
organics the only thing that can be
outputs are actually something
is grown or produced from plant or
animals yes so our soil for example I'm
working on getting it approved for use
in organic production it can actually be
certified organic for the reasons that
you're saying it's a sort of a
bureaucratic labeling issue they're
correct but it has to be approved for
use in organics so you have to go
through the whole process I'm sure
you're dealing with that now yes so
before we get into some of the
differences between fertile pots and
some of these other types of containers
can we talk a little bit about what the
main benefits are well the main benefit
to fertile pot is really the porosity of
the wall of the container and to try to
help you understand what that's
important why that's important is that
when you plant something in this pot
whether you put it in from a plug or you
put it in from a seed or a cutting you
know however you start when the roots
reach go through the soil that's in the
pot and they reach the edge of the pot
because the wall of the pot is about 85%
porous the roots are going to pass
straight through straightaway the pot
wall is so porous that we don't even put
drain holes in the pots we don't cut
drain holes into the box because we
don't need them and why that's important
is because it's going to develop a
natural root structure that is going to
allow the roots to develop as if they
were in the native soil the advantage to
them going through the pot is that as
they penetrate the pot in the encounter
air you're going to get root pruning and
so the air is basically stunting the
apical dominance or the desire of the
root to grow forward and preventing it
from going forward the root naturally
forces lateral branching so just like if
you say you had a basil plant and you
pinch the top of the basil plant you're
stunting the apical dominance of that
basil plant there and the result of it
is it branches out so you get a bushier
bushier basil plant the same thing
happens with the root structure so as
the roots are penetrating the wall apart
air is doing the pruning it's it's
basically stunting the able the
dominance and it's forcing the roots to
branch out and remember the tip of the
root is the only point that actually
does any work on a plant that's where
the nutrients are uptake and the
moisture is uptaken so if you have more
root tips as a written response to the
pruning process you have two things with
a fertile pot you have a natural
structure because it's not being
containerized
it's not it's not turning inside a
plastic wall
and then you have an enhanced natural
root structure because of the pruning
process so you having a better better
ability of that plant to uptake
nutrients and moisture and when you take
that pot and you put it into the next
larger container or into the native
landscape as you're transplanting it all
the apical dominance that's on the
outside of that on those those roots
that were on the outside of the pot will
return and the plant will grow faster
into that next larger container or into
the native landscape because of the fact
of the type of root structure that it's
got behind it so we see a lot of photos
online or in forms and you see people
with showing off the roots of their
plants and the roots are starting to
wrap around the inside of a traditional
container and what essentially you're
talking about here is by having that
root stopped growing and starting a new
tip we're actually increasing the
fertility of that plant or its ability
to take up nutrients correct you're
increasing the ability for it to uptake
nutrients and moisture a lot of these
photos that you see where they show you
there's massive amounts of roots
wrapping around that's actually a really
a bad thing because two things one is
that the energy of the plant is being
forced into apical a dominant roots
which really again the tip of the roots
the only important point of this so you
have all the rest that reaches carrying
the nutrients moisture up to the plant
so if you've got a wrapped around if
they're if they're encountering a solid
wall during a plastic wall or a pot that
needs drain holes cut into it they're
going to turn in they're gonna circle
and that's going to set up a pattern
that's very difficult for the plant to
break out of when you put it into the
next larger container that's why often
times you'll get directions when you see
when you see when you get a plastic pot
they'll say well pull it out of the
plastic pot and take a knife and score
the roots and the reason that you're
trying to score the roots is you're
trying to break that containerized
structure that's been set up by the
plastic pot so of course you realize
that's damage to the root structure
that's that's setting the plant back
you're going to get transplant shock in
other words the plants gonna it's going
to survive when you plant it but it's
not going to thrive because the roots
have to regenerate and form into
something that can be used by the plant
again so yeah apical dominant roots are
really a bad thing and a lot of people
get them confused with you know good
root structure yeah you know growing up
with my parents awning a retail nursery
I you know I had 20 years ago he was
teaching me how to transplant the plant
and that process involved essentially
taking a rubella plant and really
ripping the roots apart very
aggressively with a knife with your
fingers and just if you didn't do that
that plant would stay in the shape of
that pot like if I took a traditional
plastic plant growing a plastic
container and didn't break up those
roots that were root bound and planted
that plant it would eventually it would
eventually die anyway because the roots
aren't able to break out of that shape
and actually reach out into the other
you know the the natural soil or native
soil in extreme conditions is called
root girdling where the roots that have
set up in this containerized structure
as they grow and they get bigger they
get fatter and fatter and eventually
they actually choke each other off so
that you really it's like a choke hold
that's created by the plant on itself
due to the the shape of the root
structure that you put into the ground
that's why yeah your dad would tell you
to you know tear the bottom of it and
pull these roots apart but I mean you
can imagine how much stress that is on
the plant would it be nicer to just take
the entire good root structure with a
with a natural chuck sure enhancer
natural root structure and put it right
into the next container and let it
continue growing the plant doesn't even
know that it's been transplanted because
it really hasn't been you know
quote-unquote transplant has just been
given a little more room to grow now
yeah so that when I first heard about
root pruning or air pruning as I've also
heard it called was through smart pots
or fabric containers and so we've
started we started using fabric
containers only selling fabric
containers in our garden center but they
felt like an incomplete solution to me
for a few reasons one of them being is
that they're very challenging to
transplant out of trying to peel back
the fabric if you've ever done it it's a
real pain and try to pull the plant out
it's a lot of Labor I love the idea of
being able to just transplant the plant
right into the ground and not have to
worry about that container you know it's
because knowing it's going to break down
is was wonderful yeah if you're pulling
a plant out of a plastic pot or peeling
back a fabric wrapper you're you're
you're breaking the little tips that are
always at the at the edge there you know
the very very very end of the
and that's going to cause transplant
shock but I mean of course with
something that doesn't biodegrade you
have to remove that because otherwise
it'll stay there forever and ever and
ever
with the fertile pot you're just
planting it in the ground giving it a
little more room to grow and there is no
transplant shock as far as labor goes in
doing that one of our biggest markets is
actually landscape companies that are
installing large plantings and there's
generally about a 30% labor savings in
terms of the the labor costs of
installing using fertile pot versus
something that's coming out of a plastic
pot or a pot that you're going to have
to manipulate in some way before you can
put it into the ground because you're
just putting the pot right into the
ground put the soil on it and move on
there's no there's no removing the pot
there's no cleaning up at the end of the
day there's no going to the dump at the
end of the day and in you know dropping
off thousands and thousands of plastic
pots so just from a labor perspective
there's a there's an advantage there
well I think another big advantage too
is the amount of Education requires the
plant a plant or properly transplant
I've spent a lot of time teaching staff
how I want our plants transplant around
the around the nursery and that would
involve you know breaking up the roots
and going through that whole process not
having the plant out of the container
before it's in the soil for very long
and being able to transplant with a
biodegradable pot where it doesn't have
to necessarily be the optimal transplant
time if the plant hasn't filled that
container I'm not having to worry about
removing it and having all the soil fall
apart because there's not enough root
structure and I don't also on the same
note have to worry about it being a root
bound when I go to transplant it and
like you mentioned having to break apart
those roots so I love this idea
yeah the root pruning will allow you to
a bigger window of opportunity in terms
of when you actually have to transplant
because you're not going to get that you
know as you said container-bound plan
one thing that you do need to be aware
of when you plant a fertile pot
generally with any plant you want to
plant at the same grade you don't want
to bury the plant you don't want to
leave it you know raised up really high
so over time what can happen with a
fertile pot if you've filled it up with
soil you plant it in there and you've
grown in and the soil may have compacted
over the growing time so you end up with
a like a lip that's that's sticking up
you don't want to you
want to plant that so deep that the lip
is completely buried you're going to
want to plant it at grade and then just
simply tear off the lip because remember
the fertile parts going to be very soft
at this point you almost have to
consider it really more of a future root
ball that's that's not it's not
necessarily plant you can have to handle
it a little bit differently so you know
grabbing it by the lip you might tear
that lip off because it's very soft
whereas if you picked it up like a glass
of water it's very easy to move around
but these are some of the considerations
that you'll have to to be aware of when
using fertile pod versus say a plastic
pot so let's talk about some of these
differences here now like I said I was
familiar with fabric pots prior to
learning about these fertile pots and
some of the challenges I found was I
have a actual article on my blog about
some independent testing that was shared
with me regarding the heavy metal
content of some of these fabric pots
coming out of China I do worry about the
even with these I haven't seen anything
on molded plastic pots but I do worry
about people growing edible crops in
some of these potential containers
because you know you're growing out in
the summer in ninety degree temperature
if those pots have BPA or other things
that can break down at high temperatures
I do worry about that so that would be
one one thing to be concerned about with
fabric or plastic pots another potential
issue there is root temperature I assume
the fertile pot would be better at
reducing reducing the heat compared to a
black plastic pot on a hot summer day or
is that a fact well there yeah it's a
double-edged sword it will be better at
reducing the temperatures however it's
also going to try out a lot faster than
a plastic pot because remember the
entire pot you have again you have to
think of this as a future root ball
you're dealing with a way of holding
soil in shape while the plants develop
the roots penetrate the pot the putt day
the plant and the pot become one and
there is no way to remove the pot at
that point but it's also going to trans
evaporate across the entire surface of
the pot so while it works well say in
sub irrigation systems where you've got
you put the pot in a you know a small
low bath of water and it will wick up
like a sponge the opposite is also true
so you do have to be careful about
keeping the pots moist you don't want to
let them just sit in the hot Sun and
bake just like your dad told you don't
let the pots don't when you pull a plant
out of a pass
don't don't sit it out the Sun for a
couple hours before you planted you have
to consider the the fertile pot as
something that's been you know out of
the pot if you will that's a really good
point uh yeah I don't always I don't
always think about that but yeah I did
notice with my fabric pots I do have to
water more frequently than in plastic
containers yeah well I would give you
the the pluses and minuses I mean
there's you know advantages and
disadvantages to every system yeah so
another thing regarding these fertile
pots is you do have the environmental
impact of shipping them you know the
fossil fuel cost of getting them here
from France tree relatively speaking I
still think that that environmental
impact is going to be less than that of
a fabric container or especially a
plastic container I mean right now at my
nursery I have these giant one in two
yard totes that are just full of old
containers that I've people drop them
off at our nursery all the time and so
we you know no one wants them because a
lot of commercial operations won't reuse
containers because of the potential for
pathogens and disease sure and the cost
to and labor to sanitize these
containers is just not it's not worth it
so I'm excited to stop having to you
know take these containers in and store
them on my property and then potentially
also have to take them to the dump and
add more plastic back into our
environment so in that regard I think
they still have less of an environmental
impact even though they are coming all
the way from France well I can give you
a couple of little points that I mean
well first of all the majority the
shipping is on water which is a
relatively low carbon impact in terms of
you know pounds of carbon per mile if
you will compared to say trucking which
is very high but one of the neat things
about the way fertile produces these
pots is that they use hydroelectric
energy that's produced from the creek
from the stream that is is next to them
there's three generating stations so all
of the electricity that's used in the
process is you know completely renewable
the the forests that they harvest the
trees from are non GMO GMOs not
permitted in France period there's no
clear cutting permitted they must plant
with you know at least I think it's five
or six species of trees I might be a
little off on the number zero but it's
quite a few and they're they're not
allowed
to use heavy machinery in there so it's
it's really a very different way of
foresting than say in the United States
where you have you know just massive
tracts of land that are clear-cut you
won't see that at all in France they've
been actively managing this forest the
the wood is cut from for over 400 years
a long time ago they cut down everything
they made a big mistake and then the
King of France to decree that you know
there's going to be no more of this and
so that's why you don't see this kind of
clear cut and slash logging in Europe
that's great that's great to hear
so changing directions a little bit here
you mentioned that you can get some
mould on these containers yup over time
can you talk a little bit about that
sure basically what the what we're
talking about is sacrifice sacrifice are
an opportunistic fungus that will feed
on dead and decaying material the
Fertile pot itself is sterile when it's
produced because the temperatures that
that the pot is basically baked it's
almost like making paper mache
where the the wood is ground up it's put
into a slurry there's a screen or a
sieve that dips into that a vacuum is
formed it draws the enough wood up onto
the screen that screen goes into an oven
for about 45 to 50 minutes
where it's oh it's almost three hundred
and something degrees I mean nothing can
live through that there are no pathogens
at all alive on the plants or on the
pots when they are delivered to you
however in your greenhouse you might
have satellites well it's likely you
have sacrifice floating around it's a
natural part of the soil
it actually makes healthy soil to have
sacrifice in there so if somebody says
well I'm getting mold on my pots and you
know your pots are causing a problem
here it's not the pots that are the
problem it's really dirty greenhouses
that are causing the problem people
don't like to hear that but usually the
the answer that I give to them I said do
you still have some in the box say well
yes I do we'll take some bring them home
put them on your shelf in the in the
kitchen and grow some there and tell me
if you get the same fungus and the
answer is almost every single time no I
don't get the same fungus and it's a
matter of sanitation in the greenhouse
as far as as the separate fights now
several fights are not a bad thing
they're actually a good thing for soil
health
however they are unsightly and for
people trying to grow a commercial
product
that can be a problem so it's it's the
pot will support life because it is
biodegradable that's the definition of
biodegradable it must be able to support
life and if you've got a set prophytes
loading around the greenhouse it's
possible that you can get mold or fungus
growing on there and sanitation is the
key to solving that problem yeah I think
it's important for people to realize
that not all microbes are bad and that's
no they're actually good I mean a lot of
are very good you know that's that's a
part of a natural healthy soil structure
is to have mold and fungus in there that
are creating a you know a vibrant
ecosystem yeah now when I first found
out about this I was I was super excited
and I thought my natural progression
would be a you know like a 2x2 inch cube
or maybe starting in a four inch with
our veggie start and then going into
like possibly a one gallon and then up
to a five gallon and then I we started
talking a little bit more and you made
it clear to me that these pots only go
up to a certain size for a reason began
when I started thinking about it made
sense because they do biodegrade we
can't have you know mother plants or
larger plants so what what's the largest
size that's really feasible with a
fertile pot the largest size that's
that's really feasible with a photo pot
is about a five inch round pot when you
would do actually make one that's a
little bit bigger than that but it'sit's
very difficult to manage because the
weight of the wet soil in there compared
to the volume of the pot or to the
surface area the pot it's so heavy that
it's very difficult to move them around
without you know breaking them quickly
and and then becoming a problem so
realistically about a five inch pot is
about the largest size that you're going
to want to do one of the interesting
things one of our biggest markets is
grape production for for wine grapes and
many many years ago everyone thought
well we want a bigger pot for a better
plant and we actually have a pot that is
about four inches in squared about maybe
seven or eight inches tall and that was
the standard for a lot of great plants
for a long time and then somebody
decided well you know you've got to pot
this a little bit smaller than that it's
about maybe three inches wide and about
oh four inches tall they started using
them and they realized that they were
able to get a lot more plants in the
greenhouse and because of the type
rude structure remember we're setting up
the natural route structure with the
enhanced air printing that's going on
they were actually able to get de
fruiting and flowering than the same
amount of time that they were with a
larger pot going into the field before
that so suddenly these guys all switched
to a well it's a seven by nine
centimeter pot that became the standard
for a long time and then somebody got
the great idea let me look at your pot
that's even a little bit smaller than
that and right now the main standard for
the the grape industry is a five
centimeter by nine centimeter pot which
is about you know two inches or so by
about three and a half inches deep and
they've been able to put many more pots
into the greenhouse and be able to get
to a fruit production in the field in
the same amount of time but increase
their output tremendously that's great
so a larger container is not necessarily
going to be more beneficial now that
though okay in some cases it can be a
problem because if you've got now when
you're when you're transplanting if
you're going into less than if you're
transmitting into the soil let's say
you're going into less than desirable
soil conditions if you have a very large
pot and you you put that into the hole
and the the you're going from a really
nice peat moss mix or you know what
other substrate you're using the roots
tend to not want to explore into less
than desirable soil conditions out there
so this is why having the smaller pot
forces the roots out and especially if
you've got the fertile pot where the
roots are on the outside of the pot and
they're in contact they generally tend
to explore into that surrounding soil a
lot faster than something that's got a
lot more soil that it can use up in a
really comfortable space so the smaller
pot doesn't take into account the
fertility system involved or the
fertigation going on so I would assume
in the smaller container you're you're
probably fertilizing a little more
frequently for these these grape growers
because there's less fertilizer in the
soil because you're using less media
well there's there's the same amount of
fertility needed per you know cubic inch
of plant material I don't think it
necessarily you know increasing your
rates you're going to be maybe applying
a little bit more frequently because you
have less soil that that holds the
moisture and if you
you're you know liquid irrigating our
liquid feeding you might be using a
little more in terms of the amount of
time the number of cycles is you doing
there but the the fertility should be
about the same between a larger plant
and a smaller plant in terms of the
amount of fertilizers you're going to
need okay but you're able to reduce the
size of the container relative to reduce
the size of the container you increase
the output of your greenhouse per square
foot because remember the greenhouse has
an overhead cost there's you know it
cost so many dollars per square foot to
run that place whether you have you know
one plant in there or 10,000 plants in
there so when you can divide that
operating the overhead operating costs
across more plants you're going to be
more profitable sure and I think this is
even more of an issue with cannabis
because a lot of them are using
artificial lighting which costs even
more money from an electrical
perspective and energy perspective so
having being able to create that that
canopy with you know less square footage
I think is a great option for sure
now the question is going to be can you
get to fruiting and flowering with like
whether the grapes is what I'm familiar
with and you know I can't speak to
cannabis with with any degree of
expertise but it's going to be a
question of do you get to flowering in
the same amount of time where you can
actually harvest with more plants that's
that's really the question yeah and one
thing you mentioned too was going from
different types of media where you have
a really good potting soil inside your
container and then that exterior soil is
not of the same the same quality and the
roots won't want to push out we do we do
see that in a traditional landscape
because we're taking fruit trees for
example and that are grown in really
good soil that we're then putting out
into a ground where we don't always know
the fertility or the quality of the
right so that the homeowner has now for
cannabis most people are going from
potting soil to potting soil where
there's not that difference so it's not
so much of an issue yeah but if in a
situation say you had an outdoor
greenhouse where the soil quality was
not quite the same as the potting soil
then I could see where this container
size might might come into play or what
we like to do is take some good compost
or a portion of that potting soil and
mix it in with the native soils around I
guess in this case it would probably
around your container but
generally we do it around in the hole we
dig that hole twice the size of our root
ball and then mix that in so that the
roots will want to reach out past that
original shape they were right right
this is why it's important to have the
roots on the outside of the pot like you
do with the fertile pot so they're
already in contact with that right away
they don't want to just stay in this
nice little home that they've got right
there you know one of the one of the
things that we're finding in terms of
transplanting there is the the guys who
are doing sun-grown hemp production seem
to be experiencing some success with the
fertile pots because they're going into
you know the soil outside you're going
into a another larger pot with really
nice compost in there might not make as
much of a difference there yes so in
general we're using this for to put it
in terms that most growers are used to
is we would use them for our seed trays
for maybe a traditional four inch
container and then up to about a one
gallon or number one sized container is
sort of the largest size fertile pot is
that correct yeah yeah we're really a
propagation company it's it's you know
when the five inches are the largest or
twelve centimeters the largest that we
could do right now that's that's
realistically feasible we're not
somebody who's going to be providing you
with three and five and 15 and 25 gallon
containers after that it just it's not
possible with a biodegradable container
like that and we're really meant for
getting it started in the greenhouse
going from a seed or a cutting but
that's another thing I kind of wanted to
bring up is you know we our propagation
and we can produce a tremendous root
structure we can produce a natural root
structure but it depends on what you
bring to the party if you are starting
into a fertile pot with a seed or with a
cutting or a clone or even a plug
something that's coming out of a really
good plug system that's been moved right
on time or a nellie pot or some of these
other you know forties and these these
kind of plug systems it will perform
very well but if you bring to the party
an overgrown plug that is wrapped up and
in a containerized structure I can't
undo that with the fertile pot so it's
important that you start from the
beginning and get your root structure
right from the very beginning as soon as
you compromise that restructure with any
kind of containerization there is no
system that's going to be able to undo
that so the whole idea here is just
minimizing transplant shock we're trying
to keep the plant as happy as possible
so we're not adding on any delays in
terms of our overall plant cycle and you
mentioned some of these other containers
or propagation methods can we touch on
the differences between fertile pot and
the pros and cons of like soil blocks
Oasis cubes peat pots rapid rooters some
of these things that people are more
familiar with well there's there's a lot
of systems out there I mean it's a you
know absolutely amazing the ingenuity
that people have had over the years in
trying to you know produce propagation
systems I'll which particularly one do
you want to tackle let's start with so
let's just start with an easy one so no
blocks was one that I had never heard of
until recently one of my employees
mentioned that on her tiny farm cheese's
these things that make make little
blocks of soil so there actually isn't a
container around her plant
I had an initial thought on that but
I'll go and let you speak to it first
it's kind of like if you were a kid and
you had a little you're building a
sandcastle at the beach and you got a
mold that's shaped like a brick and you
pack the sand in there and then you pull
it out that's essentially what you're
doing the problem with the soil block is
that you're compressing the soil you're
reducing the the air ratio in there and
the availability of oxygen is really the
number one factor in determining whether
or not roots are going to develop so
you've got to have a substrate that
allows for good aeration in there and
when you compress something you're
limiting those air spaces and making it
harder for roots to develop yeah that
was my concern with compaction yeah you
don't see that I mean I see that in a
lot of small organic operations
especially in the Northeast but I have
never ever seen that in any serious
commercial operation I wanted to talk to
you about peat pots because I have used
those in the past with clones and
seedlings and I've seen them in you know
Home Depot for example what's the big
difference there between a fertile pot
and a peat pot one of the ways you can
tell the difference between a fertile
pot and a peat pot is look at the bottom
of the pot if there's a drain hole cut
into it then it's a peat pot if there's
no drain holes cut into it then it's a
fertile pot well the reason that the
peat pots are using the drain holes cut
into them is because the wall of the
is not porous enough to allow the air
the roots and the water to pass easily
through the pot so they cut a drain hole
into it and of course you know by
extension you can you can see that as
the roots reach the edge of that pot
they're not going to pass through
they're going to they're going to turn
inside now as the pot breaks down you
will start to get roots passing through
the sidewall of the pot this is true
but you if you go into the the box
stores and you look at some of the the
vegetable plants that are offered in
peat pots you'll see on the instructions
it says to tear the bottom of the pot
off before you plant it in the ground
and there's a simple reason for that
because they want this the roots to be
in contact with the soil and the pot is
not going to break down on its own as
easily in the ground so with the peat
with a fertile pot we do not recommend
tearing the bottom the bottom of the pot
off and matter of fact we don't
recommend recommend doing anything
except putting it into the soil or the
next larger container okay and then what
about what about Oasis cubes or rapid
rooters those are two really common ones
I see in the industry you know one is
sort of a synthetic or artificial medium
yeah and the other one uses it looks
like a rich rubber base so I sim glues
can you touch on those real quick
well the Oasis has got some some
advantages in that it's extremely
consistent material you're going to have
a really high media to air ratio in
there
but it's also completely devoid of any
organic matter so there is no cation
exchange with Oasis when you are growing
with the wases it's a it's a very
technical product and you can grow a
good plant with that for sure but you
have to be very very careful about
making sure that your fertility is
dead-on
and it's very very consistent so there's
like I said there's some advantages
disadvantages to everything when you're
using a fertile pod or when using any
kind of organic media you've got you
know good cation exchange you're going
to have the ability for that soil to
hold and release nutrients to the plant
as needed so it's a little more
forgiving than then foam products the
rubber glue is another interesting where
the glue plugs or the rubber dirt is
another interesting product it's its
media that's mixed with glue and then
poured into trays you'll see it in
things like
for Mom and I guess rapid Rooter I'm not
exactly familiar with that one but if
it's a it's a glue plug it's the same
kind of thing and the benefit to those
is that as the roots develop they don't
reach the edge of the the cell that
they're in yet you can still pull the
whole thing and the plug will stay
together because of the the glue that's
in there I'm not sure if they're
available in organic or not but the idea
with the fertile pot is that everything
in there's organic there is no glues
there's no binders that's in there okay
and any comments on rock wool cubes
ah rockwool cubes um again it's it's a
it's a mineral I do not believe it's
approved for use in organics at the
moment although I that seems to be
changing all the time so you know check
back with uh with armory on that
relatively expensive compared to fertile
pot with a media in there and then
impossible to get rid of at the end of
the story because it doesn't doesn't
break down and you're gonna have to
throw it away in a landfill and then the
last one I had on my list was arrow
cloners I see a lot of people using
those and then going into soil and for
me that challenge was always trying to
be delicate to the roots and get them
planted correctly without damaging the
plant and I always seem to get
transplant Chalk when you when going
from a narrow corner in this soil I'm
sorry I can't speak to that one I didn't
do my homework on what an arrow cloner
was it's sort of a misting system so the
the okay roots are just sitting in air
and then being continually misted in
underneath the level of the that you can
picture like up right a giant Rubbermaid
tote sort of thing with holes in the top
and then there's a aeroponic or misting
system underneath that the roots are
exposed to so you can put a nutrient
solution or or some sort of cloning
solution to that sure so that's yeah
that's that's going to be there's going
to be water roots that's that's real
lying you know exclusively on on taking
up the nutrients from the moisture there
that's in the air making that transition
to terrestrial roots is is difficult
sometimes so that's why you're getting
the transplant shock there if you're
trying to go into a soil from there you
can probably continue to grow and go
into you know hydroponic systems and it
would probably do well but the
transition between you know water roots
to terrestrial roots is a difficult one
it's a little easier to go the other way
from terrestrial too to water
roots and that's why you'll see like
with the total pot a lot of people will
start with a very very small plug like a
72 so that's a you know one of our
strips they'll start them they'll grow
them you know lettuce and other kind of
herbs that they're growing
hydroponically and they'll take those
and they'll transplant those plugs into
floating rafts and the roots will then
continue to grow down through and into
the the nutrient solution tank
underneath and the water roots will
develop there but it's a little more
difficult to go the other way around
sure and what sort of media are people
using typically in your containers or
does it vary across the board it's all
across the board depending upon what
they personally think is the the best
one for their crops I mean you know the
majority people are using a soilless
peat light based mixes a lot of choir is
now being incorporated people are doing
you know mushroom compost there's all
sorts of different formulas that are out
there but you can put whatever formula
you want into the pot it doesn't you
know you don't you're not restricted to
to one one sort of substrate or another
now I love encouraging people on this
podcast to look outside of the cannabis
industry for you know products nutrients
information in general and research and
so can you tell me a little more about
some of the applications that you're
seeing with these containers like you
said they've been around for a long time
now with the grape industry oh yeah well
the grape industry has been you know one
of our biggest customers for a long time
we do just massive massive numbers in
Europe we do very large numbers in
California some in New York here but
it's it's the grape industry has been a
you know a reliable customer for us for
a long time one of the other industries
that we do very very well with is
breeders people who are experimenting
and trying to grow you know the perfect
crop and they're their seed companies
and so what they'll do is they'll you
know maybe they might be doing GMO stuff
but they will be they'll buy a million
pots they'll plant up and they'll grow a
million different seedlings and then
they select out of that 50 that they're
going to carry on from there
the remaining leftovers they want to get
rid of and they don't want anybody to
have that genetic information so they
compost it in the composting process
the heat for the composting process
destroys all the genetic information so
there's nothing left over and they don't
have to remove and clean up a million
pots at the end of the story they just
put them in the compost pile and turn
them into wind rows from there but the
majority of our customers are normal you
know nurseries and greenhouses that are
propagating to grow on for something
that's going to be a finished product
later that's great I you know we can
probably only talk about containers for
so long as a topic yes but I will if I
could go on forever
that's impressive I mean I can
appreciate that I will say that I was
pleasantly surprised with the pricing
associated with these containers and I'm
positive that between the reduction in
transplant shock and the ability to you
know have a larger window to transplant
in the labor savings of not having to
remove the plant and Transplant it and
more traditional method is going to
Morgan more than pay for themselves
regardless of your opinions on the
ecological and environmental impact of
you know traditional containers so I'm
really excited to incorporate these into
our processes in our nursery and start
working with more of these larger
cultivation facilities or even you know
smaller you know medical or or home
growths that want to switch over it's
it's very very affordable that you know
we're talking pennies on a lot of these
pots so it's not yeah yeah I mean our
customers you know some of them are
really environmentally conscious and you
know we check all the boxes they're you
know it's a it's a it's a terrific
product from an environmental standpoint
of view but the majority of our
commercial customers are not necessarily
environmentally conscious they're
conscious about pennies and so that's
that's where we also shine there yeah I
mean I'm a huge proponent of organics
but I try not to push that too hard for
people because it can be off-putting so
I love products or methods that just
happen to be organic but they make sense
economically to where even if you didn't
care about the environment or your
ecological impact you're still going to
want to use this product or you're still
going to want to use this methodology
because it's right it's going to save
you money and time
and grow a better plant exactly one
other thing I wanted to say was a lot of
people you know this is when people are
asking me about how long does it take to
break down in the soil well this is a
question that I get a lot of times and
my smart aleck answer is it doesn't
matter because the pot is porous and
it's biodegradable it's not stopping air
routes or water from moving back and
forth over that barrier the longer
answer is it really depends on the
microbial action and where you are
located if you're in you know Antarctica
it's going to probably take a long time
to break down it's like a book you keep
it dry it'll last forever if you if its
moist and wet it's going to break down
faster so like I said the smart aleck
answer is it doesn't matter because the
plant is just there it's as if the pot
never existed realistically for most
people in North America about a year or
so you won't be able to find any
evidence of the spot so that does bring
up a storage thing that you and I talked
about off air was that you do need to
store these containers in a dry location
you know that so they're not getting in
contact with moisture which can cause
the microbes to break them down faster
mice and rats may potentially chew on
them if you had them say just sitting
outside in your greenhouse yes
in my barn here I have you know many
many boxes of fertile pots that are four
samples some of them are many years old
most of them sending out enough samples
that they're they're turning over but
it's it like I said it's like a book if
you keep it dry like it is in the
library it'll stay for hundreds of years
as soon as you let them get wet they'll
break down but we did have a problem
when we first moved here and put them
with the pots of the barn that the mice
were eating them and the problem I'm
willing to share fertile pots with the
mice that's not a problem however they
only want to eat right up the stack and
they take one little Halfmoon out of the
top of every pot as it goes up so we got
cats and that solved our problem that's
great now I want to change like switch
gears a little bit because one of the
things besides this product is you have
another product that's more specific for
gardeners and not so much cannabis but I
do field a lot of our a lot of people
are growing cannabis are also interested
in growing their own vegetables and for
me as a vegetable gardener
I was really excited and I can't wait to
try this out I've been reading about it
online and I know I have a sample coming
in the mail today I can't wait to check
it out now this product is for dealing
with slugs
yes it's called slug gone bull pellets
it's very cool it comes out of the UK
and it's been on that while it's been
around for quite a while now but
realistically as as slug on wool pellets
it's been on the market for about 10
years now and what it is it's pelletized
waste wool that you put around a plant
and when it swells up and it it felts
together it forms a barrier that slugs
and snails don't want to cross over and
the neat thing about it is that it's a
season-long barrier because it takes so
long for it to break down that'll stay
efficacious for eight to fourteen months
the way that the way that this works is
you have a sheep and you when you shear
the sheep you get the raw fleece which
has all of the stuff that has the good
fibers in the in the the the lanlan but
it also has a lot of sweat and poo and
dirt and other things like that and so
when you take it to a scouring facility
they take all of the good fibers in the
lanlan out and then what's left over is
called shaadi which is basically what it
sounds like and it was a waste product
and so in order to get rid of it what
they would do is they would throw it on
to the fields next to these scouring
facilities where they were growing
rhubarb just to dispose of it they would
turn it in and they began to notice that
in these fields they were not getting
any Sluggers nail damage where in the
fields where they were not turning the
slug the slug gun or the shotty into
they were getting some so they began to
figure out what's going on here is that
slugs and snails have a mucous foot that
is easily irritated by anything that's
scratchy wool has little the fibers of
wool have little hooks and barbs in it
that allow it to felt together to form a
fabric it's also makes its Scratchy and
so as the slugger snail tries to crawl
over this this wool product here
they find it irritating to their their
their mucous foot and they choose to go
somewhere else it doesn't kill them it's
not a pesticide it's not a poison it's a
barrier that prevents them from reaching
the plant that you want to protect it
also acts as a
Wiccans acting as a as a wick that's
pulling the moisture out of this lugs
foot they don't like that either they
don't like to be scratched and they
don't like to be dry but there's some of
there's other benefits to it besides the
fact that it's going to keep a plant
protected for eight to fourteen months
from slugs and snails it's also a
moisture mulch because as you put this
down if the pilots swell up to about
three times their size they lock
together they form this mat that the
water can penetrate through rain will
penetrate down through but it doesn't
evaporate out from underneath so it
keeps the soil a little moisture around
the plant there when the does rain or
when you have you know high winds or
whatever it's not going to blow away
it's a it acts very much the same way
diatomaceous earth does in terms of
forming a barrier but it doesn't wash
away it doesn't it doesn't blow away you
don't need to reapply after every single
rain like you do with a lot of the iron
sulfate products it's also a weed
barrier I'm gonna be like that you know
the Ginsu knife here got here for a
second but the wait there's more
it's a weed barrier because it sets up
this mat that the seeds can't can't come
up through the weeds don't want to come
up through and seeds that land on top of
it because remember it's wicking the
moisture away from the surface the
surface is very dry so seeds that land
on top are less likely to be able to
volunteer because there's not a lot of
available moisture on the surface of
this plant it's also a but wait there's
more there's also it's a thermal barrier
because wool has thermal properties so
during the summer it will keep the soil
a little cooler around that plant it'll
also keep the soil a little warmer on
the shoulder seasons underneath so you
can extend your growing season to some
extent and at the end of the story
basically it's organic matter that's
just biodegrading and adding organic
matter to your soil to increase the
health of your soil so are we getting
any nutrition or nutrients out of this
well this is where I get into a little
bit of a pickle here in the the label in
the UK there the label says contains
slow-release nutrients or because it is
organic matter so there is technically
some fertility to it however in the
United States if you claim any kind of
fertility you are a fertilizer and
you have to get DEP registration in
every single state that you want to sell
your product in and this was just not
feasible for us so the easier thing in
the US label it does not say anything
about nutrition on there because
nobody's going to buy this as a
fertilizer it's just not not really
effective as a fertilizer so the easier
thing was to say for the US we're not
going to make any claims whatsoever
about fertility at least in writing okay
but we can apply fertilizer over the top
of it that would soluble eyes in water
down through it you can apply fertilizer
over top of it that will soluble and
we'll go through correct however you're
you're if you're using slow-release
materials it might be a looked as a bit
of a barrier there you're definitely
going to have to have enough water to
flush it down through there okay and one
thing I wanted to talk about was prior
to learning about this product there
were sort of four options that I had for
organic gardeners that we're dealing
with slugs and the first one was Sluggo
which I believe is iron phosphate it's
made by a large corporation I can't
remember if it's Dow or Monsanto wasn't
one of those large egg companies which I
try not to support when I can when I can
help it
but they that's where I that's what I
was using and I didn't love the idea of
adding a you know an iron bit iron
phosphate based product to my soils
consistently over time but it did it
does help control slugs in addition to
that the next option would have been
like beer traps or things like that you
know they're messy there are a lot of
work to set up and maintain plus I would
rather drink the beer then give it to my
slugs sure the other option was going
out there at night with your clippers
and just manually chopping them up as
you see them you're not going to get
every one but you can help keep them
under control that way and then the last
option was another barrier option which
is copper tape yeah but one thing you
talked about was not all slugs that we
see are actually above-ground right the
the slug skin slugs do go underground oh
this is one of the reasons that the slug
on wall pellets cannot be used you can't
just take a barrier and put it all the
way around your garden you know ten feet
by ten feet let's say because the slugs
will go under it so what you need to do
with with the slug
you need to put a four inch wide barrier
around the base of each plant so that as
they try to come up they're going to
encounter that the slug gun in there Wow
it's again it's a barrier product that
can't be used on a per square foot basis
but I want to touch briefly on what
you're talking about with you know all
these other methods are basically
killing the slugs and slugs you know
love of our Hatem they are part of the
ecosystem and when you remove any link
in the chain and ecosystem you're
creating a less than desirable situation
birds eat them lizards and frogs eat
them they do eat depending on the slugs
they do eat some of your pests out there
but it's something that what we choose
to do is say let's decide the plants you
can't have and you can go somewhere else
and be part of the ecosystem but just
don't eat this plant here please I
really like that little way of looking
at it slugs are a big issue here in
Washington state up with the weather
that we have or we have a ton of slugs
and there's nothing more frustrating
than growing a spinach plant and putting
all this time into it only to come out
the next day and have it just be munched
well snow it's no coincidence that the
weather in the UK is similar to the
weather in you know Northwest Washington
so one other thing about this slug gun
is that we didn't touch on yet is it
does have an odor so remember I was
saying that the oh the shaadi is
basically everything's left over after
you take out the long fibers the short
fibers the landline etc and so you're
gonna have a pelletized product that
smells a bit like a barn you can
actually smell it if you put your nose
right up to the bag you can you can kind
of smell it through there first time
that we were deciding to see whether we
wanted to work with this we took a tray
we put it in our laundry room when we
put some slug on in there and I I poured
some water over I wanted to see what
happened we went out to dinner we came
back and opened up my house and like
what is that stink it smells like a barn
in here and it was the slug gun
obviously it's not meant as an interior
product however when you put the slug on
around your plant material outside as it
dries up within about a day or so any of
that odor is gone some people love the
smell of the barn some people hate the
smell of the barn
but it is a fact
of life that logon will have a slight
odor to it when it's first applied but
within one to two days at the most
I challenge you to be able to smell
anything even if you put your nose right
up to it I'm really excited to try this
out in some of my raised beds next
season because I always hate battling
slugs and I usually just take him and
chuck them into the woods you know
across my property but I love I love
knowing that I can safely protect my
plants and not have to be so vigilant
all the time and worry about losing you
know my favorite vegetables right and
you know again remember this is
something you'll put down in the
springtime as soon as you've determined
where your plants are going to be you
put some slug on around them and then
you walk away you don't have to do
anything after that it's going to swell
up on its own but you need a band about
four inches wide or so around the plant
so that the slugs can't cross over it oh
but it doesn't need to be thick it
doesn't need to be mounted up one pellet
layer thick is there one probably or
high is enough and if you want to try to
do this as judiciously as possible you
can spread your pellets around let them
swell up and then you can come back and
see where are my holes you can't have
any holes you can't have any gaps
because slugs will find their way
through those gaps to your plant so you
can come back you just drop it a couple
little pellets on top of the holes they
will then in turn swell up and naturally
felt on their own together you don't
have to you know you don't have to do
anything but put it down and let it
swell on its own and it's going to stay
in place there for the entire season
you don't you're not coming back every
time it rains this is a one-time
application per season that's great and
it brings up one last question for me
since you happen to be married to one of
the foremost entomologist in the country
what are the effects of this product in
terms of beneficial insects or other
insects no negative effects no negative
effects of it remember this is it I mean
it's like putting a wool sweater around
your plant there's there's not any
positive or negative effect there so
it's really just slugs and snails it
slugs and snails you know any other
pests will crawl right over it I mean
it's it's it's not it's not stopping
anything other than something that has a
mucous foot something that can be
irritated I mean imagine rubbing a piece
of sandpaper on your eyeball that's what
it feels like to a slug trying to
so for this stuff that's a good analogy
sorry sorry fed a patrique well I think
that's all of my questions for today I I
hope that listeners will find this
useful and if they want I will I will
definitely put all of your contact
information out there we will have the
slug on and the fertile pots available
on our website as well I'm really
excited to start working with you on on
some of these products Thank You Jen
appreciate the time that was William
Evans the North American distributor of
fertile pots and slug gun you can view
links to these products as well as
Williams website on the podcast page
I hope this podcast will help people in
considering better ways to propagate
their plants as well as more sustainable
solutions to plastic pots at least in
the smaller sizes
we've switched over our entire farm this
year and now we'll be educating our
community on why our veggie starts are
in these containers instead of plastic
pots that they have to put into a
landfill plus the big benefit of
reducing transplant shock you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast I'm your host Todd
Hussey don't forget that there's more
information and articles available on
our website and blog at WWE
organics calm as well as links to the
data and information we discussed in
this episode on the podcast page and if
you enjoy these podcasts please take a
moment to leave me a review on iTunes
and send me your feedback and
suggestions through our website contact
page or tad at K is organics calm thanks
for listening