[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge my guest this week is Bryant
Mason Bryant is a certified crop adviser
who specializes in organic cannabis
nutrition he has spent the last 3 years
working to combine Precision laboratory
techniques with data science in an
effort to unravel the complexities of
cannabis soil and crop nutrition along
with his work on soiless media he also
helps outdoor cultivators around the US
with nutrient management and cover
cropping if you would like to do soil
testing or help interpreting a soil test
his website is WW W soyd consulting.com
hey Brian thanks for coming on the
show thanks for having me Tad yeah I
know we've talked a lot off air and had
a lot of long conversations I love
chatting with you about soil and soil
science so I'm I'm really glad to have
you on the podcast uh can we start off
uh telling the listeners a little bit
about your
background sure I I am a certified crop
advisor through the American Association
of
agronomy which essentially means that I
went through a series of tests to get
certified and I work with a number of
different Growers on soil and crop
nutrition so I specialize specifically
on nutrient management and even more
than that organic nutrient management so
I work with a number of different crops
but primarily cannabis and Prim ly
soiless media so I've really enjoyed
listening to your show and I think we've
we always have a lot to talk about so
I'm looking forward to it yeah me too
and for people who haven't checked out
Bryant's Instagram it's uh _ do be sure
to check that out he's always putting up
new videos walking around in cool places
talking about organic matter or
irrigation or numerous topics so I want
to recommend that real quick for people
um but let's dive in talking about
um something you and I have talked a
little bit about is this theory of of
soil testing with soilless media versus
actual real top soil and sort of what
those differences are because they're
quite different media with quite
different levels of expertise um do you
want to kind of take that
away sure and this is one of the most
fascinating topics to me because as I've
worked more and more with cannabis
production over the last several years
I've noticed that that a lot of the
traditional soil science developed in
Top Soil top soil being real mineral
soil composed of sand silt and Clay just
doesn't necessarily apply to soiless
Media the major differences um that I
think about are um the homogeneous
nature of top soil so for eons it's been
mixed and um t uh soiless media isn't
necessarily like that so it has larger
particle sizes that are are not quite as
homogeneous um and also the underlying
difference is that there isn't any clay
in a soiless media so when you look at
the CC on a soil test for example uh
it's the cation exchange capacity that
measures the soils ability to hold
nutrients on the clay colloid it has to
be interpreted differently as does the
organic matter number and really going
down the list um you you really have to
look at the soil chemistry quite a bit
differently in a in a soilless media
um the other obvious difference that
that most people understand is the
physical characteristics uh there's much
more um poor space in the soiless media
it drains more quickly and therefore um
because there's no clay colloid and
because of that high drainage ability it
doesn't necessarily hold nutrients as
easily and so the majority of nutrient
holding capacity tends to come through
organic matter as oppos as opposed to
Mineral colloids so those are just a a
handful of different is I can kind of
stop there but um more or less I think
about solubility a lot in a soilless
media and I think less about balancing
the mineral
colloid I definitely want to hear your
thoughts on that um but just I want to
back up really quickly so when we are
looking and evaluating a soil for
example or a soiless media traditionally
with soil we're talking
about three things at least in my brain
um you may correct me based on your
Agronomy background but I think of the
physical properties of the soil which
would be sand silk clay or that air to
water ratio I think about the biological
properties of the soil that's all the
microorganism soil food website and then
I think about the mineral aspects of the
soil what sort of nutrition does that
infertility does that soil hold and so
those three things kind of form like a a
mental triangle for me when I'm
evaluating or sort of trying to look at
what the limiting factor of growth might
be in a given soil um can you kind of
talk a little bit about how these sort
of I guess pillars work together in
forming our understanding of
soil absolutely and I think that that
mental triangle is perfect I think about
that all the time as well and the
connection between the two is what's
Most Fascinating and so how I think
about it is that uh the biology is
critical for um primarily nutrient
cycling so that's that's really how I
think think about the connection between
chemistry and biology is that the the
biology is mineralizing or releasing
nutrients from the soil constantly and
there's a number of mechanisms in which
it does that and providing nutrient
availability to the plant and it's also
connected to the physical
characteristics of the soil because the
habitat as we all know soil is an
ecosystem and so if you zoomed in you
would see pore space and a number of
different um almost
I imagine the favellas um packed in
habitat where biology lives and so the
the gas exchange the water exchange all
of that the pH the Redux all of that
chemistry and all of that those physical
characteristics will Define the
biological community in act in a in a uh
a soil and um so you know when I think
about the three characteristics of
soil that you described I really think
about well what is it that we should be
managing and every single thing you do
to a soil will change all three of those
characteristics and so um as an
agronomist I think about you know how
can we measure and
manage uh the physical characteristics
and the chemical characteristics
primarily which will ultimately dictate
that biological profile and I know that
a lot of cannabis Growers are also very
passionate about managing the biological
IAL elements of soil but I think to your
point they're all critically important
and all highly interrelated and they
should all be considered with every
single decision that we make whether
it's an input decision or a tillage
decision or a cover cropping
decision yeah and just to touch on the
biological well first off I want to say
we seem to have different camps within
you know some of the more uh extreme
agonum Agronomy um theories where you
have people who've just focused solely
on BI ology and then you have people to
focus focus solely on Mineral balancing
um I guess you don't really see that so
much with on the sandil clay side but uh
it's it's interesting because they do
are are all so interrelated and one
thing that when you were talking it made
me think about is the fact that when we
think about uh biology and our soils
that soil is so diverse in any given
soil where there's pockets of Anor robic
activity pH is not constant throughout
the soil there's you know there's
different Pockets with different pH uh
throughout there that's created by the
biology by that you know air water
exchange you know we'll have the the
bacteria you know uh glomalin is
probably the most
uh known one to me in terms of the
bacteria forming glues and and and soil
Aggregates and and fungi doing the same
thing so it's a really complex process
um to think that we fully understand it
or even can really manage it on the
biological side I think is
um it might be a little bit arrogant on
our ends uh based on our current level
of
knowledge sure and yeah I I actually I I
am constantly devouring content and I
would say that where I've landed is that
because of the infinite complexity of
the the soil biology that's primarily
dictated longterm all the sence shows
that it's D that that community de
composition is determined long-term by
physical and chemical characteristics pH
um you know gas exchange I I choose to
focus on optimizing and managing those
and I let the biology fall into place
now there are some really really
exciting new scientific techniques that
are um looking at soil
biology um genome sequencing is the one
that comes to mind but there's a number
of other plfa and of other testing
techniques the problem with those is
that that the science and the scientists
that are really innovating in these
areas don't necessarily have targets
they don't know what they're striving
towards so even though it can be
measured it can't necessarily be managed
um and I I know a number of people would
disagree with me and I by all means I
think every approach um that is that is
biologically forward is positive yes but
as you know when I when I look at the
science and when I look at how to make
big management decisions I tend to to
believe that we should be doing things
that promote biological activity and
diversity but and and avoid those things
that don't and otherwise let nature go
through that complex process to Define
what that uh biological profile looks
like that being said we've come a long
way with bio stimulants just in the last
few years uh I know there's been a lot
of research worked done it's sort of an
exciting New Field in a lot of ways to
replace this whole uh chemical mindset
mindset that we had coming out of uh
World War II um that would be
essentially be applying you know a very
specific set of microbes to create a
very specific you know interaction in
the soil with with positive outcomes how
does that fit into sort of your your
thoughts on all
this yeah so I am really thrilled and
excited about the possibility of Bio
stimulants that aren't necessarily
active microbials but can also be
enzymes or various microbial exit dates
that produce a positive plant response
and I think there's a tremendous uh
opportunity there especially for um you
know late I I think of it as as sort of
a way to uh improve tpine profile and
just general genetic expression aside
from yield so really getting to those
quality characteristics of cannabis I
will say though that biostimulants can't
replace nutrition because at the end of
the day plants need nutrients to grow
and a lot of these bio stimulants aren't
providing uh enough quantity of actual
nut nutrients to for the metabolic
function of plant so they're an amazing
addition to a nutritional program but
they don't they can't necessarily
replace it unless that soil already has
uh sufficient and balanced nutrition to
feed a a heavy feeding cannabis plant
yeah that's a good point they can't
create elements out of thin air they
need to be and they need to be
accessible to the the microorganisms as
in present in order for them to have any
real effect and I think that's an
important thing because the argument
I've heard from some of the people on
the biological side would be that all
soils have sufficient mineral levels
it's all about getting the uh
microorganisms correct um however you
know I don't necessarily subscribe to
that do you have any thoughts in regards
to that as as a you know essentially a
rebuttal to this this idea of
mineralization yeah absolutely so
definitely not in the soiless media um
that that's just not uh the case now in
certain top soils sure in theory there
there's a lot of there's hundreds of
different hundreds or even you know a
thousand harvests theoretically however
we have to to keep in mind that we are
mining nutrients cannabis is uptaking a
tremendous amount of nutrients and we're
exporting that off of our farm to
Consumers and uh crop after crop that is
depleted and I think specifically of
nitrogen and and potassium um those
nutrients drop out very very quickly in
when you're yielding really heavy plants
of any annual for that matter or even
tree fruit um when you've
Harvest uh peaches or apples that those
nutrients need to be replaced and uh
I've never experienced a grower in a in
a degraded soil or a marginalized soil
that hasn't that's gotten away with not
um applying nutrition uh season after
season in a soilis media I it's it's um
there's just no way I mean the the the
quantity of nutrients in the soiless
media just isn't enough to sustain round
after round after round of heavy heavy
cropping and let's keep in mind too when
we're applying compost or compost te's
we're increasing nutrient cycling
through in you know if they're quality
let's say to uh we're increasing
nutrient cycling biological diversity
biological biomass but we're also giving
them a little bit of nitrogen and that
could be the limiting factor of growth
it may not necessarily be all these
microorganisms that are are really
helping when you're seeing results in
marginalized Souls it may be just a
little bit of n too I would
think absolutely and actually Tad I
think about this all the time and I
think about the great papers that you've
put out uh through kiss that that really
are um using experimental design to look
at these questions and I think this
would be an amazing one I don't know how
you would set up the experiment but um
to
identify if a the crop response to a te
or a canf for manage a Dom whatever is a
result of the microorganisms or the
nutrition because I've made teas with
Alfalfa and a number of different pretty
n
nutritious inputs and the output is a is
a fairly nutrient-rich tea and
oftentimes Growers report great crop
responses well we don't know the
function there we don't know the
mechanism to your point so I think that
would be an amazing study and something
to look at um just so we know more
because I think knowledge and
information is power not necessarily to
derail a certain school of thought but
rather just so we have more information
to manage our systems
yeah so
mentally I totally agree with you on
that I think when we're talking about
plant Health uh and and soil you
relative to soil Health we have to look
at what the limiting factor of growth is
for a plant is that the physical
properties of the soil is that some
particular mineral that's either uh in
excess or deficient um is it our
watering so that these nutrients are
available is it something in the
environment so figuring out what that
limiting factor of growth is because you
know I say this a lot in the podcast I
know this is something that you're quite
familiar with um we need to be really
strategic with what we're applying to
our soils into our plants it's not one a
silver bullet you know if your soil has
sufficient nitrogen don't put down a
nitrogen-rich product even if it was
that secret sauce that your buddy used
that made his crop turn out great it's
not it's not going to help and could
potentially be detrimental um which is
what which is kind of leads into this
idea of soil testing so um did you want
to add anything to that or you want to
dive a little bit into soil
testing yeah let's dive right into it I
I I mean I agree with everything you're
saying I think Precision is is is the
key to nutrient management so let's
let's jump into it okay so when we talk
about soil testing um a lot of people I
think find it daunting uh understandably
so I think I would even say I'm one of
those people and as I looked into it
more and more I actually had less faith
in a lot of the numbers I was I was
reading um in terms of variability
and I also had um I had trouble making
actionable decisions based on a soil
test and here's where someone like you
comes in as as a really helpful uh you
know area of expertise someone that you
can rely on to help interpret these
tests but how do you utilize Soul
testing like how how as a grower can we
become more comfortable with these tests
too great well let me first just touch
on variability because I know that
there's a lot of concern around that the
amount of soil that's used when running
a soil test I I um use Logan Labs
exclusively for the reason that all soil
tests and all soil labs are a little bit
different and so you have to stick to
the same uh lab to in order to make
sense and to order to in order to
establish targets that are useful so
that's really kind of an apples to
oranges industry which is unfortunate so
Logan uses you know a very small sample
size but and which sounds concerning on
when you first hear that but what I
found is that and I've looked at
thousands of of cannabis oils is
that the vast majority of the time the
the variability from sample to sample
does not actually change the ultimate
management decision so oftentimes
Growers will send me 10 different tests
maybe a test for every single baded in
five different group houses and um the
there's always variability um sometimes
upwards of 30 parts per million between
samples but ultimately the same pattern
always exists across soils and in fact
when it comes to top soils and a lot of
soiless media that's really homogeneous
the variability is is Tiny the first
time I uh worked on hazel nuts in the
wamit valley a really great grower uh
broke his farm into 10 different zones
and I was out there all day sampling
taking um extra careful precautions to
just make sure my sampling was rigorous
I I took multiple samples aggregated
into a single sample 10 different zones
it took me literally all day and the
results came back and I was shocked at
how they were almost identical the
chemistry was almost identical across
all of these samples and I've seen that
over and over and over again to the
point where I believe that often times
Growers are over sampling and there's
just kind of a common rule of thumb to
to break your F into a bunch of samples
but the reality is most of my
recommendations are are almost identical
across all of those samples so to me the
variability is less of a concern the
more I see this phenomenon does that
make sense it does I've sort of
experienced the same thing I would say
um what do you do though my my thought
goes to indoor cultivation with you know
soilless medum
or what a lot of people are calling
living soils um and uh crop differences
across beds so let's say we had 20 beds
in a room and five of them are doing
poorly and five of them are doing really
well I you know how do you have people
manage in in those situations in regards
to
testing what are the cultivars the same
in the thought experiment I mean rarely
yeah let's say they're they're probably
not in a in a realistic
facility okay right um so that's the
first thing so I I what I do is I help
Growers get their soils in a target
range where the vast majority of
cultivars will do very very well however
we all know that there are significant
cultivar differences nutritional
requirements and so the best way to
address that is to do to get your soil
in sufficiency and balance and to get it
close enough the goal is not Perfection
the close the the goal is to get it
toward improving levels and and then to
tissue test each individual cultivar and
change your soil targets based on uh
this the the tissue results and I've
I've worked with a number of Growers on
this but to go back to your question if
I'm seeing differences in if there's
like if there's significant deficiency
what that probably tells me is that all
the soil is out of whack but certain
cultivars are able to handle that
difference a little bit better so the
ones that are showing lower production
or uh deficiency symptoms are sort of
the canaries in the Coline in a sense um
that's one explanation the other
explanation is that the soil across that
Greenhouse isn't homogeneous and so what
I would do in that situation is I would
have uh the Growers sample from the poor
area and and the good area they could
either do two samples or four samples if
they just want to um again control for
that variability and usually what I
would see from my experience is that
that soil is again relatively similar
it's showing the same pattern but
certain cultivars are able to hand
handle you know that high magnesium or
uh the low the lower phosphorus or
whatever it may be that's that's showing
up in the poor producing
plants now that you say that I'm kind of
going thinking back in my head mentally
to some of the tests I've seen and
that I find that to be fairly accurate
the one thing I'll see variability on is
usually nitrates and pH across when
someone will test let's say all of their
beds sort of thing individually those
are the two things that I find kind of
fluctuate and maybe that's just due to
the genetics in the bed um or maybe
their watering habits I don't know but
um I think N I agree with the nitrogen
the nitrogen thing is is extremely hard
to manage both in outdoor food
cultivation as well as in cannabis
indoor outdoor nitrogen is is I spend so
much time thinking about nitrogen
Management in organic production P it's
it's extremely difficult the I think you
nailed it with watering you know if you
if you overwater one bed just a couple
of times even one time your nitrate is
extremely mobile so you're going to um
essentially flush out a little bit of
that nitrate so yeah the most
variability between beds I agree is is
usually in the
nitrogen do you want to talk a little
bit about nitrogen or do you want to
dive into
water um let's chat about nitrogen I
mean I have a few thoughts on nitrogen
um there's the like I said it's
extremely mobile and I think Growers
should keep in mind uh that it's removed
from the soil at the highest quantity
that nitrogen and and potassium are um
are removed in in cannabis production
in the highest quantity so in a soil the
first thing that's going to become
deficient is is going to be nitrogen and
potassium and specifically uh nitrogen
you know the the tissue Target for
nitrogen is is anywhere from three and a
half to 5% of the leaf tissue that's a
lot um there's no other nutrient
actually I take that back calcium is
also removed upwards in the 3 to 5%
range so that the first thing to keep in
mind is that is that you really have to
have a way to replenish nitrogen um
round after round otherwise you'll start
to see issues the issue with nitrogen is
that um I see it kind of like a gas tank
and so Logan tests for available
nitrogen which is defined as ammonium
plus nitrate and ammonium will always be
low as long as the soil uh as long as
the organic Amendments have have fully
mineralized um it should be about less
than one or two parts per million so the
nitrate number is really the important
one to look at and I see that as sort of
a gas tank but the issue is if you put
too much in you start to have crop
quality issues you start to call in
pests and disease uh fungal pressure
I've noticed a decrease in flavor and
aroma so it it messes with the
tpin and in general I believe it it it
can produce kind of a a lower density
flower quality and it it just causes
issues however the minute the plant runs
out of
nitrogen so many of the metabolic
functions stop so the physiology the
growth the flower development it really
is the fuel um in plant growth so the
final thing I want to mention is it's in
soil signs it's ephemeral so it's it's
uh mobile it changes very quickly and
there's there's not an easy way to get
an accurate accurate portrayal of how
much nitrogen you have because that
nitrate number is so fragile it's
bouncing all over the place all the time
so to me that's the most challenging
thing to uh manage and I believe you
know the Growers I've seen who get
consistently you know three pounds per
light or however you want to measure it
grams per watt they are actually running
their nitrogen a little bit lower but
they're feeding they're feeding soluble
amino acid nitrogen through the cycle
and that allows for that quality to
remain really high but you have to be
really careful you never run out of
nitrogen at any point in the process
obviously you can let it draw down
lateen flour but um that's the essence
that you see the plant still has enough
of it it's just translocating it from
its older leaves into the parts of the
plant that are still growing so I know
that was kind of a stream of
Consciousness but um that was great
those are kind of my my high level
thoughts on nitrogen management yeah so
one one question I have based off of so
I'll use the the mik 3 test to look at
nitrates and when I I've seen some tests
you know really high I aim for around
100 to 120 pounds per acre kind of in
that corn range for nitrogen um but I've
seen tests double and triple that
sometimes um what's sort of your target
with n nitrate and and how do you manage
it when it is really high because you
mentioned it is so ephemeral do you not
worry about that as long as your visual
crop response looks
good yeah
so um
I my nitrogen Target changes based on
how long the plants are going to be in
that soil so if it's a full-term crop or
um if it's just for flour for example I
mean more and more it's transplanted in
it's in veg for one to three weeks and
then flipped into flow yeah I always
think of it as just a flower just
mentally I'm for this let's just think
of it in in flowers and it's a
transplanting into the soil as a
flowering
soil okay so so in that case um and I
just want to mention that that pot Size
Matters of course and the form the am
the the the release rate of whatever
nitrogen matters but in general um for
flour I aim for for 150 pounds per acre
so um very similar to you but the P to
just make it more complicated I do some
complicated math on on the pounds per
acre because we're converting something
that's very agronomic top soil in nature
and putting it into a soiless media in
um cubic yards so I still use that
metric but it's it's adulterated so in
general I'm looking for about 75 PPM I
think that's a good level to you know
going into flour and then any remaining
nitrogen you may need um you can always
apply later the goal to me is to is to
end it down near 20 or 30 um not too low
so it's completely deficient but not too
high where it's it's affecting your flow
quality Yeah you mentioned uh nitrogen
in an amino acid form what sort of
amendments or products are are you
finding people are using effectively to
get that nitrogen in in small
doses yeah I would say
soluble amino acids derived from soybean
meal um that's that's my favorite that's
my go-to is a is a soluble soybean meal
um amino acid I know a lot of people use
uh aminos from fish which I'm sure are
just as good um I don't I don't have an
opinion or a preference one way or
another um I think the idea being that
in in the plant nitr
is converted into complete proteins in
the leaves through a pathway called the
nitrate reductase pathway it's a really
interesting thing that Google if you
find it on Wikipedia it just shows the
complexity of plant physiology but it it
requires miminum as the enzyme co-actor
that converts nitrate um into complete
proteins this process metabolically is
extremely taxing on the plant it's I've
read that it takes upwards of 18% of the
plant's total photosynthetic energy to
convert nitrates into complete protein
so the theory behind amino acids is that
you are giving the plant the building
blocks for protein and therefore it
doesn't have to convert that nitrate and
it saves a tremendous amount of energy
let's just say
18% um just for over
simplification and the plant then has
18% more energy to
devote or allocate toward other uh plant
growth functions or root exitation and I
just think you know 18% more energy
every single day I would do anything for
that me too uh so what what kind of
product are you finding make this uh soy
based amino
acid thing I haven't I haven't heard of
you mean brand yeah is there like a
particular product or brand that that
you could throw out there for listeners
to maybe check out sure sure I hate
naming Brands because I try to be
product agnostic but I'll do it fair
enough fair enough um agino is a is one
uh there's one ferin Nitro that's a
great one
um and
I yeah there's there's a another good
one um grower secret
n um
okay yeah those are the three that come
to mind yeah I've been using a product
called moch Chum uh from plant success
because it has n and K
specifically um but I am totally open to
maybe that's something I need to look
into is offering to our customers on
kiss Organics is a soy based one too so
I yeah absolutely appreciate abolutely
um yeah okay so we talked about nitrogen
and uh did you want to talk about
potassium or do you want to dive into
water let's talk about pottassium real
quick all right I I can't resist so
potassium is an interesting one because
um well and and let me connect it to
nitrogen really quickly there's a number
of products there's a number of
amendments but at the end of the day I
believe that compost is the winner when
it comes to a slow relasing source of
both nitrogen and pottassium and and um
that's nothing new you know the best
organic Growers were were uh using
compost well before I was born so
compost is is key the the trick with
soiless media in cannabis production is
all compost is so different in quality
and so different in nutrient profile and
it has such a differing amount of sodium
and salts that it's really easy to
overdo compost so it's really a
balancing act so my belief is that um
once you get your base mix once you
build your soil or buy your kiss soil or
whatever may be the the trick there is
to apply just a little bit of compost
every single season or every single
round because compost doesn't release
all of its nutrition in year one it
continues to release it forever so
you're just sort of it's almost like
saving money every year you're putting a
little bit more money in the bank
account that's going to spit out
dividends or interest every single year
thereafter and that really mitigates the
nitrogen and and pottassium
um mining that I referred to earlier
Okay so
otherwise the only you know good sources
of
potassium um you know there's
there's potassium sulfate there's
potassium silicate there's green sand
there's wood ash uh I know a lot of like
KF guys will will use sunflower Ash I
don't like ash because it concentrates
all salt so just because it has high
pottassium you're bringing in a bunch of
other stuff um and so and and those so
potassium sulfate and pottassium
silicate those are both highly soluble
they're soluble at about 420 gram per
gallon of water so um compared to gypsum
that's only let's say eight grams per
gallon in its solubility so that
solubility is great because you can feed
it and you can you can you know dissolve
it in water and Drench it let's say
through flour but it also means that
it's it's soluble in the soil and that
it can leech out it's it remains in the
soil solution it doesn't necessarily
cling to uh the organic comp lexes like
uh let's say copper that's on the other
end of the spectrum it's extremely
sticky so pottassium you're not only not
only is the plant of picking it a lot of
it through the entire plant growth stage
but it's also Le very leech in in the
soil solution so um I found that
potassium is an interesting one because
you it's it's and this isn't new to most
folks but it's incredibly important for
for flower development flower
sizing flow density hardness as people
like to refer to it I density yeah that
weight if you want to get that weight on
your flower um you need so much of yield
depends on that
yes so it's a hard one to manage and on
the other end of the spectrum I don't
believe you want to push too much
potassium in in veg because potassium
and calcium are highly antagonistic in
both their uptake and their
translocation around the plant so I
found and from talking to really good
Growers again who are getting
consistently high yields is that you
really want to you really want to push
calcium in veg and load your plant with
calcium because that sets you up for a
really good harvest but you want to flip
the script in in flour and just make
sure you're getting enough potassium so
there's a balancing act between those
two minerals and I think the key is um
it makes it easier to to either have a
lot of fresh compost in the mix that's
constantly releasing pottassium or you
really do want to feed um potassium
through flour that's that's my general
rule of
thumb yeah so that leaves us with sort
of pottassium
sulfate or potassium silicate um
potassium silicate would be the egg sill
16h a lot of people know dagro protect
which is essentially a a bottled watered
version of that potassium silicate
um potassium silicates allowed for use
in organic production um as I believe as
a pesticide is that correct Suzanne
would kill me for not uh knowing this
off hand um I don't believe it's allowed
to be used as a fertility management
tool though I think many PE many folks
do are you talking potassium silicate
yes you know I'm not sure I've only
recently started recommending it because
so many people are using it I've always
used pottassium sulfate um and I've only
recently switched over so I I didn't I
was not aware of that okay well I can I
can go look over that with it but I'm
fairly confident that that's that's
right but you know people can fact check
me on that one um that being said the
potassium sulfate uh is something that I
use as well it's a mind product um 50%
pottassium it's a really easy way to get
and a very affordable way to get
potassium into your
soil uh when we need to get that little
boost but I totally agree with you about
compost um let's go back and we keep
skipping skipping around water but you
keep bringing up these great topics like
you mentioned you know not all composts
are the same it all has different uh all
varying levels of minerals of heavy
metals of nutrients all these things um
of microbial activity the other thing
about compost or the other thing about
this process that I want to highlight
that you touched on was um every time we
Harvest a plant this is not a closed
system you're pulling out nutrients and
you're pulling out organic matter and
that's what compost replaces it really
helps get that organic matter fraction
back up too and if you're adding back in
compost at some point in time you may
need to add back in irration so um or
some sort of like yes thing to maintain
that air to water ratio that we want
that gas exchange that you highlighted
so I just wanted to kind of highlight
that one more time but um let's talk a
little bit about compost you know you
said what's what is good versus bad
compost how do we evaluate compost and
that could be a whole podcast I know but
let's just do a quick little thing on it
and then maybe we can have a whole
podcast on it down the
road okay great well I'd like to chime
in well one thing and I'm have a lot of
to say on compost but to take a step
back when you're people live running
living soil beds that are on round 20 or
10 even what's happening is that that
organic matter is
mineralizing and the usually the bulk
density goes up in that mix um and
especially as more compost is added to
your point and I've never seen one of
these beds that doesn't have worms in it
so by around 20 I think those beds have
pretty much turned to worm castings
which isn't a bad thing worm castings
are magical in so many ways but the but
to your point I really think it's
important to be adding more aggregate
because when the bulk density increases
of your soiless media it really changes
a lot of the the water holding capacity
and drainage characteristics so either
you have to adjust your irrigation
technique or increase aggregate so I'm I
I agree 100% Tad okay when it comes to
compost
um here's here's how I would Define a
good compost well aged so uh usually
that's indicated in two different ways
one is through the ammonium to nitrate
ratio so you want lower ammonium compost
that usually means that it's fairly
mature and the second way is do the
carbon to nitrogen ratio which I think
maybe the most important thing when
looking at a compost ability to provide
nitrogen to your crop yes so and to not
immobilize nitrogen because when the the
carbon and nitrogen ratio goes over
about 18 to 22 to one right in that
range I know that's a relatively large
range but um I I my rule of thumb is 18
to one when it's greater than that you
shouldn't you shouldn't count on any
nitrogen release from that compost in
year one and in fact when it's above 20
you could actually see um a nitrogen
draw where those microbes need nitrogen
to break down the carbon and they they
steal that nitrogen from your crop so I
think that's the first really important
thing to look at
the the next thing that I look at is
sodium and salt so in the Arid West um
anywhere where they're making compost
out of high salinity feed stock or the
water that they use to keep the compost
moist is you know high in bicarbonates
you can start to see uh salinity buildup
in compost which is uh going to to
import a lot of of negative ions into
your um soil and by negative I don't
mean negatively charged I mean
um poor for plant
growth and the next thing I look at is
the total nitrogen phosphorus and
pottassium on a wet basis or as received
is how this little on the compost test
look at it just so I have a sense of if
it's on the hotter end of things or um
if it's more of a inert organic matter
source that may not be providing a lot
of nitrogen so usually hot nitrogens
come from um chicken uh chicken manure
other uh poultry manure as well as
castings that have been fed you know a
really rich diet I sometimes see really
high nitrogen numbers in different
castings um and I tend to avoid mushroom
compost because I tend to see really
high sodium and salinity for mushroom
composts um I love manure so I love
manure-based compost especially Cal
manure horse
manure goat sheep anything any uh ulate
like that usually has a really good
manure that's not it doesn't provide a
lot of nutrition but again it's giving a
lot of that um kind of slow release
organic matter the final thing is a a
fungal Rich compost from from what I've
heard and read is is um
typically very very beneficial and so
there's something called the Johnson Sue
bioreactor that that I think your
listeners should check out it's a very
simple um self-sufficient way to produce
a really high quality highly fungal and
very well uh broken down and aged
compost so I'll leave it at that do you
have any
thoughts I mean I I think right you
touched at it right at the beginning
well-aged like nothing beats time
in Mother Nature when it comes to making
compost and I think the majority of
commercial composts that we see are just
produced way too rapidly to optimize
plant growth um that's that's probably
my biggest takeaway find make your own
compost let it static composting is by
far the best way to make high quality
compost you know thermally compost at
first kill off the pathogens weed seeds
sure but um that would be the one thing
i' I'd say so I totally agree with you
on that great uh the other
thing I I would say to all of that would
be um I haven't had the best experience
with cow manure-based composts relative
to some of the other manures I I much
prefer horse manure over cow manure um
but
uh you in general I think manure-based
composts are are wonderful if you if
properly managed um I would I would
totally agree with you on that I just I
find the fertility on calure compost to
be prettyy poor um in general it's
pretty low yeah it's pretty low but um
yeah no I think that's great and so when
people say add compost that I don't
think that really captures what you um
what you need to know like if uh there
there's so much more to it than that um
I'm thinking of just you know on a forum
for example people say hey add earthworm
castings add compost but that doesn't
take into account the quality or the
nutrient levels or the biological
activity and whatever it is they adding
so it kind of goes it's my biggest issue
with with with
recipes soil recipes
are uh they're garbage in my opinion uh
because the the if you're if you're
mixing Coots mix for example the compost
you'd be applying in the wamit valley
versus the compost you'd be applying in
Oklahoma or Nevada or Colorado is so
it's the difference
between eating a salad and eating
McDonald's I mean it's just it's just
night and day in terms of what you're
contributing to the soil so you can take
the same soil recipe and create a a
nearly ideal soil and with the same
recipe you can create something that's
complete
garbage that's a really good point and
even uh cot himself has said multiple
times you're not making cute mix because
you don't have my earthworm castings um
which would speak exactly to what you're
saying so it's a good point when people
have you know successes or failures with
recipes um I think that's I think that's
exactly true and then the other the only
other thing I would add is that I like
to do some level of biological testing
even if that's qualitative when I look
at a compost I want to see under a
microscope what sort of microorganism
activity I'm getting you know do I see
good diversity um in terms of the
morphology of organisms I'm seeing am I
getting good biomass uh that's what I
like to look at as well um what kind of
nematodes am I seeing um in in the mix
so yeah I other than that though it's a
great idea I agree with you on the
compost thing I don't think everyone has
to have a microscope I think it's the
least useful of all the agronomic tools
I can't believe I'm saying that on the
air but I I I really do believe that
when people ask me buy a microscope I'm
like oh you know what get a get a dino
light first or some way to look for pest
or get a dissolved oxygen meter or you
know a pH pen or these other things
first and then if you want to start
getting a microscope great but yeah yeah
people might people might eat you up for
that one i' I'd recommend a pulse meter
and I'd also recommend a an neurometer
tensometer yes BL M sells them too I'm
sure you could bu but but I think my my
two favorite
tools um well I have some more advanced
tools but if I were to recommend my two
favorite for the average grow be a pulse
meter and a
tensometer I think if you're going to do
a lot of soil testing too having just a
you know a very affordable uh soil
sampler um I think is is really an easy
easy
buy that's true the only thing is I have
a really expensive probe I use it all
the time of course but it doesn't
necessarily always uh jab into soiless
media that well yeah sometimes I end up
using a TR anyway yeah I do like a trial
for slor lless media um I would agree
with that too that's a good point so
okay let's talk about uh let's talk
about water because it's something that
frankly I don't have as much experience
and knowledge with um as I would like I
always tell people to test their water
so we can see what's going on um can you
talk a little bit about a water test and
what we should look in evaluating
water yeah
absolutely so water
chemistry uh is more complicated than
than most people think um
especially the relationship between pH
bicarbonates and alkalinity which are
all which are three
different metrics on a on a water test
that are all very related
so the amount that the pH of your water
is simply a function of the the pH by
definition is the hydrogen ion
concentration so
anything that contributes hydrogen
ions
is um going to lower your pH it's acidic
and anything that um consumes them is
not and so that's That's the basis
that's the Baseline and there's a lot of
I don't know water snake oil out there
but it just it's just good to remember
that that's the fundamental the hydrogen
ion concentration so um when it comes to
I look at a lot of water tests and the
the more important thing to look at than
pH is
alkalinity and
alkalinity is slightly different in
definition than pH what it says is it's
it's saying how much acid would it take
to lower the ph or how resistant to pH
changes your water so why that's
important is
because when your when your water enters
your soil the soil is going to buffer
the pH people usually most cannabis
Growers understand that
term and so if you if you have low
alkalinity the water is going to be
buffered really quickly so it doesn't
matter if your pH is 8.0 if your
alkalinity is super super low then as
soon as it hits the soil it's going to
revert to whatever the soil pH is and it
doesn't matter too much however you
could also have a pH of let's say
6.9 but a really high alkalinity which
means that when that water enters the
soil it's not going to be buffered down
as easily and it's in fact going to
change the soil PH over time so what's
important to understand is that um if
you have high alkalinity that's a better
indicator that you should adjust your pH
than if you just have high pH alone so
that's the first thing I want to mention
now the third metric that I mentioned
was bicarbonates so
bicarbonat lead to high
alkalinity so um usually when water runs
through the parent material of a soil it
picks up carbonates like calcium
carbonate or magnesium carbonate um also
referred to as Free lime and it will go
into the solution and and convert into
bicarbonate which leads to a higher
alkalinity and a higher pH so what
you're doing when you add acid to an
irrigation water is you're dissociating
the
bicarbonate and therefore lowering the
alkalinity and lowering the pH I know
that's so complicated and it's taken me
years to really have a fundamental grasp
of it but I hope that makes
sense it it does how do we so when we're
looking at this test in terms of uh
bicarbonate levels how do we adjust and
how concerning is that I guess in
evaluating a water for growing yeah so I
recommend that
when when bicarbonates or I'm sorry when
total alkalinity goes above about 120
parts per million that's when you should
really consider applying acid to your
water now that's that's a relatively
arbitrary number you could you could go
up to 140 or 150 but but usually when
the alkaline over about 150 160 you
should definitely consider acidifying
your water the alternative would be to
run your your soil PH a bit lower and if
you submit a saturated taste test with
your irrigation water that's looking at
the combination of your water with your
soil and that's the pH you should really
be looking at because if you can you can
definitely have a high pH water with
high alkalinity and apply it to a low PH
soil but together they combine your pH
is really bright in range so if you you
know you should that's what I mean by
consider acidifying over 120 you don't
have to but you should start thinking
about how to how to change your
management to to make sure your soil
solution pH is optimized so you're
you're saying when you go to Logan with
a complete soil test send them a sample
of your water too so that when they run
that saturated paste portion which is
where they again correct M you this if I
get wrong they take your soil and
essentially dissolve it in they'll use
distilled I think I believe or fairly
neutral water unless you send them your
irrigation water and if they do with
your irrigation water it's essentially
What ions come out or or nutrients come
out into that liquid solution and then
they measure
that exactly and so it's a more accurate
representation of what your plant roots
are actually seeing so every grower who
goes on my website orders a soil audit I
send them the forms to send in a Logan
test I recommend that they send their 4
ounces of their irrigation water for
Logan to run the test with their
irrigation water for that exact reason
now I don't recommend that if you have
super clean water like um r or even most
Municipal Waters they're not going to
significantly change the soil solution
uh enough to justify having to go find a
4 oce bottle and ship in
water so when we talk about acids to
it's typically the lower pH most of the
tests I see are dealing with you know
high pH alkaline bicarbonate um there's
three that I'm aware of sulfuric
phosphoric and citric um I I think
there's pros and cons to all three I
tend to just stick to phosphoric because
citric just doesn't have much buffering
capacity it'll fluctuate pretty quickly
um doesn't really seem to change the
soil PH over time and then sulfur cvoid
Cu uh there's a lot of reports that it
damages soil microorganisms
significantly more we so I don't know
what are your thoughts on on ways of
lowering pH effectively and as
organically as
possible yeah so technically in
certified organic production you can
only use citric you can't use phosphoric
if you're but again that that's only if
you're a veggie producer that has to be
certified yeah I
don't so with citric acid you're right
and any organic acid for that matter um
there's it it's for one thing if you
acidify your water and come back a day
later it'll just jump right back up
because I my understanding is that
biology there's bacteria that that
consume the conjugate base and
it it's chemistry that that I couldn't
really explain on this podcast without
reviewing so anyway it doesn't to your
point it's not as stable it's also more
expensive and it's just not as powerful
you have to apply it so much more um
phosphoric is is great because you're
actually getting soluble phosphorus and
cannabis just loves
phosphorus um the downside of that is
that in top soil and in research which
again may not apply to soiless Media but
High soluble phosphorus will decrease
micro isal
colonization because one of the primary
ecological functions of microa is to uh
solubilize phosphorus and deliver
phosphorus to the plant new research
also shows that it does deliver nitrogen
and or other compounds but I'm getting
side you know sidetracked here so
phosphoric I think is wonderful it's
less expensive it provides soluble
phosphorus and it's much more powerful
and it doesn't change to what you're
saying Tad sulfuric I recommend for
orchardist um who have a high pH soil in
a calcarius region because you're
changing the solution you you're never
going to reduce the pH of that soil um
because it's there's just so much Free
lime that you just take lifetimes of
huge sulfur
applications um but you can change the
soil solution pH which is really where I
work I work on this on the solution um
both in in all my Consulting and so the
the you can install a sulfur burner
which um essentially uses sulfuric acid
it it shoots sulfur into the water drops
I don't necessarily I haven't used
sulfuric acid specifically a lot of
people have come to me with that same
concern that you just expressed around
um you know hurting biology and I
understand that sulfur can be used as a
Fungicide and a biological suppressant
but I haven't seen a lot of evidence or
research that um sulfur decreases
biological uh Community composition
biomass Mass activity necessarily so I'm
I'm totally open to learn and and be
schooled on that but I think that's one
assumption that we should all question
and just make sure that we are I like
that uh following the research on that
yeah I will say that I've been working
with some facilities that have had been
battling high pH in their soils and the
applications of agricultural sulfur
every cycle in low doses has
successfully lowered the pH over
time um great and while we haven't been
measuring soil biology you know
effectively what we're seeing in terms
of plant growth and plants response is
uh increased yields because and my you
know my hypothesis on this is as our pH
drops into a more optimal range for that
plant it's easier for the plant to
access nutrients thereby allowing it to
like like you talked about uh with um
the amino acids it allows the plant to
receive those nutrients uh in an easier
form or with less work so that it's able
to put more energy into its its overall
biomass and
yield absolutely I I think that you know
pH is is and again I think everyone
knows this it's so important and I would
choose to fix my pH and it's also
important to keep in mind that
um there was a there was a 2020 study
that happened this year it was a meta
analysis that analyzed uh over 1,200
experiments that examine soil microbial
diversity and which is a very specific
metric it's not examining uh microbial
Community composition or Community
activity or biomass it's it's diversity
specifically and it found that the
number of species or the species
diversity is most explained by a change
in PH so again pH is the driving Factor
behind species diversity in soil and
again may not apply to to soiless Med
may not apply to these systems where
we're constantly applying teas and
ferments and things but it's important
to remember that if if we get the right
pH in the long term that's going to
dictate diversity more than anything
else sorry I had a quick cough there I
turned down my mic um apologies no
problem um yeah I that makes I thought I
said something no it wasn't you I was
trying not to cough on there but it
looks like I didn't make it um cool uh
one other thing I know we've uh we're
starting to run long here um probably
have to have you back on but I wanted to
at least there were two more topics that
I wanted to cover in this podcast um
really quickly would be heavy metals and
then cover crops but let's start with
let's start with heavy metals um I'm
seeing a lot
of not a lot that I don't want to
exaggerate the issue but I'm seeing
people fail for heavy metals uh
typically our Snick I've also seen lead
um how do we manage that most
effectively in soils in terms of our
input as well as um what other outside
sources of contamination do we need to
be concerned of um you know primarily
thinking of water and other other metals
in our building um do you have any
thoughts on
that yeah so I don't know the LA that
the answer to the the second part of the
question um in terms of I don't suspect
it's coming from most people's water
unless they're using some contaminated
well water and I don't know the sources
in a facility however I can talk to
inputs
and the so I've I've actually been doing
a lot of research um and I've pulled the
I've I've found and sourced heavy metal
tests from a number of
different um brands of soft rock
phosphate Kel meal poultry products
Alfalfa caranas soybean neem blood and
on on and on down the list and I've been
able to Source numbers for arsenic
cadmium Mercury lead and nickel and um
and by the way T I'm I'm releasing all
this in a an online course that I am
launching called become a cannabis soil
expert I I'll share it with you after
the podcast oh cool and yeah what I'm
finding is that
um there are certain product categories
that are consistently high in certain
heavy metals so and oh and one more
barium so for
arsenic there's a whole bunch of of
learning here and there's a number of
products that I could mention to stay
away from but if you're failing for
arsenic the number one thing to look at
is your Kel meal okay and I'll leave it
at that for arsenic now if we want to
talk about other specific heavy metals
um we can kind of go through the list
but uh I've found that consistently
there's a number of Kel meals that are
really low and a number that are really
high so when comes to arsenic now
there's other sources of arsenic there's
certain alala products there's um a bit
of arsenic that comes in through uh
different Rock dusts um as well as a
couple different brands of
gypsum but otherwise I mean those are
the those are the categories that that
are going to bring in the most
arsenic yeah I think in general uh
people have to realize when you're using
organic soils or organic amendments
there will be low levels of of arsenic
uh naturally it's just a matter of
management of heavy metals um I I think
trying to completely avoid them would be
quite challenging using Strictly Organic
amendments but knowing knowing what
those levels are and making sure we're
not doing anything to really increase
them um I think is really important and
then we're finding genetics plays a huge
role some cultivars just pull up heavy
metals like crazy and other ones could
seem to care less uh you know two two
genetics in the same room can have
significantly different heavy metal
levels just from the testing I'm seeing
um but when I talk about water my my
thought is primarily with people who are
using RO water you know
it's water wants to bond with something
and uh when you when you have it like
that and it's and it's uh strictly just
H2O I think that you're at risk you're
you're at higher risk of it coming in
contact with metals and then stripping
those metals um of potential heavy
metals I I think of like in a reservoir
having a an irrigation pump for example
could be a risk or um your plumbing in
your facility and might be able to pull
strip lead out of that depending on the
type of Plumbing that you have so that's
sort of what I was getting at in regards
to water got it that's a great point my
wife uses a berky filter is double
charcoal filter she puts our our water
through and you know I always I actually
don't love that because I don't want a
water that's super super stripped of
everything I actually like minerals in
my water for the same reason you're
talking about I don't have any basis for
that other than just the idea that there
you know that water may be stripping my
my stomach or my body of of minerals I'd
rather have minerals in it so I think
that's a that's a valid point and by the
way I want to I want to clarify on that
Kel meal comment I'm not saying don't
use Kel meal I'm not saying don't use
these products I don't want people to
misinterpret that I'm saying if you're
failing for something
and you're using large large quantities
of Kel meal just second G you know you
should just consider going with less
oftentimes less is more and I I'd say
don't freak out about anything unless
you're actually failing um so I I don't
want to be misinterpreted there that's a
good point and when we talk about
um heavy metals in soils one of the
questions I get that I haven't I haven't
had a chance to research yet is are
there any good cover crops someone could
run to pull heavy Metals out of a soil
let's say you fail hypothetically for U
Arsenic and you don't want to throw out
all your soil How Could You amend that
quickly with a potential cover crop that
might pull out you know in its biomass
the Arsenic is there any particular crop
you're aware of that would be really
effective at
this gosh I I'm not I'm not aware of
anything for specific Metals um I could
dive into my my folder of extensive
resource that I can try to find
something but
the the thought I have is grasses are
are usually bioaccumulators I've worked
with Growers on cropping out excess
phosphorus for example with grasses I'm
sorry potassium with grasses um and you
know the sad thing is hemp hemp and
cannabis there it's it's the the most
wonderful bioaccumulator so
unfortunately to your point a lot of
cultivars are going to be really good at
it um so that's OB obviously not the
right answer but yeah I'm not sure I'm
not I'm not aware of specific species
that would do a better
job okay that's fair I kind of put you
on the spot there uh one other just
since we we started talking a little
about a bit about cover crops uh I put
up a video uh this past week on the use
my thoughts on the use of cover crops uh
in indoor commercial facilities specific
to controlled environment agriculture
uh specific to commercial operations not
saying not to use cover crops if you're
uh you know in a tent or you have a
small grow to manage I'm talking about
on scale um what are some of the pros
and cons to cover crops and let's talk
about all their benefits um in an
outdoor environment you know if we're
talking about maybe in a uncontrolled
Greenhouse or in a field uh why do we
want to use cover crops
yeah so the the purpose of cover crops
is very context specific Outdoors but
what comes to mind is uh biomass
production weed
suppression and and um
nitrogen uh fixation those are the three
main you know there's other things
there's water conservation and water
filtration and soil biological promotion
but usually Outdoors I'm thinking about
how to build organic m matter how to
build nitrogen stocks and how to
suppress wheat as the three primary
benefits of cover crops but you know
there's poll there's pollinator benefits
and benefits to attracting uh predatory
insects um there's a whole number of of
benefits and I'm sure I'm missing
several now uh if I can just jump jump
over to um that indoor question really
quickly you know I
think I think that anyone who's putting
time toward mastering the art of cover
cropping is that that is time well spent
and I think that um I don't see a a
severe disadvantage to people who are
really innovating in that way personally
I don't
necessarily uh I tend to agree with you
Tad that that the the possibilities of
increased pest populations in a cover
crop indoors probably outweigh um the
possible benefits that you would get
from the things I I discussed and you
know think it's really laudable that
that a number of cannabis Growers and
really most organic farmers are trying
to model aggro ecosystems after nature
but we have to remember that when we're
in an indoor environment we've already
sort of disconnected in such a way that
um you know we can't perfectly replicate
nature we're under high-intensity lights
we don't have the same predatory insect
populations air flow temperature
fluctuations Etc and then and because of
that test populations can really get out
of control so I do think that personally
I would I would try to um control that
variable by eliminating multispecies
cover crops inside um and even even
single species cover
crops I will say I have one more thing
what yeah go ahead and I have one more
thing I want to talk about when it comes
to Blends versus single species if
you're open to that of course yeah I
just wanted to touch on the and just
highlight that I have no issue I I think
that running trap plants running
indicator plants running Banker plants
um all make a ton of sense um so I'm not
opposed to having other types of plants
in your facility just not maybe using
them as a as a cover crop necessarily
but in a separate space or container um
in the room um and like like you said it
I think it's great that people are
innovating in this area um for me my big
concern like you said is Pest Management
it's also Labor Management when we're on
scale and we have to think the number of
times that we literally touch or prune a
plant uh because of the scale it I think
it adds a whole another variable and
then the last thing is really I think um
the last thing is sort of a failing on
my part in terms of trying trying to
understand fertility management when we
add in a diversity of cover crop species
um I I think there's enough challenges
around fertility management when we're
talking about living soils it's just one
more variable that makes it even harder
for me to really wrap my my brain around
um and then the last thing would be I
like to till the soil um when I go to
remend I want to get my nutrients
directly down into the rizosphere so
that I know the plant has what it needs
for its next flowering cycle if we're
talking about flowering in beds and when
you have a cover crop when you have a
heavy mulch um it makes it really
challenging to try and reimen that soil
in that manner um and that's not to say
like Outdoors I'm a a big proponent of
no till big proponent of cover crops um
for all the reasons that you listed I
think they're wonderful um I'm just I'm
not as convinced as of today as of the
recording of This podcast that all of
these Concepts necessarily translate to
controlled environment agriculture on
scale
indoors great take it away yeah you know
it's it's well yeah know I have so many
thoughts and I think that's so well said
p i there's a quote I really love once
you start asking questions innocence is
gone and I feel like that in so many
ways where I have a general sense of how
I idealistically want to create
agroecosystems but the more that I learn
the more nuanced and con context there
is that doesn't always allow it uh
perfect application so I think the
general mindset of of cover crops is so
wonderful and diverse cover crops but um
when it comes to scale in production it
there's tradeoffs and I'm with you that
and on that note I mean I I totally
understand the benefits of no till
especially in outdoor um
soil top soil um I think it really
is half of the equation to soil Health
when we're talking about soil organic
matter but I have the same thing in in
soiless media um in cannabis production
I really like to a really thorough
homogeneous Amendment and and that
requires tillage so there's trade-offs
there really are and um I think those
are the tough decisions that that
Growers have to make and and the final
point on this is there's multi-species
cover crops are uh really popular
they're really great and another study
just came out another meta analysis this
year that that looked at cover crop
Blends versus single
species and there were 2 studies they've
looked at and they ranked um these
Blends versus their constituent
monoculture species based on uh biomass
production weed suppression water
conservation nitrogen
retention and um soil biology promotion
and what was so interesting it was
painful honestly for me to to read the
results of this because I was expecting
the the cover crop blends to outperform
the single species but they actually
found that uh 88% of the time there was
no difference in those um criteria and
there were a few single species Blends
that did better a few multispecies
Blends that did better uh across these
studies but um it was just kind of
humbling to me to to realize that that
obviously we're trying to mimic nature
and we're trying to mimic diversity but
it doesn't always give us the result
that we're intending because of the
complexity of nature so uh it was a
really fascinating study now the the
research does show that when you're
cover cropping multi-year so in the
three to fiveyear time Horizon grassland
studies show that that
multispecies um tend to produce much
more biomass because they're less
they're less susceptible to fungal
disease um which will wipe out a a
monoculture but when we're when we're
talking about cover cropping outside I'm
I'm going back to the basics and and
coaching Growers to just keep it simple
stick with something that's going to
work and that's going to achieve the
underlying production goals um because
sometimes I think we can overthink
things put together a 35 species blend
and not necessarily uh make our lives
any easier in the process so I I know
that's a qucious way to to talk about
cover crops but um I hope hopefully
that's helpful insight yeah maybe that's
something we could put up on the podcast
page for listeners who want to Dove a
little deeper into that I I think that's
really interesting I get the I get the
question sometimes from outdoor Growers
of what cover crop should I
run and you know everyone has a
different uh environment that they're
growing in I usually tell them to talk
to someone like yourself an agronomist
but then I also say go talk to your
neighbors find out what the Farmers near
you are using and what they've had
successes with because they that
microclimate is going to be very
different than what I'm dealing with
here in uh the Seattle area um so that's
that's where I like to start when it
comes to cover crops but again I I
totally agree with you they work we we
should be using cover crops um and um we
should be using no till when we want to
talk about regenerative agriculture for
improving soil
health I love that find the oldest
farmer in your area and ask ask them
what will do the best yeah and one other
thing I want to just add to this is I
love that when I put out that video on
Instagram the majority of people uh that
even that didn't dis that even that
disagree with me or maybe made reaction
videos um it was all in good
spirit we can disagree on these things
these points we're all organic Growers
at the end of the day we're all
promoting soil Health we're all doing
what we think is best for the plant for
our facility for our bottom line uh it
doesn't have to be personal um and these
decisions that we make don't make one
person smarter or or less or more
educated than another person um I think
these dialogues are what further our
knowledge and then let's take these
conversations and put put them into like
experimental design and really get to
the bottom so we have a firm answer that
supports our conclusions cuz right now
that research just does not exist so I
can't say with confidence that what I
shared regarding cover crops is optimal
um I can give you my Logic for why I
think it is and someone could do the
same in response but at the end of the
day we really don't we we can't say uh
conclusively one way or another and I
think that's important that that
dialogue stays positive and I I
appreciate that about the majority I
mean there's always going to be Trolls
but I appreciate that about the majority
of people that I've interacted with on
on these
subjects Heen yeah I think we're all
just looking for more information more
knowledge and more Collaborative
Learning when i s see those
conversations and those videos I just
think arising tide lifts All Ships we
are all in this together trying to learn
more so we can produce better crops and
be more profitable and I think dialogue
uh is the best way to do that so I
support that 100%
yeah well I I really appreciate what you
shared today I look forward to um
further conversations uh maybe further
podcast uh I know that uh you and I will
continue to chat off air and I um I I
I've even talked to you and Ben I know
we've talked about uh working on some
papers in the future to submit to
journals potentially to to further this
whole process along too I know there's a
lot of experiments you want to run and
Ben and I have a a a lifetime list as
well so uh I really appreciate that and
and thank you so much for coming on the
show
today yeah thank you so much Chad for
having
[Music]
me that was Bryant Mason and you are
listening to the Cannabis cultivation
and science podcast don't forget to
check out the podcast page at www kis
organics.com just click on the learn tab
then podcast and please take the time to
leave us a review if you listen on Apple
podcast or other platforms I do read
them all and appreciate your feedback
and the more reviews help us rank higher
so others can find the show thanks for
listening