[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discussed
the cutting edge of organic growing from
a science-based perspective and drawn
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge this
week's podcast is with David Bronner CEO
aka cosmic engagement officer for dr.
Bronner's a top-selling brand of natural
soaps in North America not only do they
make the best soap but they've dedicated
themselves to advocacy around our food
supply
regenerative organic agriculture animal
welfare fair labor practices and
responsible integration of cannabis and
psychedelic medicine into American and
global culture in my opinion this is one
of the best examples of how a company
can operate ethically and sustainably in
today's society and it was an honor to
spend this time with David I could do an
entire podcast just talking about all
the amazing things dr. Bronner's has
done for the community and its employees
but the main purpose was discussed their
partnership on the Sun and Earth
certification for cannabis and the
nonprofit David has helped establish
called brother David's now onto the show
hey David thanks for coming on the show
today
yeah big gravity yeah I really
appreciate you you taking the time I'd
love to start off just giving listeners
a little bit of background into sort of
your your own personal history and you
know a quick overview of the company
yeah so my granddad dr. Bronner founded
our company as a nonprofit religious
organization in 1948 ish it's a little
hazy he himself was a third gym third
generation master snow maker from a
German jurist so making family his
grandfather began so man
facture in 1858 in a small southern
german town of Lao pine in the duysts
under their Jewish quarter and as by the
time he was coming of age his dad and
two uncles had expanded the family
business to be pretty much the biggest
snow maker in Germany and they were had
a factory in a LeBron another southern
German town kind of in the heart of the
manufacturing kind of super center in
southern Germany and he was used
apprentice to another master master so
making family and earn his master's
certificate but you know in the late 20s
when he was working with his dad and two
uncles I mean he was pretty activist
from day one very Zionists and and then
just personality-wise his clashing with
his dad a lot and you know his dad
didn't really want him mixing politics
and so think and as far as the Hitler
and and in the rise of fascism that
wasn't clear that that point but more
just out of the kind of generational
class or their dad my granite came over
in 1929 to the US and set up shop in
Chicago and Milwaukee became a
consultant to the US soap industry
helped design factories and launch
products and married and had three kids
and but also was becoming increasingly
desperate with the rise of Hitler to get
his family out and his two sisters got
out one his youngest sister got he got
out in 36 in age of 20 and ended up on
in a kibbutz in Israel and being kept
kibbutz and then and I was Lodi and
Louisa got out in 38 right before the
close the borders and she eventually
became she came to us and eventually
became a professor of German Hebrew at
UMass Boston for what four short
centuries a chemist
ourselves and actually made the
waterproofing compound for American GIs
going into Korea but then didn't get
credit like her mail whatever supervisor
just kind of screwed her she quit and
discussed you got her PhD and became a
professor and but anyways so dr. Braam
my grandparents were told in Francisca
like a lot of Bushwick Jews that they
were going to thought they were going to
write out the madness and in 1940 the
factory was area nice and then shortly
thereafter they were deported and killed
in the camps in 42 and 44 and then also
in this time my granddad's wife my dad's
mom was very sickly and in and out of
hospital and died I think in 1945 and my
dad was too so just a lot of it's just
huge tragedy was hitting my granddad and
somehow in the midst of this you was
having these a mystical experiences that
of the oneness of humanity and on all
the faith traditions and all the
shamanic and faith traditions were
pointing at the same transcendent
mystery that were all children of and
that you know at the deepest level it's
it's about love and and getting down and
serving each other and loving each other
that in a nuclear-armed world if we
didn't realize that transcending unity
across ethnic and religious divides
we're gonna all perish and it felt
urgently called on his mission to unite
spaceship earth and what about lecturing
around the country selling his soaps cut
on the side and and you know and he saw
it soaps are cut out of fashion and a
post-world War two ERA it was all about
better living through chemistry you know
from from agriculture to plastics to you
know person don't care everything was
moving to a petrochemical basis and my
granddad early on saw the problem that
in saturating our
with all these toxic compounds and in
stay true to the natural versatile about
a gradable soap formulas of his family
and so he's going around lecturing on
his peace plan and kind of soon realizes
people are coming more to get the soap
which you know words got out like wow
this is I'm really good soak and realize
people are coming more to get the soap
then here stick around and hear what he
had to say so he started putting his
message on every label of our bottle
bottles and you know for him the bottle
was there to sell a label I mean as much
as the label that was there to sell so
and you know and he did found the
company when he considered a non-profit
religious organization with the rise of
the counterculture and hippies and the
wholesale rejection of the war machine
and you know they are of seven spring
and the ecological catastrophe that was
becoming more and more apparent the
soaps is really resonated and you know
the whole kind of became a soap of the
generation that he could you know wash
your hair your dog dishes by the side of
the river and not worry about it
and you know grew on this label of peace
and love and so you know that's you know
that's what really I think cemented his
place and you know and and then he was
part of you know are so part of the
health room store movement and healthy
movement kind of through the 70s and 80s
and and into the 90s well and then also
in this period the IRS kind of stepped
in or came down on my granddad and
basically you know disagreed with my
granddad's tax exempt status and my
grand I was fortunate bankruptcy in the
late 80s and and so my dad mom and uncle
Ralph at that point stepped in to kind
of fire a lot of bad advisers and right
to ship an exit as a for-profit but you
know we have that nonprofit DNA at the
heart of our business and my dad for his
part he you know he can't
a series of foster homes because my
grand I was off saving the world and
financially supported my dad and uncle
and aunt but wasn't really around as a
father and kind of bailed on his
responsibilities in that way and so my
dad really compensated and he went to
the Navy at age 17 served four years
came out worked for a bit from my
granddad but then went on to run a
chemical specialty operation or
manufactured in LA even when my granddad
move down Escondido here in North County
San Diego and so so he my dad oversaw
that he developed a bunch of products
including firefighting foam and then a
special effects version of foam and so I
personally grew up working for my dad
and so then in the late 80s Oh him and
my mom so they slept in my granddad's
health was failing at Parkinson's so my
dad and mom and uncle were running dr.
Bronner's and then my dad was also
running on a chemical which is as
independent at that point his own
independent chemical consultancy which
primarily was dealing with firefighting
foam and then also special effects foam
for Hollywood so I grew up going to
alka-seltzer and commercial shoots like
blasting foam on trees and movie movie
shoots and such and you know grew up
with my brother just blasting foam on
each other it's super fun out of a
engine and house fire hose but you know
my dad wanted nothing to do my
granddad's cosmic trip and he felt as
soon as my grant started on the all one
mission at dads I kind of wanted nothing
to do it he was all he was all about
family and community and what can you do
right here what's in front of you what's
practical you know looking actually
leverage and make you know a difference
in you know kind of near immediate
sphere of influence and um so and I very
much came up under my dad and and really
downloaded his kind of moral kind of
compass and in my granddad it wasn't
really until after college when I was an
absent
I mean my granddad was you know amazing
but just really sailed way over my head
as a kid I just didn't grok it and you
know you know we must make this patience
and you know and I just wasn't in the
space yet they appreciate that but then
you know in college I started smoking on
cannabis and you know this realizing
just how beautiful music and friends and
just really prioritizing that and kind
of retiring from alcohol cultures and
and then going to Amsterdam 95 and
intersecting the cannabis cup I had a
euro past went to Amsterdam and really
just got blown blown open had some huge
psychedelic experiences that really kind
of uh made clear that my granddad was
100% on point and he was exactly right
and that our deepest ground is his love
and light and that somehow the swirls of
absurdity and suffering that that is the
truth and that's what all these fake
traditions are pointing at when they're
not making idols out of their own
beliefs and symbols and systems and you
know and just kind of dedicated myself
to making the world a better place and
also in this time you know just
realizing that cannabis is a sacrament
as are all psychedelic allies and that
one is going to dedicate my life to
ending the war I saw that the drug war
is in large part a religious war on the
sacraments of our people and you know
and in my squat in Amsterdam I actors
there's a church in Arkansas in 1993 of
all places Clark called our church that
formed to which cannabis as a sacrament
and and you know explicitly to make a
First Amendment challenge and of course
in 93 I mean they got busted up pretty
quickly by this by the FBI and people
were arrested there were two people that
had escaped and immigrated to EPSA dam
and they were in my squat they were just
one of these guys with Sam Smith like
just a real heavyweight dude I think
he's up in the northwest somewhere
but just real spiritual cat you know
just be really dedicating his life to
cannabis as a sacrament of higher
vibration living and so this very
influential at that time and so anyway
so I came back became a mental health I
came back I sold all my stuff was gonna
move back to Amsterdam to grow plants
and activated became vegan in this
timeframe of just realizing the disaster
of Western consumption on a planet just
wrecking an environment you know I hope
for ecosystems and communities around
the world just being completely
disrupted to see the kind of
capitalistic machine of making us you
know food you know tasty food and
fabulous clothes and there's all the
consumables that we consume without
thinking about it and how they're
produced or who's producing them or
where they're coming from and just you
know to seeing that machine on the earth
it's like a comet hitting the earth and
you know just waking up to that
dimension of things and so so so just
there's a whole series of events and and
I came back to the states and became a
mental health counselor in the boss in
the walsim Kennedy Walton Watertown area
suburbs of Boston working primarily this
mental with a paranoid schizophrenic
population and my then well my
girlfriend and then wife and now
recently acts and she's amazing Chris
she was finishing up school and and then
and then we got pregnant and and yeah
and our baby my I was born on March 7th
97 and you know in this time like I've
been doing this a lot to be greeting of
course redjac hairs Emperor wears no
clothes and a lot of different just you
know just deep thinkers but really got
turned on the cannabis and hemp as a
this just such a powerful crop you know
for industrial for medicine for
spiritual use
and also realize that a company like dr.
Bronner's would offer me a job I would
go for a second leaving alone you know I
had really not wanted to do my own thing
with them just realizing wow what a what
a gift that you know an opportunity I
have and so I let my dad know yeah
surely around when does the birth of our
daughter and she was born on the same
day dr. Bronner died the same same exact
day my I was born dr. Bronner guide and
a high fived in and out and and and then
you know let my dad know and and then he
was diagnosed with stage 4 lung cancer
shortly after so you know fortunately I
already made that decision to come back
so I came back in keeping him in six
months but he lived for for a little
over a year and his goal was to see my
sister marry to my brother-in-law
Michael my sister Lisa which happened
June 6 of 1998 and then on June 12th he
KeePass transitioned and just was an
amazing man and we had an amazing year
together and it's just very intense I
just downloaded a lot of the ropes and
just the ethics and wait he rolled and
one of the last things he did until he
died on June 12 which was my uncle
Robert a his brother was one of the last
things he did is give effectively
one-third of our value our net worth was
was in a was in a thousand acres in East
County San Diego and he wanted to give
that to the Boys and Girls Club this is
kind of really cool kind of full circle
like the mentor programs youth mentoring
programs that helped him in the kid and
and all our advisors like man oh don't
do that we got a refuge the state taxes
from what my granddad died let's not do
that
my dad's like Adam is like no we can do
this you know we're gonna be alright and
this is what I want to do and so he my
mom mount my growth oversaw that gift
and really just set the example tone for
what we were going to be as a company
and that you know and as I
you know came in and you know this was
me and my mom initially and that my
brother after a couple years I convinced
to come in my brother Mike is now
fifty-fifty with me
he's company president and I'm the cause
the engagement officer and but we put
into place a five to one compensation
cap versus our lowest paid warehouse
position and that all profits not needed
for the business we were going to
dedicate to the charities and causes we
believed in and so one of the first
things we did was we added hemp seed oil
to the soaps in 1999 and thinking that
we were on the verge of Rica Mercia
lysing but also you know in part opening
up cultural space for cannabis and you
know just kind of a hemp team at the
perfect nexus of policy reform and
environmental sustainability and and
being an example you know so the worst
example of an out-of-control ice
terrible drug war that would schedule a
non drug agricultural crop is a Schedule
one drug and you know and then kind of
got into it with the DEA and we were in
an extended battle from 2001 to 2004
that we were when the DEA tried to ban
imports of MC m seeded and M seed oil
for food and body care and we beat them
and there's a hearse FDA was beat
we funded the industry's legal defense
coordinated help coordinated and yeah we
actually won a Bob Marley's birthday in
February 2004 we got a clean 3-0
unanimous victory in the Ninth Circuit
and then in parallel was funding
American safe access stuff share it come
out as anti-globalization movement to
set up if she got tackled by federal
marshal and the IMF protests in DC and
really jacked her neck and was using
cannabis and to help heal so she founded
the you know nation's was affected
patient advocacy group and we're big
supporters of her and he saw
and then um you know and then in
parallel we were putting in place you
know understanding that our supply
chains that you know whatever cool stuff
we do here at headquarters with our
employees and a manufacturing process
but that's like 10% of our impact and
that 90 plus percent of our impact was
in our agricultural supply chains and
how our materials are being grown and
processed matter way more than what we
were doing turning that in the soap in
in terms of environmental and social
impact so the first you know like most
people we bought in price inspect we
just you know you know bought from
brokers we had no visibility or real
interest in knowing exactly where our
stuff was coming from just like pretty
much everybody and you just buy on the
con it come out of your market but you
know realizing that that what's kind of
making the roads go to hell in a
handbasket and you know that that this
is the race to the bottom pitting
farming communities against each other
and you know it just leads to these huge
corporate industrial plantations ripping
up rainforests and you know displacing
small family farming communities up
their land and they become you know
plantation workers for slave wages and
it's a it's a horrible cycle and you
know especially around our tropical oils
like coconut and palm and then olive oil
and mint oil and where our main
ingredients along with the hemp oil so
so we said about identifying farming
communities that we could work in direct
partnership with and on regenerative
organic terms you know not using a whole
bunch of synthetic inputs synthetic
pesticides and fertilizers to produce
our raw materials and you know basically
trying to figure out like how do we farm
in nature's image if you look at a
forest there's no external chemical
inputs it's completely self regenerating
and and so just been on a just an
amazing crash course for the past 20
years getting better and better and
working in partnership with our farmers
and
kind of best practices as far as compost
and cover cropping and minimal sort of
the servants and intercropping with
complimentary tree crops of different
canopy heights the markets maximize
photosynthetic capture and biomass yield
and so carbon sequestration and and and
yields are much higher and so then so is
income and and then you know making sure
we're investing in the communities where
we're working in and so we've got really
cool project for coconut in Sri Lanka
and now a new one and Samoan we've got a
really cool palm project in Ghana or
intercropping Coco banana and cassava
with the palm and it's you know wow
device file diverse you know wildlife
habitat
you know Paul and that's you know always
making sure there's plenty of habitat
for beneficial insects and predatory
prey predator insects and pollinators
and then in olive oil we actually
partnered 90 percent of our olive oil
comes from olive farmers from the West
Bank and doing all regenerative
super-rad projects and then to be clear
when I on to Israel about it although we
do hate to occupation and in the current
government we source the balance from
half from a Jewish family farm and half
from a Arab Christian project in the
Nazareth green so we have Muslim Jewish
Christian olive oil and or soap all
organic and regenerative and then you
know and then all this time - we've been
using our profits to fund different
causes and ballot campaigns and so
engage them GMO labeling campaign really
hard against Monsanto and DuPont down in
Oregon when we came so close in 2014 you
know we lost but 800 votes it was such a
heartbreak but um you know learned a lot
you know finding 3 ballot measures in a
row they're you know parallel we're
helping fund the you know the cannabis I
mean cannabis prohibition first
california's failed prop 19 like even
though we all thought it was a bad idea
to go in that year in that time I
remember coming off Burning Man it was
like wow this
turn around without the first serious
national discussion happening about
ending cannabis prohibition and so this
really I realized it's the power of
these ballot measures to really advance
the cultural conversation and kind of
move the needle so that you can win in
subsequent years and indeed we did we
broke through in Washington Colorado
2012 an Oregon DC in Alaska in 2014 and
we actually funded entirely the DC
campaign in our social head of social
action is Adam ire hiding her and he was
the campaign manager for legalizing weed
in the Capitol which is huge is because
we're talking to the national leadership
within the local media you know in 2016
you know obviously it was a huge year
but also in this time we started it was
becoming crystal clear that the same
forces that were screwing up all the
other commodity crops in the world that
you know that we had to set up you know
put forth a lot of effort to you know
kind of go against and set up in a you
know truly sustainable regenerative
supply chain but that those same
corporate industrial forces were moving
big time in the cannabis and you know
part of what was really helpful for us
in in our just kind of normal raw
material supply chains and in our
products and having the USDA Organic
Program and then also
Fairtrade certification programs and you
know consumer facing programs that could
really tell you know cynically
communicate to consumers who you know
wanted to buy products that didn't go to
hell and back you know you could certify
with a third-party like in that this is
a trusted you can trust but indeed this
product was produced in a way that you
would want and you know this soap this
food that Apple you know that t-shirt
and so you know we saw in camp with
cannabis but because of federal
prohibition you couldn't access USDA
Organic program because it's a you know
federally regulated word and you know we
you know neither there was some pretty
good local certifications out there but
but nothing that seemed to have any
traction and degree and so we were
interested in my figuring out how can we
kind of get some kind of third-party
certification program that's robust that
addresses not just soil health and land
management but also fair labor practices
and you know in parallel we're partners
how to go with Patagonia on the
regenerator organic standard so the
regenerative organic Alliance and the
website for that is regen organic org so
that's this next level certification
that takes the best of fair labor so
health and animal welfare and pasture
based criteria into one single standard
and we're all in the pilot of that and
we're going to launch that early next
year
for you know full-scale commercial
launch so kind of in parallel we were in
the cannabis space kind of parallel to
the regenerative organic we we
identified Andrew black who's you know
works with organ tilt who's our our main
organic certified and just really cool
awesome cat you know driving and
certified count kind and then Jacob over
in Colorado doing cannabis Conservancy
doing great work and realized these are
two really great cats to work with and
then flow kana you know really
appreciated their business model and
that they very much have the ethics of
going to partners going to market in
partnership with their farmers and not
trying to play them off against each
other and you know also a really good
sounding partner and to some other
stakeholders mostly farmers and then
just identifying some just really
kick-ass farmers we were growing
cannabis in a truly regenerative way a
lot of time I've met many of them
multi-generational back-to-the-landers
you know their parents were you know
part of the original organic kind of
revolution and are just growing like
really beautiful integrated farms where
cannabis is growing alongside vegetables
and just you know taking care of their
land right and treating their people
right so we were you know we
we help bring everyone together or just
help you know throw some fuel on the on
on the process and so long story short
Sun and Earth is a certification
standard specific to cannabis but
basically is you know very something of
a regenerative organic in that it you
know basically celebrates farmers and
products and brands that are you know
sourcing and producing that assume in a
righteous way you know without chemicals
in the soil under the Sun a fair labor
and you know it's kind of tending their
land right and and you know receiving
you know prices from brands that are
also certified but you know that they
can you know take care of their land
correctly so yeah so I guess you know
that's oh yeah and then brother David's
was a so then we're and we're
brainstorming okay what's the most
effective way of communicating sun under
certification in the market and to the
trade and we realize like actually
launching a brand but you know that
would be consumer facing and in the
stores and talking about tenders but you
know making it not-for-profit and being
clear that we're not you know we want to
see all our competition certified
southerners like we're not out here to
make money you just want to you know
create you know market presence and
consumer demand for Southern Earth and
have that be like the organic USDA seal
or Intel Inside and just everybody can
jump on that and that's exactly what we
want to see and we're now starting to
see that there's a lot of interest and
we're hoping we're going to have a
critical mass with farms and brands so
that by second quarter next year there's
a really high-powered marketing firm
that wants to do a bunch of pro bono
work for senators but we want to wait
until there is like a critical mass of a
certified product in the market and
brands before we kind of pull the
trigger on that but then that would be a
pretty big marketing campaign on behalf
of senators
and so we're looking forward to that and
then I guess the you know other thing
here going on it's like super awesome
somewhat related but maybe not the most
related but awesome is the psychedelic
or the psilocybin therapy campaign in
Oregon alongside a broad-based drug
policy reform I would say general
decriminalization of all drugs and shift
from mass incarceration to treatment
measure and so there's two measures in
Oregon that are right now being pulled
tested and make sure they're viable what
we're pretty optimistic that both will
be so that in Oregon you're gonna have a
perfect storm of psilocybin therapy and
ship to Portugal style a criminalization
of all drugs and treating addiction as a
health problem and and and using tax
revenues from marijuana there to fund
treatment centers and then introducing
psilocybin therapy into the culture you
know in a really in a way that license
just licensed and trained facilitators
and make sure that there's a you know
good preparation good set in setting you
know good integration afterwards and
really optimize the therapeutic outcomes
because I think it's like it's really
exciting what's happening up there and
we've committed resources to both
campaigns so but anyways this shifting
back the Sun and Earth
yeah we're just really excited that you
know we're just the amount of interest
there is out there and yeah it's hope to
see more and more farmers I think we
just had a first for Oregon farmers
certified senators which is awesome
and it's you know not in the brother
David's supply chain and that's also
important so so yeah so I guess that's
the background where we're at now wow
that was a lot of great information it's
so wonderful to hear your your family's
history and
that strong foundation in in sort of
ethics and morality that's been
expressed and and the history of
activism that's really been passed down
generally generally generationally it's
really cool I have a lot of questions
but since we last talked about sun and
earth why don't we just dive in with
that you've talked about how it's this
regenerative organic certification that
just goes so far beyond anything that
currently exists and people can I'll put
all the links online here so people can
read more about exactly what that
certification entails so we're not going
to go into all those details I'll
probably have Andrew on to talk more
about them but you talked about this
need for a unifying certification around
regenerative cannabis can you touch on
that a little bit more as to like the
importance from you know as someone who
has a background in you know
understanding cus ort of marketing and
large-scale distribution of things how
important is this certification from
that perspective yeah and you know first
I do you want to shout out to dem Pierre
and you know by dynamic and you know
there's other real quality efforts and
standards out there and you know we see
that we're in solidarity and alliance
with with all the high bar standards out
there but you know we we do really feel
there is a need for senators and that
third party kind of system for consumers
especially when you have want to get to
scale and you have distance between the
consumer and the farmer yeah that so
that third party is you know and then we
like multi ingredients and all that that
third party verification is pretty key
so yeah I think for you know that
yeah the importance of a certification
in the first place is you know there's
over it's easy to to talk to talk you
know it's much harder to walk the walk
so the certification is a way of like
kind of breaking through the
greenwashing - you know sincerely
communicate honestly communicates
consumers that you know
indeed was produced to the highest bar
you know regenerative organic criteria
and then um and then yeah the marketing
campaign I mean it's just kind of
crucial that there's a lot of noise in
the market and a lot of competing you
know whatever so yeah it's as important
you know put together a good
communication campaign so that you know
consumers are aware of what this is
about
you know why it's important and why they
should look forward and buy these kind
of products yeah I'm up here in
Washington State I was grateful for your
contributions that dr. Bronner's made
towards the GMO labeling campaign that
was where I first really started hearing
about your advocacy and inter in terms
of the organic movement up here in
Washington State because we can't use
the word organic on any of our products
it gets really sticky it's really hard
to know how things were grown and it's a
big challenge here we've had a lot of
issues with pesticides the use of
illegal pesticides known carcinogens
even with regulations and testing by the
state and I know as a consumer I have
very little trust level in what's being
produced here in Washington without
having a personal relationship with the
cultivator and so I think allowing
greater access and greater confidence in
what's being produced is is really
important yeah no that's it man right
there I mean that's that's the problem
right I mean there's so much pesticides
and crap in a lot of flowers being grown
and yeah so Southern Earth is definitely
a way of guaranteeing that's not
happening and you know like if you don't
know your cultivator and you know you
can trust like a Sun and Earth product
nothing kind of exactly the point that
we're wanting to achieve here and and
just to clarify sun and earth is only
for people that are growing in soil
outdoors under the Sun it doesn't offer
a certification option for people that
are growing in indoor environments
no it's you know I think there's some
level of like some light that might be
allowed and and you know and I think
you're you know you know as far as like
the first few weeks or something can be
in a greenhouse or something you know
there's there's some reasonable
allowance but yeah but the general point
is we want it to be like in the soil and
you know farm like you know most things
or you know most most crops but you know
that said I mean there's a whole
spectrum of indoor and you know there
are much more ecological ways of growing
indoors obviously than others very much
appreciate you know people doing it much
more high bar and indoors but I think
the kind of gold standard is you know in
the soil and Under the Sun yeah I think
from an ecological impact perspective
growing outdoors in the Sun is is great
I think it's a challenge in certain
states depending on environment but
overall I think it's a very lofty and
very worthwhile goal and something to
shoot for and this standard goes so far
beyond anything organic it's it's pretty
crazy if you go to Sun and Earth org you
can read about it and I'll put links on
the website it's it's pretty
comprehensive and I've had long
conversations with Andrew black as I'm
sure you have too I didn't realize how
challenging putting together a
certification really was in my head when
I first started learning about I was
like well is it an organic input sure
then it's okay but there's so many other
things to consider and it's really like
navigating this grey area almost it's
not as black and white when you're
trying to establish it and then once you
have it like in the case with your
certification it becomes more black and
white you can say this is ok this is not
ok but getting there I I can see all
those challenges in that path ya know
it's like yeah it's nothing not easy and
you know it's important to bring that
you know
various stakeholders together they you
know everyone can hear everyone's you
know experience and views and you know
it's you know and then put the standard
out for comment and get like more
widespread feedback it just makes sure
it's you know both rigorous and workable
and and all that so yeah andrew has done
a great job
yeah and I'm looking forward to
interviewing him here soon to kind of
dive into some of the more technical
aspects but I did want to ask you so
brother David's is a is sort of a brand
sort of lender like a nonprofit more of
like a co-op model it sounds like from
what I was reading are all the are all
the farms that are working with brother
David's going to be sun and earth
certified as part of part of being
accepted into that program yeah exactly
I mean that's that's what we are we're
we're we're basically a not-for-profit
brand celebrating senators farmers like
that's you know we're a brand platform
to kind of celebrate the rocks these the
rock star farmers they're the
celebrities and the point of the whole
project and you know we just generally
want people to really kind of think
about the fact that you know everything
reproduces or everything we consume has
been you know grown and produced in you
know somewhere by some farmer and you
know how was it produced who is that
farmer was that it was their farm labor
respected or exploited you know just
just really connecting to the ed to the
farm level so yeah so we're we're
exclusively working with some of their
certified farmers okay so the the idea
is then that farms are incentivized to
join this program because they're going
to have people backing them handling
more of the marketing and those aspects
and they can focus then on the farming
and cultivation and then from a consumer
perspective will the product cost maybe
a dollar or two more but you're getting
all that reassurance and you're
supporting the farms and ethics that may
support you know your own personal
ethics when you're buying a product is
that is that sort of the idea behind
that yeah so it's
Minoo it still depends I mean
southerners we argh
I mean brother David's for sure we pay a
premium to our southerners farmers and
you know and there is going to be a
marketing budget for Senate earth so if
you are just a farmer selling direct to
consumer you know hopefully we're going
to create awareness but you know such
that you commit can command a price
premium but you know generally speaking
I think a lot of you know what we're
going to really target as far as getting
that premium to farmers and we want to
see the brands at the brand level
certified a son on earth and then as
part of that commitment like they would
then pay like a 10% premium or you know
or whatever to farmers that they're
sourcing from who are you know go
through the effort to become senator
certified you know that's not like
mandated but it's like something that
were you know recommending that that be
the case and you know it's kind of like
organic on the shelf I mean it is a
higher price and it's just about
communicating to consumers you know why
they should pay that higher premium and
you know we're gonna set about doing
that but I wouldn't say advice ours like
you know oh we totally got it and you
don't have to spend time like telling
the story we kind of need all of us it's
kind of like a what do you say open
source project we all got to be talking
about it so I'm kind of curious your
opinion so you guys have managed to
maintain your ethics and integrity with
dr. Bronner's and still lead the
industry in in your field with natural
soaps I'm kind of wondering how do you
manage to compete with these larger
corporations that are making more money
and spending more on marketing you know
using cheaper inputs and yet you're
still able to pay an equitable wage and
donate considerable funds to the causes
you believe in
I think there's parallels here in the
cannabis industry as some of these
larger companies are moving in do you
have any advice or anything you can
share around that yeah you know I think
just being kind of true to yourself and
[Music]
you know doing the right thing
you know making sure your your pain your
people well you know sourcing from the
you know right kind of farms and farmers
and and all that you know results in a
somewhat higher price point but you know
you know telling that you know just
being effective and telling that story
and communicating that there's you know
a huge swath of cannabis consumers who
like organic shoppers for food I mean
they want to know where their medicine
comes from they want to know it didn't
suck and um you know I think that there
is a real market there to tap and yeah
you know I think um you know the big
players they've you know they're gonna
have a lot of a lot of money it's the
campaigns and whatnot but you know they
generally aren't going to have as much
soul as a really kind of smaller more
awesome more nimble kind of brand or
company farm and I think that you know
just kind of really connecting and that
more soulful way with your customer base
and I'm just really appreciating what
you're about is I you know really you
know not just producing the right just
product and you know best way possible
but um you know there's also generally
vibrating in a way that's trying to make
the world better I think that you know
definitely can um with sand well I mean
it's you know I'm not well I don't want
to minimize how hard and difficult it is
with all the players moving in and the
huge disruptions going on in the
industry and that's part of what's on
earth is about is is really about
helping you know the farms and small
family farmers you know really
struggling in this kind of catastrophe
really to survive and this is one of the
tools it's like okay how do we
effectively communicate to the consumers
like dr. Bronner's it's connected with
you know how do we get you know what
what are the tools how did we do it so
that's part of what some of nurses and
yeah and I would just say that you know
we were small once and that you know I
guess yeah and then you know just making
sure you got the you know right margin
structure to support all that
but you know not too high a price point
that's a big trick and um
yeah I guess just navigating the waters
skillfully is you can and with a whole
lot of luck yeah I guess that's how we
did it so what I'm hearing is is have a
good product stick to your guns and keep
your ethics and what you believe in and
then make sure to tell a story and tell
your message effectively is that sort of
the some some of what you're what you're
getting out there that's it and then and
then yeah and then I don't know I mean
maybe that you resonate in an in a cool
way and you get some cool breaks yeah
just staying true to your guns in some
ways that you wouldn't otherwise and
yeah but um but yeah that's it
that's pretty much the the recipe yeah
so your your advocacy for hemp and
cannabis goes back you know quite far I
know you were even arrested in back in
2012 in front of the White House how do
you feel the legalization process has
gone so far in a lot of these states and
where do you see it headed for
cultivators yeah well you know actually
and that's the view point out something
there's like you know instead of a
marketing budget like we've got kind of
an activism budget and we're like really
good at leveraging our activism to
generate you know not just when the
cause do we want that's our main purpose
and goal but also it effectively gets us
a lot of you know kind of media
attention and you know whatever social
media and stuff so you know I think like
spent you know just being out there and
fighting for causes that you no matter I
mean most of all you to ourselves but
also to you know people who are buying
our products
I think that's um you know just being in
they're really fighting the good fight
is you know just helpful for building
building business in this kind of space
and then yeah so legalization yeah I
mean I think that a lot of legalization
is you know it's kind of like I don't
know I forgot who said it but somebody
said once
like you don't want to watch laws or
sausage get made and you know a lot of
these like you know legalization efforts
are you know they're kind of driven by
polls like you know okay what do you
think what do they think they're gonna
get to 50 plus 1 with and all the
concessions that they make and that kind
of over over burdensome regulations that
you know what you know various interests
feel are necessary to win and I
definitely do appreciate the you know
kind of goal of any prohibition is first
and foremost but yeah I think a lot of
them legalization efforts or you know
kind of less than ideal too far from
ideal as far as the regulatory burdens
being placed on small farmers and
businesses and yeah so you know
hopefully we can you know clean clean
things up legislatively and then um you
know then this would like market-based
programs like seminars just try to you
know really help kind of what's kind of
you know clearly the big industrial
players are moving in and or you look
able to navigate this super complex
regulatory environment you know much
easier um so yeah I mean ideally we move
to a world where you know cannabis is
just another crop and it's more or less
regulated and treated like one and not
like nuclear waste yeah
do you see cannabis following a wine or
whiskey model or well do you think big
big AG is going to take over the
industry here with potentially with
federal legalization no I think it's big
one I think it's like wine right you're
gonna have your what do you call it too
but Chuck you'll have the you know super
commodity stuff but you know I think
very much cannabis will follow the wine
model and you'll have you know everybody
who's producing quality cannabis not
everybody but you know I think people
are really producing like the top
quality styles and doing a smart job you
know communicating and marketing you
know what they're up to and
you know just connecting in a soulful
real way with their customers and
getting a good name for themselves it I
think just very much like you see with
the wine and I'm you know microwire II
to whatever scale winery model um in
California and elsewhere I think that's
pretty much how cannabis will go so
they'll be big players mixed in with
kind of smaller smaller players so you
don't see federal legalization having a
dramatic impact on that because like for
me I had this an interesting discussion
with an some some other people that are
involved in canvas advocacy over on the
East Coast and my concern with federal
legalization is someone who you know
makes potting soils and provides organic
amendments and things like that to
growers is that you know Scott's or Dow
or Bayer could come in at any point with
federal legalization and pretty much you
know wipe me off the face of the map in
about five minutes
and so I don't see my business model as
being something that has a potential
long-term success just because I don't
have the dollars and the PhDs and it
were a small company to stay relevant I
don't know what your thoughts are on it
on the you know on all of this but I
think it's an interesting subject to
talk about for sure ya know I mean can
you say again what's your business focus
what's your so Iowa I have a seven-acre
like farm and feed store that's organic
in in Washington State and we you know
we're big advocates for growing your own
food and regenerative agriculture but
I'm actually having to shut down the
farm due to some compliance code
compliance issues with the county and so
we're just focusing now on our gardening
side of our business which is providing
you know organic amendments and then
soils and things like that organic soils
to the cannabis industry and I know that
you know Scott's already has a line
called black magic that's available in
Home Depot you know more and more
companies are focusing on organic
and coming out there but a lot of the
big AG companies are still holding off
due to this you know the federal
regulations but I'm just wondering if
we're gonna get flooded the moment I'm
wondering if they're already doing
research and they're just ready to take
over the moment you know someone else is
elected or the things go legal I did
it's really interesting
ya know I mean that's definitely you
know a concern and I mean I would say
that I'm just kind of like you see with
organic and and the point of like
regenerative organic is that it kind of
rewards there's only you know it's
generally hard to be a senator's farmer
or regenerative organic farmers here big
this is it's pretty management intensive
style farming and you know lends itself
to smaller scale to kind of handle the
diverse crop rotations and I mean
they're much more productive funds by
area and um you know and just a you know
much more knowledge intensive management
intensive versus chemical intensive so I
think that you know that's part of what
we hope to do with Sun on earth you know
is you know create that market space and
consumer space this is hard to do at a
large scale and then yeah you know I
mean for any given I guess input or
commodity you know I guess yeah I guess
it depends but yeah I mean I you know I
can see how the you know big players
moving in it that's definitely not a
concern but you know hopefully you know
you can get a you know customer base I
just really appreciate the integrity and
soul that's you're putting into making
your amendments and you know whatever's
going into the Scott's black magic stuff
you know not nearly as awesome so you
know and that's something I guess per
senator to think about on the input side
as well you know that kind of reality
well well Sun on Earth is interesting to
me because there aren't a lot of inputs
coming from off the farm which I think
is is wonderful I mean that's ultimately
what we all aim for realizing that much
of
cannabis cultivation is not going to be
able to qualify for senator certified do
you see another certification like I
know certified kind already exist and is
a great program but do you see other
certifications showing up down the road
I know the Washington State Department
of Ag has talked about having an organic
certification and they're working on one
what what would can we have for indoor
growers for example or other forms of
cultivation yeah yeah
hundred percent I mean I think it's all
about incremental progress and I don't
want to say that the perfect should be
the enemies are good you know I think
there's definitely room for
certifications at different levels I
mean ideally they are like an on-ramp to
Sun and Earth eventually as farmers kind
of get off chemical employees and start
generating more on farms utility and you
know just get a into that rhythm but I
think definitely a spectrum makes sense
and is gonna be the reality so you think
there's a chance you know chemical or
synthetic growers will switch over to
this type of certification because the
way I saw this is like this this
certification is so far beyond even just
organic certification the people that
were going to the farmers at least that
would be interesting to be the ones that
are already like pretty passionate about
regenerative agriculture or at least
have some working knowledge cuz the
amount of knowledge involved to meet the
standard is pretty high I would say yeah
he's a jumping off point so some years
is organic not not conventional farming
I mean honey I would say convention
would need to go organic and just kind
of learn you know you know I mean it's a
big thing to go off chemicals and manage
custom you pressure fertility you know
without synthetic inputs and yeah I
don't think most conventional growers
are in a position to go to seminars but
I think if we're successful as a program
you know like the USDA Organic Program
we create a charity man you know that
will create you know the incentives for
many farmers who you know who are
removing organic but not quite to sunder
it so like go ahead and up their game to
that level I guess you know Indian
dimensional farmers can um you know
there's things like integrated pest
management you know different
regenerative act techniques that are not
they're not necessarily an organic
program but are farming in a relatively
more ecological way versus like the
complete disaster you know monoculture
GMO deserts but uh but ya know I think
it's definitely a um the high bar is
definitely enough everybody is ready to
merely summon earth but we do want to
recognize everybody who is there who
right now don't have that kind of market
distinction you know we want to give
them that recognition and
consumer-facing recognition so your
philosophy is really to meet growers
wherever they're at in the journey and
if you can just send them a little a
little closer a little further down the
path towards helping the environment and
being a little more ecologically
conscious than it's a wind so this
really isn't intended to be exclusive
it's it's more of an inclusive process
it sounds like yeah that's you know in
the regenerate organic standard we've
got a bronze silver gold system and I
think they're entertaining a tiered
system if that's not already the case
and seminars and yeah a magic guys
definitely want to you know and then
there's those incremental steps all
along the way you said it well it's all
about like wherever you are you know
just begin that journey towards uh you
know regenerative organic kind of holy
grail you know that's the idea Legrand
vision is like a flaw all of us take
responsibility as consumers and we see
our plates as farms and our knives as
returning knives and our forces pitch
boards and you know we you know what is
our section in the garden look like what
is
we're kind of farm where does that land
what is the farmers that look like his
workers you know is he able to take care
of his land in a degenerative way or is
he just you know this is just like a
blasted industrial landscape that's just
you know wrecking the world and what
there's one third of their surface is
under a duster or agricultural
mismanagement if we can shift that to
regenerative organic linear farm in
nature's image farming ecosystems are
replicating natural ones and important
functional ways you know I've been most
importantly good for about Everest I
have a tad wildlife habitat going
nutritious nutrient-dense food medicine
and clothes and everything else I mean
that'sthat's the goal so the consumer
side you know creating the demand and
I'm a farmer side that putting forward
the certification program and then
training programs also is really
important to just help us get there yeah
I love it
you're speaking my language I'd say it's
so great to hear it and I I really
appreciate the work you guys are doing
this is sort of an unrelated question
just out of curiosity to kind of end the
podcast I know you mentioned you had
some time over in Amsterdam you started
you know consuming cannabis in college
I'm sure at some point in time you've
had conventional versus organic and and
probably a variety of different
cultivars do you have a favorite
cultivar out of curiosity and then have
you can you tell a difference smoking
you know organically versus
conventionally grown cannabis well I
mean I've been I guess back in that you
know I had like not any real
consciousness I mean my my experience in
like the mid nineties was when the dead
were local talented you know podcast
it's on a whole other dimension of
awesome it was like ridiculous
you know versus like them kind of
message that was and all around them and
yeah Amsterdam is you know I didn't
really you know I wasn't yet kind of
vibrating on that tube yeah and it was
until late
you know I guess you know now I mean I
generally just don't really smoke I
guess much that isn't outdoor you know
sun-grown organic you know my favorite
strain I would say the I'm really
digging water dog farm the phoenix
rising pretty pretty pretty amazing
sativa both also like the lemon egg it's
a kind of a lemonade rolls-royce Rose
choice coming out of urban ology it's
one of our seminars certified media is
also a nurse certified I guess I like
the sativas generally speaking but also
really harmony rose from oh that Elysian
Fields or no soft pitch I'm blanking on
the farmer but that's harmony Rose it's
the the lady she's actually cultivated a
lot of high CBD cultivars is kind of
really dialing in on the vibration of
the high having no ideas underlying
cannabinoid profile and yeah Harmony
Rose is from oh my gosh anyways yeah and
you know he gets I guess I don't know I
you know if you did a blind taste test
on the I don't know fun like that
sophisticated like really pulled apart
but I guess vibrationally I just like
knowing you know same thing with an
apple I mean I guess you could you might
fool really conventional versus organic
apple or something but you know I think
just library should only just really
knowing that my medical center of my
this Apple came from a farm those you
know doing everything right and it is
like a great place to work and live
early your farmer or the farm dog or cow
or the you know bugs that it's all well
not the certain kind of bugs
after that kind of buzz it is a pretty
good place you know I get that you know
it's just more that knowledge it's like
what's really important and then of
course the experience is also crucial
and that's something you really want to
emphasize the Sun on Earth is that these
are some of the top quality flowers you
know top top top shelves flowers but
anybody's producing and doing it in a
totally regenerative way so you're also
setting I think that's a good point so
you're also setting a standard in terms
of the flower itself you're not just
saying because you grew in this method
if it's you know poor quality it's not
going to go under the brand you're not
going to be putting that out there at
least with brother David's it's still
going to be a premium flower product
alright percent I mean to the question
yeah earlier like you know how they
succeed I mean number one and foremost
is your product quality we brought dr.
Bronner's you know peppermint soap that
quality started going sideways and
people weren't getting that awesome
tingle you know beautiful lather you
know that experience like every time you
know all the other awesome things we're
doing is like not going to happen so you
know just definitely qualities the
number one and you know all the other
things are you know equal or you know
just also super important and we're not
going to compromise but you know the
qualities has got to be there that's
awesome man I uh I'm so grateful for
your time today and for your company and
as someone who's having a our first
child here in about three weeks I'm
grateful to have access to products like
you know your baby soaps so that i know
that what i'm you know exposing my child
to while there's a lot of toxins in the
environment that's one thing that i can
check off the list and be less concerned
about so thanks for all the good work
you do and and everything and i really
appreciate your time today
right on thank you ted thank you for
having me and congratulations with your
new baby that your first or yeah this is
our first child
yeah we're three weeks out haha yeah
we're pretty excited yeah well
everything's gonna change
yeah you
superb congratulations a big love to
your wife's and you baby and yeah tear
down that was David Bronner CEO of dr.
Bronner's natural soaps stay tuned next
week for my interview with Andrew black
on the importance of certification and
what considerations go into creating one
soon after that though I'll be diving
back into the science side of
cultivation with some university
research on cannabis to present from the
University of Guelph in Canada
you are listening to the cannabis
cultivation and science podcast I'm your
host Todd Hussey don't forget to check
out our web site
www.kpbs.org/news/evening