[Music]
thank you
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad Hussey
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawing top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge my guest this week is Michael
brownbridge Michael is a biological
program manager with bioworks in this
role he provides technical support for
the company's catalog of disease
management products and their
utilization in integrated plant health
programs prior to joining bioworks in
2019 he was fortunate enough to have
traveled the world flying his craft with
research and Outreach positions in
Israel Kenya the United States New
Zealand and Canada putting new
biological control tools and knowledge
into the hands of Growers now on to the
show
hey Michael thanks for coming on the
show today
oh it's a pleasure Todd I'm glad I was
finally able to make it to have a chat
with you
you know me too I I kept saying I
thought we'd recorded this podcast
together because we've talked so much
um so I'm really grateful for you coming
on the show and uh I wanted to start off
kind of just taking a little bit
different angle and and getting since
you are a pathologist well sorry let me
back up why don't you tell me a little
bit about yourself
all right I'll I'm a I'm a recent
pathologist
um truth be told Tad um I spend a lot of
my career actually working on the insect
control side of crop management and
transitioned into
pathology because
one of the you know I firmly believe
that when you're doing Crop Production
you you cannot look at just one thing in
isolation you've got to look at the
whole crop and if you have pest issues
why do you have pest issues and
um do pest issues lead to disease issues
and so an understanding of the whole so
um as my career progressed it became
less just focused on insects and more on
the crop taking an integrated approach
to crop management rather than Pest
Management or disease management and and
then more recently
um as my responsibilities have shifted
I've taken a more active role in
Plant Pathology and use of Biologicals
to control plant pathogens or manage
plant pathogens is probably a better way
to put it
so a bit of a jack of all trades and
dangerous in a lot of things but
um yeah I've I've really enjoyed getting
deeper and deeper into the Plant
Pathology world it was not something I
thought I might do originally but it's
been a fantastic Journey
um and I'm enjoying it tremendously
yeah so so given your background
how do you approach a cultivation space
and let's just use an indoor cultivation
space for this example
um how do you approach that from a from
a pathologist perspective and how does
that differ say from like a grower or an
entomologist
yeah
um
I think any time
you enter a space it's it's always very
tempting to
hone in on something specific
I think you have to take a couple of
moments really to just appreciate the
environment
and I mean environment in the broadest
sense there that you're walking into
um understanding you know what's going
on what sort of heating lighting
ventilation systems do you have what
sort of watering systems do you have
what sort of watching regime do you have
how do you water the plants
um
how tightly packed are the plants
there's a there's a lot going on in a
crop at any given time and you know
plant diseases
typically don't just appear because they
feel like it you know there's there's uh
circumstances that result in that
disease manifesting itself on a plant
so you
sometimes can tell based on the disease
but oftentimes
say it's it's the environmental
conditions it's too humid there's not
enough air movement to keep that air dry
or the leaves dry that that sort of
predisposed plants to certain diseases
is the medium over watered if it's over
watered over watered again that can
predispose the plant to certain diseases
how are the plants being fed so I think
you know if I boil it down to a sentence
it's it's coming into a into a room and
then appreciating
how that plant is being grown first and
foremost and then saying okay let's go
have a look what are your problems
here's why I think it may be happening
and here's how I think here are some
steps that I think will be will will
help
so you're essentially trying to
identify all of the different variables
that go into this plant's growing
conditions or or overall health it
sounds like
um yeah pretty much anything yeah just
to say all the variables I think that
would be a little much a little too much
but certainly the the key variables you
know I'm sure
you and many of your listeners are
familiar with the good old disease
triangle you know where
there are basically three three primary
things which control whether
um a disease will take on your repair on
your plants
um or not one of them is environment an
environment again in the broadest sense
the other one is that the disease has to
be present that inoculum the infection
the Infectious part of that disease has
to be present at high enough levels to
be able to infect a plant and so you you
need virulent inoculum in inside that
inside that room that Greenhouse
Wherever You Are
and certainly you have to have a
susceptible plant and there's a lot of
factors will affect
all of those variables
you know environment what does
environment mean if you have in relative
humidity we can manage relative humidity
we can manage that through good air
exchange good air movement between the
plants let's say so you don't get
localized humidity
we can manage
um the crop to a degree
in terms of which varieties we choose to
go I know that in in cannabis you know
varieties are normally you know the
varieties that have grown are driven
more by market than than my choice for
say a variety which is more tolerant to
certain diseases or not but how else can
we affect the plant and its
susceptibility genetics is one thing but
the second part is really how you grow
that plant
so yes you know how you grow it do you
as I mentioned earlier over watering
underwatering too much of certain
fertilizers too little fertilizers Etc
how you grow that plant matters so it
can
make that plant more or less susceptible
to the disease
and then the third thing you know do we
have sufficient infectious inoculum in
the plant that can be influenced Again
by so many things by
people can bring that inoculum into the
greenhouse or the grow room it can be
there in the media it can come in on the
plants so there are a whole lot of
variables underneath each variable but
having a good sense of that I think
makes you realize perhaps where to
invest
your time and energy in terms of being
able to prevent a disease or to
successfully control it so I think it is
important to take account of as many of
those variables as you can on you know
clearly we can't do everything but we do
we we can I think have a have a good
sense of what goes on and be behave a
little bit like um
detectives to a degree to figure out of
of all of these variables which are the
most likely and and those things can
then help you narrow down sometimes as
to what disease it is some diseases are
pretty self-evident particularly some of
the foliar diseases that are prevalent
in in cannabis but some of the below
ground diseases you know good luck but
we do understand
certain conditions which will which will
make it easier for those diseases to
occur let's say so yeah it's it's I
think understanding a little bit
um
what drives disease occurrence
helps and I think it would having that
again understanding you know the old
saying understand thine enemy if you
understand your enemy you can understand
how to
um prevent that Enemy by understanding
what what specific conditions really
promote uh its incidents so it's
important it's important to take to take
that type of approach so even with pest
you know there's a relationship between
all of those all of those um
plant environment and and pest
uh incidents too so again understanding
the crop first is is probably one of the
most important things you can do
so assuming that we do have an issue a
plant issue
um I would guess the next step would be
proper identification of that of that
disease
it's it's important to have diseases
identified correctly because that can
actually determine
how you go about
controlling
or preventing that disease
um
so for a disease like powdery mildew it
it has quite characteristic symptoms
although you wouldn't necessarily be
able to identify the species
um you know there's powdery mildew
itself is not one fungal species it's a
it's a collection of fungal species that
have very similar symptoms on different
host plants but in cannabis you know
those white fluffy growths on the on the
foliage that's pretty likely to be
powdery mildew
when you get down below ground
um
there are several diseases which can
infect the roots and subsequently sort
of move up through the uh through the
through the the vascular system of the
plant so
actually determining which of those
killed the plant or made the plant sick
is not always easy because they look
very similar and sometimes
one disease can predispose that plant to
infection by another disease and it's
that second disease which actually kills
the plant or renders it you know very
very sick so it is important to get
proper diagnosis so you can understand
how to
um
what steps to take against that disease
preliminary diagnoses may tell you some
very basic steps like if you can just
take the plant out because you're not
going to be able to save it you know but
but I think it's important to get a
diagnosis at some point in the proceding
as well because it it can also help
identify the source of that infection
for example we know that you know a lot
of diseases can be
can't come into a grow via infected
clones let's say
um
but you can't really prove that if you
don't test or do a disease test to begin
with let's say
sometimes disease comes in on certain
media you don't know that unless you
test your media or you test your uh test
your test your plant for a specific
disease so it's kind of a key piece of
the puzzle
not only from a treatment perspective
but looking ahead to the Future Okay
where did it come in how did it come in
and then how can I prevent that
happening again in the future so yeah
it's an important step
foreign
so how prevalent are a lot of these
plant diseases like you know pythium
fusarium
powdery mildew like is it I realize we
can reduce
uh pathogen pressure but is it really
possible to keep those things completely
out of a facility and so is it more
about managing thresholds or having a
healthy hot less stressed plant or or
how do you I guess how do you approach
that
yeah I think you hit the the two Nails
let's stay on the head there
um yes I think a lot of these diseases
are often present whether we like it or
not
um so it comes down to how how do you
keep
numbers low because diseases like pests
you know plants can tolerate
low levels of disease or maybe it's the
levels of disease that are present are
not high enough to actually infect the
plant because the plant will will be
able to withstand a certain a certain
level of Challenge from a disease
um I think that's where maintaining a
healthy plant is absolutely essential
you know
growing the plant not forcing the plant
too much making sure it has what it
needs when it needs it rather than
trying to sort of force feed it or
grow it in a swamp when it should be
grown dry or dryer things like that you
want that plant to be as healthy as
healthy as possible I think it's also
important to to take very seriously you
know before you even start growing the
plant is we we oftentimes when we talk
we say you know sanitation first
sanitation is so so important
by way of
um
the area you're growing the plant in
making sure that's clean sanitation by
how say workers come in and work in a
certain space
if
you have an area where there's a known
degree of infection let's say or pests
for that matter then don't go there
first go there last go into the clean
rooms where the crops are still clean
first for example
understanding your water is your water
clean is your water
full of disease
because of where you're pulling that
water supply from have you had water
tested so there's a lot of steps can be
taken
right from the get-go to ensure you're
growing that plant in the best and
cleanest environment that you can make
it
and then it comes to sort of knowing the
plant material not just buying uh
necessarily the cheapest or what's
available but but I think having a good
trusted supply for uh safety buying in
clones rather than doing them yourself
um I I see a lot of benefits to
growing plants or at least mother plants
from say tissue cultured material
because you know there's a there's a
very high degree of certainty that those
tissue culture plantlets are going to be
free of disease period so
um
again using disease-free stock as your
starting point is going to eliminate
potential Ingress of a lot of pathogens
to these areas but you know we live in a
world which is got a lot of microbes
floating around in the air in the soil
that they are there so it's up to us to
to try our best to eliminate them as
best as we can from a grow room and
create a growing environment which
favors the plant
as much as possible and provides the
plant with what it needs to grow
healthily and robustly and and you know
it's just like us the the
better we eat the better we sleep
um
and look after ourselves the more likely
we are to be able to
resist certain infections
um or at least we recover faster from
those infections if they occur but
generally speaking I would say say um we
can tolerate a certain level of
infection without falling down and
that's a good place to be if we had to
take
certain steps to mitigate that disease
and use you know control products to
basically knock back
um
the disease pressure to knock back
inoculum levels and prevent it spreading
sort of from one crop one plant to
another so yeah there's a there's a lot
we can do to to equip plants
um very very well to be able to resist
diseases too so
it's an interesting area it's an
interesting area
yeah yeah and I know there's testing
available like we offer testing for
you know viruses like oblating thyroid
and you know Alfalfa cucumber tobacco
Mosaic those sorts of things I know
those testing tests kits exist but for
the average grower where do we find out
if our plant has pythium or fusarium for
example or some of these other
um fairly common common diseases I don't
know if pathology labs are there any
resources that are widely available
across the United States
I I think there are
it used to be that University extension
systems would be able to
provide those surface Services often for
a fee but they would provide those
identification services
with the sort of sorry go ahead oh no I
just realized I asked the Canadian where
do I find pathology labs in the United
States so I realize it's probably not
there that's all right no no no we we
have the same issues here Tad I mean
it's I think it's a North American
challenge sometimes being able to find a
Testing Lab
um if you live in a state which has an
agricultural you know Most states have a
have an agricultural uh or a land grant
University which has
um some
um degree of extension services attached
to it that would be the best place to
start but I think increasingly and I'll
I'll speak for I live in Ontario in
Canada and you know and there are at
least three testing Labs that I know of
um where I could send plant material
um it's all done for a fee it's a
fee-based service but there are those
diagnostic facilities that exist
I suspect but I don't know for a fact
that there should be those diagnostic
labs in the US as well within it not
necessarily within every state but
somewhere within a sort of certain area
if we to Cluster all these states in the
Pacific Northwest let's just say for
example I'm sure there's a commercial
Testing Lab where you can send material
for testing and get a definitive answer
on
on what's infecting your your plant
within a within a reasonable amount of
time
um switching crops for a second you know
I know a lot of um vegetable growers in
Ontario will will actually send samples
over to the Netherlands for testing
um
that's a whole you know that's a whole
different undertaking but uh if there's
nothing available in your state that I
would say you know cast a wider net and
and just see which testing Labs may be
accessible to you
so assuming we're talking about
some sort of vascular root disease like
pythium or fusarium getting back to
those two how different is your is your
treatment approach for
those two diseases
um
is the plant a goner at that point since
they are vascular diseases is it better
to just remove it and then are there
ways to treat the soil so I realized
those a few different questions
yeah I would say once once you've got
the disease in the vascular system and
you know you've you've probably seen the
classic pictures of plants where if you
if you sort of slice along the stem of
the plant it's starting to go Brown
inside that's pretty good indication
that the disease has developed up
through that vascular system it's
probably not worth investing a whole lot
of time and resources trying to save
that plant it's it is cheaper probably
to just get rid of that you you do two
things in doing that one it's it's
removed as a headache for you to try and
look after
and and the chances like I say of
actually getting anything out of it are
very very low at that point and secondly
you know the longer you keep that or
plant around the higher the likelihood
that it can serve as a source of
infection for the plants in the in the
near vicinity
um best thing to do is is not wait until
you see plants that are infected I would
say is to
again know your enemy do you have
sources of infection is you know by
Water by clones by soil what are the
what are the risks posed by all of those
things in terms of is there a a
likelihood that there may be some
infection there that you're dealing with
or do we just go ahead and assume that
you know I'm working in an environment
it's highly likely that at some point
there will be disease present
when we're talking cannabis particularly
we it's not a crop where we have really
any
uh real Curative products available to
us that like in um if you if you use a
comparison be say outdoor agriculture
you know where there's a lot of
um
synthetic chemistries
or synthetic products available where
you can see a problem you can spray it
with with chemistry and that takes care
of the problem we're in the prevention
game because we have access to
materials that really rely on us
preventing the disease issues happening
preventing infection taking hold that
plant and protecting the plant against
disease as best we can and this you know
there's a number of products that can do
that and they're best used in a in a
production system you know we we kind of
touched on best cultural practices for
the crop so if you've got good cultural
practices in place your
your plant's going to be better equipped
to sort of handle itself and and deal
with with any any disease challenges but
that's the situation you want you want a
healthy plant that we can then layer on
top of that some of these biological
materials to to further mitigate the
risk or eliminate the risk of diseases
getting into the plant so we really are
we're playing a preventative game here
by how how we approach disease
management
and so what are some of the tools
in the Gardner's arsenal when we
you know I think we may be have to deal
with some of these things
yeah if I start with the soil it's
probably a good place to start
um
there are various
um microbial
biophungicides based on uh fungi like
trichoderma
or bacteria and there's you know various
bacillus species which which can be
really used effectively both the
trichoderma and the bacillus species
um
work extremely well in terms of
preventative control agents the bacillus
sometimes certainly on if you're using
for Folia diseases they have a little
bit of a Curative property just based on
the nature of those products but again
we're ideally talking a preventative
game here
um so you know bacterial
fungal products would would be would be
those of choice for me
um in in that uh prevention game I know
there are other
um
streptomyces let's say products which I
think are registered in in some states
for use same type of scenario as
applying those early in that in that
cropping cycle so they can work as to
prevent diseases I should back up a
couple of steps Ted and and and
talk about the growing medium itself I
mean we we've frequently just talk about
dirt or you know potting mixes but
though having a healthy microbial biota
in there as well is is an important part
of of I would say crop health so
whatever we can do to promote good
microbes versus bad is going to go a
long way to help that plant flourish in
that environment because there's a lot
of you know plants and microbes have had
associations for thousands and well
since the beginning I guess
um just like we really could not survive
without microbes so the plants really
can't survive without those microbes
either they form a very close
associations with them
um certain different microbes have
different functions in soils some are
very good some microbes not so good so
we want to
try and shift the balance of the soil
and um and I'm in no way shape or form
an expert on this you would be much
better positioned to talk about this
than I would but I I firmly believe in
you know healthy soils are part of the
solution as well
um the reason we go then to what are
some of the control products we can use
is that you know at a certain point you
can do everything correct culturally but
the disease pressures are
higher than those cultural practices can
can necessarily prevent that disease
taking hold and that's where we're then
bringing these additional beneficial
microbes to
work within that system
to further prevent the disease and and
these are microbes which have been
specifically
selected
because of their disease
suppressive properties let's say so you
know that you know by introducing them
they they will perform that that
function
um so that's that's that's a very high
level looking at the soil go ahead you
had a question
yeah yeah and that that sort of is my
question it is very high level
um
when we when you say trichoderma
or bacillus like you're acknowledging
that that's a a pretty wide range of
actual species and efficacy and then now
when we talk about marketing and
products it gets even more confusing and
then you add in shelf life and
um all these other things and Spore
counts where it's I think it's really
hard for the for the cultivator or the
end user to really know what's best
because I can go online and find a paper
around your credit trichoderma is
suppressing you know various pathogens
but yeah how do I know that the product
that I'm buying is going to have any
efficacy whatsoever or what is even the
best product for what I'm dealing with
yeah it's a that's a that's a great
great question and how long have we got
we could talk about it for quite a while
and be honest you know I I did very high
level just saying trichoderma and just
saying bacillus just saying streptomyces
doesn't really mean anything
um I'll pick on trichoderma but you
could say pretty much equally the same
for bacillus trichoderma is one of the
most widely distributed organisms
throughout the world you know you can
find trichoderma fungi in pretty well
every every environment you look for it
um
they perform different functions
different trichoderma species do
different things so just saying I have a
trichoderma does not necessarily mean
you have a trichoderma that can suppress
a disease similarly simply saying I have
a bacillus does not necessarily mean you
have a strain of bacillus or
streptomyces if we're talking bacteria
that is capable of suppressing diseases
some bacilli perform other functions in
the environment as do trichoderma some
workers you know decomposers or they can
work together with plants they don't
actually do any Disease Control but they
will perhaps solubilize certain certain
elements in the soil or pre-digest
organic matter and then make the
products the breakdown products are then
made available to the plants so
different organisms have different
functions inside that whole biota that
we call a living soil if you would like
to call it that
um
if we get to you know what do I look for
now in a Disease Control product I I
firmly believe you know
that
products per se that are
registered and that can be registered
with the EPA
registered with the pmra in Canada
those products have to go through a lot
of
testing and in order to be considered as
bio pesticides because if if you make
any
disease management claims on a label you
it has to be a registered product and in
order to get registered there is a lot
of
um
prerequisites in terms of filing a
portfolio of data on the safety and
efficacy of those those particular
microbes to the respective regulatory
authorities
so
choosing a registered product is I think
one way of
safeguarding you know your investment to
some degree that you know what's in that
product it has had to have been tested
you know that what is written on the
side of the the bag it says contains
1 times 10 to the 7 cfus per gram or 1
times 10 to the 9 per gram whatever it
is
if it's a registered product you have to
conform to what is written on the label
so that's a guarantee what is written on
the label as a manufacturer the
manufacturer has to guarantee that what
is in that bag
contains what it says it contains on the
label and that means product Purity so
if it said you know contains 1 times 10
to the 7 cfus trichoderma heart CNM at
least per gram
that's what it contains and it also
guarantees that there's a a minimal
amount of other microbes in that bag and
there are very strict guidelines from
both the EPA and the pmra around
acceptable levels of contaminants and
it's very very low so in order to get a
product registered you have to go
through a lot or or jump across a lot of
hurdles go through a lot of Hoops
however you want to word it in order to
get that product registered but then
what it does as I said it sort of is a
guarantee for the purchaser of that
product that it contains what it says it
does and it will do the job that it that
is stated on the label unfortunately
there's a lot of unregistered products
which are sold
um
as or plant growth enhancers or
I don't know plant growth enhances the
best one I can think of right now
that may or may not contain the microbes
that it says on the sheet or may contain
significantly fewer microbes that it
says in in the literature that you might
accompany the product
so
just because it a package says it
contains a product doesn't mean it's
actually living it doesn't mean it's
actually contains spores of that product
at all and tests that I know you're
you're familiar with some of the work
that that I've been involved in
previously is looking at some of these
sort of unregistered materials and it's
quite scary actually what you find
inside them it's also quite scary the
flip side that it says it contains you
know
um 10 to the 7 of a specific fungus
let's say and it actually doesn't
contain anything that's living inside it
at all so you you think you're on a good
thing it contains trichoderma that's
good right no I understand that there's
a there is a there is a reason why
certain strains have been commercialized
and it's not just any old trichoderma or
bacillus or streptomyces that goes into
a commercial product they have to have
met certain performance standards they
have to have men met certain production
standards in terms of uh producing that
consistent level of the microbe that
goes into that product The Jug of the
bag
um and there's a certain safety
associated with that product as well it
I've I've
seen examine products and some of the
organisms that come out of them are
actually things like aspergillus
penicillium now certain aspergillus can
be very that human pathogens you really
don't want to be spraying that into your
crop when you specially when you're
talking a crop like like cannabis you
know if you think I'm I'm doing a good
thing here
and you're spraying on penicillium or
aspergillus I mean that's a that's a
real
um
you're setting yourself up for failure
when when that when those those flowers
go for the sort of total yield uh yeast
and mold counts you know because you're
just putting
um spoilage microbes contaminant
microbes out in the crops so
I told you it'd probably take a good
hour to talk this one properly through
but there are risks associated with just
buying any product so it really is
inherent upon the
buyer to do a little bit of homework
around the product and make sure what
you're buying has has
is registered as a good track record and
if in doubt you know if somebody knocks
on your door says hey I've got this best
thing in some unmarked bags out here you
want to try it always always ask to see
some data sort of supporting
um
supporting the sort of the claims that
are being made on the label or by the
person selling that product
um and that oftentimes sorts out the
good the good from the bad or the wheat
from the chaff depending on how you want
to you want to phrase it but uh
um it is hard to navigate sometimes and
um
it really is inherent upon the
individual I think to do a little bit of
uh do a little bit of checking and if in
doubt you know call the companies and
ask for the ask ask for some of these
details we've just discussed
yeah I know this was a pretty Hot Topic
at the latest biosolutions conference
because
um
as the industry is trying to gain
legitimacy for
biofungicides for biostimulants all of
you know using microbes commercially in
agriculture you have all these products
out there that are essentially either
ineffective or making wrong claims or
skirting registration and that are you
know painting a bad name for the
industry and correct me if I'm wrong I
believe uh Suzanne got a sample from one
of the largest uh
companies in my part of the living soil
portion industry I think it was Bavaria
and you you tested it and found it
didn't contain enough spores to have any
efficacy is that
does that sound right that's absolutely
correct yeah and another sample we
actually found no living Bavaria in the
product at all and with
pretty particular about how we how we
ran these tests as well and you know you
run a test once
and nothing shows up you you always
doubt the results so you make sure you
run it again and then run it a third
time just to just to triple check the
validity of the data that you get so
yeah it wasn't just a fluke
um it was true so yeah I mean these are
Suzanne found the sample we we did the
testing for her and found nothing in it
oh nothing in it of value let's put it
that way
yeah yeah that's crazy and then
um but yeah if you went on the reviews
for that product on the product page
you'd see positive reviews and you'd see
on Instagram a lot of reviews that are
positive but yet the efficacy isn't
there so that's I think that's amazing
and that's where we have to separate out
actual like science and data from
marketing
um you also I had heard found another
product that had on their label and I
believe it was bavari again levels so
high that it wasn't
it wasn't physically physiologically
possible to have that sort of volume
in yeah or sport count and of all in the
amount of volume I'm saying that's right
it was a it was a it was a mix of
microbes and if if it contained
everything that it said on the label you
could not fit all of those spores into a
gram it was just physically impossible
but but again the claim was there
and we indeed tested it and I think the
claim was there's something like a
10 billion or 100 billion scores per per
gram I think it was and we we
got some samples plated them did the
counts and then you do the math and
there was you know something like a
10 000 times less lower level of
organisms
the only things that we could get out of
it were
um bacteria so presumably a bacillus we
found no no fungi in the in the product
at all I mean you know we we throw
things the word we throw words around
like penicillium and fusarium and we
think they're all bad in actual fat
that's not the case you know
um just to clarify this or or get it on
the record I'd say you know 95 percent
of the uh penicillium and fusarium
strains you find in in a typical soil
sample are actually very very beneficial
and in fact some I know some some
penicillium strains have have been
commercialized because they actually
solubilize soil nutrients very very
efficiently and can make them more
available to the plant so
um again it's just just saying
penicillium or fusarium doesn't doesn't
hold a lot and this kind of gets back to
an earlier question that it's important
to know the species because some species
even though it has that genus fusarium
or penicillium the actual species can be
totally harmless so
um but again back back to this question
yeah I mean it's ridiculous what people
put on the side of a side of a label
sometimes and and I I question why
put so many organisms in there because
many of the organisms do exactly the
same thing
many of those organisms live in exactly
the same niches either or on the plant
route or close to the plant root or in
the soil
they don't all
colonize at the same time at the same
rate so you know all soils are different
soils are very dynamic they will evolve
through the life of a crop so what's
what microbe is predominant today may
not be the predominant microbe tomorrow
so
um
I don't know I I sometimes question the
value of putting you know 20 different
microbes in a mix unless they're just
trying to cover all the bases I I I
don't know
um and especially as you know some of
the
functions that those microbes have will
only really happen if those microbes
establish
and form a an association at a certain
level and by certain level I mean the
microbial population size has to be at a
certain level to actually do any good so
yeah it's a it's a very gray area I 100
agree with you there are some excellent
products out there microbial products
out there really really excellent there
are some excellent biostimulants out
there but for every good one you have I
would say there's probably
two or three
dubious ones
um which which sound great but don't
actually do a whole lot
yeah and when you say registered I want
to just make sure people realize that's
EPA registration not State registration
um there's a big difference there in
terms
yeah I was gonna say if I wanted to
register a product in Washington state
or Oregon or California for example
that's very easy process I don't have to
show any efficacy especially you know I
don't know if 25b applies to microbes
I'd have to check on it well it yes it's
a little more complex than that most of
the states
will only register products if they have
EPA registration now this is products
making
pesticide claims hmm
okay but if you don't make any claims
around it then you're okay if you don't
make any claims you can probably go in
and you still have to get State
registration yeah 25 B's are a great
example I think and that
people look at 25 bees as as
unregistered products well they're not
they are actually EPA approved because
the EPA says we're categorizing this as
a 25 B Because based on the information
we have we don't think it poses any any
risk to the environment
or to human animal or plant Health
therefore you do not need to go through
a lot of the EPA regulatory requirements
to you to get that product approved for
use so it's categorized as 25b which is
an EPA categorization
now those still have to be registered at
the state level so there is a certain
level of responsibility and
accountability in order to get that
product approved for use at the state
level
cannabis then typically has an
additional layer of requirements to go
through to get products approved for use
on cannabis so it is a process
and and that process will differ
depending on as you rightly said the
claims that are being made on on the
material you know if if you're not
claiming any um
pest or disease management not making
any pest or disease management claims
then but you're registering it for the
plant benefit claims then it's it's a
different process altogether
yeah and I get emails all the time time
from uh Chinese companies that are
selling various species of bacillus and
trichoderma and all of this like I could
I could very easily today
go online make a mix and sell it without
having any efficacy data showing that
one that's actually what I'm saying is
in the product is in the product or two
that it even works but it that's what I
think a lot of companies do
unfortunately
yeah you're absolutely right and I you
know this was another
product that Suzanne
um found and it was being sold I think
on
Etsy or something like that or you know
you can get these products on Amazon and
Etsy and goodness knows where else
um she sent us a sample it was it was
supposedly a a meter Museum product now
materism is
typically a Associated as a with insects
it's a it's an insect control fungus and
there's again there's some great
products out there
but
um
these barrels of materism I think it was
anisopley was apparently coming in and
very cheap very cheap sold in from China
um we got a sample and again it was one
of those
products we tested there was absolutely
no no living matterism in the product
or in that in that material I I hesitate
to use the word product because it
really wasn't
and you have to think as well there's a
lot more goes into a bag of product than
just
spores there's a whole lot of
stabilization which keep those spores
alive over time that's kind of relates
to your earlier question about shelf
life so the way in which those spores
are preserved and formulated
affects how stable they are and and how
long they will remain alive and
therefore effective when you when you
store them either in the fridge or at
room temperature
any formulation
back up on that one formulations often
as well contain additional materials
which help
the grower then put that material if
it's a microbial putting it into the
spray tank or into the into this where
however the whatever they're using
whatever equipment they're using it
helps that process of of getting those
spores into suspension and then it helps
them stay in suspension and it helps
that product when it actually gets onto
the leaf or targets the pest it'll help
it work better and remain
effective for longer in that environment
so there's a lot more to a product than
just say getting a bag full of spores
from somewhere
um
again that's why registered registered
products have have made the investment
in in coming up with a formulation that
is stable that will preserve the
viability of those microbes and and will
help uh at the application end in terms
of preparation and application and and
oftentimes improve efficacy as well so
yeah there's a lot there's a lot we
could talk about in this whole area for
sure
well and I would just add you know that
they're going to be clean to or cleaner
in terms of heavy metal contaminants and
things like that that could also
cause issues especially in Kansas well
yeah yeah and we have to conform to uh
again that's one of the requirements of
any registered products that you you I
mentioned the contaminants I was kind of
referring to microbial contaminants but
it but it also applies to
um heavy metals as well you know you
have to fall under EPA prescribed levels
of any heavy metals in any product so
that's also another guarantee that
around heavy metals if it's coming from
offshore and they're making claims on it
number one it's actually illegal to use
it because it's not registered
and number two you have no idea what you
buy you really don't
yeah the problem with that though is
like um
unfortunately there's a lot of companies
again a lot of the companies that I that
do quite well and sell you know millions
of dollars worth of product every year
that have not gone through the step of
registering their product and you know I
do I do blame them but I also kind of
blame
this one the states were making it so
difficult to have to register in 50
states is frankly stupid I think um we
should have some sort of federal
registration but
um there's there's no really
accountability like in the state of
Oregon
you know you have companies that will
continually not register or their
products don't contain what they claim
they do and they might pay 150 fine or a
thousand dollar fine well yeah you know
if you're doing 10 million dollars in
that state do you really care like it's
not the financial incentive is not there
uh I think to discourage or eliminate a
lot of these a lot of these products
either because like on my side you know
in the living soil industry one of my
one of my biggest competitors has done
gone by without registering for years
and is now just starting to register
their products even though they've known
that this is something that you're
supposed to do there's no incentive to
do it because it costs money it requires
more regulation
um
it's yeah it's a frustrating topic for
me it is I I couldn't agree more with
you it is it is frustrating but and and
yeah if it's cheaper to pay the fine
then actually pay the registration costs
not just the registration costs but you
have to have data
you know which is a cost
um and time so yeah frustrating but uh
I I tend to think that or I would like
to think in an Ideal World
um registration means something
um we need to get a little bit smarter
perhaps about the processes required to
register a product and having one
Federal registration would be ideal you
know it would save a heck of a lot of
time and time and energy
and you know I I think again it
you know registered products it can be
registered and still not work because
there are a whole lot of other factors
around making a product work effectively
when you apply it but but at least you
know what you're buying is what it says
it is and has a good chance of doing
what it what it says it will do what it
says or what the what the the vendor
promises it will do so
um I'd like to think it was
again it's incumbent upon people to to
really
take a look at what they're buying and
are you are you getting value for money
there are you getting are you sure the
product's doing what what it what it
what is
said on the label or advertising
literature is it doing what it says it
does and how do you know that
I I
it's always an interesting com
conversation to have with how do you
know the products worked
uh because things look Greener okay is
that a true measure
and I just I'm being somewhat flippant
there but I think having a a good idea
in your own mind
um what does success look like if I use
this product
what am I what do I want this product to
do number one and how will I be able to
measure that to sort of say
pretty done uh equivocally that that the
product's done you know what I wanted it
to do so
it's not always easy to do either yeah
it isn't and and on the flip side like I
I at this conference that we were both
at
um there were companies you know
including bioworks it's like I have this
product it's coming you know and you're
not talking about a matter of days and
weeks it's it's more on the scale of
months a year because or years because
of the amount of research that has to go
into it and then not just that research
but then
um you know the registration process in
all these states so even once you have
the data there's still that waiting
period and that that to me is one of the
most frustrating things about the
regulatory process is that you know
you've got it you've got this product
that you have a solution
um and you just can't get it out there
but I still I'm fully supportive of
Regulation
um you know for me I almost equate it to
like the pharmaceutical industry like
you're not going to go get your
antibiotics from the the farmer's market
or the guy in the alley if you want them
to act know that they're actually going
to work you know right like you go to
the doctor absolutely and that's the
difference absolutely that's literally
the difference it's that extreme almost
between
regulated products and the unregulated
products
yeah yeah I couldn't agree more and it
you know
putting my company hat on now I mean it
is very frust frustrating at times the
amount of time it does take from
submission of a registration package to
actual approval you know it does take
um
months to years for that to happen and
it's a shame we we haven't figured out
to make things move along faster there
but oh well
to go through the same system
unfortunately
yeah no I appreciate that I had one last
thing I kind of wanted to touch on
um you and I started this conversation
uh in Reno at the conference talking
about
and it's a complex topic this idea of in
soils or you know in my case with living
soils so soilless media that we're
reusing and treating like soils we have
we have this microbial Consortium
that's constantly
co-evolving with our cannabis plants and
changing
um
uh what are your thoughts around how do
we ever really fully understand this
process
um or or can we ever really fully
quantify or understand it
golly what a question
this is this is Nobel Prize stuff if we
answer this one Todd you know
I think
for sure you know
plants
don't stay the same of course throughout
their life and
at certain times of that plant growth
those roots if we're talking about soil
specifically those roots will
exude different compounds
and some of those compounds like sugars
favor
um
Association of certain microbes
certain sugars certain microbes
um sometimes when plants are stressed
for example they will put out different
chemicals to try and recruit in other
microbes
at other times the plant's development
you know as it gets older again those
those exudates will change slightly and
the microbial population in and around
that soil will change slightly I think
if it's a true living soil as well you
have to understand that the soil itself
is constantly changing let alone what's
going on with the plant but the soil
itself will be changing because there's
always
organic matter which is in different
states of Decay inside the soil and
there's different successions of
microbes will come in and take advantage
of certain elements
that are released from that organic
material over time so it is a constantly
evolving and changing microbial
landscape in there will we ever fully
understand it good question but you know
I think
we can
understand it to a point
um and maybe's
by having certain microbes in a certain
place at a certain time God it's it's
difficult to sort of say because the
plant needs
some microbes at some time other
microbes at other times how do we how do
we try and ensure that those microbes
are present as and when the plant needs
it so I haven't answered your question
at all I've danced around it very very
neatly but I don't think there's an
answer per se to it that I can come up
with I think
we will over time develop a better
understanding of what goes on in the
soil and I think that's what
some of these
studies I've done you know where they're
using these wonderful micro arrays to
identify
different
microbes and the the level of their
um
Presence at different times through the
plant's life I think the mistake would
be to take one sample and say look at
all the microbes I've found and say
that's it that's all the plant needs now
and forever I think we have to
understand that things change
and that microbial population will
change over time as well and be okay
with that
um
but then by using some of the new tools
that we have we can get a better
understanding if we have that
understanding and then maybe as we get
to a point
to sort of say well at this time the
plant typically needs microbes you know
X Y and Z or something like that
um let's make sure they're there or what
can we do to promote these microbes at
this time and then change perhaps a feed
in the soil to encourage other microbes
to be present at another time I think
it's incredibly complicated
um but as as humans we we try and
simplify it as best we can and come up
with a with a very sort of simple answer
to a very complex solution so yeah I
think it is complicated
again you could probably spend a
lifetime
investigating that and uh still not have
the right answer
yeah I find it absolutely fascinating
yeah beautiful question Todd beautiful
question thank you I mean I guess I
asked this in the context of
the idea that we have knowing that the
microbial life in soil is constantly
evolving constantly changing
um yeah hopefully selecting for
microorganisms that are going to be more
beneficial for the plant as that plant
is continually putting out exudates to
support those sets of microorganisms
um
I I guess for me it almost feels too
derivative to try and a reductionist to
try and make
um
any assumptions around
microbial life other than to say hey
we're dealing with this problem and we
know that these species
can there's research the point that you
know trichoderma battles these problems
or mycorrhizal fungi with this uptake
yeah and so there's there's targeted
things I feel comfortable saying we can
do but as a general rule looking at
you know fungal to bacteria ratios or
you know entire sets of organisms
um and that's where it feels like it
it's like the forest through the trees
almost
absolutely agree I mean I think you're
right there are certain key organisms we
can we can uh hone in on and I think
that to you to your reference there the
strike certain certain trichoderma
species for Disease Control they will
also help you know help the plant let's
say uh mycorrhizae uh bacillus species
we we know that they can they're pretty
um
tough organisms that will establish and
grow in a wide range of soil types a
wide range of pH values and a wide and
the form associations with a wide range
of crop species or plant species better
put
um
so I think those are again ones we can
sort of look to and perhaps count on to
bring in their their a game every single
time you you use them pretty well rather
than trying to get
um
understand what the heck's going on with
that whole microbial ecology in the soil
and somehow
um control it you know I think I think
one of the things that just popped into
my head as well is you know every single
organism we've talked about including
plants
um
The Beneficial ones especially need
oxygen so you know how else can you
affect the microbial Community well it
depends on
how much water you put into a plant as
well
will affect the plant will affect the
microbial community and so there's a lot
of
you know it goes back to what I was
touching on earlier you know what role
does environment play in all of these
associations as well so that adds an
extra layer of complexity to to uh to
any valuation or to any study but but I
think
to sort of bring it down to simplify it
somewhat and back to your point I think
yes there are certain key microbes we
know
will perform well will consistently
establish and form those beneficial
associations with plants and uh
those are things you know from a from a
perhaps from a disease management
perspective ones that we can we can
pretty well hang our hats on and say we
know this works and here's the data to
show it
yeah okay so last question I'm going to
throw you a curveball here
um
I've seen this for foreign
[Laughter]
I'm trying to think how to phrase this
so I see a lot of people on social media
um or you know coming from the compost
tea industry where
when you add
a food source let's say alfalfa meal or
uh oat flour you get uh
you get a growth on the surface a sort
of a white fuzzy mold growth and people
show this as as it being beneficial or
probiotic or a sign of good microbial
activity
what are your thoughts on that
I would say what is the fungus I
guarantee I can throw anything like that
in my garden and within a matter of days
it'll be white and fluffy too it doesn't
mean it's a beneficial fungus it just
means there's a fungus there which can
utilize that
whatever it is as a food source and
proliferates on it
so
this measure
there's no evidence that it has any sort
of plant or soil benefit it it could
very well be innocuous
could be totally innocuous you know the
soil is full of all sorts of
um microbes which just hang out there
you know they derive
food from a you know
a wide variety of sources a lot of them
are just decomposers you know
some of them may form associations with
plants others might form associations
with
um
arthropods which live in the soil you
know they just happen to be there and
um went for it to be ingested by an
arthropod and then they yeah I don't
know but yeah just to get something
white and fluffy growing on
um
a Alfalfa powder or oatmeal powder
doesn't prove a darn thing
awesome thank you hopefully that will
make people think a little more
critically about some of these photos I
see yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah and you
know
I'm not I I I know there's a lot of
thought and passion put into a lot of
these things so I'm not doubting the the
good intent behind a lot of a lot of
these claims but I think we need to be a
little bit more
um
discerning
yeah or scientific and how we actually
say this is good this is bad or this is
a sign of something really good or or
whatever and Discerning is a good word
that just because it's white and flooded
fluffy doesn't make it a good thing you
know botrytis can be white and fluffy as
confusarium be white and fluffy as can
penicillin be white and fluffy
um is that a good thing have we got good
or we got bad again
it doesn't really answer the question
which is good you've got a fungus here
that's about all you can say what is it
I'd love to know what what that fungus
is so
um
great Point thank you yeah yeah you're
welcome you're welcome we'll continue
this conversation next time we meet Todd
I think it's a fascinating topic
absolutely thank you so much for your
time today and I I do look forward to
catching up with you again soon
beautiful talking to you thanks very
much for the opportunity
[Music]
thank you
that was Michael brownbridge and you are
listening to the Cannabis cultivation
and science podcast I'm your host Tad
Hussey if you like the podcast please
leave us a rating and review and give us
a follow on Instagram you can also sign
up for our newsletter on our website
homepage to stay up to date on the
latest research and information thanks
for listening
foreign