[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host CAD Hussey of KISS
organics this is the podcast where we
discuss the cutting-edge organic growing
from a science-based perspective and
drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge I want to warn listeners that
today's podcast is not about cultivation
I do have some great guests lined up
soon for more interviews on growing but
today I want to discuss another
important topic for anyone growing
cannabis as a business or working in the
cannabis industry
you know that having a great product or
growing top-shelf cannabis is only half
the story the other half is shaping your
message in a way to effectively reach
your audience on that note I had the
pleasure today of interviewing my good
friend Chang golos who has had his feet
in both the marketing and cannabis world
for a long time now Shengo is the
founder of shaping fire and the host of
the shaping fire podcast if you haven't
had a chance to check it out I highly
recommend it his YouTube channel
features exclusive how-to videos and
expert interviews
Shengo is also the founder of Vimeo the
medical cannabis entrepreneur trade
group on Vashon Island here in
Washington State where he lives that is
now involved into a patient outreach and
educational organization hosting some of
the top cannabis speakers in the world
not to put myself in that category but I
did have the honor of speaking at the
Vimy event and that video on living soil
home growth can be seen on his youtube
channel Shingo has been working in brand
strategy and marketing for 25 years and
since 2013 has been helping cannabis
entrepreneurs bring their products to
market
hey Shango thanks for your time today
welcome to the show hey thanks for
having me on you know it's a it's kind
of fun to have the the tables the
microphones turned because you've been
on my shaping fire podcast a couple
times but but now you're interviewing me
so this is this has got some different
flavor for it so thanks for having me on
the show yeah well you and I have talked
off air quite a bit and I know you have
such a wealth of experience from your
previous careers and also everything
you've done in and around the cannabis
industry so I'm excited that we'll get
the opportunity interview you and share
some of this marketing and branding
information with our listeners yeah and
it's a little different than your other
shows too because I like I enjoy
listening to your your podcast and you
know it's it's all very scientific and
the the idea that we're gonna kind of
plug in some marketing information for
for people out there that are bringing
some kind of cannabis related product to
market I think I think that it's going
to be you know a fun little something
different yeah I think so too and I kind
of wanted to start off by giving
listeners a little bit of background
into who you are and what what you're
all about right now cool so um so I
guess the the two important things about
my background that that would would
inform our discussion today would be
number one I've been doing brand
strategy and marketing and what we used
to call back in the day in the dot-com
boom product evangelism you know for you
know over 20 years or so and and I was
lucky enough you know I did the first
dot-com boom and all of that chaos an
investment capital and and I got to live
that experience and and at that time
people always said oh my gosh to to be
alive and to be an entrepreneur you know
when a whole new industry starts this is
a once and a lifetime thing and I was
very grateful for it you know I was in
my early 20s and I was making more money
than I ever had in my life right then
and the funny thing is that once in a
lifetime experience who I'm having again
now in cannabis and and so I'm very
grateful to you know be alive in this
time and to be able to participate so
but back in the dot-com age
you know or the first boom we were doing
lots of tech related stuff and we were
doing a lot of brand building and and
and destroying a lot of companies and
and then building some that survived too
so that was great but but as far as what
we're talking about today
I think the most relevance is is since
2013 I've been helping cannabis related
companies bring their products to market
it all started with I founded this
organization here on Vashon Island where
I live that brought together all the
medical growers so this was this was pre
taxation and normalization here in
Washington State and you know people
were getting together and and I live on
this island in the and the farmers were
just competing against each other
selling against each other on the island
and so we had very low prices for very
high quality flour and value-added
products like RSO and edibles and things
like that and and when I kind of
realized what was going on I'm like oh
my gosh all you farmers could make so
much more money if we got the product
off the island if we got it into the
dispensaries in other parts of the state
and and since it was legal enough I you
know I started this this group called
Vimeo the Vashon Island marijuana
entrepreneurs Alliance and and I and I
know that the word marijuana is not
really people don't embrace that as much
as they did but in 2013 you know I
didn't I didn't understand that cannabis
it was going to be our preferred word
anyway so so I pulled together all the
for all the farmers and I said listen
you know I can help build these
relationships with the dispensaries over
town off the island and then we if we
all work together we can do things like
bye-bye soil and bulk and living soil
nutrients in bulk and packaging in bulk
to bring everybody's cost down and then
to bring your profit up and of course
they were all like into this idea so
that's that's really where I got my
start bringing my you know the the brand
strategy and marketing and operational
stuff that I had been doing in tech into
cannabis because I myself am a cannabis
patient
a traumatic brain injury and then and
then started teaching what I knew to
people here on the island and so after
helping the growers on the island kind
of set up this distribution network
through the Washington medical system
people started asking me for help with
with you know different products a you
know a soil nutrient or a you know a
specialty you know value-added canvas
product and then and then it's just been
continuing on now for four five years or
so I must admit I'm I'm kind of moving
away from the consulting well I'm still
available for like products that I think
are cool now that the shaping fire
podcast is taken off so much and and I'm
traveling a lot to do that and to
interview people and to speak I'm not
doing nearly as much consulting I'm
doing but it doesn't mean that my brain
doesn't think about it all the time
still yeah that's great you know I've
had a lot of discussions about marketing
and you've actually helped me with
considering how to position or look at
another podcast and I'm looking at
starting and some other stuff so I've
really appreciated your your knowledge
and your perspective on things
throughout the years I think it's great
well cool I'm glad I could be helpful
yeah so now that we know a little bit
about you and I have to say like if you
meet Shangaan person you would never
picture that he was this like tech guy
you know he you feel to me like someone
who's been around cannabis your whole
life and yeah the Vashon Island is just
such this amazing place for artists and
on and people looking to kind of get
away from sort of every city life yet be
pretty close to the city it's such a
cool experience if people ever get a
chance to make it out there I highly
recommend it yeah I'm really I'm really
lucky and actually it was my brain
injury that brought me to Vashon I used
to live in Seattle proper and my after
my brain injury my neurologist said you
know if you really want to heal properly
yeah use the cannabis medicine but also
you should move out of town and so I
moved here to Vashon in in 2011 and
that's been pretty great and you know
even though I only started really you
know being involved with cannabis
business in 2013 I mean I've been
talking since since college so you know
that's like 1989 I got turned on to
smoking cannabis so I've been in
cannabis culture and I'm a Deadhead too
right so yeah I followed the Grateful
Dead for a couple years and you know I
still I still listen to them you know
weekly so you know I'm an old head it
was kind of funny too recently this this
year I let my hair grow again because
you know at the beginning of this more
formalized version of cannabis that
we're getting into a lot of the early
people they you know they wanted to talk
to people in suits they didn't want to
trust their millions of dollars to
somebody who didn't look like who they
were familiar with so when I started in
cannabis you know I had my hair a little
shorter and when I would speak at
conventions I would wear a suit and then
after a couple years of that I realized
that the kind of people that I attracted
in my suit was was different than the
people I wanted to work with so I said
ah hell and I just let my hair grow long
and Farrell again and and I wear my
normal clothes too and and and and
everything's still fine and I'm still
making money and people still want to
hear my my opinions so I just decided
that wearing a suit was a was a not not
an important variable nice well that
talks a little about your own personal
brand and how you wanted to position
yourself in the market and be perceived
so I think that's right on topic but
let's let's go ahead and dive in a
little bit now about some of the things
you and I talked about in terms of
branding and marketing I wanted you to
be able to give a little bit of a
foundation for say growers or someone
who had a product that was coming out in
the cannabis industry could you give us
a little bit of a foundation around best
practices and things that would gallon
the marketing side yeah for sure so so
I'll take a little module out of a out
of a class that I teach and and this is
also where I start with all of my
consulting clients just to put us on on
the same page so I'll go through five
categories of a brand strategy I guess
we'll call it that should be considered
both by by folks who are are launching a
you know a farm or something that's
going to produce cannabis itself but
this also works just as well for a non
regulated product whether it be you know
bongs and pipes and rolling papers or
your like like living soil nutrition or
something so
so there's five categories the first one
is going to be naming a lot of people
they've got the name that they've been
calling their project in their head and
so it's kind of like a default that
that's what the name of the business is
going to be but there are some really
important things to think about when
choosing a name for example you want to
make sure that you know it's unique in
cannabis right you want to make sure
there's not already somebody doing that
name also you want to pick something
that is is has got some kind of unique
word in it
so that it's easily searchable right you
know if that's why we get a lot of these
these companies called like purple
penguin right because you don't usually
get the word purple in the word penguin
next to each other so if somebody
Google's purple penguin they come right
up if you were to call your company
let's say green rush right one of the
most common terms used in cannabis media
right now you know if you put in Green
Rush company they're not gonna find your
company right there's going to be all of
these news articles about the Green Rush
and so I encourage my clients to to do a
little brainstorming to find something
that it's unique that catches the spirit
of how they want to be seen and and and
you know in the old days we would do
like a whole half day brainstorming
workshop but most folks don't have time
or resources to do that so so I just
recommend this this quick little
exercise to get you going which is to to
brainstorm 50 descriptive words for what
you do or sell and and when you get to
probably you know somewhere between
eight and twelve it's going to start
getting hard and and and don't give up
then because it's when your brain is
search
for other words that don't come to mind
quickly that you actually stumble across
really good names and so you want it you
want to press your mind you want to make
your mind really work for these words so
so the first time through you
brainstormed fifty descriptive words for
what you do or cell and then and then
the second part of it is that you
brainstorm another 50 words that you'd
like your customers to use to describe
you so now you've got two columns one
column is all about you know what you do
what you're selling or what your service
is and the other one is descriptors and
then you could just play with that
massage those words back and forth and
and start to find well well what jumps
out to you what excites you what
combinations of words do you think are
cool and because you've pushed your mind
twice you're gonna have a lot of
unexpected words that that came to you
after you've done your first you know 10
or 12 and chances are you're gonna find
a lot of really interesting unexpected
highways to go down and then and then
with all of those resources you have
made mix and match them and and until
you have at least five acceptable names
right five names that you think okay I
could I could live with this name for a
while don't just stick with the first
one because just because you've gotten
one name that it is acceptable you know
the next one may actually be better and
you're gonna be you're gonna have this
name for a lot of years hopefully so you
want to make sure that you you pick a
good one
so do your brainstorming exercise mix
and match the words make file at least
five acceptable names and then we go to
category two which is social media so
now that you you know got a name for
yourself or at least a proposed list of
five names you need to really check your
social media because it is going to be
forever a pain in the butt if if someone
else has already got the social media
handles that are the name of your
company you'll find that you're you're
having to do like an underscore in
between them or do a weird spelling or
man all that stuff really degrades your
marketing and so after you've got your
list of five acceptable name
number one go and make sure you can get
the dough name domain name go make sure
you can get the dot-com for it then go
check Instagram and Facebook and Twitter
and make sure that you can get the your
name the same in all of those places and
why this is so important is because you
know not only you want to be able to
tell your customers where to go very
easily but when you start printing up
flyers and and and printed materials
it's a it takes up a lot of space to
list four or five different social media
locations for yourself because your your
this on IG but your this different thing
on Facebook and then you've got a
different domain name it just gets
really confusing so it's important
enough to pick a unique name that is
unique enough that you can pick it up in
all of your social media uniquely and
you know if someone is sitting on a name
that you want to use say for example you
know on Twitter or something I mean
domain names are much more regulated so
it's you can't really grab somebody's
domain name but for Twitter for example
I was working with Gaja preneur calm and
somebody had been sitting on the twitter
handle ganja preneur but they hadn't
posted anything in two and a half years
and so on their behalf i wrote to
twitter and i said hey you know this is
that this is our legitimate business
name and and this cat has got this this
twitter account that says contra preneur
but he doesn't do anything with it right
and he hasn't for years so how about you
consider taking it from him and giving
it to us since it's our official
business name Twitter people and they
said yeah right and so and so I was able
to you know capture that furred forg
entrepreneurs so so if you've got a
company and and and you can get the
domain name and you can get a couple of
the social medias but you can't get one
of them know that it is a possibility
that you could reach out to them and and
and claim that you got this business
and couldn't potentially
grab that that social media if somebody
is active on it that's probably way less
likely but if it's neglected it makes it
makes it really easy alright so that's
the second category so first one is
naming oh good well I just wanted to
jump in a little about naming cuz I
think that's so important and I think
people under value it as exactly how
much of a priority it is I can tell you
that when we first started my business
or I came into my parents business it
was a compost tea brewing company and
our name was simplicity but it was - TE
a witch from a dot-com perspective is
really tough so people had trouble
finding the website right away my
parents didn't know anything about tech
you know this was back in 2000 when
comms weren't even really a thing but it
became a big challenge and as I've
looked into naming future businesses and
ideas and products and things like that
I've had the opportunity to meet with
some really really amazing people on the
marketing side and one of the things
that they've they've taught me is sort
of take the values that are associated
with your product whatever your product
is whether it's cannabis or cannabis
related you know fertilizer or something
and figure out what those values are and
then figure out how you can convey them
to that audience and you can do it by
making word-association you like
creating an association like Apple for
example or Amazon there was no
association with the company week they
created that so now when you hear the
word Apple you think of you know these
technology and an iPhone and and with
Amazon you think of an online on the
online store so there they were able to
create that Association out of nowhere
through marketing and branding or you
can take something you can try and use
the name I love the stuff by Jonah
Berger have you ever read contagious no
I haven't oh it's this awesome book you
can I'll put a link on the podcast page
for people he has a lot of YouTube talks
the guy's amazing
and one things he talks about was he
actually came up with the name Swiffer
which was you know they had this mop
thing for cleaning dust off of floors
and so they were like what kind of words
sound like when you hear the word
Swiffer when you
you think well it sounds like Swift so
it sounds fast you hear that this fuss
sound in the middle which sort of makes
you think of like moving a mop along the
floor and they used a made-up word that
already had associations that you
weren't even really aware of in your
brain around this product and they did
the same thing with Febreze and I just
thought that was really interesting way
of approaching naming that was really
successful yeah and I love any kind of a
name where you can get onomatopoeia like
that where the the name sounds like the
the service or device that's always fun
to it gives a it gives a extra set of of
character to your company and people can
put it together I got two other things
to hit on to that that idea of of making
a name like Apple that that doesn't mean
anything in technology until you make it
say that that goes further the same with
my podcast right shaping fire I mean
that doesn't really mean anything to
most people and and and once people
become aware of of both the shaping fire
podcast and our popular YouTube channel
then people are like oh yeah you know I
know what shaping fire is but but we
have you know imbued that instilled
meaning into shaping fire what nobody
knows though is that when I was coming
up with it I did the I actually did the
brainstorming exercises that I had just
been just talking about and more right I
did you know my naming process took
about eight weeks and and I came up with
about ten names in the end that I liked
and it was finally shaping fire that I
stopped on and for me the shaping fire
the name has always been about you know
there's this this normalization
legalization taxation thing that's
taking off and and cannabis industry has
now become this this wildfire and it's
chaotic and it's and it's both creating
and destroying at the same time and so
through good quality education which I
aim to provide both on the podcast and
on the YouTube channel we are shaping
this fire we're in and you know we're
sculpting it into something that has
meaning and and so anyway so that's
where I came from
another thing you were talking about -
you said simplicity right and so you're
taking a word simplicity that is in the
dictionary and replacing it with
something that it's like a homonym like
simplicity te a and and I generally
suggest people avoid those because
they're easy for people to not be able
to find you when they search for you one
of my good friends did that recently and
he jokes about it all the time when he
does interviews Patrick from green
bicycles he puts together a great
compost tea and and and and soil
amendments but but green bicycles is gr
e a n and so you know this was a
decision he made early on in his process
and he's gone with it and he always
jokes about how it's a hassle now to
always have to explain people to people
that green is not the color green it's
as grea and even though all of his
marketing really uses the color green so
so I caution people to to really focus
on words that when people hear it they
will understand how to spell it that's a
great point that's a really great point
and what's funny is when I when I heard
shaping fire well one thing I love about
that is if you type shaping fire into
Google they're gonna find you yeah which
is really really nice it's it's very
very intentional and very easy to spell
everyone can spell the word shaping in
the word fire it's not challenging for
someone to spell that but I thought it
was because I was seeing on Instagram
everyone you know when someone puts up a
good bud or a flower picture they always
did people would use the fire emoji or
say it was fire so I thought you were
using that sort of slang term that had
become popular in cannabis culture as
the way of saying like shaping fire like
growing top-shelf cannabis which is
interesting because up until now I
didn't realize you had a totally
different meaning around your pot it
certainly wasn't lost on me when I chose
the name that it had these multiple
meanings in our scene that's for sure
right and a fire is a word that people
in our scene you know embrace readily
and it's a good thing it's a good to
scriptor so I mean I wouldn't have
called the show like you know shaping
larf you know what I mean
you know I would a having it come
together like that was important but
yeah what was not the initial intent
anyway all right so talk to me you were
you were on social media I think when I
interrupted you there yeah so so we did
naming and we did social media because
we want to make sure that your your your
company is set up to win from the
beginning and then the third one is
trademark and and I always recommend
people to trademark early as soon as
you've decided what your name is really
gonna be go ahead and immediately
trademark as much as you can now if you
if you are a farm and you are selling
cannabis the USPTO will not give you a
trademark for selling cannabis we're
still waiting on that to be legally
possible but perhaps you could you could
start your trademark by trademarking
your name and your ability to make
t-shirts with it right or your ability
to consult with it and so you start
building up this legal history of
relationship of you and that name and
and that you're using it publicly now if
you are in the cannabis industry but
you're in a non regulated product say
for example you know bongs and rolling
papers or or whatever you know something
something that's not regulated by the
state then you can go ahead and
trademark right away and and you should
do that right away because there's never
been so many people starting cannabis
related companies as there are right now
and the chance that you know if your
company is in Florida that somebody else
in Connecticut is going to come up with
the same idea it's very likely
especially since the lexicon of cannabis
words is actually surprisingly small and
so you know if you you know if you're a
technical kind of person you know
certainly you can file your trademark on
your own but I'm a big fan of having
legal help and you know you could you
can get into a trademark attorney you
know for as little as probably 800
bucks to be able to get your initial
trademark placed so it's on the books
and if you're taking this game seriously
spending 800 bucks on a trademark should
be probably be considered a reasonable
expense to protect your company's
identity so so yeah so that's that's a
that's a short area trademark but but do
it swiftly as soon as you have decided
on a name so then the the next category
is is what I call a thin slicing and and
for for for folks who are listening who
have grown up with the internet this
will be like a duh but for but there was
a time before the internet and and if
you were gonna open a company you
normally had a storefront and I think
that for most companies I mean unless
you're you're opening a retail shop
right when so that the whole point is
having a storefront I'm a big fan of
Internet only companies because you
don't have to pay the overhead for a
retail space you don't have to pay the
overhead for the labor you don't have to
deal with municipal bans on cannabis
companies and and you get to take
advantage of what's called thin slicing
because in your you know let's say that
you live in a small town somewhere and
you've got you've come up with this
really cool product there may only be a
couple hundred to a couple thousand
people in your immediate area of driving
distance who will drive to your store
and buy whatever it is that you're
selling but if you're selling it on the
Internet and now everyone is you know
pretty comfortable with e-commerce and
putting their credit cards online and
all that kind of stuff you get to thin
slice the entirety of the country
whereas locally there might only be a
few people who want your product if you
take the entire country there's plenty
of people to keep your company and float
and doing well and you know one of those
folks who I think has done a good job of
it is Alan Atkinson at crow Kashi right
Alan does not do a lot of marketing
right he's he doesn't do a lot of
marketing and and if anything his
biggest marketing is probably being The
Cove
founder of probiotic farmers alliance
and his leadership there tends to lead
people to his product crow Kashi but the
thing is is that there are enough people
across the country that hear his message
about Gro Kashi and then can buy it on
the line online way more people than
there are in Laytonsville even though
that's a hotbed of cannabis growing
right I'm not I'm certainly not
belittling that there's a ton of
cannabis being growing there but there's
only so many people in Laytonsville the
fact that he's able to thin slice this
national market and sell to all those
people he gets to access a nationwide
consumer pool without having to have
retail shops all across the country and
it works out really well to his Vantage
so so consider thin slicing and and and
and being an internet company and if you
and if you're thinking about owning a
retail opening a retail store you know
make sure make sure you are clear in
your head that your business model
demands that so then similarly and then
this is the this is the last of the five
categories is um start using tech
marketing as fast as you can for example
right away as soon as as soon as even
you have a placeholder on your website
before you've even launched make sure
you integrate integrate some kind of
like MailChimp newsletter to capture
emails because sometimes people come to
your your website once but they won't
ever come again and so if they come once
it's shown enough interest and if
they're willing to give you their email
address now you can reach them again
when you actually go through your
product launch and any future product
launches and you can start to develop a
relationship with them so so capturing
emails with MailChimp it's it's free
it's very easy to use and then you can
start building customer loyalty programs
based on your newsletter and and you
know creating original content for that
newsletter that causes people to share
it with their friends and this is all
very low-priced marketing that is very
valuable when you're
starting out before you're actually
creating revenue and then there are some
other really good high-quality tech
marketing tools out there like the
Facebook pixel right I mean one of the
greatest tools that we've got for
marketing in cannabis you know even
though Instagram and Facebook make it
difficult to mint to market cannabis
related products if you take your time
and you massage your messaging and you
don't have pictures of cannabis in your
ad you can actually make it work and
then you boost those and they're your
return on that kind of marketing is
really good if you take the time to
write it in a way that you can kind of
disco around their rules and so then you
can use what's called a Facebook pixel
and it tracks everybody who who clicks
on your ad and go to your website and so
you can remark it to them later so if
you're not familiar with the Facebook
pixel you should look into that and then
there's there's there's all sorts of you
know different technology where my
favorites is actually called hot jar
it's pretty cool it tracks the movement
of people on your website so let's say
that you've got an online store and and
you're not getting the the number of
sales that you want for the amount of
people who are coming to your site so
let's say that you have a high bounce
rate people come but they don't buy well
it would sure be great to know what
they're doing on their on your website
while they're there maybe they're
getting lost maybe they don't understand
how it works and so this this service
called hot jar actually records video
records everybody who comes to your site
and so you know whenever you want to you
can log in and and watch each user's
session and track where they're moving
around it gives you a heat map for the
website and you may find out that that
people are confusing you know your your
catalog with your shopping cart or or
maybe they're coming you're they're
coming to their website and and you're
expecting them to go to the the store
part but maybe they're going and getting
distracted by your blog and your videos
and they're spending all their time
there and they're forgetting to go back
to the store
so so hot jars another great technology
too and you know often it's worth it to
bring on an expert at this point because
you know if you're in cannabis chances
are you're focused on the operations and
horticulture of growing your cannabis
and if you are manufacturing or curating
products for sale that's probably where
your expertise is and you're working on
that and you know for example myself
even you know I know that my tech
marketing has to happen but really what
I enjoy most is is is reaching out to
industry experts and then chatting with
them and then going into conventions
that's what I like to do and so you know
you might want to add somebody who's a
specialist like like I hired blunt
branding and so you know I work with
Kirsten Nelson at blunt branding to
sculpt my message and I'm like okay this
is what I want to say and this is how I
want to say it and then she'll take it
and and plug it into all this kind of
the technology and a Facebook pixel
she'll deploy it and and then and then I
can just go back to doing the things
that I like to do now granted bringing
somebody on like that
you either want to you know you want to
make sure you negotiate something that
you can afford dollar-wise but the
amount of time that it frees you up is
really helpful especially if you don't
know how all this technology crap works
the first place you know if this is not
your if your this is not your
bread-and-butter you're gonna spend so
much time learning the technology that
you might as well you know get somebody
at the beginning so so those are the
five categories that I always start with
my with my clients to to you know
brainstorm and get a name make sure it's
available throughout social media and
domain trade market as soon as you can
lean towards a thin slicing internet
company with less overhead and start
using technology marketing apps as soon
as possible so that you can track and
you know get into relationship with the
people who come to you that's great I
agree with everything you just said and
I know that you had some company
examples to sort of highlight some of
these principles do you want to touch on
some of
right now I know you already mentioned
green bicycles for the naming was there
was there some other things he had in
mind in that regard well sure I mean as
far as as far as that goes I mean there
are some folks that do it really well
like our mutual friend Jeremy Silva
right over at build of soil he does a
great job about this right I mean he's
got he's got a unique name that's really
easy to say really easy to spell and he
does he does
you know he's creating new content on
Instagram all the time like I you know I
can't be the only one who loves watching
him grow he does like a be testing with
different with different growing
supplies in an in - 4x4 tents that are
in his shop and you know he's creating
original content and and people know him
as a human but then they also know his
company as curating good products and so
you know he's one person that does it
really well um can we another we talk
about Jeremy for a second cuz there's
some things I want to highlight that
that I thought he did a great job on -
is I met Jeremy you know digitally in
the IC mag forum for organic soil I
don't even know how long ago and at this
point I I'd found it or started kiss
organics build a soil was wasn't even
around yet and so we were selling these
amendments online but I was not doing
any marketing and then one day a banner
ad for build the soil showed up on the
IC Meg forum for organic soil and he was
sponsoring that for him and that was you
know people started talking about it he
probably didn't pay that much for the
banner in the first place but he was he
was really a marketing guy and what he
did was he built this idea around
amendments by taking the information he
was learning on IC meg and putting it on
his website in the blog and sharing the
things that people like Clackamas coot
were saying and and sharing these
recipes and just simplifying the
information so what he did was say hey
I'm gonna give you all this information
for free and a lot of these these
products that this information talks
about are going to be available on our
website
and the other thing that I think Jeremy
did a great job of was he focused on one
social media platform and that has been
very consistent with it they have 20 or
30 thousand followers now on Instagram
and what he's done there is he's been
very consistent about his posting and
it's something that I am terrible at but
rather than him diluting is his time by
posting on Facebook and Instagram or
these other markets he's picked the one
that he thought was most relevant to
growers which was Instagram and then has
really stuck with it like you said
sharing all that information but he's
also created this sort of lifestyle
brand around him and his company where
it's not all of this post or not about
just about cannabis or about product and
there is a lot of stuff that he puts up
about his products and deals and that
sort of thing but he also you know talks
about his girlfriend's hip surgery and
the martial arts that he's doing and the
his his pet pig and other things in his
life that make you feel a little more
connected to the person and the business
that you're you know you're contributing
- yeah for sure I mean the whole build
of soil brand just screams authenticity
right I mean he's the kind of guy when
you run into him at Emerald cup or or
locally there in Colorado you're you're
happy to run into him not because he's a
successful business owner necessarily
but just because he's a nice guy and you
know I gotta say that probably applies
equally to you tad because you know you
run a similar type business and and you
also provide a lot of value through your
podcast which then drives traffic to the
keep it simple website where you are
able to provide these these amendments
as well and I would say also you are
also a likable guy right and so I would
I would say that the idea of of you know
not being plasticky corporate and
instead kind of like letting that veil
between your business and your personal
life be a little bit transparent I think
that it creates customer loyalty because
you know there's a reason why we all
push back against like you know better
months with no personality
miracle-gro right it's it's because it's
it's a bunch of c-suite executives
behind it and not some person who you
know we'd want to sit down and talk with
and and I think that's a good thing and
sounds like we both agree that that
Jeremy's done a really good job of that
yeah I want to highlight too
something that was really tough for me
when I first got into business or having
a product in a market was I spent a lot
of time noticing other competitors
things they were doing right things they
were doing wrong information that they
were sharing that was just blatantly
inaccurate and I would get really angry
and I'd get caught up but focusing more
on them in their product then what I was
doing with my own business and it was
totally the wrong approach
since then I've really learned that a
lot of times you can collaborate with
people and realistically it's important
to be aware of what other people are
doing in your industry but it doesn't it
doesn't and shouldn't be the focus of
your time and your energy like Jeremy is
probably my biggest online competitor
when it comes to selling products and
I'm talking about him on my podcast
but at the same time I'm also you know
I've established a good working
relationship with Jeremy even though
we've never met in person but we've
talked on the phone a lot you know we
get along great and I wish him the best
and I'm hoping I can collaborate with
him in the future because we can only
become stronger through these
partnerships it doesn't have to be this
antagonistic relationship and you know
like you mentioned green bicycles well
we started as a compost tea business
compost tea is still a big part of our
business but yet I realize there's other
people out there that may be doing as
good or better job as well in in the
industry so it's I think it's one of
those things we just need to recognize
is that we don't have to focus on what
other people are doing but really focus
on what we're doing and find ways to
collaborate with people yeah I think you
make two really solid points there the
first one about watching what everybody
else is doing there are so many people
doing so many businesses and they do it
in competitive combative ways that I
would find that I find frustrating
antagonizing that I find when when I
focus on what everybody else is doing in
the industry I get so upset and stressed
out that I have a hard time taking care
of my own business and and similarly I
want to do my podcast and my youtube
channel in my way and so people are
often talking to me like hey did you you
know listen to this particular podcast
or this particular podcast and people
are often surprised when I say you know
I only really listen to like three or
four podcasts you know and there there's
probably easily 30 that are popular in
in cannabis right now but I don't listen
to them all because mostly I'm focused
on keeping my head down taking care of
my own business and doing my things the
way that I want to instead of feeling
like I need to know what what what
everybody else is doing to replicate
because normally I don't want to
replicate with anybody else's doing
anyway I want to do things in my way and
so I think I think that's a really good
point that you have to don't worry what
everybody else is doing like if you want
to if you want to drop in and follow
somebody for a little while so that you
can learn you know some of their secrets
and then you can cross apply those
secrets to how you're doing business
like for example you know really smart
growers go and tour their competitors
grows if they can get into them right
because they can learn best practices
from other people and then bring them
home to themselves now that kind of
research and development is really smart
but to sit on social media and be
obsessing about what other people are
doing and at that that you'll you
that'll just all end in tears the second
point you make about collaborative you
know I tell my clients that this is
something that everybody needs to take
from hip hop right because one of the
most brilliant marketing things to come
out of hip hop is the idea of guesting
on somebody's album right you can use
guesting to either have a popular artist
help build the career of somebody who's
just coming up
or you can take two very popular artists
and have them guest on a song together
and now they're they're trading
audiences right so now they're they're
both enriched by that partnership and I
think that that is a fantastic example
that fits very well in with cannabis and
I think that you will be seeing more and
more of these Co branded products come
out as as the industry gets beyond the
prohibition competitive secretiveness
and becomes more open to working
together and you know where I need to
think that has to happen as soon as
possible is within with artisan cannabis
growers the heritage growers because
because if the heritage farmers you know
since the one acre cap was removed in
California it's turned into a bloodbath
and the corporation's have gotten the
money the organization and the
experience to just come in and roll out
these large marketing programs and
inundate the market with
brand messaging but but the heritage
farmers while they've got better flour
they don't necessarily have the
messaging reach and so as artists and
growers can come together and work
together and and get their messages out
as a group on why heritage farming and
why small farms are important and why
you know growing and living soils is is
you know preferable for a good tasting
artisan flower I mean more power to them
you know one one farm in California
that's doing a great job with that is
moon time medicinals and so you know
their website you know they they you
know it's pretty right so so that's
number one it's nice to be there number
two they know how to talk about the
importance of artisan you know farming
heritage farmers and and you know they
are there they're legit there on the
hill and Garberville I mean being in
Humboldt County that's that's pretty
legit and they've been doing it for
decades and
and then and the fact that you know they
know how to talk about all right so we
use KN f we use inputs from our own
property we grow in the sunshine and
this is why you should care about that
so you know not everybody is into that
because a lot of it yet because a lot of
the Heritage farmers have never really
need them are needed to market in that
way but they will get up to speed and
and if and if they don't it's gonna be a
lot harder Road yeah you brought up
another good point too which is sort of
what message are you looking to put out
there you have to be I think very
conscious of what what you want your
brand what values you want your brand to
promote and then make sure that you're
consistent across your social media
posts to promote that branding so you
know for example if you're gonna be a
high end craft cannabis company then
your photos need to look high-end you
can't put up you know crummy photos from
a bad you know bad phone camera you
actually have to take professional
photographer dose and I think too along
that line there's so many Instagram
accounts now which seems to be those
still the major platform for cannabis
there's so many Instagram accounts that
just have photos of buds or you know wax
or whatever rosin you know some just
photos of the actual product there it's
really boring like if I scroll through
my Instagram feed a lot of them are just
the same pictures over and over again so
how do you differentiate yourself from
all of that how do you you know take
unique looking photos or take a
different perspective on social media or
how do you create a message around that
and be more than just you know bud shots
but actually a lifestyle brand you know
how do you create that and I think
that's really important that people
think about that when they start
thinking about their social media it
actually requires a little bit of
thought
[Music]
hey guys I'm pausing this podcast here
as the end of the first part of my
interview with Shango I'll be sharing
the second half of this interview next
week stay tuned
again that was Shang golos host of the
shaping fire podcast I posted the
information in links we discussed in
this podcast right on the podcast page
at WWII s organics comm just click on
the podcast menu on the top of the home
screen and don't forget to sign up for
our newsletter on our website right on
the home page and subscribe on your
favorite listening platform so you can
stay up to date with all the latest
information and podcasts right when they
come out thanks for listening
[Music]