[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host tadd
hussey of kiss organics this is the
podcast where we discuss the cutting
edge of growing from a science-based
perspective and drawn top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge my guest this week
is ryan lee ryan is an educator breeder
and researcher specializing in the
chemical and genetic diversity of the
cannabis species ryan comes from a
background in neuroscience focusing on
the endocannabinoid system but later
focusing on plant breeding technologies
and the study of the molecular aspects
of the cannabis genome and how we can
use science to shape and improve the
plant now on to the show
hey ryan thanks for coming on the
podcast today
thanks for having me ted pleasure
absolutely can you uh tell listeners a
little bit about uh yourself and your
background
yeah i'm a cannabis breeder i've been
breeding cannabis for roughly 30 years
i've got an undergrad degree in
neuroscience and i studied plant
breeding in biotechnology at
a post-grad level
so i've really been kind of looking at
cannabis from a scientific level more or
less
quite seriously for the last 25 plus
years at least
um and growing for about 30 so i've got
a fair a fair amount experience in the
in the space
um
yeah i've got to see a seed company in
europe called chimera genetics
which some people may know
and i operate as a consultant and
genetic supplier to companies in north
america while really canada
and then globally
through our legal export system
so that's kind of where i come from
yeah i first heard you speak at emerald
cup uh a few years ago now um with seth
crawford and
jeremy plum and i know you and jeremy
are good friends and he said that you
were the one i need to talk to when it
came to this topic
and i'm going to admit right at the
beginning of the podcast
i don't know much about breeding it's
not something that i've really dived
into or having experience with so this
is just going to be an organic
conversation off the cuff
just kind of
talking about talking about breeding and
you know i kind of wanted to start with
sort of a historical aspect here in
terms of how cannabis has been bred and
get into sort of you know where you see
it going uh in the future
yeah that's a huge interesting topic
um so
different plants have different breeding
systems okay
and that dictates a lot about
what traits persist in the genome and
what traits get purged and taken out of
the genome cannabis is called an
obligate outcrosser which means
in nature
no plant will ever never ever really
self-fertilize i mean we can talk about
intersex plants to a degree and there is
a certain degree of inbreeding that
happens with those plants
but the standard kind of method for
breeding or for cannabis to breed in
nature is a male plant has to land on a
different female plant for progeny or
for a seed to be made
and
that natural state
is really designed to preserve
a wide genetic
diversity within the genome
because things don't get purged out you
never you know
it's just a factor of the mating system
that traits kind of stick around forever
and it leads to a huge variability in
the population you know of the species
as a whole let's let's kind of look at
it from that perspective
um
so when when humans
really got into
breeding drug cannabis i would say
seriously
you know mid 20th century
call it
60s and 70s
people started taking plants from
populations that they could get right so
you know say you're a grower in the late
60s
you know you're probably selecting seeds
out of like colombian or mexican flower
that's coming into the united states
being shipped all over
and
you know you would just kind of cross
those plants with the seeds you grow
them and the next year you'd collect you
know more more seeds over the bud that
you were buying and smoking of plants
that were a flat of weed that was kind
of exceptional or better quality and
you'd breed that in to the plant next
year and so
this one-to-one type of breeding system
is very different from the way the
cannabis produces in the wild right in
the wild you get these large stands of
plants
say
well i mean it depends on the stand as
the to the number of vigils individuals
but you say that there's like you know
somewhere between 10 and 100 or a
thousand individuals and they're kind of
having this like big orgy where all the
males are fertilizing all the females
and so it's just like kind of like a big
shuffling of
traits
ongoing generation after generation and
that's good because
you have genetic variability so that
when you when those seeds move from one
location to another
there's usually enough built-in
variability
that no matter the new location or the
environmental conditions in the new
location there's going to be some plants
in that population that will survive
so we kind of changed the
the script on that in the like the 60s
and 70s when we started breeding plants
one to one
um you know taking one male some some
grower would think oh i like the the
structure and the habit of this male
plant and it smells good when i rub stem
and so let's cross a little bit of that
pollen to each one of our females and
then you know the next year they'd kind
of make selections from you know which
breeding events or reading experiments
turned out well right
um
and that's one way to do it but that's
not really the way that if you were a
scientist you would
um
start you know
measuring you know if you're a scientist
you're breeding wheat or corn
every little trait is considered from
from pest resistance to mold resistance
to
you know rate of growth yield flavor of
the plants you know all that kind of
stuff
and
it's been a little more loosey-goosey
the way that cannabis growers have done
it so
that practice really
took hold for i would say you know from
like let's again call it late 60s to
late 90s and in the late 90s some people
started
breeding plants with a little bit more
accuracy and scientific intention either
measuring cannabinoids or terpenoids
um
and really going after specifically
changing the chemical profile of the
plant and you can't really do that i
mean you can do it with smell by your
nose a little bit but the real way to do
that is to use like an analytical
laboratory
so that you're actually analyzing the
chemistry or the chemicals that are in
the plant
and then making breeding decisions on on
individual plants based on that lab
analysis
um so that's kind of like really i you
know in a short summation where we've
come from in the past kind of 50 years
now i think that can ask you a quick
question here so absolutely so
philosophically um
speaking from an evolutionary
perspective
you know from the cannabis plants
perspective having greater genetic
versity you know pollinating a whole
bunch of plants with a whole bunch of
different genes
allows it a better chance to survive in
a variety of environments you know
someone's going to live on that's one of
the reasons as humans we have these
stigmas against um you know breeding
with our our close relatives
in every culture um
so you know i think of michael pollan's
book you know this idea that cannabis
and some of these other crops have sort
of
enslaved humans to
look for these traits in their own
survival and then
so now
i look at cannabis as having as a plant
sort of used humans as a way because of
the effect that it gives to breed for
you know more specific traits so now it
may be more evolutionary advantageous to
produce higher
thc because of the effects it has or
higher cannabinoid content
is that
i mean i know i'm kind of rambling here
but does that make make sense or is that
sort of something from a philosophical
perspective or evolutionary perspective
uh for the play
it totally makes sense i mean i tried
not to answer promorthai's plans too
much that's fair that's fine
really you know all organisms on the
planet are just different forms of dna
and different expressions of dna
trying to replicate itself right
and so it's an organism could be said to
be successful i mean this is one
perspective of course
an organism could be said to be
successful if it reproduces
right and so from that perspective
anything that a plant can do
to increase its chances to
reproduce to have more progeny and go on
you know in an evolutionary context
is a win right and i don't think the
plant really cares what it does it's
just
these traits come along or they evolve
and then we as humans come in and we
start reinforcing those traits because
you know like look the plant that we
found when humanity came in contact with
cannabis was nothing like the plant that
it came today it was a small little kind
of weedy plant that followed camps
around
because we would you know eat the seeds
and stuff like that
and it probably produced very little
cannabinoids and like
you know
a lot less terpenoids and volatile smell
molecules than it produces now
and over generations of generations and
generations of humans growing these
plants let's call it you know over the
last it's hard to put a time scale on it
but say 10 000 years at least
um
we've done we've changed the plant right
we've selected for things in the plants
or individuals that we would find in the
population of plants
that might suit our use so you know for
fiber we
we for example we took plants and use
them to make cordage right and ropes
and so plants that had long fibers
which is a result of like large
internode spaces you know that was a
useful trait so we changed we
essentially changed these plants over
time
um you made a really good point
when you when you mentioned humans and
how humans humans breed breed humans are
also obligate outcrossers like we can't
have
offspring without mating with
an individual of the opposite opposite
sex right and so
very much like cannabis our mating
system is the same kind of way it's
designed if you look at humanity across
the globe
there's this huge amount of genetic
variation not only in skin and eye color
and hair color but every conceivable
trait
there's variation present in the species
right
lengths of fingers even number of
fingers i mean we have these like
polydacty people that have like six
fingers right and so there's all these
little weird mutations that can exist in
this in in the species
but we don't as humans go in and
actively breed for those traits and
certainly like you said
we don't breed tightly within our family
right because we've learned probably
through
experimentation in the past
that like you know when you have
kids with someone that's closely related
to your family
you know there's problems that arise and
you can point to any of the royal
families
that have existed around the world over
the last you know few hundred years as
an example of like you know there's like
a spanish
royal that they essentially bred the
line within within a given family to the
point of sterility right
and this also happens with cannabis when
you
you start um taking these very unnatural
breeding programs and you self-implant
you know say over five generations right
you really narrow down the gene pool and
you start uncovering a lot of the
negative deleterious traits that are
buried within the within any any given
individual's genome
so um these are you know these are the
consequences of things that we have to
think about on a very top level when
we're going about about our breeding
programs and i think that
a lot of people
that come into the cannabis breeding
world
they come from
being growers and then they want to
start to make their own plants and the
truth is is that
as much as there is an art involved in
selecting plants and mating them
together there also is a science and a
math behind the art
right and so to be truly the most
effective that you can be
you combine that art and passion and
love for the plants and knowledge about
you know that you
acquire about plants growing you know a
species over say 10-15 years or more
when you add in that level of science
and math and plant-breeding
understanding you can really make some
quite significant gains right
compared to what we're doing today
uh on the whole i would say
i don't know that's a good answer to the
question yeah yeah i'm just trying to
decide if i want to talk a little bit
then about what your selection process
is because
i i realize you have to pick for you
know maybe a single trait or a small
group of traits at any given time
whether that's powdery mildew resistance
or it's uh you know more vigorous root
growth or
a particular terpene expression or
cannabinoid content or thc um
what's sort of the thought process
behind that
well
you know it's it's really no different
than i think the way that anybody looks
at it
um
the the only difference is you know
there's look there's every time you
breed a plant there's a cost right
there's a cost in terms of you're
selecting one plant over another
but there's also like materials cost to
grow the plants and then if you're doing
either genomic or
chemical analysis
those are like extra costs that start to
add up like really really quick
you know
you say you know i know in california
last few years you can get a cannabinoid
and a rudimentary terpene test done for
like roughly 100 bucks
right but if you grow if you're growing
100 individuals from a seed line and
trying to really understand what's
happening in the population and select
for rare plants
that's a ten thousand dollar bill like a
hundred times a hundred bucks right
hundred individuals 100 bucks per test
that's a ten thousand dollar analytical
chemistry bill just from the lab for
that one crop
and we haven't even talked about genomic
selection or anything so
it's really about balancing
the money that you have to spend on
doing r d
with the results
i think that we're entering this world
now
where
you know obviously there's these public
publicly traded companies and and and
companies that have been invested in by
even private individuals
that have pretty significant budgets
that understand hey
if you're gonna do you know when you do
research research and development
yeah it there is a cost
but at the end of the research and
development
you you should end up with something
better
like a product that's better in the end
from which you can then make up those
costs right those added costs that you
took on
um and so this is kind of like the the
debate between
you know the small farmer home grower
versus
more of a corporate style of breeding
which is funded and i've you know i've
had the
pleasure but i've had the ability to do
both
um
and i gotta tell you after building a
really high throughput lab with really
sensitive um analytical equipment
once you've done it that way you really
would have a hard time going back to
doing it the other way without all that
chemical analysis because the gains that
you can make when you're analyzing
plants
and and looking at them not only from
like the passionate perspective that we
all have as growers of you know 20 plus
years you also get all this nerd data
that tells you about like
you know the quant the cannabinoid
content or profile or the terpene
content and profile
that influences smell and taste you know
it's really hard to go back to less data
yeah you have a huge advantage um i mean
what i'm hearing is
to a certain extent that you know these
small
breeders small farmers are just at a
huge
disadvantage i mean
is it almost becoming a lottery ticket
to a certain extent in that case yeah
well i would i would say the smaller
farmers that are doing it without
um
without that kind of funding without
that kind of chemical analysis it is a
lottery right you really are counting on
luck in your ability
as a grower and a or a selector to go
through a population and find plants
you're going to miss like i'll just you
know from my perspective if you do it
that way you're going to miss things in
the in the mix because for example it's
really hard to
you know buy organoleptics like for
example tasting every plant and smoking
every plant it's really hard to identify
not only the differences in like that
top tier cannabinoid production plant
but also like it's like near impossible
to find a plant that has cbd
or thcv or cbdv for example some of
these more rare cannabinoids like
you because those things are not they
don't have a psychoactive impact on the
on the
yeah sorry i don't know
the psychoactive can be a problem
problematic word
if those compounds don't produce a high
right so it's really hard to
quantify them or even qualify plants say
you know you can't pick out a plant that
has thcv or cbdv
by smoking it
right so i would say in that [ __ ] in
that sense they are at a disadvantage
you know the the people that put the
money into
analytics be again either be it chemical
analysis or genomic analysis they
definitely have an advantage you know
they've got a leg up
so following that
line of thought like where do you see
the industry headed as
we get federal legalization here in the
united states as more states come online
and more of these big egg companies get
into it i mean are we going to end up
is it going to be like when you order
corn or
tomatoes are we going to lose genetic
diversity
well i i mean i would argue that we're
already losing genetic diversity because
and we have been for the last 20 years
right and even like say the last 15
years since the
you know the occurrence of like og and
these these cushy plants i guess we're
closer to 20 years at this point in time
um
that flavor profile like you know if you
if you do a chemical analytical survey
of the plants on the market the vast
majority of plants are beta-carotelline
near seen limonene dominant right and
that's that's the cushy market profile
that cushy market profile that everybody
wants that gassy nose
is a very small subset of the plants
that cannabis can produce right so we
already are going towards
um a smaller genetic diversity
by
consumer choices right
um
i don't
i don't know that big ag is gonna be
i mean
look it's if for these big pot companies
that we see that are building right now
these msos the multi-state operators
like cure leaf and tree leaf
once a company becomes like a public
company it's really their only goal is
to make more money
right they want the stock to go up for
their investors
and so
those type of companies are not really
too too keen to put like millions of
dollars into a breeding program
because it's a cost it's a cost center
right it's something that's always going
to just be costing you money all the
time
okay um
i would just say could one argue too
that
consumer uh
the consumer-driven markets in the sense
that people always are chasing the next
type strain or cultivar will keep things
you know somewhat fresh and and keep
maybe smaller breeders in in the running
for
you know
genetics down the road or
i think yeah i think that there's always
going to well i think that the breeding
will be done by smaller companies or
smaller groups um i don't think it's
going to be you know these small smart
small farms are really going to be
leading the way because like i said it's
quite hard to compete
against plants that are bred you know
for example i mean one of the companies
i worked for down in california we had a
client that we did some breeding for and
they actually ended up winning the
emerald crop with a cut with a with a
cult a cultivar called lemon crush
and that year
the lemon crush like you know we we used
a lab to obviously to guide our
selection process
and our breeding process
and
that left the lemon crush plant beat the
competitors by like a really significant
amount like all the people that you know
all the judges of the emerald crop were
really quite
unanimously blown away by this one plant
um
you know i think i think it had like
you know it was like 30 to 40 or maybe
it was 20 to 30 percent more votes than
any other plant in the competition which
is like that that's really quite
significant right it wasn't a close
margin
um
so i think that we'll probably see less
people
breeding in the future i mean there'll
be more people playing around
the the the flip side to the coin is
that you know
this market-driven approach that always
depends something new is a little bit
fickle it's a little bit fickle it's
really fickle to the point where it's
kind of ridiculous like
you know the market wants something new
every six months you can't breed plants
that fast to be finding new plants that
quickly right that are truly
better plants
um
so i think that like the the market
height
side that we have has kind of
accelerated to the point where it's like
it's ridiculous at this point in time
um and people need to you know
i just don't think fashions need to
change that much and really when you
look at these plants chemically
the names change but chemically
the plants aren't changing that much
right like the plant that was popular
six months ago or eight months ago is
really no different chemically than the
plant that is popular today it just has
a new fancy name
yeah that's a that's a great point and
when i think of other crops like
tomatoes you know i'll see a couple new
varieties maybe come out in a given year
but everyone's going back you know and
i know i have my favorites that i order
every year i like to run a sakura red
cherry tomato for example and
i love the fact that i know exactly what
i'm going to get
as a gardener and i can order those
seeds and they're consistent and that's
uh
that's really nice um
do you see something more like a
traditional crop
experience for gardeners down the road
like uh the way we currently get a lot
of our vegetable seeds
yeah well again like okay so tomato is a
really
interesting example because
tomato is kind of the opposite breeding
system of cannabis it's not an obligated
crosser it's it's called a salting
species so
selfers
once they've been bred and purged out
like the negative genes which tomato has
done over really the last
few thousand years
[Music]
they're like when you grow if you buy an
heirloom tomato seed and you save the
seeds and you you know you rot off the
that like the whatever the material is
that surrounds the seeds you kind of
have to decompose it
and then the seed is able to germinate
if you plant those seeds the next year
and you harvest the tomato from the
second generation they look almost
identical and taste almost identical to
the tomatoes that you got from the year
before and also they all look identical
to their cohorts in the in the
population right like all the brothers
and sisters
come up looking the same yeah um
and if you again breed it again another
generation or on for like you know say
20 generations
those seeds look they're the fruit look
and taste the same in the 20th
generation as they did in the first
generation that doesn't happen with
cannabis right
um because again it's not like an
outcrosser just like you have you have
brothers and sisters or the audience
members that have brothers and sisters
they know aside from twins
that your brothers and sisters might
share traits that you have but they
don't look identical to you right
they're not the same
um
and so i don't think that like
i think really once we have full
legalization
in multiple markets across the world i
really don't think that there will be
much of a seed market
um
i think the majority of people that are
growing from growing will grow from
clone or tissue culture
and you know we get to that point call
it 10-15 years down the road
then you will actually have breeding
companies that put in the time and the
work
to make
um
crops that are plantable from seed and
uniform chemically that you know like in
the the corn analogy that we're giving
before
where you know you talk if you have like
you know you want to plant an acre or 10
acres of corn you can go out and buy
corn seed and they all come up and they
grow the same height and they have the
same number of ears per
plant and they're all like what i call
bulletproof they're all resistant to
pests and diseases and drought and they
all have high yields and they all look
the same
right eventually we will get there with
cannabis but i really don't think that
that type of breeding is going to be
done by people on a small scale that's
going to be done by
companies that put work into you know it
they put resources into
genetic analysis and chemical analysis
right and they they truly create uniform
plants using
like
more let's just say more advanced
breeding technologies
right
are we at risk of roundup ready seeds
hemp seeds or cannabis seeds down the
road i don't i don't think so as long as
we have
the straight the stringent chemical
controls that we have on the plants
right i mean
i think you're in washington so you guys
have like a pretty regulated system i'm
in canada we have a federally regulated
system and it's very clear that you
can't have
more than a specific number of parts per
billion of any given chemical chemical
pesticide right and so really you don't
want to be using chemicals on your
plants because it there ends up being a
trace
or like even a disqualification of your
crop if the cow
chemical burden is too high right so i
really don't see roundup ready being a
thing
um
in cannabis right i just it's like you'd
end up with all this roundup in the
final extract or flowers and that's just
that's not allowed by the regulations so
you know i think that the regulations
kind of protect us from a lot of those
bad they're not not that they're bad
practices but they're necessary
practices to do
you know to do again like 10 000 acres
of corn right when you're in iowa or
somewhere in the midwest and every your
neighbors are all growing either soy or
corn or whatever it is
everybody's growing the same crop right
and so pests can come in and just
destroy things
and that's why you end up using these
you know agrochemicals to essentially
protect the crop from either weeds or
pests
so um
i know your talk
or your panel uh this was like probably
four years ago now maybe five years ago
at emerald cup was about uh crispr
and and talking about
gene editing
and there was a lot of concern from
in gmos and there was a lot of concern
from the organic folks in the audience
of uh gmo cannabis
what
if anything has changed in the last few
years on that or what are your thoughts
on that
i mean
i come from like the opposite end of the
spectrum i mean don't get me wrong i'm
like you know i'm pretty hippie-minded
and the environment is a big deal for me
um
that said i also studied like like i
said i studied plant breeding and
biotechnology at a post-grad level in
university
so i like i have a pretty good grasp of
like you know genetic mutation and
how genomes change over time um and even
you know you know like for example like
there's there's viruses and bacteria
that change plants that they create
genetically modified plants and a lot of
the species that we
we work with and we use as egg crops
have undergone these genetic
transformations naturally in the wild
right and so
i i'm like i'm not a religious person i
don't believe in like
i don't really believe in the concept of
there's a god making all these decisions
for us so when people start talking
about like
it's not the way nature intended like
nature does all these things and we
harvested these tools for genetic
modification
um and we're at the point now where we
can you know
we can very specifically change
genetic bases and plants to make those
plants have traits that we that the
plant might not have right
um
so my anyway my point is i'm a little
bit biased and i think that a lot of
people would probably disagree with me
but i think that when you get to the
point where you really understand that
the cannabis genomes or genomes in
general are always in flux
they're always changing and so
humans using
crispr or similar technologies to go in
and very specifically and precisely edit
base pairs to induce changes is not that
it's not only not dangerous it's
gonna be the only thing that's gonna
allow humanity to survive the next few
hundred years
with this insane
global climate change situation that
we've created
we're gonna have mass famines we're
gonna have
areas geographical areas that were crop
production areas that are going to
become destroyed by the changing
environment and we're going to have to
adapt
plants to regions that they weren't able
to grow in like really damn quickly if
we're going to have any shot at all
and so you can't do that through
conventional breeding like you have to
really use all the technologies
that we have learned about to get to
that point right so
um
that'll probably upset some of your
listeners but that's kind of my
perspective on it
it's all good so you do see this as
being the future with um
with cannabis i guess
it yeah and it's you listen for me it's
it's not an inevitably feature
it's just a technology and like for me
technologies are tools
right it's like you know i gave this
analogy
on the show a couple of weeks ago
it's like having a golf it's like having
a golf game right if you're out on the
golf you don't just take your driver out
every time you need to hit the ball and
smack it
right
you you learn to have
a toolbox of shots that you can pull out
at the time when you need it right so
not everything is a crisper
solution right sometimes you need to
make a crisper modification to a plant
to induce a trait
[Music]
um but then from that point on you just
classically breed you use classical
mendelian breeding techniques to shuffle
that trait around right
and look there's genetic modifications
that you can do to plants
that don't ever end up passed on into
the offspring right it's just something
that you would use for a seed production
technology so
there's a lot of ways to use these words
like crispr these technologies like
crispr and i think that like a lot of
the anti
um
this anti-gmo
kind of ethos comes from people that
don't really understand the science
and i think once you start to understand
the science and the way that cannabis
genomes are in flux already
that like these things don't become too
much of a big deal right
well you know i know this is totally off
the cuff too and this wasn't a topic we
planned on talking about but um
for me as someone who
falls on this the organic side of things
and you're right i don't
i don't totally understand the science
behind it i'll be the first to admit
that
my concern is more the corruption of
these these major
agrochemical companies i don't trust
them
i don't feel that they have our best
interest in mine and i think that their
bottom line is going to supersede our
health and i feel like our government to
a certain extent is willing to push
these things through through lobbyists
and so my concern is that
even if the technology is okay
there may be
uses of it that could be
dangerous for human health
down the road i mean when we talk about
roundup for example and roundup ready
crops
there's there is more and more research
that maybe this wasn't as safe as we
thought it was and you know it's been
used to bankrupt a lot of indian farmers
in terms of their inability to afford
the seed and litigation around um
you know drift of of pollen and things
into other organic crops i mean it's
become a little bit of a contentious
issue
so i think that's sort of my perspective
on it because you're right i absolutely
don't understand all the science behind
it listen that that's totally a fair
perspective and i i can't i disagree
with you there at all
but you know it's like to me it's like
nuclear technology we can build safe
clean thorium reactors that can safely
produce nuclear energy or we can take
plutonium and make bombs out of it or
hydrogen bombs right
those are like
let's not confuse the tool or the
technology with the use of the tool
right by unscrupulous people with
you know with unscrupulous unscrupulous
agendas right like there's always going
to be people that take the technology
and they try to develop it for their own
financial interest
but that doesn't mean that you should
throw the technology out because
you can also use technology to to
benefit humanity and i think that
you know the the points that you're
making are very fair given
the track records of the companies that
have developed
um these technologies i.e you know
monsanto and the roundup ready thing
you're right
we made these plants resistant to a
chemical and i think a lot of people
don't realize that monsanto was a
chemical company right they made
chemicals that was what they did before
they got into plant breeding and then
they developed then they found this gene
and the whole company business switched
because they found this gene they could
put into plants they had a patent on
that genetic construct
and
that really gave them
the ability to switch into this kind of
life sciences company right or ag big ag
company
and the the only the only goal
was to make these resistant plants so
they could sell more chemicals
right sure sure
yeah so anyway i guess i i think people
should understand again it is a fine
discussion i think that we have to
separate the technologies
from
the the technology and the potential
good uses from
bad actors using those technologies for
their own profit
right because we can't you don't just
throw away the baby with the bathwater
because there's people doing bad stuff
right
these technologies really can
change the way that agriculture is done
they can we can make better more
resistance healthier more nutritious
plants right
um and we should be if we have
technologies do those things i think
that we should be doing those things to
make our ecological footprint on the
planet
lower
right sure well i mean you bring up a
good point like we may need some of
these technologies just to survive as a
species down the road um
i you know i don't know but i could i
could very well see that being the case
and
um you know whether i like it or not
it's going to happen and i think that's
the that's the aspect of it that uh
i think i think i'd be cognizant of is
it doesn't really matter what my opinion
is on it at the end of the day there's
gonna be people out there that are going
to do it whether it's uh
you know whether i like it or not so
what and can it be done in the safe way
that protects consumers right and i
think that the science has shown at this
point in time that it really can
um and that's that's why we have
you know i'm not sure what the process
is in the states but i'm pretty sure
that the epa must have some say about
the release of genetically modified
crops i know that in canada
you can't just take a genetically
modified organism and release it to the
environment without like millions of
dollars worth of studies
right so there is like a big regulatory
pushback
on a lot of these technologies where you
have really do have to demonstrate that
the plants are safe
so
okay i want to i want to change
directions on this a little bit in the
sense that you know i see a lot of
breeding happening for
you know the retail market
is there much breeding being done i mean
i know there's some but where do you see
this going in terms of identifying
specific compounds or effects uh for a
more medical nature like around
anti-seizure or
you know anti-nausea or some of these
other benefits that people are seeing in
cannabis how do we get more consistency
there
well yes through breeding and product
development right like it's kind of
those two aspects go hand in hand one of
the things that with the company that i
worked for in the states
they were they owned a series of
dispensaries or one of their affiliate
companies owned a series of dispensaries
and so the r d was really designed to
see to create products
that that could end up in those
dispensaries or could end up benefiting
you know
benefiting patients
and so we did a whole series of breeding
programs using like thcv and cbdv and
cbg
to like up regulate those compounds and
create new cannabinoid profiles
that might have some
therapeutic advantage right and i think
epilepsy is like one one area where i
think we made some decent gains
um
some people might not know that this cbd
v compound
is very much like c cbd but it's got a
shorter little chain on the side of the
molecule
that compound is more effective for
epilepsy than cbd is
and
so we we had bred a line that had
elevated levels of cbd cbdv
and you know at the time we were doing
all this work where we were pairing
specific cannabinoid profiles
with various terpene profiles
kind of to like optimize the entourage
effect right
um
or the concept of an entourage effect so
i looked into the literature and started
look figuring out trying to figure out
what terpenes and terpenoids
had anti-spasmodic or anti-convulsant
properties
and realized that both
beta-caryophyllene and linolol
each have some of those properties and
so
i started hybridizing our cbdv line into
plants that were high in beta carotene
and little law and after a couple of
generations of shuffling we ended up
with plants that were essentially cbdv
dominance and had terpene profiles that
were dominant in beta-carotene and
little law and so the idea is that
you've now got a plant that not only has
a cannabinoid that is directed towards
you know epilepsy or reducing seizures
but all the compounds
the sorry the other major compounds that
are in the plant also have
anti-convulsive or you know
anti-spasmodic properties with the idea
being that
these flowers could then be given to
to people that have these conditions or
you would use those to make extracts
right that are that are more suited to
giving to like for example kids for
example right you don't want like
four-year-olds to have to be smoking big
fat joints
so it's better to give them an extract
that they can take orally right
yeah no that's really exciting
for anyone listening that may be dealing
with these sort of medical issues do you
have any
recommendations where people might be
able to get their hands on genetics or
reach out to companies that may
be able to point them in the right
direction
yeah unfortunately that's the
the corporate trade offside to this
whole thing right it's like these
companies that develop that kind of
intellectual property they don't just
give it away um
i mean can you buy the seeds even though
or can you no uh
buy the product you can't
i i'm not sure what the status of the
products are in their dispensaries these
days
um because again i've been i've been
going for that company for you know five
years at this point in time
but um
yes i don't really know what the status
of their availability is i know they
filed some patents and i think that
their their business model was more
about trying to find other businesses to
license the technology to and license
those plants too rather than getting out
with patients
um
which is a bummer but i mean it's it's
kind of the way that things are done
again if you're spending hundreds of
thousands of dollars or even millions of
dollars building these labs
and running breeding programs to fill
you know we're talking like
tens of thousands of samples going to
the lab
that's a pretty hefty bill right a lab
bill and they want they they obviously
want to recupe a return on their
investment so
handing out seeds to some growers in
humboldt that are going to multiply them
and hand them out for free
isn't really part of their business
model
yeah i was just curious if there if they
were
you know even selling clones or offering
uh the final
you know
end product in a form that people could
purchase if that was something that
i mean at the end of the year
yeah i mean look we're still stumbling
out of [ __ ] prohibition right
and i think that you know give it like
let's call it 20 years i mean that's
pretty far out but even 15 to 20 years
after legalization
people are going to have you know the
united states and canada as well will
have really good systems for protecting
the ownership of plants for for breeders
that actually develop new plants you'll
be able to register it
and
those things when they're propagated or
sold through nurseries the breeders will
get
you know little bits of royalty right
that come back to them
and as those systems develop i think
that we'll see
a much more robust legal clone sales
right so that growers don't have to buy
seeds and search through
to find winter winter plants like you'll
be able to go in
to any nursery and select from probably
i would say 100 to 300
different genetic types
right that have been selected for either
specific cannabinoid profile or specific
terpene profile or flavor
um
so are you talking tissue culture now at
this point
yeah i would say a lot of that stuff
they might not be the plants that you
buy might not be from tissue culture but
hopefully the moms went through tissue
culture right
um i think all of these systems that we
use in cannabis including including
nurseries like i think
growing plants mother plants not using
tissue culture those days are pretty
much done or they're you know we're
we're seeing the beginning of that that
the extinction
of that process
i think mother plants should be fed from
tissue culture they should be certified
past and virus and viroid free
um and then those clones get turned into
moms
like you know and mothers are probably
going to be replaced like mother plants
will be replaced either every three or
six months
right and you wouldn't run them that
much longer you're constantly
you should constantly reproducing your
your
mother stock with new tissue culture
plants for that same genetic type
right so that just helps me
let's talk about that a little bit so uh
for growers with mother plants from a
genetic perspective you know if you're
what's best practice here so we have
some people that will keep a mother
plant for let's say six months
you'll have others that will every crop
start a new mother plant
as they uh take more cuttings now i i am
aware that mutations can be more likely
to occur due to
plant stress of of any type um which
could affect your next crop but in
theory you know your your clone is
a clone of the
prior plant what are the what would be
best practice or what are the risks
associated with either model
good question so i think one of the
risks with tissue culture is again just
to say not all tissue culture lobs are
the same a lot of tissue culture labs
use hormones
to
ramp up multiplication rates or plant
growth rates
those same hormones that have all those
properties that are beneficial for
tissue culture like for example phi
diazeroline one of the one of the
negative traits with that one which is
very often used in cannabis tissue
culture is that it increases the
mutation rate
and so there is the opportunity that
that
that your plant is going to change
genetically as a result of going through
the process and good tissue culture
companies
they monitor the you know the genetic
stability of plants going through
culture to make sure that they're not
creating a whole bunch of off types
um
you know
this stuff also happens in outside of
the tissue culture lab too plants
undergo natural mutation rates all
eukaryotic organisms have a natural rate
of mutation
i like i like to use the pinot noir
pinot gris pinot blanc example
pinot gris pinot blah are just
they're they're
white and pink grapes that actually
derive they're actually cloned copies of
pinot noir which is a purple grape right
it's just that through natural mutation
of cells dividing
some clump of cells lost the ability to
produce that purple pigment and
therefore the grapes on that branch grew
white right and somebody was walking
through a vineyard at some point in time
probably harvesting the grapes and
realized that this one branch of a vine
had a had a um a white grape and so they
they took that branch off and cloned it
and
you know started making mother earth
started that plant to be more or less a
mother donor plant
and propagated a whole army of those
plants right
so anyway the point is is that like
mutations are a natural part of life
they happen anyway they're happening all
the time
um
yeah so i don't know like i think that
like
you know if you think about all the
other negative stuff that can happen
when you're just using mother plants
like obviously the huge pest burden and
viruses and virus like we've seen with
the hot plate and viroid
if you're not maintaining like really
good sterility practices and like making
sure that you don't
cut more than one plant with the same
razor blade or scissors or like you know
pruning shears or whatever that's how
those viruses and viroids are passed
around
right so
i think that there's obviously benefits
to d with tissue culture and monitoring
the health of your tissue culture plants
with molecular biology tools to make
sure that you are virus free
right there's a huge benefit to that so
i think that that model is probably
going to change like i think it's
already starting to change in the next
five years most people will be buying
plants that
came from
they're either tissue culture plants or
more likely
the tissue culture plants were feeding
um like the the tissue culture process
was feeding mother rooms which were then
being propagated for say three to six
months
to make clones and then that whole
process just starts over again and
so as a seed producer you don't see that
as a viable industry down the road you
think everyone's gonna be moving to
tissue culture
and clothing
we're gonna go through phases i think we
already already are moving to tissue
culture now
um
seed production
i mean look it depends on the crop right
if you're growing cbd distillate it
doesn't matter if the plants all look
the same or not
it would be better if they did
right but i don't think that you're
going to spend the money
to buy tissue culture plants to plant in
a field when like cheap hemp seeds that
all produce cbd anyway
are just being you know co-extracted to
make a cbd distillate right
yeah so for different parts the
different parts of the market like
different strategies will
prevail but i think that like
flower producers will probably
have mothers it'll go through phases
right like
the current next phase is going to be
tissue culture and then call it 10 15 20
years down the road once real breeders
have really had a chance to like
get into towards stabilizing lines
then we'll probably see crops being
planted from seed right again
but until we get the level of uniformity
that you can expect from a clone crop
i don't think that we'll end up seeing
flower crops grown
from
seed until we have that like level of
breeding right and the price of seeds
will have to come down too
um i would think as well
you'd be surprised man like for example
like you know
monsanto you know you're looking at like
depending on the the seed and then the
seed supply you're looking at like 15 to
of the revenue from the crop goes back
to the seed supplier
and the reason that they pla they pay
that amount is that like i said the
farmer knows that they've got a
bulletproof
crop and so if you're growing 100 acres
of corn
and 25 is going to go to the seed
supplier or 25 of costs are going to go
to the seed supplier you'll just plant
an extra 25 acres
right because when you're planting corn
it's really not that much work you've
got one of those
you know gps guided john deere tractors
that you just essentially plug the data
into an ipad and it go it goes and does
the work
right um but i think there will be like
a premium cost for premium seed
but
usually those things are scaled to make
sense in in you know they're they're
scaled to make sense to the operator
right
sometimes provided
government's still subsidizing corn and
all that other nonsense but
i don't want to get an industrial egg
but i i hear your point so you're saying
there's a value there for the farmer
that would still allow for
higher seed prices um essentially
exactly that's a better way to say it
so uh real quick what about uh what
about this idea of genetic drift or uh
you know genetic degradation of clones
over time
beyond you know stress or random
mutation are we really looking at there
being any
issues
and then i've also heard
people say oh you just need to take your
indoor plant and grow it outdoors and
then uh that sort of restores the vigor
of the plant can you kind of touch on
those
uh those topics
yeah for sure so genetic drift is like
the wrong word to use to describe that i
know that everybody in the cannabis use
industry or a lot of people in the
cannabis usually use that word genetic
drift really means like
a change in the genetic frequencies of a
population from one generation to the
next
and so
that's really the definition of genetic
drift i've heard what you're talking
about
use that word you're talking about or
the concept that you're talking about be
described by
clonal drift
which is really just
you know somatic mutations building up
was a research paper that came out in
the last couple of months
that showed well it purported to show
huge levels of genetic mutation they
actually they took a mother plant from a
canadian facility and it was this big
unhealthy mom that had been grown for
you know well over a year and they took
clones from the top of the plant and
they took clones from the bottom of the
plant and they took clones from the
middle of the plant
and they sequenced those clones all
individually and the rese their paper
showed that there was all these
accumulating mutations in in mother
plants
i think there was actually some flaws in
their data because like
it just it doesn't ring true to me
that there would be that degree of
mutation i've grown i've have plants in
my library that i've had for 20 plus
years you know approaching 30 years
and
they haven't changed right like they i
can tell you they look and taste and
smell
and grow the same way they did like when
i selected them from their seats right
um
so i i just
those two pieces of data just don't go
together with me if we're having this
uh huge rate of selection and there's
another genomics company out of boston
that was that's been doing a lot of work
in cannabis
and he said that he thinks there's some
flaws in the study so
the point is is i don't think we have a
conclusive answer to the question or the
question you're answering but it is
important to
to know that all all plant species and
even animal species like you know you've
got as your skin cells are dividing you
look down at your wrist or your hand you
know the skin around those wrists it
might get a mutated genetic mutation
in humans
a genetic mutation in your skin cells is
never going to get passed on there you
know especially if it's in your hand
that has no way of getting passed on to
your offspring
right but
plants
especially cannabis don't really operate
that way like a plant
if a branch has a genetic mutation that
say destroys a thc gene or a
pathogen resistance gene or even a
terpene flavor gene
that can be passed on if that branch is
then cut and used to make a mother plant
right
um
so
yeah i don't know that's true so so
essentially there are some level of just
natural mutations that occur
but
stress
plant stress can lead to
more mutations so it's very important to
keep healthy mothers and clone off of
healthy plants
short answer does that does that kind of
summarize
yeah more or less like when people say
like stress causes mutations i don't
think that we necessarily know that to
be true but for example
you know
well i mean what what do you define to
stress change in ph like high
temperatures
you know like definitely like pests or
vectors for viruses and stuff and
viruses cause genetic changes
or can cause changes right um
so i would say that like the
in theory the practice is true i don't
know that like what i don't think we
really know what stresses
induce mutations because we just haven't
really done those kinds of studies in
cannabis right sure i was just thinking
environmental stress whether that's past
cold
heat water
um
you know this idea of cloning off of a
unhealthy plant
um
you're more likely to have
mutations is that i mean and maybe i'm
wrong like i said this is not my area
wt's
mutations is probably not the best word
there i think that the concept that
you're talking about is called
epigenetics okay and epi epigenetics
just means like epi means above
so it's like a level of genetic
regulation that happens above or on top
of the genetic level
uh and it's something called dna
methylation that happens on the genome
and it and it really like
you can think of it like you know dna
comes in like these big bundle.coils and
we have these proteins that regulate
that
winding or the compression of the dna so
that it gets coiled up and is efficient
to package
right and then when genes need to be
transcribed
machinery will come along and and
unravel that piece of the genome so that
the dna can be read
and so dna when it's coiled can have
these little methylation sites added to
it which tell the machinery you know
transcribe this gene more or less
right and those things are actually
heritable or they can be heritable
um but it's not actually a genetic
change it's a
is it a change in like a more
deleterious expression of the genetic
of the genetics
sometimes but sometimes it might be
beneficial
okay right so yeah it's hard to make
those kind of those like hard and fast
rules
about genetics right like you know for
example
somebody was saying the other day like
all genetic mutations are negative well
[ __ ] if you're if you're trying to find
a plant that has
cbg in it you want a plant that has a
broken or mutated thc gene
so that that thc gene can't turn the cbg
precursor into thc
right and when you have that mutation
what happens is cbg backs up right and
so
sometimes we want to destroy a gene
right like for example there's a number
we were talking about powdery mildew
earlier on um they've just showed this
genetic sequence
that we have a susceptibility gene to
powdery mildew so if you have this gene
then the plant is more susceptible to
powdery mildew infection
it's like has to do with like a docking
protein of how powdery mildew like
actually attaches to the plant and so if
you can break that gene in the plant
you kind of destroy the docking
mechanism and it makes it
so in that in that
example destroying a gene makes the
plant more resistant to battery melted
right so this idea that like
yeah
there's
people got to kind of get rid of the
idea that like broken genes are bad
things because sometimes a broken gene
might have a phenotype that we actually
like
right that is beneficial for us as
humans right
are you referencing the paper from dewey
scientific
uh that came out a little while ago
because i actually had someone on the
podcast recently uh jordan zagger
talking about
a paper directly relating to that
powdery mildew gene no this is so that's
the other side of the equation so
there's they found two genes in powder
ability one group in canada found this s
gene which is the susceptibility gene
and then cess group working with dewey
out of washington
they found a resistance gene
and so it's like there's two those so
those are like two separate independent
genetic factors
one that causes resistance
the other one and so you want the
resistance scene but the other gene
causes susceptibility and you don't want
that gene right so you can stack the r
gene
with the broken s gene then you're
you're kind of off to the races right
yeah
so sometimes you're in a better position
yeah i wanted to come back to this idea
of taking uh
a long cloned plant and growing it
outdoors as some way of restoring
vigor to it
have you heard this
yeah we've seen it we've done it and
actually to a degree it works right like
i think what happens is a lot of times
people have these plants in these
libraries and they're either growing in
them like you said past they got pests
or
low light conditions or whatever and
there seems to be something about
putting these plants out in the intense
sun in the summer
allows that plant to like get back to
traditional health
um i don't think there's i don't again i
don't think there's been any studies in
cannabis but it might be that like you
know intense real sun is able to rip
some of that methylation off the dna
again that's just pure speculation but
um there is definitely something going
on with certain plants that like
whether it's the soil or being held in
these compact root systems where it's
the light or it's like all those things
over a year you know when you take that
plant back out and put it back outside
of nature where it evolved it seems to
bump back into optimum health right
that's really interesting so there is
something potentially to that
um you would hypothesize but we don't
have the research yet to really identify
exactly what that might be
yeah i've seen plants go from like weird
kind of [ __ ] up like you know not in
the viroid sense but like just not
performing very well and then you take
them outside and you put them in the sun
and they like kind of kick back into
into hell so i don't i don't know what
it is i don't think that's like a
solution to every problem
but it does seem to work on some plants
that are suffering a little bit for for
some reason right yeah
fascinating well
we've been talking for a while now
is there anything else you'd like to
share with listeners uh before we end
the call i know we kind of jumped around
quite a bit
no just keep growing seeds i mean i i
you know i think people should always go
and see it even if it's just like a few
you know in their gardens you can't find
anything new we can't ever move the
species forward unless we're making
seeds right
and growing seeds so don't ever stop
growing seeds
um it might have to be like a small
little patch that you do on the side
just to keep things normal but yeah
i'd like to see us getting back into
growing more seeds um
because and i think we are as we see
legalization coming you can see more
people like in california like
you know five ish years ago there was
really this like seed growing like
explosion right and people stopped
really leaning on clones as much clones
are fine you know great for uniformity
and you can do all these interesting
things when you have you know a ton of
biomass
to make like specific flavor profile
extracts but you're never going to find
that next profile without going back to
feed
so i i you know i always like when
people grow sleep
so even with all the disadvantages uh
for that small home grower that wants to
play around with breeding you'd still
encourage them to do it because at the
end of the day they might come up with
something really novel and exciting or
that works really well for them
yeah
well it's just you know it's like they
listen they might not fly and create the
perfect plant but it's like you've
probably seen this freak show plant
right the plant with the weird
serrations the leaves kind of look like
ferns yeah it's like that was stumbled
across by a small home grower
um and it might turn out that that trait
has
some kind of advantage right like you
that maybe maybe that plant is less
susceptible to powdery mildew again
because like
you know
the powdery mildew just can't grow
across the leaf like it would normally
or maybe it allows more air through the
leaves
right and so again it's like doesn't
mean that the people that are
discovering the new thing are going to
build the bulletproof plant but it's
like it takes
you know it takes a whole community of
people growing all this different stuff
and just randomly somebody is going to
find
something new right and then hopefully
that gets shared with the community and
these things kind of get
passed around and integrated and
optimized right
yeah see i speculated that um
we were at a level in the last five ten
years of the greatest diversity in this
plant genetic diversity because of all
the the legalization that's happened
and um how many more people are growing
it that we would have seen more
diversity but you think we've already
sort of limited or funneled down that
diversity towards a very specific
range
there's two forces right at play like
one of them like you said we got more
people growing more seeds but also the
market
there's a fashion in the market right
and that fashion is for gas
right and so
it's like you go into a dispensary and
i've seen it in california i've also
seen it in canada i've been to a
dispensary and there's like 20 different
cultivar names on the menu
but really when you go through and you
look at the plants from chemistry it's
like 18 of them all have the same
chemical profile right so it's like even
though there probably is genetic
diversity
across the population it doesn't really
make it to the marketplace
right yeah well is this where
uh
the the skill of the grower comes into
play in terms of bringing out certain
aspects of
those genetics through the way that they
grow the plant because
i mean obviously your genetic expression
is going to be tied to how the plants
cultivated
it is but there's also plants that just
don't like you know there's plants that
are like for example i have this really
equatorial plant so a hybrid that i had
made
and we ran through the lab and it came
back to have like
high levels of pinene and limonene and
almost nothing else which is a
relatively rare terpene profile it's
really like associated with what people
would call a classic haze plant
so we're talking like you know 13 14
week flowering time
to grow it indoors i think we had like
three plants on that and that produced
like a quarter pound total right and
we're talking like three three three
foot plants but it's like it really
didn't yield [ __ ] yeah but the flower
was exceptional
um and the rosin
that
came back at a very low rate was even
better than the flower
right but it's like you'd need to grow
acres an acre that's of that stuff to
have enough material to make an extract
so
it's like some plants just don't produce
enough
um
so the genetics are still the driver in
your opinion and you know we can
pull some levers
on the cultivation side at the end of
the day it all comes back to good
genetics
yeah the genetic i think the genetics
are really the key to diversified
products in the marketplace
right like you know if you're going to
build a rosin brand
it's fine and dandy to have gas but like
everybody's got gas right and so like if
you want to build like a unique brand
you might want something like with a
really ripe garlic smell or like a
really
floral
kind of little
like a real flowery kind of smell to it
right
because i think those are the things
that are really going to have
those are the things that are really
going to be able to get
traction in the market
right or or like we said before with the
epilepsy plant right like
you want like having a specific plant
that produces a specific chemical
profile that's therapeutic for
you know a whole segment of the
population like it's the genetic that
allows that product to exist right
so i think
you know again i'm biased as a plant
greener geneticist but like
i really do think that the genetic
diversity is a lot is what allows the
product differentiation on the market
it's you know
it's not like i don't think the growers
if everybody has the same plants i don't
think one grower is going to be better
than everybody else
right but if that one grower has a
unique genetic they might be able to
fulfill a market niche that nobody else
can
right
i mean yes and no coming from the
cultivation side i would say that
given
you know the same genetics to different
growers you could see
a different plant structure different
expression
different quality of flower
just based off of the ability of the
grower and not just the ability to
grower but the environment which i tied
to the grower the light spectrum that
the plants given the light intensity
um
you know we're able to manipulate plants
quite a bit
on that side but i don't think that
discounts like what you're saying in the
fact that at the end of the day it's
really the genetics that are are going
to drive
a lot of your
of how that plant is going to finish
yeah i feel like i'm i'm a grower too
don't don't let me sound like i'm
discounting the role of the grower in
the creation of a great product right
um it definitely there's a huge role
when you know this from wine and you
know it's from food right like
the grower has definitely an impact on
the outcome of the quality
but without that diversity in genetics
you know you can have an excellent
grower in a shitty genetic
and that grower is not going to be
successful commercially
right but if you had an excellent grower
or even a good genetic like they they
might be
successful and if you have that grower
a really interesting or unique genetic
then they're really going to be able to
set themselves apart in the marketplace
right yeah yeah no i like that i like
that that's a fair
fair analysis i'll give you that one um
well uh ryan thanks again for your time
today i had no idea where this
conversation was go but i i learned a
lot and really enjoyed it and uh
hopefully we can talk again soon
for sure thanks for having me dad i
appreciate it man it was nice to chat
with you finally we'll get some time to
actually hang next time at one of these
events that would be great man i'd
appreciate it all right have a great day
you too take care of you cheers
[Music]
that was ryan lee and you are listening
to the cannabis cultivation and science
podcast i'm your host tad hussey if you
like the podcast please leave us a
rating in review i do read them all
thanks for listening