[Music]
thank you
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad Hussey
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawing top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge my guest this week is Dr
Nicole goche she is a professor and
extension specialist at the University
of Kentucky her program focuses on
disease management of specialty crops
including hemp in her extension role she
develops educational and Outreach
programs to help Growers manage disease
through identification
understanding of patho systems and
integration and management strategies
her research program focuses on a range
of hemp diseases including fusarium head
blight Dr gotcha earned her Bachelor of
Science in Horticultural science and her
PhD in Plant Pathology from Louisiana
State University
she joined the UK College of agriculture
in 2011 and began working with
Industrial Hemp in 2014. there will be a
link on the podcast page to access her
resources and research now on to the
show
hi Nicole thanks for coming on the show
today
hello how are you
I I'm good I'm really excited to talk to
you today uh I've seen on LinkedIn that
uh Paul coxon who's been on the show
before had linked to some of your
research so I reached out to you
directly and you were so kind to take my
message
messages and um can we just start off
telling listeners a little about
yourself and then we can talk a little
bit about your research okay sure I am a
plant pathologist which means I study
disease and um actually I am I'm a
professor of Plant Pathology with a
specialization in extension so extension
specialist is what a lot of uh Farmers
call me and by extension meaning that we
or the interface between the university
and Growers so every state has extension
uh faculty and then most counties within
a state will have another component of
extension so I'm a specialist I
specialize in plant diseases and by crop
I work with specialty crops and hemp has
been on my commodity assignment since
2014 when the reintroduction came
through with the 2014 form bill
that's that's really exciting so you're
sort of the
uh the the Bridging the Gap between
Academia and the university and then the
actual farmers and growers in your the
fall into your area is that that is
correct so I can work directly with
Farmers as long as it is a plant disease
issue or I can work with County agents
as part of their larger programming so
they're kind of boots on the ground
um and then
um I I write a lot of spray guides and
fact sheets and do a lot of training so
we train Growers and we train County
agents so a lot of trainings and um of
course in the modern era our trainings
can be anything from YouTube videos we
have a YouTube channel so anything from
YouTube to
um
just some some
um featured videos that are a little bit
more
um more published than some of our raw
video out in the field
okay well let's just let's just go ahead
and Dive Right In now one of the things
that we talked about off air was just
getting a good foundation and
understanding of sort of what plant
disease is and what those what those are
in sort of the hemp cannabis world right
now
okay so uh we'll start by saying that
plant diseases
um those are the symptoms that's a
plant's reaction to whatever is
happening so it's an it's a um
it's a disorder so when we talk about
disease we use terms like Wilt and
rotten and blight and those are usually
descriptors
um now we have disease names so those
are kind of more colloquial right so
think of entomology or think of uh plant
names like we don't use the Latin
binomial every day we're using common
name so that's what diseases are disease
names are common names and so we'll call
flower blights or Leaf spots or circular
leaf spot or bipolaris leaf spot
um powdery mildew so those are kind of
some some
um some common names
um so uh diseases are caused by plant
pathogens and that's what we get into
um fungi bacteria viruses uh water molds
or oo my seeds so that's when we start
talking uh start talking with the Latin
binomials that um most people don't
really like to talk about of course any
pathologist would love to talk to talk
the nerdy uh Latin to you but um
so when I study and when when
um a lot of times we make references we
do make references to those Latin
binomials because that causal agent or
that plant pathogen the fungus the
bacterium the water mold it's really
critical that we know what that is and
that's where my research comes in and so
that's yes I have the education and
Outreach component from extension but
that's where our research really Dives
in
um so to answer your question is we're
trying to figure out what exactly are
those causal agents are they the same is
it the same circospora that causes a
leaf spot on soybeans or on tomatoes or
is it a different circospora for example
that causes the leaf spot on cannabis so
that is kind of part of the research
that I do is a kind of a fancy
diagnostic if you will and then
understanding the life cycles what are
the alternative hosts what is that Host
range how does it over winter
what are the optimal conditions for
infection to occur and
um thus the the does the disease matter
right does it just make a spot for
example on that leaf and it's in it
doesn't matter or is it something that
can be really devastating and and
detrimental to a crop and cause crop
losses or food safety issues so nutshell
that's what I do
yeah so it sounds like identification is
is critical in the entire process and I
know that's something that in reality
kind of gets skipped over or
um I guess push the side a little bit
I'm wondering
from a grower perspective how important
is it that I know the actual species or
can I just say oh this is powdered
mildew because of the way it presents
and that's enough for me to at least
begin a treatment option or for
something you know something else like
fusarium or one of these other more
common diseases do we need do we need to
dive that deep as a cultivator or can we
just sort of narrow it down
more modern techniques now we're
starting to understand a little bit
about just crops in general why may why
didn't management this management
technique work five years ago or why is
it working for my neighbor and it's not
working for me
um and um
it may be really the the the pathogen
itself
I'll use fusarium as an example
um you know people who are not
Pathologists they talk about fusarium f
as if it's one thing
um there are so many different fusarium
um complexes and species that uh we're
finding
um for example as a fusarium Wilt we
have identified four different
um pharmacealis of fusarium oxysprum so
we're finding a lot of different ones
and that starts to matter that matters
on how it overwinters what the other
hosts are and and we do a lot of
fungicide sensitivity tests and
I know I don't want to get anyone in an
uproar but
fungicides are used for a lot of crops
across the board so in Plant Pathology
that's one of the ways we characterize
pathogens is what is that sensitivity
we also do temperature sensitivities we
also do we do a lot of different
characterization studies but fungicide
sensitivity is kind of like an in your
face
it shows differences right
um
and think about species what's the
difference between a cat and a lion
right there's a huge difference in what
we know in our everyday life so there's
just as much difference across for
instance fungal pathogens and
um and the fusarium the fusarium
oxysperum group or the fusarium all the
other species the ones we're working on
that cause a bud and flower blight head
blight
um they're very different and it matters
it can matter more than others
um another another question you
mentioned powdery mildew we know that
there are two different powdery mildews
different Genera
um
of powdery mildews which one do you have
well one of them prefers about a it can
survive at about a 40 relative humidity
and the other one more in
um more than 70 relative humidity that's
huge uh 40 relative humidity really
plants are unhappy at that level versus
70 relative humidity a year kind of
plants are really happy there but so are
most of your fungal pathogens for
example and I I have I have a million
other examples of how species are are
generous sometimes it really makes a
difference in in the grand scheme of
things
okay that was a very compelling argument
so
basically right so should a grower
should grower care commercial Growers
should absolutely care
um a small grower or a backyard grower
or
um you know somebody with a grow in
their basement
um won't matter as much
um but a commercial grower should
absolutely know because that's really
that sometimes that difference between
um that real good profit margin or that
that really
um high level efficacy of a management
strategy versus just okay and we did it
we did well
so if I I so I hear what you're saying
you're basically saying that you know
even within fusarium we're gonna have
ones that have different temperature
ranges different
humidities
um
a different spread all these things are
factors so so it does matter I I guess
as a grower then
so if I were to walk into my
my room let's talk about an indoor
facility so controlled environment
agriculture
um
I I see something on a plant that looks
off to me
um how do I determine that that's a
disease and not a nutrient deficiency
what are some keys that I would look for
in terms of uh
physical display and then what should I
do at that point what are my next steps
from a pathology perspective
so um
or not a diagnostic feature you need to
know you need to see the sides you need
to find those fungal spores or whatever
and a grower is not going to have that
capability don't expect you to right
that's what we're here for but if you
walk into your your basement or your
huge facility or or a field like
whatever it is so you kind of walk in
you take a look across right so kind of
take that wide angle view imagine that
first look what's the pattern
um if it's a nutrient deficiency it may
be across the entire block or the entire
you know house or whatever that is
um planting dates when I talk about
block it could be planting date it could
be cultivar it could be a lot of things
so but if you look across that entire
block a nutrient deficiency can very
likely be all of the plants plant
diseases are rarely all they're usually
we usually have hot spots
um or if you're on a drip irrigation
system and you have an irrigation issue
or a fertility issue it there may be
some kind of pattern right
um or if it's a cold end of a greenhouse
maybe you have an air leak on the cold
end of the greenhouse so you'll start to
see kind of patterns
um the lobe into the field the high end
of the field the cold part of the
greenhouse where is the heater that
maybe you wouldn't believe how many
people have gas powered heaters or
kerosene heaters in their Greenhouse
um or it may be something like if
there's a clog in one of the irrigation
lines maybe all of row 10 looks
different than the other rows so what is
the pattern
um and then you're going to look a
little bit more closely look at the
whole plant
um is it the entire plant that's going
down is it just the new leaves it's just
the old leaves
um is it just one side so right a
fusarium Wilt just one side will start
showing symptoms first so what is the
pattern within the an individual plant
you're going to look at multiple plants
but what's going on
and from there then then my number three
you go down into the soil or the the
media and you're going to look at Roots
you're going to look at the crown what's
happening right could it be mechanical
damage rodents for example a lot of
rodent issues or or if it was a clogged
irrigation system what does the root
system look like if it's a root rot
issue what do the roots look like so
you're going to kind of look there so
you're you're still just gathering
information at that point
but you're giving a sweeping look and
you're closing in closing in
and from there from a leaf for example
if you have a root rot well then you'll
have a leaf die back that's a Wilt right
because if you're losing Roots you're
not getting the water and nutrient
uptake that you need because the roots
aren't there to do to do the job so you
might have a Wilt
um maybe
um consistently for an entire week or
maybe when it cools off at night you'll
the plant will recover so there's a kind
of Wilt and recover phase or you might
have a marginal Leaf Scorch marginal
Leaf Scorch is an uptake issue that
might be a root problem or or maybe salt
buildup in the media so just kind of
gathering it's it's kind of like um
it's kind of like a
um
an investigation if you will right
um just eliminating the obvious
and if you still keep saying okay I'm
still going back to root this is still
I'm still thinking there's a root
problem well then you can investigate a
little closer or you can say this is a
very clear leaf spot they're fungal
structures inside that spot I'm going to
go to leaf spot or
um a Bud Light you know what is it
what's happening so a bud blight
generally won't affect the leaves or you
know so it kind of it's kind of putting
together
um
all of that that information so that you
can take that first guess but there will
be patterns or there will be
um hot spots or there will be something
to give you more information but it
takes some thought and there's no book
there's no checklist
um that gets you there you it's
experience and feel but it's also
taking that wide-angle look
could you
if you were on Facebook or Instagram see
a photo of a cannabis plant and be able
to diagnose it just from that photo as
having fusarium or I mean powdery mildew
I guess is probably an easy one Pottery
build is the only easy one okay so
that's my question because I see this
all the time where you're like you'll
see people post photos and they're like
oh that's fusarium Oh that's phytoptera
oh you know whatever what
what are your thoughts on that you know
just as a pathologist
um besides uh there are very few
pathogens that
seeing the symptoms
um if we are going to communicate for
example you and I are very far apart so
if you called me I would say send me
five pictures I want to see the whole
Greenhouse I want to see the entire site
I want you to look for patterns for me
right you have to be my eyes
um so sending photographs and just
trying to narrow it down in exactly that
pattern of thought that thought process
that I just laid out
um to show me one leave rarely
um to show me one plant rarely there's
more to the story if it was a fusarium
Wilt for example I would make you cut
into that stem
um I would make you cut into healthy
plant stems I would make you tell me the
history of that site I would make you
tell me a lot of things but until I saw
those spores I would not especially in a
commercial in a commercial setting tell
you that you have a specific disease
if I have a Jeweler's Loop for example
or I don't know if you're familiar with
the dino light it's a little fancier yes
I have Dino Lights I've got Pro Scopes
I've gotta okay I've got it all I have a
Dyno light too so what let's just go
with dynolite because that's kind of a
little bit better than a Jeweler's Loop
if I was a grower with a dino light uh
what could I what diseases could I
identify with that tool okay on my plan
okay so for you Growers who don't know a
Dyno light is a
powered little handheld microscope
magnification can get pretty good
um
so you can see a fungal structure like a
pygmodium
um so septoria leaf spot is an example
and if anybody wants to just Google
septoria leaf spot just right right up
on their computer as they listen to this
um inside that leaf spot that fungus
will produce a a structure a survival
structure called it
um picnidium
magnetia are like capsules okay they the
size of a black pepper flake and they're
raised like little pimple-like rays and
inside are those microscopic spores
but
um
pignettia are very large I say very
large so from from a pathologist
standpoint they're very large
um young eyes can see them without uh
without a Jeweler's Loop right without a
hand lens but
um if you zoom in to some of those those
types of spots you can see Canadia and
Canadia Force Canadia or asexual spores
and they stand up on little stalks
the stalks are called the Canadia four
and the Canadian will be on the end
and they'll cluster they'll look like
maybe little bristles and so with a with
a dino light or even a Jeweler's Loop
and good sunshine
you can see those structures and over
time you become familiar with the same
ones over and over
um you can't put me in a um in a wheat
field and I'll be able to use my Loop to
identify certain structures you become
trained
um with the things that you see over and
over but if it's a fungal disease and it
sporulates
we can usually see enough that I can
take a guess
and we can Circle back to this in a
minute but your question was when does a
what does a grower do in the meantime
and we could double back to that so
usually if I see enough we can give a
grower some guidance until we get that
confirmation from the lab
um but there are there are fungal
structures you can never see bacterial
cells with a dino light uh but you can
see oozing you can see water soaking you
will never see viruses viruses are the
absolute hardest even symptom-wise it's
very hard to guess
um but even with a dino light you can
see things like a um like a root
infection
um you can see where that infection
might have taken place pythium for
instance pythium root rot that pythium
will infect from the root tips whereas
black root rot you'll see lesions within
the uh within the root along the root
you'll see those lesions those small
lesions there lesion nematode is another
one right a lesion nematode kind of goes
in right to the side of the root and
it'll create a small lesion so we can
see those kinds of things and remember I
was talking about narrowing down from
the field level you can also narrow down
when you're at that magnified level even
if it's not a high-powered microscope
from even that hand lens or Dino light
level you can start narrowing down
um okay root tips or okay
um this this flower blight is is on the
calyx or sorry on the brat
um or on the pedestal like where is it
happening and magnification gets you
closer to those things it's a better
it's a better communication for you and
I so that when you do submit that sample
you get the right sample and then of
course we can help you with a management
strategy until we get that confirmation
back
so I mean I kind of want to we could go
one of two ways here I kind of want to
talk about some of these diseases and
their life cycles but I also want to
talk about treatment options because
like the first thing when you say uh you
know when I think of a lot of these
things that are on the leaf surface I
want to spray something like ceph oil X
like a mineral oil based some sort of
oil-based suffocate
um
are there better options that are safe
and approved in cannabis than that
um or is there something how do you
approach that I guess
in a really difficult position
um with cannabis because the
the products that are out there are
they're new to cannabis they're new to
these production systems they're just
new and also in cannabis there's a lot
of misinformation out there
um and and that's why you've got this
podcast right that's where I'm working
in this space because there's so much to
do so
um but oils are really not good of
fungicides
um they're they're just not
um they're they're great for suffocating
a lot of arthropods but they're not
something I would ever list in my
fungicide Arsenal
um there are a lot of
um
there are a lot of uh Biologicals that
are really just starting to to we're
just starting to understand them right
you've got your bacillus products your
trichodermas the eulocadium
um so we're just starting to see some of
these products come on the market
um and really I am really loving a lot
of those bacillus products
um there's some really good ones out
there
um and and trichodermas also have their
place
let me say that we use Biologicals
differently than we use our conventional
fungicides so it's not way for disease
and spray and oh it didn't work
um it's the opposite right you've got to
have some preventative preventative
measures and we could we could Circle
back to
um
we can Circle back to cultural practices
but you've got to be able to use these
these products as as often living
objects right they're either
um SARS or they're living
organisms so they also need
um humidity they also need certain
conditions to uh to to survive and to do
on that leaf and to do what they need to
do
um there are a lot of questions about
persistence how long are they on that
leaf right once you spray how long are
they on that leaf or on that flower or
in that soil
so there there's a lot to be learned
there but um the best things I think we
have on the market or your bacillus
products and your trichoderma products
and um I do not have a favorite bacillus
um from what I have tested they really
work pretty well all all pretty well
um we've got some research going on ask
me again in a year I hope to have a lot
more information but so far what we know
they're all kind of right there
um
doing the best that they can with what
we throw at them with a monocultured
system in a very humid indoor
environment and uh
you know
farmers are abusive we don't treat our
plants well so we put a lot we put a lot
on it right yeah honestly that surprises
me a little bit about oils I I was not
aware of that um
I I've used the oils
because and this is another thing to
talk about too is how much are insects
and pests spreading disease or pathogens
too around your room and killing you
know some of these arthropods like you
mentioned
I think could I assume would have some
effect as well on reducing or preventing
disease spread
um
I have I haven't had really good success
with Biologicals
um once I've identified disease in the
room
um right it seems like at that point
it's too late I mean
I don't know I would love to hear you
just talk a little more about this
because and I'm thinking in my head I'm
thinking of powdery mildew just to give
you a little more context okay any
disease right
um so your Biologicals I like to say
they're not a Magic Bullet in any way
they are not going to cure nothing cures
disease but our conventional fungicides
which by the way there are none uh label
for any cannabis or hip product
um your conventional your conventional
fungicides
um
they're tough right they're really good
and they can suppress they're a great
big Band-Aid for two to three weeks and
your Biologicals don't do that
so your Biologicals must be used
preventatively they must be used
preventatively and we say the same thing
about our conventional fungicides but
they they have a staying power that
Biologicals don't
um so so if you have a history of a
disease
um you must use your Biologicals
preventatively or at the first sign of
or first symptom of a disease hands down
um powdery mildew
is powdery mildew is like it's like easy
but it's tough like I it's I have I have
mixed feelings about that one
um with powdery mildew and for those who
don't know what you're looking at is
actually the fungus it is a mass of
Canadia and Canadian Force right so
those are the the Canadian forests that
stalk and then the Canadia or those
um Highlander clear
um
asexual spores and they form in Chains
so those are chains of spores the
fluffier that Mycelia is
the longer those chains of spores are
and they're airborne and what do you do
in an indoor grow you've got fans on so
you're blowing it around
um so when you see powdery mildew you've
got more spores than you can come than
you could possibly count on a single
leaf
um just just really high numbers that's
what makes powdery mildew so hard to
manage
also remember there are a couple of
different powdery mildews out there and
one of them in particular
um it's it's relative humidity it can
infect at a relative humidity of about
40 that's low that's dry
um so that so this is one of the
situations where it's sometimes hard to
even use cultural practices for
management
is there any human risk with the amount
of spores in the air when you do spot
powdery mildew in a room are you would
you like go running out of there to put
on a mask or is it not something to
worry about that would not be something
to worry about unless you're
immunocompromised and if you are
immunocompromised it's really hard to be
in any agricultural setting right for
just a lot of the things we do
um another thing about powdery noodles
can I add one thing about powdery milk
absolutely people don't know is that
powdery mildew the white the nice fluffy
white mildew that you see if you will
um that is only that's the asexual stage
of that uh that fungus and so later in
the season or the end of its life or as
plants begin to finesse it will produce
a different type of structure called a
chasmodesia and that is an overwintering
capsule
um that will that's that's going to
initiate that sexual recombination that
sexual stage but it's also the
overwintering stage in chasmodesia or
like some little
um round
velcro balls like they have appendages
and they stick to things so your powdery
mildew is gonna stick it's gonna stick
to anything
um that's that's coarse so any kind of
wood any kind of table legs or any kind
of pots or containers or
um so it's going to stick on everything
everywhere
and the field is sticking on the stems
and debris and um it's hanging out and
once those cosmethesia they're black
they're dark colored that means they're
melonized when they're melonized they're
UV resistant they are heat tolerant
they're cold tolerant they are fungicide
resistant so that is that carryover from
season to season
um so following a greenhouse in between
but sanitizing a greenhouse in between
crops is really critical if not you're
leaving those cosmetesia in place so
again we're back to that life cycle we
leave those cosmetesia in place each
year you've got or each each crop you've
got more and more of that inoculum in
place ready to ready to infect
so many questions but let me let me
start with a couple so my first question
is
um
how are are the are the powdery mildews
that we're seeing in cannabis also
um ones that could be uh
could other plants be carriers whether
those are cover crops squashes I think
of like in my outdoor Garden
um that sort of thing and then two uh
just so I don't forget my questions uh
Biologicals which you mentioned being
effective are are challenging and that
we can't
a lot of states are testing for
microbial contamination on the buds
themselves and not differentiating
bacillus
species in terms of what's safe and not
safe so that that's another thing and
then
um how effective is just water at
killing powdery mildew I've heard that
it can you know there's a physical
mechanism of just rinsing it off the
leaves too potentially so sorry there's
a lot of questions but I don't want to
forget them I have a lot of questions
and that's two hours worth of answers
okay okay
so what was the first question now now
I've forgotten the first question uh
other carriers that's right cross
species
contamination so what we finding and
back to speciation and my my favorite
thing in the world to speciate
everything is that um our powdery
mildews basically do have a wider hose
range than we have than we have known in
the past so yes
golovenomyces chicory Sierra morgola
venomyces spodacious
um absolutely is the one that you're
gonna see on wildflowers on Weeds on
other crops it is out there yes
um so
um do you always see the weeds like I'm
picturing indoor facilities that run
cover crops
um inside the facility itself like you
know some of these cover crops have very
narrow leaves they're smaller
um you'd have to look really closely is
it possible that you may not be seeing
the spores or um
or something like that too I guess
yeah so so it manifests differently
sometimes it's not as preferred host
sometimes it um you know and so it will
look differently also
um you know again so we've got a lot of
levels and you and I were talking about
this last week you've got a lot of
different types of Growers right and
your listeners are probably in a very
wide range from um two plants on the
black on the back patio to a commercial
facility that is sealed
um but even in your larger facilities
you would be surprised at how much
outdoor air is coming in
so remember the fluffiness remember
everything you see in powdery mildew is
spores is my their microscopic spores so
there's a lot of powdery mildew blowing
around and so just air exchange through
a fan through an open window through a
some type of ventilation system
bringing that powdery mildew in
so and again once it's in there it's
there for a very long time
and I I'm gonna laugh and I'm gonna tell
you that this pathologist cannot get rid
of pottery mildew in her own Greenhouse
we have just infested we have done
everything and we can't get it we cannot
eradicate it so it is tough
um it is really tough so think about the
entry it is coming in and then it's
building up so once you have powdery
mildew which everybody does once you
have powdery mildew if you you know how
many of us are guilty about after we
Harvest we leave the plants in place
right we don't really get rid of them
like we should and then so that's when
you start seeing those cosmetesia
develop you might not see them but
they're there and
go ahead can it only grow on living
tissue powdery mildew powdery mildew can
only establish and and survive no live
but it will survive as survival
structures so right
um but you can go you can go years with
those cosmethesia those survival
structures being viable and waiting for
a crop
yeah I'm full of bad news right
so
distilling the soil have any positive
effects in terms of potentially killing
the chasmodesia is that the correct word
yeah yeah that's right it's usually
somewhere on some surface it's it's not
as much on this on the soil or in the
soil so tilling it into debris tilling
the debris in yes that will bury it but
it's in other places right so if you
have a hemp field it's on fence posts if
or you know it's clinging to anything
um it's clinging everywhere and there's
always some debris there's always
something around but in an indoor
facility
um I don't know any grower who truly
does a full disinfestation between crops
I mean wash floor to ceiling
so mer filters though can be effective
at reducing that or is that getting
outside of your area of that's getting
outside of my area but your um your
filter size your uh will affect you know
it determines which particle size gets
in but you still have to walk in right
and again the best facilities
are are rare
um so
not just filtration but opening of doors
and you walk in right you've been
outside and you walk straight into work
during the day do you really suit up do
you really shower I mean not many even
our best grows are not uh not the level
of a containment facility it's going to
come in and once it's in
it's very it's going to establish
yeah no that's that's really helpful
um
so I I guess what I'm wondering then is
you know we talked a little bit about
these Biologicals and how in a lot of
States we have testing that doesn't
allow us to effectively use them because
of the the regulations essentially
um
which leads me back to oils and then my
question about water and sort of
mechanical
means of removing powdery mildew how
effective are those things
say in the vegetative state before we
have the formation and the flower
formation
oh wow okay I'm gonna start with your
second question uh water
so think about how powdery mildew
infects so the um
so this is a cuticle infection so the
infection is right under the cuticle so
it is not literally on the surface so
the sporulation is on the surface but
there is a there's a level of infection
so if you wash it down you have spread
those spores and then you have not
gotten rid of the infection so the
fungus will pop back up so
I would not I would not waste my time I
don't see where that could even
buy you any time like 12 hours but
powdery mildew sporulates right back
if you have a missed bench for example
if you have cuttings and you have a Mist
bench yeah powdery mildew is not real
happy
um but you know you haven't gotten rid
of the infection you just kept it kept
it at Bay for however long your plants
are under the Mist
so what tools do we have then as a
grower in our current system besides
oils I guess we haven't talked about
soaps at all
um those are insecticidal soaps or
anything like that do those have any
fungicidal properties
not really not enough
um so we've we've got
we've got
um I don't like to to mention products
but there are a couple of products on
the market that do a pretty good job and
um regalia does a good job
um
um I have a study that we use cease
which is a bacillus so uh cease does a
good a good job
um
used properly with other cultural
practices
um that's kind of been our best bet and
if you look at some of my old work
um a student did a project several years
ago where one of our Growers had to use
organic milk and uh he did and that was
one of the most effective but again
um you need a lot of applications right
so it's not just one uh one application
like most Growers especially any grower
who goes from a conventional system into
something like cannabis that you can't
use conventional products they're highly
disappointed but
um
there are some products that work well
um when combined with cultural practices
when combined with air circulation and
following greenhouses in between crops
those types of things
so I heard about that a study like that
um through the giant pumpkin Community
actually I wonder if this was if your
student and you were the ones that did
that original study or were you guys
replicated something around that no we
just did it uh we did it when we were uh
looking at some products in powdery
mildew in hemp in the greenhouse and uh
you know we we had all kinds of crazy
things in that study anything a grower
told us they used all the you know the
anecdotes and
um wives tales we kind of threw those in
there so we had B propolis and we had
all kinds of things
um but the milk the organic whole milk
and it was a powdered milk mixed I don't
remember the details of the study but it
did pretty well so it uh
that's not systemic you're going to have
to spray on a five-day interval
oh that's that's a good point then okay
so every five days just because of the
life cycle of the yeah of the mildew so
do you know if it was an enzyme or
something in the milk itself or the
lactobacillus because I know a lot of
Growers are using lactobacillus and
making their own
what they call Labs essentially and
spraying that I don't remember
um it's not something I pursued I did
some powdery mildew work years ago I've
since worked on other things so I don't
remember the details of that study I'll
see if I can find it if I can find it
I'll give it to you to link to your uh
your bio and your uh show notes but um
but yeah it's a powdery mildew is tough
especially indoors
well let's talk a little about what some
of the other diseases are that you're
seeing uh prevalence of and maybe how
they're misunderstood or misdiagnosed
right now
oh wow I could go forever on that all
right so another really common one in
indoor facilities now when I say indoor
that means
um a true and or closed facility it
could mean a greenhouse it could mean a
basement it can mean anything except the
field okay so I'm going to use that term
very generally but any indoor
environment
where you're using a soilless media
the premise the premise there and now
this can also include Hydroponics or
anything in that line as well
um it's pretty we'll call it sterile uh
for lack of a better term
um so you don't have the antagonist you
don't have the the microorganisms that
you would in a field situation all right
well we'll kind of set the scene there
um so uh pythium is probably number two
right behind powdery mildew in any
indoor grow any soil is mixed or soil is
um or hydroponic system if you will
and that's because there are no
antagonists
um also we do a lot of watering in a
soilless mix we're also in it's wet
right we're either flood we're either
flood benching or we are you know having
dripping and just just it's just wet in
an indoor environment because we've got
pour through and uh pythium
um is a water mold it's an old Micey
it's not a true fungus
and so once pythium comes in It's Got
Roots it's got water it doesn't have
antagonists and that's another really
persistent fungus that is uh or pathogen
rather sorry not it's not a fungus it's
a really persistent pathogen that a lot
of Growers struggle with and often fail
to recognize what's really going on
because it manifests as a nutrient
deficiency it manifests as a lot of
things and
um of course you get wilting in the more
you more it wilts the more you water the
more you water the happier pythium is
because it's water mold
um so there's a lot of pythium in our
systems
um
I know that we have five different
species that we have identified we've
got the cool weather pythiums and we've
got the really hot Greenhouse
um pythium species so there are a lot of
pythians out there from across the board
and we're finding lots of it
um so
just knowing you have pythium would be a
big deal but to know which one you have
kind of complicates things unless you
have a lab that's willing to do that for
you
yeah
so when we uh when we suspect we have
pythium
our identifiers like you said it's going
to delete the above ground
material is going to look a lot like a
nutrient deficiency but I would assume
when you dig down into that
media you're going to see a very
distinctive I mean I've always called it
root rot
um sort of brown slimy
Roots what what are the distinguishing
characteristics epithium relative to
other pathogens okay so
um for everybody listening when you when
you expose those roots rinse very slowly
right you don't want to break those
roots those roots are really brittle
when they're infected
so your younger younger plants are going
to become infected more they're more
susceptible
um a young plant like right a new
cutting or a Seedling or just a young
plant has more of those young tender
Roots
um
they're more susceptible the older a
plant is the less the less problem
you're going to have with pythium so
it's an early season disease so think
about timing
um whereas nutrition is usually a
problem later in the growth the growing
cycle
pythium is a root Nibbler so it comes in
on the root tip so the very tips and it
goes upwards and once Roots get tough
and strong yeah it doesn't really like
that
um so you'll see them more on the tip
and if you rinse slowly and you take a
look at those roots so you're saying
Brown and mushy that's extreme you want
to catch it before that right so with
that extreme you got stunting and dying
and but whereas if it's a if it's that
the beginning stages and you've just got
that
myoclerosis or maybe it's stunting maybe
it's not I'm not real sure could it be
the cultivar so when it's when it's at
that low level
looking at those roots so you want to
look at the tips of the roots with your
Dino light or your hand lens or whatever
you have to magnify
um I know some of my Growers who have an
old-fashioned magnifying glass don't be
too proud for a magnifying glass
whatever it takes to magnify
and so what you want to look at is the
root tip
the root of an effective infected root
will be flatter it won't be really
turgid it'll be discolored not
necessarily brown maybe starting to turn
a little gray
um and at the tip
very easily the cortex will Slough off
and just that steel will stick out
so we call that rat tail so a rat tail
root tip is my favorite indicator of
pythium
so
um
picture again
the cortex left off and just the steel
sticking out sometimes it's a very small
amount sometimes maybe as much as an
inch but you have to rinse your roots
very carefully so you don't break them
up and you can see those sometimes with
the naked eye the older I get the less
of the seeing things with the naked eye
are possible but a little bit of
magnification heck turn on your phone
camera and zoom it's usually enough
so if I spot pythium on
my plants they're they're looking you
know like you said you caught it in
early stage Wheat Growers tend to
diagnose these things probably too late
but assuming we caught it early what
what options do we have to for treatment
oh
bad news again
um so some of your trichoderma products
are good preventatives so let's back up
if you ever have pythium in your
Greenhouse you probably still have
pythium and I'm saying Greenhouse your
indoor environment you probably still
have pythium
um again following starting over
Cleaning Santa disinfesting sanitizing
everything every tool every piece of
equipment from wheelbarrow to garden
hose to Flushing out your irrigation
lines
um cleaning everything out and starting
from scratch making sure that when you
get a delivery of your media you're not
throwing it on the ground outside
surprising how many people do that so
then your media becomes contaminated but
um so to go in and if you have a history
to go with something like a trichoderma
or something like that so really you
want to get those plants to that six
week stage and once you get to that six
or eight week stage they toughen up and
they're pretty good unless you really
have a severe infestation
pantheum is a soil-borne pathogen it
lives its entire life in the soil which
means at any propagule any Spore is
going to move with soil and when I say
soil I mean soil and soil is mixed and
water so it's moving it's moving
anywhere that soil particles would so
it's under your shoes it's on your hands
if your hands are wet it's on your wet
pruners it's um well you wet clothes
it's definitely under the bench on the
ground any crack in the in the concrete
under there so it's everywhere and
you're moving it around you're moving it
very easily
ones for rarely we'll we'll set off an
epidemic but there's rarely one sport
and then of course once you add a host
plant that's highly susceptible and then
you add all that water because it's a
water mold remember then you've got that
slow build up of inoculum and then
suddenly bam you're hit with a disease
epidemic you're like where did this come
from but it slowly Creeps in
um so sanitation sanitation sanitation
there's nothing you can do no perfect
fungicide will do a good job without
sanitation and being we don't have a
good fungicide sanitation is all we've
got
okay yeah because we we do work with a
lot of Growers that are using soils that
have a compost fraction they're they're
using more biological so we do have I I
guess what you said like more
antagonisms too pythium and frankly I
haven't seen a lot of pythium and with a
lot of the grows that we work with
relative to other other diseases but
um
if we want to reuse that media for
example if we were growing in a in a bed
versus a disposable media
would repeat applications of trichoderma
or something like that have a potential
the potential to at least reduce it
below an economic threshold
um I really don't want to say yes to
that
um
if you
I'd rather see you steam it or or
somehow sterilize it right somehow
heated them I'd much rather see you do
that with anything in a great house
think of a hospital a hospital is quote
unquote sterile that's how staff kind of
takes a hold or or something else in a
hospital right uh that's what happens is
those antagonists are not there so even
if you've got some compost in your media
you still don't have the antagonist
utils don't have have the biodiversity
that you have out in the field that's
why you don't see a lot of these
problems in fields you see different
things but that's why you really don't
have a lot of these in the field because
um you've got really a an entire uh
ecosystem you're never going to create
an ecosystem in an indoor environment so
you've got to keep it
on the sterile end
um don't reuse your media if you do have
a good steamer
or have something to be able to really
heat it up
um
two weeks at
110 degrees Fahrenheit would uh make me
happy but 110 degrees inside of a large
container is different than 110 on the
surface
so why why can't we create uh
successional functioning ecosystem
in indoors because I know that compost
contains higher
microbial biomass overall
it may contain less diversity but I'm
just curious to hear your thoughts on
that
oh that's really not my area but think
about
think about an ecosystem is underground
at soil level right so it's your
rhizosphere it's your phylus sphere it's
the
it's the arthropods in the air it's the
microbes and so it's it's bigger and you
don't have that in an indoor environment
right
um
it's not going to be a biodome it's not
you know you would have to really open
up so you can't have like a micro
ecosystem
um
alone
right so if you've got a micro ecosystem
it's happening and the bigger ecosystem
outside but you can't produce a micro
ecosystem in a container or on a bench
with the rest of that Greenhouse doesn't
have that the components needed
um to support the rest of it
yeah that's something I've been thinking
about because we have
well we have Growers that you know want
to do things that are more organic and
be more natural and and this idea that
things that happen in nature are somehow
better than other things even though
agriculture in itself is fairly
artificial growing monocrops and
harvesting them so consistently but you
know I some of the facilities we work
with like one of them has had the same
media in place in in their rooms for
over eight years and I know they've
battled just about everything at this
point and yet they're able to
continually produce product
um
I'd love to see more research around
what sorts of ecosystem successional
ecosystems are created in soilless media
that's being reused over time just from
a sustainability perspective that would
be really interesting right because you
know I I could go down a whole
sustainability rabbit hole but but there
is so much waste
um that I would like to see that too
that would be really nice
um think about though that without the
full spread of antagonists that when
something is introduced it it can just
get away from you so this grower you
said that's been reusing media
um that's a unicorn it would be nice if
we could say that and I I would love I
would love to stick my hands in that in
that system
um but it's unusual for that to happen
and it just takes one introduction
um
one introduction of a pathogen that
um that really kind of can set can set
things off in the wrong direction but if
they're good Growers and if they're
careful about what comes in if they're
planting from seed and
um usually when we're moving soil borne
pathogens we're moving them in soil
again soil soil is mixed so you know if
you get cuttings from someone else or
anything like that sure that's where
you're kind of re introducing versus
um I know grow like vegetable Growers
who only bring seed in because they have
less chance of some of those that are
Seaborn pathogens that's a whole nother
that's a whole nother podcast episode
but
um but yeah it's really about
introductions in the end if you don't
introduce it it's not there you can't
have disease if you don't introduce the
pathogen
totally that makes total sense and you
know one of my best friends is an
entomologist who I've had on the podcast
and I understand from a pathology
perspective from an entomology
perspective like
you want to keep things as clean as
possible
um that's just to avoid any issues in
the in the very beginning and so this
this idea of reusing media creates a lot
of a lot of a lot of risk yeah and I
think that's something people do need to
be aware of I plan outside because I'm a
I'm actually a I'm really an avid grower
for outdoor outdoor production but again
that's a whole I'm sure you'll get that
has its other challenges from the
growing perspective yeah but yeah we're
not without we're not without challenges
especially when you invite a pathologist
to talk about it right yeah well just in
the interest of time because I know
we've been chatting for a while here
there's so much more I want to ask you
but
um originally I'd reached out because of
some of the research you had you had
contributed to
out of Kentucky University of Kentucky
there and can you talk about
a little bit about the the silica paper
I knew you were going to ask me about
the Silicon paper so yeah if we could
start with that one and then I want to
touch a little bit on the other
fungicide one that you did too just you
know even if we just spent a couple
minutes on it that would be great okay
all right so we uh we did a test where
we used
um where we applied silicon to
um soilless media in the greenhouse this
is my green house with all of the
powdery mildew that I cannot get rid of
um and that was a goal of venomycy
spodacious I think was the was the
powdery mildew and
um we use three different rates of
um of um silicon
I'm trying to think right offhand like
250 550 and 800 pounds per acre the
equivalent so we did the math and so we
did all of this in in replicated trials
and then we had two different cultivars
um one was highly susceptible to powdery
mildew and what was moderately
susceptible to powdery mildew and um
basically we so we started our plugs in
uh um in these media and then we
transplanted into larger containers also
so we started really we set our clock
when we actually transplanted into
I think it was the equivalent of three
gallon pots if I remember right and
um we we grew those plants for six weeks
and we looked at we rated the amount of
powdery mildew on those plants
um and
this was by the way this was last night
uh well last night sorry I um and so
um essentially that
um 600 kilograms per hectare which comes
out to
535 pounds per acre
um calculation
um that is what that really managed
powdery mildew to at really low levels
for an entire six weeks
so we were talking about uh what are
what our
um Arsenal is there's a lot of work that
needs to be done with silicon in um in
cannabis all together it is an
accumulator by the way that's a whole
nother part of that paper and we
confirmed that it was an accumulator
but
um we were looking at 80 to 80 reduction
in the amount of powdery mildew compared
to the non-treated control
it was fascinating that's that's
incredible and while last night is a
very affordable option a couple things I
think of um so when last night calcium
silicate
um like I said very affordable uh you it
will raise your pH and it will add
calcium to your soil so you'd want to
account for that in your fertility if
you were to add it like I wouldn't just
add it indiscriminately to get to the
silica levels I assume you guys looked
at the fertility there too we did yeah
we did we adjusted pH so that that is
all in the paper
so
I just wanted listeners to think about
that before they just go running out to
grab last night
um yeah that's right is there any is
there any future research around other
types of ways of adding uh
silicon to soil
no so here in Kentucky
um we have sufficient amounts of silicon
in our soils in our natural soils
um so it's not something we think that
would be beneficial at the field level
um definitely at the greenhouse level in
soilless mix we do know from other
research in other systems that bipolaris
or Casper fusarium septoria are all have
all been documented uh confirmed to be
reduced by
silicon in soil as media
so those are all big pathogens in in
help in particular and so it would be
really great if someone would pick up
that torch and run with it I don't see
that in my future I just have other
things
um but but cannabis is an accumulator
and
um a lot of cannabis pathogens are known
to be
um reduced by silicon
yeah I did a whole podcast on Silicon
with another
um
with another University Research and it
was it was amazing I learned so much
about it
um
one thing I will add if people are using
elastinite is to make sure that it's not
high in heavy metals because there is a
lot of heavy metal testing now happening
being that it is a mined product that's
another thing to account for
for folks but that's uh that's wonderful
so
I'm excited to see where that research
goes uh can you briefly tell me a little
bit about your other research that you
did comparing uh Biologicals and
fungicides on hemp oh yeah
oh that paper in particular
it was we called it pre-screening so
this was all done in vitro we did this
in the lab in uh Petri dishes and we we
did a variety of um
of screening methods so uh one thing we
did is we
um amended media with different
biological fungicides we also had our
conventional fungicides as our controls
right so what was that comparison so we
we had another
um
another test so we put
um a strip of or stripe of
um
of a fungicide a biological across the
center of a Petra dish and then we put
plugs of our pathogens on each side and
so that was the the
um
the premise there is that if some of
these pathogens produced any kind of
metabolite that was the antagonistic
component
um
so there was the direct
um antagonism then there was some
release of some kind of metabolite then
our third
um screening method was that we
um mixed spores with a suspension of
these fungicides so that might be the
ones that that needed time right so
um so we did that mix then we plated
those spores out and we looked at
germination right
and so one of the things that
um we don't know about of a lot a lot of
our Biologicals is how long do they need
to be on the surface to actually work
if you spray them at noon and you know
it dries up and whatever's in there
doesn't have time to work whatever that
mode of action those are some things we
didn't know so we developed this
pre-screening method that we were um
hoping to see and really
there was a really wide range and um
I have not just the the paper but we did
what we call a um a translational piece
where we kind of write the research up
for for Growers who don't want all the
nitty-gritty uh scientific jargon and uh
there's a table in there that we added
that really just shows all of the
different types of of experiments like
how how to best screen those things
um which products seem to have the best
results and so this is intended to be
our next our first step in what will be
a series so our our next go-to is we're
going to take select products the ones
that did the best in some of these
studies and we're going into the
greenhouse
and then from there we'll take the next
the next group and they'll go into the
field
um because we can't afford to put
everything in the field
um there's not much hemp or we have to
all of our research at the university is
on hemp by the way so if anybody who's
wondering why I keep saying Help
um we cannot work on marijuana at the
University
um
so
so we can't afford so the the funding is
just not there so we can't just bring
all of these products into the field and
test for all of these different
pathogens it's not possible so we have
to we have to have some kind of
pre-screening method where do we start
um where where is our time that's been
where is our money best spent so that
was the premise of this pre-screening
method but you can look at this table
and you'll see that
a lot of these products are working in a
Petri dish why don't they work in the
field that's where we know it's not the
product it's our use it's our
application method it's our time of
application there there are other
questions and when I said at the very
beginning of our conversation we don't
know how to use them
um we really don't so we have a lot of
things coming up this year and next
where we're going to start teasing some
of this apart
so if it didn't suppress well in a petri
dish
is there ever a case where you might get
an infield response that would be
surprising or
is that a product that we may not want
to necessarily use at this point in our
garden I know you can't make
recommendations necessarily but just as
a general rule
if there is for example systemic
acquired resistance you're turning on an
immune system in your plant
that product should not work in a Petri
dish right because it does not have a
direct effect on the pathogen it's a
it's a plant immune response and so we
do have a couple of those in the study
and um they didn't do well of course
they didn't
um we knew that and we say that very
clearly in our conclusion like this is
not so so if you are going to look at
this study by the way any of your
listeners
um be careful about what we're actually
what we're actually saying there right
um regalia is one like regalia didn't do
well in this study because it's not
meant to it has another motive of action
um and I've picked on regalia twice
today and it's a fabulous product but
this is not what it's meant for
so that is and and we know we know those
so we have we have conversations with
these manufacturers they tell us what
we're what they expect it to do and they
guide us along the way too they
developed it they know their products
yeah
um so yeah a systemic acquired
resistance would be the one that we
would not expect to do well in our
pre-screening but we would definitely
bring it to the field
yeah I mean we haven't we didn't really
talk about SAR responses and how
products might trigger that or different
applications
around chitin and the chitinase pathway
and if those things affect microbes
there's so much I would love to ask you
but I know we've been talking for a
while maybe we could do a follow-up when
you have some more research or when you
have some more free time I would love
that
absolutely um
well well thank you so much one last
thing uh
so you work with people in Kentucky that
are growing hemp you're not available to
work with just any old person who just
has a plant disease what resources does
someone like myself in Washington have
where should I begin to search from a
pathology perspective to get assistance
with with my plans
you need to know where your local plant
disease Diagnostic lab is and in some
states you can your University
Diagnostic lab will take not just hemp
but cannabis as well some State Labs and
on the west coast there are State Labs
they may or may not also take those
um there are some private Labs out there
we're seeing a little bit more of those
um get to know people though
um really
um be careful where you go make sure you
have an actual pathologist and not just
someone who's been uh who's been reading
a lot of online articles and um really
get a diagnosis and that that gets you
started and even if there's not a
reference on that pathogen in cannabis
you can at least learn that life cycle
and we talked about some examples today
but knowing those life cycles and
knowing overwintering and survival of a
pathogen will take you so far I can't
say that enough
um
we didn't get to talk about
environmental conditions or humidity or
and so we'll definitely have to do that
again but I would love to have you back
on hand yeah no I think I think uh plant
diseases is like in in this sort of
thing is one of the biggest challenges
for Growers and there's so much that we
don't understand and there's so much
misinformation so I really appreciate
your time today and you sharing all this
with us so
okay well thanks a lot and um
if you have any questions just reach out
to him
[Music]
that was Dr Nicole gotchae with the
University of Kentucky and you are
listening to the Cannabis cultivation
and science podcast don't forget to
check out the podcast page at
www.kisorganics.com just click on the
learn tab then podcast and if you want
to access the podcast as soon as they
are recorded along with additional
content and video we do have a patreon
account that we are just starting up
again
the kiss Organics website also offers a
variety of soil amendments lighting
fixtures beneficial insects and the
highest quality commercial soils on the
market we carefully research all the
products we offer and manufacture to
make sure they are science based and
meet our standard of quality thanks for
listening