[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host tadd
hussey of kiss organics this is the
podcast where we discuss the cutting
edge of growing from a science-based
perspective and draw top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge my guest this week
is dr jack muns jack obtained a bachelor
of science in botany from colorado state
university while working as a lab
assistant facilitating the development
of genetic markers for invasive species
jack then earned a master of science
from illinois state university where he
worked towards increasing vegetable oils
and temperate grasses like corn for
biodiesel production using targeted gene
expression he also has a phd in botany
from the university of british columbia
during which he worked to unravel the
genetic regulation of nitrogen
starvation responses in plants with
next-gen sequencing technologies
jack is now applying his experience in
plant molecular genetics to diagnose
viruses and cannabis with three rivers
biotech based out of vancouver canada
three rivers biotech also has a lab in
ferndale washington and a future lab in
california later this year
hey jack thanks for coming on the show
today
thanks for having me it's a pleasure to
talk to you today
yeah let's start off telling listeners a
little bit about yourself
yeah so i have a doctorate in botany but
i've been working in uh plant molecular
genetics for a little over 10 years now
i've worked on a variety of different
projects but i have a really broad skill
set in the
molecular genetics field and that's sort
of my core competency
so now i've been working on diagnosing
viruses
so the most sensitive way to do that
will be
using genetic diagnostics such as pcr so
i'm working
um with three rivers biotech to develop
a platform to help
uh specifically have their sorry hemp
and cannabis growers to diagnose viruses
and we're sort of expanding our platform
to
include other plants as well
yeah so the reason i want to have you on
the show today was to talk about your
experience with viruses that you're
seeing in cannabis and sort of
simplify
the the science behind uh not just the
testing process but also the um the
virus itself
or the viruses i guess i should say um
you know anecdotally a lot of people for
a while there it seems like you know if
i go back historically everyone the big
plant problem was spider mites and then
we moved on to like broad mites hemp
russet cannabis aphids and i'm hearing a
lot more about viruses uh for a while
everything was being blamed on
tmz or tobacco mosaic virus but uh kind
of take me through a little bit about
about viruses in general and then a
little bit more about what you're seeing
in cannabis
absolutely yeah so the first thing is
it's one of those problems that you
can't
diagnose
just based on the symptoms alone so a
lot of viruses will have overlapping
symptoms
and so if you go into a field and you
see
something that's a virus like symptoms
such as leaf mosaic or chlorosis
or stunting
you can you can easily mix them up just
on a visual diagnostics you have to rely
on molecular diagnostics which then sort
of
is part of the reason why it's taken a
while to catch up in the cannabis field
specifically
um so not having sort of the academic
researchers do some of the basic
research to figure out what viruses
might be out there has sort of hampered
our
knowledge of what's been in cannabis
however there are some reports that go
back and help to the early 70s
um and then recently there's a big
pickup in that but i do expect there'll
be more uh viruses on the horizon that
are found in cannabis as as researcher
or researchers are able to open the door
to that now with with the legalization
and regulate regulations being a little
easier
um so you mentioned tmv a lot of times
gets blamed and i think
so so
in in hemp and cannabis it's actually
been found to be symptomless regarding
morphological features
so
it was back in 1970
it's a paper by paulson at all who
basically
infected hemp with a variety of common
viruses and they basically studied to
see if hem displayed any symptoms
and they found that while tmv could
infect
the cannabis plant it didn't actually
cause any obvious morphological symptoms
and so they could then spread the virus
but
there weren't any any major uh
phenotypes associated with um or
passenger pathogenesis sorry
pathogenesis associated with gmd um
it's something that i think deserves a
little bit further study uh for example
a plant could be
symptomless
uh morphologically but may have uh
changes in in metabolites or something
like that
um so i think
one of the reasons this has sort of
become so prominent recently in in
cannabis specifically is the
um the findings of things like hop
latent thyroid which is pretty
widespread and we're seeing a lot of
that
in the pacific northwest it's sort of
the main thing we diagnose
but then there's a lot of common viruses
that are known you know across
agricultural
platforms worldwide that have become
we
there are able to infect cannabis and
cause symptom
infections such as
leaf mosaics sclerosis necrosis dwarfing
of the plant and abnormal growth
so
it's definitely a
growing field for cannabis and it's
definitely a
um a resource now that we have tools
that we we've developed here um and then
there's other tools available out in the
um the community for for growers to
begin actually figuring out whether or
not they're dealing with something that
is virus related
and so
they're often introduced to facilities
via something like aphids that's sort of
the initial infection but most commonly
they're spread
through clonal propagation and pruning
that's just not been um
sterilization standards maybe maybe
you're a little wax so
typically they're spread via mechanical
transmission uh via from from one
facility to another off like a clone
that came from an infected mother or
something like that um or or spread
within a facility uh if pruning tools
are not sterilized between
uh between plants
so what i'm hearing are the main vectors
are
uh insects
or potentially um
the sharing of clones what about the
risk like i know with tmv in other crops
i've heard it's a big issue and like you
can't even have a cigarette or be around
anything
related to the tobacco plant
just because of that risk
with certain crops so
how common is it for people to spread it
through clothing touching um things like
that
so it depends highly dependent on the
virus or viroid
but tmv is known to be perhaps
maybe the most stable of all the viruses
it's very very stable
and it can and just be dormant for
for a very long period of time such as
like you said cigarettes
now it's not the smoke from cigarettes
but it's the touching of the cigarettes
and so
there's no
main vector known for tmv per se it's
mostly by mechanical transmission so
touch based transmission
but it can also be spread on seed coats
so again it's sort of touching the seed
and so now that that seed when it
germinates has sort of a reservoir or
tmv present
so yeah for tmv it's very stable but
then there's other viruses like cucumber
mosaic virus which is very unstable or
instable sorry
so cucumber mosaic virus really only
lasts for
i think it's that in vitro it's only
stable for for a matter of minutes to
hours
so that one's a virus that
when it's transmitted it's what's called
non-persistent so it's um
it's not circulating in the insect
but if it's sort of like you know i
guess sort of like an insect lipstick
you know if it goes from an infected
plant with cucumber mosaic virus it gets
it on its mouth part
um and then when it moves to another
plant within minutes hours um it can
transmit the uh actually i think it's
within seconds to minutes for cucumber
mosaic it can spread it to another plant
um however there's other viruses that
are more stable and that are persistent
or semi-persistent in insects
and can either be in the insect for
hours or days or within the insect for
months to its entire lifetime so it
depends highly dependent on the virus so
each virus sort of has a different
stability
but going back to your original point
yet tmv is very very stable virus
so what so it does vary quite a bit one
question i had kind of relayed to this
then is you mentioned which i thought
was really interesting uh that
tmv doesn't display any morphological or
so any you know noticeable physical
changes or structure in the plant itself
could you speculate then that most
plants potentially could have tmv i mean
there seems to be a high
overlap between smoking cigarettes and
smoking cannabis uh to a certain extent
and so would many plants be exposed but
if that was the case then i would think
um
you know if it had any effect my thought
would be when you did a tissue culture
with plants
you would see a
improvement in yield or a change in
morphological structure
due to the removal of tmv does that make
sense right
yeah so i think it's a little early
so when i say there's no morphological
symptoms there's no obvious you know
there's no obvious leap mosaic that was
found with tmv regarding hemp when i was
back in the 70s again this is sort of a
burgeoning field of research that it
would be wonderful to enlist some more
you know i know i know of
quite a few professors that are working
on enhancing cannabis now um but yeah
it'll be great to have like you said a
tmv infected plant
that you can measure you know do a coa
and check all the metabolites and and
sort of get a real fine you know
granular detail of the plant and then
cure the plants of tmv whether
tissue culture is probably the best
because then you could have a
genetically identical version that you
could then compare clean versus not
clean and see if there's any significant
differences
um so yeah the the when i say it's not
symptomatic in in
hemp and cannabis right now the only
evidence would be anecdotal there's no
scientific literature that would say
that there's a morphological change from
tmz
um
but yeah i think the science it would
the science has been catching up to do
regarding um
some of those those efforts but
yeah so tmv and then going to the other
point um would a lot of plants be having
you know non your asymptomatic tmv
infections circulating so far we haven't
seen a high incidence of that in in a
lot of our testing
that's not to say it isn't out there
however tnb is still going to need
um so while it is transmitted by touch
it's still going to need a wound or some
sort of entry into the plant um so
when insects
infect plants they cause a wound and
then the virus which is circulating
either in their gut or salivary glands
or on their mouth parts is then
inserted into that wound
so
when it's you know when we have these
spread of infections and facilities it's
often because of
poor sterilization practices with with
pruning tools
or
leaving
cut you know cut cut plant material
that might have phloem you know sap
that's available to then transmit to
another wound
so as far as like having tmb circulate
because of that
provided you know if you're if you go
for a smoke break touching a cigarette
come back so long as you're not touching
a wound on a plant that wouldn't
necessarily
confer an infection
but yeah so far we haven't had you know
i mean the overwhelming amount of
positives we've had have been for
hopliting thyroid and not necessarily
for um so our tmp positives have been
relatively low
that's really interesting so if we um if
we table that discussion for now because
since there's not a lot more on tmv uh
you know you mentioned tops like hops
latent virus a couple times
um yeah can you talk a little bit about
some of the symptoms associated with it
you talked about mode of transmission
one question i had then this seems to be
a good reason not to
keep any of your leaf matter or biomass
in the room itself and
also potentially avoid having other
plants that could be vectors for viruses
in the room too as in cover crops or and
just be very careful with banker plants
trap plants things like that
right yeah so yeah that's a great point
about trap plants and um it's a i mean
it's a good practice in theory but yeah
if you have to be careful with um with
the spread of possibly you know
you know an aphid going from a trap
plant or something like that to uh to
one of your your crop plants um so this
is something to be aware of um and
regarding just the
the plant matter you know as clean as
you can keep it the better obviously i
know you know larger the facility is the
harder it can be to have all of the
floors swept routinely and they must get
pruned fairly frequently
but anything that has you know phloem
tap
could be a potential reservoir for a
virus infection
um so you have the hop blatant
so hobland's interesting it's not a
virus it's a viroid so there is a
hot-blatant virus but that's
not been found to infect cannabis it's a
specific i think to hops only but
the viroid is
they're unique from viruses
in that they don't
have any
protein coding regions of their genome
and their genome is is incredibly tiny
it's about 120th the size of a plant
virus so these are tiny pieces of rna
that's circular
they don't code for any proteins or
anything like that
and so
they're sort of
insidious in that regard is that they um
they don't they they can they can get
into a plant relatively easily because
there's a small
so any any sort of wound infection they
can get in
um so far i don't
think that it's primarily by mechanical
injury that they're transmitted so
hopefully in thyroid and viroids in
general
typically are primarily transmitted by
mechanical injury
so you know the exchange of phloem sap
however they can be transmitted through
seeds pollen
and
so hot blatant viroid this is the kind
of sort of academic study that i'd love
to see done in cannabis but in hops
um hoplaton thyroid
was very minimally transmitted by seed i
think it was less than
about eight percent in the publication
that was in 1990
um and so hoplane viroid is very low
seed transmission and hops
however that said the two ways to get
rid of it would be either either seed
or tissue culture and the seed method
you should be aware that it's possible
that it's still there so you should just
carefully uh you know proceed with
caution if you're if you're going to try
and get rid of operations blatant virus
via
via breeding
as far as symptoms so the things that
you're looking for
are typically going to be stunted or
slow growth is sort of the main one and
so
we see a lot of horizontal growth and so
the the
shoot apical meristem seems to not grow
very much and you get this lateral
growth and so it kind of looks like
depending on how many branches you have
sort of like a trident almost you have
two long branches on the side and one in
the middle uh just slow growth it's
really obvious when you compare
asymptomatic versus symptomatic
operating next to each other how slow
the growth is
and it's very horizontals or outward
growth
so stems are typically brittle
no that's really interesting are you
saying that you don't see the same level
of like phototropism as in the plant
growing towards the light or um
apical growth
right uh it still grows towards the
light it just sort of um the lateral
branches
grow upward and sort of overtake the the
the primary you know the shooting cool
oh
um so yeah it's sort of like this yeah
as i said sort of a
sort of a trident shape where the middle
one is is lower than the outer two but
they do still grow towards the light but
it is
so your secondary branches are growing
at a right faster rate i'm picturing
like uh
candelabra for people yeah that are
listening because we can't really have
visuals here okay all right so i i get
what you're saying okay yeah
yeah so it's and i mean but overall the
plant is just much smaller than a
symptomatic infection too so um so it's
pretty it's pretty apparent when you
have a really symptomatic hop latent
infection
and then relief symptoms
yeah yeah so we also get
malformed or chlorotic leaves so it's
release sclerosis
yellowing or or pale leaves
and then
you have stems that are often brittle so
they can snap when you brush against
them
and then as far as the flower you get
very reduced flower
mass so the the buds are going to be
smaller and they're usually very really
leafy
so you get these loose uh loose buds
that are it's a pain to trim so
um lots of leaves and then the buds
lower trichomes just sort of lower yield
in general
wow you just described
you just described like every symptom
related to anything from watering
environment nutrients yeah
man none of those things are really
specific enough
and that's tricky about a lot of viruses
is they have really overlapping symptoms
some of them appear to be you know they
could be for all intents and purposes
look like a nutrient deficiency
um so chlorosis of leaves obviously
there's a lot of viruses that have like
intervenal chlorosis which could look
like a magnesium deficiency but
it's not and so one of the things
that you need to consider when you're
looking at your plants is is the
distribution of the symptoms uniform
that is to say
does
your entire crop look the exact same and
then you could maybe pinpoint something
like a nutrient deficiency or is it sort
of irregular you know sort of an
irregular distribution where one or two
plants are
showing the symptoms whereas the one
next to it may not so the plants won't
always show the symptoms if they have
the virus
so we often get asymptomatic hoplite
viroid infections and so you'll have an
asymptomatic plant extra symptomatic
plant and will be a very clear
difference in the
size of the growth of the plant and then
one may have the chlorosis whereas the
others does not so
you're right it can be you know i mean
it's difficult to just walk in and see
like that's obviously a virus unless
it's sort of the one plant out of ten
and then you can be like okay it's
probably a virus because it's only
affecting this one plant
um and i don't see any obvious
insect or pathogen such as a fungi so
yeah it's um
challenging
sure and just to present a contrarian
view there um yeah it could also be you
know uh
essentially you know what you're saying
is if you see it
in one place in the room it's more
likely to be a virus than something
that's affecting you know your whole
crop and that allows you to guess maybe
it's a
it's a virus uh it could also be you
know a fan your lighting the way the
airflow is through that space so there's
a bunch of things you still have to
check off
and it all because also could be uniform
in the sense that maybe all your plants
are infected it sounds like so yeah
um yeah so yeah so what do i do as a
grower you know i want to talk about
some of these other viruses but um you
really got me thinking like okay
if i see something going in my room i
can't identify i want to check virus off
the list um or hops late in this case um
what do we do like what if we were if we
wanted to work directly with you guys at
uh three rivers um how would that work
yeah so we have a testing kit that we
would send out to you
so the testing kit is a test tube
uh small testing filled with a
stabilization buffer so this
the vast majority of plant viruses are
single stranded rna viruses and so
that's got i think approximately 75 of
known plant viruses are rna-based so rna
is not a particularly stable molecule as
i mentioned with cucumber mosaic virus
it's very unstable so they're unstable
um so
this buffer helps preserve you know any
viruses that may be in the sample and so
when you do the sampling the
if you have symptomatic tissue
you would take
a small clip of that symptomatic tissue
so we only need 100 milligrams somewhere
between 50 and 100 milligrams so for
frame of reference that's roughly the
size of a penny a nickel you know so
sort of between a penny and a quarter i
guess would be the
range of a leaf that you would need to
chop up and the more you're able to chop
it up into little bits the better that
the
stabilization solution can penetrate the
tissue and preserve any any virus that's
there
you then put that in the fridge
overnight it allows for the the buffer
again the stabilization buffer to
penetrate the tissue and preserve any
rna viruses that might be there
so then after it's been in the fridge
overnight you would just mail it back to
us
at which point i would then run the the
pcr
so from there i just extract the rna
and we do an rt pcr to to test for for
the uh to detect any viruses that might
be present in that sample
if you don't have symptomatic tissue but
you are concerned of an infection or
you're doing routine testing just to be
sure
um you would use young t lease tissue
so just an emerging leaf
same protocol from there 50 to 100
milligrams so about a penny to a quarter
size of the leaf close to the petiol is
also is also
better
so these viruses typically travel in the
phloem or the plasmodesmata between
cells
so they're pretty pretty much going
where the nutrients go so
oftentimes we find better diagnostics in
the young tissue that said i mean if
your symptomatic tissue is an older
tissue and that that we found that works
just fine as well so very small amount
of tissue
because it's from a leaf
and it's destroyed in this buffer so
there's very very it's considered hemp
for the purposes of delivery
because there's little to no thc and
it's a very small sample um so we don't
have any any um
we haven't had any troubles there
i'm glad you touched on the mail aspect
because that was something that i
brought up with your colleagues and they
mentioned that the sample is destroyed
essentially um
by the way it's a biological sample yeah
and uh
so there's no real risk there as far as
you guys are concerned um
one question is what does this sort of
thing cost approximately i know there's
a range based on volume but
right yeah so we do offer bulk discounts
on orders over 10 but right now for an
individual hot latent test it's 75
canadian so that's about a 20
discount for u.s customers that's um
because yeah we are based
out of british columbia out of vancouver
british columbia but we have a facility
a testing facility in washington and
we're opening up one in california
um the
75 for the hop latent that's about 60 us
if you want to do the full virus panel
which we test for eight viruses
currently
and that's expanding sort of we've got
our ear to the ground regarding
professors working on finding more
viruses and we're looking into some of
our cells that that um appear to have
virus symptoms that don't appear to be
one of the major ones that we have so
far so um so it's expanding so we have
about eight yes we have eight viruses
now in the full panel
and that costs 150 canadian
which is approximately 120 us
okay and uh
you know how many samples would i need
to send in to get a really good idea of
if my plants have
you know a particular virus can i send
in one sample if i think i just see it
in one area or if i just want to test a
room i realize sending in one sample of
a room that's asymptomatic or
potentially
free isn't really going to
you know be statistically significant
right right so it's it's um
so yeah if you have symptomatic plants
obviously the symptomatic plants should
be tested
from there uh typically
for statistically significant you'd have
to do a lot of testing to get sort of to
a 90 95 confidence interval you'd have
to do you know a significant amount of
testing so it's it's good to sort of
identify where the possible entry points
of the infection might be so if you
think it came from a mother like if you
have a really widespread infection it
may be coming from your mother plant so
it's good a good place to test
um
to see if you're spreading it through
through propagation if you think it came
in from
sort of an acid infection you know if
it's only in one part of the facility
plants sort of spread out around that
area are a great place to start
so if you have a few symptomatic plants
you can start there and then if you get
some if we find positives you can then
expand the search to figure out the
extent of the infection
one thing that's important to note
is that we
with it with a hot blatant thyroid
sometimes the virus tighter is too low
so the concentration of the virus is is
there but it's just too low to detect
with even with the most sensitive pcr
so we typically recommend
that you do multiple tests to ensure a
negative
so we have and it's it's sort of
industry practice to do three to four
tests
um on a negative to ensure that it's
negative
and we try and you know you want to
spread those two
approximately two weeks apart
so some viruses also are more prevalent
in certain stages of plant development
and so that's why we use the younger
tissues the younger leaf tissues because
it's sort of one of the best testing
locations just from from other crops
for uh for the development of the plant
but um so yeah so going back to your
question
it's gonna it just sort of depends on
whether you're seeing symptoms whether
you're just doing a confirmation to
assure your your facility is clean um
how big your facility is um but
obviously wherever your your your
cloning from your mother stocks those
will probably be your um if you have a
clean if you think your facility is
clean um doing routine testing on those
mother stocks is a good idea just to
make sure that they are clean and then
if you have something like an aphid
infection you should definitely cons you
mean it's worth thinking about whether
or not those aphids may have brought in
a virus
and so so testing
uh around where the day if an infection
was first observed things like that
and then lastly if you're bringing new
genetics in um
it's really good practice to quarantine
those not put them straight next to your
you know not not put them straight into
production but quarantine any new
genetics
and test those you know multiple times
just to make sure that they come up
negative before putting those into
production um so you don't spread you
know from from from a new new or a new
variety that you bring in
okay you guys are primarily testing
plants and veg too is that correct
i'm sorry what's that you're primarily
testing plants that are still in their
vegetative state um
right flower right yeah that's primarily
what's yeah that's right
yeah so this is yeah primarily for
vegetative growth um yeah please please
don't try and send us anything from the
flower um because yeah the uh
the fact that we're using leaf tissue
and uh tissue by the petiole it's very
it's it's little to no thc which which
makes it
hemp for for regulatory purposes
so yeah right now we're not doing so we
do offer
beyond just virus testing we do offer
fungal testing too for for pcr or
identification of certain fungi but um
we don't we only do that for vegetative
tissues so root and root stem and leaf
okay yeah i asked that because you know
a lot of these things
i know it's really easy to have a
healthy looking veg plant and then a lot
of these issues seem to crop up in flour
uh especially late flower that's sort of
like the test for how good of a grower
you are in a lot of ways i feel like so
you know are we is it pretty obvious
in veg or what like let's say i noticed
an issue in flower would i then go back
to my next round of clones and that's
where i would want to test and just say
okay these these are done i'm not i'm
not trying to find out if the virus is
in these
my flowering crop for this cycle
um you know how would you approach that
got it um yeah so
you can yeah you approach it one two
ways and it's it's the the way that you
had mentioned is uh not a not a bad
method so if you think there's a virus
and you're you're at the flowering stage
and testing your next uh batch of clones
uh you can start there we can you know
we can still test uh leaf material from
a flowering crop
um
it's yeah i mean i mean because we're
using you know
as long as it's leaf you know far far
away from the flower and the thc content
should still be pretty low um but yeah
typically we prefer to test stuff from
vegetative plants so the next round of
plants would be would be a good place to
start
um
regarding
the infection levels so oftentimes so so
for something like lettuce chlorosis
virus
they found that the
infected
the infected clones developed symptoms
much earlier than the
uh originally you know the patient zero
so to speak the originally infected
mother
so
when you are making the clones from
whatever plant you you
suspect as a virus
you may actually see the symptoms
earlier in the next in the next batch so
that's sort of another
test i guess you could say if you did
see something virus-like towards the
flowering stage you may end up seeing
symptoms earlier in the next
growth cycle or or the one following
that so these these problems the level
of virus typically
compounds over time and so
yeah the uh as far as the testing goes
we can test either but um you know
before you go through a whole another
grow cycle it's uh it's probably a good
idea to try and test some of those those
early early plants from from the next
gem
okay and and i know your numbers are
probably skewed a little bit because
people um
you know are more likely to reach out if
they if they have an issue
but yeah you know what approximately
what percentage do you think of the test
that you guys run come back with some
virus or viroid
so
you're right that our testing numbers
are skewed um towards people who think
they have symptoms and we are still sort
of early
in our commercial aspect so we started
selling tests back in march we've been
three months in
and
for growers sending us in there's only
been one time where everything came up
negative um so we're typically finding
hot blatant uh you know in a lot of
growers in the pacific northwest
regarding how many strains
um per
um
regarding how many strains per per
grower it's it sort of varies uh
depending on whether or not they they
have a worse infection um or not and to
sort of by random sampling and sort of
our sampling numbers are probably too
small to get any sort of meaningful
numbers from there but yeah we are
seeing you know the people that send us
some symptomatic samples um all but one
so far has come up positive for
something mostly hot blade
so it's pretty prevalent
that's really interesting um
that just that kind of surprises me a
little bit but um
yeah and i mean it really just go to
your point that it's sort of skewed at
this point because we are you know
mostly having people reach out with
something that's symptomatic sure but it
tells you there's a level of prevalence
that's higher than i would have
speculated before talking to you um
absolutely yeah in the northwest and i
mean it's it's known sort of in
california too it's the west coast i
guess and i mean hopley and viroid is
worldwide i mean it was found and i
can't remember when it was originally i
beat and hops i think 70s or 80s but i
mean it has a worldwide distribution
um i think this reports populating
positives and cannabis coming from
from uh i think it's new z12 so it's
it's and we're trying to start doing
some testing uh for for you know other
other areas um but it's uh it's
definitely there and i mean part of the
problem is that
it's not been
you know because because canada's
finally coming out of uh out of the
shadow so to speak um we now have the
ability to test for it so previously you
might have just assumed
some sort of variation
due to any number of other other
reasons you know we had mentioned
earlier how it can be
tricky to just walk in and point out a
plant say that one has a virus
because a lot of times the symptoms can
overlap with other things
and also the the symptoms of a virus
sometimes don't manifest until an
environmental stress occurs so you may
just chalk it up to the environmental
stress and
before you know before now when things
were sort of operating in the shadows it
was easier to do that because you didn't
even have the tools to test for the
viruses so
um
it's
not uncommon i mean as other industries
where especially with clonally
propagated crops
until you until they started looking for
viruses they didn't realize how big the
problem was so potato and strawberries
or industries
um that had a lot of virus issues uh
prior to
sort of
industry-wide testing practices so it is
somewhat alarming the first time you
hear it but it's not really
all that unsurprising when you sort of
look at sort of the landscape of
agriculture and just how
sure how easy it is to accidentally
spread these things and and how you know
genetics were just sort of being passed
around previously okay okay so if we see
in a forum someone posted a photo uh
which
you know like facebook or instagram and
people start saying oh that's tmv oh
that's hot blatant viroid
you can pretty much uh
shut them down and tell them there's no
way they can possibly know that from a
from a picture it actually takes genetic
testing
is that right yeah so you could yeah
some molecular testing so you can also
do not for hot latent thyroid but for
some viruses you can do protein testing
it's less sensitive uh it's called elisa
that's an enzyme linked immunoabsorbance
i forget about the letter
spectroscopy so it's a chlorometric
assay that basically measures
um the amount of protein virus viral
protein present in a sample
but essentially you have to send into a
lab i guess is what i'm yeah what i want
yeah out to people
so that they don't uh they don't fall
for that i guess in that regard um right
there are i mean i think
there's one sentence the least mosaicism
that one's pretty
i mean there's very few causes of sort
of that kind of variegation and a leaf
other than a virus so that one but i
mean then you don't know which virus
because lots of viruses cause leaks
mosaics
um and we don't see that we haven't have
any scientific literature to see that in
tmp yet can that be genetic though too
or is that always viral related
so
there are tropical plants that are
naturally variegated with sort of a
mosaic-like leaf um but
it's very rare for that to be you know
as far as as far as cannabis goes
there's no reports that i know of of a
specific gene that if it gets you know
mutated causes mosaicism so
and even if there was it would only
affect a small portion of the plant
unless it happened very very very very
early in that plant's development it
also would only affect that one plant so
to chalk it up to genetics is
far less likely than the odds of a virus
so okay and it's so it's so
unlikely that you can you can almost
rule it out but uh because i don't have
any any scientific information regarding
you know genes that cause leaf mosaics
and cannabis i don't want to just
just sort of
rule it out completely but
okay uh yeah another question i had for
you are you have you aware of any
uh viruses that could possibly cause a
plant to hermaphrodite or produce seeds
in a female plant
that's a great question um so i don't
know of any particular virus that would
cause that however
you know i mean hermaphroditis
or hermaphroditicism that's my food
it's often
triggered by
environmental stressors
um so
you know i mean there's certain strains
that are more predispos predispose oh
man i'm struggling where it's
predisposed to hermaphrodites than
others sure
but still it usually takes an
environmental cue to trigger that
so the virus if you had a viral
infection
it could make the plant more stressed
and result in that but at this point you
know i don't have any scientific data to
back that up
it's going to be
i think that will be an interesting area
of study for for some of these academic
institutions that are working on
cannabis now
yeah so uh you know we've talked a
little bit about hops latent and
uh
tmv are there other
viruses that you know you'd like are
viroids that you think are worth
highlighting
uh yeah i mean
so
they
i mean okay there's a whole group um of
viruses the viroids so far there's no
other
viroid found in cannabis as of yet
there's only 40
roughly 40 viroids worldwide it's sort
of another area sort of growing now now
that people are looking for it with
next-gen sequencing
but for viruses
the ones that we know are symptomatic
would be so alfalfa mosaic virus causes
leaf mosaicism and stunting
it's a pretty common virus so you know
agriculturally that one's relevant
cucumber mosaic virus is another
worldwide distribution virus very common
in the agricultural field
cucumber mosaic has been shown to cause
weak mosaic and dwarfing in cannabis
um
these are you know alfalfa mosaic and
cannabis or sorry alfalfa mosaic and
cucumber mosaic uh
both can be transmitted by aphids
um but then also mechanical transmission
and so
uh i think
you know i mean that the the
transmission
mode is important here because if you
have an aphid infection then you might
have you know alfalfa mosaic or cucumber
mosaic uh
lettuce chlorosis virus has been found
in cannabis recently in israel
so far we haven't had any positives here
for lettuce sclerosis and i don't know
of any north american lettuce corrosive
virus in cannabis however lettuce
clorosis virus was originally found in
lettuce in california
so we're sort of just on the lookout for
that one
but the different
lettuce chlorosis virus the initial
infection the natural infection is by
white flies
so that's sort of a less common vector
for us in the cannabis field so that one
um you know unless we we get
uh i think it's in hotter climates
tropical climates that have sort of more
whitefly
uh
problems
but in the greenhouse i don't know if
that one's going to be
you know we haven't seen it yet teletub
chlorosis virus is something that causes
uh stunting in early development
but if it's a later later infection then
yellowing chlorosis
some necrosis drooping foliage foliage
there's sort of a fat plant
um
there's
i think in the in the southwest
they're starting to see more beet curly
top virus so this one's a little
different than most plant viruses this
one's a dna
based virus not an rna based one
but that one's transmitted initially by
leaf hoppers so that's sort of a
specific vector to sort of
tropical regions also so they're hot
drier drier areas of the southwest i
think in colorado they have more be
curly top virus than elsewhere
to be curly top
is going to cause symptoms that are
again sort of you know similar to most
it's uh you know leaf colorosis leaf
curling the yellowing of leaves necrosis
um so yeah a lot of these viruses have
sort of overlapping symptoms
um
there's there's some other major ones so
tobacco streak virus tobacco ring spot
virus they known to cause symptoms in
cannabis
but so far these other viruses we've
seen a much lower positive rate for so
um they haven't been as prevalent
but for tobacco ring spot virus that
one's transmitted by nematodes so this
will be soil
soil based vector so it's not as likely
in a greenhouse to get a natural
infection for tobacco ring spot it's
more of an outdoor grow problem
but again all of these viruses can be
transmitted mechanically so if you're if
you're
if you're not fairly sterilizing your
pruning tools effectively you can
transmit or spread it um
if it already exists in a plant
so this this means if you are working on
one plant you want to sterilize your
equipment before moving to the next
plant um it's pretty common practice in
a lot of horticultural situations that i
don't see carried out as as prevalently
in um
cannabis
yeah so we definitely encourage uh
strongly encourage our clients and
growers to to sort of
take on some of those common practices
from other agricultural industries such
as that um
that's
you know the the the lack of sort of um
sterilization is probably how some of
these things spread in the first place
and and so doing sort of due diligence
to try and limit the spread um
that way if you do get a natural
infection which is less common you know
the primary mode of infection we're
seeing is mostly just from clonal
propagation and spreading it around so
the natural infection seems seem
less common and so if you're doing the
due diligence of sterilizing your tools
between plants and you're not spreading
it
limiting the infection then
then you stand a better chance of of
keeping these things sort of out of your
facility and then once you're in once
they are in your facility and it's
relatively easy to manage once you sort
of put in these sort of sterile
practices to avoid spreading it
and cleaning up your genetics either
with tc or bringing in new clean
genetics
um so
they're totally manageable if you do end
up getting a positive which is another
thing i sort of like to mention with
people who do
end up having a positive is it's not you
know it's not time to panic it's it's
just it takes some time to clean things
up but um
it's totally manageable
now in other crops do you see
resistance to viroids in specific
cultivars or varieties
is that a possibility in cannabis
yeah so so for viruses absolutely
there are certain
cultivars that may have higher levels of
resistance to
a natural
infection um
so the again this is i said this a lot
but it's one of those areas that would
be it's going to be really really
wonderful to have academic institutions
begin to take up some of this research
because um it is entirely possible but
it takes a lot of you know a lot of
effort and research money to sort of
hunt down any cultivars that might have
improved resistance um so you can sort
of see that as sort of a fishing
expedition where you're going out in the
world trying to find any any cultivar
that might have improved resistance to a
natural infection
um the alternative which a lot of
industries use is genetic you know
modification to to just
skip all the fishing and just improve
resistance right away
but obviously there's a lot of you know
sort of
backlash to that still
so naturally finding strength resistant
i know there's efforts for fungal
pathogens i know of an effort
to find resistance for powdery mildew at
a academic institution that's working on
that
essentially what they do is they um they
take a resistant cultivar that doesn't
have as frequent of an infection
uh and then they can do genome-wide
association studies so they look at the
genome and try and find the obvious
similarities among those that are
resistant compared to those that are not
and try and figure out you know gene or
gene usually it's multiple genes but try
and find uh reasons why you know trade
those traits are conferred
so it's totally possible it's sort of a
longer term you know hope and project
that definitely requires sort of the
enlistment of
sort of academic institutions to do some
of the basic research behind that
uh to sort of speed it along
but it's possible
um viroids
the viruses viruses have you know sort
of three steps to their infection you
know it's the
entry to the cell whether it be
by an insect or other
and then releasing their protein coat
which releases the genome into the cell
and then replication of that
genome by
most often by plant proteins will
replicate the genome
by you know just by happenstance
some some plant viruses can replicate
their own genome
but it's it's fewer i believe and then
from there it's it's trans it's moving
itself from one cell to another and so
those three steps you can you can have
traits of the plant that are able to
stop it in its tracks
one of the main ways the plants do this
is
by silencing the rna of the virus so so
they have
a way to recognize double-stranded rna
and target it for either
degradation or prevent it from being
translated into a protein
so that's sort of the method that's most
commonly employed in genetic engineering
is
is improving the silencing specific to a
virus
so it depends on the virus and how it's
being moved from cell to cell
and things like that as to where you
want to stop it in its tracks and how
there might be traits that you can
select for
viroids a little different because they
don't
they're so tiny the viroids can enter
small they can thyroids can travel sort
of spell the cell via phloem and and
plasma does not
without the same problems that viruses
incur because they're larger
and then viroids typically reside in the
nucleus where the plant host just
replicates it
um and then it sort of just diffuses
from there
um there are some viroids that exist in
the chloroblast and are replicated there
but there's less of those mostly during
the nucleus but um in order to stop the
replication of a viroid you would need
to have um the rna silencing mechanism
of the plant
tailored to target that viroid and
prevent it from from from being
replicated
so silence it essentially that's a part
of what's called the rna interference
program implants so they have proteins
that can specifically recognize certain
sequences
and they and they can uh silence them
from being replicated so
that's sort of the method that you would
do that for viroids and i i mean you
could do with genetic engineering i
don't know
i have not come across and i could
probably look i i think i haven't come
off now i think you covered it that's
getting a little beyond uh
sorry
my academic level um
so just just to kind of cover some of
the highlights uh you know from today
just to make sure
uh people catch it um essentially these
viruses do exist in cannabis
they are mainly trans plant or
transported by
pests as a vector and also
mechanical through like pruners clippers
humans things like that
um
if you want to get it tested you guys
offer those the testing i'm hoping to
work with you guys soon on that i was on
the phone with a couple of your other
guys there about getting it set up on
our website too so i'm excited about
that
um
to offer that to our our customers um
if you do have
uh a virus or viroid in on your plants
um your real options there are to take
it to seed which may help but not is not
a foolproof option or do tissue culture
which is a podcast that i also just
recently uh recorded
with someone from your company as well
um and that's really the only surefire
way to get a clean plant
correct did that cover unfortunately
you covered it all and then yeah just
unfortunately there's just no chemical
or
you know there's no vaccines for plants
so um so yeah tissue culture and seed
are the only way and some viruses still
are transmitted via seed so depending on
what it is we can we can work with you
there um that's the options but yeah
that is that's that's the gist of it
oh and that this is not necessarily
something that can be visually diagnosed
in a lot of cases
yeah yeah you may have
a strong
you may have some strong supporting
evidence that it could be a virus but
you have no idea which one unless you
get it tested um because they often have
very similar symptoms across the viruses
well how important if we know we have a
virus how important is it that we
identify the virus i mean does it really
matter at that point isn't the treatment
going to be the same
true um so
you know immediately if you think you
have a virus it's best practice to
quarantine that plant so it's not
spreading the infection to neighboring
plants
however
plants will often go asymptomatic so if
you just remove the symptomatic plant it
doesn't necessarily mean you've removed
the entire infection in your facility
so getting a positive diagnosis would
tell you a yes it's definitely a virus
and then b you should consider doing
some testing on on neighboring or other
plants in that facility um to see if you
have asymptomatic plants there and try
and get a handle on the spread so it is
still a valuable tool um
and then
it does give you some information
regarding whether or not you can use
seed to get rid of it
or you're stuck with tc because some of
the viruses are transmitted via seed
yeah and i would i would add i wouldn't
recommend anyone makes an assumption
they have a virus i mean identifying
your problem is something that is the
most important thing in terms of
figuring out your mode of action or
treatment i mean i know with insects
suzanne has drilled into my head that uh
you really have to identify the insect
even know how you're going to approach
uh you know solving the problem because
the treatments vary so much um
i would say the same with viruses
because it could turn out to be some
other form of plant stress that just
displays in a way that looks similar
enough that you may be making the wrong
assumption
that's true it's true and obviously
nutrient deficiencies are not really
something that
we expect you know i mean growers
usually have a really strong handle on
their nutrients and things like that but
um
yeah it would it would be
unwise to just assume
you have a virus without getting a
positive diagnosis from a lab
to then you know give you
full information that you can go forward
making the right decisions for your
facility
great well was there anything else that
you want to share regarding uh you know
viruses with our listening audience
no i think that's about it
all right well hey i really appreciate
your time today i i learned a lot and
enjoyed the phone call um
maybe we can talk again soon as you guys
uh you know discover more in the in the
world of research here
yeah thank you very much for having me
on today i really enjoyed our
conversation i really appreciate you um
helping us spread the word and i look
forward to talking again when uh when we
have some more information about what
the full scope of viruses that are
threats to cannabis are so i look
forward to talking in the future
[Music]
that was dr jack muns and you were
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast i'm your host tad
hussey of kiss organics if you are
interested in virus testing you can now
find it available on the kiss organics
website under the products section and
don't forget to check out the product
page at www.kisorganics.com
for links to the websites and topics we
covered in the podcast just click on the
learn tab then podcast
also if you haven't already please take
a moment and leave us a comment or
review on whatever platform you listen
on i do take the time to read them all
and appreciate the feedback you can also
follow us on instagram
to stay up to date on the latest podcast
releases and information thanks for
listening