[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation in
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge our
guest this week is Rennell Anderson
she's been a speaker panelist and think
take contributor for a number of
organizations universities and other
symposiums related to the education and
advancement of biochar and sound
environmental practices she carries the
message of sustainability tangible
methods to combining climate change as
well as the vast agricultural and
environmental benefits of the
manufacturing and implementation of
biochar she stays on the forefront of
newest innovations and advancements of
this rapidly adopted technology Brunel
is the founder of blackout biochar and
also president of the u.s. biochar
initiative blackout biochar is the
leader in the industry in regards to
university studies and research and
today Rennell will be sharing with us
some of the ways to both make and
evaluate the quality of your biochar in
honor of our guest this week I'd like to
offer 15% off of black owl biochar no
coupon code needed you'll see the sale
price on the website if you go to
www.hsn x-com and search for biochar
this is a great opportunity if you've
been waiting to try a high-quality
biochar in your garden or growing
environment without further ado though
here's this week's podcast all right
well I'd like to start asking you first
off a little bit about what is biochar
like how would you define it and can you
talk a little bit about its relationship
with Terra Preta in some of that history
sure biochar is biomass in some form and
then and it can be any form of biomass
anything from sewage sludge to
unfortunately dead creatures to
grasses and woods that are carbonized in
the limited oxygen atmosphere there's a
variety of ways it can be carbonized but
you end up with typically a product
called ash biochar perhaps water and in
some cases bio oil so it's a very
general description for what biochar is
once the American Association of
fertilizer Control Officers got in there
they've narrowed the definition for
agriculture and horticulture down to
wood based biochar and so that would be
wood that's been thermo chemically
processed from being wood into being
more of a charcoal type product high
carbon black charcoal looking product
it's related to the Terra Preta because
in those days in South America what it
took science to figure out a long time
why there were certain areas of real
high productivity and agricultural
success and therefore population success
what they found was that they had been
taking their excess biomass and putting
it into pits which made them low oxygen
and then creating these fires
underground and then using that material
mixed with pottery shards that would
have minerals in them and creating a
really high nutrient high soil organic
carbon soil that's lasted for thousands
of years and not only that it kind of
grows additional soil with time so that
fertility supported large populations
and it's only something that we're
really about in the last decade or so so
just to simplify the the definition
essentially we're taking wood and we're
paralyzing it or we're heating it to a
really
temperature but with very low oxygen
conditions is that correct that's right
okay and so the only real relationship
with Terra Preta is the fact that it has
sort of this loose association with this
area that there's no other relationship
with the South America beyond that we're
trying to kind of replicate this using
more advanced technology is that correct
yes yes we learned from looking at what
they had done and you know modern
agriculture has in tilling and the way
it's been done most of the carbon in the
soil has been released I think the
carbon stores have been reduced by about
60% plants are dependent on that the
whole soil ecosystem is diminished when
the carbon levels are diminished so
enhancing the carbon levels ie that
being the most important component of a
biochar that they learned from studying
the soils they very rich soils of the
Terra Preta okay and how did you get
into this exactly I know you own a peony
farm with your husband and have been
doing that for a long time and I'm
looking at a photo here which I'll add
to the podcast page that shows some of
the trials that you ran initially can
you talk a little bit how you got into
biochar in the first place yes that was
interesting we had this farm we were
going to develop the field so it was
sort of in a natural state with a lot of
weeds and I wanted to do everything
organically for a lot of reasons but
among them was that I'm allergic to a
lot of the chemistry that's used and in
normal farming I get asthma attacks so
we were going to make this an organic
farm and I read I had been through heart
a culture school but I read every book I
could find on organic farming and in
every article and I came across an
article about biochar and then it it
really sparked my interest
so I we spent I spent a few months
trying to run some biochar down because
this was way back in 2009-10 and there
was no commercial biochar so to speak
available at the time what did you find
in terms of some of the benefits of
using biochar we'll talk a little bit
more about how to tell different types
of biochar and inputs and all that but
what are just some of the general
benefits if you're using a high-quality
biochar product I'll answer that real
quickly but I want to say that when we
put biochar en we were just going off of
this one article and it was a leap of
faith we were able to get some what
would not really be considered biochar
in this day and age but we we ended up
having this bumper crop of flowers in
the first year and you're supposed to
have three years of waiting before you
get a bumper crop of flowers so we've
got enhanced growth that we got hearty
growth we got disease disease prevention
or suppression we we've had the field
inspected by the University and they
can't find any of the typical normal
expected fungal diseases on on the
plants we got by with a little less
water but the main thing was the vigor
and the speed of the plant growth and
the productivity when we planted that
field I simultaneously did a hundred and
fifty pot randomized study that combined
fertilizer and biochar and potting soil
and then what you know controls for
everything and we found that potting
soil and biochar outperformed potting
soil and fertilizer which I think is
there's some dependency on the biochar
to get a result like that but the
results were run through WSU's
statistical analysis machinery
they found out that in every case where
biochar was used versus the control we
got 70% more so more 70% more biomass
70% more root mass 70% more blossoms and
on and on so that was pretty convincing
evidence that the biochar was
responsible for some very positive
outcomes okay and just for those
listeners who are not in Washington WSU
stands for Washington State University
and they are one of the bigger
agricultural colleges here in Washington
just to clarify so when we say biochar
it has this connotation that there's
biology in it but when we get biochar
and we're charring this wood there's no
biology we have to inoculate it or
charge it with something is what do you
recommend for that okay let me just say
this would the starting product that we
use is virgin wood it's important that
whatever you use it's not a treated wood
and I think it's important to use wood
there's a there's a big industry and
chicken manure biochar it has different
properties it's a high ash content thing
but it has different properties than a
wood biochar so agreeing that you don't
want to use treated wood you just want
your virgin and we use the waste part of
a tree like limbs and tops and bases of
harvested trees we don't use any trees
for our our process but anyway in that
the word biochar the bio came from it
has to be made from biomass because most
charcoal historically was made from coal
at that point it's not considered
biomass anymore it's considered a fossil
fuel so biomass indicates it was a
living matter
so why you have to pre charge it is that
when you process it it vaporizes the
things that turn into gas
and one of those important constituents
is the nitrogen that's held within the
planet in it vaporizes it goes up as
nitrogen oxide and so if you're not
processing it correctly you can add to
the burden of pollution air pollution so
there are there are some actually
multi-million dollar processing machines
out there that cannot get past the Air
Resources Board it's very much in our
case that is that gaseous component
there's some carbon there's some oxygen
there's some hydrogen and nitrogen all
that are are reformed into gases and
eliminated from from the wood lignin and
hemicellulose and cellulose that
survives in the form of carbon the
heating process those we burn to run a
boiler to create energy and other
machinery can create energy
were they finding that there's a little
bit of difficulty in getting a good
biochar product is when they are also
trying to make biofuel which is you you
get three Co products from the
processing of wood like this so if I
have that final product then how do I
prepare it for my soil or my garden so
like in our case in full disclosure we
use your product The Blackout biochar in
our biochar soil mix and we're soaking
it in fish hydrolysate for a few days
prior to mixing it into our soil mix as
a way to buffer some of the high carbon
in the biochar and also lower some of
the pH which we'll talk about here in a
little bit - but what it what are you
finding a lot of people are using to
inoculate that biochar because as I
understand it if I were to take raw
biochar and stick it right on to a soil
with a plan it could potentially pull
some of those nutrients because of the
high
on exchange capacity from that soil or
be more efficient at utilizing them than
the plant could be is that it's
particularly nitrogen that you find out
because when you do the same studies
with mixing like sand and woodchips and
biochar not adding any nutrients with
the nitrogen fixing plant you don't see
any slowdown our competition for for it
so it's basically pre charging it needs
to be adding back nitrogen but it
doesn't take a lot to offset it because
you can do it with compost tea you can
do it with organic fertilizers that are
low you know in numerically low like a
two to two it depends on the crop that
you're trying to grow and a lot of
people pre charge it with compost my
thought there is that you want to know
what what the compost is but typically
that's enough to pre charge it
fish is it's really high nitrogen
quality product the one thing I would
say is that you know this this product
in completely cooked or our charge that
have tar formation in the process that
recondense us on the chart
those chars tend to be a little oily and
they're hydrophobic or they will not
take on water or take on liquid
substance as well and actually they can
be toxic
ours is hydrophilic it likes water it
will absorb water and any liquid that
you put with it so that becomes part of
the particle then and is retained by the
particle and is available for plant use
okay so just to be clear backing up
really quick we can charge biochar with
just about anything including compost
the fish you said was fine in fact I
know some permaculture guys that are
there peeing on the their biochar is a
way to add
so it sounds like there's a lot of ways
to do it we've also run compost tea
through it sort of like a sieve is that
okay yeah and compost tea the
interesting thing about it we make
product like that but and it's fairly
popular it will lower the pH as well
almost anything almost anything that
you're gonna mix it with has a lower pH
lower than 7 so compost fish fertilizer
and most organic fertilizers on the
market if you actually were to get their
pH as their below so you get a balancing
of the pH though I want to say something
really quick here there is a difference
in the kinetics or the speed and the
amount of cation exchange with biochars
so in the case of ours if you didn't
pre-charge it but you put it in a system
with a dry fertilizer and the soil that
you're gonna plant in its kinetics for
grabbing the minerals that are needed
happens really fast so you come to
equilibrium in the soil real quickly and
so once it's satisfied itself for oxygen
and nitrogen
you know it's willing to give it all
back to the system charge that take a
lot longer to do that transaction are
pulling for a longer time and aren't
able to give it back so it's a unique I
think to our chart that it reacts so
quickly and that in the broader scope of
things what you're trying to do is make
sure that you have all the nutrients
necessary for the plant they're
simultaneously with the char if if not
infused into the char itself okay so you
brought up that there there is a
difference in quality with biochar not
all products are the same we have the
same issues in the compost tea industry
in terms of claims that people are
making and a variety of quality so one
of the things I'd like to talk about
first before we get into the lab
tests which i think are really important
is you'd given me some general ways for
a gardener or homeowner to test biochar
just on the surface level one of the
things he talked about was whether or
not it floated in water can you expand
on that a little bit yes it's gonna
float on water only like if it has oils
or tars attached to it or if it's
undercooked
because like wood chips will float in
water but they're not cooked if there's
oils that if this product can be
processed in several types of machinery
and if it happens to be a long tube as
this product goes down the long tube
those gases can reform into tars and
they actually end up on the chart itself
so one of the big tests is does it smell
does it taste does it leave a film on
your fingers that's something you want
boy because actually those stars can be
again be toxic so when you talk about
leaving some residue on your fingers I
know when I pick up your biochar and
frankly that's really the only biochar I
have experience with is it looks like I
have charcoal I mean it's not a it's not
a leaper se but it will leave residue so
we're not saying no rest you're saying
no oily residue it is no oil eNOS it's a
concern and that because it's oily it
will float if it's a poor char
okay so the quick easy test for a home
gardener or a grower would be to take a
small amount put it in a container of
water and see if it floats or not well
that's one test okay that will eliminate
that the potential toxicity of oils and
tars
in which you don't really want there not
a benefit um so should it should it sink
immediately to the bottom should it stay
a little bit suspended in the water well
some of it flow and some of it sink what
would be what would be an expectation
you want it to have it take it on fairly
fairly quickly Matt again is how porous
is it
it's a measure of porosity however
minerals are heavier and they will sink
first and fastest and they look very
much like char pyrolysis minerals which
do which are not the carbon fraction
that we're talking about that's so
important in all of this they will sink
really fast there okay so we're talking
about biochar quality and we talked
about a floating were there other ways
you can evaluate biochar
besides the floating test no without
looking at lab tests yeah we'll talk
about that next
it's really hard I will say I've had
people who who are speakers who are
quote-unquote experts who have a lot of
familiarity with these products and I
have had them come up and had what would
be considered just ash next to medium
grade biochar next to very high grade
biochar and said they all cost the same
which one do you want and and this is
one of the problems in the industry but
you know some of them people that should
be carrying the most knowledge all
pointed the whole ash pile it's it went
that so you can't really tell by looking
at it and that's unfortunate ash you
know I think people think ash is gray
and people think also that that biochars
but they take out of their fireplaces
residue with just its ash what they're
taking on their fireplace and the reason
they're getting a good response from man
is because of the calcium magnesium and
potassium that that's in the ash but
that's also raising the pH as part of
where the pH number comes from but in
the case of biochar that's commercially
made your your ash is gonna be black
it's not gonna be great or white okay so
you can't tell for the most part just
looking at you do a lab test one
question I brought up before the lab
test was particle size
so I know you do remediation work and
some other things around with a bio with
the biochar how what should we be
looking for in terms of particle size as
a as a grower I the particle size
depends on what you're trying to achieve
because if what you're trying to achieve
this better drainage in the soil or
actually if what you're trying to
achieve if you have a sandy soil and
what you want is more aggregation you
need a different bulk of the particles
to be larger right in because they will
actually help the soil perc in the other
case they they're forming soil
aggregates in the sand but the small
particles the real small ones are
actually eaten by worms if you're in a
field where there's worms the worms will
eat it they actually grow amazingly
large themselves but they excrete this
clear gluey substance that that helps
with the TEL thenis of the sandy soil as
well there and then of course then
they're moving around and they're
creating air flow and oxygen so they
like to eat it so with a smaller
particle size be better in terms of the
cation exchange capacity or the ability
of microbes to process some of the the
biochar would it be would it be faster
acting in terms of the plant growth and
healthy would see not necessarily it but
it it's true like when when we were
first started working with this people
would say and but we've tested all this
they would say our largest particles
aren't terribly large they're like four
millimeter particles but then it goes
down to microns in size and I like that
diversity of particle size because you
got different functions from
the different sizes but we do screen it
for particular purposes and there's some
groups of folks that want only the large
and some groups of folks at what only
the small you would expect with a
typical bio chart that the smaller the
particle size the more surface area you
would have yeah and surface area is
everything with biochar but
interestingly ours is so porous and so
it has so much surface area that
grinding it into a smaller unit does not
really increase the surface area it's
it's it's that much like the catacombs
you know it's just slice of orange it's
already so porous okay so particle size
in our case doesn't really work like
that but the general assumption would be
like if you were making it at home and
you have those larger chunks grinding
those down which should make for more
surface area and then therefore you get
more the transactions that you want in
the soil
ok so let's dive into these lab tests
and I'll post these on the podcast page
where people don't want to see them tea
but we'll we'll talk about this right
now here so you have these two tests
looking at two different samples of
biochar and the difference in numbers
and I wanted to have you point out some
of the more important figures on the
test as a comparison and this is really
the only way to effectively compare
biochar as I understand it is in order
to compare apples to apples is to
actually look at the tests I see the
first one on here is moisture can you
talk a little bit about what the
differences in numbers of what we should
look for is optimal ranges yeah so let
me just say this first this bottom half
for their where they're showing the
heavy metals this is required if you
want to get ordered organic
certification by any state or or armory
once you put biochar in the soil you
can't get it out so therefore you these
people that have created products with
tars and negative things
the producers have run into legal
problems because you can't get it out of
the soil so you can potentially although
this is rare but you do want to know
what the company what your biochar
consists of so this heavy metal section
down here shows you if you're low on
heavy metals or in this one report we
had fairly high arsenic it was a
different chart yeah you showed me over
here so yeah you have three samples here
and on one sample it looks like you
range from 1.5 all the way up to 18
point four and this is in ppm so it
looks like so there's a fairly big range
in terms of what what we're looking at
in terms of arsenic and some of these
other heavy metals so the first thing
you're suggesting people look at heavy
metal content that's the the most
important aspect to make sure you're not
bringing anything in your soil that's
dangerous right now
edibles things like spinach they mistake
cadmium for calcium they need a lot of
calcium and everybody tells you eat
spinach oh good calcium bet if there's a
lot of cadmium in your chart the plant
or in the soil anyway which there is in
California quite a bit of cadmium in the
soil plant will uptake it and you'll end
up beating it's not a good thing so I
guess the first rule of thumb is do no
harm moisture is indicative of just what
you're getting for your money so when
you buy biochar you're buying water
carbon and ash and in some combination
one thing we found is you've got to be
really careful about your water sourcing
because that water can be the place from
which this copper or lead or arsenic is
coming from so the these reports that
are produced about the heavy metals the
moisture can be the source of the
problem most producers produced biochar
comes out of the kiln super hot 500
something like that or Celsius or higher
and so what they do is they put
industrial water on it to to cool it
down and so it's very hard for them to
create a char that doesn't have about
50% weight of moisture so moisture is
like 50% on this report I don't know
what it is on that one but we have found
a way to bring it out of the kiln dry
let it cool and what water we add back
in is there is a death suppressant and
it's it's water that we we track the the
purity of okay so just to give listeners
a range here the black about char has
about 23 percent moisture content and
the the other ones that I'm looking at
here are range from 48 percent to 52
percent so you're getting about 25
percent more water which means you're
getting I assume 25 percent less product
so even though another biochar may be
less expensive or if they're comparably
priced you may not be getting as much of
actual biochar which is what you want so
that's a good number to be aware of and
this 23 is us moistening this because
the biochar that we make inherently
comes out what they consider bone dry
but in that bone dry there are some
hydrogen and oxygen gases trapped in the
particle and they will come together
under the right circumstances and form
ten percent water which is a good thing
because for transportation you want it
to have a little bit of moisture content
because it's a lot less flammable but
when you get up to this waterway so much
more than biochar that while a
percentage of of it is is water it makes
a transportation of these heavy water
chars much more expensive does that make
sense so moving on here it looks like
your
you've highlighted the total ash content
and it looks like the range between
these three tests go from let's see 34
down to 4.7 and I know you you had said
you want a low ash that low total ash
number can you explain why and what that
tells us about the combustion okay well
that means that your if you if there's
three components water carbon and ash
low ash content ash is it's not
necessarily a bad thing and in some of
our products we add it back in you know
I'll get to that in a minute
but generally speaking the reason you
want biochar is for the carbon what the
carbon the organic stable organic carbon
does in the soil for the whole
rhizosphere for the whole ecosystem down
there and replacing that carbon that has
been lost is really important and
there's a lot of chemistry that goes on
that we never think about and
biochemistry that's related to that
carbon so the higher the carbon content
the more valuable the biochar is to the
soil that you're putting in it now ash
can be used you can see that when they
put it as carbon it's this is a liming
value so if you want to buy biochar and
use it to lime your soil a high ash
content is a okay thing but it does seem
like an expensive way to approach
lightening a field do you know yeah
calcium carbonate is really cheap you
can get egg lime for nothing compared to
the cost of biochar or other products
right so I want to ask you so the next
one down here the point out was this
butane mm-hmm and then what is the AC T
stands for activity butane activity and
what is that significant okay well one
day they try to determine this surface
area using this beauty
activity test or several approaches but
this lab is sort of the standard in the
industry and they use butane activity
and that's how much butane gas is orbed
you know under they heat it up they put
in the dry char and they see how much
butane gas disappears because it's
correlated to the surface area there's a
mathematical equation that ranges
surface area so the absorption
properties of the chars what that number
shows us yeah only and also in a way it
ends up being the surface area
correlations being based on the butane
activity now you can get there other
ways like with electronic microscopes
but this is like the ordinary lab tested
that an on University lab would have the
university labs can get down to not just
what the estimated surface area is but
what the actual surface area is and also
what part of that surface area comes
from macro pores micro pores and mezzo
pores and most of the transactions that
happen with biochar including the cation
exchange you know all the interactions
with the soil minerals so you're turning
soil minerals into more useful or more
usable forms with the addition of carbon
how much surface area is available to do
that how much surface area is available
to hold water how much surface area is
available to hold nutrients because
biochar does it by adsorption more than
absorption and that means sticking to
the surface of the particle so having a
high surface area means you have a high
efficiency in the product that you're
putting in the soil yeah I usually
describe biochar as a sort of a giant
sponge so it has a really strong ability
retain nutrients in the in the soil and
then release them to the plant as the
plant needs them so if you're doing
living soils if you are farming if it's
if you're reusing your soil mix it's
really great to have biochar in there
for those properties that's is that an
OK way to describe it or is there
something even say yeah that's very a
good way to look at it and I'll put up
some photos too we are seeing about 8 to
10 percent better growth and yield with
our biochar soil over our water only
soil and that the only difference there
in the recipe being the addition of the
biochar that we're soaking in the fish
we're really happy with the quality of
the biochar and also that the growth
that we're seeing with it so I I want to
move on from the test because they're a
little dry but I think it's important
that people take a look at these numbers
and actually compare what they're
getting because the term biochar is
synonymous as you said with so many
different things that we don't really
know what we're buying and what we're
applying to the soil so it requires some
education on the part of consumer rights
right and yeah let's move on though and
talk about some other questions let's
see here what research is being done
right now with blackout biochar I know
you've talked to me off there saying
that you've been doing some some work
can you is there anything you can you
can talk about well we work we work with
a lot of universities and some of the
work is egg oriented Cornell Purdue just
Washington State Montana State and
usually we ask for the results and we
have yet to get back anything that's
we're embarrassed about our unhappy
about Montana State just sent us some
results that they got with grains they
got 40% more harvestable grain I believe
it was wheat and with the use of biochar
do you know how they were using the
biochar
study hurry that trial and not really
debate I know it was a field study it
was it wasn't hot steady it was a field
study was plots okay and the Purdue had
forty to sixty percent better they
they've been working with it for about
three years and different crops Cornell
was able to overcome a problem in their
tomato high tunnel using it because the
phosphorus didn't lock I guess
phosphorus locking is an issue and I
think it may be an issue in cannabis
plants too because you because the way I
understand it a lot of growers go
through and add these nutrients and then
they wash them out because they're ready
for it to move on to the next phase but
what biochar does is make that
phosphorus available but it doesn't lock
it into place so this washing notion is
probably eliminated as necessary
yeah phosphorus doesn't it's it's fairly
a mobile in soils it doesn't leach out
like other nutrients like nitrogen would
but it I think what you're referencing
is how available it is which I believe
is I believe it's p2o5 which is what
you're talking about in terms of night
phosphorus that the plant can
immediately uptake it sounds like
there's some some good research being
done using biochar and then also I know
you do projects on the remediation side
how are people how other where are other
ways people are using biochar okay well
we've found that in water remediation
and filtration this product is activated
carbon substitute in some cases is
better than activated carbon and about
the tenth the cost so what we found with
our char and this is it's funny to
overlap between remediation and egg
science because some of the things like
the kinetics a speed of the reactions
are really important because like in
water remediation they found that
you know typically it takes 24 hours for
a biochar to filter out sand heavy
metals like copper and zinc which are
really prevalent in the water here it
takes two minutes for ours to filter it
out what that means is you need a lot
less of it a lot smaller bed
they make these gigantic swimming pool
treatment areas with other products and
if you can cut that footprint down it's
a lot less expensive for the industry to
maintain that water so that's one thing
and then it has a natural affinity for a
lot of these heavy metals but not the so
much the an ion ones which would be
selenium and arsenic and let's just talk
about selenium in arsenic right now but
we are able we are able to make a
coating now to put on that biochar and
still get that real speedy reaction time
but have it attract the arsenic sand so
and and the anion problem things salsa
really good at oil oils petrochemicals
and that has some bearing on restoring
fields that have been damaged by some of
this death making land usable again so
can you tell me a little bit then about
what makes black owl unique what makes
your biochar different than say some of
these other ones on the market besides
the fact that you're fully you know
paralyzing the material you have the lab
tests and the university research to
support what you're doing is there
anything else that really separates you
and your eyes for me
yeah we're it kind of and working on
we've done several publications where
we've pointed out this kinetic thing
which is really really important
also if a biochars got enough time
against a this oh it's understandable
it has a charge to it it's a negative
charge and that charge the strength of
that charges is really important because
the scientists are theorizing that
that's what stimulates the plants growth
hormones and why in part that you're
getting faster maturation you'll
absolutely I also get compost to mature
faster in stimulating the growth
hormones it's also making the plants
larger and the yields larger so it's a
standout in the forces and you know that
magnetic charge thing is there
speculating
there's more than one school of thought
on how to explain this but they think
it's what's communicating underneath the
soil with the fungi which like it the
beneficial fungi but the negative molds
gray black and white are getting their
communication systems messed up so the
plants have a better resistance to those
molds so how what kind of research have
you seen with biochar and mycorrhizal
fungus oh well quite a bit enough so I
brought one picture down to show how
good the interaction is encourages it so
you're seeing a symbiotic relation yeah
and what levels are you recommending for
people to use biochar in potting soils
or in fields to see results okay I would
like this one say one thing about
potting soils and compost we have number
of landscapers who come and get the
biochar to put in the compost because
people round up and some of these
herbicides and pesticides survive the
composting process so I put the biochar
in there and it has a natural affinity
to hold that so that when they use that
composted product they know that they're
not going to and
have it the growth of the plants that
they have just put in the landscape you
know it holds it within the biochar
particle it doesn't allow it to be taken
by the plant we have the same research
on eco lion and taro caucus too by the
way so so where does it go exactly that
if it's it's it's stuck in the particle
forever yeah and you know microbes do
come and eat degrade that stuff in time
okay so but at least it doesn't cause a
compost to do crashing a new planting so
they they put it in there as a
preventative so what rates are you
seeing people using okay so the rate
that's why this carbon number is so
important we use five percent by volume
in a container and get excellent results
beyond 15 with ours would not be good
but I call our biochar a high efficiency
biochar because it is holds more water
holds more nutrients works faster and
has this high carbon and high surface
area that its orders of magnitude higher
than these these other charts and so you
need less of it yeah it's high
efficiency char so 5 percent 10 percent
snice if a person wants to go that far
with it and 15 percent is max Cornell
did really interesting bunch of studies
were they they kept adding salt salts
are a problem from synthetic agriculture
their residual in the soil and their
impede the growth of plants in future
years and so Cornell took these plants
and they put our biochar in some of them
and not another biochars and some of
them and no biochar and some of them and
they kept putting on briny water salt
water and you know
the controls died and the and these were
soybeans which are sensitive the
soybeans in our biochar went to full
maturity and created new soybeans and
even though they increased the
braininess
continuously to try to see what upper
level it would take so that may not be a
common situation but it's fairly common
in the California soils so it has a good
buffering capacity was what you're
saying yeah for sodium so for people
that are say doing imagined synthetic
chemicals or ionic salts all right are
you seeing that people use are using
biochar with salt based fertilizer
programs as well yeah we we have people
using Oh in just every imaginable way
and that's one thing that we've been
criticized for is having white why do
you sell a biochar
that's just biochar and you're not
adding this and that the other thing to
it well we do do that if somebody wants
us to do it really the reason is is
because everybody has their own unique
thing that they like to do and products
that they like to use so we think just
give him a really good high-quality
charter add to whatever that product is
it not yet have we had anybody say that
gave them a bad result if you're using
biochar in a living soil like let's say
a raised bed for example and you have it
in there at well with our souls we're
like eight to ten percent mm-hmm how
often would you reinvent that bed with
biochar or would you ever rien oculi tit
or would you just assume that for the
next year or two it's probably gonna be
at optimal levels or what are your
thoughts on that if you have it in there
at eight to ten percent I don't think
you need to do anything more for the
foreseeable future
okay frankly it should be there and it
kind of it kind of grows and multiplies
and also it speeds up the formation of
humic acids we've had apple growers over
and one add you use it and they
called up [__] but he make acid in
that biochar you know because it your
lady they have their agronomist doing
the test so yeah and nature intended
carbon to be in the soil so that brings
up an interesting question for me I know
when I was getting my soil labels made I
was told that I had to put virgin
forests slash on my ingredient list for
the black out biochar and that sounded
terrible to me when I first read that's
just those three words together didn't
sound like it was a good ecological
solution and then you sort of explained
to me a little bit about what that
actually means
could you just review that a little bit
for listeners yes if you've seen there
are a lot of slash piles around even in
our neighborhood now where they taken
down trees because they're clearing to
do more building well they they let
those piles build up and dry and then
they ignite them that's the typical
slash and we're you know harvest tree in
the forest or outside of the forest they
burn those things up well in a
commercial tree operetta creation and
like a private forest what they do is
they can get a forest certification and
that means for every tree that's been
pulling a lot of carbon out of the
atmosphere each one of those that they
take they they have to plant like five
trees to replace it and then the growth
of those trees they're pulling more
carbon out we would never recommend
harvesting trees for making biochar but
there is this waste that's called slash
which are the limbs that they can't turn
into two by fours right and the tops
that they can't turn into two by fours
and the bases which they can't turn into
two by fours so those things and most
forestry operations aren't left in the
forest and there's two problems without
one if they don't end up being tinder
for a forest fire what they do do is
degrade over a period of time the
microbes come in and they're just
releasing all that
I've been dioxide up into the air so we
take that stuff and converted that's
what virgin virgin meaning it's never
been treated wood forest means came from
a forest and slash means it's otherwise
waste okay so essentially it's a
byproduct of the logging or forestry
industry and it's a way of sequestering
that carbon into a usable by-product so
you're taking a waste stream and
actually making it more ecological by
making this biochar crap
that's wonderful which makes me want to
switch gears a little bit so as as you
know because we've talked about this my
father after retiring was got really
into biochar and started he bought a
kontiki kiln or built one and was
looking into how to take this technology
into poorer countries
and villages and as a way of raising
soil fertility so he was looking into
China and he took a few trips over there
before getting ill himself and was
working with them but then he was also
working with the Oregon some forestry
people down in Oregon as a way for these
kilns to be something they could take on
to site and then as they're doing the
cuttings or the the harvesting in the
timber industry they could then take
this slash and put it right into the
kilns pyrolyze it right there on site
and then apply that material back onto
the forest so is there any have any
thoughts on that or I think it's a
really good idea however you know it
you've got to manage that equipment and
you have to you know take several hours
in a kontiki kiln and so I think it's a
good idea it would be nice to have
really good pyrolysis units that are
mobile however we found that bringing it
out of the forest on the logging trucks
themselves didn't add to the pollution
so our way of doing it is to
take it out of the forest and then
process it and therefore we can use the
energy the you know who can create
energy yeah I love the I love the idea
of taking a byproduct like this or a
waste stream and making it into
something that adds fertility and I know
my dad was really excited about that
whole process in terms of how he could
utilize that in you know recreate this
and maybe some villages out in China and
other places in the world now in terms I
mean I have a kontiki kill on our
property but I still choose to use your
biochar because I can't produce it in a
quantity that makes it cost-effective
for me and it like you said it is a lot
of time but I do love the idea of being
able to hopefully encourage the forestry
industry to start considering biochar as
a viable option rather than
slash-and-burn and and you know some of
these other things that you've talked
about one other question I had along
those lines though I know my dad
initially when he started licking the
biochar he took a class to make a
biochar stove and then he came back and
showed it to me and this was he was
first getting into it and and we looked
at it or like this isn't actually
pyrolized
you're making ash essentially you might
as well just go put this in your
fireplace for probably what you're
getting so do you have any
recommendations for people on a small
scale and who say I wanted to try making
their own biochar I've seen people
digging pits I've seen a whole bunch of
different designs is there any anything
you can recommend there's all kinds of
stuff there's another dr. T Lloyd whose
actual name is Paul Anderson he he makes
a cook stove you put the wood and this
is really meant for villagers in there
and you really control how much oxygen
is burning that fire they're using the
heat to cook on and then they take that
little bit of material out and throw it
on their garden and it works well I've
seen these some people have cans that go
into their wood-burning stove and while
the wood-burning stove is throwing up
gases into the atmosphere at least what
they have
the can is low to no oxygen and so it
actually will retain the carbon and as
long as they don't cook it too long you
need to look at pyrolysis a lot like
baking your baking you want to bake it
rather than burn it there's a million
different models of product and I know
that they've taken made some larger
units that they're taking out into the
forest but nothing that can utilize the
heat or the energy and and unfortunately
I think I'm not talking about the
kontiki kiln because that's a basic
thing that as long as you're there to
suppress it at the right time you can
get biochar from it it works and I liked
your dad's unit because it could take
fairly large limbs and work with them
because a lot of people don't have
chipped wood to work with so that that
is practical and inexpensive but I don't
like is this mid tier group of things
that are put on wheels that don't use
the heat in energy and do create tars in
the end so knowing a little bit about
the engineering but this can all be
calculated from a lab report so I think
with any big outlay of capital for
machinery a person should always use get
their own feedstock that they anticipate
using have a load run and and then pay
for a test to see what kind of result
they're getting yeah I just think we
have two different types of listeners
here potentially we'll have people that
want to make it themselves
you know just for their home garden or
for home grow you know really small
scale just to try it out and you know
and it may not be the highest quality
biochar but it's not gonna hurt their
plants and they want to you know give it
a shot nothing dangerous and then you'll
have other people on a commercial scale
that say hey I have all these biochar
companies out there and they're all
trying to sell me product and they all
make different claims how do I evaluate
them and that's where that lab test
I think is really important yeah I was
talking about if you're buying equipment
and in you and you're putting some big
dollars into equipment it's like you're
talking about the forest model the
kontiki kiln makes a lot of sense some
of the machinery that's been drug out
into the forest is $300,000 machinery
okay before you do that get it a lab
test is what I my strong recommendation
sure and there's all kinds of different
configurations vertical horizontal
gasification as as opposed to pyrolysis
which just means there may be some
airflow or some people put oxygen in
there and it depends on you know what
you're trying to achieve in the end but
for a home gardener I think the kontiki
kiln is a good thing for a third world
country I think a cook stoves a good
thing it depends on how horrible you
need it to be but with any of these
things if you do it right you can you
can end up making some very good carbon
even Boy Scouts can do it with campfires
you just want it to burn from the top
down not the bottom up often it gets
some links or resources to put on the
page from you after this talk this got
me thinking and this is gonna be kind of
a silly question for you but something
that I know I've seen online is people
think of biochar and they go okay well
why can't I just go get some charcoal
briquettes and pound those up and add
that to my soil or pulling out of a
fireplace or things like that so I know
we talked about a little bit but can you
just reiterate again any potential
dangers there what the major difference
is besides the carbon to ash ratio right
okay so charcoal in a bag is made to be
an energy source to cook food its
purpose is to be a source of the energy
like coal for instance but it's charcoal
usually it's made from wood but it also
has binders in it that gives it the
shape that it is I and sometimes they
put accelerants in that charcoal but in
any case it's not a nice pure carbon
product to enhance the soil its whole
purpose is different and there's a lot
of unknowns about it that are of concern
to agronomist so there could be other
things in that charcoal briquette that
may not be safe for you yeah I just know
you don't know you don't know what it's
made of you don't need to it's
supposedly you don't need to know but
you know there's been some some
criticism in the health field about
charred meats cooked on a charcoal grill
and you know all of this stuff when you
heat something up you get reformation of
chemistry and you can end up with things
like dioxins and stuff that's just not
good so with the charcoal briquettes
they're not they are not to be used in
substitution for actual biochar and did
we we did go into the fact that you want
it to be at least sixty percent carbon I
don't know if we talked about that from
the test results but you know the
combustion what you're doing in a grill
with charcoal too is they're doing full
combustion house all air coming in on it
right and what you end up with is a gray
ash you're burning up what carbon is in
there but it could be wood it could be
torrefied wood that serves as that
charcoal and so that hg ratio would not
be a good number for plants for for
optimal stability and the soils so okay
so the hydrogen and carbon ratio is a
reflection of how stable that product is
is in how long the the carbon will stay
in a form that will allow it to remain
in the soil that's what you're saying
right and not degrade so you probably
find that the degradation rates of a
charcoal that are meant for barbecue are
much faster I think that you'd find the
absorption is much lower in much lower
cation exchange capacity yeah which is
its ability to retain nutrients
okay well was there anything else you
wanted to cover talking about biochar do
you feel like we got a good foundation
there for people to get an idea of what
biochar is you know I just want to say
this you can't there's a lot of magical
thinking around biochar and you won't
believe it till you see it I mean you
really experience and it turns you into
a believer if you end up with a good
product on the other hand you know buyer
beware would just like anything else so
source a good high quality biochar and
then try out a plant or five plants and
use scientific method so make sure you
have a control so the only difference is
the addition of biochar versus your
other the rest of your crop and see the
difference for yourself is what you're
saying right out that's right
they used whatever fertilizer you would
use otherwise and but you know some
biochar with it and see if you don't
have a better experience with one plant
over another great well thanks for your
time today
I appreciate it okay thank you that was
Rennell Anderson founder of blackout
biochar I posted all the lab tests and
information we discussed in this podcast
right on the podcast page don't forget
that you can try blackout biochar for
15% off for the month of November on our
web site at WWE to search for biochar on
our product page
you are listening to the cannabis
cultivation and science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy don't forget
that there's more information and
articles available on our website and
blog at WWE organics calm as well as
links to the data and information we
discussed in this episode on the product
page and if you enjoy these podcasts
please take a moment to leave me a
review on iTunes and send me your
feedback and suggestions through our
website contact page or ta d @ k is
organics calm Thanks