[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge before
starting the podcast I wanted to update
listeners on what's been going on with
kiss organics and some of our future
plans we are in the process of closing
down kiss farm our seven acre farm and
feed store due to issues with the county
around permitting but it's also been an
impetus to refocus our energy around
kiss organics soil science and research
in cannabis I recently brought dr. Ben
Higgins from episode 51 into the company
he's already a partner of mine in Kaizen
consulting and working over at Golden
Gardens I'm excited to get his help in
expanding our in-house research through
his connection with gold leaf and
ability to monitor and set up
experiments in addition I had double
knee surgery a couple weeks ago and I'm
slowly getting back up to speed with our
first child arriving here any day now
I'm glad to be moving around better and
hope to continue the podcast schedule to
the best of my ability speaking of
upcoming podcasts I have an exciting one
coming up with dr. Darren Kaplan Darren
was the first person in North America to
earn a PhD with research focused on
cannabis production Dr Kaplan has
written and published several
peer-reviewed articles on cannabis
production focusing on irrigation
growing media fertilization and
propagation so that's what's going on
over here at KISS organics we do plan on
expanding the availability of our soils
and products to a greater number of
states come 2020 it took a few years but
we have gotten our soil and nutrient
packs certified for use in organic
production with the CDFA in California
Oregon tilth
the Washington State Department of
Agriculture and the Oregon Department of
Agriculture and much of that was done
with the help of my guest this week
Andrew Black is the certified kind
founder and director Andrew spent the
last 11 years working for Oregon tilth
one of the nation's most trusted organic
certification agencies andrew has worn
many hats an organic certification
including farm program manager inspector
final reviewer latin-american specialist
and certification officer andrew has
inspected hundreds of farms and food
processing facilities in the United
States and Latin America and has made
certification decisions for hundreds
more he is an expert compliance reviewer
for products certified to the USDA
National Organic Program plus the
organic standards for the European Union
Canada and Mexico he also has hands-on
experience growing plants in greenhouses
and for several years grew vegetables
for fifteen families from a small urban
farm he has also been an integral part
in establishing the Sun and Earth
certification which we discussed last
episode with David Bronner now onto the
show yeah can we start off giving
listeners a little bit of an
introduction to your background in the
certification world absolutely yeah so
I've been I've been involved doing
organic certification work since 2005 he
started working as a full-time organic
inspector for oregon pihl's which is one
of the nation's oldest and largest
organic certifiers of farms and dairies
food processors and so I got involved
and during that time when I was an
inspector I visited hundreds of
different organic farms throughout
Oregon Washington California and we had
clients over in the Midwest and also
speak Spanish so I get sent to Mexico
for six to seven weeks a year and look
at the farms down in Mexico and so all
that work you know it was very
interesting to see farming organic
farming at different scales so I started
to do that work and then I got involved
behind the scenes that were again self
helping to make certification decisions
you know to approve an organic
certificate or to deny it
spend it relocate whatever needed to
happen and also
I started managing the latin-american
program that we had and so yeah that was
it's been a great way to actually get a
deep dive into organic agriculture and
food processing yeah now I met you boy I
don't even know how many years ago now
I'm gonna guess five or six years ago
through Jaya Palmer he introduced us and
that was sort of my first foray into
learning about certification
you've taught you've set up a
certification called certified kind for
the cannabis industry and we're gonna
definitely talk about that quite a bit
but what I guess what made you
interested in setting up a certification
in the first first place and what are
some of the challenges around that that
go into that process yeah well you know
the idea for doing like a cannabis
organic certification a lot you know
that goes back pretty far a couple of my
colleagues that were gonna Tilton I you
know had talked about the need for it
with in Oregon specifically and then
once they once Oregon started allowing
medical dispensaries and for like the
retail sale of cannabis and Medical
dispensaries that's when it became clear
that we needed to have some sort of
certification program or oversight
because people everybody was calling
their cannabis organic and folks like me
who care about organic agriculture and
you know have had organic farms and
certifications and also work to do
inspection work what not seeing cannabis
market is organic was when we knew that
most of it wasn't that was the
motivation to start certified time we
wanted to put truth in organic cannabis
labeling and so that's what we did
and you know the heart the heart parts
of doing a certification well everybody
thinks it's like easy to set up a
certification program throughout the
years have been approached a number of
times by other people saying a we want
to we want to set up we want to do an
organic certification or oh you know
we're not going to get your
certification maybe we'll start our own
and I kind of always laugh at that
because the if you're trying to do a
professional third-party certification
you really have to have the systems in
place to be able to receive new
applicants and you have to have the
experience to be able to evaluate the
farm plans that they put together and
talk to them at a really high level
about what they're doing their farming
practices and not only that but you've
got to manage all this information that
you collect that you're using to audit
them and and hold their feet to the fire
you know when it comes to doing what
they say they're doing and ensuring that
they're actually farming organically so
I think there's a lot of moving parts to
third-party certification and you know
the best part for me is getting out on
the farm and seeing what people are
doing so there's a few challenges here
if I'm hearing you correctly one is
setting up the the rules and regulations
around a certification because the term
organic and cannabis is meaningless
because there is there is no unifying
certification that everyone turns to
like if we look at the AG model you have
or you know our foods model we have you
know the NOP the National Organic
Program that sets standards that then
different states will have certifying
programs to match those standards more
or less and then you also have Omri
which is a third party certifier
can you just touch really briefly on
what that what that model looks like
sure so in the United States we have the
USDA Organic Program and that's actually
housed under the USDA agricultural
marketing service and so the National
Organic Program what you mentioned is
responsible for sort of maintaining and
curating the National Organic Program
standards and then that standard is used
by like accredited agencies so the USDA
will accredit third parties to act on
their behalf to administer certification
program so there are 54 around 54 55
USDA Organic accredited certifiers
within the United States and there's
about 50 outside the United States and
so um the work of like getting an
organic certification and USDA Organic
certification for your farm your dairy
your food processing facility that's
done by these third parties and so um
one of those third parties already
mentioned was Oregon tilt but there are
others that people might know about like
qai or CCO F that stands for certified
California certified organic farmers on
the East Coast there's private
certifiers like New York organic farmers
association etc etc so Omri is actually
only specializes in material review so
these 54 accredited certifiers they they
specialize and actually certifying that
a business meets the USDA Organic
regulations and Omri specializes in
reviewing materials such as fertilizers
and pesticides for
clients to the USDA Organic regulation
so Omri is a special beast and there are
there are a couple other army like
institutions one of them is rum it's
called the double USDA Washington State
Department of Agriculture organic
material review program the other one is
a California Department of Food and
Agriculture z-- organic input materials
program the CD FAO I am and they only
work with fertilizers by the way so
those those three entities will do a
material review and approve it for
organics or not and then those 54 other
organic certifiers that work with funds
and food processors will respect the
decision of Omri double USDA Organic or
CDF a oh I am and allow farmers to use
those material that's that's actually
really helpful I didn't totally
understand that in my head exactly so so
hearing it is really useful and I know
like you were actually we hired you at
one point to help us navigate you know
with Oregon tilth
and with the Washington State Department
of Agriculture and then finally we just
recently got our CDFA approval for
organic materials so on the fertilizer
or soil side and we register our soil as
a fertilizer because technically
anything that helps make a plant grow
they call a fertilizer and it has an NPK
value so it's it's a little more
convoluted on my end but having those
certifications I think is really
powerful because it shows that my
product is regulated it's tested and
there's someone there's third parties
that are determining the quality of it
and I think that third party aspect is
really important that's something that
that you mentioned that I want to just
touch on if for example is kiss organics
I made a certification around it and
called it you know the kid
organic certification and you used my
products I don't feel that certification
would carry the same weight as if
someone unaffiliated with my company
created a certification like you know
like certified kind I think that's
that's a much more powerful
certification because it's not linked to
any products or another company and
that's that's something to consider when
we talk about certifications as well but
let's uh let's dive into certified kind
a little bit so when you set up
certified kind you were looking to
establish a certification that would be
as rigorous as these standards on the
agricultural side as well correct when
we talk about material review and and
farms that would qualify and such yeah
exactly
the goal of certified kind was to offer
a professional third-party certification
for cannabis growers medical or adult
youth that were licensed I'm permitted
in their state to grow so essentially
what we were trying to do is to create a
program that was very similar to how
folks get certified on their youth on
their organic farms how they get USDA
Organic certification there were a
couple reasons first of all we wanted
foot we want folks to get the
certification and instead of using the
term organic to market their product we
wanted them to use kind or certified
kind so we we didn't want them using the
term organic to market their cannabis
because that's a regulated marketing
term and it introduces confusion into
the marketplace if people are saying hey
Dazz we is organic but there's no
third-party certification or
verification system in place so certify
kind serves that purpose you know it's
to verify that farms that work with us
get certified or actually only using
organic approved fertilizers and
pesticides etc right
and you know for it's interesting
because you mentioned the kiss kiss
organic soils and yeah what I found
through working with a lot of materials
manufacturers is that not all the
ingredients listed on a fertilizer or on
the pesticide not all the ingredients
they're actually in the product are
listed on the label and so and that's
Kanan what happens when you go through
this Omri certification or a good
third-party material review is that they
ask for detailed information about the
ingredients to verify that the
ingredients that are listed on the label
and also the ones that aren't are
allowed in organic farming yeah it's
it's crazy how strict they are I beat
the CDFA I was hung up for six months
because our source of neem they sprayed
a small amount we're talking very very
small amount of molasses on the product
during the production in India and
because I couldn't get in the
manufacturer in India because I was
buying it through a couple third parties
by the time I got to me too he was they
weren't willing to list their source for
the molasses the entire product failed
so I had to find another neem source
where I could get the entire process
laid out which made CDFA a lot harder
than some of the other material review
certifications yeah yeah it's amazing
how detailed people get when there's
like a standard involved and it becomes
a lot of people it becomes very you know
black and white oh they ask you about
the neem you tell them all they spray
molest on it and now all the sudden you
have to track down you know where did
that molasses come from and so that's
why you know when people say when they
complain about Omri you know to me or
CDFA they they're complaining about all
me not being rigorous and
or whatever that's a bunch of BS
armories armory in the CDFA are very
rigorous when it comes to material
review see I wasn't aware that army was
as that strict I didn't go down the army
route because they take as a third party
certifier part of their business models
they take a portion of your profits as
payment for the seal so I chose to go
with the CDFA and the double USDA for my
certification but one of the things I
learned from you is that armory if you
see that armory certification on a
product it means that the products been
legitimately certified and you can trust
that symbol which I think it's so the
good thing about armory I think this is
something we should talk about so a good
thing about armory is consumers
recognize and know it growers see that
label and they go okay it's Omri
certified and that means that has value
because they've captured a certain
portion of the market and you know
Washington State and California have
that same power I think because they're
a state regulatory body people see that
as having value too but in the cannabis
industry right we need we need a
unifying certification you know one
where and my hope you know frankly I may
be fairly transparent about it my hope
is that certified kind and ones like Sun
and Earth can be those certifications
for our industry because I know you and
I know what this the value of the
certification is because the challenge
there is one you have to have good
standards so you have to have someone
that runs it that understands what
standards should be and so you have to
have the right standards and then you
have to have the right level of
regulation and that costs money and you
know farm visits cost money but we need
them to happen so that we can guarantee
that what people are saying they're
doing on their farm they're they're
actually doing but can you just I know I
kind of rambled there but can you talk a
little bit about that sort of that idea
of needing a unifying certification and
the value of it yeah sure so you know
and then if food in the food industry
you know the gold standard right now for
a third-party certification is USDA
Organic and in cannabis it would be
really nice if the
sumer could look to just certification
label and say okay it's been it's been
certified by for instance certified kind
we trust these guys we we look we know
that they do a professional third party
inspection and certification all the way
through and that would be really nice
rate to be able to have something as
powerful as a USDA Organic that symbol
so for folks that care about these
things they could walk into a dispensary
ask full ask for hey which products are
certified and the bud tenders would be
able to point them in the right
direction you know I think it'd be I
think it's interesting I think we should
talk a little bit about what does a
certified kind farm look like yeah I
think that's a good idea right before we
do I just want to add one last thought
to your your latest comment and I think
as a consumer walking into dispensary is
a great example so there are consumers I
mean a lot of them I'm sure that listen
to this podcast when they look at
products that they're not growing they
want to know that they were grown safely
and in a manner that don't want don't
want to consume and so when I walk in if
I see all these different certifications
I may not know what each certification
stands for and what their standards are
and what the value of that seal is on a
given package so it's it's a process of
educating consumers and having enough
marketing and to get out there that the
people know what it is and then also
understanding the value of it too you
know creating a certification and
putting a sticker only has value if
that's backed by something like you said
in some some level of regulation and
expertise so yeah let's talk about what
what a certified kind farm actually
looks like right so so just as in
organic farming you know the the amount
of commitment and dedication to like
organic regenitive
farming practice rent it's a range so
but there are certain things that are
characteristic of a certified time farm
so let's talk for a second about the
outdoor farms and then we can sort of
talk about the indoor farms so for for
an outdoor farm what we're looking for
is first of all farm that's only using
organic approved fertility so that soil
amendments organic approved potting soil
and organic approved pest control
materials so that's that's the first
criteria so we actually kind of have to
deny a lot of certification requests
because a lot of folks are using
synthetic liquid fertilizers or
synthetic powders that they fertig ate
in and so that type of farming is not it
that's not for certified kind we don't
work with conventional non-organic firms
a lot of our farms are doing things like
using cover crops for instance you can
use daikon radishes to as a cover crop
in the fall and in the spring winter and
spring and that really can help to
penetrate soils that have been hardpan
due to cultivation and rototilling right
and then when they decay you know you're
creating space and habitat for a lot of
microorganisms and natural nutrient
cycling so on these on these farms
there's a lot of natural nutrient
cycling going on now the interesting
thing with some with certified kind we
we include indoor growers in our
certification and we hold them to the
certified kind standard for the parts of
the standard that are applicable to an
indoor grow and what I've been seeing a
lot of and of course you're aware of it
sowing the kiss soil is that the trend
an organic indoor car is more raised
beds and natural nutrient cycling within
those beds which is pretty interesting
and unique what I'm talking about course
is like your no-till soil I think I
don't know that it's not really the
probably the right terminology to use in
a pure agricultural horticultural sense
but it's these are these are soils that
where you're planting cannabis cycle
after cycle the only thing that's really
happening there is you're cutting the
stock cutting the plant out of the of
the bed and you know we see folks
reinventing the soil but the interesting
thing is that in that indoor setting
where you have the perfect temperature
and humidity you see nutrients like
natural nutrient cycling that's off the
hook fast right
so somebody somebody croats comfrey and
does a chop and drop in an indoor crow
and it's gone really quickly what's
happening there well there's you know
microbiology is taking over so anyway
that's a really fascinating thing about
the indoor growth and we're seeing a lot
of that yeah what were some of the
challenges with indoor grows I know I
was talking with Nate over in gold leaf
recently and he said one of the things
that ws ta was stuck on our challenge
with was how do they regulate co2 being
brought in and some of the methods for
which that happens in an indoor
operation and qualifying those things
for organic standards what are some of
the other challenges with indoors versus
outdoor from an organic certification
perspective okay fer for certifier that
working with USDA Organic regulations
it's there are a lot of obstacles to
certifying cannabis and so one of them
would be you know do we allow co2 so
you're in like it
door space where you're you're trying to
add co2 and this isn't really done in
any other type of crop there's no
there's really aren't a lot of indoor
organic vegetables being grown and
they're not pumping the facility fro
full of co2 so carbon dioxide is not
first all first of all they have to
determine if it's synthetic or
non-synthetic now carbon dioxide is it
comes in a you know maybe that's why
there's some hesitation just to allow it
they probably are saying that that
synthetic and that it's synthetic co2 is
not listed as a farm production aid in
the National Organic Standards so you
run into roadblocks like that with some
of the practices that are common in
cannabis so with Kinnick in a farm you
co2 supplementation with your current
standard was with certified kind that is
a really good question
I currently I don't think we we have
anyone that's doing co2 supplementation
at all and if we looked at the standard
itself we'd probably find that co2 isn't
listed but I'll tell you what I can
check and maybe get back to you on it
because it's not one that I was just
ready to hook up yeah I didn't put you
on the spot I'm surprised I hasn't come
up yet because I think any a lot of the
not a knee but a lot of the commercial
facilities would want to supplement co2
in order to maximize yield just based on
the research out there around lighting
and in co2 supplementation so I'm
surprised you haven't encountered that
yet but I I know that there are these
challenges associated with indoor
environments that you know another one
another one like that that I can speak
to is sulfur burning sulfur so in
indoor facility or a you know greenhouse
and enclosed space people have been
burning sulfur or vaporizing sulfur -
it's a great way to control fungus and
and also like him brush at night broad
nights but burning sulfur is not
something that's allowed in organic
agriculture you can use micronized
sulfur but you can't burn sulfur so
there's another spot there where so or
you know organic rules don't really save
her some of these cultural you know
practices that cannabis growers use
indoors
another one is potassium silicate which
I think you and I have talked about
before oh yeah but potassium silicate or
Axl
a lot of girls like to use this in their
as a fruit as a fertilizer you know to
add to their potting soil and it helps
strengthen the cell walls and create
probably a denser product that's less
susceptible to powdery mildew and yet
using it that way is not allowed in us
the organic farming so the point here is
that these regulations that are in place
for USDA Organic are not no one
considered cannabis production when they
were putting these rules together back
in when they were forming them back in
their late 1990s and early 2000s so so
it's going to be difficult for a state
you know the state or the federal
government to come in and try and offer
organic certification for cannabis
without some tweaking of their own rules
and so what we should look to right you
know if we want to understand how the US
government will one day regulate an
offer organic certification we can look
- what's going on in Washington State
and also in California
both the Department of Agriculture's in
those states are creating their own
certification programs for cannabis so
on that note you mentioned like
potassium silicate it is allowed for use
with as a spray a foliar spray for pests
I believe is that correct yes you're
correct it's it's listed as allowed in
its aqueous form so aqueous potassium
silicate for pest control Disease
Control in the in the National USDA
Organic rules in the national list so a
product like film matrix is an aqueous
solution it's been approved
Tom reproved that can be used but the
other material made by the same company
he gets the same company called axle 16
would probably get you in trouble with a
certification and we ask at certified
time we ask people to stop using that so
if you were or they have it's a
concentrated powder when you receive it
but you're mixing it with water into a
potassium silicon solution it's similar
to everything you find in the hydro shop
at that point could you use the product
if you're not putting it in in its dry
form because it's it's too highly
concentrated anyway to do so yeah
perhaps
I mean you would you would have to say
well I'm using this as a pest control
material in a Jake waste form and and
the thing is that in the production of
USDA organic certified fruits and
vegetables nobody's done that so so
we've never seen anybody try and make
the claim hey I'm using this potassium
silicate powder I'm adding it to water
and I'm spraying it as a pest control
material I'm making my own fill matrix
basically right that's that's kind of
the argument you have to make and then
you would have and then the certifier
would have to receive that argument and
and agree to it for you on your front
but no but see the the current USA
organic certifiers don't have any
experience with canvas or cannabis
growers so um probably they're going to
just respond saying no you know because
they don't understand the life cycle of
cannabis or the specific pest pressures
or what people want to use and what they
they prefer and so they're gonna have a
hard time fitting like you know around
well square peg in a round hole so so
take me through the process here so if
I'm I'm a cultivator I'm a grower and I
wanted to consider certified kind or a
certification agency for my farm or my
growing operation what what's the
process with you guys for that how's
that occur well first of all we require
that the farm fill out one of our
applications and the application doubles
as their organic system plan so all
organic farms are supposed to have an
organic system plan that sort of
describes how they're farming how
they're compliant to the regulations and
so for us we have a certified kind
standard that you can download from our
website certified certified kind calm
and the application or the organic
system plan document it asks a series of
questions about your farm and that are
applicable to the certification there's
information that we need to know what we
do is once that filled out is we do a
really thorough initial review and
that's a formal step where we evaluate
the application and then we respond to
you saying you know hey these are the
obstacles to certification you would
have to change X Y and V if you wanted
to to be part of our certification or we
could say you know your farm plan
looks excellent let's proceed to
scheduling the inspection so once we
receive a farm plan a farm organic
system plan that is complete and
demonstrates compliance to our standards
then we schedule the on-site inspection
at the on-site inspection we look at
every facet of cannabis production this
on-site inspection that first time
usually takes between I would say four
to five hours and at that time we're
also with certified time we take a leaf
tissue sample and we'll send it to a lab
that tests it for pesticide residue of
over two hundred and forty metabolites
and so that's one way that we try and
put teeth into this program so that
we're not only verifying through
observations on-site that there are no
pesticides at the facility or at the
firm but we're but we're taking this
tissue sample and testing it if they had
applied anything for you know any
pesticide over the last six months
or over the duration of the lifecycle of
that plant we would catch it in our
residue sampling so that's kind of an
extra step that a lot of sort of
cannabis certifiers don't do I think
we're the only one that takes a tissue
sample like that oh yeah I'm expensive
but I love it
I didn't realize a farm visit took that
long I mean in my head I just I picture
you kind of like walking around well I
don't see any advance nutrients on the
shelf I guess you guys are okay and then
you sign off that's really interesting
that it takes it's that detailed and I
love that you are taking that tissue
sample as verification I think that's
really a key component to all of this
really being successful yeah it's been
it's been interesting we haven't gotten
a positive result back on that lead
tissue samples in quite some time when
we first started we got a few paws
test results from outdoor farms but it
was such a minor concentration you know
that we suspect it was from like
neighboring drifts from a neighboring
land use so plus I drift or the guy was
using some spray tanks that weren't that
he had used in his landscaping business
that weren't cleaned out properly so you
know I don't know you know the rules for
pesticide residues and different in
different states are different like in
in Oregon they test 459 residues we're
testing for like 220 whatever 230 in
Washington I think it's not even
required for retail cannabis to have the
pesticide residue test you can opt in
and choose to but you don't have to that
correct you know that's a great question
i as I understood it there was some
regulation that was put into place and I
could be miss speaking here but as I
understood it most growers knew that it
wasn't being enforced and so there are
sort of what happened was this one
particular dispensary uncle Ike's in
Seattle kind of became like a third
party check for people and they've found
that a lot of not a lot but a
significant number of farms have failed
for things like Mike Michael butanol and
Eagle 20 and it's it's been really it's
been really challenging here in
Washington State
because at the end of the day like
you're taking people's word for things
and that's what I like about a certified
kind with this this tissue testing is
that you have some quantifiable
third-party data that shows you know
unequivocally that this material is
clean yeah yeah and you know when you're
developing a certification system
third-party certification system a lot
there is a lot of it that's built around
trust so this testing kind of
counterbalance is that and
and you know it's the other thing about
third-party certification is that if we
were to certify somebody and then find
out that they had been cheating using
fertilizers or pesticides or or selling
product that didn't come from their farm
a certified product I think that would
be a huge hit to the farms reputation as
well so you know you have the source of
residue testing but also reputation all
these folks reputations are on the line
when they when they sign up and part of
a certification you know they can be
proud say hey well you know we we walk
the walk we we went through the
certification we passed but if they end
up having to drop out for some reason
you know that that doesn't look too good
so so what you're saying essentially the
idea is that a company a grower is
buying in there it costs money for the
certification and you're not the
cheapest certification out there for it
a lot of the reasons that you just
listed but if they buy in essentially
they're buying into your certification
your reputation that the certified kind
brand has value because of the
stringency and the regulations that you
put in place and so if they were to lose
that because they cheated or something
else happened because that is I mean it
happens that that potentially would hurt
their their company quite a bit and on
the other hand by getting this
certification the idea is that as people
you know even more and more consumers
start worrying about organic quality and
how their cannabis and medicine are
being produced that that cannabis will
have a higher market value so they can
get maybe 20% more I made that number up
but but a enough of an increase in their
sales and the price of the flower that
they're growing to offset the cost of
the certification exactly and I think
that that's where so far the
Annamayya certifications have struggled
so it's been a struggle to get that
price P premium for the grower that is
part of the certification so with
certified kind yeah you know folks are
able to get a price premium and they're
also able to get into dispensaries that
they might not otherwise have an
introduction into because they can go
into dispensary and the dispensary knows
what certified pine is okay you're
certified under are great as opposed to
you know some folks have to approach
dispensaries just cold either just cold
calling on these dispensaries so so the
certifications can help make business
connections it can help it can help
prove to some a complete stranger that
there's you know that they're farming in
a certain style in a certain way
organically and they think that you know
I should probably mention the Sun on
earth program because one of the
interesting things about Sun earners
certified which I'm also part of is that
they've been able to demand for the
brother David's brand anyway that's the
cannabis brand that David Bronner's has
created it's a non-profit cannabis brand
they've been able to leverage a 10%
price premium for their growers that are
marketing with them so yeah I want to
just touch on this so your job as a
certifier is our certifying agency such
as Sun and Earth or certified kind is
one to make sure that that the farm is
doing what they say they're doing that
the product that's coming out of the
farm is clean and in theory organic and
then your other job is to educate the
public so educate dispensaries so that
when customers come in and ask
you know what's what's your safest
cannabis or what's your you know
cleanest most organic cannabis they can
look at the certified kind or Sun and
Earth certification as a way of knowing
that product is going to be of a certain
quality or at least produced a certain
in a certain fashion and then lastly to
educate consumers so that a medical
patient or even a recreational user like
is someone up here in Washington could
walk into a store and say hey what what
can I get that's that's organic where
that term actually might mean something
they can then they could point to
certified kind or in California and you
know certified kind and Sun and Earth I
think that's really powerful so there's
a lot of challenges associated with a
with setting up a certifying agency like
yourself that I think people need to be
aware of but let's let's talk about
Senator so Senator that goes so far
beyond Organic Standards it's pretty
incredible I just interviewed David
Bronner yesterday I may be putting out
both these podcasts really soon do you
want to just give your quick take on it
cuz I did talk about it already and I
know you haven't heard David's podcast
so you're kind of firing from the hip
but what's your what's your quick you
know one to two minute version of the
Sun and Earth certification yeah well
you know if certified kind is helping to
ensure that cars are following Organic
Standards Sun and Earth certified goes
beyond that so it's it's a level up from
certified kind because it only they'll
only certify or outdoor growers that are
planting in native soil so that means
Under the Sun in any earth right that's
why it's called Sun on earth and there's
also so those three pillars the Sun on
earth one is Earthcare and that's the
most rigorous part of the standard right
now the other two are community
engagement
so it's it's human empowerment and
community engagement or the other two
and that has to do with having written
policies for for employees
that protect them and it has to do with
engaging with the community so right now
it's creating a written strategy about
how you will engage in uplift the local
community that way the cannabis firms
aren't just acting in isolation not just
exploiting land and resources but giving
back to the local community so on the
cultivation side though there's also
additional standards there that make it
pretty difficult for example one of the
one of the hardest parts is producing
your own fertility on your from on-farm
resources so there's a requirement that
requires composting on-site increasing
biodiversity you know so on these farms
so far a lot of them are on the smaller
side but there are some that are you
know around 40,000 square feet as well
and they're doing things like
polyculture which means planting
cannabis and other plants together one
of the farms planted potatoes on both
sides of their cannabis row and I'm not
just talking like one potato here and
there but like a full-on potato planting
every foot for 300 feet on both sides of
the cannabis row you know so that's
amazing
that type of commitment to biodiversity
on the farm and and growing food on the
firm's well you know some of these farms
there's a farm down there that Senators
certified that only uses this plant this
algae this blue it's like a say oh no
it's like a algae that has a symbiotic
relationship with cyanobacteria it's
called a Zola have you ever heard of it
I haven't done a lot of research on
algae but I'm somewhat familiar with
what you're talking
about yeah it's pretty I did an
interesting subject for sure yeah anyway
there's a farm down there that has a
pond it's covered in Azolla and they
just take the azolla out of the pond
it's that prolific in their pond and
they use that as a soil amendment and
they use water and that's it
and so so the sun-earth certified
program is trying to help some
small-scale family farmers in in in
northern california maintain their way
of life essentially and they have
partner in that program is dr. Bronner's
and they have a David Bronner has his
own nonprofit canvass brand called
brother David's and the farms that are
that that they put underneath that brand
um get a price premium and are pretty
happy with the arrangement and that's
the other important piece you know it's
like if you're gonna have a third-party
certification and we have to take care
of the farmer and we have to educate the
consumer like you mentioned and so I
think all I think the Senators program
is nice because it's going to raise the
awareness of certification the value of
certification in California and
hopefully it will become a model where
we can have more of a unified cannabis
certification nationwide and that model
is really that these cannabis brands
that are profiting off the farms
themselves are paying in to help the
farmers pay for certification these
brands are helping pay for education
about why regenitive organic practices
are important and why consumers should
vote with their dollar and and support
these farms yeah and I think the fact
that you have a company as you know as
wonderful and ethical as dr. Bronner
supporting you in this certification is
huge you know I think that goes a long
way and really getting getting the
message out for people and yeah the
standard itself I suggest everyone even
if you're not you know thinking that's
the direction you're gonna go with your
farm I suggest people go out there and
just take a look at it on the website
I'll have the links to everything on the
podcast page for a certified kind and
Sun and Earth but it would give you an
idea of what what standards are
necessary if you decide that you want to
be organic or even if you're not ready
to go there right now but in the future
if you see you know in your state that
becoming something that has value this
is a way to set yourself up to be
successful now because I know what Sun
and Earth and I haven't I need to go
back and read the standards for a
certified kind but I know it's sudden
earth just like with the USDA you need
to have three years of organic practices
on a property before you can be even
considered is that is that accurate yeah
that's accurate the way organic
certification works around the world is
they've selected three years as the
transition period so that's you need to
have a clean land history for the three
years prior to the harvest that you're
going to be calling certified organic so
yeah that means people need to plan
ahead but the other thing that's
interesting is that in a in an indoor
setting where you're coming in
containers with new organic approved
potting soil you kidding you can
decrease that time so you know you can
get an a certification more quickly on
virgin land or fallow land that hasn't
been far in the last three years or an
indoor facility with new ponds well
that's interesting I wasn't aware of
that and great just to be clear you've
looked at you've you think you know my
recipe in my soil like my soul would
qualify kiss organic soil qualifies for
your program grout oh yeah we have a
number of the indoor growers are using
your soil yeah you're so
for organic it's double usda-approved
and it sounds like it's CDFA oh I am a
fruit so yeah okay that was my that was
my Ken shameless plug no oh no and I
think we also got it approved with
Oregon so a few years a few years ago
yeah I really I really appreciate your
help with all of that well is there
anything you want to add just before we
sign off regarding what you're seeing on
these farms since you are visiting so
many farms any you know potential
pitfalls or stumbling blocks that are
really common for farms that are
interested in moving towards organic
certification well yeah a pitfall would
be to not do your research not do your
homework if you want organic
certification you can't rely on somebody
trying to tell you or convince you that
a certain fertilizer is allowed in
organics unless you absolutely know that
it is and so that's I see that a lot
like you know uneducated people or
people that don't really know what
organics means trying to convince
managers or owners that a certain input
is allowed when it has actually
synthetic calcium nitrate in it or you
know monopotassium phosphate so so first
of all do your homework and get away
from bottled nutrients because a lot of
the bottle of nutrients do have
synthetic chemical fertilizers in them
and the whole concept of organic is
trying to enhance natural nutrient
cycling in your soil you can do that in
if you're an indoor grower you can do
that definitely if you're an outdoor
grower I I think that folks are starting
to experiment with plant ferments and a
lot of the people that are deep into
plant ferments this is like Korean
natural farming they they
see higher or unique terpenes being
expressed but you know a strategy and
organics would be not to put all your
eggs in one basket either so I would say
you know although some of these things
are trending right now you always have
to keep an open mind but stick with what
you what works for you you know in
organics and so for a lot of folks
that's you know if they're outdoors you
take a soil test you you valuate it and
you apply organic soil amendments prior
to planting and what we learned with
hemp this year was that if done properly
you don't need to apply any other
amendment or for fertigation step at all
and so devising like these simple
systems is the best way to go like a
complex feeding schedule is isn't
necessary and in it it is probably going
to confuse you and you're not going to
know how to tweak it really I would say
just you know if you're trying to go
organic so as simple as possible that's
good advice and just to build on your
your previous comment one thing I
learned from being a supplier to the
organic industry on the AG and
horticultural side is you always want to
check with a certifier before you apply
anything if you're not sure about a
bottle of nutrient or an amendment or
anything like that call up a certifier
and and double-check those lists so you
can look on the Omni list and you can
look on the double USDA and CDFA lists
and see if that product is listed and if
it's not do not apply it without talking
to whoever sort of fire you're working
with because it's much easier to go to
not apply a product than it is to deal
with the aftermath of applying something
that wasn't allowed so oh yeah that's
the worst it's the worst
you know because you
it's your land kicked out for three
years for applying something that's not
allowed in organics yeah well hey Andrew
I really appreciate your time today
I thought we I thought we covered a lot
around certification and I'll include
your information if people have specific
questions but thanks for thanks for your
time and I hope people will check out
certified kind and the Sun and Earth
certification right on thank dad andrew
black was certified kind and the sun and
earth certification stay tuned next
episode when we dive back into the
science with some of the latest research
and cannabis cultivation with dr. Darren
Caplan you were listening to the
cannabis cultivation and science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy don't forget to
check out our website at WWE
for more information and resources sign
up for our newsletter on our website
homepage so you can stay up to date give
us a follow on Instagram and leave us a
rating and review on whatever platform
you're listening on thanks