[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge my
guest this week is a timely one Michael
Bowman is founding chair of the National
hemp association he's also the author of
section seven six zero six of the 2014
farm bill a provision that grants US
farmers the right to cultivate hemp in
states where hemp production is now
legal for the first time since Congress
passed a 1933 farm bill he's known in
some circles as mister hemp firs
activism and he has been instrumental in
shaping the state of Colorado's hemp
policy as chair of Colorado's new energy
future and served as co-chair of
governor elect bill Ritter's energy
transition team a graduate of the
Colorado agriculture and rural
Leadership Program Michael spent his
entire adult life in rural advocacy he
has served as founding board member of
numerous environmental and hemp advocacy
organizations including the rocky
mountain hemp Association Colorado
industrial hemp commission the American
Renewable Energy Institute and the
sustainable biodiesel alliance to name a
few he is also a co-founder of the
Colorado farm to cafeteria workgroup
adviser to the savory Institute and a
board member of the National American
industrial hemp association Michael is a
next generation fellow in couple of
Columbia University's American assembly
and a 2008 recipient of Gamma Sigma
Delta's significant achievement in
agriculture by Colorado State University
with everything going on right now
around him I thought it was the perfect
time to get him on the show to answer
some questions about what to expect in
2019 I brought on Nelson Lindsley from
poetry of plants to assist me in the
interview some of the audio quality of
this taping wasn't as good as I would
have liked so apologies in advance for
some of the background noise
anyway onto the show hey Michael thanks
a lot I appreciate you coming on the
show today it's great to be here and
thank you as well to Nelson Lindsley
poetry plants for coming on as well to
help with the interview thanks dad yeah
so Michael I really wanted to start out
just talking a little bit about your
personal background and how you got into
everything that you're doing now well
well thanks dad I am a fifth generation
Colorado and I grew up on our family's
farming and ranching operation on the
eastern plains and after college spent a
couple of decades full-time with the
family farm we had a rather large
operation but I was always interested in
sustainability and the environment and
and rural development and technology and
all that Nexus of things that that kind
of keep us on the cutting edge of you
know what's next in agriculture and then
we were plagued by the fact that our
operation was over the overall aquifer
where we grew a lot of grew and grow a
lot of corn in and that an entire
aquifers you might know as one of the
largest underground aquifers in the
world and we run sustainably depleting
it to grow corn predominantly in a way
that in under a kind of an economic
model where it was it may be one of the
worst economic models ever devised were
fully fossil water from the ground with
coal-fired power from Wyoming to produce
a crop that needed that still needs to
be subsidized by the federal government
it is it is it is of absolutely a house
of cards that we've set up and so I was
always interested in you know what's
next how do we how do we transition from
corn to something else how do we keep
our rural communities viable you know
what's that next what's what's the next
magic trick to to help us get better or
what we do and at that time and this was
in the late 90s and early 2000s I was
spending a lot of time in Zimbabwe with
Allan savory on on soils management soil
carbon was it interested me a lot in its
play and you know in absorbing
atmospheric carbon was with with good a
great organic content and
and and such and in those days you could
say you could talk about carbon sink or
carbon absorption and mostly get blank
stares from everybody but I happened to
be in the Bob way one trip and we were
sitting around a campfire one night and
an Australian couple came through and
they had just been in India of where
they were talking about this transition
from hemp economy basically have based
economy to GMO cotton and all the
struggles of the farmers were going
through and the trouble they were having
taking the centuries-old practice and
what they were doing in the industrial
had been moving into this chemically
based world and at that time they were
and still are there was a lot of
suicides happening in the farm country
because of because what was happening in
that society when you can't take care of
your family financially you there's
there's an honour killer there's an
honour suicide and there is something
over over two hundred thousand farmers
today that have committed suicide that
are generally related to this trend this
change this transition and they were
doing it and as many of them are doing
it by drinking the very chemicals
they're being forced to put on their
land for the first time ever and so I
came at this from initially from from a
kind of a social justice warrior
perspectives like this is just wrong we
got a you know we need to figure out
what what's happening here and then as I
wandered through that that history and
the story and the industrial hemp plant
I became obsessed with the plant and I
keep in mind our farm was in the in the
central Great Plains we were far enough
West that they were just breaking out
Prairie and starting to farm about the
time prohibition was in place so it
wouldn't place in 37 so industrial hemp
farming never made it as far west so I
was you know he's never introduced to
the to the plant and then as I learned
about the plant and it's you know and
it's need easily something that's
environmentally benign and something
that could that had thousands of
products it can be made from the plant
and and could be drought tolerance
checking every box for me is like okay
that why aren't you know why aren't we
in the United States doing that went
back and studied the
three of the Prohibition and what
happened in 37 then through 1970 with
with Nixon and and the Controlled
Substances Act and and then got really
fired up about the policy side of it I'd
done a lot of work in in in DC and
continued to do so around environment
sustainability over the last couple of
decades so I was no stranger to
Washington and no stranger to state
politics as well and so started my
journey in Colorado of educating people
about him from 2006 to 2010 I an another
woman at Linda Parker and Denver did
quarterly meetings and reached out to
farmers and the Bar Association and
legislators and and regulators to talk
about this plant and why is it illegal
and could Colorado step up and it take
be the tip of the spear runs on ending
this national prohibition and so 2011 we
got our legislature to pass a resolution
unanimously supporting the
reintroduction of the plant and 2000
2012 and we got our legislature to pass
a fight or phytoremediation bail a small
one that cara state university could
play and after the forest fires kind of
reclaiming some soil from from the vast
fires we'd had the summer before and
then in course in 2012 the fall of 2012
we passed our historic amendment 64
which ended prohibition and of the plant
in its entirety from recreational adult
use to industrial hemp farming so we
took our we scored that as our win you
know a washington state legalized that
same night where a time zone ahead so we
like to say we did it first but we did
it believe yeah we did it to say we did
it the same night and and off we went
and formed a national organization the
National Association of which I was a
founding board chair and and worked on
worked at both a federal level and state
levels then on getting states to
legalize so today the from that night in
in November of 12 in Colorado and
Washington I legalized we've gone from
to that evening to 41 today in this in
the late
late late May early June of 2013 I wrote
some language and took it to then
congressman polis it was now the
governor of Colorado and asked if he
would consider including that some the
amendment process for the then house
language for the 2013 which became the
2014 farm bill that that became section
7 606 which was the the amendment that
really opened the door for this industry
to to you know is to start doing what it
does best innovating and growing and
creating opportunities and so as you see
now over the last five years seven six
oh six by opening that door is we've
created the beginnings I think of a you
know a substantial and lasting industry
in the country I think last year we had
about seventy five thousand acres us
wide in the in the inner space and then
of course the the recent farm bill that
was signed about a little over a month
ago these schedules the plants and does
a number of other things along with that
language so I think we're we're well out
of the barn now and and looking forward
to you know creating these opportunities
and and and letting America get into a
place again where we can lead in
production and development of products
and job creation and all the things we
can do well when when when we have good
policy in place so what can we expect
for this year with the addition of the
2018 farm bill what are you seeing out
there well I think there's there's a
there's some irrational exuberance about
where we are not about the plants
potential or where we're going to go but
really where we are as an industry for
the the farm bill you know we still have
a process that has to be put in place by
the feds federal standards state plans
being approved and such and keep in mind
the government went in to shut down the
day after the farm bill was signed so
nothing has been done
per the prescriptive remedies in the in
the in the farm bill so we still have to
get you'll get those done the state said
that our
illegal will be in the process of
putting you're submitting plan to the to
the USDA those that aren't legal are
going to have to step up you know this
session and they don't well they don't
have to do anything but their
opportunity to step up legalize and let
their farmers be in the game you know
I'm in Iowa today and tomorrow and
Iowa's one of the nine that has not
legalized much to the chagrin of many of
the producers here in the state so we're
going to be you know trying to tease out
those those legislators who have been
somewhat reluctant to step into this
space and and get them in the in a
position of support and I'm going to be
talking to a conference of over 900 land
managers in the u.s. tomorrow who
control a lot of land in the United
States that are interested in in this is
a viable third crop a new rotation and
you know and frankly if we're gonna if
we're going to take this industry to the
you know to the fiber and bio plastics
and and in composites world and
hempcrete and the things that that we
know that spine is very good at you know
we're gonna have to get to a scale and
acreage that that's far beyond where we
are today so I think 2019 is still going
to be I mean I I still see this as a
transition year they'll likely see again
a bump in acreage but I don't think
we're gonna see the you know the large
increases until after until after this
year because of some of the constraints
that we that are you know still
practically in place
Michael what's the biggest pushback
you're hearing from legislation and the
politicians are on the government scale
side of things to keep this from being
legal in all 50 states I mean that's a
curious thing for me is it directly
related to cannabis or is well another
yeah you know it's still a I think I'm
lingering the reefer madness here a lot
of it is generational if you've got if
you have a regulator or a legislator
who's maybe in their 70s or early 80s
they really do believe that this is the
devil's lettuce you know no matter what
you say it doesn't matter what what it
is
to them there is no distinction and in
fact interestingly enough in Hawaii
yesterday representative Cynthia Thielen
who's been a bulwark office she's just
an incredible been incredible supporter
of this industry over her years in the
Hawaii State Legislature had to put out
a very terse press release to the
department to the Hawaii Department of
Agriculture's bill that they had
submitted to the - they're just convene
legislature where they still refer to it
as a scheduled substance and and and in
their case there's a very active DEA
concern over there that that has that
has never liked the idea of legalizing
hemp and so they're you know so that's
one case and the other and the other
case is I'd say in Iowa I think it's
been a Senator Grassley has been very
slow to warm up to this idea and again I
think that's for him that's generational
they do you know they they just believe
this is a slippery slope to you heroin
for babies you know the questions where
do we stop well you know well maybe you
stop somewhere between heroin for baby
you know I mean it's you know the jokes
gonna write themselves and then and then
I don't mean that is it it's not funny
because this is a serious issue when you
were talking debating science but it is
amusing that in you know twenty nineteen
were still having science-based
arguments on this plant sure one of the
things you mentioned was just sort of
maybe to mute the exuberance a little
bit for 2019
that was something I heard a lot of from
other policy experts around that are
around hemp so if I'm understanding you
correctly you're thinking that 2019 is
still going to be the year of getting
policy and regulation in place and it
probably won't be till 2020 or maybe
even later when you could it's really
gonna it's really gonna hit and we're
gonna have this boom with industrial
hemp agreed I think we really are I
think we'll still see some growth in the
industry this year I think you know
we've we've seen sometimes two to three
x growth year to year since 2014 so I we
will have some growth but but you know
frankly we don't have the infrastructure
in place to handle a large crop and what
we don't want to do is May
the same mistake on a Canada did in
1998-99 where they opened the door let
the farmers you know the farmers grew
you know a lot of acreage early on with
really no market develop no
infrastructure to take that seed into a
hemp heart or you know the the stock
into into a fiber or herd and and and so
we've got that we've we've got to have
it this isn't all hands on deck you know
opportunities last challenge here to to
bring you know private private interests
and and money and government and policy
and farmers together to build us out i I
think we can do it quickly with the
right but with the right partners but
again we you know we have a lot of
probably the most the largest void and
all of this is the the lack of
infrastructure so one other question
I've I had is I've heard a lot of issues
around cross pollination with type 1
plants a lot of concern from cannabis
growers that are growing high THC plants
with this idea of industrial hemp taking
off and poor regulation on the part of
farmers will cause you know them to ruin
a lot of sense of mere crops well that
is a you know that is a valid concern we
had to deal with that in Colorado early
on south color southern Colorado and
your Pueblo where there was a lot of
both outdoor marijuana grows and hemp
and in that case you know I think under
the threat of the the county and state
you know instituting regulations they've
self regulated I know in Oregon I think
they if I remember right that the first
year they canceled that industrial had
program the first year because of some
of the most concerns of the established
type one grower so I think that those
are valid concerns that those are
concerns in Hawaii they're frankly going
to be concerns in a lot of places if not
everywhere and so those that's one of
the you know that is that is one of the
issues we're really going to have to
look at carefully and and you keep
everybody informed on that because we
the last thing we want is a in and then
the possibility of a train wreck where
we have you know people permitted to do
type 1 and type 2
you know offense the offense or defense
here so we've got to incorporate that
that can it's real so is the solution
right now regulation around locations so
that making sure say for example that
any industrial hemp is going to be at
least five miles or whatever distance is
deemed appropriate from say pre-existing
type one cultivation locations I think
at the very least is going to take some
you know the state regulators to be able
to map this and be able to you know what
would I know an application is received
to you know either either respond or
because I think it's going to be a
little messy in the in the beginning
because there's going to be a rush of
permits you know for for this and in the
lack of a state or county regulatory
framework is going to is going what
we're gonna do I think we'd almost be
assured we're gonna have a couple train
wrecks to the shooter and then I mean
large ones but we're gonna we're gonna
have this collision somewhere some well
how some way because there just isn't
you know enough oversight in place to at
least even just alert the folks you know
what's happening in their backyard oh so
you think that some legal growers in
states are going to get hit with pollen
just out of the blue at some point
unaware that there was even have going
on in their area is that is that the
concern that you're raising I do think
yes I do think that that's exactly the
like the case tab that there will be
there will be some you know unintended
these aren't going to be you know a
purposeful plants and and nobody's doing
that job to you to purposely harm
another but I I can imagine that we will
have that scenario in more than one
place in nineteen teaching direction on
the genetic side where are you finding
most most people are sourcing seed and
are you seeing any particular cultivars
being more highly sourced or cultivated
than others at this point in time well
most of the seat for the traditional
grows I would say just from my
experience it
mean out of can another X X 59 seems to
be you know very popular I know there's
some there's a company bringing in seeds
now from from Eastern or Western Europe
that they believe will be the wool you
won't get hot so and that we're gonna
see a lot of that until we get you know
more certified seed in place more more
of our own genetics in place of course
Colorado's come a hot bed right now for
genetic work see genetics and and so on
and but but you all be all everything is
coming out of there your small quantity
still test plots so I think the bulk of
this is still going to be from the
traditional side again imports okay and
when you see I haven't seen an
industrial have field in person yet but
what I'm picturing is something with a
lot of genetic diversity and variety
where you're gonna have plants of all
Heights and sizes
we haven't gotten breeding as I
understand it to the point where like
another agricultural crop where you'll
see consistency across the field are we
headed that direction or are you already
seeing some of that in the field well I
you know from what I'm I keep in mind
that you know the vast majority of acres
in the US haven't have been
non-traditional but the in some fields
of the Canadian seed brought in that was
very uniform I have witnessed a field in
Colorado and and one in Kentucky that
was very erratic in its in its heights
so I and I don't know what seed was he'd
stock the the erratic Heights were but
but from what I saw on the I'm the
import from from the Canadian side they
seem to be pretty uniform so I've got a
two parter Michael is there any way you
can explain why the wording regarding
the FDA and the Food Drug and Cosmetic
Act Authority was included in the bill
well keep in mind that you know this
bill was was predominantly written in
Senator McConnell's office although it's
been the bulk of that language has been
a kind of a succession of language
from the 2000 I'm from that from the
industrial hemp farming act that started
in 2013 I can't say that I think that
you know as word as word as we're ending
and an eighth decade old oversight of
the federal government by this and the
concerns that have had their fingers on
this pie so that would that be FDA or
DEA you know these you know these these
old regulators die hard and I and I
think that I'm gonna I'm somewhat
speculative but you know the FDA has
always had authority over labeling and
claims and I think they will continue to
to do that to the extent that we're
going to be in the supplement or food
additive space even though we're deep
even though that we are going to be d
scheduled on an agricultural crop you
know I think they're the this is just a
matter of a time frame of how we kind of
we lessen that oversight and and and and
get to a you know kind of you know a
less relaxed atmosphere and I don't
really relaxed in the sense that we want
to put anything out bad I just mean that
that the the a and I think and I think
we need to look at the the nuance and
the rhetoric that comes from their from
their statements their their their
statement kept that which came out the
day after you know I think was you know
when I look at it I think it's you know
I think they had to do what they had to
do they they still have their their
framework and what they think they need
to do and and again this policy journey
isn't done we're gonna have some we'll
have some clean up language I think we
may you know over time see things like
increases in the THC we know that a year
ago congressman Bob Goodlatte who was
the chair of the House Judiciary was
open to moving that up to a to a point
six you know so I think III don't get
too tangled up and in some of this I
watch a lot of social media feeds and I
generally don't engage because I think
there is a lot of you know Osteria
there's a lot of it goes from hysteria
to concern to well this is you know for
n for my role which
generally been policy you know I think
these these things are it's just not one
giant step and you fix everything will
continue to tweak and and and make it
better for the industry and I I'm not a
I'm not really a conspiracy theory guy
on what's going on here but maybe they
exist I don't know I I don't you know
that's not my world and I don't and I
don't really kind of fall into that camp
I think that we're demonstrating that
this is going to be a you know a serious
robust industry with a lot of
opportunity and I and and the and if
there's anything politicians understand
is you know the job creation and the
things that all the things that are good
about this industry and so it's our job
as advocates to continue to push for you
know better and better language and
environments and it's and it's a the
regulator's job to to take is that
generally take it as conservative
approach as they can what's a with with
the with the regulations they've been
handed so in somewhere in the middle of
all that we we find a way to all coexist
and I think that's you know that's
that's my net native my opinion and and
not shared by everyone but that's but
it's but it's mine so you're in Iowa
like you said which is a state that is
not legalized yet what are you seeing
from farmers they're like you know crop
farmers that have been growing other
vegetables and other crops is they're
becoming sort of this acceptance of of
hemp as a possibility are people getting
excited about it is there's still a lot
of negativity and and and things like
that around the crop what are you seeing
well I see oh and I see and hear a lot
of enthusiasm for that I think again at
just the this general disconnect between
policymakers and you know farmers and
and rural advocates and those knows on
the ground
mostly rooted in you know again
decades-old myths and lies and and
constructs that that made no sense at
all so I I think his general enthusiasm
and but but in and then I was case you
know they're very corn centric there's a
lot of genetics companies and
chemical companies here most of this is
all you know built upon that that house
of cards which we call the you know the
farm bill the and and you know
everything that that props that system
up so there's there's infrastructure and
history here and the legacy to what
Iowans many Iowans think they are and
then you have a very I think a strong
and growing group out there that know
that we need you know we need a third
way we need up we need a third
illegitimate third crop to do a lot of
things whether it's clean up soil
cleaning up the environment and creating
new jobs for rural Iowa and rural
America ok that brought up an
interesting question because you
mentioned remediation when we're talking
about hemp right now how do you how are
you defining that versus say a lot of
what people are talking about around
CBDs so I realized that it seems that a
lot of the cultivation that people are
most excited about right now is not from
like a textile or a more traditional
industrial hemp perspective but really
for the the CBD possibilities what are
how are you defining these terms and how
do you think they're relevant in terms
of how people are looking to grow the
plant well I'd say in the regenerative
space that is that is that is most
definitely going to be in the
traditional growth not the not the CBD
space so I think we have in one side we
have on the CB side you know health and
wellness and and and and you know grow
naturally and job creation doing what
we're doing then then over on the other
side of the ledger with more traditional
grows is where we're going to see the
you know I think the practice of
regenerative soil and and and so our
remediation and and then the things that
that plant does best when it's planted
you in the more traditional terms sir
you seeing is maybe becoming part of a
more conventional crop cycle for Iowans
is a way of remediating the soil then is
that that's how we you know I think
it'll be both because I think that the
magic of this plant is that it it
presides it you know it provides a space
for
for everyone whether you're a small Iowa
farmer who wouldn't be surrounded by
traditional crops of wanting to
incorporate you know some a CBD Grove or
a young one of your children wanted to
return you're a young person coming back
wanting to come back to the rural
landscape you're gonna have I think the
end and you're willing to put in that
work in that time you know I the the CBD
space you know allows that opportunity
to come to fruition if you're a more
traditional AIA one if you're a corn and
soybean farmer you're looking for a
rotation maybe your your buffer areas
would be better suited to a hemp crop
from from a water quality and soil
quality perspective you'll do that now
again we're going to get back into you
know that this these spacing issues and
and in the pollination challenges with
that but but we're gonna have both so if
you could wave a magic wand and create
whatever policy you wanted around hemp
and cannabis how would you set up a
state like Iowa
well I think that we may see and it may
be useful if we get it down to a more
local level or from a county perspective
you know now that we've we've ended the
prohibition of the federal level we have
statewide regulations but I think
ultimately this is going to have to come
down to some some County involvement
where we we're where we map our they
there's going to have to be I think
there's gonna have to be a lot of work
on the county level on on how these
worlds are going to live together
I don't see any way of getting around
that because in in as in my you know my
my earlier description of you know small
farmers coming back there's a lot of
small you know small farms here in Iowa
are trying to hang on did it over
Minnesota and Wisconsin they where I've
spend a lot of time with the last couple
of weeks there's small farmers wanted to
get into this space and and and and
maybe we're gonna have regions where
where the counties will permit one but
not the other or they give priority to
one over the other so the permitting
process has a you know it has a priority
chain though and but I just don't know
how we're gonna get around not doing
that frankly so you think this crop
could be a savior for a
of struggling farmers on the
agricultural side or at least it might
have that potential oh I absolutely do I
mean I I've seen it in Colorado you know
this is this is attracting young people
back to these small farms and towns that
I'd frankly you know these young people
and and are very excited and they're
excited about the scrub now they're not
going to come back to these small towns
to grow corn or soybeans or you know
those kind of things but there's this
plan just opens up a whole new range of
opportunities for that to happen and I
can tell you I've spent a lot of again
going back to Minnesota and Wisconsin
the last couple of weeks you know these
these small dairy farms that are just
you know just dying on the vine if
they're not dead already as a dairy farm
you know they have land they have barns
they have ways to you know get back in
the game and stay on the farm and that's
you know that's really excited me my
maternal grandfather was a small dairy
farmer in Minnesota he lived in a county
that was one of the largest milk
producing counties in Minnesota you know
40 years ago there's there's almost no
dairies left today but the whole you
know the rich land the barns these it's
the descendants who want to come back
that's the that's a real thing
and so I'm really I for me I'm really
excited about that you know that kind of
opportunity I'm also excited about the
regenerative nature and getting a
legitimate third crop in that in a real
rotation for the corn and soybean
farmers but for me what hits home the
closest is this opportunity for the
smaller farms to you have something
that's going to let them be viable well
this could be a big economic boon for
the state as well I feel like especially
those states that are more agrarian and
have struggled you know that sort of it
seems like you know the center of the
United States there you see sea hemp is
maybe being that possible crop
especially if we if we eventually move
to some intrastate eat you know commerce
on this
I do I do I'm more convinced than ever
now that that is that is that this
that's this is the real deal for the for
that for those communities Michael when
we're looking at the the regulations
around the THC percentage do you think
that will get to a point where they'll
be some rounding on the THC percentage
or is 0.31 going to be counted the same
as point or are you know 10 you know
like dude right there's very like the
cultivars for CBD hemp and I did seven
acres this last season but they're
they're not super stable you can have
very you know a lot of them have best
back crossed and do cannabis strains to
get certain term profiles or structure
and my question is how are they how
we're going to be looking at this at the
future because then once you extract the
CBD you're going to be left with a
concentration that's above that limit of
THC that's to be destroyed so how are
they looking at this and where do you
think the future of how they're going to
treat the THC percentage in the plant
well I we are going to have to have this
conversation both of the federal level
and we're and as we see how the the feds
put their standards in place maybe we'll
get a little flavor of where we're USDA
is going to come from I think it's a
state level for instance in Colorado you
know I do think we're going to we're
gonna have it we have to and I think we
have the political will to set some kind
of research you know research category
in place it goes from let's say 0.32 one
I'm just sorting out some maybe point
eight or it may be something other other
than that but I think in our case I'm
going to use in use Colorado's case we
have a legislature and a governor and a
university system who wants our farmers
to flourish and understand that we're
early on in this game you're you know
not everything stable and and there's
there's no reason with the technology
and the science week we have and access
to that that's something that's point
three one should be destroyed and
considered you know marijuana
just a ludicrous so I think we're gonna
I'm gonna guess that in this next year I
think Colorado is going to be one of
them there may be others that they're
gonna step out and say okay we're going
to you know we're gonna we're gonna put
a buffer here and demonstrate it and
again then then and then probably have
to go back from a policy perspective
back to a federal level to the federal
level and and do some tweaking again
that's what I kind of refer to earlier
these these policy changes or you know
they're just not a one and done we're
gonna you know this is going to be a
constant modification or at least it's
gonna be a modification for for a period
of time as this industry grows because
as we know I'd you know what we want to
get back to science-based arguments I
have been in private meetings with DEA
concerns who would say privately that
they think the standard ought to be 1%
now they're not going to say that
publicly that's against you know that
that's in the face of the scheduling
parameters and and and whatever but
they're forced to regulate but they
would tell you that you know that they
think just and we know that there's
nothing there's no science behind two
point three right so I think our next
battle is is going to be proving that
you know proving that out and and in
putting something in place that's that
can be from a scientific perspective
perspective would be be put in place and
with that also relate to other
cannabinoids that are in the plants that
are not considered Schedule one but may
have a medical value because there's a
lot in the hemp and cannabis emo bars
that have more value that we haven't
even discovered yet and have there even
been a conversation on that or has it
just been a conversation around THC and
CBD which in my opinion is kind of
limited right well keep in mind you know
Abe language does you say you know all
extracts you know from that plant so and
into more to your point to your question
dad was know that the only conversations
are really around you know THC and just
the general CBD discussion but nothing
you know we have not drilled down beyond
that
you know in Washington well the other
thing I heard I got to hear Ron Ronald
Turco from Purdue speak and I'm hoping
to get him on the show too and one of
the things he mentioned is a lot of it
was around timing of harvest when when
you harvest the plant really determines
that THC content and plants that you
know may fail or may not fail was really
related just to timing agreed again
another one of those you know that
you're kind of that going back to you
know making those you know those
science-based arguments like he made you
know to regulators and and again you
know I think we're you know we're so
early in this game I mean if you really
think back we we took on you know eight
decades of lies and myths and and and
turned it on its head now how often do
we see that happen you know in our
federal government from you know from
policy so you know again and again going
back to that exuberance or irrational
exuberance I think what we what we where
we've gotten to is monumental I think we
still have a lot of work to go you know
a long way to go yet and getting this
right and good and so we can't rest on
our laurels we've got a you know
bringing at ease these things out test
some of the state levels we have an
argument in Congress for you know for
making tweaks and changes and and we
certainly have near the activists in
this community or passionate and I think
we if we can if we can not if we can
even if we can not mire ourselves and
infighting and and you know and focus on
kind of what's next
will will be a lot better off for and
then there will be a lot of what's next
is we've got a lot of those we're going
to deal with so Michael when I talk to
other individuals that are getting into
the space or investors a lot of what I
hear is that they're looking at
international supply of hemp biomass and
derivatives of him and that that's going
to be where the market that the market
isn't going to really land and I'm
Erica and I don't really believe that
personally I think that there's a unique
environment here that are going to be
specialized but I'm hearing that you
know there's a bit it seems like the
International hemp market has a good
head start on American Progress and the
question of you how do we balance those
imports with our our own growth and how
do we help educate people on the value
and the timeline essentially it's what
it does there appears to be a timeline
on the market in a sense as you know I
threw it through my glasses and and in
my view if we are going to have some
imports we see a lot of that happening
and whether it's important to biomass
with those imports of Canadian money
coming into the country to you know to
build this industry what Americans are
really good at is when you put a good
policy in place and turn them loose and
the world knows this
you know we innovate quickly we you know
we do good big things fast and so you
know I'm I think we'll have two phases
here we're going to see some of this
international we're gonna see the
importing we're gonna so we're gonna see
a lot of positioning by folks who want
to you know claim that X is going to
happen I don't believe that I believe in
kind of an American you know ingenuity
and what we're gonna do what we could do
here and I think we are we are going to
quickly catch up with the world and then
and then then be a leader beyond that
point in time part of part of what I
think is going to help us become that is
on the genetic development and
innovation around the cannabis genome
and the research that that a lot of
cannabis companies are beginning to do
and how that will carry into him so with
all that in mind do you is there a clear
path for hemp seed USDA certification at
the moment or is that still ambiguous
it's still ambiguous yeah it's ambiguous
okay so when I look at the some of the
regulations in California because
California has not issued farm IDs yet
but they're allowing it so it's this
weird kind of Wild West cowboy gray area
but what they require is
a type of seed certification and they
call it like foundational generational
and there's another term that that's
escaping me right now so if you're a
hemp farmer in California and you're
required to start with some kind of
level of certified hemp seed would that
mean that you would have to purchase the
seed out of the country like for you
know with some other international
certified seed stock or is that
something that we can create under a
research program with the right research
institution well I think that they're
gonna have to get the oscar sort of the
international certifications probably
enough to kind of like California is
just you know but when I talk to folks
when you look at the mess in California
and them and the the Keystone Cops and
in Hawaii on this thing you just think
really I we are in 2019 right yeah well
some of us aren't yet but but so so I
think that's yeah I I think California's
you know well I'm gonna welcome
California to the family when they get
their act together got here to your
point I think they're gonna they're
gonna have just some kind of
international certification of course
the I believe I haven't stayed you know
was like really close to the rollout of
the of the you know they're down in the
weeds but I do believe that there's a a
pretty significant influence from the
canadian seed market in that in that
california framework so guess we'll see
how that plays so with that in mind what
i've seen
so the hemp the hemp cultivars that i
was able to purchase you know i really
look at is a low THC cannabis cultivar
those were created under a research
program and certified under the purchase
of another industrial hemp seed and it's
just been a little unclear on how
there's a highway or a path for these
new cultivars to emerge where they can
be considered hemp or is it just being
measured on THC or is there going to be
some is this is still muddy and i'm
and questions that can't be answered
yeah I think for me that you're probably
asking the question that I can't answer
I think that you know is yet to be seen
and yeah yet to be seen how that plays
out so I I wish I could I wish I had a
good answer for that Ted but I don't
okay so and then the final thing I just
wanted to say is I wanted to thank you
personally for being a part of this
movement and doing the work that you've
done it's opened up a considerable
amount of doors for a lot of people you
probably don't know and a lot of people
you know and I see that this opportunity
is saving a lot of struggling cannabis
cannabis farmers as well and I'm seeing
a lot of pivots from cannabis into him
because some of the understanding and
experience will apply especially when
cultivating the higher CBD I just wanted
to thank you for all that work well I
thank you and I'd be remiss if I didn't
mention that you know I've had the
govern the blessing I'm doing the Willie
Nelson family for a little over 15 years
and one of my first conversations with
Willie back in the day when and early on
who this and he said that you know we
will start saving the small American
farmer the day that they can start
growing cannabis on their farms and I
got you know he was he was right it just
took us a long time to get here but at
least we're here we got a place to start
from now I did have one last question
for you Michael I was wondering if so if
I'm if I'm a person a grower or a farmer
that wants to get into hemp do you have
a sort of a pathway or any
recommendations for someone he wants to
start exploring that as a potential
field well the best place to start you
know is at least I know in Colorado and
many other states are putting together
some really good information on their
son or State Department of Agriculture
websites so you know that's always a I'd
say that's always a good place to start
there your regulators or you're gonna
have to you know go through them all
roads go through them and so I know
Minnesota's you know putting together
you know has a nice place Colorado does
as well you some of the other national
organizations or soup
great resources you know bode hemp and
and the HIA I've got some great
resources on on their web pages as well
so I think I you know kind of focus on
both and get to know your know your
regulator and and then and then then
move into some of those those
organizations and and and join the
organization and and you know help
support the cause because they're
they're the frontline of policy great
well I really appreciate your time today
that was very helpful for me and
learning more about what's going on in
the hemp industry and yeah good luck
with your with all the talks and
speaking engagements that you have
around hemp and everything you're doing
thank you oh you're very welcome as at
the site it'll be fun tonight this
conference has had the keynote at Baia
by Martha Stewart so I'll have a chance
to bend Martha's ear this evening over
over dinner about about campuses where
will we get her in our space that was
Michael Bowman and you are listening to
the cannabis cultivation and science
podcast I'd like to thank Nelson Linsley
for coming on the show to assist with
the interview I'd also like to thank
everyone who is donated to the patreon
account I really appreciate the support
of the podcast you can check that out at
wwk tree on Comm backslash kay is
organics and don't forget to check out
my website where I put up a ton of
information and also offer a wide
variety of organic amendments soils and
other gardening products at WWE is
organics calm thanks for listening
you