[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host tadd
hussey of kiss organics this is the
podcast where we discuss the cutting
edge of growing from a science-based
perspective and drawing top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge
my guest this week is rufus atkinrenlola
he is a phd candidate and graduate
research assistant in the entomology and
plant pathology department at the
university of tennessee knoxville he
works in the research programs of ut
specialty crops and field crop pathology
focusing on sustainable disease and
integrated pest management systems where
he's co-mentored by doctors heather
kelly and zachariah hansen
rufus has a masters of science degree in
agronomy focused on plant pathology from
the university of nebraska-lincoln and a
bachelor's of science degree in
microbiology from atakunle adjacent
university in nigeria his areas of
interest include management of field and
specialty crops with emphasis on the
improved adoption of integrated pest
management and natural products and crop
protection rufus was recently awarded a
developing emerging agricultural leader
and talent grant by cortiva agriscience
in recognizing his potentials as an
emerging crop protection future leader
now on to the show
hi rufus thanks for coming on the show
today
hey hi kay thank you for having me
absolutely so can we start off uh with
you just telling telling listeners a
little bit about yourself
okay so uh my name is rifle sakurai so
i'm originally from nigeria
and
i
nigeria i started microbiology and then
in 2016 i'm 2014 i moved to the u.s
where i studied
agony and plan pathology in university
of nebraska
and 2018 i moved to tennessee where i'm
currently
learning of my phd in plant pathology
that is that's quite a journey so uh
you're you're currently a graduate
research assistant at the university of
tennessee you studied microbiology in
nigeria and then nebraska and now
tennessee so you've you're fairly well
traveled um i'm just for listeners to
understand i know some people are uh
have been have mentioned in the past
they're hard of hearing so i may repeat
some things
rufus shares just just for the ease of
those people but um
i really wanted to share
rufus's uh his research because it's
it's quite interesting so you
you have a paper that i'm looking at
right now that's called hemp fungicide
efficacy field trial for leaf spot and
powdery mildew
can you
talk a little bit about um
how you're working with hemp and uh why
you picked
uh you know leaf spot and powdery mildew
for your trial
yeah thank you chuck
so in tennessee since turn force uh
maybe lies and
in
and you can see there have been a lot of
people
interested in going home and um
but there is so much uh little uh
knowledge and information about
uh disease that are facing
since so little research have been
you know conducted in that area
and in tennessee
uh among the most
common disease that our growers
reported to the professors on extension
especially
um
please support
one of the most important
diseases
especially uh are fed
in
speed you know you can have damage up to
50 to 60 cents of leaf
and when that airport can cause a lot of
trouble i can leave the evolution and
illusions on the leaf
and
if it's not properly managed it could
you know affect
the quality of the
belief including even the
tricon
and in home in tennessee the
the muslim varieties of henrietta so
these are the same for cbd
uh just for clarity between him and
marijuana
uh
in tennessee trump
is
this major whereas marana is illegal
um to differentiate that
where
the
the thc content which is the psychology
compound in m is about 0.3
uh
so if it's higher than that it is
considered to be marijuana so the hemp
that we produce is a ham for cbd which
is there which is different for uh
marijuana so
yeah going back to
why i choose the disease
so there are a lot of trouble with uh
helpless part and problem will do
but there's no information there's no
amount of knowledge on
how to what can be used to control it
there's no data
and
even
products that are labeled
they are not labeled for hemp
so some relatively new new plan to these
states so that's why we picked
the research company to look at
some products that can be
you know can use to manage the disease
okay so that makes sense so it uh
there just isn't a lot of data out there
or research it really doesn't exist yet
this is a new crop
um
pretty much worldwide when it comes to
the academic world there's been some
research i know out of israel and i've
seen some work out of israel or italy
as well um and and we're starting to see
research here in the united states on
hemp which
as you mentioned is different than um
what you know the government calls
marijuana what growers call cannabis um
but you're absolutely right there now in
terms of
hemp leaf spot and powdery mildew you
know
that's going to cause leaf necrosis so
we're losing the leaf's ability to
photosynthesize
um it's stressing the plant which can
lead to
greater pest uh or decreased pest
resistance um and also like you
mentioned just affect the overall vigor
and health of of your crop
and which which would affect your yields
overall so
yeah powdery mildew is one i'm more
familiar with here in washington state i
haven't had to deal with hemp leaf spot
or
anything like that
myself but i'm aware of what you're
saying so
so for this trial
um
you guys looked at
the research shows let me see here i'm
i'm looking at the paper now and i'll
attach it to
the uh podcast page for people
but you set up a bunch of plots um what
why don't you just tell me what um
what did you compare in your research
okay
so uh you looked at four fungicide
products
correct yeah
can you uh
i'll go ahead and list them because i'm
reading this so you have stargus from
marone bioinnovations
death guard which is a general
hydroponic product
exile
from general hydroponics and regalia
from marone bio
um
what's uh so
what what did you find now these um
it looks like
a couple of these are
biological fungicides
oh yeah so
yeah
so the question is why do we select
those products right
yeah let's start there that's a that's a
good question
yeah that's a very good question
and
as i said earlier there are so
little uh products if i if there's this
at all that is delivered for him
so um
in
recently i think about last year or 2019
the epa
approved some product about 59 of the of
them
for him
and in tennessee only our photos were
approved by the uh can i see
uh department of agriculture
to be used on hemp
that even though they have been you know
approved there was no um
data
and also
the
uh all the product i see obviously uh
they are like
they call them reduce risk products are
unrealistic
and then that means the biological
products which
potentially are a lot less uh possibly
environment or to
an iman
compared to
the the conventional products
in in that are used for controlling the
such disease on other crops
so
basically these products are selected
because uh one they have just been
uh
approved by the uh tennessee
department of agriculture for use on
health and tenancy and secondly you know
we are particularly interested in you
know testing
uh
reduced risk products
which are you know more friendly
to the environment
so reduce so the reason you chose them
are because uh
you could you had to choose a product
that was approved
by uh the state of tennessee for use on
hemp and then you wanted to go with more
reduced risk products so things that
were you know organically listed or
approved by omri
which makes sense
and one thing that you mentioned that i
think is really important is is
that there is no data on these products
from a university and
just because a product is approved does
not mean it has good efficacy
so uh i think that's that's a really
important point for growers to think
about when they're choosing products to
apply because there's a lot of good
sales information around these products
but not a not a lot of research
now why not an oil-based product like so
the first thing i think of would be
something like um self oil x which is a
mineral oil based
product that's omri listed um
but it's not necessary i don't know if
it's been approved in tennessee for that
specific use
um
but but wouldn't pretty much any
oil-based product kill
a fungus
oh you say uh with any product skill
fungus is awkward uh in any like oil
based because it looks like you went
with um
you know biological and then uh
the regalia is a not weed extract and
then the exile is the potassium salts of
fatty acids
um
is there a reason you didn't choose an
oil-based product
in your trial
or was there just not available
on the market
yeah
yeah another another another criteria we
we use also to say let
uh data
uh me select that product to
to be tested is we also look at
some other states
what are the products that have been you
know tested by other scientists
in other states
so and when we looked at those are the
ones that we found that that from united
states has been tested and when when
scientists are interested in some
products in other states it shows that
every green light that such products may
be effective
you know
so the way you look online
there is no any data uh i mean you can
scientific uh thank you
like a plant disease management report
uh if you
look at that the superior basis you find
uh information on
uh
a particular product in the nearby you
know states
or seats within the same region you can
you know have some green lights weather
testing because ultimately we although
we want
results
that ultimately also we also want to be
able to recommend products to our
growers
and we want something that would be
effective for them
so
when we look at
the the
uh scientific literatures from other
states these are the ones that we see
okay maybe it has infected little ones
in other states and
it shows some potential
so
that's why we
we
we let us so not necessarily because
the other ones
uh that maybe all these periods are not
any
uh initial information that can
uh which we used to qualify as a
criteria you know for testing uh
yeah and
to be fair as a scientist i mean you
want to test everything you want to do
all this research but at the end of the
day you have to pick
something you have to start somewhere
and you know you can't
you can't test 20 products or your
statistical significance would be too
low so
yeah you know if you want to test every
product in fact
you you're gonna have a number of
numerous of them to test because there
are a lot of products there a lot of
products and so you have to have some
criteria
to go but a lot of
um all those further if you end up
testing one that does not mean you don't
have like good information i mean uh who
the efficacy is from me so at the end of
day you want to a twitter that's gonna
actually have
some good advocacy so that your growers
that you are serving as an extension
professor my my pr dr anthony
uh here is an education especially for
specialty crop
and and at the end of the day he
received calls from growers to get um
you know to give them recommendations on
something like this
so at the end of day we want to be able
to have like positive recommendations
something that can you know we can
actually say oh this is effective in
tennessee and you can use it
so you want you want to find something
that will be effective that you can
recommend to growers and that you know
works
it doesn't matter if it works in alaska
or in europe it matters if it works in
tennessee because those are the growers
that you work with
that makes sense so
you set up this experimental design and
um these plots
you were uh hand watering
uh two to three times per week and
weeding with mechanical cultivation
and um once you had it looks like i'm
reading your
your report here um leaf spot severity
around two percent you started the
fungicide applications and repeated
seven times at ten day intervals
and then you did disease ratings to
measure the severity of the disease um
and the the amount of disease
symptoms and instances you were seeing
on the leaf so
all of that sounds sounds great uh let's
let's just dive into the results what
what did you find with uh these four
products compared to your control
as far as reduction let's start with
leaf spot
yeah
as you probably see from the the results
section this resource table that's
prepared
uh
[Music]
most of the products have some level of
efficiency
uh
we have
okay let me
describe the treatment
in total we have a test treatment
and one of the treatment is the positive
control the positive control means
we know that this is effective it can
control this pathogen
and that is the quarters and even though
it's not labeled for tempting tendency
uh we we use that as our check you know
you can say that
when something work we'll be able to
control you
we're able to control it with our
treatment
then we have this another treatment we
have the untreated untreated treatment
which is
it means it is not treated with anything
that means the disease is there usually
continue to increase it was not
uh they're retaining then the four other
treatments
are
tested products which include the stegos
the regalia the dev guide and the exact
and you can see from the
result table
that
the
the most effective form among among the
four
uh
products
is the
regalia
and regalia has
moderates
relatively higher efficiency efficiency
compared to the
other uh two products
and if you can see
we look at the to summarize the affected
efficacy we look at the
uh you look at the disease in this table
this descendants means the summary of
the
uh indents
and this the summary of the incidence
and the
severity so the incidence measured
out of
let's say out of
the old plant
how
what is the proportion of the plant has
disease
for instance if the if the plant has
five branches is it all the branch that
has at least
a center of least what or just one of
the the branch or all of the branch so
that is in incidence
then the severity we look at the leaf
you know
on each leaf on of the plant
how many
uh parts or what proportion or
percentage of that leaf has the disease
so when we take the data
both incidence and severity together we
we multiply that and divide by hundreds
so to determine our disease index so
that is summary data
so if you look at the disease
uh index table
for
regalia
you will see that our value
in
during our
um
three days data collection date
you will see that it's always
uh
lower than the on on
than the
untreated can you see that
uh the on twitter has like for instance
during the first date the on twitter has
like a level
11 disease index why do they treat uh
regalia has six
and if you look at the final dates
regalia has um
and the on twitter has
24.
so
that shows that
is
controlling disease compared
to the untreated
again if you look at the area under
disease progress
that is also known as disease intensity
across the tire if we want to summarize
disease across the date
or during the period of the trial
so we also use that term also to
describe the disease
so you also look at the untreated which
is our
uh negative control you see that the
data
is higher than regalia regalia has lower
disease and disease
area under disease progress
compared to uh the untreated the
entrepreneur has 3
regalia has only
serious
one also if you look at the letter the
letter
after the the the
the value
regalia has letter b
whereas the untreated has letter a that
shows that this the letter is different
so when the letter is different it shows
that the values
or the efficacy of that treatment is
different from the untreated
so
yeah you can see that then
uh
when i'll go to the next effective one
is staggers
uh we can see that staggers
okay no exile as i as i
then followed by staggers
so for the
uh least thoughts
that regalia if you look at um
if you look at uh devgatt
you can see that the the number
for the dev guard is high
is
almost is similar not almost it's
similar to the data or on twitter's
control and that means
um
the plants that are treated with delgad
is not different
i mean the disease
not
significant
exactly
yeah i see what you're saying so
so so to summarize what you're saying is
between the untreated and death guard
when it came to leaf spot uh there was
no
uh statistically significant difference
you had potentially a two percent
reduction but your standard deviation
was probably greater than that yeah i
guess
um yeah and then and then you had exile
with 44
disease reduction stargus with 43
and regalia showing 41 so they all
that's why they have the b after the
disease intensity so
fairly moderate
um
disease reduction now one question i i
had in my head while i was i was
listening to this was did you spray uh
the the contr the untreated crop with
water as a way of removing that as a
variable in comparison to these other
treatments
like could just the application of water
reduce the amount the uh fungus
growth
um no that's a good question we did not
spray with water
because we were this study is a fit
study
if it was
uh if it were a growing study
where there is no rainfall
you know we
we
we normally you know spray with water
but the free trial when you spray your
products
and even though you do not spread the
untreated with water
you know
rain is always falling and
and so the same
rain
rain water can fall on the plants and
have the same effect on the heat
so
so we do not stray with water and
and i
that does not really have any effects on
the treatment
okay okay i was curious because i've
heard that even water with powdery
mildew i don't know what leaf spot can
help suppress powdery mildew but
obviously it also increases
the humidity on the leaf surface and
could lead to greater
powdery mildew uh grow yeah too so
i was just curious about that so so
you're saying with the rainfall and
everything else you guys chose not to
because you're you want your control to
be most similar to what a grower would
do
in tennessee which is
yeah
will be an application okay um
one other question i had with the
microbial products that you applied did
you did you do any microbial testing to
see
um if the microbes were present in the
concentrations that were claimed on the
labels
oh and
i think okay we did not test that
that alone is another yeah another story
to
to do that's a good question we we were
not you know planning towards direction
that direction we just want to test it
in the face to see okay
and to be clear i'm not bringing these
things up to criticize your work in the
least bit because
uh there's always there it's impossible
to look at every you know every variable
but it's important when evaluating a
study to look to ask questions
you know to think about what the
implications
you can draw from the data so one thing
you could say is well maybe those
bottles weren't as viable because they
had been sitting on a shelf for a long
time um so it may be worth going back at
some point as a separate researcher and
looking at that but that doesn't yeah
it doesn't invalidate your results at
all so i just i want to clarify that for
listeners that i'm not
i'm certainly not criticizing your
research
you get you give us a very good research
topic to to to
to to think on and that's a very good
one you know that would be another maybe
masters
uh
project well we should talk because um
i work with a
a gentleman our research scientist who i
work with dr ben higgins
he and i are always
coming up with new
new research we would love to see around
cannabis and hemp so i'd love to talk to
stay in touch and talk about this but
i'm glad to see more of this research is
coming out so that's that's the most
important thing is that we're starting
to get a body of knowledge that we can
begin to learn more about this crop
because
none of the research we're seeing right
now is definitive it's just it's just to
start pointing us in a direction to say
hey this is worth looking at you know so
yeah
and that's where we have to start um
let's let's talk about powder and mildew
so your results with
uh and this was what made me think of
the water thing is is the comparison of
the leaf spot versus powdery mildew
results because uh let's just start with
def guard you're you're you got no
significant reduction
um in disease intensity with def guard
on leaf spot but how about with powder
and mildew
yeah the problem of the uh we can see
that um
uh it's like uh if you look at devga and
status
they're like um
uh they walk in an inverse inverse
inverse way
the struggles control disease on
uh
this spot
but um
[Music]
uh powder will module
uh it was
relatively ineffective but that guy
became effective in controlling powder
mode
even though it was not
you know effective in controlling um
it was interesting when we saw the the
result
so we can see um that guy control about
52 percent disease control compared to
the control
um
uh
the sagas
uh only control less than
you know
very low disease
so the the the stargas and death guard
kind of switched ethicism
when it came to leaf spot and powdery
mildew so def guard
not effective against leaf spot 52
effective against powdery mildew stargas
43 effective against leaf spot which was
one of your higher
marks and yet only 20 against powdery
mildew so very not really effective at
all um
but then your other two products exile
and regalia and yeah
i have to go back here because i'm not
familiar um i know regalia is a not
wheat extract is exile a microbial or is
that the
potassium salts of fatty acids yeah it's
potassium salts sorts of
fatty acids that's exact and regalia is
the extracts of
these plants and root nuts
and
yeah regalia has been very effective
generally on both disease as you can see
yes you know and exactly it's more
effective on the padu module
so you basically with regalia
saw
no powdery mildew i mean 99
disease reduction
so it was it was
barely you were barely able to find it
that's amazing that you can't get better
data than that on efficacy um
that's quite good
so um um
oh go ahead um again
i do want to point the fact that in
steve's study
uh
powder module
trial is always compared to indoor
indoor trial now powder mildew is always
relatively
um
compared to in greenhouse
it's relatively low compared to the
prior is always very low compared to to
indoor
so
one of the reasons why you have that
level of
highly control
may be the fact that disease prior
you know uh
in in
outside is is
low because the as you said earlier
rainfall actually can affect the powder
modulu prayer
you know when there is water it can you
know reduce the the building of a spores
on the leaf
and then if you now put an effective
product it's easily uh control the
disease so that's one of the strengths
of the regalia the fact that and also
you know i have other
i've done several other tests in the
greenhouse and we are hoping to push out
another uh publication
and by the end of this year uh great for
for a ton of greyhounds uh trials and we
have tested some
new products
and i'm deciding about that so you're
gonna see some
results as well wonderful i would i
would love to see that when that's
available um so so you're you're
speculating that um
this the spore pressure from powdery
mildew
is lower
outdoors than indoors and the rainfall
events help wash away or don't allow the
the pm to get as an effective of a
hold on the leaf itself
um yeah is that what you're saying yeah
yeah you know i've worked both in both
systems so i've seen powder module prior
uh uh in both system and i've seen you
know how the difference the difference
that you know in the greenhouse you have
the humidity and
and
you know warm temperature grows the
control in the control environment which
is very conducive for powder models
to develop
and
there's no that scenario or occasional
info that washes the weather the plant
there's no
the eye temperature that you know you
know very high temperature during the
summer that can
you know so
uh
i see as i said in the in the greenhouse
it's always if
i can share some of the pictures i have
if you look at the picture of the
greenhouse infestable model and they
feed infested you're going to see very
very different you know a very good
difference you can get
oh so they they physically display
powdery mildew the same species of
powdery mildew will physically display
differently in a greenhouse leaf than an
outdoor leaf is what you're saying
that's a good question that you you
raise now
when you were talking my thought was i
wonder if we could if we could do
targeted heat treatments
or targeted humidity treatments similar
to what you might experience outdoors as
a way of lowering spore pressure in a
controlled environment i mean there's so
many there's so many different ways to
approach this yeah very good that's a
very good in our greyhound study we look
at the
the
we look at we
we have been able to identify the
species that caused the
igneous powder model
and but we did not
look at them
even though generally speaking in
thailand so we know that gonover my
scene gonna gonna know my series for the
species that caused the parliament we
cannot say that we have not uh looked at
the
species itself whether is uh
there are different
species
species that cause them
the problem on the bed we've not been
able to identify for the
grain
for the
feed
and
okay
so you're what you're saying is that you
identified the species for the
greenhouse which is golovino mices
but um
actually
we
id the identification goal of enormous
ambrosiae which is the most one of the
most common uh powder module pathogen in
this environment okay okay
but just for listeners uh powdery mildew
is sort of a catch-all term for numerous
species that produce a white powdery
substance on a leaf surface so
and they don't all cross between plant
to plant so you could have two different
species of plants and one could be
infected and the other one could not uh
just based on that particular species of
powdery mildew and what plants it can
infect so
um
well well getting back to your research
here so so you found um neither neither
of the biological products interestingly
enough
was able to provide moderate efficacy
across leaf spot and powdery mildew
yeah but both of the uh non-biologicals
so you had an extract and then the
potassium
salts of fatty acids uh showed good
efficacy across leaf spot and powdery
mildew um yeah
did you find any degradation of
trichomes or or anything that affected
the final product with any of these
applications
okay so the question is
is
does any of the treatment affect
the trichome or is that what you mean
yeah the quality of the final product so
uh obviously as a grower you know if i'm
you know you try to avoid spraying
things as we move into flour now
sometimes you have to but that can
affect the quality
um whether that's the the terpenes or
the tricho development of the product
itself
the crop
did you find any differences based on
these
these treatments
as to the final
uh you know hemp quality
that's that's a very good question um
seriously i've been thinking about
uh one direction as we did test
uh the the amount you know the quantity
we did the
quantitative analysis
of the
cbd which is the you know i said earlier
that most of the hand that we tested are
for cbd production so we did third is
that our treatment affects the quantity
of
the
uh cbd content initial
uh
okay and
and we did not find any difference there
was no no any difference but as we are
talking now are you going to think about
the chemical analysis maybe that that
may be very good because it talks about
degradation and
you know he also is a very good point it
may be nice to look at
you know the
the uh qualitative in term of uh
uh chemical analysis of the
of the
uh the products i mean the the cbds
whether there is a contaminant or
whether is that normally degradation or
so maybe that that may be a very good
thing to test where we've not we've not
looked at that
yeah one concern would be if a product
contained levels of heavy metals um
then that would that would be something
that you could be potentially risking
with your crop
even though these products
by nature of being registered as a
fertilizer or a pesticide i'm not sure
with pesticides but i'm pretty sure that
that's the same case i know with
fertilizers you have to get tested for
heavy metal analysis but that would be
something to look at but um so you did
you didn't find any
statistically significant results when
you measured the cbd the cannabinoids
across all four treatments did you see
any
biomass differences so they were the
yields i would assume that the regalia
plot would have higher yields because
you had a greater amount of disease
reduction so the plants were probably
healthier
did you
find that or what were the results there
because i don't see them here in the in
the paper itself
yeah
we look at the biomass
um
you know obviously we saw that you know
those like uh more highly effective
treatment has like increased
environments but statistically
again they were not different
as you can see obviously i mean visually
you can see that the numbering is is
higher
greater than the known untreated
and when we do the analysis uh you know
static statistical analysis that was
most significantly different
statistically different
so okay that's
let me make sure i understand this
because i think this is an important
point so so you're saying that even
though the biomass visually was greater
in the treatment plots than the
untreated
based when you did the the statistical
analysis when you did the the math on it
there it was not statistically
significant
yielding yes
yeah that's that's a huge point i just
want to emphasize because that's really
interesting because
if
if that were to play out as as more
research becomes available
you know these your next table here
table two shows the cost of these
products
um yeah you know you're anywhere from
500 to over 1700
per acre across the season yeah
well in theory that's a waste of money
if uh
we're not getting biomass
increases
uh yield increases
right
yeah yeah
it's true um
one question that we always talked about
the game is
uh
what level are statistically
significant or different is it is
financially or economically
significance
you know you know what level of
statistics statistical is different or
is is
economically significant
you know in ipm one objective of ipm is
to
is to reduce disease
so below
our economic threshold yes and that is a
threshold that our injury threshold we
call it economic injury session that's a
stress show that it's gonna cause
economical uh damage
so
when you apply your product you may be
able to you know at the end of the the
uh the
be able to know that if this product
uh
even though it control may be little
disease does that little disease
uh fed my uh
uh economy you know does he does he
bring some
uh
profit
yeah so these are the questions that are
also that needs to be considered
that's that's a really really good point
rufus so
just because it's not
so the whole point of all of this
all of this is that is to
is to stable you know figure out what
the economic threshold of a disease is
so
um yeah if some just because it's not
statistically significant
yeah from a grower perspective it could
still be economically viable yeah it
could still be worth it um yeah that's
does it talk
that that's a very very good point so
even though the research may not show
significance the um
visually you're saying so in theory if
we apply stargas
and it costs us around 500 for the
season
and we get
you know half a pound more out of that
crop or a pound or whatever would would
make the difference then it's worth
doing that application once we figure in
the cost of the product and the labor
association
and the equipment to make that
application so
excellent point i i that's that's a very
good way of explaining that
um
so
you know one i want to i want to kind of
turn away from this research you've
i looked you up on google scholar you've
done a lot of research
over the years here uh and one of the
things you focused on is uh a lot of
microbial
products um
or dealing with uh you know microbial
disease
but i wanted i wanted to just talk
really quickly about um
you know you've looked at different
bacillus strains
for promoting
plant growth
and i'm curious you know
what
you know your research was on corn and
wheat and soybean it looks like
um
how what
bacillus species do you think would be
most promising for research with
hemp or cannabis
that's a very good that's a very good
question and
uh talking about my
some of my previous research on with
barcelona
with my experience although i have not
tested any
i've not tested specifically
we're not trying to see the effect of
bacillus
on on the pottermodule
even though some of the uh on on him
even though some of the product that we
tested contain uh barcelos
and we're not like trying to see look at
the products because we are back in law
we're trying to look at their mode of
action but in my previous um
uh
my previous
research i've looked at effective
vessels on
different crops including corn soybean
and wheat
and some of the one that we found to be
very uh effective
in
promoting growth so when i did a study i
look at the their effect in promoting
growth whether in the absence of disease
or whatever it is is present so that
what i mean that i did not include like
a pathogen
into the the rhizosphere
to cause this this so we just look at
normal soil
feed soil we put the the the
we know collateral the the rhizosphere
with the vessels and in
we watch the plants grow in the
greenhouse and see what are the batch
laws going to increase the growth
in that environment and what we found we
found that um
that's the last
premium is some
um some penny barcelos
i swear
they were
effective
in
increasing uh
calm corn growth and
other ones including salvensi and the
best loss and
megarium was also effective i think from
soybeans
so and that's basically what uh
what i've done in with um
bachelors on
other um
other i mean or other crop
in my greenhouse experiment
with a
powder module on hem
we tested some product and one of the i
think one of the products
has
has a bracing loss
i think basilar substitutes
and i think it was
you know
strategy
relatively effective compared to other
products that were tested
so
yeah that's
what i i could say about that
so so you found
in in by applying uh rhizobacteria you
got increased plant growth and yield um
up to uh 200 percent increased shoot
well weight on corn
but you were doing it sort of like you
said in a vacuum so there was no
competition for these bacillus strains
um like you would find in a normal
soil or media um
but but you did find that they were able
to increase yields overall so there's
it's it's promising research but not
not definitive at this point is what you
would say in terms of
adding these bacillus species to a crop
yeah
as
you can see in that study
those
strains that were tested
are
talking about the one that increased
very very out to
the uh let me look at it now
um
yeah penny bass laws uh
battles offenses that's lost in place
the increased growth in that
condition we we we include we
inoculate this plant
the roots with this with these
vessels and the increased growth then
know that these were
very um isolated that we isolated from
the soil these are not like products
these are not like commercialized
products and the objective of the study
was like you know battles they are very
they they can adapt to
a very uh arch environment
and also
we also know that
some of the bacillus even though they
are they might be effective in a
particular environment or region
when you take them to another region to
apply they may be inconsistent in the
application
so
so all of these strain that i work with
in this particular study
we were we isolated them in that
environment that we intend to use them
so that we can see where they can you
know
uh increase growth in that environment
and the objective was this product was
going to be developed for
further develop for that environment so
that's that's orientation so and as you
can see
the most of them
work very well on calm in in a
greenhouse in that environment
so the next study which uh probably
they are going to take on
is to
the most effective one
to like take you to the feed environment
maybe in a micro plot wire and see
whether they're gonna have the same
effect they have in the greenhouse
so so basically you're taking the
bacillus strain and these are not
commercially available strains yeah
and um
you're going to take those and
and since they worked in a
essentially when they were the only
uh
bacteria applied to the roots and they
they did it they did show good results
now you want to take that and apply it
in a field situation scenario and see if
you get similar results there
is what yeah
and i think
oh go ahead
yeah i said that would be another
objective research suggested now that i
you know i i did my research in the
greenhouse and
uh the further study now would be to
look at
the the most effective ones
to take them to the feed environment and
apply them to to corners and see if
they're going to have the same effect
they have anywhere else
yeah and one thing this is probably less
something you're familiar with is but um
what what will happen is is i find on
the on the commercial side on the sales
product side someone would take a paper
like this
and say okay uh you know just to find
one bacillus megaterium
they wouldn't worry so much about the
r181 so it's not that particular strain
but they would say okay well bacillus
megaterium is shown to increase shoot
weight by 200 and then they would go and
buy bacillus megaterium from
you know china or you know on alibaba or
something
as a powder put it on a label and then
they would sell that and make these
claims
so because the biostimulant or microbial
industry
on the product side is growing
dramatically and so i would just suggest
that people do their research and and
then look a little deeper into the
product itself because
the strain matters um you know yeah it
matters a lot we can't just assume that
all bacillus subtilis is going to have
the same effect it doesn't and yeah we
also can't assume that something you
know in vitro or in
uh you know your plot is gonna have the
same effect as it would in my potting
soil or in my garden so um
people need to be careful with data and
how they interpret it um to not
draw conclusions that may not be
may not be true that's that's all
because
the canada's industry has a lot of
products and they're not all good and uh
it's something that we talk about a lot
on this podcast
so
yeah you you make a very good point and
i just want to emphasize on that again
you know if you look at my
my
data on the
feed
fungicide hem trial
you you don't see that dead guard and
status
do you know that they have
the same species of of bacillus right
yeah we have that i wouldn't so both
products have the same species of
bacillus is what you're saying yeah yeah
different species of basilars the
different strength but different strains
okay i missed that
yeah and you can see that this here
different
effectiveness
so
very interesting right
yeah so that's how it is with uh
microorganisms
that they are the same species does not
mean they're gonna have the same
mode of action
uh because now if you look at the the
second objective in that my microbial
microbial essay study
you see that
most of you look at the second objective
is to look at the um mode of actions
on the
of the
the bachelors
and what you will find is that
these
bacillus have different
uh
mode of actions
even though
they might be the same species
and they're going to have different
traits they're going to have different
traits for instance unless if we ever
get antibiotics against bacteria
they may be the same
the things to see
they're still going to have different
antibiotics efficiency against other
bacteria or other fungi
uh
they may be able to produce uh one may
be able to produce uh
therefore on the other
cannot produce it therefore one may be
able to like uh maybe produce some
growth a plunger to more and the other
one uh the other strength cannot do that
so it is very important that um you know
that uh
we consider this trend
when we are talking about you know that
someone uh one bachelor's
substitutes work
does not mean all personal sustain is
gonna work and that is why
it's very important that extensive study
is done
on every strain of
bachelors or any but any
from routine agent
or plan about our biological control
agent
essentially research must be done on
that stream before it can
actually be
released
for
for commercialization
that that's that's really interesting
and uh
it i think it shows too just how much
research there is
available to be done
um on
on hemp and cannabis and that's
for me that's the most exciting thing
about this plant and one of the things
that i'm most passionate about
with this industry is that we can do
this research and even if the research
that say um
you know my
my my good friend and colleague
ben higgins is doing even though it's
not backed by a university it can be
preliminary work where we could say hey
we're seeing statistical trending that
this
you know this product may have this
suppression effect or
you know
running
nutrients at this level will cause this
sort of plant growth response
to where then then a university or
someone like yourself a researcher could
then
repeat the trial
and get more uh
you know more data to to make a
a better decision for growers long term
so
it's it's an exciting industry to be a
part of and we need the research that
you know people like yourself is are
doing it it's just so important so i
thank you for that
yeah sure there's more research there's
smarter shout-outs
to be done more and more and a lot of
them
yeah there's more more
there's a lot of
things a lot of questions that they need
to be answered
yeah well i
i really appreciate it i hope we can
stay in touch and uh share research and
learn from each other and i thank you so
much for taking the time today to share
your research
uh with this audience and
appreciate what you're doing
sure thank you todd i really appreciate
you know thanks for helping me and you
know i always look for opportunity to
share the
the result of my research because i
always say that while the use of
research if those people who need
information can get it yeah so uh
it's always you know i'm always as
exciting to to to
uh share the
the result of my research so i'm so i
thank you for for having me to do this
it's great so thank you again and uh yes
i will continue to work to share this
research directly with growers so that
they can help make better decisions in
their uh in their gardens so
yeah thanks again have a wonderful day
rufus
thank you thank you
all right talk to you later
bye bye
[Music]
that was rufus at kenrin lola and you
are listening to the cannabis
cultivation and science podcast i'm your
host tad hussey i'll post pertinent
links on the podcast page at
www.kisorganics.com
just click on the learn tab and then
podcast thanks for listening