[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host Tabb Hussey of kiss
organics this is the podcast where we
discuss the cutting edge of organic
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge our guest today is Jeff Lowen
fellows in honor of our 50th episode I
wanted to get Jeff our very first
podcast guest an old friend back on the
show Jeff is the author of the popular
teaming series teeming with microbes
teeming with nutrients and teaming with
fungi Jeff is an extremely respected and
popular national garden writer he is the
former president of the Garden Writers
of America Jeff has been a good friend
now for over a decade and is a wonderful
advocate for organic gardening compost
teas and the microbes in our soil thanks
Jeff great to have you back on the show
you know you're an old friend and it's
wonderful to chat with you again
it's always fun I never see you enough
so this is this is a poor second
substitute I guess well let's let's just
let's just start right away
you know we talked about a few different
topics off air but one of the things you
ought to talk about was rise of [ __ ]
which is something pretty interesting
that I'm not that informed on so why
don't we just start right there
yeah we should it's a fascinating
subject rise Oh [ __ ] RHIC opha g ey i
think it is or maybe just g why it's
something that I stumbled upon oh gosh
about probably about ten years ago a
friend of mine in New York sent me a
article about tundra plants that are
capable of actually ingesting organic
molecules now just just as by way of
background in teeming with nutrients one
of the one of the takeaways is that the
microbes in the soil put a charge on the
17 nutrients that you need to grow
plants and is that that charge which
enables the nutrients to get into plant
cells so it needs that charge and and so
I wrote the book teaming with microbes
which is about how much stuff gets
delivered and then and then teeming with
nutrients how it gets into the plant
based upon the soil food web concept
that the that the exudates that the
plant drips out of the root system
attracts bacteria and fungi bacteria and
fungi attract the protozoa nematodes who
eat the bacteria and fungi and poop out
the excess and feed the plant because
it's all happening right there in the
root zone so that's sort of the model
that I've used and then about seven or
eight years ago the this rise of a key
concept came up and it was sort of an
eye-opener because plants aren't
supposed to be able to take in organic
molecules that don't have a charge on
them and so there there were some
pictures of some tundra plants and they
were actually doing that now you know
you can think okay they're living in the
tundra they've had to adapt for a
special way to live they have a very
short growing season blahblahblah but
what it turns out is that there appear
to be a set of bacteria and I don't know
what the identification of this
particular set is but these bacteria
operate in a different way than that
standard soil food web model these guys
go into the meristem of a root so those
brand new cells you know so the stem
cell area of the root they go into the
tip and when they go in they drop off or
lose their cell wall and they move into
the root where they are up against the
cell wall on the plasma lemma all of
this stuff if you don't know these words
they're in teeming with nutrients and
they are oxidized and the nutrients that
they contain that the plant wants are
stripped out of these shell-less
bacteria who then continue to move
through
the route to the edge of the route where
they stimulate the production and growth
of a route here now a root hair is just
one cell as a single cell it moves into
that single cell out to the tip of the
root hair and pops out into the soil
putting back on its cell wall or
building a new cell wall and then
repeating the process so these guys
cycle through the soil losing their cell
wall inside the plant giving the plant
its nutrients moving back outside whoa
that is an unusual new way of plants
getting food holy crow it's pretty
interesting and if we can figure out
which bacteria do it when they do it why
they do it we're going to have a neat
tool it seems to me to be able to grow
our favorite plant pretty amazing unit
oh that's fascinating yeah it is and
they've got pictures of it if you go on
the web they're pictures of it where
they can actually show the off the
oxygen creates a situation where they
can mark it and so they can actually
show where these guys are in the route
and it's not just one little guy in the
root I mean it there there's quite a few
of them in there Wow
now you know we gotta back up a second
because I think a lot of people don't
understand that there are two ways to
move through a plant's Alyssa you're
going into a route you can go into the
room once you get into the cell you're
inside the cell you can move from that
cell to another cell to any other cell
on the plant by going through the cells
okay so you're it's called the
symplastic pathway but you could also go
into a plant in the cell walls and move
from one cell wall all the way through
the plants just by staying in the cell
walls and that's called the apple
plastic pathway and in that situation
there are there are things that live in
the cell walls that are that you want I
mean there are bacteria and fungi and
these are capable of of Buddhist
reservation sure going back out in the
soil and and they do also they drop
they're in antibiotics you know they
take out bad guys so it's kind of
interesting now we've got a situation
where not only do we have these guys you
know going into the symplastic pathway
and moving back out into the soil which
is something that I always thought they
could do by going through the cell wall
but uh you know you got a sort of a
second way the plants are feeding
themselves what is there a different
there's not enough information for me to
be able to tell exactly what's going on
here and I'm so excited about it as you
can tell because this information is
going to be coming available no question
so so everybody needs to keep an eye on
that I think that is interesting so we
don't quite know what the commercial or
human application might be for this this
amazing process but it's something new
kind of like what mycorrhizal fungus was
oh gosh now probably what 15 20 years
ago well yeah and yeah absolutely and
that's a very good comparison because in
a way these guys are operating like
mycorrhizal fungi they're going into the
plant root you know I mean it's kind of
an interesting situation and and and
it's going to be fascinating to figure
out how they and to watch how they study
it and figure it all out it's quite
simple so we're going beyond obviously
the tundra plant now we're in depth into
regular plants I does cannabis do it I
don't know I assume it does you know
it's one of these things where an
article sort of plopped out in there you
know and it just doesn't have enough
specifics oh so maybe I got a I just
read it about a couple of weeks ago so I
got a I got a maybe I need to contact
the author and see what's going on so
stay tuned on that one oh my gosh and if
it turns out to be you know a
significant way plants obtain their
nutrients ah I'm gonna have to revise
the books yeah it's interesting I have
seen commercial applications now for our
commercial products around endo FIDIC
bacteria where they've yep studied
studied this essentially in this case it
was from the vents of Yellowstone so a
specific bacteria that they're now
culturing and and using and they found
supposedly great success in
mediating abiotic stress in plants by
using this end up fitting bacterium
we've set up some trials over at a local
cannabis facility that I work with but
we haven't gotten any definitive results
yet but that was something I was
interested in - yeah I love that because
when I when I throw teeming with
microbes uh you know above ground every
plant has at least one and really really
many more than that up to about 300 350
different in the Indo fatik organisms in
there in the plant above ground you know
there's sort of a comparable to the like
the horizontal giant below ground but
above ground you got all these and
pathetic fungi and endo FIDIC bacteria
and I predicted back then that gee you
know we're gonna start seeing these
things in commercial applications and
wow just terrific I mean so so what's
the name of the product if I may ask you
or does it not have a name yet you know
I don't remember off the top of my head
I'd have to go back into my email and
dig it up cuz it's been a few months
since we started but they were there
working in agriculture they're actually
a local company to me and yeah we're
gonna hopefully get some information off
the trials and see if we can figure that
out
yeah ah just fantastic I mean you know
then that's that's what's so exciting
about this this particular hobby I mean
you get to do things that you just
normally wouldn't think about doing I I
heard a guy speak in Baltimore a very
interesting talk and it's right up our
alley you and me what he was talking
about was making specialized teas really
specialized compost teas and and and his
theory and I think he's proven it out
you can put a lot of stuff in your
compost pile and end up in your compost
teas that you wouldn't normally think
about and he was concentrating on a
number of things one of which was chitin
which I found very interesting too so he
he he goes to the ocean or the beach and
he collects soil that can you know that
was made by kelp and seaweed and all
those things decaying etc etc I suppose
you could make your own by going to get
kelp and seaweed and and
then I what is discovered is that back
the chitin are in the bodies of the
organisms that eat that kind of soil or
live in that kind of soil that chitin
becomes an unbelievable tool in
protecting plants as you know a lot of
the mycorrhizal fungi chitin prevents
some nematodes from getting into the
roots they just don't like chitin and
and so so what this guy does is grow it
grows organisms that have Titan in their
bodies fungi but they're also bacteria
and other things that you know deal with
chitin and break it down and do all
sorts of stuff and and then he and then
he uses it in his in specialized teas
and he's done the same thing I make by
taking some of the beneficial insects
that you might use you know I can never
pronounce their names Kim personally on
the mite any any grows in in massive
quantities in this compost so that
they're meta mites that you know the
things that they produce are in that
compost and then become useful in
growing the plant now which is sort of
just a little bit more of an extension
of what we do but trying to make a
designer fungal or designer bacterial
[Music]
compost tea pretty exciting exciting and
and since I live near the coast I'll be
trying it that's for sure yeah you know
that's an interesting concept I'd love
to see more research on that I know the
like for example the insect frass that
we source has really high levels of
chitin ease producing bacteria which
produce a particular enzyme I believe
it's called chitin ace and that enzyme
rice is what is effective in dealing
with these insects in a lot of ways so
what you're describing there and then we
are seeing a lot of like these Korean
natural farmers and and natural farming
where they're taking local their local
soils and using that in teas as a way of
increasing indigenous microbes so right
it's it's definitely catching on I'm
curious to see how it all plays out
funny enough yeah I'll send you the name
of the he's got a
lab and you know I think I think be
worth you're communicating with
particularly since you know you're
you've got a lot of inputs on your farm
and and you live close enough to the to
the ocean you can you can really fool
around with a lot of this stuff plus I
happen to know that you makes a pretty
damn good compost so this would be fun
really fun but it makes a lot of sense I
mean you know we build this for a
forever that if you can if you can give
it to the plant the plan will figure out
how to use it and and that's what
happens and that kindness is important
stuff it enables our stuff to break down
without it you wouldn't break it down so
very cool stuff very cool stuff lots of
new stuff going on but lots of old stuff
going on as well and I think people
people who listen to your podcast
probably get a little bit of a chuckle
or maybe are just a little bit confused
by some of the things that they read so
for example last week there was an
article about a she was in Saskatchewan
and this was a research assistant
obviously in the university she
obviously had an advisor and the article
you know was one of these articles that
I just couldn't believe it
the article said oh my goodness gracious
we've just discovered that plants create
their own microbial communities around
their root system and I read and I went
wow there's this lady Ben where has this
lady been so more important where has
her adviser been all these years
I mean this is not a new discovery but
it's written up like it is you know and
so so people read it ah you know it's
pretty interesting how much how further
further along the spectrum we are as
growers you know and as hobby' growers
compared to so many other people who who
deal with glances it's just simply
amazing and then I think cannabis
growers have to give themselves a pat on
the back frankly best best gardeners
I've ever met frankly yeah I like the
idea that you know you're pushing the
envelope with cannabis growers and giant
pumpkin growers people they're really
trying out new things but I also love
that science does catch up and then tell
us where
were way off base you know there's a lot
of stuff right campus industry is tried
and honestly a lot of things that giant
bunkers pumpkin growers have done that
it's just not panned out over time that
we thought was good science when we
first started doing it so yeah it is a
bounce but I totally agree with you
cannabis growers are great and I was
just talking with someone how a lot of
for a lot of cannabis growers it's
becoming a new gateway drug to vegetable
gardening and where their food comes
from so that's been a right right
generating all this sure but lanessa as
you know we don't want to ruin it for
the next show but we'll do a future show
on my upcoming book which is on
autoflowering cannabis and I take the
perspective and this is not a book that
I've written for you or for the
listeners of this particular podcast
this is a book I wrote for you know my
wife a sister you know somebody that's
not a professional grower that's just a
gardener because I believe that
autoflowering cannabis have reached the
point now where they are they're going
to be the next tomato plant and and just
without getting too far into it just to
cap it off you know I think they've
reached the point now where they are so
easy to grow and so effective in terms
of what they're able to deliver in terms
of CBD or THC uh you know that I think
they are the next Hobby plant in our
lifetime a new plant comes along once or
twice in the vegetable world snap peas
is the one that I remember more than
anything else
there weren't any and now all of a
sudden is you know seven eight ten
fifteen different kinds of snap peas
everybody grows them they're terrific
you know that's what autoflowering
cannabis I think is going to do to the
gardening world the stigmas dropping
once it drops hey this is the next
tomato the Holy Grail so I'll leave it
there we'll do another show I hope
you're right I think you know we are a
gateway into growing food and growing
food organically well I know I said I
wanted to wait on that because you have
your books coming out when in October
is that right yeah yeah so we can have a
whole conversation about that but yeah
we well we will but I do you want to do
you want to talk briefly about it I mean
do you want to talk a little bit about
what Auto flowers are I know most of the
people on this podcast are probably
pretty familiar but have you learned
anything in it really interesting about
their history or something that you know
might surprise listeners that we didn't
know about Auto flowers well I think the
most surprising there are two surprising
things the most surprising thing is that
Auto flowers are now as strong and can
produce almost as well as standardized
or the regular kinds of cannabis the
second thing is I was dumbfounded that
many people do not know what
autoflowering cannabis is they've never
heard of it and once they and even
professional growers and once they hear
about I think a WoW the possible ISM and
so so for those who don't know
autoflowering cannabis does not require
a photo period like indica and sativa
cannabis plants do and that means you
can grow at any time of the year and
where the temperature is okay and that
means you can grow it indoors or
outdoors any time of the year but better
than that they go from seed to harvest
in seven to nine weeks Wow because they
don't have the breeding that we have put
into our sativas on our indicas we put
ask Afghan hash plants they had a basis
of all the plants we grow except with
these OTO flowers and they take a long
time to mature these OTO flower is seven
to nine weeks harvest seed to harvest
and they are spectacular and the
breeding that's going on with them is
spectacular
you can breed them yourself it's quite
easy to breed to existing Auto flower
plants but if you wanted to breed an
auto flower plant with you know a
regular cannabis plant you can do that
as well it takes a bit longer and
obviously takes many more generations
but it's just an exciting new adjunct
to our hobby but to the gardening world
I think it's going to be a brand new
hobby the next tomato so if anybody
wants to just quickly hop over to Amazon
and pre-order the book you can do that
it's called the DIY autoflowering
cannabis a new way to grow and I like to
say there's a new bud in town and this
is it it's going to be spectacular and
and if your broiler currently and you're
turning your nose up to you know these
things go on the internet look up some
of these seed companies get some of
these new seeds and just try them out I
guarantee you'll be flipping out no
question about it now one question I had
I had heard that I don't know if you
know research you found the origin story
of what what cannabis ruderalis
essentially is otto flowers as I
understand it and that they were
discovered in Siberia on the side of a
road or something is that true what what
have you found
yeah the story goes that there was a
scientist in the Volga River area and he
stumbled upon this in his travels and
and it was about 1900 1903 or so and you
know it didn't have any THC in it and
and you know sort of a scrubby looking
little plant st. really think too much
about it I mean he did he did realize it
was a photo a photo period lift plant
but he didn't think too much about it he
didn't really do much about it and
people fooled around with them a little
bit in the 70s but they just they just
weren't kicking around and and then
people begin to discover him in other
places so so in addition to the volga
river area which is not siberia i think
they found it in siberia people have
found them in canada i've heard stories
that people have found them along the
railroad tracks in alaska although i've
been unable to track that one down but
there are scrubbing little plan there
about a foot foot and a half tall
sometimes a little bigger if you give
them a little bit of food but it's just
a funny looking little cannabis plant
that grows so quickly it doesn't have a
photo period and the reason it does
a photo period is because it you know
it's the evolution it's a great example
of evolution these escaped from
plantations when people were growing
hemp for a probably rope and sailcloth
and things like that and they realized
oh oh I've been a flower right now or
I'm not going to survive and they did so
there you go
autoflowering cannabis the next tomato
and I want to do a quick plug for a
forum called Auto flower net so if you
want to go and read a little bit about
it that's a good one
Jeff's posted on there I've posted on
there I don't check it as frequently as
I probably could but there's a lot of
great guys on there that are more
familiar with Auto flowers than anyone
oh my goodness gracious and if and if
you want to you know soup to nuts if you
want to learn about where to buy seeds
they cover all the seed companies
there's little you know little splays
off various different forms I don't like
to tell a story you know a tag that you
know when I came up with the idea to
write the book and again it's not a book
for growers it's a book for you know
parents who want to be your gardeners
who might want to get into a new kind of
plan boy I really have drunk I I have
consumed the kool-aid that the stigma is
gone haven't I you know oh yeah your
father and mother will be growing plant
you know rather yours might be but I
don't know you know it's just one of
these it's just a phenomenal thing I
think people just gonna fall in love
with this it everything you like about
growing a regular plant you can do with
this one colors shapes sizes breathing
not breathing feminizing you know
male-female the whole bit it's just
fabulous and all in seven to nine weeks
can you imagine what the difference is
in a breeding program if it's seven to
nine weeks versus seven to nine months
Wow
yeah I haven't had a chance to grow Otto
flowers yet but I think this year I
might get the opportunity to get to
experiment with them a little bit so I'm
excited for that and I'm excited to read
your book we'll definitely come back on
and have a podcast just on Otto flowers
here you know maybe closer to October
that'd be great
yeah it could be it's going to be
interesting to see what happens to the
book because again you know so I write
these books for my
often a random for anybody else and this
one I did write for somebody else I
wrote it you know for people who don't
grow but yeah I always amazed on these
books I just learned that the teaming
with microbes and teaming with fungi are
both being translated into German I
talked to a woman the other day about TV
with microbes in Chinese Wow wouldn't
that be something
ah it's unbelievable and you know I got
to thank people like you and your
listeners you know who've just adopted
the book is a sort of a good reading and
and I thank you guys for that cos again
write these books for myself but only
one person buying a book you know yeah
it doesn't go anywhere so so I thank
everybody for this for that there were
even more than kind and buying the book
and telling friends about it or all the
Boston daily been together well I didn't
tell you I was in the San Juans this
past week on weekend for a friend's
birthday and we walked into the
bookstore and of course I went straight
to the gardening section and teeming
with fungi I was right there in the
front best location on the bookshelf and
there was also Jesse blooms book and
Steve Solomon's book a lot of people
that I've interviewed on this podcast I
was like wow I know a lot of the really
cool people in the gardening world I'm
very fortunate isn't that fun yeah
isn't that fun yeah it's fun so you did
Steve something I you know Steve Steve
of course lives in New Zealand yeah and
I you know I used to be on this list sir
for a little while I just don't have any
time anymore because because he was you
know he initially he thought his system
are growing which is you know for lack
of a better word minerals versus
microbes he you know he was not a big
fan of the microbe system and I think
he's come along quite a bit I you know I
think some of them exactly said he
didn't agree with and so I think he I
think he sort of went the other way and
I think he's back again but you know the
two systems work quite well obviously
you know it's the microbes that put the
charge on the minerals so they can get
in there so you gotta happen both yeah I
think they're both a little writing a
little wrong to you so we try and call
use a combination of both by
remineralizing the soil and then having
good biological activity and diversity
and promoting the sorts of things that
you talked about in teaming with
microbes yeah oh hey that reminds me of
something I want to I want to go back
into correctors I think I think this was
the show where I created the the
controversy I you know we talked about
whether cannabis should be grown in
fungally dominated soil or bacteria
dominating so remember that conversation
and I think I what I said was you know
it's an annual plant it's not a
perennial plant and it likes bacteria
dominated soil and III believe again I
don't want to put any words in her mouth
but I believe dr. Lane said I know her
research indicates that really likes a
little bit likes fungally dominated or I
know again I don't want to put words in
her mouth and I said I said I think the
right answer is a and I as I went back
and so I look and looked and thought
about it in light of the autoflowering
book and I want to I want to sort of
change my answer a little bit if I can
it is an annual I still believe that it
likes bacterial soil but I think you got
to take a look at which variety you're
growing first of all so if you're going
in Auto flower plant chief these are in
the ground for only nine weeks both
those love bacteria dominate soil
there's no question they are clearly in
my mind that clearly dominated all the
testing I've done you know they thrive
with the bacterial soil but if you make
it if you make if you make the soil too
rich they don't do very well so that's
that's the first thing the second thing
is when when we talk about bacterial
soil we're not talking about soil that
is or I'm not talking about soil that's
void of fungi so that clearly dominates
simply means that you have more bacteria
than Punjab but you have fungi and and
obviously you need to have fungi to
break down stuff you know you've got to
have you got to have the fungi in your
soil even if it's a you know it's
supposed to be heavily bacteria
dominated you still have to have some
fungi I believe in the soil in order to
make it soil
so if you're growing a let's go back to
my original thought I thought if you're
growing in Afghani you know that's a
nine-month long plant it you know if
necessarily in nature is going to have
soils that we're fungi have have come in
you know and and establish themselves so
you're going to want to have more fungi
for the plants to take longer to grow
and we know now pretty well how long a
seeds going to take you know blue dream
takes X amount and you know whatever you
know you know blueberry takes and Y
amount and so and so I think we got to
be thinking of in terms that way so so I
just wanted to clarify that a little bit
I still think they they like specularly
dominated soil but you've got to have
fungal in it and if I'm if I'm correct
in putting words in her mouth I believe
that dr. Lane thinks that you need to
have a little bit more fungal than
bacteria so I'll sort of leave it at
that
I never want to argue with dr. Lane I
she is she's been so important to my
life and I hate to argue with her until
I have empirical evidence and we sit
down and have a discussion so oh there
we go
well I have a few thoughts on the
subject I'd love to get your opinion too
so great
yeah in my opinion when we talk about
fungally dominated act aerial dominate
we're really talking about the plant
succession table which I think our chart
which people get I think overly caught
up in so yes if we were trying to grow
cannabis or lettuce or some you know
annual crop at the very edge of an old
oak forest we may have issues with that
because that's soil right established
and that's why when we till the soil
we're getting that reset that you talked
about and and getting some more bacteria
in there so all right right but then all
sales are probably you know like you
said all soils need fungal activity
that's the subway system for our
bacteria to move around it creates soil
structure it prevents erosion all of the
things that you talk about in in teeming
with microbes and and teeming with fungi
so right when I make a compost tea
because this is where I
I find it people email me or like I'm
growing cannabis
I need a bacterial tea this is you know
I don't want fungus so I'm doing it this
way or I want a fungally dominant - so I
need to add you know baby oats and then
and then get this fungally dominated tea
and I think people get so caught up in
that that they forget that compost tea
is really about microbial diversity and
nutrient cycling because realistically
that that cannabis plant or that tomato
or lettuce is really controlling the
rhizosphere right what organisms are
going to be successful so we're just
trying to put out as many as we can and
really let the plant be in charge of
that process
would you agree without it right
absolutely absolutely and I always you
know in my talk I always start out with
the concept that yep this is how the
system worked but the plant is in
control not you it's the plant that
makes the decision and so even if you
even if you put down a back securely
dominated tea if the plant needs fungal
ooh fungal you know materials or needs
to attract more but it'll change the F
Shadid and do what it needs to do to get
the fungal and it needs is you're right
we tend to get we can to get hung up on
the theoretical so to speak I mean in
order to explain the system we talked
about you know fungal bacterial the the
succession chart what I do now in my
talks is I as I as I say basically if
it's in the if it's in the ground for
more than a year it really needs much
more fungal than than bacteria and if
it's in the ground for less than a year
it doesn't that's not how I leave it but
the plant
you're right is in control and it's
going to make the decision if it can
live long enough and generally you can
you know if you're in a situation where
you've taken a plant up to space and
you're growing it in a baby diaper you
know and you've given it fungal and it
needs bacteria it's not going to live
but if it's in regular soil it'll it'll
figure out if I can live long enough how
to get the goodies that it needs from
those but those bacteria it's just
simple as that the plant is in control
we don't give them enough credit and I
agree with you 100% I would also say
that when we talk about bacteria and
fungi
so many different species you know tens
of thousands of species of bacteria in
the soil we don't know which one is the
mechanism of action in a lot of cases so
we can't just say I would argue we can't
just say bacteria by adding bacteria is
going to be beneficial without knowing
what species of bacteria strain of
bacteria were we're adding so again with
compost tea it's the shotgun approach
but I don't want to get too caught up
because it's very easy to add bacteria
bacterias everywhere it's it's easy to
make more bacteria but we want to make
sure they're beneficial bacteria and
that they're working in you know a
functioning nutrient cycling system sure
well yeah yeah absolutely and of course
then I always I always add but if
nothing else and you put a bacterial
down you really wanted a fungal the
bacteria might die they become food they
become food and so you know something
else in the cell food web will use it to
make whatever the plant ultimately is
going to say it needs
yeah such a beautiful system in it yeah
so that that reminds me of something so
it's pretty crazy I I see you being
quoted now as like a authority on the
subject so people will say in forums you
know I read in teeming with microbes
this and then already write someone else
will say well in teeming with fungi Jeff
says this and and in this particular
case the topic was soil pH does it does
pH matter because in this case the
gentleman had water that was I think
like eight three or eight four and
people were saying you don't need to
worry about that the plants and the
microbes in the soil are going to buffer
the pH now I have my own thoughts I
personally believe that pH is still a
factor I think we've gotten away with a
lot because the microbes do offer some
buffering capacity so you know 75 80
percent of time and I'm making those
numbers up we can we can check our pH
pen and not have issues but if I saw
water that was you know seven six seven
five or higher I would want to be adding
an acid and you know like citric me to
lower the pH so go ahead tell me your
thoughts on
okay yeah I think you know I think what
people are forgetting is what I say is
the the only place where pH counts is
around the rhizosphere now that's that's
really probably too much of the
generalized statement because the pH
doesn't just affect the bacteria the
fungi now other organisms are impacted
by pH as well but but but we tend to
think of it just in terms of how it how
it impacts the ability of a plant to be
able to take up certain nutrients which
is bacterium punji related I think
ultimately but so so the area where pH
councils where the plant in it doesn't
count on the surface if there's no roots
on the surface who cares what the pH is
and so that I think you know that's so I
get into that but if someone gave me a
glass of acid and said here what are
your plants with it you said the plants
are going to take care of themselves I'd
say whoa whoa whoa you're
misunderstanding what I'm sayin yeah of
course you got to be cognizant of what's
what's going on but in general as you
say 7080 percent of the time you don't
got to worry about the pH the plants
going to take care of it for itself if
you're if you've got an extreme
situation yeah you've got to pay some
attention why do I test for pH all the
time now I don't but if I see something
going on with my plant that's one of the
first things I think about this pH and
and it's one of the easiest things to
adjust so so that's where sort of where
I come from yeah the plant and the
natural system should take care of your
pH for you but but but in your in the
example you gave you know you got
somebody adding a you know an outside
substance with a pH of 10 oh my god you
know whatever that's not a natural
system yeah when I when we talk about
commercial cultivation you know where
you're doing this for a living I I like
to see a good soil test initially in
this case we usually use the may like
three in the saturated paste just to get
the ballpark figure I don't take these
numbers is you know is Scripture you got
to be able to track trends and so you
got to have a number any number is
helpful but if you've got some specific
ones and that's and as long as you use
the same ones each time that's great
yeah and I think testing your water - is
really important especially for people
on the wells as that water may fluctuate
throughout the year it can make a
difference and we've seen it with plans
so yep I don't disagree I don't disagree
but but but here again if you were
dealing with a normal crop you know
you've done it adjust as helpful we're
done with a commercial crop and we you
know you're you're you're selling it you
got to pay attention to it in all
aspects of it you know you want to know
everything but you want to know with pH
you want to know NPK you want to know
Michael biomass all of these things are
have you been fooling around with the
bio micro bio meter at all I haven't I
haven't quite gotten on board with that
product yet and I loved I think we
already had this discussion but we can
have it on air for fertilis nurse - so I
approach this the microbe side a little
differently than you do for me for
example this this microbe bio meter that
would tell me you know microbial biomass
in the soil it doesn't identify species
no for me it doesn't change my my
behaviors in terms of how I garden and
that that's why I haven't quite figured
out a use for it in my head because I'm
already going to be you know making
compost teas or using a high quality
compost or doing things to increase
microbial biomass and diversity you know
getting a test back that says it's lower
high doesn't change my gardening habit
particularly but what are your thoughts
well I use it for a couple of reasons
first first I use it well let me let me
back up a second Michael biomass in
general you can you can use Michael
biomass changes in micro biomass to tell
you whether inputs are helping or
hurting and so that's the first place
where I use it people come to me all the
time and say hey when you endorse this
product I suppose of any good you know I
mean I got to grow plants and do it
knowing that is able to increase a
biomass in the soil in a positive way is
a good indicator it's a pretty good
product and so I use it for that and I
think you could do that as well you know
if you make a new kind of tea you want
to see whether it's whether it's
effective is it adding to the biomass or
not you know you take a test before and
then you take one after it's just like
you do an NPK
you can also use it to determine what
the plant is doing so so plants in the
springtime produce tremendous amounts of
exudate and increase their biomass
around their root systems and you can
track it which is interesting you can
track the cannabis plant biomass changes
they change biomass when they start to
flower and so so it's just it's another
tool now yes it does not identify
species and right now it doesn't
distinguish between bacteria and fungi
although there is now a beta test going
on on the next version which will do
that which what I think will be very
useful and maybe increase your potential
use of it if you can do a little bit of
bacterial fungi identification Oh ratio
or quantity identification that would be
very very useful it's going to be able
to do pH as well which i think is going
to be useful and so it's just another
one of these tools I don't think sim
exclusive tool but it's just another one
of these tools to help you quantify
whether what you're doing is actually
helping whether it's hurting and I find
that to be a fascinating thing to do not
all gardeners need to do it but but but
if you want to analytics information is
power this is another little piece of
information so you know micro bio meter
calm it's fascinating and people are
coming up with new uses for it all the
time which is kind of fun
III don't know if you're aware of it I
did you ever meet James Sotelo anyway
this was the guy in it's either one by
yeah he was what he was the guy that
gave the talk that the woman who
invented the thing heard and decided to
go home and and put the thing together
and James was a wonderful compost tea
brewer really avant-garde designer teas
maintained the High Line in New York the
World Trade Center the battery parks a
lot a lot of the stuff along along the
harbor in New York and unfortunately he
died last week so we lost a great guy
who's really a lot
a compost tea world I think so so upset
about that but he had some involvement
with the micro bio meter which is flat I
thought about it but don't want to be a
downer we're all on the back nine and
it's how we gotta pray that game well so
the organic folks yeah I'm sorry to hear
that
I do recognize his name that you say it
from compost tea so that yeah yeah I
don't think I ever met him but I'm sure
my father knew back in the day yeah yeah
so just to talk a little more about this
micro bio meter if I were to apply
mycorrhizal fungi or apply a coli or
Salmonella it would show an increase in
biomass potentially yes yes it would but
it would smell bad well but my cries she
she's got some stuff very exciting stuff
about mycorrhizal fungi coming in the
test so again it's in beta but but yeah
I mean and I had this conversation with
I thought about Blakeley with these Lane
you know I smile you know yeah if you
put any coli in your soils can I smell
that I mean in other words you gotta you
gotta you gotta know something about the
soil food web in order to be able to use
that tool if you pick up sort of smells
bad I don't care what the microbiome is
is this bad song you know there's
something wrong with it but if you pick
up that soil and it smells sweet and
measure the microbiome ask that's a
different story so so it's just so so so
it doesn't it doesn't so just so I'm
clear it doesn't replace NPK or soil
food web tests I think you got to do
those as well
or look in the microscope in front of
the cell food web test but but but it is
a very interesting effective new tool so
yeah it's right well another question I
had then was so I went to this soil
scientist conference last January in San
Diego and it's very cool and what some
of the speakers were talking about you
know they were actually identifying the
specific bacterias and their levels in
soils but they were talking about how
biomass changes throughout the day even
they're like an hourly basis so yep yeah
we just really range with a product like
that or because will change
it will change it's not that dramatic to
change frankly but it does change but
it's not that dramatic interp all we're
talking about is you know if you look at
a soil on it on the scale of one to two
thousand and it has a reading of 285 on
the micro bio meter test which you take
out in the field the neat thing about it
it shouldn't do it right there in the
field right away you know and then you
know you know that you need to add
something that's not high enough biomass
to be able to feed those plants but if
you have one that's 1700 oh my god you
know you've got a pretty good situation
you can start concentrating on other
things then you're in your microbiology
so that you know it's a useful tool in
that regard I find it incredibly useful
I'm having I'm having I'm having fun
just sort of wandering around and you
know I go into the forest and they holy
crawl you know whoa some of that some of
the things I measure it's just about
anyway I'm a nut ball you know I mean I
would walk around with a microscope if I
could even waste a lot of time
yeah fooling around testing with these
things you know the missions in
practical that's that's the bottom line
right on right I like that so one of the
other companies that I looked into was
Sol vida
they do soil respiration tests and
there's actually a lot of really good
research around measuring soil
respiration and co2 coming off of soils
to see what sort of aerobic activity you
have in soils but they're just the issue
I had was they were just really
expensive still a great company but
expensive expensive and they're there's
some limitations to the test as well but
yeah you know I again all of these tests
whether you know whether they're perfect
they're not they all health they don't
give you information and information is
power
and you want to know that you know i
think i think the standardized test for
michael you know microbiome a cyst is
measure the phospholipids you know they
come from their cells and just take two
one five hundred dollars you know so I'm
glad we're seeing these new tests coming
along and I think ultimately let's go
back to the question of the bacteria
ultimately we're going to happen
she's in our own homes that are going to
our fall hit our cell phone you know
that's going to enable us take pictures
and be able to go to able to determine
what we have and boy would that be an
exciting time so for example I was talk
about this this article I read last year
in science I think was in science news
where they go around they test soils all
around the world and they're 511
bacterial taxes you know bacterial
families and pop up everywhere they test
soils you know what if you go to the
kiss farm you test the soil and it's
only got you only got 428 it's missing
those other one you know which one is
missing you can put them in does it make
it does it make a soil better you know
well you got to be able to identify
these bacteria and so when we get in
there we're getting closer and closer
and closer all ultimately I believe
going to be growing or flower cannabis
we're all going to have a you know one
of these 3d printers in our houses you
know so that when you want a new piece
for the kiss machine you just go to
kisses Webb's website you know and you
and you download the template to make
the new pipe and poof you make it you
know huh and then I forgot what the
third thing was which was the point it
was trying to make but you know we're
all going to have bacteria like a
bacterial and fungal identification
abilities and we're going to be able to
say oh wow this soils missing 16
different kinds of bacteria that it
needs or this soils got powdery mildew
in it
Wow can you imagine it's coming it's
coming
yes Oh science is so fascinating to me
but I was you know getting back to what
you talked about with cannabis growing
and all of that being sort of on the
cutting edge some of the stuff that they
were sharing at the conference very
specific but it did seem like things
that was kind of like oh yeah we already
we were too kind of knew that right but
then they're able to prove it with you
know trials and these these the
methodology that they're setting up with
these studies so it was definitely
interesting oh yeah I mean let's face it
as we get more legalization
opportunities to study you know who the
things we're going to be able to pick
out you know when you study a plant in
the like cannabis where there
is a demand and they need we know in
different kinds of uses and all the
different different chemical ingredients
that we're all trying to find hollowly
quo we're going to have some
unbelievable research opportunities you
know again once in the lifetime and this
it's going to happen because sooner or
later our stupid federal government is
gonna back off I mean we just you know
we're just gonna make it happen and once
it once that happens and you can do
research on this stuff oh my goodness
gracious
unbelievable so changing subjects here
anything you want to share looking back
at your three books that are already on
them on the market
you mentioned yeah you know I know
remember when you first came out with
tea made microbes you had the pH
switched in there and yet it's an
election sillier but was anything you
found that you've been like you know
looking back this was really important
and I wish I'd talked more about it I
know you did that with micro eyes'll
fungus or I've changed my mind on this
maybe something's changed well you know
I didn't include algae I think I should
have I mean Alice he's part of the soil
and they're part of the soil food web
and I think that was a was a mission um
gosh you know I have here every now and
then jotted down little things and I
just I'm drawing a blank right now
ah but I guess what I ought to say is if
any listeners come across stuff that
bothers them let me know right away
and we'll take a look at this stuff boy
that pH problem plagues me because every
time they do a reprint a reprinting they
go back to the first one it has the
mistake in it but and then I always
worry about if the duck does the Dutch
version have you mistaken pH does the
Korean version oh yeah it's in 11
languages also that's that sort of
bothers me but ah you know to talk about
the books in general I think what I what
I have found to be the most satisfying
in addition to the fact that people have
accepted the books and and I've read
them and you know sort of applied and
improved on them and all that kind of
stuff is the fact that people are now
reading the books as a trilogy and I was
a little
concerned that people were going to
think these were three very separate
books but they're not they really are
tied together I mean obviously the the
teaming with fungi is an adjunct with
teaming with microbes fungi are microbe
at the time I wrote the team with
microbes there wasn't really this wealth
of information or or I don't want to say
craze but I need for the mycorrhizal
fungi stuff and it just appeared you
know 2011-12 and so that's why that one
kid but teeming with nutrients appears
because why right team with microbes
teaming with microbes is just how the
food gets to the plant and it's so
important to know how it gets in the
plant and how it operates in the plant
and then you could you can think about
it in terms of where it was in the soil
miss all packaged and all fits together
and and and I I really encourage people
when they pick up a gardening book to
any kind of gardening book to always try
to fit it into the to their body of
knowledge you know because these things
are not written in isolation and a lot
of people do just pick up a gardening
what's wrong with my plant you know and
they meet it and they don't think about
it in terms of the soil they only think
about it in terms of what beliefs are
telling you know that kind of stuff no
you gotta be thinking more holistically
in or in order to be really successful
at what you do so there I go I thought
about I thought about biodynamic concept
isn't it you know it's not as a whole
it's the whole hippie just put
everything together you can't look at
just one part yeah I think it's funny
cuz soil really gets a bad rap or
nutrients in general when we talk about
a plant that's not looking as well
people forget about all the other
variables like lighting and great
humidity temperature in my case I find
I'd say and again I'm making up these
numbers 75% of the people that have
issues it's their watering habits even
because the next the microbial
communities so dramatically with these
living soils that they end up what looks
like a deficiency is actually over or
under watering
yeah absolutely you know it's funny
because you raised these things over
here it might in my basic talk that I
give you know but the fifth or six lakh
slide you know when you give it talking
if you if you put in slides that
generate in theory if people are
understanding what you're saying a laugh
you know that they're listening and that
they understand if they don't laugh and
they get to that slide then you didn't
explain it properly and so you're going
to go make sure you do so and one of my
laughs slides at the very beginning is a
picture you know of a guy standing in
water and now I have one of a reader
board that says spring is here I'm so
excited i wet my plans No and I always
say to people we water our plants not
necessarily to give the plant water
although that's obviously important but
to keep the bacteria and the microbes
alive they need water for God's sakes
and you know it's amazing but in the
gardening world not the cannabis world
in the gardening world every garden
writer in America has written it at
least one column or done one radio or
television show were on the subject of
the number one mistake people make is
they over water their plants the number
two mistake they make is they under
water there and that's that's a standard
and if you don't write that column once
during the year you know then you
haven't you haven't you know complying
with the rules of garden writing so
you're actually right watering is some
tea okey it's just you'd think it's
intuitive but it's not have you played
around with moisture meters at all we
use one from blue mats it's a digital
moisture meter but I'm always looking
for other you know other suggestions and
what other people are doing to measure
you know more quantitatively they're
they're levels in the soil I I used to
you know and then I found there was
enacting the one I had was an accurate
night I've never I've never gone back
and done it again
I suppose I could I like to use my
finger not very accurate of course but
something I've always done talk about a
myth huh your finger can't tell where
the soil is moist properly or not a lot
of my thinking ah crazy
you know I've heard that too but then
one of the best gardeners that my botany
teacher he that's what he does he's his
finger and I was like well it's not that
scientific but man you know you're the
best gardener ago or I've ever met so
I'm not gonna argue with you on this one
yeah yeah I guess yeah my father taught
me how to do it you know it yeah yeah
yeah I go wait a minute that's the same
finger you pick your nose where that's
not an instrument what are you talking
about you know but it is yeah this is
but meters are fun again because the
quantum of information once you start
collecting this information you know if
you do it properly oh my gosh you get a
whole different picture whole different
picture you know what is with holding
water to this flowering the you know
what is you know what is withholding
water due to the to the production of
trichomes all that kind of stuff is
fascinating stuff unfortunately in the
cannabis world we tend to share that
information we were talking a little
earlier I don't think we want to
necessarily get into it but about this
Philo's situation you know because
people people in the cannabis world were
sharing information you know now we got
a problem
but we do we tend to share information
and I hope we continue to do so it's
very important very important
particularly with the big guys trying to
get into the business you know we gotta
we gotta support ourselves not it's not
competition that way it's you know
that's healthy competition it's the big
guys we gotta worry about yeah I do have
actually one other question I wanted to
I wanted to bring up and see if you had
any information on so I got a call a few
weeks ago about a woman who was
vegetable gardening and she'd done a
test on her native soil and then also
her raised bed garden and it came back
with 40 ppm of lead in her raised bed
garden you know where she bought potting
soil versus the one where her native
soil was 0 ppm so she was you know
obviously upset about that and I had no
idea what 40 ppm of lead meant on this
particular test to know if that was an
issue or not so I called the double USDA
and the Washington State Department of
Agriculture and I said hey what kind of
regulations do you have around heavy
metal testing because for me
as a soil company who because of the
level of fertilizer or nutrients we're
putting into our soils I had to register
our soil as a fertilizer which requires
heavy metal testing to make sure it's
safe now if I had registered as a
potting soil or a soil amendment what I
learned from the double USDA is there
really isn't any requirement there so I
could have high levels of cadmium or
lead or arsenic and they wouldn't they
wouldn't know or really no I won't say
they won't care but there's no
legislative policy around this so oh
it's even more it's worse it's worse
than that it if you wanted to have
radioactivity in your material it's not
tested for that either and so so you you
know it's unbelievable that you can get
away with putting in potting soil yeah
so I called the Oregon Department of
Agriculture because they've always been
really great
whenever I've talked to them and
basically what they said is they I think
I did pass me through to a few people
and came back with well we don't if
you're buying it for off you know by the
truckload or you're just getting loaded
in the back of a pickup we don't we
don't test it but if you're putting it
into a bag then we do require heavy
metal testing because all these states
have different regulations and in this
case what they said was and it was I
don't want to say it was a very specific
number it was like 238 ppm or 243 and I
was like how is this how did you come up
with this number I know it was somewhere
right around that range and they're like
well the FDA hired this consulting
company way back you know 20 30 years
ago to set these levels and we've used
them ever since and so I asked for him
to send me research I haven't seen that
research yet but you know that made 40
ppm not look so bad but whiff but then I
got thinking about it you know if we're
growing root crops if we're growing
cannabis you know things that are
there's a lot of research to show that
they're dynamic accumulators they uptake
heavy metals really really well
how do we know that what we're getting
is safe and that's something I just
wanted to bring up for listeners because
the people are sourcing things from so
many different places or using really
really high levels of rock dust and we
could be getting these heavy metals in
their final
and it could be an issue I just wanted
to hear your opinion and what what you
found on the subject
well I'm very concerned about it first
of all let's talk about the forty number
I mean this stuff is cumulative and so
so yeah it may only be 40 you know but
but you know then you go then you go and
rub up against your wall or you know who
knows what I mean so it adds up it's
like having a backpack you know forty
but then you run into something else
that's forty and all of a sudden you
have a me in your backpack not just 40
so so that I'm concerned about any
number I don't think it had anything to
do with the fact that one was raised bed
one was in ground I mean it was the soil
that they brought in it had the lead in
it I am very concerned about the fact
that that we do not test for lots of
stuff in the cannabis industry in Alaska
where I live they don't test for
pesticides on the plant wait a minute
that ticks me off you know I mean
where's our where's our clean green
certified organic yellow standard this
is something we're putting into our
bodies so so you know it's not just lead
it's radioactivity it's all it's arsenic
it's all sorts of stuff and and yeah I
mean we should be testing this nothing
and if you're growing a plant like a
fern or
cannabis that can create this stuff you
know one of them is fine because you're
not eating or smoking it the other one
it's not so so it's upsetting I'm upset
I need to go back and look at the
research but I'm not sure if it
accumulates it into its trichomes or if
it just goes into its leaf biomass in
which case it's a little less concerning
for cannabis but there are always some
leaf material you know when you're
consuming well wait a minute wait wait
wait wait a minute we're putting you
know in the new modern world they're
putting those leaves into a machine is
turning them into oil and so on the lead
still there in theory so so so whether
it's trichome or leaf if it's in the
plant you're turning it into oil and oil
you know that's a potential problem
let's talk about the research a little
bit there's a terrific podcast that ran
recently uh and I'm trying to remember
whether it was radio lab or something of
that sort per team
google it involving lead standards and
lead keep the little Dutch boy that's on
the lead paint and basically also it's a
brand new podcast I remembered it's a
brand new podcast where they're trying
to say to people why don't we pass these
we got to do something about this with
various subjects and one of them is led
they have a whole podcast about the lead
paint industry the little Dutch boy and
how there's so much lead and lead paint
and why it was there and and and and why
it's still around thirty years later we
haven't done a damn thing about it and
we're not holding national lead company
that made the paint and other companies
accountable good god you know it's crazy
anyways fascinating google it and
listeners will be fascinated by it no
question I'll have to check that out
that's that's really interesting
especially since I'm getting ready to
pay my house so but yeah yeah yeah but
again not just not just the lead
radioactivity is something that that
always gives me in you have to in order
to put you know your radioactivity into
a landfill your nuclear waste you've got
to fill out form after form after form
in order to put it into your potting
soil nothing bad bad what have we done
to ourselves so the moral is you know
definitely test and you know you get
information you get smart yeah kind of a
downer to end the podcast on but nowhere
you source your ingredients I would
agree with you that is very important
right and all if all regards and just so
that we can you know keep it into the
organic it's not just these chemicals
that you gotta worry about so if you're
using manure for example and it's got
tremendous amounts of phosphorous in it
you know it could be that you're using
so much manure that your phosphorus
levels in your soil even though the
stuff gets locked up are so high that
mycorrhizal fungi will never work in
your soil for a hundred years
you gotta test folks to know what your
numbers are so you can figure that idea
you end up with a with the soil that has
a you know phosphorous number that you
know 250 parts per million you got a
problem you know it should be 50 parts
per million or lower I think and so so
yeah testing is so important it's not
just for the chemicals that we know are
bad it's for the good stuff as well yeah
I've seen some recent testing around
nitrogen where you know it's being over
applied and we're seeing you know some
nitrogen toxicities actually from-from
too high of levels so that's where a
test came in really handy to sort of
confirm what we thought we were seeing
visually with right exactly exactly well
exactly so and again the place like like
Alaska for years and years we had a
garden columnist not me who was telling
people to put down 8 32 16 8 32 16 three
times a year on your lawn with a holding
call that's a lot of fun
that's a lot of phosphorous those lawns
they've got phosphorous afford the rest
of time so yeah they've even allowed to
apply phosphorus on logs here in
Washington they passed laws around that
because of issues with it leaching it
well I think I think nationally if
people take a look at the lawn lawn
non-organic lawn foods you'll see there
is a no-no number zero from the middle
number you're not allowed to put
phosphorus were 3040 years away from
peak phosphorus and and and that's gonna
be a bad problem we thought climate
changes a bit if we run out of
phosphorus we're dead well you know Jeff
I really appreciate you taking the time
today I look forward to seeing you soon
here at the cultivation classic though
this podcast will probably come up after
it's already been it softer it's already
happened but I'm looking forward to your
talk and I always keep an eye out for
when you're coming to my area because
it's always great to hear you speak in
person well you know you can hardly shut
me up as you know so if anybody needs a
speaker and they can afford it contact
me I'll be there
simple as that and and this new book I
think your sister is going to love
that was Jeff Lowenthal's and you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast be sure to leave us
a good rating a review on whatever
platform you listen on and check out the
podcast page and kiss organics YouTube
channel for more information and it's
not too early to pre-order Jeff's new
book on Amazon so you can be one of the
first to read it and stay tuned because
I have some great future episodes coming
up where I'll be sharing some research
from some trials at a commercial
cannabis facility and an exciting new
collaboration thanks for listening