[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host tad hussey
of kiss organics this is the podcast
where we discuss the cutting edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge
my guest this week is my dear friend
jeremy plum jeremy was the director of
production science at proof cultivar one
of the most technologically advanced
cannabis cultivation facilities in north
america at proof jeremy combined decades
of cannabis horticultural experience
with cutting-edge technology to deliver
previously unattainable consistency in
both product quality and consumer effect
prior to his leadership at proof jeremy
was the co-founder of pharma recently
acquainted by rolling stone as one of
oregon's top dispensaries jeremy has
served as a cannabis consultant to
israel medical cannabis researchers and
and as a cannabis policy advisor for u.s
members of congress he also serves on
the olcc's rulemaking advisory committee
in 2015 jeremy co-founded cultivation
classic oregon's leading craft cannabis
competition he lives in portland oregon
with his border collie lucy and when he
can find fewer greater joys than sailing
on the mighty columbia river now on to
the show
okay
hey jeremy thanks for coming on the show
again today
hey chad great to be on the show again
thank you so much for hosting
you are coming to us all the way from
ireland you took time out of your busy
schedule um
and you know a work vacation a little
bit too to
talk to us today about
aroma i think was the topic you wanted
to tackle um take it away
fantastic given that i'm speaking to you
from dublin i feel it's appropriate to
start the conversation
with a quote from one of my favorite
writers and poets
william butler yates
who is also from ireland
he wrote these lines a long time ago but
i think this is really relevant to our
conversation
he says the world is full of magic
things
patiently awaiting for our senses to
grow sharper
that little quote is almost i think a
bit of a mission statement for the
direction that i'm excited to talk about
which
connects to some of the recent science
i've been doing both from the
cultivation and the consumer education
side
um so specifically trying to create a
bridge between
sensory science done in a mature way
to the cannabis cultivation efforts and
to the rich analytical chemistry that we
have access to because i i think i'll be
able to
share means by which it's even more
relevant
in a lot of ways than say a focus
narrowly on terpenes and i'll get to
that material but
chad i want to start with i actually
have an exciting announcement which has
been forthcoming for some time and
there's been some delays but
there is a
scientific white paper that is a journal
journal article
that is going to be coming out in the
journal molecules that i have
the privilege of collaborating with dr
edie ray
and jeremy sackett previous founder of
cascadia analytical
and 80s grad students who've been
helping to digest
a lot of the data from the cultivation
classic event that i co-founded
like eight years ago something like that
um so
the exciting thing is that i you know
when we set out to start cultivation
classic when
i actually was in washington dc on a
cannabis lobbying trip with congressman
blumenhour trying to think about how we
could support oregon to have its own
voice which is a lot about ecology and
ethics as well as about
community and education and trying to
empower all the producers
to understand the cutting edge of both
production dynamics and product
character
you know i really wanted to open source
like all the sort of trade secrets that
were going on as a long time cultivator
myself and
empower the community to do better and i
think in many ways we've we've achieved
some of that aim but this is really a
specific way that has always been
something we've been excited about but
just haven't had the resource
to follow through on so we've created a
ton of data because i think as you know
cultivation classic is really distinct
from any other cannabis evaluation
competition
um i'm really in love with our
colleagues who put on a variety of
different kinds of cannabis events and
bring the community together and i you
know will never forget my very first
high times cannabis cup in amsterdam
long time ago late 90s
but
the reality is i also quickly became
aware of the fact that in all of the
competitions
you would see these scenes where there's
a handful of really amazing judges
usually who are deeply involved and
and they're kind of dumped on with a
huge amount of samples and they have a
very short period of time there's almost
no controls about how they're exploring
those samples
and then various competitors are given
these awards which end up having massive
impact in their business and their brand
development and in many cases
i think that we see that inherently
those awards aren't tied to
the sort of quality evaluation you would
hope to see
if you were looking from the outside in
you know you'd really like to see that
all of the samples were very thoroughly
and rigorously
reviewed in a process that could create
truly differentiated
sort of samples so that
what i mean is you know sometimes the
best products don't win full stop
uh that's not always the case of course
but
in any case cultivation classic was
a bit of a response to that and
i am really proud of the fact that we've
had double-blind
very scientifically rigorous evaluation
at the event
that it includes agronomic or
agricultural grading
i include sensory grading
it also included the very first versions
of an ecological energy efficiency
tool called the power score that
derek smith's organization the resource
innovation institute
brought forward to our event first
and actually the oregon producers who
would fill out really long forms like 14
pages
talking about energy and water empowered
the rii to be more effective nationwide
in having baseline data for indoor
outdoor and greenhouse production models
but we also have some other weird stuff
like uh the most important i would say
thrust and the organization that's been
led by 80
in that she as a neuroscientist and the
dea and a licensed
cannabis researcher
was able to work on the qualitative
patient perspective we can't speak in
patient terms though because
that would run afoul of the fda so we
talk about consumers
and instead of being able to talk about
therapeutic effects
we really talk about consumer enjoyment
that's you know working within the
limitations of our
fractured non-federal regulatory
situation
uh the only way that we could do this
truly clinical level research
you know with trained judges who work
for
up to
six months in some cases and
have a massive amount of time and
purview of of the samples and detailed
process and input tools
to summarize their findings so
one of the exciting things is also
simply being able to avoid all the
inter-lab variability to choose a single
analytical testing partner
to be able to qualify all of those
products with a similar baseline
but what's exciting is the findings that
we're putting forward in the journal
molecules is really the very first bit
of the data that's been harnessed at
cultivation classic which you know has
been an entirely volunteer run program
and i initially found that with steph
barnhart previously of the willamette
week now co-founder of smart cannabis
which became the back end data effort
but
i think for anybody who saw behind the
scenes and was just used to cannabis
competitions being pretty rigged
i'd hope that they were kind of blown
away by the level of rigor and blinding
to the evaluations that went on i
guarantee there's not a close second
currently although i hope there are more
we've done a lot of work to map i think
the oregon chemoscape by having lots of
craft producers you know funneling
through that same process
but i think this first work that's
coming out is some of the most exciting
and disruptive
because we find ourselves in a time
where
i think a lot about the consumers we
serve as cultivators
and the experience that they have when
they go into a retail dispensary to
acquire the product
the reality is if you come from the old
school and you had the privilege of
being very close
to a cultivator who was really skilled
you would frequently be able to observe
quality and character in the product
samples
that were like vastly better than what
you typically see in wholesale
cannabis and retail cannabis in the sort
of adult use program
this is often
simply because of freshness
is my perspective and i'll say more
about that but
the
importance of aroma cannot be overstated
i want to jump to the punchline and
share a couple of the findings
that have actually come up before but i
think now are a little sharper it came
out of this research which to the best
of my knowledge is
the biggest scale clinical trial level
quality
study
using contemporary products not like two
percent moldy nida weed
but really exceptional craft cannabis
produced by organic cultivators in
oregon
to then
look at what attributes
are most enjoyable what do the people
which you know are very diverse band of
judges in this rigorous setting
what are they enjoying the most about
the product it's a simple question in a
way
but when we think back to the retail
experience so consumer walks into retail
they see you know things that are high
thc
they're talking in terms of indica
sativa hybrid
they're now using terpene dominance
and correlating that to personal and
targeted effects
worse there's marketing efforts
that use proprietary modalities to
categorize things
into targeted effects
if you peel the veneer you find there's
absolutely zero evidence
to support
that kind of marketing language but the
marketers understand that there's a
great importance
for the consumers to parse this
incredibly diverse landscape of products
into effects
so people do want sleep aid they want to
be stimulated and focused
they want to be relaxed and calm they
want to be aroused they want to be
creative etc
the problem
is that this fundamentally
is
deceit let's just call it what it is
it's it's an earnest effort to meet
consumer demand but it's early stage
they have no tools or scientific
evidence to support
that this flower will cause that outcome
and the other will cause a different
outcome
quickly i want to insert a little micro
thesis here which is my notion of the
effect matrix
you know how do you determine what kind
of an effect a product is going to have
well
you have an endocannabinoid system it
has a tone
it's engendered that tone by virtue of
genetics your genetics as well as your
diet
there are other things that factor in
but those are giant forces
and i've actually talked with cannabis
clinicians who feel so passionately
about the diet component they don't want
to work with phytocannabinoids until
the diet component is better understood
until people work on eating
in a more healthful way
because the benefits will be so greatly
reduced but
in any case
um the endocannabinoid system tone means
that your experience tab is going to be
different than mine and every other
person in some important way and that
that exact same product will act
differently
that's only one variable in the effect
matrix next up we've got to deal with
the phytochemical inventory so what
chemicals are in this flower
but you're left with this
sort of uncomfortable reality where
we're only measuring a tiny fraction and
typically the things that are the
largest molecular weight
in a product
um but you do not inherently have the
most bioactive or the best awareness of
the full range of secondary metabolism
and what those compounds can do for
people yet we're just so far from that
and
a few examples are that you know gas and
fuel smells we now widely understand are
driven by compounds
they're detectable to human olfaction at
parts per trillion
so for example thials and dilates if you
have in a natural gas line
then now you can smell the otherwise
inert explosive gas because it's so
tiny of amount of files needed
to create that sensory awareness that
there's danger there's natural gas
leaking were being used
dials are rich in a very important
category of aromatic chemistry in
cannabis
and
ultimately at a parts per trillion level
basis you can imagine where
of a consumer perceived aroma
could result in one billionth
of the total chemical inventory
of that sample
so this is a very important data point
that's certainly not reflected in a
chirping report
but there are many other examples like
how esters with all these tropical and
sweet sugary and fruity notes or the
aldehydes things like green apple and
banana are
so prominent or a paper in 2012 that
summarized more than 50 of cannabis
aroma being aldehydes
um
there's all this other categorization so
the bottom line is we're measuring a
tiny bit of the phytochemical inventory
and we're making too big of a leap about
the representation and significance of
that
and when i just look around the other
consumer products i don't see
nearly anybody except for say winemakers
being concerned with that in consumer
representation of wine
in brewers in representing that other
than to the ultra beer geeks cicerones
in their representation of beer
instead you find pretty commonly sensory
language but i'll save that for a later
risk
the third part of the effects matrix is
that you have dosage and
you know dosage is getting increasingly
better measured but really dosage is the
biggest variable in determining
the intensity of the effect full stop a
little tiny bit more and you may be
outside of the therapeutic window and
now result in increased awareness of
pain or anxiety as opposed to
a decreased you know desirable
therapeutic outcome
so dosage and titration are huge but
then you have to throw in because we're
talking about
altered states of consciousness when
we're evaluating cannabis product
qualities you have to deal with mindset
and setting
similar to how the new psilocyte and
assisted therapy
modalities are working and you know they
work in curating beautiful music
playlists and having amazing
environments and blindfolds and
headphones and therapists
they're really working on that component
in a way that cannabis folks
i just genuinely don't see hardly at all
other than
you know a few circles in my life so
that's if you want to get to a targeted
effect that's an honest way to educate
people
to you know observe their own experience
and take notes and start to understand
uh how to achieve that but the marketing
that stands in the way of a normal
consumer walking into a shop
and trying to attain
something that they either just find
enjoyable
or even potentially therapeutically
useful
is a giant obstacle currently in the
industry and this is really important to
cultivators
because we're the ones who have to
create these products
we we're trying to you know essentially
work within what is the most genetically
diverse horticultural crop on the planet
with tons and tons of different
production techniques and variables and
i think in general those of us who are
working hard at it are trying to delight
people
we want to make things that are truly
enjoyable and useful but if there's no
measurement or mark
to ascertain what that enjoyment is
correlated to
i think you're left with a lot of people
who are working on a sample size of one
taking their own anecdote
and expressing from that position and
that's great if you have say you know
the tremendous privilege of being in
this industry or since long before was
in industry and it's just been a
movement of
finding the entire range of possible
sensory experiences in cannabis possible
uh there's another great long word uh
phenomenologically qualified samples so
phenomenology is this idea of you study
your own experience
it's that's kind of
the gist but that's that's what i've
done you know my career in cannabis i
have always tried to
understand myself as a baseline and not
project that that is relevant
or valid to others in many regards but
for my own ability to understand what is
the most desirable cannabis character
how does that language connect to the
idea of product quality
and which plants are the most
exceptional plants and what are what is
the range
in the king escape or in the
expressiveness
of the plants and what are the more and
less intense expressions
of each of the core categories in that
range that's a kind of filtering that as
cultivators i think you inherently
are left with so then jumping back to
the white paper
and then i'll take address
there is a
really clear emphasis
in this standout signal of what directly
correlates with consumer enjoyment
uh it is very distinct from how you see
cannabis being marketed currently
and it is 100 related to aroma
aroma is different than flavor
when we're talking about sensory science
you know flavor
say we're talking about again a beer or
ale and i understand the complexity of
correlating cannabis to alcohol but i
just want to use that language because
it's very practical from a sensory
perspective but flavor has to do with
mouth feel or salt sweet
umami fat bitter etc
those things are actually flavor when we
really are talking about
the character
of a cannabis flower product especially
we're talking about the aroma most
importantly by far
and
in fact thc potency
uh did not positively correlate
with consumer enjoyment
seven out of ten judges
preferred samples when blinded and
randomized that were under 20 thc
um there's a really important
idea that's at the base of that
which is that you know there's a
biosynthesis in the plant that's
creating and manufacturing all of these
different classes of compounds
so when the glucose the sugars and the
photosynthates are
converting at the base of the glandular
head
at the tip of the stock of the trichome
you'll see this incredible enzymatic
process where the olivetolic acid and
the durano pyrophosphate
are
taking that glucose and turning that
into cdga
this is the path by which the
biosynthesis of cannabinoids are created
here's an interesting piece and
this is a bit of a complex one i don't
have all the answers about or anything
but i am fascinated that
gpp durano pyrophosphate
is used for both the pathway to make
cannabinoids as well as to make
terpenoids and other aroma components
so imagine we're selecting plants for a
wholesale market
that is pursuing
you know thc potency and strain names
correlating to value so if you want to
make the most money or make any money at
all you'd better have something well
north of 25 thc potency
and then think back to the biosynthesis
well we're making decisions
that are essentially resulting in
products that incentivize
the cannabinoid potency
in a hierarchy over the aroma synthesis
but
it does not turn out to be the case if
we look at other literature
that thc potency neatly correlates
to intensity of effect either
there's this fantasy that we're
economizing as consumers
by purchasing a higher thc rich product
when in fact you find that actually as
you look deeper into the literature
there's numerous anecdotes about people
who find that while they love cannabis
and have a lifelong relationship with it
when they're consuming those products
they're very high thc
they're both having less desirable
experiences less enjoyment
and essentially evoking anxiety that
cannabis is fantastic at assuaging in
some cases
i love intensity of effect i'm in no way
trying to diminish the pursuit of strong
experiences i i micro dosing is great
and all but i am somebody who loves the
whole range of expression and really
understand
the consumer desire to feel things
deeply and richly
but the problem is that in our data
you can see which is again i believe to
be the most rigorous
at scale clinical evidence that i'm
aware of on the planet so far and maybe
there's others are always excited to
learn more we need to
do a lot more work ourselves
but we see that it really is the case
that the aroma
correlates with far more enjoyment and
that enjoyment correlates to both
intensity and diversity of effects
so
this is the beginning the tip of the
iceberg in terms of trying to tilt
this equation away from
uh there's actually a really wonderful
woman named kristen yoder who has
a t-shirt line that says cannabis what
is it indica and sativa is lazy
marketing
i couldn't agree more i think this is
one of the most important statements
that we have to attack
to get into serving people better but
then as cultivators
being able to produce the most amazing
cannabis products you know on the earth
to really focus on the things
that are going to matter the most um
so
uh i should take a breath ted i know
that was the wrong
well i i kind of want to just go back
and try and
summarize and make sure i'm
understanding
uh because you covered a lot of
different things um
and and some of the things that i want
to possibly highlight are one you
mentioned that we one we don't have uh
we don't have the right tools to capture
all of the sensory experiences
analytically that are occurring
in this plant
um you talked about um
thiols and some of these other
aromatic
aspects and and this is some i'm coming
from a place of someone who does not
have a very good sense of smell so this
is difficult for me um
but
i i think that's a really important tool
and then one of the things that the
cultivation classic found that i just
want to re-emphasize that you that
you've mentioned multiple times here is
that the
the most popular or the most coveted uh
cultivar
cultivars were not the highest potency
or highest thc so as an industry we've
been driving for like more thc more thc
uh but the reality of it when we from a
consumer perspective is that uh when
given a blind blind options so they
don't know the thc levels in them uh
people were consistently choosing ones
that were slightly lower thc and and
honestly this i know the alcohol
uh correlation is is challenging in some
way or comparison but for me i much
prefer a lager or an ale over an ipa and
that's because i enjoy the flavor
profile of it
more so than the heavy hoppy
bitterness associated with a lot of ipas
even though the alcohol percentage is
lower
i'm going to pay the same amount of
money for the
the beer
and i'm not going to get as much alcohol
which is a lot you know a lot of the
driver that for a lot of people and
consuming um
so i think that richness riches of
experiences is an important conversation
there and
uh the other thing that i really want to
highlight that you mentioned was this
idea of titration so
when you you've talked we've talked
about this off air and you talk about
the biggest driver for on the effect
matrix so how your your experience
of smoking that joint or consuming that
cannabis
but is really
dosage
at the end of the day you know
environment mood
uh cultivar all of those things thc
percentage are all going to be factors
but but like you've told me multiple
times dosage is the biggest factor and
people should be aware of that when
consuming and i think that's really
important so
how do we address all of these
challenges
then to give us a better model for
understanding
our experience with this plant
great summary and great question
one quick caveat i want to stuff in
before responding to that is that you
know it was a huge revolution to get
access to chemistry analytics
i remember when i was with ray bowser at
the time of od diesel and there was a
circle of us working around pat
marshall's lab
in wilsonville oregon called sunrise
analytical
this was actually the i believe that
operating well in advance of steep hill
in california and was the first
analytical testing i'm aware of in the
u.s to try to we were looking at 64
compounds
you know and we were really informed by
the way that
phenotypic plasticity was occurring in
our cultivation efforts that
a single cultivar
taken cuttings from that cultivar shared
with different gardeners would produce
very different
range of chemistry
and that's a really important insight
and as growers i think it's really
exciting to talk about analytical
chemistry as a metric by which we can
measure performance and etc there's many
exciting components there and not to
throw it out but what i want to suggest
now is that like even when i founded a
dispensary called pharma on uh hawthorne
in portland
this was the dispensary of the very
first terpene categorization system
first the first dispensaries i'm aware
of that just displayed terpene data for
all flower products
uh all tested at one lab was one of my
big notions of how do we get people
into utilizing cannabis in a way that's
like lifelong sustainable relationships
and not just serving
uh one population or another but being a
resource for everybody
i look back cad and i think
i did the best that i could at the time
and you know and
tremendously indebted to dr ethan russo
and
raphael mashulim and others who had laid
the groundwork to try to understand from
that perspective but i tell you now i
look back and i think
it's not that it was a mistake it was a
step in the past
that now
i think our whole industry has become
overly reliant on very fallible
analytical lab results
the the output we see in an analytical
lab result will vary from lab to lab
from crop to crop
in ways that simply are astounding if
you look at the level of data i've been
able to digest over the last decade
i can share with you that it's just it
means very little
i there's a particular way to
demonstrate an analytical testing
process that from a consumer perspective
is useful but that's not what's
happening in general it is pretty
chaotic when we don't have third party
regulatory oversight over lab testing
and when we have even with after the
american herbal pharmacopoeia standard
huge variants and methods
and
in any case what i'm trying to say is
what would be far more useful
is an accurate sensory expression
in describing that and just to take on
beer because i actually love beard i've
been learning a lot from scientists
involved with hops in the last years
um you know and beer if you have a lager
that's a brand promise the consumer now
has an expectation
of that brand it should be crisp
refreshing
moderate abv something like five percent
it should be a crystal clear um you know
cold fermented product and there's a
certain range you could find more
biscuits or certain notes that are going
to stand out but that's an expectation
now that the consumer has and the
producer is obliged to fulfill that if
it is a logger if it's a hazy ipa
however now we have a product that we
have an expectation it's going to be a
viscous liqueur that's thick mouthfeel
with low bitterness with massive hop
aroma and mouth feel characteristics
now as a producer i can work within that
range
and i would say that we haven't moved to
this level of maturity
in the massive amount of genetic
diversity we have in cannabis into these
archetypal sensory buckets yet
but you can imagine how much more
rewarding it is to people
who are purchasing the products when
say they're looking for their peak gas
expression
and they look and find that there's a
range of gassy products but in fact one
is much much more expressive as i saw
recently at a cultivators curatorial
event in san francisco
the node labs and cultivated industries
was involved with there was one product
that was so clearly the dominant dial
rich product but then there's like 10
others and this one was so much louder
but i would say a majority of people
wouldn't have noticed that
and that's that's really interesting to
me and then you look to how cannabis
producers
curate their products
i hate to say this but as you know a
grower myself it's sort of like we rely
on our own
sense
disproportionately because we haven't
studied sensory science
and don't have the tools to make
relevant
the language of sensory to the consumer
in a way that's very very useful you
said we literally have one person saying
this one's the [__] this is the best
product look at you know i i know take
it for me and sort of like well yeah but
when you look into sensory science you
learn that we all have
certain things you can smell and not
smell so well and when you say you can't
smell so well
i a little bit want to challenge that
because i think
the sense of smell is a very subjective
interesting terrain to dive into
and there's an amazing movie for those
of you who want to geek out on smell
called les parfums that just came out
that actually features this protagonist
who's a nose she's a perfumer and that
is the most elite uh training you can
find for century on the planet and the
well beneath that is wine well beneath
that is beer cannabis isn't even really
on the radar yet i mean it is but it's
just not showing up in that way
um
so it's just a great uh sort of
exploration of what a nose
must be able to achieve to essentially
uh demonstrate
effectiveness and sensory but in sensory
you use typically panels of people
uh you know 20 or 30 people would be a
pretty ideal uh size group and there are
masters who have really taken this on
with incredible discipline
in the world of craft beer that i've
been looking to for a while
uh lindsey barr i believe is one that
i'll just throw a name out
my good friend nick ziegler who is the
head of r d at yakima chief hops there's
another great one
drew hole is a man who's composed of
sensory science team for the company
true terpenes
these people all have real world
experience that are you know based in uh
characterizing products from that
perspective but in any case what i'm
trying to say is that
it sure would be useful
if as cultivators and as an industry we
leaned way more toward the sensory side
of the equation
not to abandon analytics both are
important like for example i'm a breeder
and i'm very privileged to be working on
some at-scale hep genetics
program this year in addition to things
that i'm doing
still at proof cultivar because i'm now
a consultant and have the ability to do
more exciting and different things
after having recently found an
unbelievable head grower uh who's named
sam hoefler who i
if those of you who have not listened to
the podcast you hosted with sam
he in one paragraph i think says some of
the most innovative thought about
irrigation practices i've heard that
once he came on and
the team has gotten really strong i've
been able to focus in areas that i'm
looking forward to developing more which
is more r d stuff and engagement with
the world and different visions
but any case in the hemp breeding you
want to have both sensory
and analytics
in your funnel so that you can truly
find those most differentiated plants
but
back to on the importance of aroma
i would say that if you do not have
aroma as a key target and you're working
in say a smokable hemp or a craft flower
space
then you're really missing the point i
hate to say this we have an instagram
culture that looks at frosty flowers and
you know i'll never forget when like
this snow was big or when bc like
beesters was coming through and there
was this huge amount of trichomes
and it had no character at all it was
like this inert biomass it had also no
effect like it was just it looked so
good and it was so disappointing
we continue to see plants bred from the
white i'm just going to call it out the
white it's a soulless plant to me i've
grown so many versions of it i've grown
so many hybrids from it yes you'll see a
dominant trait that increases the
trichome production of this visible
resin content but it's not about what's
visible it's what's inside that matters
you can't judge the character of the
finest wine by looking at the bottle or
looking at the the quality of the skin
of the grape it's absurd
it's the aroma
and the magic of all this chemistry but
you know i think
actually to just jump for to another
level of depth
this is partly a reflection on our
culture right this comes from an
industrial culture that has been focused
on throughput and quantitative goals in
many ways
that are very distinct from qualitative
growth like when we bred many different
plants for food systems
flavor and nutrition and aroma were
nearly left out or were among the last
items to be considered and that's
appropriate you have to focus on
agronomic targets first
but to miss what the heirloom tomato is
as opposed to the roma or the not the
roma is actually the tomato but to this
sort of flavorless you know grocery
market tomatoes it's just it's we're
like missing
this substance in life which is about
being
present centered
and using your senses as a vehicle for
enlightenment dare i say
um this little bit correlates and even
further afield with like
the fact that we in america especially
are in a very puritanical culture
and i think we need to be cognizant of
the impact of that kind of culture
that suppresses the senses that values
work above all things but you know and
here i am in europe there's a very
different balance of power
here there's a lot more focus if you are
in various places in europe you go to
the cheese shop you go to the bread
maker you go to you think of course
there's big chains and everything but
in general there's a much higher sort of
level of development and sensibility
applied to the expression of craft
products i would say across the board
and
i think that's a little bit less
puritanical and it's a bit of a radical
notion
to embrace the senses but back to that
yates quote sort of like there's all
this magic in life and magic is a tricky
word i know for a lot of people
but i'll just say that there's
surprising depth and dimension
once you choose to focus on the sensory
experience of a product
that opens
that is its own path you know it's
infinite in its range of expression
you'll never find all of the possible
expressions no matter how hard you work
and i've really tried to do that my own
way in cannabis and i'm now a national
judge for the national cannabis
competition i've
put on these events i've done all these
things to try to get to a position where
i can truly qualify
these different kinds of aroma ranges
but
it's infinite but that is exciting
that's where the passion of a cultivator
comes from me no kidding the most
exciting thing about cultivation has
always been discovering a new phenotypic
expression
and a particular aroma diversity or
intensity that's novel or that enriches
my sense of what's possible
that is absolutely the key of course
i've also very much focused on
therapeutic
use and having consistent chemotype
expressions
because i want to be a resource for
patients they're using it for quality of
life
improvement in a reliable way
but the reason i would also
jump to organic crop production
being so very important is that
in decades of cultivation i have always
used both organic cultivation methods
and
synthetic mineral salt fertilizers and
hydro methods i've always done both
but for an elite consumer-focused
flower brand
to not
value organic cultivation is it insane
to me to see this industry develop in a
way
not just jumping directly into a
critique of the industry
i there's there's this huge miss that's
going on when we're relying on two-part
synthetic mineral salt fertilizers
with very very thin emphasis on biology
or say rhizophage or
endophytes you know the endophytic
organisms that intracellularly
congregate inside of the plant
and the fungal networks that the plants
have evolved from the beginning of time
and partnership and synergy with
these things clearly
up and down regulate
aroma synthesis and are a part of the
equation
i saw this linkedin article recently by
arroyo who are amazing team doing a lot
of data-driven cultivation support they
asked what's your favorite media and
there's like it's rock wool
core
perlite and another hydroponic substrate
i believe hydroton
um there was like there was no sort of
uh you know living soil or
biology rich media included and i
thought what a miss
like this is absurd that we come to this
place where a product that has an
enjoyment that is most increased by
aroma intensity
we're using
essentially production methods
that are less effective at evoking that
kind of passion from the plant and i
talked to others i mean if you talk to
kevin jodrey or folks
been around a long time i think you
consistently hear this message that if
you're really looking for the best
organoleptic expressions
the best
aroma intensity and diversity in
cannabis
absolutely need to use uh high biology
you know whether it's a
biology forward living soil soilless
substrate or you're you know working
like
so many amazing farmers like green
source or you know biovortex or others
using regenerative farm practices
to really uh support
that sort of uh expression in the
product and i i wish there was the white
paper that could evaluate that dynamic
that may well be something i'll get to
work on in the future because i can't
wait to come out with the kind of
clarity i can now speak about aroma with
with regard to organic crop production
i'm confident that's a significant
variable and that the industry has
essentially taken the cheap and easy way
towards you know there's this fear of
managing the agronomic crop balancing
of a rich organic program that is
well-founded it does take a lot of work
so jeremy real quick um a bit of
rational yeah so you went though
recently with your facility from
uh you know organic bottled nutrient
program to more of a living soil
methodology
essentially moving towards that that
biological aspect that you talk about
with aroma expression did you notice a
change
in
your your cultivars and how they were
expressed when you made that change made
that switch i can speak anecdotally
about that the reality is we have so
many new cultivars at the same time we
have this new program and the new
cultivars continue to get more and more
expressive as my experience okay over
the years
but yes i just want to say that i think
that is definitely the case
but now if we could just shift to well
gosh here organic cultivation can
improve that expression
look at what happens after the plant is
cut and how that veers from say ancient
cannabis culture it would milk the
freshly grown plant it wouldn't even cut
or harvest that plant but rather you
know gather charis by hand and create
you know hashish and actually create a
sort of means of a sort of shelf
stability by using the rind of the
product itself to capture all of that
freshly milked whole plant phytochemical
inventory that over time gets more and
more interesting
but there's this word i love to have is
fidelity it has low fidelity to the
flower itself it becomes its own thing
it's wine it's fermentation almost it's
there's so much going on i know before
frenchie passed there was up to 50
compounds identified
uniquely in hashish that started with
the terpenoid hashishin
that do not exist in the planet that
were showing up in the interactions of
all these vocs on the side of the
hashish but that's very distinct from
rosin
and the solventless outcomes that are
very high fidelity to the flower
that actually are capturing that but
here's the problem with flour i think
when you look at even this is a part of
frenchie's teaching and anybody who's in
the
sort of hash world
it's that there's too damn much
oxidative surface area
the heads of the trichomes are you know
a thin veneer
it's cuticle that easily breaks down the
oxidative forces and
then releases the vocs and the aroma
so i authored a white paper last year
in partnership with dr ethan russo
and we created a novel solvent-less
process and i should share this with you
too because it has
in the back part of it i've
open sourced many of the production
targets we've used at proof
uh that we've evolved over the years
with lots of data and insight using very
specific uh whether it's vpd or ppfd or
every ingredient we use in the program
including the kiss media
and i mean just
open source that whole program because
there's still so much
you can't still can't just implement
that but anyways in this paper
we showed you the chemistry
that is in the typical flower sample
it's very technically dried or dried as
well as it can be um using existing
equipment and and say proof that's
it's
above average for where i see a lot of
the drying process in the industry going
you lose that minimum about 50 percent
of the mono terpenes by the time you're
done with drawing
but then if we use the language of the
hops industry they have a word for
spoiled hops or an idea for spoiled hops
that's related to a loss of more than 50
of the aromatic inventory
it's nearly spoiled by the time we
freaking dry it
that's a giant issue this is why whole
plant fresh frozen has become such a
giant deal
you see living resin which is you know
hydrocarbon distillate mixed with whole
plant fresh frozen aromatic fractions
include more than terpenes of course
blended in and people grossly prefer
those products and all the consumer
market data
but that's still nowhere near to the
qualitative depth of the rosin which you
know doesn't separate those things out
or you can but it doesn't have to the
batters that are i'd say my favorite
versions of high fidelity
aroma forward rosin products
uh don't
in any case we uh using ethan's
leadership
developed a method for cryokeeps it
actually uses whole plant fresh frozen
but doesn't go into water hash because
water unfortunately is also another
solvent and yes even when you're making
water house you're losing a bunch of the
water-soluble aromatic compounds and we
show you that data it's all in the paper
and we we paid a lot of money to life
skill labs to be able to
illustrate that actually we preserve
that 50
otherwise lost monoterpene inventory
which on an analytical lab result is the
best metric to identify from a producer
perspective
our success at retaining aroma
so
i i just want to suggest that we're
moving into a conversation where the
supply chain itself needs to evolve
to support the best quality of product
or vets let's actually distinguish
quality according to my friend nick
siegler and i think he's correct uh
should be more narrowly applied as in
quality analysis and quality control
to particular steps in the producer
ecosystem
character is actually a more effective
adjective to describe
the outcome of an organoleptic
expression so you're dealing with
product character when you're talking
about aroma really i i sometimes
mistakenly interchangeably use those
words and i think everybody else does
too but i just think it's important to
bookmark that
in any case um
the character
of the product going in the supply chain
once i've cut it down dried it say
you've dried it not so well well now
you've lost more than that 50 i'm
talking about and now it's getting
packed and then it's going to go through
you know the wholesale channels and it's
going to eventually be distributed
through retail and then it's typically
still in a glass jar
at least in oregon in our deli style
often there's lights involved definitely
there's no temperature control involved
and things are oxidating oxidizing
radically so a quick experiment i did at
home anybody can do this
cut down a fresh freshly dried plant
excuse me cut down a fresh plant dry it
and then put one section into the
refrigerator in an airtight light proof
container and then put another just on
your shelf at ambient temperature
and my experience is consistently that
within two to three weeks the flower
that's stored at ambient temperature
does not smell anything like it did when
all that incredible product character
was expressed before and most of that's
lost certain things are more resilient
than others like terpenoline the haze
and jack inspired aromas are very stable
i have products that have been around
for years in the vault that still smell
like that terpenoid rich floral
intensity
but
in general the nuance in character goes
and it goes fast
so you started by drying and then losing
most then we've kicked it to the curb
past that comparing it to hops which is
like pennies on the dollar
relative to the wholesale value of the
cannabis products for mature
premium cannabis flour
they pack it in mylar zero degrees once
it's you know in noble gases the moment
it's finished drying and they do
long-term shell stability trials and
validate when it becomes spoiled and all
the stuff that the cannabis industry
doesn't do or brewers who put fresh beer
out on the pack on the shelf here's pro
tip look at the bottom of a can of beer
you'll see the date it was released
buy fresh beer and tell me you can't
taste a difference and not fresh beer by
fresh maybe 30 or certainly under 60
days but there's beer on the shelf
that's 90 plus and if you're drinking
say a craft ipa massive difference and
they understand that so if you're like
ben edmonds at breakside brewery you go
reclaim your product at day 45 if it's a
fresh ipa because you don't want to have
that poor representation of your brand
we don't see this
in cannabis yet you just sell it and it
goes and it's beat to hell and it smells
like alfalfa hay or inert were worse it
had too much moisture now it's got some
blue cheese or ammonia notes so these
are the off notes that i want consumers
to look out for
what could we do to change this well
we would get more advanced with our
drawing using water activity more
frequently
we would work more with like the
cryokeef method and these solventless
products that in concentrate
constantly move through a cold chain all
the way to the end point of use
i am so proud of the rosin that i built
that proof because
with this team which includes you know
our incredible hashishin uh fuji
bondwater and uh our operator val and
this whole great team
we're finally translating the quality of
that living soil grown led driven you
know exciting new boutique variety
cannabis products
all the way to that end point of use if
you go get a fresh sample batter of
grapple pie it's going to smell
incredibly diverse and dynamic and
you're going to enjoy that product so
much more
typically
i would say than the flower sample that
has now gone through non-temperature
controlled
uh sort of long-term storage and has
been beaten all around
so here's a simple idea
i think that we need temperature control
and airtight vessels
you know this is a contentious issue and
we don't have a ton of time so i can't
go deeply into debating curing like the
idea of long curing
gosh flowers are not hash it's all this
oxidative surface area i can show you
all the analytical lab tests i can show
you my sensory experiences and with big
groups now that flower becomes usually a
bit fungal
and highly oxidated and now you're left
with the cannabinoids and you've lost
all this product character i'm not a fan
of that i know people are i that's more
of like a
something i can't explain i think people
would benefit the most from the freshest
version of the flower but in order to
get there we'll have to use temperature
controlled environments so ultra premium
flower i see going in refrigerators or
in a sort of whole
chain and distribution that's
refrigerated as well as packed
in low oxygen environment you know and
sustained once it's been well cured but
the reality is in the supply chain we
have
this is where the solventless products
are pretty remarkable in their ability
to get all the way to the end point of
use
they're tiny
and they're also you know expensive but
they're precious because they do
constantly work to maintain that
integrity of the organoleptic voice and
the aroma intensity but
i think as cultivators it's really
important to just have aroma in mind
constantly and and when we think of rob
clark and mojave richmond who talked
often about
this is an aromatherapeutic crop
and we're like missing the point if
we're focusing on strain names
thc even dominant terpenes indica sativa
hybrid and the nose really does know but
the problem is the nose doesn't believe
in itself so often so back to your sense
of sense ted
i think that they're terribly before the
amount of people who distrust their
senses yes before we touch on that okay
please
can you just take me through uh for a
cultivator
your optimal process for sort of drying
and curing a plant from harvest
on
just in a little more concrete terms to
give people um
just a better idea with what you're
comfortable sharing i guess
so you've mentioned absolutely
colder airtight temperature controlled
yeah can you just touch on that before
we let's let's even rewind it a bit so
the drying process first you know
identifying peak maturity is a thing
people who harvest on the calendar eight
weeks you know or nine weeks routinely
are generally missing the peak
organoleptic expression one example
we've been cultivating joker's 31 from
excuse me jokers from uh the
compound genetics team huge style
profile i noticed that there's a 72 hour
window where that part of the profile
peaks
it's like eight and a half weeks in
i that is an example of a window of time
where if we want to capture that in its
most expressive state we need to harvest
at that time
so using sensory in the cultivation
facility to identify that
ideally combined with analytics except
in the case of this one if you're
looking for gas
there's no limonene near seeing
beta-caro filing correlation to that
that's the compounds we would see in
that sort of a cush profile
but
so what i'm trying to say is first it
starts with when you harvest and then
it's how you harvest
are you rapidly getting the
freshly harvested bucked plants
carefully into the temperature and
humidity controlled
drying environment i would say that
where people have gone awry in drying
environments is that ideally if you
could wave the wand you'd have two hvac
systems
one that's a beast that can take out a
majority of the water content in a short
period of time
say 48 hours or less
with aggressive dehumidification and
being able to immediately with the water
activity process
get down to your between 0.65 0.85 uh
sort of water activity so that botrytis
cannot occur
uh that knocks out a huge amount of crop
loss but
then have a second smaller hvac system
that stabilizes and carries those trends
you know for the duration of the
qualitative components in the drying
getting that 90 reduction of moisture
down to you know 10
pretty ideally between 8 and 10
and essentially uh the moment that's
achieved
being here's the big trick facilitating
a large scale crop
into hand trimming the moment it's a
perfect moisture content and water
activity that's not easy to do i i don't
know many people that can pull it off
you do the best you can and you have to
probably
cut some corners occasionally but the
best you can mobilize a team to go
through that quickly so maybe you start
trimming at 12 or 14
and then you're monitoring it and not
sealing that product and being very very
careful with your water activity
monitoring to keep it in the safe zone
then
keeping that constantly from that moment
in a either inert gas we've a
combination of
co2 and nitrogen uh blended so it's like
uh co2 80 nitrogen
just hand fill that you don't have to do
it with a really accurate precise method
but displace the majority of the oxygen
that's in the container where those
reactions are occurring and then of
course even in burping
we talk about burping that dr allison
justice was the first person who takes
my awareness with the huge amount of
ethylene content that's in the finishing
gases they're off-gassing in that flower
product ethylene is a ripening agent now
we can only speculate about what all
it's doing in cannabis but look to
everything else
we see that complex carbohydrates are
rapidly breaking down on the sugars and
you know imagine how fast the banana
ripens in the bag when it's ethylene is
more concentrated than what's out in the
open and it's less concentrated
i imagine there's a similar dynamic and
that who knows that maybe it's
advantageous to trap in that ethylene
but i doubt it so you need to burp the
excess co2 and ethylene the excess
moisture and before you seal it in that
inert gas environment really correctly
but then going from there it's this cold
chain keep it in you know temperatures
that are going to be more like
refrigerated temperatures never freeze
product unless you intend to rapidly use
the product after you remove it from the
freezer
because there's a process called
nucleation where essentially ice
crystals are building up inside of the
plant cellular tissue
and then as soon as they um
thaw it's an expansion and contraction
exercise
it breaks and bursts these you know sort
of simple uh uh these these stores for
the vocs and so forth
so refrigerated temps is my
my target and i would say that um
you could you know stay at the low side
of refrigeration and that'd be that
would be ideal but most people are going
to be closer to probably 55 or 65
degrees
that's okay it's certainly better than
uh
not having any refrigeration
but really the cooler you can be the
less brownian motion this is a great
word i learned recently about
the way molecules move and
even
various uh liquids and chilled steaks
but
essentially you want to package that
product and continue to sustain it in
stasis so the freshness is there
um i do not use or advise the use of
boveda packs or other
branded
desiccants or humidificants
i think those really uh absolutely
pillage the aroma it's been my
experience personally
i i see retail nearly universally using
those things which is
like a fix to a
to problems that happen downstream it
doesn't really work
you can never add water back in you know
without compromising aroma or increasing
the likelihood for new biology
to to grow there i just i'm not a fan of
that i think
getting it correct in drying and
transferring and unpacking is more
important i would like to see a lot more
emphasis on those things
but then keep it refrigerated all the
way to the point where the consumer is
picking up and purchasing the product
that would be a revolution people would
see and smell
a kind of sort of experience that only
the producers typically
get access to which you know is where
the most passionate people in the
industry sometimes are it's the people
growing the plants
and you see why when you see this
massive aroma expression and i'll just
share personally it's a bit
heartbreaking to me when i know what the
product looked like before it went
through all these many steps and then i
see
on a random spot by at some retail where
i have flower at
and this kind of really degraded
expression and it still looks good it
tests well it sells well it's still got
some character it is one tenth or maybe
even less of the character it had before
that whole thing started so
i really do want to see um airtight you
know sort of light proof refrigerated
packaging for elite uh flower products
but at some point you start to realize
that's a bit crazy you know it's
interesting that only in the last 50
years do we have this culture that is so
uh about the flower itself and i really
really love flower and i love fidelity
to flower
but i would just suggest that we also
need to be humble and acknowledging this
ancestral ancient cannabis culture
around the world that for hundreds of
generations worked exclusively on hash
production
i'm not
i i love traditional hash i think it's
probably my favorite product but i i'm
not at all against like the high
fidelity exciting massive rotten
ecosystem that's opening and i would
suggest for people who don't have enough
experience
try not always against a distillate
formulated live regimen i i can
absolutely discernibly feel a difference
for myself
it's clear i'm not making it up it it's
less desirable i get more narrow effects
i get
less uh sort of nuance and less
less good feelings there's something
about keeping everything together and
this whole platform
uh where you're not combining and
re-combining things
you're really just trying to
capture the peak freshness and maturity
and carry that all the way to the moment
you ingest that in
an inhalable or otherwise other form
here's one really quick weird thing we
just did a trial where actually there's
like six different kinds of inputs in a
gummy for a long time people were
wondering well does it make a difference
to have these big whole plant
phytochemical inventories and gummies
like isn't the thc and cbd the only
compounds really getting through the
bile etc
it absolutely makes a difference there's
no question left
dr natasha riz who used to be chief
science at genevis was one of the first
people to show me data about lavender
and linole getting all the way into the
gut and being able to be a very
powerful aid to ibs and crohn's
therapies
it's very clear that the rosin infused
gummy it's just a better product that's
a much more
enjoyable edible so
but i think it's easy to achieve what
i'm talking about with cold chain post
process
with hash and rosin products
it's harder to do that with flower
products
in the current industry i would say that
people who have yet to build out have a
lot of opportunity to differentiate and
use what we've learned
to be able to better facilitate this
massive variable and consumer enjoyment
and to really
then
lastly i would say that it's not enough
to do all that
actually do sensory science and you may
not be able to do it in-house but like
we're collaborating with true terpenes
team who will bring their folks
hopefully to the table to
have a third party characterize the
products and you know this fantastic
process where they've done training
um they they're effective in being able
to sort of create their own blends and
find the expressiveness and range
this is back to the riff i was starting
before you asked the question about
practical
uh thoughts related to uh the post
process
it's simply this you can imagine that
there
are at least a trillion possible aromas
now how much language do you have
this is the fundamental challenge with
everybody who i think looks down the
barrel of sensory science at first
you don't trust that you yourself are an
expert or and most people are not
certainly or that you can be that i i
believe that more people than i think
they then identify in that way could
with the littlest bit of training or as
a part of a larger sensory process
become educated and useful in this
unfolding conversation
and that's what i want to encourage and
it is a challenging thing i talk to
people who describe sensory like
architecture and it shapes
or who describe it as sounds and have
like various synesthetic
modalities or
it's a really tricky space because it's
so
it's so vast you know there isn't a
million or a million adjectives let
alone a trillion that we're going to
deploy but as we get better and you use
groups to round it out
simply reporting a few adjectives about
what's exciting in that product from a
sensory perspective
after you've done your excellent cold
chain post process
will create a whole new level of
cannabis enjoyment and i would argue
that enjoyment is in some ways tethered
to therapeutic use and to long-term
relationships
and it's really the maturing of what is
a very early stage kind of new industry
in this ancient culture
that needs to be addressed and i'm
trying to do that work with a variety of
teams and
thrilled about the results that i've
seen
but again i think the nose knows
but the next part of a statement i would
add on is people don't trust
themselves yet though
it's like the nose nose but there's some
disconnecting cognitive dissonance
if you will and
what i'm excited to do is to help
support people to be more effective in
that regard
but then also
not even to
to encourage everybody to do that but at
least on the producer side if you're
spending your life cultivating flowers
and not working on sensory in a way
that's above and beyond you using your
own anecdotal perspective
you're missing a giant part of how we
can make the richest best
most valuable expressions of craft
cannabis on the earth
i really mean that and so really excited
about this conversation
as it unfolds
you know i think you've given us a lot
to think about
i know myself
as a consumer
i want to be more cognizant of
my
dosage my
environment my mood
and how that relates to the cultivar how
the plant was grown and all of these
things to get a more comprehensive
understanding of what that effect is
uh for me and and how that the plant
interacts with my personal
endocannabinoid system which i found is
quite different than
the majority so um
yeah i might i appreciate that my friend
you gave us a lot to think about today
and i'm so grateful for your time
um
i hope you have a wonderful
rest of your trip oh yeah
really quick thing
in summary there's one other thought
just to go all the way back to the
beginning it's simply that
think again about the person who walks
into the retail dispensary who may be
from out of town who may be not hooked
up and connected who doesn't have the
elite cultivator uh group of
connoisseurs that you do or you know
that really are just trying to find
their favorite experience
and think about the layers of [__]
they have to wade through yeah indica
sativa hybrid high thc strain name
terpene dominance um and now we'll add
proprietary marketing effect language
that's literally five layers of deceit
and lies
that stand in between the person and the
planet
i would say we do so well to
start to just remove all of that just
take it away
and educate retail staff
with sensory language
use language that actually is accessible
that connects to people that also that's
accurate and when it's accurate and you
have that product and you finally find
that sort of
uh gosh
fermented blueberry with a
floral punctuated note with a sort of a
top note a middle and a bottom that's
still got gas
you're so delighted by that experience
it's like a discovery and then you want
to reproduce it but you've at least
internally mapped that i think that's
the kind of stuff like i'm in dublin
there's this giant whiskey museum
you look at all these people i mean
they've been doing this for generations
and that's what they're looking for
they're looking to reproduce that
amazing experience they of course have
mouth feel and actual flavor
but i i anyways more to say but
you sir thank you for this platform
thank you for the opportunity and
privilege
to get to communicate with uh all of the
amazing folks that tune in and
i'm just so grateful to you for also the
best version
of an organoleptic
enriching media that has happened
certainly in the last five years of
proof and the supply chain disruptions
and chaos
that led me and sam and todd and the
team
to make the bold move to with absolutely
no time to trial
jump in headlong and to the necessity of
agronomic balancing and liquid injecting
in small sized containers with living
soil i bet really your product is second
to none it's been fantastic and helpful
unfortunately due to some technical
difficulties the end of the podcast
recording was cut off but we caught the
majority of the content so i decided to
publish it as is
that was jeremy plum and you were
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast i'm your host tad
hussey i'll post pertinent links on the
podcast page at wwe
just click on the learn tab and then
podcast thanks for listening
[Music]
you