[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discussed
the cutting edge of growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge my
guest this week is Colin Bell colin is
the co-founder co-inventor and chief
growth officer at grow Sencha parent
company of mammoth Colin completed his
PhD in soil microbial ecology in 2009 as
a research scientist at Colorado State
University
Colin published dozens of peer-reviewed
publications that were focused on Alisa
dating microbial mediated processes that
enhance plant growth Colin left his
academic position at Colorado State
University in March 2015 to launch
mammoth a young company in the AG tech
sector that develops microbial
biostimulants to sustainably increase
plant yield and an all-natural bio
control product to prevent pests their
first product mammoth pee is a
beneficial bacteria bloom stimulant that
targets phosphorus cycling to maximize
both quality and yield in cannabis
plants now on to the podcast
hey Colin thanks for coming on the show
today
dad hey how are you doing it's great
talking to you today yeah I'm excited to
have you on here I've known you for a
long time and we've chatted you know
become friends through this process and
I wanted to get you on to talk a little
bit about microbes since that's sort of
what your your background is in and
microbes are my saying I appreciate
that's a perfect topic for us to discuss
today well can we start off by giving
listeners a little idea of your own
backgrounds you know going back into
maybe into college sir absolutely so you
know from from an academic and college
perspective I ended up getting a PhD in
soil microbiome micro by
Algie but it was really a speciality in
microbial ecology which is the study of
microbes in the environment mostly how
they integrate with plants and if I kind
of interact with climate as well on some
level I was a desert microbial ecologist
for years and years I did a lot of work
in the Chihuahuan Desert and I did some
work in the Great Basin and different
parts of the trail one desert and what I
was looking at we did a lot of climate
change studies in my research as a
student and then in professional in my
professional career I worked for the
USDA department of agriculture
agricultural research services is called
the USDA ARS I worked from the Forest
Service and then I worked for Colorado
State University the natural resource
ecology lab and almost all the projects
that I was employed in and those
different organizations were relating
not only effects of climate change but
those effects and how plant microbe
interactions responded to climate
scenarios and so I have a long-standing
career in understanding how microbes
interact with plants not only in in
natural settings but also in agriculture
settings so I've been geeking out on
this holy moly for almost 20 years now
that's great you know I want to talk a
little bit about how you founded the
company and some of that stuff too but
you've already brought up some really
interesting questions for me one of the
things that I'm curious about is how how
do you microbes differ different in
these various regions geographically and
then what sort of persistence DC because
I guess when I was I got to go to this
soil science meeting a couple years ago
now and one of the things that they
talked about was how microbial
populations will differ just from you
know just from watering or hydrology
will change the populations quite a bit
and again over a you know a fairly short
period of time so what were you seeing
you know sort of on a macro scale with
these microbes yeah there's a lot of
great work on this and we you can look
up some of it also I'm talking to the
listeners here as a mile microbial
biogeography is kind of the the study of
microbes and how they're dispersed
across a large geography so to speak but
but what it really comes down to and
this comes back to the very fundamentals
of microbiology 101 and that's an
environment selects tab and in all these
microbial biogeography studies what
you're going to find is the only way to
look to to correlate why microbial
communities and communities is
assemblage of multiple species and so
microbes don't exist as isolates or a
single species in nature they exist as a
community or consortium just to be clear
and so you're looking at have microbes
and how their relative abundances form a
broader community or the total microbial
biomass within any region that's
typically how these questions are framed
and you're looking at the environmental
factors there could be cold there could
be heat there could be moisture there
could be soil textures have a big big
part to do with it you know there's sand
silt clay and they have different
hydrology properties and there's this
interaction more importantly and then
there's pH which as a big II know if the
era is one of my favorite microbial
ecology scientists of all time he's here
at Colorado University of Colorado in
Boulder he's got a lot of great science
and we could probably make an
introduction we should get him on the
show sometime man he's smart but uh he's
done a lot of this work and what he
found was more than any one factor pH
significantly shifts microbial community
assemblage across a wide geographic
region and again there's a lot of
factors that control environmental
factors that interact to actually
control and form these environments you
think about biodiversity to add from the
equator from a plant perspective it's
been well studied moving outward towards
the poles you get more diversity at the
at the center and then it it narrows as
you get to the poles because environment
selects plant species and more
hospitable environment allow for more
diversity and more biomass and more
climate and more and more cohabitation
so to speak and then as we go up through
North America through Canada etc you get
fewer species because they environment
that much harsher you can think about
that from a microbial perspective but
it's not on that scale it's on a micro
scale and so these ad aphek which are
soil properties are and and temperature
and hydrology are the main properties
that influence microbial communities and
I want to overlay
one extra interaction and that's plant
because microbes in soil around the
world interact and cohabitate very well
with plant in the writes us here a root
zone because those are nice food sources
and so another layer that controls
biodiversity is actually how plant and
different plant species might be feeding
microbial communities within their
righteous fear when they're with a root
zone in the soil well that's a lot to
think about so essentially if you were
to bring a plant then I'm thinking into
a regional community that would have a
pretty a pretty dramatic affect effect
on the biology in that rises here so yes
so it would have a dramatic effect
potentially in the soil so microbes
occurrence soil and let me let me layer
this one more so I was obsessed for a
while as academically as a research
scientist of how plants might be able to
engineer unique Rice's here microbial
communities which is the microbes in
their root zone to support plant success
and some of the examples that I was
hypothesizing were invasive species and
I worked with cheatgrass for a while
because I was it was an interesting
grass species it's an invasive grass
species that's spread across North
America it's not that great of a forage
for cattle but it was introduced by
humans because it grew quick and it
greened up quick in the season so it was
it was planted to try and feed cattle
earlier what happened is it dries
earlier it creates a lot of seeds and it
chokes out other later season grasses
ultimately and it wasn't a good choice
to introduce but it is what it is and
it's spread across the country one of
the hypotheses and I published this work
now and I could probably show this paper
with you for sure is a sort of
cheatgrass engineer unique rhizosphere
microbes as it spreads through different
soil types to nurture its success to
help promote its ability to create seed
to create biomass so maybe compete below
ground so it even has a stronger
competitive advantage from from a
physiological point of view and so I did
conduct that study and some native
grasslands and not only in the field but
also replicated it in greenhouse that
he's going we realize that different
grass species and different
photosynthetic groups c3 c4 some forb
species and even some cam species are
able to uniquely engineer different
microbial community assemblages at some
level with their root exudates and the
root structure so there's a lot to that
but the other physical properties of pH
may be a soil texture and temperature
and hydrology I'll fill it will it's
that so you know I hear a lot of a lot
of talk about like fungal to bacterial
ratios in soils and such but that almost
feels too reductionist to me in a lot of
ways because what you're essentially
saying is that this in your example here
this grass is able to change the
microbial you know populations or
communities in the soil around the
rhizosphere making it more hospitable
for this one grass and less hospitable
for other grasses so if I'm
understanding correctly would you say
then that that if we want to look at
this
from a broader perspective that that
might be challenging to do we really
have to identify the actual consortium
in you know with each with each
particular plant species and the impact
it has on soil or am I totally missing
the point here
are you saying are you thinking relative
taking it one step to a higher
resolution than just using growth fun
fun little backfill ratios is that what
you're trying to make the comparison
fourth
yeah I'm not explaining this very
accurately but essentially you know so
so what I'm trying to get at is that we
have a lot of people claiming that if
you get the you know fungal the
bacterial ratio is correct or if you use
these specific indigenous microbes you
may get certain impacts on plant health
but to me that feels a little a little
squishy like we still don't know exactly
what's going on and you know what I'm
finding is that there's so there's so
much in the range when we say the word
bacteria or archaea like there's so much
we still don't know and there's so much
that falls into those kingdoms that do
we do can we really make those sorts of
comparisons at that macro level or macro
scale well you can make them but it's
it's about defining the assumptions and
what actually what data you can actually
get from those and I think I think what
you're saying is a really fair statement
I used to use fungal bacterial ratios to
kind of assess as one measure of
assessing plant health across different
ecosystems and and and sometimes you're
like oh this might look interesting but
it's very limiting and until you dive in
like you suggested to the actual
contributors of those fungal populations
and those bacterial populations or
communities more specifically
assemblages of different fungal species
assemblages of different microbial
bacterial species you're you're not
you're gonna have limited information
and what I mean by that is you know
fungi have different functional groups
you know there's some more muscular
mycorrhizal groups that perform specific
functions as symbiotic plant roots and
there is a lot of plant specificity here
we're supposed to
big fungal species of our busco
mycorrhizae are only really associated
with certain grasses and echo
mycorrhizal another example where
there's some real specificity of those
host plants to these fungi and then
other fungi do a very good job of
decomposing and breaking down organic
matter and so those functional groups
are pretty typical of fungi and there's
some nutrient cycling but in the
bacterial world there's a lot more
functional group specificity meaning
that there are certain groups of
bacteria that are very specific for you
know known for delivering or cycling
nitrogen or or phosphorus or other
nutrients or doing more specific
functions and so you really have to know
what's there to form again what I was
going to say is to form robust
hypothesis and any kind of de there any
kind of science if it's good it's really
just generating more better questions
that you can address the new studies and
and that's the iterative process of of
science and the scientific method we
have these hypothesis these guesses that
we hope resemble some form of reality we
test them and with the answers that we
get we're going to we're going to ask
new questions we're going to test those
new questions via hypothesis through new
experiments and so it's kind of a
never-ending cycle I kind of enjoyed
that never-ending cycle I don't do as
much experimental science as I used to
but that's the idea and that led me down
many really great paths of understanding
how microbes are engaging with different
plants and in desert systems or more
music grassland systems and it kind of
just forms my my perspective of how
nature performs and functions at least
on some level you know as a scientist
dad I actually think about everything
from a microbial perspective first I
don't know if that's healthy or not but
I can't help it I just think that's how
that's the scale that I think adds
enough get then I kind of extrapolated
that from there
so so we know that a ratio of fungal to
bacterial in soil will influence the
soil pH and we typically see certain
ratios associated with the types of
plants in terms of like a plant
succession table that we see in soils so
we'll see higher levels of fungal
activity in forests over grasslands for
example but what I'm wondering is can we
take that data and extrapolate it any
further like it sounds to me and from my
own just online research it's it appears
to me that the plant really controls
that relationship more than its one of
the strongest variables and determine
microbial populations more so than you
know what a lot of people try to do when
they try to add specific microbes we're
trying to make compost teas that are
more you know it contain more bacteria
than fungi for example it seems like the
plant is really the driver of that
microbial community is that would you
agree with that or what do you think I
mean I know there's so many variables
like you mentioned and it's really the
functional consortium for when we're
trying to improve the rhizosphere but
what do you see is the real driver there
in that system yeah so I think that's
that's a great point a little consent
conceptually here you know you think
about even even desert systems you know
they're very very much higher fun little
bacterial ratios are all relative to
abundance of fungi versus bacteria and
in natural systems in general and all
terrestrial systems they're typically
going to have higher all natural
terrestrial ecosystems you're going to
have higher fungal go back jobs you're
gonna have higher fungal bacterial
ratios then you are obviously in aquatic
systems because fungi don't thrive in
aquatic systems and you are in
agriculture systems because agriculture
systems are very harsh over time on the
natural microbial flora of the soil for
several reasons because of the chemical
inputs because of the physical tilling
and and other aspects of management
human management that really break down
and influence microbial biodiversity and
microbial assemblages fungi the way they
grow they hate tilling you know you
can't till soils year after year and
maintain significant communities and
healthy fungal abundances in those soils
that's why in natural systems they
persist from year after year and they
can live off of the roots I want to say
that in general you can create different
microbial assemblages they're different
food sources I think this is what you're
getting at there will relate it to the
plant example I can have a soil sample
that I take from anywhere you know I'm
great at growing microbes that's what I
do I've done it for so long I just know
how to do it and I can create 10
different food sources just broth which
is just like a super sugar soup and
maybe I'll Drive that sugar soup from
beets or carrots and then I'll make
another broth or media is what we'd call
it in microbiology there's different
sugar sources and maybe I'll make
another media that has a carbon source
and sugar is carbon tour time these kind
of words together microbes need carbon
nitrogen phosphorus sulfur all the macro
macro nutrients just like plants do for
the most part plants need all those
other nutrients as well but they get
their carbon from the air that's the
only difference in how they acquire
those nutrients and so we have a media
that's rich of carbon and all the
nutrients but they're different chemical
compositions and if I had the same soil
sample and maybe I you know made us a
slurry where I mixed a gram of soil with
10 mils of water and mix it up and and I
Alec wanted a drop of each of that the
same sample under those ten different
media dishes what do you think the
result would be I'm going to tell you
everyone of those media's would nurture
different aspects of the microbial
community from that initial sample and
so there
potentially tens of thousands of
different microbes and that one sample
and again we're using one soil sample
one scoop of soil one spoonful of soil
mix it in some water and drop it on 10
different easily accessible food sources
and you're gonna get ten different
results potentially and I think that's
fascinating food source is a huge
determinate of what microbes are going
to be nurture and growth and microbial
abundances is at some level a
probability game if there's a food
source that a micro blue group likes and
prefers and can take advantage of moreso
than another microbes repeat and grow
and multiply so quickly that they can
actually physically out-compete their
neighboring microbes because they can
take advantage of a food source quicker
the same thing happens with different
food sources and so different plants we
know they create different food sources
for microbes meaning they score
different carbons and different organic
acids from their roots into the soil all
plants have evolved to do this to
nurture microbial communities that bring
them success success meaning you want a
healthy thriving microbial community in
the root zone because microbes do a lot
of great thing that plants will love
cycle nutrients is one of those if you
can create a hotbed of nutrients that
plants can take up they will succeed
they'll be able to produce seed or
produce or stay healthy to the next
generation and biology success and
biology is passing your genome to the
subsequent generations and so typically
evolutionarily speaking plants that are
here now have succeeded because I've
nurtured a healthy rhizosphere
microbiome that's helped them succeed
from one generation to the next just the
very beginning of their existence to
today does that help answer that
question was that too long no that's
great it reminds me so I think
essentially what your acquaintance is
food source and so whether the in this
case the food source is the plant
exudates what the plants putting out
through the roots which thank you is
that exactly right but I don't want to I
don't want to minimize tad the other
sake or physical properties because soil
texture pH water sources you know
there's different minerals in the soil
that significantly affect pH you think
about calcareous soils where there's a
lot more calcium and crece in the soils
that's going to create a very basic
outline tool that the plants are not
going to be able to change so there's
this layer this parent material layer
and soil layer that the plants are
growing in that aren't affecting pH as
much as their their rhizosphere their
hot zone within their root zone yes they
definitely to nurture and create a micro
ecosystem within their root zone but
they're still in this broader
environment of a very calcareous or or
alkaline soil type that they're not
going to be able to influence to a
neutral or to an acidic soil and so some
microbes that grow better and an
alkaline environment along with the food
sources that the plants are feeding them
are going to be strongly influenced and
succeed better than microbes that do
better at neutral or acidic soils with
maybe a different food source or even
the same food source so there's multiple
layers of interactions physical and
biotic that you have to kind of conceive
holistically to understand the life of a
microbe I mean it's in this room there's
getting food squirted on it and there's
all these physical pressures and
temperature and hydrology and pH and do
you know why pH is a factor for microbes
you can talk about that for a sec yeah
before we do though I just want to I
just want to highlight one of the things
I've found so essentially what you're
saying is we you know taking the same
source and I've done this with compost
tea I'll take the same compost source or
earthworm castings and add you know
unsalted molasses or add alfalfa meal or
you know with some other sorts food
source for example and you end up with
very different things under the
microscope 8 12 24 hours later and if
you go longer than that I found if you
you know people asking about brewing
compost tea for a long time or can I
leave it perpetually brewing what I find
and this is
best analogy I've come up with to date
but it's not perfect to me it's like
this idea that if you opened up all the
gates in the zoo at the end of the day
you'd have your apex predator you'd have
your lions and you'd have probably some
rats and then so that's all that's
really left at that point cuz you've
lost all that diversity because they're
the most efficient microbes at utilizing
whatever food source or what lasts the
longest and in the case with compost tea
all we're left with is one morphology of
flagellate and one morphology of
bacteria and they just sort of fluctuate
as they you know pray and pronate on
each other over the next however long
until the food sources eventually run
out yes I think that's a perfect way to
talk about it I think you're thinking
about it they I might not be saying that
in those words that's exactly what I'm
trying to say you're thinking about it
right and there's there's another level
to I want to say so you have a limited
food source and you're going to nurture
only so many like microbes that grow
great at that food source and that and
then those microbes are going to get
more concentrated than them other
microbes that that don't grow as well I
want to I want to layer in there what
happened you know not as much in T's if
you really teased out longer this could
happen but also in soils is you have
fast-growing microbes you have
moderately fast-growing microbes you
have slow growing microbes and you have
very slow growing microbes etc and so
there can be a secession event where
those different microbes are also
favored different food sources and so
you can have for fungi and bacteria
layers of succession and that's why I
like to talk about it you can have this
initial secession community you know
what would happen if you left the T
going for a week or a month which is
impractical for for agriculture or for
feeding I would do that but for the
purposes of a microbial study you would
see turnover in that for a mentor or
that that tea vessel from one month to
the next until it finally stabilized
that's because the environment and that
food source continues to turn around and
you're going to have life and death of
certain groups of microbes that ate the
initially yummy easily accessible
carbon in the tea then they would die up
and then you'd have another microbial
group or groups of microbes echod kind
of decompose and take in more easily
that next more concentrated or more
recalcitrant food source so that's an
example of so many layers temporal and
spatial and physical that the microbes
are experiencing that might influence
how we're growing microbes and how to
grow them consistently which all of
these things are important so now you
know I'm kind of in the microbial
manufacturing business you have to
understand all those physical and input
properties to understand how to grow
microbes with consistency and the T
there's a real tricky thing because you
have to have consistent inputs also
don't you because if you don't have that
completely you're not going to get
consistent results every time because
it's going to be a slightly different
food source
well that and that's why most research
and most scientists don't like compost D
and I totally understand that it's
impossible to get consistency because
even a different teaspoon of compost is
going to have slightly different
microbial consortium which is going to
lead to slightly different responses to
you know a given food source so I and
you know like you mentioned your
temperature your water source the amount
of area you know the dissolved oxygen
levels in the tea itself there's so many
variables so I understand why compost
tea isn't is loved by the science world
though it has caught on a lot more I
will say over the last 15-20 years since
we first started experimenting with it
for sure you know Ted I love compost
teas and I love the idea of it I love
the practice of it I just I think it's
important to acknowledge the limitations
or to acknowledge what we don't know and
it's just hard to know everything in
that tea over time also because both the
microbes will actually change I did this
in a study looking at different natural
systems microbial communities can change
significantly seasonally just because of
those environmental shifts in
temperature in hydrology and in plant
structure where the plants die in the
winter and so different microbes
actually thrive better and other
herbs that thrive well in peak growth
season and mid summer will decline and
so if you're gathering nutrients or grad
gathering inputs from your surroundings
or your tea if you know all that stuff
you're fine and I don't think that
you're at risk because people love that
but you have to understand that you're
introducing variability into cultivation
if you're using teas without consistent
inputs totally and if you're using
sources of compost or other microbe
sources that are not they haven't been
thermally composted then you are
potentially at risk for bringing in
disease organisms as well so that is
that is definitely a concern I that
completely ignores that's a good point
let's talk a little bit about the fact
that so you're like you mentioned you're
in the the business of producing
microbes you've found it
you founded mammoth P which is a
consortium of microbes that are
shelf-stable
and something that can be added in to a
resume or to someone that's watering I
have a few specific questions about
mammoth the P but I wanted to share my
mammoth P experience first I was given a
sample oh it was years ago now and I
just left it sitting next to my
microscope for probably about a month
month and a half and I don't know how
long how old it was when I got that
sample I just threw them the microscope
one day and I was shocked to see motile
bacteria it's the only problem you know
microbial product I've ever seen on the
market that actually has active
microorganisms which I know is not
necessarily you know not having motile
or you know bacterias not doesn't
necessarily mean it doesn't have
nutrient cycling properties but I
thought that was really exciting to
actually see something moving around on
the microscope which was cool yeah yeah
it's really cool to happen you know I
can kind of talk about how we developed
this particular product but these
microbes are actually flagellated so
they are mobile and so it's very
interesting to think about that extra
functionality a lot of products in the
market are bacillus you know species
quite frankly and a lot of them creates
endospores and so they're not
necessarily active and you have to
activate them over a period of time and
they might be in a dry or a liquid
solution I've seen them carried in both
but um and many times they're actually
entered or inter formulated or developed
on the bore or non vegetative state and
so it takes some more food source we're
engaging with plant roots to actually
get them going so I think that's why you
don't necessarily see active microbes
and a lot of those other products
haven't spent a lot of time looking
under a microscope in a while I loved
early on remember we met and then you
did the study you did the you did some
substrate work - is that the same study
you're talking about that's one that's
on YouTube I believe what I would say is
yes so what I did was I just experiment
different food sources to see about
feeding the microorganisms and how they
would respond to different food sources
so that was something that interested me
what I see from most microbial products
on the market like you mentioned is when
I when I add different food sources I'll
see a growth in overall like bacterial
biomass yep but that's that's really
about it which is good it's just not as
exciting under a microscope yeah hey I
want to be clear you know mammoth T is
bacteria quite clearly but they have
these morphology structures called
flagella which are simply tailed little
tails sell out for mobility of the cells
yeah sorry about that sorry about that
yeah okay
definitely bacteria I know you knew that
okay that's okay that's what I
originally thought I misheard you
Langella are actually a lot of that's
how bacteria are mobile they have these
little tails that typically span are
they crank as as corkscrews and they
allow them to move through the substrate
and move through the rhizosphere and the
water columns or moved through the soil
and it's a really interesting level to
add whenever a bacteria is highly
functional but it can move around and
activate through different parts of the
rhizosphere or through the bottle and
even when you're using microbes like
this and this is kind of what I
determined over time if
some environmental stress and you're
dealing with mobile microbes they can
actively get out of the way of that
stress an example is like a pH sometimes
if you forget the pH your nutrients and
and you add the microbes and it's not
too harsh and then you're trying to pH
your nutrients and you're adding acid or
a base into that you know it can
potentially affect a lot of the microbes
where that pH buffer enters into that
mix where your microbes are are mixed
into the tank but if the microbes are
mobile they actually get out of the way
until experience that much stress so
it's a cool added feature that is cool
so with with mammoths pee what do you
what sorts of results are you seeing out
there with people that are using it are
there any environments where it doesn't
do quite as well or there others where
it really thrives you know that it's
probably a never-ending question I know
that when we started when we want to cut
me just as the history I left the
university about March 2015 to start the
company and we've done a solid a really
rigorous year before we actually started
the R&amp;D on the technology at the
University it'll very late or very early
in all fairness we were we were getting
ramped up to try to do something like
this at the very end of 2013 got some
funding and started it in 2014 went
through the process got some great
validation after we do up the product it
was a pretty efficient process that's
pretty well funded and then launched the
company in March 2015 into the cannabis
industry and so a scaled-up
commercialization and production and got
a small team on the ground and I turned
I was kind of still in a lot of ways
wearing all hats not like it was back
then where I literally was and getting
out and engaging with cultivators and a
lot of the commercial growers in
Colorado releasing cocoa but with our
first validation but but I will say that
before that the university validation we
tested on several different real soil
types meaning we we brought a bunch of
soil back from different environments at
least local
around Colorado that that represented
different soil textures different soil
types we worked with different potting
medium we worked with a lot of different
plant types we worked with a lot of
cannabis growers outside the University
and so we had a pretty good
representative dataset that we thought
it worked well across a lot of different
plants and a lot of different substrates
because we felt like these microbes are
very robust meaning very efficacious
they could work in a lot of different
moments they had a targeted function
that all plants needed and so if we
could just deliver these microbes to the
rhizosphere a root zone they would
engage the plant and deliver the
function that you know that they needed
and wanted that would help them succeed
their development you know yield and
other properties shinsen you know it's
had we've grown and we're selling its
technology over the world thousands and
thousands and thousands of girls are
using this and we heard great results
across the board I don't know if I hear
all the bad news if there is bad news
out there quite honestly but we hear a
lot of great news I mean you've probably
seen some good results too over time
having you known each other for years
now put me on the spot yeah so actually
I've been working with the gold leaf
gardens I didn't interview with Ben
Higgins he's their research scientist
and one of the studies they just
retrials they recently completed was
with mammoth pea and they found they got
about a 12 percent increase in wet
weight relative to the control and so
now they're doing ongoing trials to
replicate that but the initial results
were quite quite positive and this is a
this is this is a setup that I think is
fairly optimal from a microbial
perspective we're talking about large
beds that hold about 1/3 of a yard of
soil per bed and that soil is relatively
undisturbed for the entire cycle and has
been around for I think they're on five
years now with the same soil that
they've been amending so it's a fairly
it's a fairly living entity that they
have for a media compared to others so I
thought they would actually see less of
a less of a response than that because
of the fact that they were doing so much
to already you know help out the
microbial communities in the soil yeah
you know I think
their hypothesis - if there's only so
much value
I think microbes will brain wants that
to maximize do you know and there are
some functional redundancy so that's
actually that's a really good that's
really good feedback I love that I want
to stay in touch with you on that I'll
say that most ignores in Northern
California that we work with are trying
to engage in some type of living soil
where they're you know they're they're
minimizing or trying to minimize the
amount of nutrients are adding and
they're trying to stay as holistic with
their environment as possible I think
they do add some as needed across the
growing season and particularly in
flower and they're they're adding
microbes and in nurturing microbe life
and a lot of them are plugging in
mammoth pea and seeing good results but
you know what's interesting about that
also is the targeted functionality of
mammoth microbes in particular where
there's a lot of nitrogen delivering
microbes the pretty common function and
phosphorus is the world Lesko and
phosphorus is really tricky to deliver
to plants and in those particular
substrates because phosphorus is sticky
chemically xx and having some catalysts
and microbial catalysts liberate the
phosphorus might be why this particular
environment this grower facility is a
steam that added benefit 12% great
that's a pretty good value at oh yeah
when we're talking about such a high
value crop that's that's a big deal so
there what I'm curious about now is over
time what sort of persistence are we
gonna see I know you recommend
applications over a certain period of
time I'm curious to see how that if that
yield increase stays the same across
multiple cycles or if it starts to at
some point sort of level out to where
you know they're consistently getting
12% with these applications over what
their control was used to be I'm sure
they'll eventually switch everything
over if things continue down that path
but yeah I'm just curious how these
microbes do over time I know
spend some research on persistence out
there yeah it's that's a hard question
to answer but overall I'm kind of
winding in and that's why I gave some
background on some of the research I did
before starting this company cuz I think
about that and I think about persistence
a lot and one of the differences into
the work that I was doing in natural
systems that was by definition
undisturbed until I went out there and
disturbed some of it was my research to
collect data was the disturbance that's
inherent with management systems with
agriculture management systems you know
what I do know is that microbes thrive
with a living plant root because plants
feed microbes and so if you're
delivering the microbes or the
rhizosphere is an example of an
inoculate
those microbes are more than likely
going to love that environment because
it's a nutrient-rich environment and all
those other adaptiq properties that we
kind of prefaced earlier in our talk
here are right for the microbe the
plants definitely feeding in a food
source and it's going to be a happy home
but what happens when at the end of the
growth season well typically the plant
gets chopped the exudates quit coming
out because the plants not
photosynthesizing anymore it's harvested
and so that creates a completely
different environment and so what I
would say is there's probably some
persistence but I don't know enough to
know how much turnover there's going to
be for mammoth microbes in particular if
you don't mind just preface it by that
because you're dealing with a very
different environment and now the roots
are dead and they're decaying it's
probably going to nurture more fungal
life because fungi like that break down
those very complex root structures that
the bacteria then can follow up and take
advantage of them continue to mineralize
and so there's a good chance that the
rien oculi ssin with a new plant cycle
is going to be critical and I don't know
I could probably could probably do some
work together to get to the root of this
question maybe through some sampling or
whatnot do some microbial analysis but
Mike my guess is it's most efficient to
add these inoculant with every new plant
cycle because of the effects of a living
plant and the inter
action to living plant would have on the
microbial community that the soil
without a plant or plant roots that
don't have a plan associated with them
anymore they've been cut off are gonna
have it's just the environment selects
and it's a very different environment
there is going to be some persistence
though it's harder to manage because we
can't see that or mayor or measure it
regularly so regular applications for
sure you can manage that I would
hypothesize and again this is pure
speculation on my part that after this
one cycle for example in gold leaf where
they got a 12% increase and then they go
to a remand the cycle and they'll
probably do a light till and then
replant you're right you're gonna see
some die-off but I wonder if you know
some of those microbes that were
introduced will persist and stay active
to where they may see a four percent
increase in wet weight over their
control next time or something you know
some level of persistence in that regard
but I wonder if you know the addition of
you know mammoth pee in this case of you
know microbes are more active right back
into the rhizosphere
would speed up that process because one
thing that you know of all people is
that these microbes can survive some
very amazing conditions environmental
conditions you know through dormancy or
insisting or all these other processes
but we don't really want to wait for
that when we're talking about a
high-value crop that we're trying to
cycle out as fast as possible - yeah
that's where my head's going and so we
think about two things we think about
the targeted functionality and how
microbes are engaging the other level
you've already said it is he's a bun two
abundances or density at some level that
denser microbial communities or the
biomass in general is going to create
more function because there's more
microbes to create more function and
with those applications you're gonna get
to that more that higher density quicker
instead of having to revive maybe latent
or a more dormant microbial community
that overwintered in a natural example
or you know is trying to be brought back
from last season's crop in this
particular example so
I think both of the hypotheses that you
stated are really fair you know I'd be
interesting
w that'd be a fun study to conduct yeah
there's just so much we don't know about
the rhizosphere that I think it's really
I think it's really interesting I mean
you've kind of touched on so many things
just in this podcast that has brought up
a lot of questions are you seeing a lot
of new research coming out on this idea
of microbial inoculants I mean it
definitely seems to be taking off in
agriculture yeah yeah I think just to be
fair I think it's the quickest growing
agriculture industry segment across all
crops and the biggest reason for that is
because nutrients are really hard to
deliver in soils and farmers are having
a horrible time managing nutrient
absorption and uptake for nitrogen and
for phosphorus in particular potassium
is very difficult in rural schools and
in mineral soils as well and so the
industry is taken out because there's a
real need for it
I've seen a lot of interesting
technology it's focused on a couple
different do you think about effective
products and there's been a challenge
for the microbial biostimulant industry
in general that's what you call it an
agriculture microbial biosimilars we
call it you know beneficial bacteria and
the cannabis industry but their
microbial inoculants and that's fair
across both and it's pretty intuitive
you know does do the microbes what do
the microbes do to do it consistently
and do they work in many different
environments those are the three
questions you want to bridge if if they
work consistently and they have a
targeted function then you can use them
with confidence for precision because
you know what they're doing and they
continue to do it and that's great for a
farmer but if there are efficacious mean
they work across a lot of different
management or environmental conditions
and they can work for a lot of farmers
and those are the three big hurdles I
think any manufacturer wants wants to
overcome and that's what we acknowledge
I think that's what we overcame with
developing a MFT and it's it's just one
of those things we'll went into it from
a scientific perspective and we engage
in a site that's we didn't engage
the microbial manufacturing company was
a science experiment quite frankly in a
scientific fundamental scientific
endeavor and so do I think that there
are a product out there like that yeah
there's been some products out there our
busco mycorrhizae is an example it's
been around forever
there's nitrogen-fixing bacteria they've
been around for a long time those
technologies will continue to evolve
some of them are going to get rebranded
and have been in spaces for a long time
and we'll get rebranded for new markets
or new crops new industries and I think
there's other cool technologies coming
out now I was at a talk it's been a
little while now where there's some some
notion of endo fight bacteria and in
some crops it's it's developing quicker
than than others where you can have
specific bacterial species that will
actually engage intracellularly with
plant roots to help facilitate plant
health or trigger specific growth
through chemical signaling so those are
pretty interesting technologies because
they're super specific the trick is if
you have an intracellular or endo
Finnick bacteria that works well across
one crop you really want it to work well
across a lot of crops or the crops of
interest at least and so that's a lot of
pretty deep research there's a lot of
other tips
he's also that you think about I guess
there's a performance vertical we want
points to be very healthy and grow and
yield and maximize or quality or flavor
or bricks or whatever crop you're
talking about
I think cannabinoid and THC is a good
example in in the cannabis industry and
then there's this bio control space and
those are the two industry verticals
that I'm pretty fascinated with we're
not performance and then you want
protection and there's a lot of products
in the general agriculture space that
use microbes to mitigate pests I love
that tad I think it's amazing you can
apply biology with biology but it's
tricky in the cannabis industry because
a lot of these technologies are fully
early applied
and with regulatory pressures of
microbial talent sunflower on the
biomass if you're adding microbes to
above-ground applications and this can
happen with some teas also you might be
engineering microbial counts you don't
want to engineer for regulatory purposes
you have to be below a certain city of
to you so it's tricky and I our company
is actually steered away from thinking
about microbial technologies above
ground right now until we figure out how
to think about this better but maybe
deriving biochemical solutions through
microbial growth that will attack
certain pests or milled or mold or or
mildew we're thinking about this we did
have one product that we just launched
on the market that's not a microbial
product for that very reason I explained
but uh I got pretty sophisticated and
simple at the same time targeted oil
product for a different insect pest
mitigation it works good yeah are you
are you seeing any issues with using a
product like mammoth pee or other
microbial products in terms of failing
microbial tests with soil applications
and I'm not asking specific to your
product per se more just this is
something that was brought to my
attention recently as some of these new
states are coming online in Canada
they're the restrictions around
microbial testing on flour is really
really tight and doesn't take into
account a lot of the probiotic and
prophylactic microbes that exist in
these growing systems do you think
you're putting yourself a greater risk
by using microbial products or using
living soils when we're talking about
passing these tests versus a more
pharmaceutical approach no I think just
the opposite but I've validated it was
mammoth because I was interested enough
to ask that question went to some
resources on our team and what what I
think is honestly microbes are very
rarely the elusive bacteria willing to
infiltrate the cells and work their way
all the way up intracellularly in the
plant
and then emerge in the above-ground
flower tissue it's just such a tall
order and we haven't seen it it's very
hard to do that's where some of the
challenges or hurdles endophyte bacteria
are right now that technology that's
that's cool from a scientific
perspective but very hard because you
know plant and just like our skin cells
you know it's a barrier you know it's
supposed to keep out microbes and so
it's actively keeping out microbes and
so keeping my Cubs in the soil where
soil microbes actually function in their
active plants is brilliant we conducted
this study and our farm here in Colorado
where we did a greenhouse and an outdoor
soil study looking at simple very simple
treated mammoth be treated and
non-treaty keeping everything else the
same school applications just like we
would with our technology and we looked
at a few counts on the flower of the
outdoor crop and the greenhouse indoor
crop and in both environments
Tad's the CFU bacterial counts both of
them we were passing out of all fairness
but the CFU counts on the microbial
mammoth treated plants were
significantly looked then the non
treated like wow cool and you know then
you ask well why and why I think is
because if you can engage with a healthy
right of the sphere microbiome these
points are actually creating their own
health mechanisms to maximize their
health their development and all these
other properties which could limit the
[Music]
occupancy of different microbes above
ground I'll just say it like that that's
probably not the most wild way of saying
it but the data was what it was that's
interesting i yeah i'm surprised that
sort of seems counterintuitive to what
you would expect well they're in the
soil I just don't think they come out of
the soil as a short answer I don't think
the microbes are making it up in the
soil or making it up to the above-ground
plant colas where where they're actually
being tested or the flower is in
particular but they're engaging with the
plant
mechanism to to make sure the plants
taking up nutrients and that's that's a
primary function of blow ground soil
microbes nutrient cycling and these
nutrients are actually building blocks
that help build molecules that allow the
plants to respond to environment
distress to developing quality metrics
like terpenes and cannabinoids also and
so if you can maximize naturally
maximize plant nutrient uptake
I think the plant can do a lot for
itself you know in nature this is
another example I don't see plants being
devastated by by pests in many cases or
mildew in mono crops it happens more so
but in nature what did that happen to
everything you know these plants per
system to a large degree it's because
they have an in nature of long standing
very very healthy soil microbial
register interaction that allows them to
take what they need to survive in their
environment yeah my thought was more
along the line of soils than microbial
inoculants like the idea that having a
soul in your room
things might get disturbed through
employees and some of that dust may
contain bacteria they may make its way
up on to the colas and then that may
slightly raise your CFU account that
were like a people that are trying to go
vertical with soils I think that's a
challenge there too fair enough yeah if
you're physically pliant
got it if you're physically applying
soil to to any above-ground material
there's gonna be markers on soil that's
one of the problems roll and I was in
Vegas a couple of years ago during a
facility that one of the girl in
greenhouses and I had it shut the
greenhouse down and the reason was
because it's a desert out there in
Nevada and they couldn't keep enough
dust out from blowing over their plants
and they're failing microbial test
because the dust from outside that they
couldn't keep out of the greenhouse is
blowing over their plant so there was
nothing wrong with this flower there was
this natural soil dust if you will
airborne soil that are basically
harboring soil microbes because that's
where microbes live and so there
you do want to keep soil the soil off of
the above ground because again you could
be inoculating your above-ground plants
but if it's wet you know it's not going
to fly around as much if it stays in the
pot if it's in trays I think you can
manage that but you definitely want to
take measures to manage that
it's a good point yeah I mean I think
the laws are kind of ludicrous right now
around microbial testing Washington's
gotten a little bit better in the sense
and now it it tests for more specific
strains or diseases which would impact
human health so I think that is
important I think the testings itself is
important but I think that just like any
other crop we should be able to rinse or
wash it or grow it in a way that it
contains you know probiotic bacteria and
it's not dangerous then you know I'd it
just seems silly but the regulations
being what they are and we have to work
within them yeah I couldn't agree more
and it's you know it's hard maybe I
shouldn't say this when I'm saying like
it's really hard
educating regulators I mean what a
daunting task and you know it's it's
you're right it's not yeah and this is
where this is what you were talking
about a little bit earlier they're
looking at very very coarse see a few
colony forming unit concentrations of
microbes they're not looking at what
microbes are there and so it's those are
two completely different hazard issues
and there's very very very few much you
know most microbes on earth very 99.999%
of all microbes on Earth are beneficial
you know that it's a shame that all we
hear about or most the bad ones
personally because we've about the good
one humans have to focus on the bad ones
because they they're more of our risk
you know and so categorizing all the
good microbes with with some very very
few bad players just inherently nothing
nothing personal it's just how they
evolved is it's not honestly
scientifically accurate so that brought
up a question for me I've been wanting
to ask you which is
Oh globally how much diversity to really
see in the microbial world as we move
from Arizona to Colorado to Ethiopia are
we gonna see the same microbes more or
less but probably in different ratios or
within different functional groups
because I hear a lot of talk about using
indigenous microbes so a lot of people
are culturing or promoting what is
already successful in their area what
are there any dangers with bringing in
these outdoor you know these outside
microbes into a new environment for
example do you want us to kind of touch
on this subject a little bit yeah you
know it's a conceptual question and I
think you know you hear about it's a
microbiologist one of the terms that
comes up often is ubiquitous Peschel e
environmental microbiologist everything
is everywhere and the environment
collects you know and so what you are
going to see in most cases that's more
or less true that there's going to be
vast differences in their relative
abundances have certain microbial groups
and microbial functional groups in some
environment relative to others because
again the environment selects and favors
some over the other based on some of the
conversations we had earlier in this
talk and so yeah in some cases for sure
in extreme environments for sure you're
going to see very unique species that
just can't persist other places because
that environment is not going to nurture
the vast majority of microbes but I've
seen I've actually experienced companies
and worked with companies who are
manufacturing micro manufacturing
companies and they're trying to get
their product over to Australia as an
example and Australia the regular route
the regulators in Australia were like
whoa we don't want these invasive
microbes and you know I guess I don't
blame the word invasive is pretty tough
we don't want these invasive microbes in
our country and how this particular
company got around that is they prove
that
the microbes in this particular product
they were making we're in their country
already and so I think everything more
than not is everywhere it's how it's
packaged it's the relative abundances
and there's some real some real
variability and how different microbes
are different relative abundances can be
packaged to perform different functions
and we've realized that and and there's
this whole third level so that's what's
so interesting scale my favorite word
ever and there's this whole other level
of species you know do we even know what
the species is because I'll tell you
right now you know there's numerous
species of e.coli and I'm just going to
give this extreme example and very few
of them or even bad for you we only hear
about the bad ones and I use that
example cuz everyone's like well we Cole
I'll kill ya now used to work with
e.coli all the time there are certain
strains of E coli e---coli the genus and
species it's a species it's supposed to
be distinct but that's not true it's
just like a cultivar implant there's so
many varieties within a cultivar that
have different traits well microbes have
the same kind of characteristic within
their species and so there's there's a
strain specificity that shifts more so
than species specificity around
different region around our geography of
microbiology and it's harder to measure
tab so that's this other level that is
microbial ecologists or the the industry
in general the area of environmental
microbiology is just now starting to
wrap its head around how do we measure
this with confidence within any one
species it's an ongoing challenge okay
I don't have a lot to add to that that's
it no that was good I just it just gives
me a lot to think about one other
question or something I did want to
bring up that I thought was interesting
from hearing one of your talks though
was that when you talk you you used the
word consortium white a bit because when
we talk about these micro
as being you know generalists or very
targeted you did some research that
found that any one bacteria in mammoth P
by itself did not have the same effect
as all of them together like the the
some is more than the parts
can you just touch on that really
quickly yeah I was kind of touching on
that no app and my last little rant
there where you know there's there is a
real magic and the interactions of
microbes in those relative abundances
it's just true and there's no single
species that act in nature alone because
microbes have evolved to interact not
only with other plants and other biotic
and you know counterparts but with other
bacterial species in particular at the
very beginning of the creation of life
so to speak
and so what we realized knowing that
what we knew is microbial ecologist from
academic training was that we needed to
create a consortium microbes which is
again the same word for almost the same
word for community its assembly of
different species they come together to
interact to perform a unique function or
have interacted benefit and so that was
our goal at the whole time to create
consortium of microbes in any kind of
product that we're going to deploy for
agriculture because we felt like they
would be more efficacious and that they
would have a higher functionality
because it mimic a natural system and as
an example if we had a highly functional
stable consortium we entered them and we
added them to any one soil they would
have a lot higher chance of persisting
and engaging with the existing community
in the soil and plants in that
environment than a single species which
would be very much out of its element
and probably have a lot more competitive
pressures for food and otherwise with
the not only endemic microbes with the
other the other biotic life in that soil
and so we tested the theory or the
hypothesis by not only testing the
contortion
and nurturing this consortium that we
have in Amethi but then we broke down
the intial individual species with them
within this formula and tested their
functionality and then we combined all
twos threes and four combinations to
realize that in this formula and at that
concentration we had optimal
functionality which couldn't be achieved
by any of the lesser counterparts
meaning the one or two or three species
combined really fascinating stuff that
is interesting and you know I wanted to
touch on some of the Union one of the
topics we input on here was the myths of
cannabis cultivation one of the beliefs
growers have held over time around
certain growing practices and are they
legitimate unfortunately though we're
out of time for today but I would love
to maybe follow up with you another time
down the road if that would work yeah
absolutely we're gonna have a whole
session on this you probably know a
couple yourself I've got a few ideas but
I would love to hear what you have to
say with your background but before we
sign off I want to put you on the spot
could you maybe give listeners one
actionable thing that they could do in
their gardens to promote microbial
health besides using mammoth B what else
can you recommend growers consider just
as a good good practice here's here's a
little this is an easy one just remember
that carbon is the currency of all life
on Earth you know that's what
distinguishes healthy soils and high
cation exchange from lower cation
exchange or not so fertile soils that's
what distinguishes natural systems from
agriculture systems that were heavily
farmed it's total organic matter or
carbon content in the soil and if you
can nurture and maximize your carbon
content at some level you're going to
naturally certain you're going to
nurture the soil health and you're going
to nourish the soil health not only in
the ability of the soil to hold on in
nutrients but you're going to harbour
the microbial life that can help cycle
that nutrients so the carbon is the key
for all of us on earth and it's no
different for the soil awesome thanks I
really appreciate your time today
calling and look forward to talking
again soon thanks for coming on the show
yeah thank you so much that it was a
pleasure
that was Colin bell of Mammoth Pete if
you would like to learn more about
mammoth pee you can go to WWE my cribs
com
and if you would like to try it out in
your garden don't hesitate to reach out
or you can order directly on the kiss
organics website that's wwk is organics
calm and if you haven't left us a rating
and review on the podcast any
recommendation is greatly appreciated
and thank you to those of you who have
supported the podcast via patreon and
help me keep it running my next podcast
in fact is coming up with Jon a patreon
supporter of the show we just recorded a
podcast comprised of listener questions
and it was a lot of fun being on the
other side of the microphone and Jon did
an excellent job I can't wait to share
it with you here shortly
you are listening to the cannabis
cultivation and science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
thanks for listening