[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host
tad hussey of kiss organics this is the
podcast where we discuss
the cutting edge of growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge
our guest this week is jim barrett jim
has a bachelor's of science from the
auburn university in agricultural
services
a masters of science from auburn
university with an emphasis
on physiology of vegetable crops and a
phd from michigan state university with
an emphasis
on physiology of horticulture crops he
was a professor at the university of
florida from 1978 to 2016
with a focus on crop production in
controlled environments
a major component of his work was
evaluating plant growth hormones
also known as pgrs and developing new
application strategies for greenhouse
crops
after retiring from the university he
went on to run barrett horticultural
consulting for four years with a focus
on crop production and facility planning
for florida medical cannabis producers
he has since retired again and requested
that folks not attempt to contact him
but he kindly agreed to come on the
podcast to share some of his experience
around pgrs
and was originally recommended to me by
suzanne wainwright evans
i was grateful to catch up with them on
the phone and learn more about plant
growth hormones and regulators
and how they may impact crops like
cannabis as well as what risks may be
associated with their use
now on to the show hey jim well thanks
for coming on the show today
well thank you for inviting me i'm
looking forward to the discussion
yeah well can we start off by giving
listeners a little bit of your
background in the horticultural world
sure yeah i i'm a retired faculty member
from the university of florida spent
about
40 years there specializing in crops
that are grown in controlled
environments
either vegetables or a lot of the flower
crops
and one of the main things that i was
doing there was looking at plant growth
regulators that are real commonly used
in greenhouse crops
and looking at evaluating chemicals
evaluating formulations application
methods and procedures some of my
work there was directed at trying to
reduce
the amount of actual chemical that is
being used and sold
so that the chemical that was was being
used by the commercial growers
would be more efficient and there'd be
less of it being used less getting into
the environment
the last few years since i retired from
university of florida
i got involved in doing some consulting
in the cannabis
market in florida so i worked with some
of the growers there
in developing their culture for that
environment as well as designing
facilities
and that type of thing so now i'm i'm a
retired grandfather
yeah and i'd like to emphasize you are
now fully retired and you're you're
doing this out of your own generosity of
your time you're no longer
looking for consulting work and and
there won't be any contact information
for you
uh in the podcast section of this
podcast so
i'm gonna throw that out there for
listeners as well
and uh you know i want you to obviously
enjoy your time as a grandfather
so yeah that's really important
let's uh let's dive in talking about you
and you'd want to start talking a little
bit about some of the
the definitions and labeling around you
know
plant growth hormones and plant growth
regulators and and it sounds like we're
going to use those terms sort of
synonymously
in this in this podcast so um
yeah why don't we start there yeah yes
um the term plant growth regulator plant
growth regulators
is is a pretty broad term
and one of the things that's uh often
associated with plant growth regulators
is whether or not they are a pesticide
and so the term pesticide from the
federal government the pest
the epa pesticide is a legal issue
it's a legal term and so the plant
growth regulators
from epa standpoint they are
classified as pesticides so
in general in the you have
insecticides fungicides herbicides
and plant growth regulators that fall
under what they
describe as pesticides so
in general we often think of pesticides
and something you're trying to
chemical you're trying to kill something
well the plant growth regulators you're
not trying to do that you're trying to
you're doing something to regulate the
growth and
the evolution of the crop that you're
producing
so they from that standpoint as a user
you have to treat them differently
um and think about them they're
considerably
plant growth regulators are considerably
more difficult to
manage as a grower than
insecticides or fungicides
so that whether or not a plant growth
regulator
is a pesticide becomes a legal
issue and especially in the cannabis
market
it is a real issue
well every step back you're growing
tomatoes or
geraniums or poinsettias or something
the products that you use there whether
it's
an insecticide or a growth regulator
comes with a
federal label and so you can't use it
unless it has an epa-approved label
describing how it should be used
now of course with in the cannabis
market there's not
any federal regulations there and so
there are no
real pesticides with federal labels
for the cannabis market now it's
starting to evolve a little bit more
with help
just because of what's going on there
but primarily
uh for uh recreational or
municipal cannabis is regulated by
individual states
and uh
most people know what it's like it
varies so much from one state to another
what the state approves so
um it becomes a real
legal issue as to whether or not a pgr
can be used from a legal standpoint in
any given state or any given market so
that's sort of the legal
bank growth regulator situation it is
legally classified as a pesticide
now in the pgrs they're widely varied
uh there are you know several plant
hormones
um and the pgrs in general are either a
naturally occurring or a synthetic
plant hormone or a chemical that
regulates
one of the natural plant hormones or the
plant
um so that's the reason there's some
confusion about whether it should be
coral
hormones or not and then and we've sort
of just
evolved issues using term plant growth
regulators for a lot of them
um so we have
hormones like gibberellin natural
hormone in the plant
one the applica or one of the things
that gibberellin does
in the plant is causes stem elongation
it causes the plants to get larger
obviously in cannabis we must have a lot
of gibberellin in that plant because
they grow a lot
then there's a group of chemicals that
are synthetic
that interfere with the production of
gerberline in the plant
and so these are gibberellins synthesis
inhibitors
and that group of chemicals
if you put those on a plant it will make
the plant more compact
it reduces the amount of gibberellin in
the plant and so the plant is shorter
so a product like paclibutazole is in
that category
then you have other hormones like auxins
oxen
ia is the natural oxen helps
cuttings form roots and so it's pretty
common for us to use synthetic auxins
iba or naa those are products that
are chemicals that are a product like
dip and grow
to promote rooting on cuttings
cytokinin is another type of natural
plant hormone it's involved in
promoting lateral blood growth it's also
involved
in leaf dye back turning yellow
senescence of leaves and so
the cytokinin materials the synthetic
cytokinins
or the natural cytokinins that might be
found in
in something like seaweed extracts
um they will promote lateral blood
growth
uh or uh in some of the synthetic
materials like a
material that's called 6ba it's a
synthetic cytokinin
it reduces leaf yellowing so a plant
treated with that
the leaves stay longer they stay green
longer
um abscisic acid is a plant hormone that
is involved in causing leaves to
drop off it helps the plants go dormant
in the winter
and so exciting acid is something that
reduces growth
and there recently there are very few of
cyanic acids that are used in
commercial agriculture but recently
there is started being used
pretty widely of obstacle um
for use on grapes and some other crops
now
so that the grapes turn uh turn red or
ripen
uniformly and so that makes the harvest
easier so that's just an example of how
many of these plant growth regulators
are used on food crops
a um another one is ethylene ethylene is
a gas
it's a natural plant hormone produced by
the gap by the plant
normally in response to some kind of
stress
and there there is uh synthetic products
uh one of
the depth of one is the name of one that
when treated when the plants are treated
with esophon it produces the ethylene
gas inside the plant
and then the plant responds like it is
responding to ethylene and the
interesting thing about
ethylene is just lots of lots of uses
for it
ethylene can be used to cause flowering
in for example pineapples almost all the
pineapples we consume in the u.s
the plant was treated with ethylene in
the field to get it to
set fruit almost all our tomatoes and
bananas
are treated with ethylene after they
were harvested to get them
to ripen uniformly
then there's another set of synthetic
materials
that block the action of ethylene either
the formation or the
action of ethylene in the plant
and some of these are used in the
cannabis industry
uh probably not legally but
we can talk about this a little bit more
later i think but
uh ethylene becomes an important uh
chemical to talk about very often then
there's some others uh jasminic acid is
one that's being researched quite a bit
you know in the
folks that are looking at plant hormones
across the board in all types of crops
so the term plant growth regulator
covers a wide base of
chemistry or actual chemicals and also a
wide base of what we're trying to do in
the plant
uh so it's pretty varied
so took a little time answering that
question but um
it's it's a it's a pretty complex issue
oh no that was great i mean i'm sure you
could there's college courses just on
this
topic i realize it's quite broad um
and there's a lot and we're obviously
not gonna be able to get into all of it
uh today but i would like to touch on
some of the highlights from
you know our conversations off air here
and one of the things i'd like to start
with because when i think of
plant growth regulators i mean in
cannabis i immediately go to
um paclobetrisol it's just it's the one
that everyone knows it's the one that
was most commonly used
uh people say you know i you can tell if
uh
if a plant has been treated with
paclobutrizol
can you talk a little bit about it just
as a general perspective
and then let's talk about how you know
in terms of how it affects a plant
just strictly from um you know
morphology per
a morphology aspect and then let's talk
a little bit about what's going on
uh possibly inside inside the plant
uh sure yeah paclobutazole um
this is a product that i started working
with in about 1980 so i have a
long history with paclovicazole
there is a there and so paclobutazole
is a synthetic chemical that blocks the
production of gibberellin in the plant
so it it is an inhibitor of growth
um and in general uh pecleobutanol
there are several others in this
category uh unicontazole
is uh the molecular
structure is very very similar to peclet
dissolved
uh but you know contol is more active
there are others domenicide is in the
same
[Music]
group of chemicals that block ga
synthesis
uh chloroquine chloride or some people
know it as cycle cell
cycle cells one of the cormo clots one
of the more widely used chemicals in
agriculture is used
many parts of the world on wheat and
grain crops to
prevent them from lodging to keep them
standing up
stronger in the fields
they're also being used on turf grasses
and golf courses and stuff quite a bit
so practical methods all is the one that
is
very often used and because it is
readily available
in agricultural markets i know some
cannabis growers have
have tried it and have used it so
it because it's blocking gibberella
it causes the internodes to be
more compact shorter
um there is a very very strong
relationship
with the dose amount that is put on
so unless if you take the example of
something like a cannabis plant that has
long internodes
so if you would normally be getting
internodes that
are as the plant is growing either
vegetative or in flowering
if the internode naturally would be
let's say five inches long
um you could put on a peklobuco's
all-amount that might reduce that
to three to four inches or you can put
on enough that you reduce it to a half
an inch or an inch um
and that that's just that is just a
matter of what the grower
is trying to do and so
you can get those kinds of effects
active butters always
very very active
the other thing that's important to
think about from the cannabis market
is that hectobutazole is very
long-lasting in the plant
it breaks down into plant degrees very
slowly
and the reason i think that is a
significant issue
is that more and more markets
particularly if you're in a medical
market now
all of your product has to be tested
before it goes to
to sale and peclet butas all absolutely
will show up in there it does not break
down
uh i mean i know i know uh
plants that are still showing the growth
of practical
effects of hexabuchus all five to six
years after they've been treated
um so i think that is
that is a that is an issue to me that's
a
that's a very serious issue for many of
us
in the cannabis market yeah oh
absolutely
and uh to be clear it's not it's not
legal to use
paclibutrizol on cannabis there's no
legal application for it
i've always you know being an organic
grower
had a lot of negative associations with
it but i haven't really researched it
too much
um one of the things that i think is
interesting that you mentioned in terms
of how long it stays in the plant so
it's essentially what you're saying is
it's systemic would i have
issues cloning a plant that had been
treated with paclobuterosol for
say potentially multiple generations
depends on the concentration depends on
the rate that was put on
okay now on on a mother plant for
example
if you put on a little bit too much i
mean if we don't just a little impact
abuses all maybe and cut you
the length of your reduce the length of
your cuttings by 25
or 50 or
you can just stack those nodes right on
top of each other and you won't have
enough stem there to take a cutting on
and so if you put on too much on a
mother plant you throw the plant away
that's what you end up doing well i
think the main reason people are using
it is to increase the weight and density
of their buds um or flour
and so that that's typically what i hear
about again this is not an area that i'm
terribly knowledgeable on i've never
used it
one of the things that you mentioned
because i i was worried about safety
um from a you know medical perspective
for people who may be immune compromised
you know is it carcinogenic
those sorts of questions around its use
in terms of danger
your concern from talking to you sounded
like a more
the the highest level risk is with the
applicator
and i think that's interesting
the um with with these in general i
think
pgrs uh
yes yeah and pesticides in general this
is a little bit of a side note but if
you
many of our pesticide regulations that
we see
our design and we talk about
the end user the consumer whereas
if you're working with something that's
toxic the person that has the highest
exposure is the person who's implying
um and so if it's something that's toxic
that is the person that has the greatest
potential
problem with it and there are a number
of application a number of
examples of that uh
actually i started using a couple of
specific name examples and i'm
i won't i won't do that um
because they're sort of in the courts
right now and stuff but
uh in the cannabis market this spills
over to the silver
issue in the cannabis market where
silver products are being used and
particularly
some of the products that are being
recommended for use twice a day
until flowering that person who is
applying that silver
has a potential a lot of exposure to uh
you know a metal that's not very safe
for you
so that applies to all of our all of our
chemicals
uh and back to pacobutazole
i don't know of any impact with yourself
formulation i don't know of any of these
synthetic
jibril and uh inhibitors that have an
organic label
um almost all of them are
labeled for food crops in one
application or another paclobutazole is
used on
uh a number of the tropical fruits where
the trees tend to get real large
they can use the package of butchers all
to keep the trees from getting quite so
large
rice crops in several of the asian
countries are treated with paclobutazole
to
keep it shorter and more compact and
stronger so that it
holds up in the fields until it can be
harvested so
they are used on on food crops uh
now the the paclobucosol label
that most of us see is the one is a
product called bonsai and bonsai is used
on ornamental crops flowers
it's not used on food crops so that
label does not have food crops on it but
there are other
peplobuchizole labels that do
so if i if i'm buying organic
produce though that would that would
guarantee that these
these products are not being used on
that crop
correct uh uh well you said use the term
guarantee
[Laughter]
to the to the best of our knowledge uh
you know
assuming that someone's not cheating the
system if you're if you're buying
certified organic then um these products
are not allowed in that
there's no there's no synthetic plant
growth regulators that are allowed for
use in organic production
correct that that's that's correct okay
wanting to avoid you know uh wheat crops
that haven't been treated with
uh chloramic water where you you know
you buy an organic product
yeah yes that's true but but these
things have been being used
on our organic produce for decades it
sounds like
um from what you're what you're saying
like in the case of pacquiao butchers
all
uh yeah yeah okay
um and there's no research that you're
aware of regarding
say combustion versus uh
you know consumption of
some of these chemicals which is is
something i wanted to highlight as well
um is there any research to show what
happens when you burn
paclibutrizol in the leaf tissue you
know in the case of cannabis versus
you know eating it in say a rice crop or
something like that
uh the short answer is no um
[Music]
you know in general there wouldn't for a
company who's selling the product who
has to pay for all this testing
uh there will not be a need for them to
do that kind of testing and unless
they're selling it
right now into tobacco for example
and this group of chemicals none of
these are used on tobacco
um and so no i don't know of any testing
to see what would
what the response would be on uh any of
these products that
are uh you know are burnt
okay okay well let's uh let's move on to
a couple other
uh plant growth regulators um besides
you know gibberellin inhibitors let's
talk a little bit about triacontinol
because
you and i were talking about alfalfa
because we're uh we're talking about
maybe you know organic sources
and you shared some stuff that i wasn't
aware of regarding
you know tricontinol yeah uh tricontinol
is uh gosh
i was at michigan state and uh
oh it was about 70 76
or something like that working on my phd
and one of the
faculty members i was working with made
the discovery of tricotinol
and it's it's a really interesting
molecule it's an interesting uh plant
growth regulator
alfalfa is where it's been found in the
highest concentrations
um i don't know of any commercial
trichotinol products i you can
you can go to a a chemical supply
company and buy tricotinol but that'll
be in a real concentrated form
and trichotinol is a in a concentrated
form
is very very difficult to handle it
breaks down
very readily um even if you
for example handle a spoon and get a
little bit of acid off of your
fingers and then use that spoon to to
handle the trichotinol it'll break the
tricotton all down
and so oblivious activity um
but where track continue has shown to
to really have its best effect is
using alfalfa as a mulch
around plants and uh
the original work was actually an
accident using tri-cotton oil as a mulch
and seeing how much uh promotion and
growth occurred in some of the grain
crops
um so i think the
the place for that is if the you know if
if a cannabis producer has access to
alfalfa
uh using that as a uh
either incorporated into the soil or as
a
as a mulch for in-ground plants would be
the place that there would be a real use
there
and so sometimes it works real well it's
like a lot of the plant hormones are
like this
sometimes it works real well and
sometimes it doesn't work very well
there's not any negative effects but
when it works
the effects on plant growth very
dramatic yields
the things that are increased so if i
were to as an organic grower throw some
alfalfa meal in my soil i'm probably not
getting a lot of tricontinol
benefits because it's probably breaking
down
what i'm getting or you know does the
pelletization process or even the meal
process with
with alfalfa affect tricontinol
do we need are you when you talk about
mulching are we talking about
you know uh something more stemmy
more like the original plant crop itself
yeah
now this this goes beyond my real
experience because i have not worked on
tricottnell since
you know looking at michigan state um
[Music]
and so what i'm familiar with is getting
the the performance from using
uh the alfalfa plants as mulch
okay and so what happens when it's uh
pollicized and and dried and that kind
of thing i don't know
okay so that we could do our own i'm
sure i'm sure there's some folks that
are looking i'm sure
there are some folks that are looking at
tricotinol now that have
have much more update information than i
do
yeah that's great well can we go back
you know i don't one thing we didn't
really even talk about what what is what
tri continental
does like what are the the benefits are
in terms of a
plant growth uh if gramos photosynthesis
photosynthesis it promotes growth makes
the plants more efficient
so when you say promotes photosynthesis
would it allow the plant to take in
more light as in it could handle higher
light intensity
or that it allows it to be more
efficient with the amount of light it's
receiving
uh both okay both
yeah um and co2 that's that's the other
one is more efficient with uh
of course if you're an outside grower
you're locked into natural co2 levels
and the plant is more efficient you know
yeah
now that's interesting i might be worth
trying some trials
you know some controlled environment
trials
using alfalfa as a mulch i'd be curious
to
do a little research or learn more about
that i wonder if there's any
uh negatives in terms of pest habitat
and and other things like that that
might offset but
um i'll have to talk to suzanne and kind
of pick her brain on that one
right right yeah interesting though
can we you know you touched on ethylene
that's one that there were a lot of
questions about
you know when i think of ethylene i
think of bananas and ripening
but i don't know a lot about it how
would one potentially use
ethylene gas to their benefit when we
talk about cannabis or
or detriment are there things to avoid
in terms of ripening
or how this gas works yeah well ethylene
um i've never treated a cannabis plant
with ethylene
and there is a
a product called ethaphon
can be used and is used on a number of
crops to
spray the ethaphon and then inside the
plant is converted to ethylene so it
would not be difficult to apply
basically apply ethylene to a cannabis
plant
the responses that i would anticipate
getting would be enhanced leaf yellowing
uh senescence to leaves um
if you put it a little bit too early you
can knock off flowers
um and so
timing on ethylene and its application
in plants is a
is a real issue now one of the things
that ethylene would do
um is
ethylene would tend to make a plant
more likely be female so
where you're typically where you i think
this is a little bit of a stretch but
we're having a problem with
herbaphonites
ethylene potentially would prevent that
problem
okay um but i i anticipate that you'll
see too many negative
effects with ethylene itself the
place for ethylene in cannabis
is the products that
are preventing uh the plant from
producing ethylene
ethylene is involved in sex expression
so
in cannabis a number of other plants if
you block
the ethylene natural production of
ethylene in the plant
it will shift from producing female
flowers to male flowers
and so that's where um
there are a number of cannabis folks and
particularly the
feminized hemp seed that's
you know become so popular in the market
that tends to be
produced using a product that blocks the
natural ethylene production in the plant
okay so um you know
i guess we need to get into how you
produce feminized seed but you need to
take a female plant
and get male
flowers and dust pollen produced
on that on that plant and you do that by
blocking the ethylene production in the
plant
okay okay so when i think of
ethylene i think of um
you know post-production like i assume
that you know after we harvest the bud
and it's in a jar
ethylene is probably building up in that
jar so when we burp the jar we're
going to lower the ethylene levels in a
jar and then when we put the lid back on
that process would restart and that's
something we're kind of
naturally regulating in in the curing
process
is that is that way off base
um well i i i just made it at that point
that once you dry that
material you're not going to get any
more eflain really produced by it
so as it's drying though is what i'm
wondering i mean maybe not once it's
cured but as it's going through that
sort of
curing process like moving towards
homeostasis in terms of the
the leaf tissue is is there still
ethylene being produced or
is at that point is it done it the
ethylene the ethylene production is
gonna
going to be decreasing just like all of
the other um
when when that tissue is first cut
there's a big blast of ethylene is
produced
that's a natural thing that the plant
does
uh when it's wounded it produces a lot
of ethylene
but then as as it's drying out the
amount of ethylene
that is produced will be dramatically
reused
so that that kind of takes me in a
different direction like when we go in
and say
prune our flowering room uh and remove a
bunch of material and we're making a lot
of
plant wounds would that be a good time
then to
potentially um do an air exchange
to remove any or is that probably
insignificant in terms of the amount of
ethylene that's actually being
production
yeah that staff would yeah i think
deathling is very important
but most of that is sort of internal
ethylene it's in
in the tissues and moving around okay
and
and i think i actually i anticipate
that um
in particular as we get close up the
closer to flowering and harvest
that a lot of what we're doing
is stimulating stress in that plant so
that it will produce more oils more
terpenes
and ethylene is involved in that so so i
think our
wounding of the plant at that point
is making the plant respond like it's
being
attacked by insects and so
ethylene is a natural factor there the
the gestaltic acid is an act
natural part of that process and so
we're actually benefiting from that
ethylene production when we wound the
plants at that stage
okay yeah i mean plant stress i think is
is a fascinating topic when we talk
about cannabis
so essentially it's pretty complex yeah
yeah yeah
now i've always been under the
impression with cannabis that
you know with all the facilities that
i've visited that we have no issues
creating plant stress
so i'm always on the side of reducing
plant stress because it seems like every
facility has something
you know there's no perfect grow out
there at least as far as
i've seen um but i do wonder about
targeted plant stress like i've heard of
tomato farmers flooding their fields
with salinity i've heard of other
with other food crops you know targeted
plant stress
to increase fruit production or
you know flavonoids terpene expression
um have you seen any research in that in
regards to
cannabis or any direction in relation to
our conversation that you think might be
well
the research that has been done clearly
shows
that the stress uh that's
you know tend to apply to cannabis and
the way it's grown
is stimulating terpenes
um which but i think that's as far as we
really
go in our information about how to
control it
we're doing it but we're not controlling
it very well um
so um our high salt stress
uh if we're drought stressing definitely
the leaf removal
um even the air that we're blowing over
the plants is
causes ethylene formation
and so we're doing a lot to stress the
plants
but we're not doing very much in a
controlled setting so i think
as the industry and the information
evolves
we're going to be finding out which are
the best stressors
and when to apply them uh
and right now i haven't seen any
research that really tells us that
i think i think there are a lot of
individuals that they feel like what
those works
works best in their facility but we we
don't understand
you know the why behind it yeah i mean
i've even seen
guys throw ice cubes all over their soil
to
you know prior to harvest to freeze the
plants
um you know and shock it that way uh
you name it i've seen it i feel like on
in forums and stuff
but uh you're right we don't know and
it's it's very uncontrolled and i think
it's
i think it's interesting and the other
thing to bring up is we we have a
massive genetic diversity
in cannabis when we talk about the
selection of cultivars that we're
dealing with where you don't have that
in other food crops for the most part
and that's going to affect things too i
would think and we have to account for
that as well
with all the plant hormones the the
plant diversity is a big
issue uh what works best or the dose
or the timing of the dose and one strain
if i'm working with tomatoes or
geraniums or poinsettias or whatever
this the uh what well cannabis folks
call them strains and
agriculture we call them varieties or
cultivars
but from one to another the dose and the
timing is different the optimum dose in
timing is different
and cannabis is one of the most diverse
plants and from a crop standpoint that
uh
that you can find and so there's a huge
variation
that we don't understand yet yeah i
think that's an important thing to
remind people of because what may be
perfect for one
you know strainer cultivar may have an
entirely different effect because when i
think of
uh you know when you talk specifically
about gibberellin i can think of some
plants that are already quite compact
relative to others that are you know
huge internodal spacing um and there's
there are big
and you know research on other crops
that tell me that there's big
differences in the level of ga that's
produced by those
different strains yeah that's really
interesting
yeah yeah well let's uh let's move on to
another one here we talked about
ethylene
uh jasmonic acid or jasminate is another
one that
um i've seen in relation to roses
yeah but before we get off of that and
i'm not following time
uh but under the ethylene we did not
really directly talk about silver
phthalo sulfate
oh sure yeah yeah so
for blocking ethylene um
silver thousand sulfate is a chemical
that a lot of folks that are producing
cannabis seed are using to produce that
male
plant from a female
clone um
silver also is um
it's a chemical that's been around for a
long time and this effect on that thing
is really pretty well known
um there are there you can buy it on
amazon
uh with a you know a product with the
marijuana leaf on it and that kind of
thing but
there's no labeling is that i mean it's
technically it is a pesticide and
there's no
there's no federal or state labeling
that i know of
or silver thousand sulfate um
there's information on how to make it
yourself uh
that kind of thing but it is not a
really safe product that silver is in
there
and um from an environmental standpoint
uh if you're using silver salt valve
sulfate
spraying it in a greenhouse or a growth
room or something you're getting it into
the environment
so in my mind it's not a very safe
alternative um there's another product
that this is this
uh this other product is called ethel
block or mcp is the
molecule mcp
[Music]
it is a labeled product for use on
agricultural crops it's
not labeled on cannabis
but it is a safer product
there is another product that breaks
that
stops ethylene and
it's called evg and there is a
commercial
product that's used on apples called
retain
uh that
you know if you're gonna if you're gonna
do something that's
well you know if you're doing something
that
none of it's gonna be labeled i think
you'd be better off using a safer
product than a silver
product um and you know i know
that there are some people that are
talking about using the colloidal
silver
for the same effect and to me that's the
least efficient it requires much more
silver to do it and it's more dangerous
um so anyway that's my
that's my two cents right there yeah
that's not an area i'm very
knowledgeable about
you know as an organic person i think oh
silver it's a metal
uh that sounds like a good option but
you know organic doesn't necessarily
equate
safe there's a lot of organic compounds
that are quite dangerous
and i think that's an important
distinction that you mentioned there so
thank you for sharing that
yeah yeah um actually and jim roland
gibral and uh jibrillan products are
widely used in the markets and in
agricultural markets
and they will tend to do the same thing
they're not quite as efficient as the
silver thyla sulfate but they will
they'll do the same thing and promote
male flowers okay
so i want to come back to uh
you know we talked a little about
paclobutrazole when we talking about
safety
you know i did do a little quick
googling and saw there was some research
showing
potential liver damage in rats related
to paclibutrizol
obviously growers that were using it and
it was in
a lot of these hydroponic products uh
you know
found one thing to realize is that
people are putting stuff off label in
these hydroponic
nutrient products or they have in the
past and that's the big challenge you
know so
and these are pretty major companies you
know everyone knows the names of these
companies and they were able to make a
lot of money by selling these because if
you can
it makes growing plants or growing
cannabis a heck of a lot easier if you
can cut down your flowering times
that saves you a lot of money you know
in other products i know this
isn't maybe a pgr but i wanted to talk a
little bit about
eagle 20 when we're talking about some
of these potential
you know products that people are using
in cannabis that
are not necessarily legal
did you want to touch it all on do you
have any familiarity with that product
at all
in terms of uh you know i'm familiar
enough
with it that i i know what the situation
is and
this this is a problem in the marijuana
uh cannabis market um
and and and it gets
and it gets you know back to not knowing
what's in some of these things that are
purchased and used
and it's easy to do the marketing it's
easy to create
really glossy brochures and bright
labels
and all that kind of stuff and and the
marketing
uh the marketing can make the the
product sound like that it's
you know the best things that sliced
bread um
and you don't know everything that's in
there and you don't know what
is you know what's what's there and so
that's where i come from traditional
agriculture i like labels i like
information that is legal describes what
the product is
what it'll do you know how to use it
and identifies everything that's in
there um
and so the sooner we can get to that and
you know 100 percent in the marijuana
market uh the better
uh there's still just lots of material
that you can buy from amazon or down at
uh
you know the big box store or where
wherever
um online sources that uh
i described it sometimes the marketing
is better than the product itself
and that that's unfortunate so i would
really encourage
you know everyone that's uh that's
growing cannabis
to really pay attention to the products
that they're using
and making making sure that they're
getting better that's
that's the important thing to me is that
we're always moving
in a better direction
yeah i guess i want to touch on that
really quickly jim because
you know as as a grower to be able to
use
pgrs and you know micro butanol which
we're talking about
when you say something like eagle 20 it
makes it really easy to grow the plants
finishing sooner
it's denser you know applying a systemic
pesticide allows us to not have to worry
about
things like mites or things like powdery
mildew
it makes it really easy for the grower
to grow a healthy looking plant
but when we talk about the risk
associated with it
you know i want to highlight that one
it's risky to the to the grower
because they're exposing themselves to
higher levels of these toxins they're
probably not doing it
in a manner that's safe this is all off
label and not researched
and they haven't been trained they don't
have a pesticide license to apply these
things
uh so there's a risk to them but then
the risk to the consumer like with
michael butanol you know i've read that
you know it is used on a lot of our our
food crops
and that's something that that i think
growers use in defense of its use in
cannabis however
there is no research it's not allowed on
tobacco there is no research in terms of
exposure versus inhalation
or via inhalation or absorption through
the skin
as well as um
you know when we when we burn it
supposedly
what i've read from you know people
smarter than me is that it releases
a highly toxic gas or form of cyanide
and
so i i worry that people
growers look at these pgrs or you know
some of these pesticides are systemic
and say oh well they're used on
apples or they're used on mangoes or
rice
they're they're safe and that's why when
you say you know this
this thing about labels i think that's
so important i don't think we can
highlight that enough
um because these labels are
there's hundreds of thousands of dollars
if not millions of dollars behind the
creation
and testing of what they're allowed to
put on this label
yeah and that's i mean sometimes the
government regulations are good for us
uh for a
any pesticide product
to get a label for cannabis
a federal label for cannabis it has to
be tested
residues have to be established
all of that kind of thing and so it
would be a much much safer situation for
us
um even if you just talked about organic
see that's one of the current
problems with the organic certification
it's a federal certification and you
can't get that
you can call it organic or natural or
something but it's not
tested to be that uh so and if you
really get an organic
i mean if you go to the grocery store
and you buy an organic tomato it has a
little label on there that's
you know it says it's been certified as
being organic well an independent agency
has to come in
and evaluate what that farmer producer
is doing
to make sure that they're following all
the rules and so if you're just
selling any kind of product and saying
that it's natural and it's safe for it
just using the term organic without
using the official label
there's no one that's actually
inspecting that as certifying it
so that's that's where i think as we
move in that direction of more
federal regulation and just
in this space would be a lot better off
absolutely you really it really comes
down to knowing your grower
and there are certifications out there
like
i don't know if you've heard of
certified kind with andrew black where
he is
following these same standards uh
that the nop uses and and actually doing
right and doing testing so
that's great the problem is there's just
not enough
oh i guess not enough public awareness
around it
you know to where that certification has
as much value as i think it should
you know that that certified organic
sticker
when we go into the grocery store it
carries a lot of weight at least for
someone like me i'm putting a lot of
trust behind it
compared to you know i'm paying what 50
cents a dollar or more
uh produce for it you know and i
realized that
i'm paying for that certification i'm
paying for that company to do that work
and know that my product is
what i'm eating is grown in a way that
fits with my
you know my ethics or my morality so
yeah you're absolutely right that is a
challenging cannabis right now
yeah so uh so dad one of the things that
we might want to discuss
just a little bit i think you mentioned
that you had some questions about the
uh temperature and affecting growth and
what we refer to as the difference in
day and night temperature
yes we'll take a moment to do that
absolutely so the three things i want to
cover with you before signing off i know
we're running a little long here
um was was that topic that how adjusting
temperatures may
work similar to you know some of these
pgrs and how that might be useful for
people i want to talk about jasmonic
acid
and then i want to talk about stability
because people are making a lot of
uh you know ferments or applying
organic products like kelp meal for
example and thinking that they're
getting
these various pgrs or alfalfa and how i
want to talk about how stable these
things actually are to know if they're
if they're
potentially even in the final product to
say yeah we are getting some of these
natural pgrs or no they're probably
you know disappearing before they ever
really have an effect on the plant
so those are the three things yeah where
would you like to start okay
all right all right first dip um okay
and
this is basically uh short for
difference
and and so is the difference in the day
and night temperature
and in a natural situation bites are
cooler than the
than the days are so there is a positive
difference let's say
it's uh 65 degrees at night
75 degrees during the day so that's a
positive 10 degree
diff you lower that difference
and even going to a negative diff you
create
shorter internodes smaller plants
very very similar to a peclobutrizol
effect
so in a greenhouse or in any controlled
environment
you have the capability of controlling
your day and night temperatures
and so instead of getting a 10 degree
difference you
lower it to say two degrees or zero
you'll see a much more compact plant
you can take it one step further i'm
sorry
i wasn't aware that that's really
interesting so the smaller the
difference so the
smaller the internet yeah and you can
take it one step further
is that if you make your nighttime
temperature
cooler i mean warmer than your daytime
so let's say your nighttime temperature
is 70 degrees and your day temperature
is 68 degrees you'll have an even more
compact plant
i mean there's some challenges around
that with lighting and there's
definitely some there's definitely some
challenges
now particularly in a greenhouse kind of
setting where you're doing natural
ventilation
there is an important period that is
about one hour
before sunrise and
two to three hours after sunrise
and that's when in a 24 hour period the
plant is most responsive to this
differences in temperature so there's a
technique that's sometimes called the
morning
dip so if you're going through the night
your temperature is 70 degrees
during the night about an hour before
sunrise
lower the temperature to something like
and then keep it low for about three
hours after sunrise
and then it go let it go up to a natural
day temperature
that will give you the most compact
plant you can get
wow now there's there's quite a bit of
information on this we can't go into all
of it but there's
i sort of threw the big picture at you
real quick there
uh you can just do a internet search
for uh plant
response to death or difference in day
and night temperature
and you'll find quite a bit of
information this is pretty widely used
in uh
and flower crops that are used in
greenhouses
um and that's a good technique now i
have not done it on cannabis
and i don't know anyone who is i'm
guessing there's some folks out there i
know some consultants that are very
familiar with this
so i'm guessing that there are some
folks that are playing with it
uh but it definitely works and cannabis
looks like it would be a
perfect crop to to try this out now at
the same time
uh everyone's dealing with humidity
issues
you'll if so it works best if you're in
a situation where you can manage
humidity at the same time
at least on cannabis yeah
that's really interesting i i hope to
hear from people that
that are to do more research on this and
experiment
um yeah that doesn't it definitely works
it definitely works great one of the
nice things about
it compared to using type of buca salt
is when you put pack of glucose all in
the plant when you put it in the system
it's there
this depth concept you can manipulate it
and give it two or three
days one way and two or three days
another way so you
you know if you want the plants a little
taller you can give it make it a little
more
positive if you want them compact you
you know they'll respond within two or
three days
very turn it on and off yeah
it's great well anything more on that or
do you want to jump into
uh jasmonic acid gas lonic acid
um yeah this is this is one that's
really interesting and there's tons and
tons of research
being done by you know botanists
who are studying stress and plant
hormones
um and i know in the cannabis industry
there's there's quite a bit of
interest in it uh gasmonic acid
is involved in stress response
um response to the plant to natural
stresses
like temperature and drought stress but
also response to
insects and so it is part of the process
of the plant
of adjusting the way it's growing
to account for the stress that it's
under
and there's potential uh i think i've
mentioned earlier that i think that in
what we're doing
in the way we're stressing plants we are
causing the plant to
produ be producing its own gestatic acid
as it would naturally do and general
jasonic acid reduces growth
that's in general um
but it's also working in the plant is
working with the other
hormones the gibberellins and ethylene
and iae
auxins to adjust that
and as the stress level goes down the
growth might go back
up and those kinds of things uh
there there is a gismonic acid product
being sold on amazon i mean you can go
buy it uh but there's no information
about how to use it
doses timing those kinds of things and i
have seen
i've seen the evidence that jasmine gets
you know works on producing uh plants
treated with gizmodic acid produce more
terpenes
um but then there's a whole issue of the
huge number of terpenes and how much you
apply
and and things like that and how it
affects some different uh
strains um
and so right now
i don't know that anyone can tell you
this is what to do
to use and be successful with jasminic
acid on cannabis
um it looks like there is definitely
some potential there
but like most of the hormone things
there's so many ways that
um that the hormones interact with
all the other conditions how much
fertilizer we're using how much water
it may be that we're already stressing
the plants so much
that if you go out and start treating
the gistmonic acid you get more negative
effect so that's that's always a concern
too
so while i think it is an interesting
area to look at
it's not one that uh you know if someone
feels like they're an earlier doctor
they might go
you know troll it a little bit but i
wouldn't go out there and
you know got the farm on it that kind of
thing
well jim is there any legal
uses of jasminic acid on cannabis and
i i don't know a lot about it how safe
is it i've seen
you know jazz space spray for roses
um but you know how how safe is it for
compared to say paclobetrizal or some of
these other pgrs
or is they all kind of that same
category of just untested and we don't
really know
the safety it's absolutely untested yeah
i don't know of
any uh chasmonic acid
product that's being sold in agriculture
that has gone through the
sort of rigors of testing that epa
requires
okay um but my feeling is
that it's it's going to be relatively
safe but
you know arsenic is a natural product
too
so we need to know more we absolutely
need
more need need to know more but it's
definitely one that
you know i think has some uh potential
uses for us
it may be that the system that we're
currently using
isn't the best system it might be better
for us to
do some more things to reduce stress
early in the crop and then stress it at
the end
with the gizmotic acid treatment for
example
that might be a better production system
i would anticipate
as you go up in scale and start
you doing larger production areas and
trying to do
more exact timing that getting away from
our current stresses
uh will make it more uniform and then if
we can
apply a naturally uh occurring material
near the end of the crop to you know
uh jump that terpene production that's
probably a better system
and we might find that it's better to
just
use salt stress you know
and and you know two weeks before
harvest something like that as being
the way the best way to produce the crop
or light stress we just don't know don't
know right now
i think the biggest takeaway i've gotten
from my conversation with you
uh today is is just an understanding
of what these pgrs are and how
how they work inside of a plant would
give a grower
a better understanding in terms of
potential manipulation of you know plant
growth and plant stress
so i i think just a better understanding
of botany and
you know some of these chemical
reactions
is useful for a grower
i i think that's important i think
that's important you know i
with my flower growers that i've worked
with for years
and doing growers seminars on how to use
uh
the inhibitors like factor but dissolve
and that kind of thing i
i told the audience over and over again
if the question they asked me
is what ghost to put on or what rate to
use
if my answer to that is don't use it
because that is the last thing you
decide
after you look at all of the other
inputs that you have
your the differences in your
temperatures your light levels the
irrigation the strain that you're
growing
all of that then you decide how much to
put on
and so it's it's there there's a lot of
potential but it's also
requires a more technical
growing strategy i guess that was a way
to put it
yeah and once again none of these you
know none of these chemicals that we
mentioned are legal to use on cannabis
and we're not certainly not
encouraging growers to go out there and
use them um
right so that's the most important thing
i want to highlight yeah
yeah and with with cannabis is
absolutely
um you know right now in the us at least
is look at your state requirements and
what's
legal to use in that state it varies
from state to state
if you're across the border in canada
the same
absolute chemical may be legal in canada
and not in
anywhere in the u.s or vice versa yeah
yeah
so it's it's all it's all gets down the
local regulations is
and uh and all and if you you know
and then that that whole issue i think
more we're going to be doing more and
more testing
and some of these things really last for
a long time in the plant
you know honestly my motivation as an
organic grower with this podcast was not
only to educate people but to hopefully
discourage them if they were using them
and realize some of the potential risks
associated with use not just to
themselves but to the consumer
at the end of the day i know some people
are are going to still continue to apply
these things but at least maybe they'll
have a little more
education and hopefully consider not
using them in their grow if they are
because
frankly it's illegal and i don't i
personally don't believe it to be safe
but we don't ultimately know
and that that's the biggest thing um
for people to be aware of so let's let's
dive into this last question
so you can get back to your uh get back
to your day
uh i wanted to know about stability of
these pgrs because
like for example you know i used to make
willow water
to try and extract iba you know i've
experimented with kelp meal
and seaweed extract powder and uh
alfalfa
you know trying to potentially capture
natural sources
of these uh pgrs
how stable are these like i wasn't aware
of tricontinol being
um so unstable to where i probably i you
know i was getting other benefits from
alfalfa but probably not the tricontinol
so
like what about some of these other ones
yeah uh
you know it varies a lot the auxin
materials that
um that are used for brooding
uh the naturally occurring auxins tend
to be very unstable
a little bit of exposure to light uh you
know
and they break down um
that's sort of the reason that we don't
use naturally
natural iaa in in propagation we use the
synthetic materials that
hold up longer um
and even yeah it you know it varies and
and i haven't looked into this area
that's that's definitely an area that
i have not uh not looked at so i can't
i can't answer your question directly uh
other than it varies a lot
well i think you did you know we make
assumptions as grovers that
because we hear for example you know
with alfalfa or with kelp that it
contains auxins and gibralians and
cytokines that we're
when we apply it we're getting them but
essentially what you're saying is that
potentially these these pgrs are not as
stable and they may not be making it we
may not be getting that effect we may be
getting other
effects but not necessarily the
purported benefits of pgrs
is that fair to say uh that i think
that's very fair to say
okay well naturally occurring but here
the natural
occurring hormones in the plant tend to
break down fast that's one of the ways
that they regulate
the plant regulates what's going on um
and so when you and then when you get
into
you know a system where you're applying
them
natural products you've got that same
issue a little bit
what is the processing gun uh you know
things like the auxins that they break
down at high temperatures uh
you know the processing uh
you know may break it down and so it may
not be very high levels in the final
product
well thank you so much for your time
today i really appreciate it i
i learned quite a bit of stuff about
pgrs that i wasn't aware of and
yeah i really thank you for for sharing
this sure i'm glad to do it glad you do
it hopefully it's been helpful for
everyone
oh absolutely yeah um well again i'd
like to mention
jim you are fully retired uh you're not
currently doing any consulting
uh so for folks that listen to this uh
please don't attempt to contact jim um
he's enjoying his retirement and uh i'll
let him talk to my granddaughter
there we go there we go well we'll have
a wonderful rest of your day
and uh thanks again all right thanks dan
all right take care
bye
[Music]
that was jim barrett and you were
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast
don't forget to check out the podcast
page at w www.kisorganics.com
just click on the learn tab then podcast
and if you haven't already please take a
moment to leave us a comment or review
on whatever platform you listen on
i do take the time to read them all and
appreciate the feedback
you can also follow us on instagram at
kis
organics to stay up to date on the
latest podcast releases and information
thanks for listening
you