[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge if
you're enjoying these podcasts please
take a moment to subscribe to our
newsletter on our homepage to stay up to
date on the latest podcasts product
announcements and videos now this week's
podcast was a fun one some of my
podcasts can get more technical or
science focus however for this podcast I
wanted to talk directly with a grower to
get some hands-on experience and
knowledge from someone in the industry I
had the honor of sitting down with my
good friend Nate Gibbs owner of goldleaf
Gardens a tier 2 producer here in
Washington State gold leaf is an
excellent proof of concept for living
soils and this style of cultivation on a
commercial scale they are known for
having some of the top shelf flour in
the state this podcast was my first
attempt at a video podcast and we shot
it in Origins coffee shop which is right
next door to origins cannabis shop a
recreational store here in Washington
State that is taking a unique approach
to selling cannabis by focusing on the
customer experience and selecting the
right product based on the CBD to THC
levels let me start by saying I'm not a
tech guy my last podcast the volume
levels were off and I'm constantly
making improvements to the recording
process I'm hoping that this can be a
learning experience too but I apologize
in advance for the echo as the empty
coffee shop added an echo to this
particular podcast and while I haven't
been able to get the audio and video to
sync properly I was able to make a short
YouTube video with photos and video from
goldleaf Gardens that is available on
the kiss organics YouTube channel or on
the podcast page for your viewing and if
you're local to Redmond Washington you
can swing down the origins and Redman on
4/20 this year to meet the gold leaf
crew live and see the new coffee shop in
cannabis store as they will be having a
luau
from 4:00 to 7:00 p.m. and you can check
it out for yourself and if you want to
see more of what gold leaf is doing you
can check out their website at WWF
Gardens calm or on Instagram at at gold
leaf gardens 4:20 and if you want to see
the inside of origins go to WWE gens
cannabis calm and on the bottom of the
homepage they have a video tour of the
inside it's pretty cool anyway let's get
on to the show alright I'm here today
with Nate Gibbs doing our very first
live video podcast here in Origins
they're opening a new coffee shop right
behind us that's not open yet but will
be opening soon and there is a
recreational cannabis shop next door
it's really cool it's it's a new way of
sharing and showing cannabis and I'll
take you guys over there with the camera
afterwards at the end of the show if
you're watching on the YouTube channel
now Nate here is a tier to cannabis
cultivator here in Washington State he
grows organically and is someone that I
met quite a while ago but what Nate's
what they're known for is with gold leaf
gardens is having the highest quality
top-shelf cannabis here in the state and
we have some samples here which I'll
zoom in a little bit of some of the
products that they produce yeah but Nate
can you talk a little bit about your
history and tell us a little bit about
how you got into growing cannabis
originally um yeah I have to think about
that the you know it's it's you know
we're grateful for for where it's come
to now you know just to being in a place
like this you know out here public with
it you know amazing beautiful stores you
know or our products displayed on the
shelves and you know on TV screens and
and you know just to have the sort of
environment to be able to showcase you
know the work that we're doing at gold
leaf gardens and polarised racks and
lyric ana gars
it's just it's a long long unimaginable
way away from from you know the the
dingy five foot high basements that we
were starting off in
you know a decade ago but you know here
we are so now let's talk about when we
met so when I met you it was working in
collaboration on a potential project
that a friend of ours was looking to set
up and you at the time had a hundred
light facility yeah on the medical side
that you were running and so can you
talk a little bit about that process
yeah you know I mean you skip over a lot
of details but you know kind of starting
from just the early grassroots
cooperative patient to patient care
provider model here in Washington State
you know one person growing for a couple
of patients in their basement we you
know sort of moved from there into you
know opening her own dispensary where we
worked with the collective of growers
and then a larger collective of patients
eventually that we outgrew our home grow
operations and moved into our first
warehouse which like you said is I
bought a hundred light warehouse and
that was a that was a big step you know
at the time you know Washington state
laws were still a little bit ambiguous
we were taking a you know sort of
progressive interpretation of the laws
and and you know that point you know
nobody knew you know day in day out if
you were gonna get shut down and
everything seized or if you were
positioning yourself to become part of
this burgeoning you know
legal markets that was a that was
beginning to to become you know
legalized so so I think we met at that
time we were we were looking at how we
were going to transition from this the
medical days the medical model into the
recreational model and and everybody was
ambitious and the future was you know
very optimistic and and there's a lot of
big money going around to finance very
large ambitious projects so we were I
think we were
something that you know was ten times as
big as we have land anyway yeah but um
yeah the best thing that happened from
that was really meeting you we were
beginning to come into our own as
organic growers you know sort of
following that path from just you know
figuring it out on our own to you know
starting to realize that was the
direction that produced the best
products and was most in line with our
values but we didn't really know what
we're doing can we can we talk a little
bit about that so all right so tell me a
little bit more about how you learned
how to grow at a time you know back then
there was a lot of information available
what was your what was your source of
information what did you know well there
was not a lot of information and there's
a lot of misinformation you know you
know the time we were you know nervous
about even logging on to computers a
search for for info I mean it all felt
that illicit so we would go I remember
I'd go to the they use bookstores and
get these old tattered copies of you
know and Rosenthal book how to grow
cannabis and we you know there's a small
network of people that you know we would
we would share ideas about what worked
or what didn't and and then there was
you know that the local hydroponics
store which was sort of this you know
hub of where growers would go and and
you know cross-pollinate ideas and you
know yeah ironically you couldn't tell
anybody what you were growing but
everybody knew and you sort of had this
little dance you had to play but um I
mean I remember I would I was so you
know I would I tried everything you know
I would literally if there was a new
product on the Shelf that offered to
boost my yields or boost my my flavors
or fix my mites or anything I mean we I
think I tried everything and that was
about the time I
I ran to keep it simple which was the
exact opposite philosophy I had I was
keeping it complicated but well it's
funny because we had completely
different upbringings you
and ways that we ended up around
cannabis so for me I had no experience
with the plant I grew up with my parents
owning a nursery and landscaping
business so I was around plants you know
my entire life but never cannabis so for
me I'd never been to a hydro shop the
first time I walked into hydro shop I
was like what are all these products and
it was it was really intimidating for me
I had never seen you know fertilizer was
like a bag with a label there were no
three yeah and three numbers there was
no like hot chick in a bikini like these
fake monster plants and I've never seen
the word bud so much in my life yeah but
I I was my dad's and my mom sold their
nursery and leased the land out to the
company they sold it to and when they
did that my dad decide you want to start
a compost tea business so this was like
way back in like 1999 when that whole
industry was just starting out with dr.
Ingham and so he had this compost tea
business that was going and we I was I
came back from Australia and started
helping him out and he'd get these phone
calls from guys to be like yeah I got
you know 20 tomato plants in my basement
and it took me a little it took me a
little while you know I was like how
these guys really like their pasta sauce
or I figured out what they were actually
growing and I started googling compost
tea and found some forums online
but even with the forums you know you're
right there was a lot of misinformation
I mean there still is but on top of that
it did feel a little illicit it was a
little scary you know what yeah what
direction the industry was heading and
then like you said we met and at that
time I'd been working and learning about
soils and just getting into cannabis
myself and started working with giant
Palmer you know you know in regards to
testing out different soil recipes and
seeing how we could grow the plant more
organically and without all of these
other products and so Jaya was really
instrumental in that
and it was it was quite a journey you
know it was a lot of fun getting to
learn about an entirely new plant and
learning how to grow indoors it's
totally different than growing outdoors
and and and the higher value of the crop
sort of allows you to to really
experiment with inputs that I you know
just don't make sense if you're if
you're actually growing tomatoes or
you're growing you know cabbage or
something and so I think it kind of
opens up the whole of the realm of like
you know well if we can absorb these
these input cause you know we know how
to really maximize this plan you know a
ten percent yield in a cannabis harvest
you know could be thousands and
thousands of dollars right and so so
you're think that's part of what drives
that the cannabis nutrient market of you
know trying to always sell you more and
more some of which works and yeah what's
does it yeah at all when we originally
were working on the soils that I thought
was really interesting was the goal
initially was not a commercial
application it was to create a product
where a cancer patient or a medical
patient could walk into a hydro shop and
rather than getting hit with all of
these you know bottles and nutrient
lines and this craziness they could just
take a bag of soil and walk out the door
and just water their plant and then Jaya
was able to start figuring out some of
these commercial applications on scale
which is sort of when we met you and you
were doing some of our first trials too
with the product and I know there was a
learning curve there and like some you
know it didn't work quite as well as you
wanted initially yeah but well I mean we
were skeptical just because you know it
was such a different thought process
than what we had been sort of accustomed
to in terms of buying a lot of bottles
of you know off the shelf we had a
I think you you know you remember we had
a really complicated recipe yeah you had
this this piece of paper I remember yeah
five milliliters of this and three
milliliters at this on the fourth day
and then on the eighth day algorithm you
know it was insane it was the craziest
nutrient I've ever seen and your plants
look great like yeah you know you guys
were really good growers and I think
that's an important aspect of it well I
think you know what was happening
because it was you know we were
successful I mean at the time you know
and you know you couldn't tell me that I
wasn't growing the best cannabis then
which I wasn't but yeah the you know we
had so many things going I mean I would
talk to all these people and they say
old it you know the secret ingredient is
you know roots accelerator the secret
ingredient is this by booster this and
that so I would you know my logic was
well if I take everybody secret
ingredients and it's just gonna have to
be awesome right yeah and and but it's
you end up coming out with like you know
pretty good results but because we
weren't very scientific about it we
couldn't tell you what it was that was
leading to that right and what was just
more things we're buying I know I was
spending a lot of money yeah I had a
very complicated recipe well there's a
lot of redundancy and as you taught me
there's a lot of bottles of things I was
greatly overpaying for because you know
it might have been them
now then I look back it's you know guano
suspended in water but it's you know $50
a bottle instead of you know the dry
inputs you buy four dollars of dollars I
think five of the bottles you had had
the same seaweed product and it right
yeah yeah for sure so let's talk a
little bit about that transition so you
did some trials with living soils and
then decided to commit your new facility
to that method of growing with the goal
of reusing the soil you know cycle after
cycle with minimal amending amending
can you talk a little bit about what
your facility looks like now and how you
set it up yeah well I remember when I
was you know kind of modeling out the
the new facility which was you know more
than twice as large you know just taking
our nutrient costs and putting on paper
taking the way we were doing things you
know and it'd be very expensive and I
was starting to have to think about you
know the scalability of our processes
and and it was really opportune you know
when I met you and Jaya and and you said
you know here's this you know here's
this way of growing plants which is
going to require you know which is gonna
let the plants dictate what they need
and instead of as much you know you know
as much of the growers you know
manipulation of the of the you know
nutrient systems and and then that would
allow us to you know tend to thousands
of plants right because you know we're
you know in a short period of time in a
few years we went from you know a few
dozen in our basement to you know we
have four or five thousand in our garden
anytime so you know you can't do the
same things you can't give each plant
that seemed to have retention so so I
think that's that was you know you know
we're the light bulbs started to go off
but also as we were going through these
trials with sort of that as the end goal
you know we realize we're growing some
of the best product better than we had
been
you know and your yield wasn't
necessarily any larger at that time was
it you know I don't think it was you
know significantly larger but it wasn't
it wasn't worse no calm I would say the
quality was was better and also to you
know we just found the overall health of
our gardens began to kind of just tack
in a different direction part of you
know being very hands-on with the
nutrient regimen also meant we're really
hands-on with our sort of our IPM
program you know we're using a lot of
we're spraying a lot of things and
treating the soils and treating things
above the ground and running to a lot of
problems you know we'd have a you know
have a lot of issues and and once we
sort of you know really let the you know
built a good living soil environment the
plants became happier and I think their
natural immunities began to be come
fully actualized and we just found
ourselves fighting a lot less problems
so I get a lot of emails about blog post
I put up with actually a photo from your
facility Rhian reusing soil so you use
you've got you got a bunch of plastic
pallets in like blue plastic pallets
which is great because they're a lot
easier to clean and you know they're not
gonna harbor disease like a wood pallet
wood and then you had a custom-built
fabric pot I believe made specifically
for the pallets with the ID and then
they're on racks so they're raised up so
you're not bending over the whole time
you talked a little bit about like what
gives you how many rooms how you haven't
set up yeah so you know we have so our
soil beds you know which might be kind
of a modified version of you know what
you know you and I have kind of designed
there they sit on food grade pallets and
then on top of that we had a geo pot
design us a fabric bed that fits exactly
on that pallet you know part of a great
thing about pallets for anybody
designing a large facility is there you
know a lot of material handling options
you know warehouses house pallets
racking forklifts everything sort of
knows how to their affordable you're not
irrigating the way
you're not repaying the wheel exactly so
we kind of use that as our standard um
you know unit and from there we have a
soil bed with with with you know kiss
soil that we reimagine we'd ever throw
it out and and in each bed we'll plant
six plants and then they'll have sort of
a independent trellis system per bed so
we'll we'll use you know sort of a scrog
type of training too for those same six
plants that share that bed and that
trellis so you're you that's just for
your flower room so your vegging in a
separate room in smaller containers yes
and then transplanting into the beds for
their final yeah so so we have one room
that's you know one 400 square foot room
that's dedicated to all of our
propagation they'll spend a couple weeks
in there in smaller plastic pots and
then they'll move into one of our seven
production rooms each room has 50 beds
and we'll plant six plants per bed and
then from you know so well 300 plants
and then um and then they'll live the
rest of their life cycle in that room
for about we'll give it about a week of
transition time in that room just
because they're going under something
more intense lighting we found that
that's a good amount of time and also
when we harvest we try to turn that room
over and get plants in there within a
day okay so for for reusing soil you
know we had to really figure out how we
can thread the needle harvest our plants
get our inputs back into the soil
transplant in there within 24 hours
I remember when limited to yes remember
when you were first doing that yeah we
were to play around out a lot you know
we were trying to put all the nutrients
back in right the beginning of the cycle
and it was just causing this oil to heat
up from the amount of microbial activity
was going on so what you guys sort of
figured out was okay we can put some
nutrients back in then and some organic
matter but then we'll also talk dress
nutrients yeah throughout the cycle and
to to allow that to allow you to get
that immediate 24 hour return when you
could start planting back in yeah it's
really you know you know if you have
that downtime to let that
those nutrients you know heat up and
cook in there you know you lose that
production time so you know and and if
we sort of loaded up the soil all the
way and transplanted we notice there's a
lot of transplant stress so we found you
know we we re amend a little lighter and
then we'll use top dressings of water in
a few things and you know put some
things into the compost tea as we brew
them so that they can be integrated into
the plants life cycle through so you're
not just doing water you're doing other
things but do other things yeah a lot of
compost tea some some foliar
applications you know micronutrients and
and some you know like some top dressing
as well and you're always experimenting
with new things that's one of the things
that I really like to encourage with
growers and one thing that you and I you
always tell me to is you're always
trying out new things and seeing how
they do with a control and I think
that's the important aspect of it yeah
you can actually see is this one change
making an improvement or is it making
things worse is it worth the amount of
time and money I'm gonna spend on it and
that and you know one nice things about
you know growing at scale with a lot
more plants a lot more beds everything
being uniform the rooms all being
uniform is that it allows you to
dedicate you know small amount of you
know your canopy to these experiments
without really impacting your overall
production as much you know if you're
you know when we only had you know when
I was only growing 15 plants if I wanted
to try something 2 to 5 plants you know
enough for a decent sample size and it
didn't work out you know it really
impacts you now if we wanted to try and
experiment to one or two beds you know
they maybe don't get quite the returns
or the the results we wanted you know
we're still able to absorb that so you
know it's hopefully leading to
improvement year over year I think yeah
so one of the challenges with the style
of growing they're doing with reusing
the soil is the fact that you're not
able to fully you know sterilize the
soil or clean the media
so insects and diseases are I think
you're at higher risk for some of these
things and that's one of the criticisms
that I hear from traditional agriculture
and horticulture with this style of
growing can you talk a little bit about
some of the ways that you guys deal with
that and what you've you know some your
experiences um actually I want to ask
you a question about that but the you
know so I mean don't you know an outdoor
farm you know in a greenhouse per se
unless they're in containers you know
they're also not you know removing the
entire field right I mean this seems to
be something in respects to a you know a
container type of system indoors you
know I guess you know overwintering
outside we don't have that going on
indoors so yes there is definitely that
issue but yeah that is a challenge you
know I think that we don't have the we
don't wipe the slate clean in between
rounds where everything's removed and
sterilized and started over that being
said you do keep your facility very
clean
yeahbsolutely yeah you're you know
disinfecting the room just not the soil
and the beds themselves right and I
think that's important it's not it's not
messy when you go into gold leaf you
know yeah I mean as much as you know
being able to have soil you know it's
not like a laboratory level hydroponics
facility like some of them I I've been
into we still have we're still trying to
promote a very in our environment that
or you know life is proliferated and and
you know encouraged you know on the soil
level you know robust you know microbial
environments you know around the leaf
surfaces as well so you know sterile is
definitely not our end goal at any point
but but cleanliness is important
absolutely
but with with you know with you know
perpetually you were using your soil it
does force you to
you know really think about your
environment the sustainability of it
over time and your modes of your modes
of pest management you know you can't
you know you can't apply any type of
product that's also going to damage the
the beneficial
you know microbes and insects in your
environment so you know we use a lot of
beneficial insects for example and you
know a horticultural spray that's meant
to knock knock out pathogenic insects is
also going to kill our good guys and so
we have to you know you know what I
think
you know we're ultimately working
towards is is just the the right balance
of you know biology and our rooms that
you know you're never going to eradicate
something all the way but you're gonna
you're gonna keep it under under control
yeah where there's a good economic
threshold and you know and when you kind
of have the right pieces in place you
find that you know the gardens would
sort of tend to themselves and do as
mother nature
you know intended well when you compare
it to outdoor so the thing about being
outdoors in a field is you can still get
you know this these pathogens where they
you know overpopulate they're always
around just like they are at an indoor
facility people that say there might
free or that I just I don't believe in I
think that's really really hard to
achieve and maintain but I think you are
able to maintain them at a low enough
level through a good IPM program to
where they are very manageable yeah and
having those beneficial insects there I
think is huge in protecting the plan and
having good microbiology in the soil you
know on the leaf surface and the thing
about outdoors that's so nice is you
have that diversity of predators that
already are naturalized to that
environment and indoors you just don't
have that so I think the ability for
these pests are really proliferate
across a mono crop in an indoor
environment is a lot greater and when we
talk about greenhouses or like
horticultural operations I've gotten to
see more
one of those over the years they are
running you know they may have a
thousand different you know a different
varieties of plants and things that all
have different insects and pest problems
so they feel like the only solution is
to spray some pretty heavy pesticides
and sterilize everything but well yeah
with the bin you know with like for
example our beneficial insects and we
found you know I think everybody's still
trying to learn how to you know these
world's converging cannabis is so you so
new but you know we found that some
things that work on you know other crops
for that same pests aren't really taking
hold you know developing breeding
populations and things in our rooms and
so it becomes sort of economically
unviable they keep using them yeah I
found other things that just sort of
take root and get established and just
become part of the you know the
environment and you know so that's
that's just been a lot of
experimentation you know yeah do you
have a favorite a favorite insect or
whatever you like to add your room do
you want to share with listeners you
know I mean I the Rove beetles right you
know they're they're a little expensive
on the front end but we you know III
don't remember the last time we
reintroduced him but if you scoop up a
handful of our soil or I mean they even
crawl they crawl everywhere you find
them you know all over your facility
well you have them in the in the holy
compost too already covered lowly
cobbles okay yeah so you know that those
you know they seem like apex predators
as far as you know you know bugs go on
so you know I think you know definitely
if you don't have those established in
your organic soil facility you know
those those are those are they're good
one good partners that have in there but
but yeah and and just being very
prophylactic and proactive right I think
kind of wheeling it back to those early
days it was get a problem look for a
solution try it doesn't work go to a
bigger gun until your present the
nuclear option and and now you know you
have to be extremely cognizant about not
letting a problem you know flare up so
you're constantly screening your rooms
or looking constantly screening your
rooms and you know one of the hardest
disciplines I think is to for example
spend money on an IPM for problems you
don't have right and yet it's you know
when you go back and study all of you
know you know your notes you realize you
spent much more once you have a problem
and you have to fight it that's a really
good point
yeah so and then you you don't even
think twice about Spain the money you
have to do it it's crop loss or it's
been you know hundreds or thousands of
dollars on a solution so you know when
things are going well you know it seems
a little hard to say oh I really have to
you know be disciplined in order my you
know hundreds of dollars of beneficial
insects and keep introducing them in the
room but then you realize we haven't had
a problem in six months or three months
and and and so you know I need to keep
up with that you know and I think that
once you're able to get from a you know
sort of a knockdown or combative you
know yeah cycle into more of a
maintenance cycle that's when you know
it gets actually does get much easier
and you know so less stressful that's
stressful yes you got you got to keep
you got to keep investing in that part
of your gardens if you're if you're
getting especially are going to be you
know uh or reusing soil yeah you know
keeping some other plants that are you
never never clearing out your mother
room so you're always gonna have you
know some some plant there so so there's
there's so many aspects to cultivation
besides just growing the plants one of
the things that you and I have talked
about more recently is the whole idea
around lean farming oh yeah and I know
you have a lot of experience with lean
manufacturing and then I was like read
this book Hartman yeah and you've sort
of embraced that and your facility
little bit key talk a little bit about
that experience well yeah I wouldn't I
don't know if I would you might be
giving me too much credit
i I've always been you know interested
in the subject and is just always
thinking about you know writing it
random production business you know
looking for for the right strategies you
know I I've always you know been very
interested in how how to sort of take
that these methods that work you know
I've given you know like Toyota there's
great advantage over its rivals and yeah
and apply that but I always had a hard
time connecting the dots you know it
always kind of stopped ideas made sense
on paper and so when you gave me that
book by Ben art man there it is you know
somebody somebody smarter than me
finally connected the dots at Evan you
know so we've been going through a
process at our place of removing waste
you know and then just really analyzing
doing a lot of deep reflection on on
every step every touch is it necessary
does it add value or does it not and
it's amazing once you sort of take
inventory of that you know how many
things you do in a day that aren't
adding value to you know to your
customer so why are you doing it you
know and so it's it's a transfer
transformation process that I think is
going to be going on for a long time but
I you know I think it's it's really the
right direction
especially as this industry becomes
highly competitive you know now you know
the the prices of cannabis here in
Washington State and you know from what
we've seen in other states you know are
falling I'm getting much closer to you
know representing their manufacturing
costs not you know this sort of artifact
of what they used to cost in the medical
market or on the street before yeah
you know I mean we grow some of the you
know
highest in cannabis in this market but
you know an eighth of our flower doesn't
cost much more than what I was paying
for you know in college 20 years ago oh
my god is at work you know so you have
to be efficient and there's
only a fat literally clear you're not
taking that money home it's the
government without the customers paying
the same thing we were 20 years ago you
know yeah we get a bit of that so yeah
you know it's you know it really you
know I think if you're not running a
lien operation a very smart operation
then it's hard to make money right now
and I think I think you know that's just
the reality and yeah it is a slow
process I've been doing it at my my farm
you know getting an employees to work on
paying attention to what they're seeing
around you know how we can keep the
property cleaner and how we can improve
the our processes because a lot of what
we do is just so time-consuming and I
know we I know we can do a better job
and I know we haven't even thought of
all the ways we can do a better job so
it's one of those things it's not it's
not so much an end goal as it is just a
journey right and I'm really I'm really
enjoying it it's definitely changed the
way we run our farm and my and our
business and I'm glad that it's you know
I thinking about its Kaizen it's that
that improvement you know that 1%
improvement you know it's not you're
never gonna get there they're just gonna
try to constantly you know carve away at
what doesn't need to be there and
towards this this purity of you know
pure value ray which is more of a you
know something to aspire to them
probably something you've ever actually
achieved but you know in that pursuit
you end up becoming you know becoming
better at what you do and oh yeah you
know and and you know one of the one of
the traps I think we've seen like in you
know probably all farming and it's
starting to apply to cannabis is that
you know one direction people take it is
to just grow larger and larger yeah and
yet you'll see large-scale operations
that have taken on a ton of debt to get
there not necessarily being more
profitable right
and that seems that seems interesting
right where's that economy of scale but
I think you know these type of lean
methods can be applied to a very small
operation or a large operation yeah but
either way you need to you know you need
to be very disciplined about how you're
running know for sure and I know for me
I've been a lot happier since we've
started implementing this stuff because
the mental cost of all of this waste was
just weigh me down like walking around
and seeing project after project that
need to be completed or just mess after
mess that we left behind it's like it
was exhausting yeah so just getting the
stuff off the property it was so nice
and it's still it's a constant battle
yeah it's been great so changing
directions we've been talking about
cultivation so far but as you well know
that's just one one aspect of cannabis
cultivation I mean there's you could be
the best grower in the world right now
here in Washington State and still be
failing just because there's so much
more to creating a brand and a market
share and interest in your product and
keep I want to talk a little bit about
your sort of your company philosophy and
the morals that you guys stand for but
before we do can we talk a little bit
about branding and marketing aspect of
things right um yeah you know I mean
it's you know the if everything is
important now and you know it's all tied
together to those two things are really
close for you what you guys are doing
yeah absolutely you know I mean I think
we were a little bit ahead of the curve
in just realizing that you know cannabis
is gonna kind of turn from this sort of
you know anonymous you know anonymous
commodity to you know something that was
going to you know look a lot more like
like products you see on the shelves and
other industries so you know kind of
early on we stuck our neck out and came
up with the name gold leaf and started
branding our product and at the time and
say the Medical dispensaries you know
you usually go in it was kind of like a
like purchasing bulk supplies you know
and you know at an old general store and
you have these jars and here's some some
strains you
necessary know who grew them or anything
like that yeah and so we came out kind
of with a jar with our logo on it and it
said you know this is gold leaf weed you
know you know for better or worse this
is this is where it's coming from
yeah I know and so we we kind of rode
that into you know into the the market
and now of course that's how all
products are sold but it's it's really
important you know I think because now
in Washington for example you know all
the products need to be sealed and kept
behind a you know behind a glass counter
or behind the bar so for the customers
you need to really develop a trust with
them and and so you know having strong
you know branding and marketing to kind
of reinforce that those company values
is is essential and you can be
incredible grower you can have the most
coveted strains and it can just fall
flat for you because you don't have that
piece in place which yeah I know a lot
of growers in Washington right now our
producer processors as they're called
here are struggling to get into new
stores and get their product sold where
as I know you guys can't even keep up
right now with the number of stores and
people that want you and want to carry
your product and a lot of that is due to
customer demand people have come this
you know signify certain traits with the
brand gold leaf and I think you know I
won't touch on that some more but I
think such a big part of that is you're
the culture you've created there you
know and the community that you guys
have and can you talk a little bit about
sort of so I know I have a little
background here it's kind of unfair but
I know you guys are for the started off
like a bunch of Hawaiian guys yeah
coming out of what Kauai I think you
said yeah you know I mean I'm for most
of our you know all of our growers are
from kawaii and okay yeah we you know we
have a we have a it's you know we kind
of identify as a Hawaiian operation you
know obviously we have you know we have
all sorts of folks there but there's a
you know we embrace that spirit of Aloha
you know regardless of where you're born
from or you know what
it is it's it's that's our value at the
end of the day and you know you know
what what what that what does that mean
you know the word has a lot of different
meanings but it means love you know and
and so just from the love of the plant
to you know the love of you know each
other the family you work with and in
your community and you know growing up
in a you know unique place like Hawaii
you had a real tight communities yeah
there was a social responsibility and
that sort of you know manage how
everybody interacted with each other and
you know it just seems to you know it's
just how we live our life and organic
growing kind of falls in line with that
as well and so you know that's that's
sort of how we run our think our company
internally and it it is struck a chord
with with people up here you know yeah
it sounds really you know it sounds
cliche but you know there's people want
to know the story behind the brand and
you know the yeah I think it's important
yeah it is and it's not you know it did
I think there's substance to that you
know I mean people you know you you have
this dollar in your wallet to spend and
you can choose how you want to spend it
you know there's some folks with hate
give me the most potent weed for the
cheapest amount of money I can spend and
we've you know there's nothing wrong
with that but that's not the customer
that seems to you know be supporting our
business and you know there's other ones
who say you know it's a good product but
also to I just love the way that you
know you you guys you know run your
business you know are good responsible
members of the community you give back
you you grow things responsibly when you
you know there's no rule says you have
to but you know we know we trust we
trust your cultivation practices we know
you take care of your your employees and
and so you know at the end of the day I
mean that that adds up to to those
those sales you know she's important so
yeah and your guys are passionate about
what they're doing I mean well you know
so my growers you know and I got to give
them credit because you know it it all
starts with them I mean without them
then the rest of the business is you
know there's no foundation and and
they're almost all you know brothers and
cousins they grew up on this really you
know on a farm in a really small town
called Koloa an island of quite and you
know they grew up growing vegetables you
know sustenance farming they would sell
there you know they go with their folks
down at the farmers market and sell what
they didn't need and then you know
that's that's where they came from where
they were really relying on their land
you know to provide for their families
and so you know now you know they've
kind of you know migrated up here and
you know the fact they're sort of able
to do that but in this in this different
market I think is something they're very
proud of and and it's and it you know
shows in the product you know with but
they take a certain pride in the gardens
and I know this is a cultivation science
podcast but you know there's just
there's this one thing I haven't been
able to to sort of like quantify
scientifically and it's it's you know
just this love and this passion forfor
being for your work and it just it it
shows up in the flavor and it just shows
up in the product at the end and so you
know I don't know how to replicate that
I just know we have something really
special and we're just trying to let the
world you know kind of see it and you
know decide if that's that's that's for
them you know yeah I mean one thing we
haven't mentioned either is that your
facility is fairly far south of Seattle
so a lot of the guys live in Seattle
even I think in North Seattle in some
cases yeah and are driving all the way
down to the facility which is you know
how many miles is that
well yeah it's in Olympia Washington and
you know it's about a 60 mile drive each
way and I we have most of our employees
and they make that drive both ways every
day
traffic they spent hours there getting
up and you know crazy hours oh yeah
definitely just for the opportunity to
work and be a part of this community
yeah and and you know everybody has a
shared shared you know sense that we're
building something special and yeah you
know you know to come from a small place
and be able to make your mark and you
know going to these stores and and you
know hear the stories that you know
there was there was people that were you
know genuinely had their their day or
their lives improved by you know by your
products I mean that's that's the kind
of thing that it makes that drive worth
it you know and so so yeah we're just
blessed and and you know wouldn't do
anything else so what are some of the
things that you do at gold leaf you know
for or with your employees that help
build that sense of community yeah we I
mean even even something as simple as
you know on Friday we you know we all
stop work a few hours early and barbecue
and it's just become this tradition you
know that I don't know how it started
just as long as I can remember we've you
know we break a little really on Friday
and we everybody has a potluck and and
yeah that's kind of a hawaiian thing you
just you know everything you know kind
of you know orbits around food and
community and and it's just yeah it's a
special time where we're able to you
know just reflect and and you know have
your team together and something that's
not work related but well yeah i mean
it's it you know it's the barbecue
everything you know it's it's such a
small thing but yet i think it just
helps everybody remember that like yeah
we're this you know it's this team we
have a we have a greater goal and you
know
or together so when I first started
running kiss we would have staff
meetings we're not all working at the
same time to where we can do these sorts
of barbecues and things but we're
working on more team-building events and
those opportunities to be together
outside of the you know outside of the
workplace and not talking about work
like my farm managers birthday was last
night and you know over half the staff
was there you know other people the
guests we're leaving in like the staff
was there hanging out because they enjoy
each other's company and like some of
the some of the people have taken trips
to Iceland together or live together or
have moved across the country and it's
like those moments at community I think
are so amazing and when I first started
looking staff meetings I was like oh my
gosh this is cut account I was
calculating out how much this is costing
me per hour that we're just sitting
there and you know people are asking
questions and I'm like 20 man hours yeah
yeah like this is a lot of money that we
could be spent doing other stuff but as
I matured as the leader or as a business
owner I realized just how important this
aspect was that people feel like they're
being heard that people have time
together that's not spent being you know
stressed or working and that everyone
gets along and likes each other is so
important and work environments can go a
lot of different ways oh yeah I mean I
know there's a lot of places where it's
like I don't want to see you till Monday
morning I can't get out of there fast
enough um yeah but uh but yeah you
nailed it Ted I mean it's it's um I
think it comes down to a sense of
purpose right and and like you know you
have not every job at gold leaf is you
know is as glamorous as the others but I
think that it's it's important to you
know you know sort of develop that and
everybody that says you know it's like
there there's this you know quote for
the stonemasons and it says you know we
cut humble stone must not forget we're
building cathedrals yeah it's like you
know even if you're just trimming and I
totally butcher that quote by the way
but you know the whether you're trimming
or you're packaging or you're delivery
and you know everybody realized
is that this is all part of that you
know that that customer experience and I
think you know there's so much to be
learned from from every person who works
there right like you and I will you know
wear a lot of hats or running our
businesses you know we're not always
down in the trenches you know at least
for myself I should say you know I can't
you know not always you know there's
there's weeks I'm not even in the
gardens as much anymore because I'm have
other things to attend to and and you
know fine you know the person with you
know maybe one of the most homeless job
you know at our at our farm will have
insights into that part of the process
that I wouldn't be able to come up with
you know and allowing them empowering
them to say hey you know okay why don't
you make this approvement this is about
me telling you how to do a job it's you
know it's me find the right people who
want to improve this company in any way
they can
yeah and and so giving them some some
Liberty which he knows takes a certain
amount of trust and but you find I think
you find overall that when people do
that you know that gives them a sense of
purpose say wow I've improved this
product I've helped my company everybody
benefited from it I think that that's
sort of really easy yeah you had told me
another time we're talking about one of
your trimmers you kind of told me a
story around that you want to share that
with the listeners was that which one
was Adam yeah he's probably probably has
to do with you know
sano and you know he's our longtime
trimmer but yeah yeah and you had
offered him other positions in the
company yeah but well yeah I mean I've
had a you know an awesome kid he's been
trimming for me for just you know years
and years and you know I you know he's
definitely earned the right to you know
move in to like you know different jobs
but he just kind of has this this old
soul in this biz oh this you know desire
this this how should I say this affinity
for it kind of you know there's one good
craftsmanship you know and this one
little thing he does he takes his one
job of trimming which you know if you
you know trimming for the cannabis
industry is you know some people think
it's like dishwashing in the restaurant
industry like it's where you got to
start and yet you know he takes so much
pride in
trimming a perfect flower and I think
you know what he's told me is that you
know I mean these growers they put in so
much time and energy from from taking a
clone and all the way through it's it's
growing life and you know the harvesting
and that the curing and you know it's
his job to to give it that final
manicure that the you know that's you
know your customers are gonna see and he
that pride he hasn't that one simple
task really embodies oh you know just
how you know how we try to view
everything we do so it's great and you
know he he might be a trimmer for ever
and you know it's it's but he enjoys
what he does
you know he's absolutely absolutely you
know you he has purpose in his work and
and he's quite talented that he's good
at what he's doing absolutely any one
simple task and I put in well do it now
I said you know I'm gonna continue to
promote you but you could still be a
trimmer right because he's earned that I
want to take care of folks but if his
you know calling is to do that one final
detail
it's like detailing a car before you put
it on the lot you know it might not
sound as cool as the guy engineering the
car but you know at the end of the day
that customer is gonna want to see a
nice shiny car and that might be what
makes him purchase it yeah and he
understands that and I think that's sort
of that's that's definitely a you know
example for how we try to do everything
there so let's talk a little bit about
what where we are yeah and sort of a
little bit about the coffee and some of
your products and how you guys brand
your your stuff for listeners yeah I
mean the where do I start so yeah we're
here you know origins coffee shop it's
adjacent origins recreational cannabis
shop in Redmond Washington we've worked
at them for a long time and we love that
they sort of are thinking outside the
box with how people are interacting with
cannabis as a whole and with the brands
in general you know and it's a
it takes a little bit of creative
thinking to be you know to making this
market so so you guys partnered on this
this coffee mm-hmm and can you talk a
little bit about where we're starting
you know at the actual origin of the
coffee itself yeah why you're why you're
doing it yeah I mean you know it's the
two things we consume the most of his
coffee as well get in businesses both
but uh you know I was I've been thinking
for a long time I mean I drink a lot of
coffee and there's a lot of restrictions
on how I can you know really market and
advertise my cannabis brand you know
just sort of what's sort of socially
responsible and and you know it's it's
an adult product and even the state set
some limitations on how how where we can
advertise obviously I'm thinking about
our brand you know eventually moving
into you know possibly other states you
know internationally one day so how do I
begin to export that you know if I can
ship my my products across state lines
you know yeah and so the coffee just
seemed to be something that sort of
embodied a lot of you know similar
similar values so we partnered with a
roastery on the Big Island and there
they work with a cooperative of Kona
coffee farmers other coffee farmers in
Hawaii you know small farms small family
farms organic same values we have and so
hopefully now you know if you get by or
you know get a bag of cold gold leaf
coffee and it's excellent too and you
know we made sure that we made sure hey
if we're gonna put the name on it's got
to be really good you know and and so
hopefully you know you maybe you try the
coffee and you say wow know what's
behind this brand in psychology if they
also grow they also grow herb and maybe
I'll check that out so just a different
way of thinking about the brand as a
whole you know eventually perhaps it
expands beyond just cannabis it's more
of a lifestyle and
culture yeah and then you guys are known
for your flower yeah that's really
what's you sort of staked your mark on
but you also produce other products as
well yes so beyond the flower you're
also he talked a little bit about the
lyric ana gars and some of the other
products you've created sort of
diversify in this market yeah so we you
know we you know we start off pretty
much strictly selling flower we
partnered eventually with the
concentrate maker polar ice tracks and
we do solvent free concentrate so hash
rosin and that's been really great you
know we've been winning some awards for
that it's just a very pure process that
involves no chemistry and so we figure
why are you gonna grow your your your
flowers organically and then you know
process it with with you know
hydrocarbons you know other solvents so
it's a it's a solvent free you know
constant concentrate processing and then
we put them all together into the canner
gars and so this is actually one of the
smaller ones we call this the cannery
low but it is a ABC of cannabis cigar
and it's it's our flower then it's
wrapped in a layer of the concentrate
and then we take the fan leaves from the
plant so instead of a tobacco wrap it's
you know each leaf is meticulously you
know placed around that and cured and
dried the whole process takes months and
you end up with this you know kind of
work of art yeah they're beautiful yeah
yeah I'll uh I'll post some photos and
stuff for listeners on the podcast page
but then also I'll show some of the
videos that you've you shared with me
because one of the things that I just
want to mention while we're talking
about marketing branding that's so
important is marketing branding is not
just a t-shirt or a hat or a coffee bag
it's sort of a collection of all these
things to create an identity and a
culture around what you're doing it's so
important I think that people have an ID
of not just where these products come
from but how they're grown and you
really have to marketing and branding is
is a holistic thing and that's one thing
I'm learning you know it's not as easy
as just running out and buying a hundred
t-shirts yeah you have to create that
social media presence you have to create
that understanding of what you're doing
and that recognition so that so when
someone sees that t-shirt or that coffee
or that hat they can say hey that
signifies this you know quality
community you know Aloha
whatever whatever you're going for with
your product and I think that's
important yeah and that's something that
I know that origins has worked really
hard on too and so I will I will do a
video tour in there that we'll have on
YouTube as well that we can share with
people so they can see how some of the
more innovative reck shops are doing
things here in Washington yeah
absolutely
you know it's I think all I can say
about its authenticity right if you you
know have a strong sense of purpose in
what you're you know why you're doing
what you're doing you kind of build your
marketing around that it'll you know
it'll it'll work out well for you I
think if you're trying to put out a
message that doesn't truly represent who
you are then it's it's just gonna kind
of fall apart yeah and but yeah you know
you got it you got to approach it from
so many different angles and and you
know it's exciting times because there's
so many platforms now to get your
message out you don't have to throw a
ton of money at it like the hard dollars
like you did before you know taking out
magazine ads and billboards and and all
of these these cost you can be very
creative and you can use people to to
spread the message I think that
nothing's better than you know like a
first hand recommendation you know and
so those are those are things that you
then you try to cultivate as much as
possible yeah that's a really good point
about being authentic because we
nowadays were just bombarded with
messages all the time and marketing and
I think people even at a subconscious
level at the very least can tell when a
message is is fake or not authentic so
that's a really good point
was there anything else that you wanted
to touch on today I really appreciate
you taking the time to chat in no no
thank you I appreciate it you know and
you know thanks again I always
appreciate your your help with us sort
of coming into our own as organic
growers and you know we're you know I
think I definitely know we wouldn't be
who we are and how we are if it wasn't
first out of our you know opportunity to
run into you at that transition time so
so that's been great
no it's been good and I think it's
important to collaborate with people in
the industry and I know you and I are
always learning new things and when I
learned something new related to soil I
think matter it would matter for you I'm
calling you up and when you discover
something you know you're sharing with
me and I think that's how we all stay
competitive you know with absolutely you
know and I think I you know I can't
stress that enough I think there is um
you know there's there's there needs to
be more unity you know the cannabis
industry you guys as things get
competitive you know the the gloves come
off and it kinky
you know everybody's kind of fight for
their own but I don't think it has to be
like that you know you look at other
industries and like-minded brands and
come together and there's a lot there's
a lot to go around so yeah looking
forward to that the next chapters as
well
all right thanks dad appreciate it all
right thanks that was Nate Gibbs owner
of goldleaf Gardens a tier 2 producer
here in Washington state known for their
top-shelf flower and organic methods if
you're local to Seattle Nate will be
back at origins coffee shop in Redmond
Washington on 4/20 this year for a luau
with his crew from 4:00 to 7:00 p.m. so
stop on by and say hello
don't forget that there is some video
content to go along with this podcast on
the podcast page at WWE sorg annex comm
or on our youtube channel under K is
organics you are listening to the
cannabis cultivation and science podcast
I'm your host tad Hussey thanks for
listening
you