[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host tadd
hussey of kiss organics this is the
podcast where we discuss the cutting
edge of growing from a science-based
perspective and drawn top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge
my guest this week is stephen arthurs
stephen graduated from the imperial
college london with a master's of
science in plant protection and
integrated pest management he also
received a diploma in applied entomology
and went on to get a phd in insect
pathology he did his post doctoral work
at texas a m researching biological pest
control for thrips on ornamental plants
and investigated insect virus
interactions while conducting greenhouse
trials to evaluate new insecticides
from there he worked as a research
entomologist with the usda for five
years before becoming an assistant
professor in entomology at the
university of florida
he is currently a research associate
with texas a m university and also a
technical sales specialist with biobee
usa a leading provider of biologically
based integrated pest management
biobee is the world's leading producer
of persimilis the most effective natural
predator of spider mites
i'm very excited to announce that in
conjunction with this podcast release
kiss organics has partnered with biobee
to offer their wide array of beneficial
insects through our website and will be
shipping direct from insectary so as to
ensure optimal viability of insects upon
arrival
in today's podcast we discuss the many
pests we see in cannabis and what some
good management options are for
utilizing beneficial predatory insects
now on to the show
hi stephen thanks for coming on the show
today
hi good morning chad i'm happy to be
here
yeah i appreciate it so i asked suzanne
uh we've you know been working with
biobee now and i asked suzanne who to
talk to over at biobee and uh
she mentioned your name so uh can you
tell me a little bit about yourself um
and then we'll dive into the podcast
all right be happy to so yeah my name's
steven arthurs
and i'm with a company called biobee
originally based out of israel
and
we now have a subsidiary in the us by
the usa and
yeah i've been with them for
about three years now
and prior to biobee i was
actually working in research for for a
number of years most of my career
so it's been a bit of a career change
and
you know i was able to work with a lot
of
these beneficial organisms um
you know in the lab and in the field and
now i'm sort of
in the um
very much in the uh the operational side
of things seeing them actually used in
practice so it's been it's been an
interesting uh full circle
well i'm so excited to be able to start
offering uh biobee insects to our
customer base one of the things that
suzanne has drilled into my head is that
you know
insects can't develop resistance to
being eaten to other insects moving away
from pesticides or reducing the amount
of pesticides we have offers a lot of
benefits um
i i'm really excited to be able to you
know dive into this a little further
today i really wanted to get into uh
some of the main pests that we're seeing
in cannabis and what some of those uh
bio control options are
and uh you know kind of talk about how
they work and what they do and give
people a little more information there
so
uh you know why don't we start with um
you know just a a classic issue that i'm
sure everyone's had over the years which
is spider mites you know two spotted
spider mite how do we
how do we uh offer you know begin to
treat that from a um
bio control perspective
right right well
yeah spider mites are probably the most
common pests that you see we've seen in
indoor grows
and uh
they can become really bad i've seen
them
really um devastate the crop and once
they get bad they can be quite hard to
to get rid of and i've seen people
struggling with them
so
luckily um if you do things the right
way the spider mites are not actually
that hard to control
the the the key really is is to be
preventive and to
once your crop is clean it's relatively
easy to keep it clean um it's when you
have a large problem that needs clearing
up where things get a little bit more
difficult
but but in general the the
several species of beneficials
uh seem to be
relatively effective and reliable for
for spider mite control
and they're primarily the predatory
mites and so i've seen
a lot of uses of predatory mites
probably the most commonly used one
would be phytophys per similar
seems to do quite well on on cannabis
and hemp
but there's a few others as well that
also will feed on spider mites and
can be effective in their own rights
so you mentioned preventative and also
uh a challenge around if it gets really
bad so one of the things
you know a lot of this is me just
regurgitating things i've learned from
suzanne over the years is that if it
gets really bad and i'm picturing like
webbing
in the case of
spider mites um
we may want to consider a knock back
spray some sort of oil like you know
suffolk x or something and then follow
that up um after the the appropriate
interval with a bio control does that
sound like a good approach or like you
know persimilis in this case does that
sound like a good approach
yeah yeah typically once you start
getting webbing then
for now first of all can work on webbing
it can navigate the the spider mite webs
whereas other
most other beneficial uh insects and
mice
can't
so but but but because you need a large
number and because once you start
getting webbing the risk of damage
immediate damage is very high
um
most most people at that point would try
to bring the numbers down
through through the use of sprays
um so whether they be soaps or oils
would be the most common
common type and there's various types
that you can use
um so yeah that that would be most
common um
that can be can be a little bit
challenging because the the website can
actually protect the spider mites to a
certain extent from sprays as well
and so you really need to come in with a
pretty high volume and you need to come
in with um
a good coverage
and i have actually seen um some
operations uh coming vacuums and try to
suck
suck them up off the plants and it's
quite time consuming but they try to do
that as a way to get rid of those webs
and some of those
very high populations
um
and in some cases you know people will
rogue plants if they don't
necessarily need them and and they want
to just kind of
be very proactive they will get rid of
some plants but because of the value of
cannabis plants often that's not always
an option
but yes once you brought the numbers
down
um that would be the time to come in
with a buyer program
um
you releasing your predatory mics and
some of your predatory insects as well
sometimes those are used for spider
mites and then you really probably want
to come in with a high rate
um higher rate higher frequency at least
initially
uh and so your problems uh and under
control and then pay attention to your
new crop coming on because one of the
spider mites do get around through being
moved from workers and being moved from
pruning equipment and and um
you know so they can get around so you
really want to be extra vigilant once
you have a source
extra vigilant on your
surrounding
tables or even in your surrounding rooms
that your spider mites are
are not transferring and you really want
to get that population down to the point
where things are clean and then you can
go back to a more um
economical
rate of application
yeah and in an ideal world we're
scouting and catching these things early
so they don't get to that stage and
realistically when it comes to
application rates
a maintenance application or preventive
application rate would be significantly
lower than
um
i guess a treatment
application
would that be correct
yeah yeah i mean
there's a wide range of different
ranges of rates that are used
and
but the most economical rate would be a
preventative rate so when you're
basically coming in you're treating your
crop that's pretty clean and your goal
is just to keep it clean to take out
those initial populations that are left
over
or those
or those um
isolated populations that either coming
in from outside
coming from another room and you're
basically preventing them from
developing
so that way you could definitely reduce
your your rate down
um and uh and obviously be more economic
at that stage
but yeah if you're controlling an
existing population
then yes you need to you need to use the
rates and most of the companies that
provide information
will give different ranges whether it's
a curative rate or preventative rate and
you can just you can talk to your
suppliers or your distributors and they
should be able to advise you
um you know given the stage of your
plants
and given your planting density and how
severe your problem is you know what
might be a reasonable rate to work with
um
depending on your situation
great now
is there anything else that persimilis
is also
effective against in terms of cannabis
pests and can you talk a little bit
about
you know how we would apply it like the
actual application itself
right so persimmons is a bit of a
one-trick pony it really only feeds on
spider mites and a few
closely related spider mites in the
family
uh it does not control russet mic
it does not control um
any other any other pests that you might
have won't control broad mice
so most most
most ipm programs will have a range of
different beneficials to control
um
the range of issues that they're dealing
with
so yeah so persimilis really is just for
spider mites
and so if you're dealing with uh for
example if you're dealing with um
aphids or thrips or white flies or
other pests it's important to have a
combination program that tackles all of
the issues that you're seeing we can
talk a little bit more about
about that
absolutely so how would i how how would
i go about applying for simulus in terms
of best practice
right right okay
so so for someone else
basically comes in several different
formats that it comes as a loose format
in in a bottle
typically in a in a vermiculite carrier
um it also comes in a sachet a slow
release factory now which is something
that buyer b carries
and this is often preferred for moms and
flowers and
plants in the later stage of grow where
you really want to try to avoid
contaminating your your plant with
anything that could
that could cause a contamination um in
those cases the sachets are just hung on
the plants
and it also comes in a a nipple form
which you can just touch to the plant
and release the prostimulus directly
there and actually unlike that
that is quite time consuming though so
you have to factor the time involved in
going around to every single plant
um
but yeah those are those are the the
basic formats uh for persimilis and in
terms of how they're applied
uh for most smaller grow operations
um whether you're using the bottles
you're basically just
inoculating the plant with a with a
with one or two small doses of the
persimilis directly onto the leaves
um often that will be done every week or
sometimes every other week depending on
on your pressure
the sachets
they
they come in two forms one is a quick
release form which you're putting on
plants that already have spider mites
and and then a slower release form
which which you can use more
preventively because they'll release for
about two weeks
um
and then um
the
um
the the
the other uh types of protein might have
used for spider mites there's one called
uh neocytose californicus that's
probably the second most commonly used
uh predatory mite for spider mite
control it comes in the same formats
basically we directly release from from
a bottle
or from a slow release sachet
and
and again you know that that choice
typically embeds in veg it's cheaper
it's it's often quicker
to release them directly from bottles
and veg and then
um people will often move to the sachets
once the the plant goes into flower
because then
you know the plants bigger there's more
area to cover and there's more concern
about contamination so so often times on
mums and on flour the sachets are
probably the most common form i see
being used and then in veg
loose material from a bottle
and one thing i do also do see
with some of the larger operations is
that because of the amount of time taken
to do a treatment so some growers will
actually mix their persimulus often
they'll combine it with other bios and
they'll mix it together
and then they'll put it out with a
blower and that allows you to basically
treat
a much larger area
quickly you're not treating individual
plants you're treating
um several rows at the same time
and because these predatory mice are
relatively mobile for similarities
probably the most mobile of them all
i really can
it really can crawl along the bench and
it can climb up plants and it can even
move between plants
so it's uh often times in the larger
operations
putting them out with a blower would be
a technique i see a lot
are there any situations where we may
make a preference for california kiss
over persimilis with
spider mites
you know there's a lot of talks about
this and and everyone has their own
opinion
there are some biological differences
for sure between them and there may be
some cost differences as well depending
on your supplier the reality is i think
you can use either
and
you can you can use them individually or
in combination
i tend to find that pristimonious is
just probably a little bit more
aggressive it does feed on a higher
number of spider mites it's going to be
in most cases more effective
when you have an existing population
you're trying to bring down
um
the only issue with presumably it's a
little bit less tolerant of lower
humidities so if you do grow dry if
you're
have a have a humid you know an average
humidity let's say
60 or less
uh persimmons may not be able to
establish very well in that situation
and you may find if you're growing dry
and you can be preventative californicus
may be a better bet for you
um
but for the most part really you can
potentially use use either or or both of
them together like i say just for
simulus is just a little bit more
aggressive has a slightly higher spider
mic consumption rate and it's a little
bit more mobile it's a little bit better
able to move around
than california
okay and you could always i assume do a
combination to really just cover your
bases
i i guess as well
you can i mean some people mentioned
that california because freedom for
similar flags uh which is true
but for the most part you're you know
your mass inoculating these bugs and
um these sort of interactions that you
do see with one maybe feeding a little
bit on the other they don't tend to be
i don't see them generally jeopardizing
your bio control program for the most
part they they can still they can still
be used together i see that a lot so um
that that's an option but
um and the other advantage i suppose in
california because the sachets do last a
little bit longer so some people will
just use a like a swarovski and the
californica sachet mix that seems to be
very common and that covers um
that will cover spider mites and it will
also cover thrips control of course
because
and and white flight control as well
because that's
those are two pests first they seem to
do it to do a good job on so again that
would be a combination of
californicus
and uh and swirsky put together on the
same plan
yeah now if we were outdoors would we
want to lean more towards californicus
due to its ability to survive in greater
environmental ranges
or do you still are you still using
persimilis outdoors with certain crops
um so in florida there's not too much
outdoor production of cannabis so it
seems to be a bit more
of of hemp but um
but yes you can like the the most
important thing is is to look at the
the environmental conditions if it's
particularly dry where you are
um
then if you want to take some advice
about whether it's going to be too dry
for proper similar and if it is then
yes you probably want to use the
californicus or
some growers also like to use ander sony
i forgot to mention that one that's
another one which is uh commonly used on
cannabis for
spider mite control
it has similar characteristics to
californicus
um
now both
andersoni swersky
and californicus can also feed on pollen
and so in some situations if outdoors
you know pollen occurs naturally
they may do you know it blows in and
they may do a better job on establishing
on plants that are pretty clean because
they're able to survive longer without
food and they're also able to feed on
things like pollen which which
presumably is not able to do
so
having a longer uh duration of survival
on the plants
um can be an advantage in certain
situations
um it just depends you know i personally
i find that for stimulus
it doesn't live very long if it doesn't
have food but it does a pretty good job
at knocking your spider mite populations
down to a very low level even
eradicating them locally so
you really have a bit sometimes have a
little bit of a breather time before the
calf before the spider mites will
reestablish and so
you don't necessarily need to have life
proof similars on the plants at all
times as long as you're inoculating your
plants frequently enough that the spider
mites can't get a foothold
so
yeah i don't really think there's one
size fits all here i think different
people have different preferences but i
think i mentioned some of the things you
need to look out for when you're
deciding which predatory mice to use
no that's great information i mean
that's one of the things about
biocontrols that i think people struggle
with and why we need
experts is because it is a little more
subtle there's a lot of variables to
consider when making decisions so this
is
this is great so you know you kind of
covered persimilis in pretty good detail
um
and also talked about californicus now
you mentioned californicus also has some
suppression of uh broad mites maybe we
could talk a little bit about broad
mites as a transition into another
target past
yeah yeah so broad mics are not as
common as the problems of spider mites
but they certainly um
they certainly do get on on cannabis and
they're they can be a little bit more
insidious because they're kind of a
little bit smaller they're a little bit
more cryptic you know often they'll sort
of hide
um in the growing
portions of the plant or they run along
the mid vein
and when they first get in they're not
so
easy to see you do want to look out for
the symptoms on the plant they can cause
crinkling and deformation on the on the
young parts of the plant so you're
probably going to see the symptoms of
bromides before you actually see them
um
but yes luckily broad mites are not too
hard to control um
a lot of growers i think with cannabis
they find it useful to in their program
to include something that's going to
feed on broadband even if they don't
necessarily have broad mites um you
don't want them and
some of the predatory mites um swarovski
is pretty effective at broad mice
um
uh californicus also can feed on broad
mites
so having something in there in your
program
that will um be able to take control of
world mice before they become a problem
is a good idea
great and is the application for
californicus similar to persimilis are
there any differences there
for you know these nights in general
um
no not not not really um they
the the formats
uh different suppliers will will have
different formats but
but most of them come in uh a range of
different bottle sizes sometimes there's
differences in concentration so
you may have um
you you want to look at the the
when you're when you're planning your
program you want to look at the
different
bottle sizes and the different
concentrations and
if you if you want to put on a
relatively high rate you want to get a
fairly concentrated bottle so that
you're not
having to put a lot of extra carrier on
the plants which is not necessary
on the flip side if you're if you're
trying to
apply to plants that are spaced and
you've got a large area to cover and
you're going to use a blower
then you want to make sure you've got
enough um volume
to distribute the the mites you want
sufficiently so you may need to use a
larger bottle or a slightly less
concentrated form
um so yeah there's a range of different
sizes um
i like i say i do find that that a lot
of cannabis growers like the sachets
for various reasons they're a little bit
more expensive so i work a lot with
ornamental growers and they're always
you know very very price conscious
and the sachets is the more expensive
way to apply the same number of mites
but in cannabis because of the value of
the crop
that's not necessarily so much of an
issue and so
in situations where
having essentially is advantageous and
so certainly in moms and in flower then
you know a few extra cents per for
per plant for applying essentially is
not not really a big deal
yeah so the sachets make the application
simpler they um may give longer levels
you correct me if i say anything wrong
here
longer time intervals of prevention
depending on the type of sachet and they
also keep any sort of carrier like
vermiculite off of our
trichomes in this case is there any
other advantages to sachets that i'm
missing here or something that i
may have misspoke on
no so the yeah the main advantages would
be um the the
the
extra time of release so
in the case of things like californicus
and conhumerus and swarsky most
saturdays typically will give you a
month of release
if if they're in a humid situation you
can get up to six weeks
um
and um so yeah a lot longer duration
um lack of lack of the carrier on the
crop
um and also of course once the fat is on
the plant most sachets have a date on
them so you can see which plants have
been treated
um when you're applying a small amount
of carrier on a leaf that that may blow
off or drop off
you know the next within a few days
unless you happen to keep records or no
uh it's if you don't have that immediate
um
ability to go to a plan and determine
when exactly when everything was applied
so that would be um
that would be another uh advantage of
the other one of course is if you are
spraying and i know a lot of growers do
still when they're using buyers they
still like to come in and spray
sometimes perhaps more than they need to
but what keep in mind when you're
spraying
even if you're spraying soft materials
like like uh soaps and oils these are
still i'm gonna be killing your your
predatory mics you know they they
they're killing your soft body
beneficials as well as your pests in
these situations where you're spraying
them directly
and of course the sachet is generally a
waterproof and so
anything that's still inside the sachet
when you're sprayed and comes out
subsequently once your spray is dried
um
that can be a better way to combine
sprays and buyers is the food you use
disgusting
yeah that's a great point and also a
reminder to folks to make sure that what
they're spraying um
works well with bio with
beneficials
you know i know suzanne's a big fan of
stuff oil x
because it doesn't have a lot of
residual effect on the plant and you can
your beneficials can
re-re-inoculate pretty quickly into a
space um so
yeah she she also mentions on the on the
flip side that neem oil for example may
deter beneficials from re-inoculating
right away so
just something to think about when
you're thinking about what to spray
getting back to though
the
you know you mentioned californicus
will work with two spotted also with
broad mites
are there any other
target species for for californicus
before or anything else for treating
broad mites that we want to talk about
before we move on to another pest
uh yeah so so one thing we should
probably talk about oh by the way before
i forget you may you made a great point
with the sprays and suzanne's point
about neem oil which can be repellent is
well taken
um
if you are going to be spraying and
using buyers
it's very important that you do it in
the right order you want to spray first
release buyers subsequently not the
other way around um
just keep that in mind but um yeah broad
might um
two of the common uh solutions for
broadband would probably be uh two
species of fertility might that would be
your swarovski and your humerus
um these are both they look very similar
you know you can't tell them apart by
looking at them but
they they both broadly do the same thing
um
i swear it needs a little bit more
flexible but
they both will work for broad mics
and just keep in mind um if you're using
your your your bios
um and you're using either swarovski
humerus it's really important to keep in
mind that they have different
temperature
activity profiles so swarsky is a more
uh sort of tropically adapted species
it
can handle higher temperatures cucumbers
is one that's used a lot more further
north
um and and used in the winter and the
south perhaps it's
it does a good job if your temperatures
are going to be in the range of sort of
50 degrees to
upper seventies uh if you humorous
that's a sweet spot it will be active it
will control your world mites
if your average daytime temperature is
going to be in your 80s and your 90s
um then yes you definitely want to be
using
sweersky because that one is going to be
better adapted to the warmer conditions
so you definitely want to keep that in
mind um
for
for for my control
great and since you mentioned swarski um
you know i'm i'm cheating i'm looking at
one of your sheets here uh it's also a
swirsky also works quite well against
thrips it sounds like
uh immature throughout reading um
maybe we maybe we move on to thrips next
since that's another common
problem here in cannabis
oh yeah yeah strips can definitely um be
problematic uh
and you know that again they can be hard
to spot early on they can be a little
bit cryptic
um
so yes there's a few things about trips
one is um there's a number of different
trips we'll get on cannabis and they're
not all the same some of them are easier
to control than others
um and so definitely if you got thrips
you know figure out which ones you have
and if you're not sure um
you know you know work with your uh
your consultant or your you know your
supplier or whoever your local extension
office make sure you know which strip
you're dealing with
the thrips are best controlled again
sort of preventatively
um you made a good point a lot of these
predatory might feed on thrips of
swarovski
uh ancient humerus would probably be the
two main ones that are used for trips
um
they they only eat the smaller stages um
cucumbers really only is the first
larval stay swarovski can feed on
most they can also feed on the second
larval stage but they're not going to be
for the most part feeding on the adults
so
your adults are still going to be out
there potentially laying eggs
so that's why it's important if you have
thrips that you're maintaining a
coverage
of your predatory mites um
continuously because you what you want
to do is is is you want to prevent all
of that all of that reproduction of the
thrips that's going to go on in your
crop you want to prevent those larvae
from ever really developing
and so you need to maintain a fairly
constant source whether that you know
typically that would be weekly either
sachets that will continuously release
uh your predatory mice for a while or if
you're not using flash age you probably
you have a threats issue you probably
want to come on every single week um and
and be releasing your predatory life
um
and if you have
the other thing about thrips is that
especially when you have a fairly
established infestation you probably
want to add something for the soil stage
as well because your thrips want to get
into the soil your predatory mics are
not going to be feeding on those so
you've got trips coming out from the
soil
um
you know these they they have a
quiescent stage in the soil and then
they develop into adults and they come
up and then they start laying eggs again
and it's not until those eggs are
hatching then that you're going to be
able to start controlling them so you've
a better way to break the life cycle is
to add something for the soil stage
and we can talk about that there's
several soil predatory mites and insects
which will feed on trips and in that
situation if you have an established
infestation you probably want to be
using something both for the soil stage
as well as the stage on the leaves as
well
yeah let's talk about that what would
you recommend then for a soil
application
if dealing with rips
right well there's three main things
that people use um
one of them is another predatory mic
which is
uh it's got their rather long name
stratego lelaps cemetus it was actually
formerly known as um hypoaspis so a lot
of people still call it hypoaspis it's
uh
it's a bit of a larger mic it's it's in
a different family it's in the leylapid
family
um and it lives on the on the soil it
doesn't really get up onto the leaves
and it's a generalist it will feed on
things like springtails and um
trips larvae and and fungus gnats it's
probably used many for fungus net
control but it will feed on those stages
of thrips in the soil so
adding something like that would be a
good idea there's another one the rose
beetle which is very popular
um it's called delosha or a theta
and that's another good one it's very
mobile it can actually fly um
in situations where you have maybe
you're not growing as clean as you want
and you have
things like thrips and fungus gnats
perhaps that are roots that are
populations that are coming from the
ground maybe you've got weeds or you've
got
some dampness where you've got algae and
things growing maybe that's a source of
pests it'd be good to clean it up but
using some of the rose beetles can be
good in that situation because they'll
get around they'll get into those
corners
and they can even establish and they'll
they'll they'll be a good thing to use
on in that situation
um and then the third option is would be
the beneficial episodes which we didn't
talk about yet
um but again they can be used in
propagation uh you can drench the plant
at any stage
potentially if you have thrips but
typically that would be something that
you would use in younger plants
if you have issues with crypts and
fungus maps and you would come in
and you could definitely uh incorporate
nematodes in that situation as well
yeah and which nematode would you
recommend for dealing with throats
so
there's several species in limited the
the one that works best for thrips is
stunning mfl ti
um we just we just
because people have such a problem
pronouncing some of these names we just
call them by their letters so sf
um
and that one that's probably the one
that's primarily used for trips
it it works relatively well it doesn't
like it hot um
once you get temperatures in the sort of
upper 80s it
doesn't really work too well so it's
something that you want to try to use uh
in the cooler part of the day or the
cooler part of the season
um or or have some kind of cooling in
your grow your operation
um
but yeah that that's the one keep in
mind that they that they these things
need to be kept uh
they don't they don't like it too dry
so you need to be put on a high volume
you need to keep the the media wet
uh for several hours
they don't do great in things like
rockwool anything where you have a very
fast draining system
um
soilless media they don't work quite as
well but
so take some advice from your supplier
about your situation
and and make sure if you're using your
nematodes you're using them in the right
way
um there's a few little things to watch
out for with nematodes like they can
clog in filters and they
um they can drown if you mix them up and
leave them sitting around for a while
before using them and that kind of thing
yeah now when you mention temperatures
you're talking about soil temperatures
in this case since we're talking about
nematodes
is that right right
yes yes that's that's right i mean
ideally we don't have
you know
we're not in the 80s anyway with our
crop
at least indoors in terms of soil temps
just to keep cannabis happy but
um
yeah that's a great that's a great point
so um
we're kind of jumping around i guess a
little bit here uh was there anything
else regarding thrips
that you want to talk about
um
well i should mention um
one of the species of thrips it's often
it's called poinsettia thrips or
echinocrypts it's a dark
fairly dark slim looking thrips um
that it doesn't really get controlled
very well by any of the buyers and in
that situation you really need to have a
have a spray program or an alternative
program
to target those um
so again you know make sure you know
which stretch you're dealing with
uh i do have uh
some growers that i that i know
they they do like using aureus aureus is
a it's the pirate bug
um
and you know you may be probably
familiar with it it's uh
it's a generalist but it's it does like
to feed on thrips
um now there is a question about how
persistent it is in cannabis because
if aureus doesn't find anything to eat
it kind of doesn't really hang around
and because it can't fly so it can
disperse
um having said that some growers they
use a lot of it it's it's a generalist
they like to have it around
even if it's not very persistent um for
them it's it's a good insurance policy
for adult trips because of course it
will feed on the adult thrips as well
and um
there are also other ways we can maybe
talk about a little bit but there are
other ways to
encourage and keep some of your buyers
around
in the crop longer by feeding them
um and so that aureus would be an
example of something that you can
actually potentially feed using pollen
or festia eggs or a product that biobee
has is
based on a type of decapsulated brine
shrimp egg which aureus just love i mean
i've got videos of them going to town on
this stuff they can reproduce on it and
it's a lot less expensive than
than
a festive eggs and so
there are potentially ways to
you can buy for example you can buy
swarski that contains the food in the
bottle so when you're putting it out if
they don't necessarily have much to eat
in the crop then you are giving them a
food source um
application and that helps to keep them
happy and
will reduce their their ability to
spread and fly away so
yeah so i should have mentioned oreos
there
um
but yeah i think that's that's the main
thing that's the main aspects of fripps
i think we covered yeah i want to
highlight one thing you said just as a
gentle reminder to folks too is that um
it always starts with identification
like you mentioned that there's various
types of thrips some are controlled
certain ways
or maybe slightly differently or less
controlled
than other species so
take the time to scout to get
proper identification which is not
necessarily posting it in a facebook
group asking what is this blurry photo
but you know make sure it gets in front
of an entomologist someone that can
actually give you a positive id
and then
come up with a treatment plan based on
that information so
again this is stuff that just suzanne
just drills into my head
so it's been yeah yeah well susan's been
doing this a long time and you know i
suzanne's probably probably the best out
there at
what she does and um
i know one of her
one of her pet feeds is some of the
misinformation that can go around on um
some some forums and chat boards and and
and that kind of thing in the cannabis
industry you know there there is some
bad information out there and
there's also lots of good information
but of course knowing which is which and
getting getting a good idea is really
important because
um
you know that's like the first thing you
really need to do because i do see
people you know maybe applying um
for some of us
when when the problem they have is not
spider mites or something like that
you're potentially just wasting your
money so yeah that's a great point pad
yeah you know i hear these stories about
facilities either you know doing uh
massive over applying of beneficials
because they have the wrong rates
or you know and sometimes that's from uh
you know a potential consultant or the
issue is they're just not applying the
right insect for the right problem and
then that's where people get into this
idea that bio controls don't work so
you know i'm grateful because i'm not
an entomologist or anywhere near an
expert on this i'm grateful for some of
the people on my team that are more
knowledgeable than me but then also
having resources like yourself and
suzanne and and other people at biobee
that i can
you know get a positive identification
just to back up
uh you know my own knowledge as a way of
making sure that my recommendation is
going to be
on target for what what's actually going
on in a room so
yeah thank you i just
i just want to go back and touch on that
because too many times i think people
get ahead of themselves or they you know
they see a problem on a leaf they post a
photo
you know of a blurry insect they think
it's one thing and then it turns out you
know maybe it's
you know
maybe it's innocuous it's just a soil
dwelling mite or maybe it's uh not what
they thought it was or a different
species so
yeah just wanted to go back and touch on
that so
okay
uh moving on unless there's anything you
want to add to that
yeah and i just one real quick thing
that related to what you just said that
that is good to keep in mind um
you know i get a lot of people sending
pictures all the time of different
things and
um
you know
so many times the picture quality is
just low it's very hard to identify
things without a good photo um
especially mics you know mice can be
hard to control uh hard to identify
um
without even from good good pictures um
so you know sometimes you need samples
so yeah so idea is important getting
good quality photos is important
um and then another thing you said which
which i see a lot is
especially you know
especially once you're growing and if
you're growing in hoop houses or you're
growing outdoors
you get a lot of different incidental
things that can come around and then a
lot of them are not problematic you know
i i see
various um
various bugs that will just come in from
outside and
you know maybe they'll even feed on a
leaf for a little bit but they don't
have the capacity to reproduce so
they're not going to be a problem so
by all means get everything identified
but don't feel like just because you
have a particular bug in the facility
that that's necessarily something that
you need to spray for or control it may
be something that's just innocuous and
just need to keep an eye out for it
um
because the more you spray um the more
you're going to be impacting your
beneficial insects so making unnecessary
sprays is probably just as bad if not
worse than not making it thin
in some ways then making missing sprays
that you need to make so
you
use what you use what you have as a
guide to what you need to do in terms of
your own particular facility
that's a great point um especially about
having a high quality camera because
it's it's it's hard enough to identify
these mites much less with a blurry
photo so it's definitely worth the
investment getting a decent camera to
take a good photo and a lot of times
your
phone camera just isn't gonna isn't
gonna cut it
um
one other thing that you you mentioned
was you know people
treating for things that aren't problems
well
you know we work with a lot of growers
doing um
what people are calling living so i
don't know if you're familiar with it
stephen it's this idea of
reusing soil typically beds
and managing the fertility in it over
time and so we do see a lot more insect
life
in these you know you'll see a lot of uh
orbited mites
or you'll see people
that'll spot you know mold mites that
may come in with a you know beneficial
insect application and
it's just important that we we get the
right id there that's
i think that's where we always have to
start so
yeah
yeah yeah yeah no i do see or about it
might um
these are from people what the heck are
these and they're they don't you know
they they're again they're often just a
secondary issue
um
i also see uh typho typhofagus mites
coming in um various different things
that
are really just pretty innocuous um
so so yeah yeah
and i think one thing you mentioned
earlier which were the isopods again
that's a that's an issue which i haven't
personally seen but i know that can be i
know whether you want to mention those
or not but that can be
um
sometimes some of these soil
soil issues you have are very much
reflect you know how you grow whether
you recycle soil how much organic matter
you have
and um
and i think you said that you've seen
sometimes those can actually be
causing damage as well so that was
interesting
yeah when we see really high levels of
organic matter in a soil
sometimes those populations i found can
get out of control and actually start
chewing at the at the stock itself
you know one or two probably not a
problem but you know i've seen it where
there's like
hundreds or probably thousands in a
given room they just get out of control
so that's where i typically recommend
um mass trapping
um and you can even put like a sticky
sticky tape or traps around
the stem of your plant to help kind of
just stave off that damage
while you're trying to get it back under
control but there aren't as far as i
know a lot of good options other than
maybe reducing their food source by
removing some of that organic matter or
that cover crop or something else that
they may be
surviving off of i don't did you want to
add
add to that
no i mean i i like the idea about um
mass trapping and possibly changing your
um
your how how you grow what soil you use
um more than coming in and trying to
spray them away
um i like that idea more but
um but no that was i don't really have
anything any direct experience with
using those so
um
yeah
yeah we'll also see super high levels of
springtails sometimes which again are
not
really problematic
but but i do see a lot of photos of
those showing up online and i have seen
them in a couple grows i've walked into
i don't know if you want to touch on
that some of the things that you list
actually feed on springtails some of the
things that we talked about it sounds
like so i thought that was interesting
yeah springtails are not normally an
issue but if they get into behind
numbers um
you know there is some some evidence
suggestion that they can vector some
some fungal diseases um if they get to
be high numbers there are certainly some
species of springtails which will feed
on young roots potentially can cause
damage again you know there's lots of
different springtails if you have a lot
of springtails um i would
probably caution about doing something
about them um and again some of the the
the predatory insects we mentioned
earlier that the rope beetles as well as
some of the the australian laylaps mites
they will feed on them and again that's
something that you might want to
consider putting in if you've got a lot
of springtails just to
just to reduce the risk of some of those
problems happening
and that's a good point that some of
these insects can be vectors
so that's something to factor in as well
thank you for mentioning that um
let's
you know we haven't even talked about
some of the major
tests that i think people are going to
tune into this podcast to want to hear
about so let's just knock out um
probably one of the most common ones um
and and definitely not one of the more
damaging or worse ones you have to deal
with which is just fungus gnats
give me your thoughts around around
fungus gnats in terms of how you like to
treat it
the fungus and that shouldn't should not
be difficult to control and
you shouldn't really be in a situation
where you're having a lot of fungus and
that's flying around um
um
most most fungus maps you know there's
just a few ways to approach fungus
that's at the
first is um
are you you know are you growing too wet
um
fungus gnats of course they they're
feeding primarily on
on algae and uh and and and fungi that
grow on the soil or
they can also grow of course on the
non-crop area on the ground if you if
your facility is not too clean
um i've i've also seen them coming out
of some water walls feeding on water
walls and things so
um
so having having a clean grow not
growing you know
not growing too wet is is the primary
thing
fungus naps are really pretty easily
controlled again by by the the
australian elapsed mites we talked about
the rope beetles and again the the
stunning method nematodes all of those
things um
will control fungus gnats pretty
effectively
so
the only thing i would perhaps add is
that if you have an established
infestation function that's quite a long
life cycle it can be a month or more
and most of the bio controls you're
really only targeting the larvae so
you've got potentially a fairly
long-lived adult stage people stage and
egg stage that are not being targeted so
it can take a while for those to cycle
through
so if you have a lot of fungus gnats and
i've certainly seen this in greenhouses
it can take a couple of months or more
before those numbers drop down
so
you know some people might want to come
in with a with a
with a a pyrethrin spray and try to
knock down the adults
um definitely putting up sticky traps
will help
monitor and to a certain extent if you
if you you know sticky rolls all the way
around you can you can help bring the
numbers down
more quickly but
in general um
fungus now should not be too too
difficult to control
yeah i i like the idea of sf nematodes
um
as my
primary way of dealing with them but i'm
glad you mentioned a couple other ways
of treating
for them we see them quite a bit in
because we use compost as a fraction of
our soil mix and it's really inevitable
when we have organic matter that's been
outdoors at some point in time
you can't have all the biology in the
compost and then not have the potential
for fungus gnats and vice versa so
um it's it you know seasonally will
become an issue sometimes
which is why you know pre-treating with
sf nematodes or being on a maintenance
schedule
as a preventative just makes it really
easy because you don't get to that
hopefully that mass trapping infestation
stage where you're having to
having to think about spraying and
things like that
yeah yeah that's a good point funder's
max can come in on eggs on on media
after buying in media unless it's
sterile
um it's not uncommon for fungus net eggs
to be in the media and sometimes they'll
they'll they they they'll hatch once the
media gets wet and so you're you that's
where your your source can can come from
like you say or if you
have your media outside it can get
contaminated that way so in that
situation you'd probably want to treat
um
you'd probably want to treat your young
plants for sure with a drench for
nematodes um one of the new products
actually that we have is a nematode in a
in a capsule which
is a slow release capsule and
that can actually be incorporated into
your your your plugs or your media your
young plants
and the advantage on that is it allows
you to have a
long application of nematodes during
that critical
period when the plants are putting at
their first roots where trenches can be
a little disruptive you don't want to
disrupt your plants when they first
start rooting
um
and so
uh in that situation you can actually
incorporate these nematode capsules into
your into your media uh um and then you
don't have to drench but then you've
still got the
extended release of the nematode so
that's that's something new we're kind
of excited about so
um so yeah that's another that's another
option as well you don't want to drench
yeah it's called the
nema plus
depot 200 is the product you're you're
talking about it's 200 capsules 320 000
nematodes per
unit
uh yeah
yeah yeah it's just come out in a
the
until now it's coming these tiny little
packets with about 200 capsules in
which is fine if you've only got a small
number of plants but i think now it's
now becoming available in a bag of 32
000 capsules wow so that's a lit that's
uh
i believe that should be available
sometime in the next month or so
um so
that's something that um you could maybe
put on a on the potting line or
something and
and
treat every plant
as it's being stuck or
depending on how you how you grow
so that's so that's exciting and again
that can be potentially automated as
well
i've seen them put on or automate
automation lines where
every part gets treated with a few
capsules
as part of the production line so that
that's uh
that's kind of a i think where the
future would be
for fungus back control
so i haven't i haven't seen this product
um
can you describe what it actually looks
like and then also how you
how you apply it like are you burying it
in the soil is it just going you know
relatively close to the surface are you
watering it in what
what can you tell me about it yeah
yeah yeah it was developed for the it's
actually developed for the for the home
uh
for the um houseplant market where
people would
would you know maybe they'd be going
away for a few weeks on vacation or they
they'd want to treat their house plants
or fungus mass but they didn't really
want to be spraying and
you could just get a few of these
capsules
make a little few holes in the soil put
them in cover them up and then you
you're good to go
um in the ag market which is kind of the
new market for for these things
um
it's not 100 clear what the best how to
use them but i but what seems to be the
best way
is just to put them on a potting line
and or put them in your plants when
they're first
when they're first
planted
and
they the capsules have to be in the
media that you can't top dress so
you know either you put them in the
planting hole when when the plant goes
in
or you incorporate them into your
potting mix
you mix them into your potting mix and
then that body mix is pre-treated
or you find some other such way to
incorporate them uh into the
into the top
into the parts where they have to you
know some device to make holes and then
put them in
so it's not it's not clear to me it
would depend on on everyone's situation
but um
like i say this is kind of something new
but
uh i really see uh this being a very
useful tool where people can just kind
of get to get their fungus map treatment
done
straight away when the plants are first
stuck and they don't have to worry about
it for
maybe at all um if those plants are big
enough and
got enough root system
by the time the capsules are done maybe
fungus fats are no longer a problem but
if you do have to come in and drench
with nematodes later on um the roots are
fairly well developed and and the
direction is not going to be so
disruptive
yeah
we should talk about that more
yeah the other thing that you made me
think of too is in a facility it reduces
i would think employee error
in application um
you know potentially not getting an even
application of nematodes across all your
plants or you know mixing and not
not properly applying to where you may
be damaging your nematodes
i i think that's really interesting
as a reason to potentially use them i'm
picturing like
like a fish oil capsule is that anywhere
close to what they actually look like
yeah they look a little bit like caviar
um
the capsules are made from food grade
material
it's like a calcium alginate sunflower
um
uh oil emulsion in the middle so you can
eat these things if you want i they
don't taste good i tried it but um
they're uh they're it's all food grade
materials um and they're pretty
persistent and you know they they store
well in the fridge
um they just look like little kind of
little um
little soft
capsules of like caviar or something
like that
um and they come in these bags and
and uh
yeah we're excited to see where this
goes
very cool very cool um well i want to
save time for what's
what's sort of new
from biobee and what you're seeing in
the industry but i also realize we at
the very least need to at least touch on
um or maybe i need to do another podcast
with you on we haven't even talked about
hemp russet canvas aphid or root aphids
as the main three and then caterpillar
leaf miners and white flies is sort of
more minor
pests um
what would you like to what would you
like to tackle next
um well we can mention hemp russet mike
briefly um
that that one can be a problem uh if it
gets well established it could be a
can be a problem and that's one that
really um
you know that there's some
debate about what role bios play but for
sure i would
i would think that if you have an
existing information pentrust it might
you've got to have a
spray program to deal with it um
soft oil x
sulfur sprays
some other
[Music]
paraffin oil type sprays
need to be done
you know you could potentially uh dip
your dip your clones you need to you
need to deal with that problem it's not
going to get any better you have to be
aggressive
and
once your hemorrhagic might populations
are under control
then there there there is some uh
evidence that having something like
swarovski or bicumerous in the mix can
potentially help prevent your plants
becoming reinfected with new sources of
hemp russet might coming in but i know
this is something suzanne's got quite
strong opinions on um that the
beneficials themselves are not going to
be an effective way to get rid of an
existing infestation but don't don't
don't wait around if you've got hemp
wrap it might i can say it tends to get
worse
um and you need to have a strategy for
for dealing with it so
um
if you apply it in the right way it's
not that difficult
but um but uh yeah suffer x i think is
probably one of the best
uh treatments um out there
for to to deal with an existing problem
and also example of where you need a
really good
camera or scope just to to spot them i
mean they're very easy to identify once
you have the right tools but without the
right tools
you'd be struggling i think to make a
positive identification
yeah they're probably the smallest pest
that you're going to be dealing with in
cannabis
they really are
even with the 10x hand lens that then
they're they're they can be hard to see
so uh yeah you you that's a situation
where you might want to get get your
little dissecting scope out or something
and get your samples under there and dig
around and find them because um the same
with broad mics you know the hair russet
mites and broad mic uh are often to die
misdiagnosed problems people will see an
issue on a plan and they'll just say
well that must be broadband or that must
be right it might the truth is you
actually have to find these critters and
confirm that they're on the plant before
you can be 100 sure
um they're not easy to get a positive
diagnosis without actually finding them
because you can't get other symptoms
that can cause potentially similar
other things that cause similar symptoms
so
yeah that's a great great point make
sure you identify them
okay well
moving on then
cannabis aphid and root aphids
okay well these are other these are um
two more difficult pests um
if you're gonna get aphids my advice
would be to get cotton aphids and green
peas aphids um very easy to control
if you're going to get aphids
not that they can't be a problem if you
don't treat for them but they they
buyers work very well for those some of
the parasitic wasps
they're pretty inexpensive
if you have them as part of your program
um then you shouldn't have too many
issues with those cannabis aphids are a
little bit tougher
um to control the buyers don't work
quite as effectively for those
um now if you do use parasitic walls for
aphids um
they do the common types of parasitic
wasps which you're using for your common
aphids they will parasitize cannabis
aphids just not as effectively
but having having them in the mix will
definitely help slow
slow down the risk of cannabis so if
you're going crazy and when it goes
crazy and it starts spreading it can be
a real problem
um so cannabis aphid yes you know you
want to have
there's there's several approaches a lot
of people at this point will bust out
the sprays and they'll try to spray it
back
um and again you know you that can work
you need to get the good coverage and
you also need to be aware of what impact
you're having on your other bio program
when you're doing that
um what i see also now is that some
growers will use predatory insects for
cannabis aphid and i've seen a lot of
interest in using lacewings
lacewings now are more readily available
they're relatively inexpensive
and
you they can be put out in large
quantities as eggs
in mixed in with things like predatory
mics so people will just say hey we're
just going to add some lacewings into
this mix
and
lacewings are fairly mobile they can get
around and
they're
they will definitely feed on cannabis
aphids
um
so again you have a you have some
different options there
i've also seen lady beetles released in
cannabis for for cannabis aphid i would
not generally recommend those they only
ever really work if you have very very
high populations you don't want to have
your your cannabis avid population
getting that high
so
well um and let's also touch on the fact
that most commercially available
lady beetles are wild harvested which is
not a great practice and
not
necessarily something that
as a consumer we would want to support
for its you know
vector of disease and environmental
damage
though i hear there are some
commercially available lady beetle
available they're just really expensive
yeah
yeah there
there is one company that does um rear
the convergent lady beetle which is the
one you're referring to it's normally
wild collected um
artists it they they they do wear it in
culture but it's very limited supply
it's very expensive
um
and um
uh yeah yeah so i honestly like lace
wings are probably gonna be a more
reliable more cost effective way of um
for as a generalist predator for aphids
then than ladybugs um
definitely i i would
go more down the the lacewing route than
the ladybug group
um
you know but yes yes go ahead oh i just
wanted to mention i've had some friends
have success with heat treatment with
cannabis aphid um by just you know
massively overheating their rooms
they've been able to knock back
populations that way because
it is a really really tough pest
to deal with it just just keeps coming
back it seems like
so uh that's just one other suggestion i
want to throw out there i know if you
had any thoughts on that
yeah yeah no that's interesting i don't
know what the exact temperature you'd
have to get to
i'd imagine you'd probably want to get
it up into the mid 40 degree
celsius range or something
before you
for a few hours probably because i think
that's a great idea if you can do that
um one really important thing about
cannabis aphid which you need to keep in
mind is that
it's it's uh it's monacious on cannabis
right so
whereas other aphids are going to maybe
fly in
come through a window come in on
come in on a weed come in on someone's
clothes
cannabis aphids they can only really
come from um from from cannabis um
or you know cannabis plants in the
cannabis family
and so
um if you have it you gotta figure out
well where did it come from because it
didn't just fly into a window
and the other thing to keep in mind is
if it means if you can get rid of it
from your from your facility
then as long as you don't bring it in
again
you don't have it anymore so there's
more um there's more motivation to make
an effort to
to try to get rid of it because
if you can get rid of it and not bring
it in you're done your problem's over so
that's another thing to keep in mind
um
well the other thing too i think you
that you brought up a little bit ago was
this idea of identification again uh
just to harp on that i know
you know aphids can be color morphs so
you can't necessarily get a positive id
just based off the color suzanne's been
like
tad you have to send me a close-up of
their genitals you know when i wanted an
id once of an aphid so i know that it's
a little more complex and i so i just
want to again suggest that people get a
positive id before jumping to the
conclusion about what the aphid species
is
uh that they're necessarily seeing
um on their plants
yeah yeah great point so both rips and
aphids uh you need an ip
um
at the species level you're saying
yeah cannabis labels aren't that hard
what you want to do is you want to look
at their head they have these little
horns
they're actually tubercles kind of
between their eyes and they look like
little devil horns
um and uh there's not really any other
um aphids on cannabis that have these so
um once you see these um that's a pretty
short bed that you've got cannabis
aphids
that's a good corner thank you
yeah
all right the dreaded root aphids uh
these might be the most frustrating
um i don't can't see if it's pretty
frustrating says hemp russet but this is
definitely in the mix i feel like
uh what what are your thoughts on rude
aphids
rude aphids are
i always used to think you know if
you've got rude assets you need to
eradicate them and just get rid of them
um because
but the more i think about it and the
more i see how difficult they are to get
rid of in
in established um grows
i think a lot of people are just kind of
living with them now and then you know
and and they can be managed to to
acceptable levels um
um
if they're not managed then yes they
they
the issue with rude aphids is they tend
to get they tend to get in on your stock
on stock plants you know when you've got
plants around for a long time the risk
of them getting established root aphids
seems to increase and then what happens
is then they
they start bubbling out of the stock
plants and then they fly around and then
they'll make their way
um
to to around the facility and then they
keep kind of spreading
um and so you're always kind of like
putting out little fires
so
um
rude aphids you have to have um
you have to figure out where they're
coming from and you have to use root
trenches
to try to maintain even if you can't
eradicate them um you should be able to
maintain a pretty low levels with with
root trenches and so most cannabis guys
they use some combination of botany
guard and pfr
um and
sometimes as a directon
some of them will mix in nematodes and
there's there's some evidence that
nematodes can affect root aphids
in the lab it's not clear to me there is
there actually is a little bit of
research suggesting that they're helpful
but it's not
it's it's pretty limited but regardless
um
some combination of root trenches are
definitely needed um typically you know
at least weekly well you have decent
populations
of rude aphids and and even after that
at least every other week to
keep them suppressed
um in combination with that you need to
be scouting for rude aphids on the on
the flowers
on the on the plants and you need to try
to stop them
because what will happen is then they'll
move down to the roots and then they'll
start another source on your roots on
your other plants so
you want to be maintaining your root if
it's on your source so that they're not
bubbling out and expanding if the
populations stay relatively low they'll
stay in those roots they won't spread
it's when you get large numbers that
they'll start crawling out producing
that your wing forms and then spreading
that's what you want to stop
um in terms of the bios
um we know that that um the the soil
dwelling predatory beetle the rose
beetles and and the products we might
can and and do feed on roulette because
i've seen them
but they're not going to be an effective
control by themselves they simply don't
get deep enough into the soil they're
just going to help stop your relatives
from spreading on the soil surface line
and maybe in the top layer they're not
going to be
eliminating them but i would say
combining your some some predatory soil
insects and mites along with your root
drenches is like a first step for for
rooday food control
yeah i think they're one of the most
persistent insects pests have to deal
with um
just based on my experience working with
various facilities that are battling it
and really like you mentioned in a lot
of cases it just comes to maintaining
them
at a threshold that's below
you know an economic an economic
threshold where it's it's low enough
that we're still getting a good harvest
we're getting the yields we want and and
the plant stress isn't necessarily
too high
but it is really hard to get rid of
especially in facilities where we're
reusing media and things like that um
it's a tough one so
it's good to know that there's some
options there
yeah yeah and actually i mean
the
root aphids um can be controlled with
some
pesticide trenches as well it's just
and um
they can actually be relatively
effective it's just not clear to me that
how many of these products are going to
be registered by your state
so some people will make off-label
applications obviously we don't
recommend that but
um
but there are and so bovaria is
definitely one that most cannabis
growers can't use i mentioned that one
too
um but things like mainspring and
endeavor
can also be somewhat effective it's just
not always clear to me if that they're
going to be registered for you by your
state so
um you have to look at that but uh i've
certainly seen those things being being
used as well as trenches but yeah your
point is once once they're established
they're they're hard
to get rid of if you can get in there
early
um
you may be able to eradicate them from
your facility but uh
once they're fairly as well established
that community that becomes quite hard
one other thing you touched on was with
bavaria and i've been having longer
conversations with suzanne
and
she's been sharing information with me
from some you know larger companies
that do
pathology and things like that and they
found with
that there's various
commercially available bavaria and and
some of the products on the market um
may not contain
a spore level that's that's high enough
to actually get suppression
um so you want to buy a reputable source
botanica is a great product for example
but there's other ones on there that may
not be as as effective or she mentioned
there may be a product on the market
where the spore count
is
is higher than could physically fit by
volume in the container so
um
it's a little you know the world of
microbials uh and biostimulants is a
little bit unregulated still at the
moment um so you you want to make sure
you go on the reputable source there on
the bavaria but it is something that
works really well for
dealing with root aphids too so
just just a little tidbit i've been
learning about lately um
let's let's talk about uh what you're
most excited about in biocontrols and
some of the new stuff that you're seeing
all right well um
you know it's it's a fascinating
industry there's a lot of changes going
on
um
you know where i see that where i see
the biggest
adoption
um and growth in the bike control market
is is definitely outdoors
typically it was very much a high value
kind of greenhouse commodity
you know cannabis is its own
of course came along with very few
pesticides and and it's been a big
adopter of bio controls and still is
um
but where i spend most of my attention
these days is um on the field ag side of
things
um how can we use some of these
beneficials outdoor for
food crop production you know in areas
where they really haven't been used
before at least when it comes to putting
them on naturally because they occur
naturally but
in terms of actually manipulating them
and putting them out so that's really
exciting um
there's a couple of things that i think
driving that one driving that difference
one is the greater availability of fire
control agents and
more species available and the costs
because come down in some places
and then another another technique which
is open that doors is the use of
drones
there's now a few companies that
specialize in
putting out bugs by drone so growers can
hire them and they'll pay on a per acre
basis and
you can apply
biocontrol agents to a crop
you know you could treat 100 acres in a
matter of an hour or two whereas
it just wouldn't be the manpower to do
it by hand so it's opening the doors um
as i've seen that happen to a certain
extent with with phil grown cannabis and
and hemp um not so much where where i am
but out west
where there's more field grown
hemp and cannabis then i know that that
is starting to be done
um so that's exciting you know
i also see
[Music]
more and more adoption and more and more
people i think using biocontrol as well
um
not just throwing a few things on and
then spraying and hoping but actually
like having a good program and
and cannabis is you know some of the
bigger cannabis growers now are very
knowledgeable you know they they're
great they they really know what they're
doing and uh
their
insect identification skills are good
and they they understand the business so
um
so that's also exciting to see because i
think just a few years ago there was
perhaps a lot less
um understanding so i you know i credit
suzanne of course our mutual friend
suzanne she's she's been one of the
um leaders in getting good information
out there but
but yeah yeah it's been it's it's been
exciting and uh
i'm happy that our you know company has
been able to um take advantage of some
of the uh some of this industry because
of course we'll have to make a living
right
yeah and
uh you know there's very few actual
insectaries out there that are actually
producing bugs you know bio-b being one
of them and so you know there's many
there's many people
like myself that say are you know
already do or going to be like i am
distributing insects i'm not actually in
a sector i'm not rearing anything um
it's actually quite difficult to do from
everything i've learned from suzanne
about the process so
one thing to mention when people are
sourcing insects is try to get them
direct from insectary or from a
distributor that's going to ship
directly from the insectary so there's
other distributors that will receive a
larger population of insects and then
repackage them and that repackaging
while maybe convenient for smaller
growers can reduce the viability of the
insects and it's important that they
arrive hungry and alive so that you get
the effects that you want so
i just wanted to touch on that too
yeah yeah but i've seen that definitely
um
with some of the um
some of the online
sources which are very easy to find and
very easy to get bugs shipped um very
quickly
but you're right that they do sometimes
get stored for longer than they longer
than they need to and so getting dead
bugs is not uh
it does happen um
so yeah you need to have a good supply
um
and
make sure that what you're getting is
good quality and it's it's fresh and
it's alive and
um
whether you go work directly with a with
a whether with a
producer such as ourselves
um or a distributor that maybe will
dropship
so that you're still getting
material sent directly from the source
um some things store better than others
i mean um yeah but when it comes to
things like predatory mites um
uh priscilla's for example um
they they really need to be fresh you
don't want them sitting around for more
than a day or two before you use them
um so yeah that's a great that's a great
point that's a great point you know it's
important to work with someone that can
give you the information you need as
well as
a good source of
um
fresh products
yeah we've been slower on on launching
this i'm kind of going to time our
launch with this podcast but there's a
lot of challenges around it because
one it's having a staff that is
knowledgeable enough or has the
resources to get the answers to make
sure that the recommendations are
accurate
um
two it's you know having their
relationship with with like in our case
with you guys to make sure that we are
sending things directly from the
insectary we're not playing middlemen on
um receiving packages and sending them
back out um and and then the most
challenging part
is the shipping because
these things are alive they need to be
shipped overnight they can only ship out
on certain days during the week to make
sure that they arrive
in a timely fashion and then
having that information for the growers
so they make sure that they know
you know they're there to receive the
package and know how to apply it there's
just a lot of steps involved there and a
lot of the cost is shipping so you may
pay more in shipping than you made for
the insect itself so
trying to coordinate and make sure that
the website
can handle all of that has been a real
challenge
and also make sure that the process
works smoothly so that at the end of the
day the customer is getting something
that is going to
perform as as it should so
yeah yeah that's a great point i i would
say if i had to just give one general
tip
um you know the people maybe out there
that are considering using buyers um
one thing that's really helped that
really helps the process and work a lot
more smoothly
is
um
you know rather than going out scouting
on a monday finding some bugs and then
deciding what you know some pests and
then deciding on tuesday what you're
gonna put out and hoping to get them on
wednesday and then being frustrated when
you can um
if you can understand what your issues
are historically going to be in that
area or what they're likely to be
and come up with a preventative plan
that covers those but at least covers
your basic options you can add
add something down the road if necessary
but
and then work with someone like yourself
um to determine how many you need
and get that order get that on a program
you know have that ordered every week or
every other week or something based on
your your production program
and and get it get it set up in advance
you know that way
once once you have that the the risk of
delays the risk of things not being
available the risk of not being able to
get what you need when you want it is so
much less and it's just a much more
reliable program
than just kind of being reactive and
feeling on a what do i need today kind
of thing just set it up as a program to
cover you at least cover your basics
your your spider mites
your thrips if you're going to have them
in the area your fungus mats you know
cover your basics and and uh set it up
as a program that's just so much easier
for everyone
when it comes to shipping
that that's a really really great point
and um one of the things suzanne and i
discussed too
was to have an option for growers that i
was actually gonna i was gonna talk to
you about uh was to set up a
a maintenance
uh option that's maybe a combination of
a few different bio controls that would
be set up by square footage so that a
customer could go on the website and say
i have
a hundred square feet or a thousand
square feet and then have a given rate
or package that we could then recommend
based off of that for
you know this preventative maintenance
sort of uh application
right right and you could potentially
have a ship a central point of being
shipped
you know you could have everything sort
of shipped as one order and then
distributed um amongst the various
customers potentially
you know and that would that would be a
cheaper way to so you're not shipping
lots of little boxes you're shipping
smaller number of larger boxes
yeah well my thought was you know for a
given
let's say just a facility or a given
grow would be to have a combination of a
few different insects that i would know
fit in a certain size box um so then i
could have the website calculate
accurately so someone could check out by
square footage for example and not
necessarily have to worry about having
to
figure out exactly what they need
because we could give them at least a
good starting
preventive program for people who want
to start using bio controls that maybe
had a problem and now we're starting a
new run
and they know that you know they're
potentially going to
see you know they have historical
historically had to deal with say
two-spotted or threats or whatever and
we can come up with a sort of a program
like that they can put out that would be
a little bit more of a generalist
program
yeah i know that's a great that's a
great idea todd i think we can we can do
that for you definitely awesome
sorry i kind of dropped out on the in
the middle of a podcast for you so i'm
excited uh
to do that and i i actually talked to
suzanne about it and she's like
talk to steven and then she'll give her
a thumb of approval and we'll get that
out on the website
awesome um
so last thing if you have time i
wanted to just really quickly
touch on your feed because you mentioned
you mentioned it briefly and i think
it's really interesting
that you guys have some ways to feed the
insects the beneficial insects that
you know people may already have
bought or may have naturalized in their
area how would we incorporate that into
a program
right so
one thing i like to do is
for example
when we supply swarovski i like to
recommend the swarovski
version that contains food already
simply because i've seen you know it it
just lasts better on the crop it's um
it's uh
you're providing a food source at the
time they're put out you don't need to
mix anything it's very straightforward
so that that would be like an easy way
to do it
um
and it can also that can work with
aureus as as well as cucumeris as well
so that that's really the simplest way
to do it there are other feed products
as well on the market people can
experiment with but um
i think you know
people don't want to do anything that's
necessarily more complicated if you can
just get a different bottle that
contains what
a food source in it
um
and you're working with a crop that's
pretty clean so you you don't have a
whole lot of pests for your beneficials
to feed on then i find that just makes
sense you know it's just it's not a huge
cost increase
um and i've just seen the results in the
field work work so much better
so if i had if i had a small grow i
could order
the
you know the insects i need whether
that's you know swerve geek commerce the
lacewing aureus and then
get this uh bioware feed at the same
time
save on this you know massive shipping
cost and maybe keep them alive a little
longer by shaking out some of the uh
direct directly applying the feed
you know to the leaf surface so to keep
the plant to keep the insects alive a
little longer i guess is what i'm
getting at extending the tree between
orders
right right absolutely so yes you can
just buy the feed by itself and apply
some to the crop when you when you're um
applying
um if you're using a blower you can just
add it to the mix that you're blowing
out assuming of what you're blowing out
was compatible with the feed um
so those are two ways to do it and
you know i i would definitely i might
not necessarily do that in in flour
because of you know risky contamination
but definitely in veg um
if you're using if you're putting out
predatory mites and lacewings and aureus
and things like that in veg
add a few dollars and put some of this
feed in it really it makes a big
difference to
the length of time that your buyers can
survive and how effective they'll be
so i've really i've already seen it it
worked very very effectively in that
situation
awesome well i i really appreciate your
time today we've already
gone longer because this was sort of a
complicated podcast so i really
appreciate your time
uh was there anything else you wanted to
add before we uh sign off
um
no if anyone out there is interested um
uh you can go to
www.iob.us and we have a quite a lot of
information on our website now new
information
um about products and different
application strategies so by all means
check that out and um
you can also um
you can also reach me at steven.arthurs
at buyerbee.us
if you need to
and
but no i enjoyed it dad it was great and
i'm really glad that we're connected and
i appreciate your i checked out your
podcast it's really good so i'm very
happy to be on it so thank you for your
time well thank you i really look
forward to working more closely with
biob
in the coming coming days and months and
uh being an opportunity to provide you
know more of these high quality insects
directly to our customers so
thanks again have a wonderful rest of
your week
thank you tad you too take care okay
bye
[Music]
that was steven arthurs with biobee and
you are listening to the cannabis
cultivation and science podcast i'm your
host tadd hussey if you like the podcast
please leave us a rating in review and
give us a follow on instagram you can
also sign up for our newsletter on our
website homepage to stay up to date on
the latest research and information
thanks for listening