[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host tad hussy
of KISS organics this is the podcast
where we discuss the cutting edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and draw on top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge the bio controllers conference
from last podcast was a lot of fun and I
met some great growers who attended the
cannabis track I hope to see more folks
of future bough controls conferences and
was grateful for the opportunity to
speak on how to evaluate commercial
products when making production
decisions this week's podcast relates to
soil testing a lot of growers and
cannabis consultants use soil tests to
make fertility decisions for this crop
what I learned in the last two weeks
really changed the way I view these
tests and my conversation with our next
guests will hopefully explain in better
detail how these tests work what
information on them is most useful and
what we should be basing our production
decisions on this week's guest is Bill
McKibben bill is an accomplished
agronomist and author of two books
relating to soils the art of balancing
soil nutrients and the growers guide to
balancing soil nutrients he has been
consulting on soil fertility since 1976
and graduated in 1975 from the Ohio
State University with a master's of
science and soil chemistry he is a
consultant to Logan labs and the owner
of soil take tech incorporated I've
talked to Bill in the past regarding
soil testing but this latest
conversation we focused on potting soils
or highly amended soils with many of us
in this industry call super soil or
living soil
hi bill welcome to the show oh thank you
good afternoon I appreciate you coming
on today I wanted to give listeners a
little background into how I ended up
chatting with you we've we've actually
talked we talked quite a few years back
but this time around
Michael over at Maine crafts cannabis
he's a good friend of mine we were
chatting and he had called and talked to
Susan the lab director at Logan labs and
he called me up and he's like hey tad I
was talking to Susan and she was saying
that some of these numbers on the mail
ik 3 test which is your standard soil
test are not very usable when we're
doing these soil evaluations and so they
I had a I had a conversation with her
about you know how much they're using in
a sample about the you know exchange
capacity and what these numbers look
like and what they mean when we're
talking about potting soils versus you
know native soils or agricultural soils
and so bill I just wanted to kind of
talk about you know a little bit about
what what some of these numbers mean on
a soil report and for listeners I'm
gonna have a am a lick three and a
saturated paste of our commercial
growers mix on the podcast page so
please go check that out and that's what
bill and I are going to be working off
of when we're talking about different
numbers so that we're all on the same
page for looking at the same test so
bill can you talk a little bit about the
Mallik 3 test and what that what they're
actually testing and how much material
they're using and and just a little bit
about that process before we will start
looking at numbers sure sure
I am big I don't really work at Logan
labs I'm the agronomist to Logan labs
but I'm pretty familiar with whatever
they whatever they're doing down there
and Susan and I talk almost daily so you
know the melech 3 and we've had this
discussion that really really the melech
3 is designed for soil
soil extraction not so much the these
modified mixes I call them MGM's
modified growing mix as some people call
them soilless mix
I know I've talked to people on the
phone that said when I said soilless mix
no no it's a soil well if it's if it's
modified with all this peat and
everything core fiber it's really not a
a soil especially once you get these
organic matters up to above 25-30
percent
this test was really not designed for
that kind of material
so the
Melek extraction is a pH of 2.5 so it is
fairly acidic and in these these
modified mixes where you're adding lime
it can it can dissolve that that lime
and make it look like you've got a lot
more material a lot more calcium on the
standard test and maybe what's really
available
yes that's a good point and one thing I
want to highlight regarding these tests
as well that you brought up is the
original goal of these tests was to
admit you know you're using soil so sand
silt and clay we're looking at the
amount of
the fractions of these of these
different types of soils and so it's
very different like you mentioned
however sort of the the colloquial trade
term for a lot of the soils and what we
make is called they're a lot of people
are calling them living soils now but
you're right they're soilless mixes so a
living soil
by this industry cannabis standard is
really what a lot people are calling
super soils and it's like a heavily
amended soilless mix that is then reused
multiple cycles so I just want to make
sure we're all on the same terms in
terms of like nomenclature here but
and one of one of the things I like to
point out when you mentioned the sand
silt and clay and that's really what the
melech extraction was designed to do was
to remove
nutrients off of the colloids now really
really these these modified mixes
don't have a lot of colloids it's
basically a bunch of minerals that's
floating around in an organic substrate
and so that's that again poses a problem
for the some of the data
yeah and I want to come back to that
when we start talking about exchange
capacity but one question that I was
wondering about regarding these tests
when you talk about these these peat
mixes or cocoa mixes is all of these
things have a purported cation exchange
of value like I can go online and look
up you know an average compost or an
average peat mix how does that translate
when we're talking about these may like
three tests
well see this is where we're I think
it's a little bit fuzzy you know they
they say that when you when you look at
a soil and you say well the the organic
matter is contributing to the exchange
capacity
you know that's really it's more of a
human that's contributing to the
exchange capacity I think then then just
the fact that it's organic matter and
so you know I'm sure some people might
disagree with that but that that's kind
of the way I look at it again it's I
know that when we look at these organic
matters in these these modified mixes
and then and then the calculation is
done for en are the estimated estimated
nitrogen release
those numbers very dependable and again
so I think that
that
you know they might be able to say that
there there's some
exchange capacity there but I think it's
very minimal
so you're another impression that these
things don't actually have the exchange
capacity that is purported to them you
know when you start looking online
which is interesting
the other the other question around
around this would be if if that is the
case then what's keeping these so so
essentially when you talk about you're
talking about organic matter houmous and
things breaking down well houmous is one
of the most controversial things in the
soil science field anyway but
essentially the concept being that
organic matter is is slowly breaking
down all the time you know it's
essentially composting and this organic
matter is breaking down into something
that eventually is undistinguishable you
can't tell if that original organic
matter was plant matter a human foot you
know whatever sort of organic matter you
want to think of it's now virtually
indistinguishable on a microscopic level
and it has this
excellent you know
biological you know capacity and also
excellent cation exchange capacity or
ability to hold onto nutrients when
we're talking about human so you know in
theory this the higher your organic
matter the more its breaking down and
the more your you're building houmous
over time and traditionally this takes a
long time that there's a lot of
speculation on that does that sound does
that sound about right or do you have
more that you'd want to add regarding it
yeah that sounds about right and I think
when you look at if you're looking at it
on some sort of time scale the if you're
taking a peat in there versus a human
that's developed in the soil there's a
huge difference in the time scale now
maybe I shouldn't say that
that there's no exchange capacity on a
peat but I think it gets as it continues
to break down and and actually it's
going to now make the organic matter
kind of more concentrated or well get to
the point where it is not going to break
down any further that's when it I think
it has the maximum amount of nutrient
holding capacity
that makes sense now peat is interesting
because it is harvested and it is
traditionally something that's already
you know fairly old relatively speaking
it's already organic matter that's been
breaking down in these bogs for a period
of time and there's a lot of speculation
too about how sustainable it is and how
long it takes for PETA is a
is a whole nother topic but yeah you
know compared to like cocoa core which
is a relatively fresh material relative
to Pete it certainly seems like Pete
would would be breaking down towards
humans or be more a much more stable
component when we talk about its humic
fraction relative to cocoa well I think
that that's a fair fair comparison there
but but I've seen Pete's where you can
actually see the sticks that are still
in there and so I mean I think the
quality of Pete there's a whole scale of
quality on Pete
that's that's a really good point yeah
not all Pete is the same though I will
say one thing that Tim Wilson discovered
was that Pete is not necessarily sterile
either like a lot of people assume it to
be when you throw it out of the
microscope there's quite a bit of
biological activity going on in there
which from an or gate perspective is is
great
now before we dive into the TEC too much
one thing I wanted to touch on is you
mentioned free calcium so for example
when I mix my soil I'm putting in
agricultural lime it's a fairly fine
mesh or grind so it's almost like flour
and in theory if that's not been cycled
yet by the microbes it could really skew
these tests or show up as free calcium
and so what we have we took what
typically what growers do when they have
Callister whistles is they'll do a fizz
test with vinegar and then they make it
the AAA 8.2 can you talk a little bit
about that test and how that's more
accurate in regards to calcium before we
get into the exchange capacity stuff
well you know this is where you and I
probably will separate company here on
this a bit the you know I'm not a big
fan of the adjusting the the melon or
the ammonium acetate 28.2 only because
it's it's
it's basically at 8.2 8.3 is when when
calcium carbonate stops dissociating so
so what you're doing at 8 to 8 3 pH
extraction you're basically looking at
what is what is what calcium in there
that is not calcium carbonate and
I I'm not saying that that for some
people that might not be good
information but for me I'm not I'm not
concerned that much with what is not
calcium carbonate I think that'll show
up things like calcium chloride calcium
gypsum z' those type of things but it's
going to it's going to leave the calcium
calcium carbonate on the table - is a
huge factor here but again at 8.2 it
should just be taking out calcium
showing up calcium that is not calcium
carbonate the the other thing is when I
look at the 8.2
that is we're going to use it you use it
for I would think for just pure calcium
because I think it really underestimates
magnesium and potassium
totally interesting ok so I'm not saying
that there isn't some value in it but
for me as a consultant I'm not a I'm not
a real big fan of using that if you find
that wow I really get some benefit from
it then that's fine you can't argue with
success but I I'm I would just soon do
the Malick and the paste analysis and
make my make my judgments from those
so how do you know then if you're not
getting over-reported calcium values on
the on the mailing test on the standard
soil test well I think I think when you
run the Malick it's going to desert
that's good unless you've got so much
calcium in there that it neutralizes the
Malick extraction
solution
which is which is going to be really
really high
you're going to you're going to dissolve
that calcium and that's going to is
going to show up as a as part of the
shays capacity
so I mean but but then again you know my
my concept of these modify growing media
is I've got these nutrients in there
floating in the in the organic substrate
so now the question is okay I can look
and I can tell you with the with the
malloc that the calcium
the calcium we have in here is
potentially available but then I rely on
the pace to say do I have enough sitting
out here in solution
that that will feed the plant and we're
looking for sufficiency values on the
pace test
looking for sufficiency levels
yes yes I'm looking at
sufficiency I'd like to see a balance in
the paste but I also want to see certain
sufficiency levels
okay well let's let's save the page
saturated paste I do want to talk about
that but let's can we talk a little bit
more about the the male ik test so the
standard soil test in regards to how the
lab processes it so I was not aware
until it was brought to my attention
that for the the male ik test they're
really only using two milligrams of
material I'm sorry to two milliliters of
material volume is that correct I think
they're using a five mil coop it's a
five million now okay but a relatively
small amount when we're talking about a
potting soil that's that's probably not
homogeneously mixed so I don't know how
you can make a recommendation across you
know 50 yards of soil off of five
milliliters in theory
yeah that that's the inherent problem in
trying to run a soil test
went on on a modified mix and
at the point at this point in time I
don't know how you get around it
because what happens is when you
dissolve that calcium it's it's it's now
picked up in the extracting solution run
through the through the ICP and it shows
you may be in a much higher Tec because
of the calcium that it dissolved
so let's let's talk about the exchange
capacity because a lot of the numbers on
this test are based off of
essentially that whatever that reported
exchange capacity is but what I'm
hearing from the lab director Susan and
then from you too is that that exchange
capacity is not a number that we can
trust
that's not that it's not that's true
that's true I could I could well
only don't want to stay quite that one I
want to hold that because I think that
exchange capacity when you're looking at
modified mixes our I would not use it as
to determine desired values see I think
I think when you take the desired values
off of these things because that's where
the exchange capacity is used to
determine desired values the values
found that's just reported what it's
found but the desired value that comes
in here
that's based on the exchange capacity
and setting these mixes up at 68 percent
calcium 12% base saturation and
magnesium and four percent potassium
so it if you if you don't if you have to
have desired values well then you better
better beware that those can be over
exaggerated but I would I would like to
say that the exchange capacity I think
probably be best if we would use that
like we would at NC number in other
words I think someplace between maybe 10
and 16
exchange capacity you get you get much
above that 16 exchange capacity
you're setting yourself up for some
salts problems
okay well I and that's that's
interesting because I you know we've
seen that you and I talked about this
how there's quite a bit of
variation that you've seen on these
tests and I've seen and I've seen some
pretty high salt levels that still are
very productive soils cannabis soils and
and vegetable soils because we do have
some growers using our souls and
vegetables and that's something I want
to talk about definitely but in terms of
this idea of using you know essentially
a teaspoon of material as our basis for
a soil test and then taking that
teaspoon and then calculating out an
exchange capacity that really doesn't
represent it
because there's a lot of consultants out
there making recommendations off of
these
using that exchange capacity and using
these numbers and then there's a lot of
growers honestly using these tests and
saying that you know making their soil
decisions based off of these tests and
they're balancing you know how much just
in a broad sweep do you feel like this
is a tool that you use in evaluating a
soil so obviously there's you know the
physical properties of the soil there's
the biological properties there's the
chemical when we talk about nutrient
values where do you think the soil tests
fall in terms of like how much can you
really trust them when you when you're
making decisions about a soil mix like
this on a modified mix I don't think you
can and I don't I don't really think
that I think that in a modified mix all
the desired values should be pulled off
that you should set your own own
sufficiency levels for these mixes okay
and and and not and not try to have them
set up
on a base a duration like you would a
standard soil I mean when you when you
look at these and you're right I mean
there's there's there can be some big
variability
but even if you go to a bigger scoop I'm
not sure that's going to solve the
problem it's just it's just an inherent
problem with it with the test if you've
got a lot of chunk material in there and
some people say why don't you grind
those samples well then you're going to
grind some of those minerals out and
make them more available too so
you know I think the thing to do is to
realize that the TECs are not correct
I'm like I'm going to continue to use
them as an easy number but I think you
should you should set up
sufficiency levels of your calcium your
magnesium and and go with those numbers
and not try to try to let the
let these desired values determine how
you're going to fertilize
but because I tip I we see if you go to
for potassium you know if you get you
get up there much over 4% I see a lot of
potassium does not hold on to the
organic traction at all I mean you just
it just it just seems to pass right into
solubility for the most part so I mean
you get up there much about 4% then we
start seeing a lot of potassium in the
pace test yeah that's interesting so how
do you feel about trusting the base
saturation percentages as part of this
test
well I wouldn't I wouldn't be you know
I'm not looking at those all that much
because the on setting desired values so
I mean specific setting specific values
that I want using using more of a slant
approach than an Albrecht balanced
okay so you're saying I want to see this
ppm for sulfur phosphorus calcium and
you've kind of set those values that way
you think is optimal for a particular
problem right right and then then I by
looking and looking at those and say
okay well at least I have those showing
up in the mix and then then turn around
look at the pace and see well are they
are they moving into solution so you
know it's a combination of things not
just I think if you if you use this soil
test or any any soil test like this
on a modified mix without using a paste
it's a crapshoot
so I've been doing this now for five or
six years trying to better understand
these soil tests and all admit I have a
lot to learn and it sounds like a lot of
what I was understanding around them was
frankly incorrect so this has been
really eye-opening for me in the last
couple weeks but I've what I've always
struggled with using these the the the
values found in terms of exchangeable
cations and so I've just been looking at
base I've been skipping straight to base
saturation percentages and what the
trend I've seen is that when for example
you mentioned potassium when I see
potassium dropped below 5% I get grower
reported
you know smaller buds and what appears
to be potassium deficiencies and one
that one other trend I noticed which
makes a lot of sense because these are
fairly weak
ions they move through the soil faster
as potassium and nitrogen seemed to be
used up by the plant or by people's
watering habits you know much faster
than any of the the other nutrients in
the soil and so typically when i
reinvent i find i'm not adding like this
mix right here that we're looking at
i'll find that the the calcium and
magnesium values will still stay fairly
similar to where they are now but my my
potassium levels will drop quite a bit
as well as my nitrogen levels even with
people that are watering with no
literally no runoff so those are the
things that I've been kind of keyed to
looking at these tests but I'd be
curious what your thoughts are on that
cool yeah I think no 8% that seems that
seems high to me
the cut but then again when you look at
these numbers you do have to look at
them in comparison to each other so I
mean when you're looking at this test
that we're looking at right now I mean
we found almost 2200 pounds of calcium
which is a which is a double charge
against the 500 pounds of
potassium so you know there there is
something to be said for the balance the
question might be well or do we have too
much calcium in there that that's
blocking potassium uptake
I'm not sure
and you know is it I just I see the you
know soluble salts thing that you you've
said you've seen some really good
results with salts you know up to 2000
and
that
that's kind of intriguing to me so but
yeah I think I think you have to look at
some some some relationships here but
are we are we just too high and one and
and when you look at potassium again
it's not held in its moves into solution
pretty quick and certainly potassium is
one of those nutrients that tends to be
get tends to be luxury consumed so
you know I'm like you I there's a lot to
learn on this thing and especially when
when you're coming from a soil to it to
a soilless mix
nutrient relationships is even more
critical because there's no stability in
the mix
so when you talk about nutrient
relationships you know you're talking
about essentially mineral balancing
which was founded by started by William
Albrecht as far as I know and then a lot
of people have gone off and come up with
different you know slightly different
bass saturation percentages but looking
at the relationship between all these
minerals and frankly for me the
confusing part like when we talk about
that like Albrecht loves a 68 12
relationship between calcium and
magnesium that was sort of his level if
I remember correctly but some people
like tensions have gone upwards of 90% I
believe and then people like Arden
Anderson will say you can't get enough
gypsum in the soil it seems like so
they're all for a lot of calcium you
know that's the big driver when we talk
about agricultural soils I mean what are
your thoughts on that well
I think I think the the actual numbers
that Albrecht settled on was 65 and 15
and then there was there was some later
research that that that said well you
could go to 70 and 10 and and then 68
and 12 came up but
you know I
those getting into that perspective
there I think is what what you have to
look at not necessarily
is it 65 hours at 68 you know that's
that's you're trying to split hairs
there but the other thing is when you
when you look at this soil and and you
see that it's a Maalik extraction and
it's and it's dissolved stuff
that's not
it's it's I mean them I don't I want to
say that
you know it's been dissolved but it
doesn't necessarily mean that it is
plant available at that at that point in
time so so looking again looking at the
whole test on a modified mix you
must be really careful I
don't know however I'll better to talk
to say it but no I think that's good for
me what I try and tell people is the
soil test is sort of it's a tool just
like a rake or a shovel or any or a
tractor or anything else you might have
in your repertoire but ultimately we're
not going for the perfect soil test
we're going for plant health and plant
plant growth your yield so at the end of
the day that's our metric it's not it's
not a soil test it's you know how is our
plant look and what are we yielding off
of this crop that's really what matters
yes and and that's why I say is the
taste test becomes the main tool here
because that is that's a water
extractable solution and that's what the
plants are see
so could we talk a little bit about the
pay's test can you talk about what how a
pastis is is processed by the lab what
they're doing and then what what these
numbers kind of kind of mean yeah they
they tend they take the the sample that
you have and I believe they're used in
some place between two and four hundred
I think the lab uses two hundred but
some of the original research would use
four hundred grams but
again we're also striving for
consistency and so as long as you it can
stay consistent so but so the lab takes
200 grams versus maybe five grams that
they would use for melech
so they'll take that 200 grams they they
bring that up to kind of a patent
pancake batter can
and they leave that set for 24 hours
then they vacuum that water off and then
run it through the ICP
just like they've run the extracting
solution on the Malick so so once that
soil has set for 24 hours they vacuum
off and then then we're getting that's
how we're getting the data here for the
for the pace test now soluble salts
they'll use a meter in the in the mix
before it's vacuumed off and
and then they'll measure measure the by
carbs and the chlorides in there too so
it's the data it collected it's pretty
much the same as on on the standard test
with the exception of bicarb soluble
salts and chlorides
but it's it's an all water soluble
situation so and when you when you look
at some of the data I think it was
Barbara and Olson
where they're showing that most of the
nutrient uptake with the exception of
copper and about 50% of the iron is is
taken up by by mass flow and diffusion
that is
nutrients in solution so the concept
here is that the pace saturated pace
test is it's essentially they're taking
the soil putting it in water that's
really neutral and then just whatever
seeps out essentially into solution is
is what shows up on the test and that is
in theory what is plant available
yeah so it's it's not it's not a strong
extraction like we had with the standard
which is an acid that's going to pull
more nutrients out but really just
what's what's available to the plant in
theory that that's the correlation
they're going for correct right and
you're if you're looking at the the DI
waters what's what's typically used and
it's right there close to seven you know
you look at rainwater today it's about
six six
I've tested it at
certainly a
lot higher than what it used to be and
so when you're looking at the DI water
extraction it's very similar to what you
would get with rain water and
but we've also used we've had people use
their their water as the extracting
solution so you know you can go to
different ways to lab we'll take your
water and use it as the extracting
solution
that's that's really interesting because
that's gonna obviously give you
different values and I think it's
important that people test their water I
just want to highlight that because a
lot of times I'll see buildup of certain
things and a lot like this usually it's
the pH will continue to rise or sodium
or calcium will continue to rise and a
lot of it is tied back to their water
when we start talking about successive
cycles in this type of media so I just
want to encourage listeners again to to
please test their water it's not that
expensive and those values are really
that's really valuable information
yeah let me say one thing about the
waters I know you didn't that's not
exactly what we wanted to do today but
one of the things that you can look at a
water test and you can say based on the
parameters that are out there is they'll
say well that's a pretty good water
but as a as a soil guy I want to know
what the effect of that water
accumulation of nutrients will be on
that soil after four or five irrigation
cycles and when you look at the balance
of the of the nutrients in the water
after four or five irrigation cycles
there's a lot of times it will start to
look your pace test will start to look
more like the water test at it than it
did originally so
what about you know I know we weren't
talking about water but I think this is
important we've had a lot of people
having good success by pH pH Inge their
watered down to sixty five I know
Michael at main craft cannabis claims
that he got you and better growth by
going down to five five with his water
using phosphoric acid instead of citric
acid do you have any thoughts regarding
you know pH in your water like this no I
think I think he's probably I think when
you get I think you're getting down to
the bottom
well at five five is certainly in a
modified mix where you're not looking at
maybe the
biological activity like you would in a
soil I think when you start getting down
to five five in a in a standard soil I
think you start shifting the biology
maybe
in the refraction but I certainly have I
see better better availability at five
eight two six two on on the PHS
than I do even at six eight
see it's funny because most of our soils
six eight is probably the lowest I've
seen we tend to be a little bit higher
even though we're using a lot of peat
moss and due to the amount of nutrients
you know cations and alkaline alkaline
amendments that we're using because
we're using biochar which is fairly
alkaline
we're using you know compost we're
adding in a lot of cations and nutrients
so our souls to run more with more
alkaline than acidic and yet they seem
to perform pretty well when we talk
about you know plant growth and plant
health the plant a lot of organic
growers say you know you can throw away
your pH pen or your pH meter which I
don't agree with and I do see results it
does appear to that we're getting better
results by pH in the water down but the
research I read is that you really can't
impact your overall you know media pH
all that dramatically by
by watering especially with something
like citric acid that's such a weak has
such weak buffering capacity like how
what's the what do you think the ability
of the water is to really lower your pH
over time in your in your soilless media
well I think I think Lauren at pH down
to that six five five or six two or
wherever you want it
basically what you're trying to do is
you're mainly getting rid of bicarbonate
your burning off bicarbonate so which
has a huge impact on calcium and then as
soils dry down it will precipitate out
calcium and then that will precipitate
that washer so you get that domino
effect but the the other thing about pH
is when you look at at some of these
mixes and let's just take a take a look
at the one here we got in front of us
the pH is 6.8
well when when we're measuring pH what
are we measuring we're measuring
hydrogen and so when you start having
these salts up here this high that tends
to block the amount of hydrogen ions
that can get to that to that sensor
so you're tending to dilute hydrogen the
height you can have you could still have
the same amount of hydrogen ions but
because of the higher salts content in
the water it tends to block that
hydrogen through that through the the
meter and you know salts typically
they're supposed to be pH neutral so you
put a put a potassium chloride or
potassium sulfate those that's a strong
acid strong base they're not really
supposed to change the pH and they
probably won't change the hydrogen ion
concentrations but I'm telling you that
that we will see increases in the pH
just because of salts concentration
so how concerning is that when we see a
pH that's you know above 7 or you know
this is where you're getting a little
out of my to a comfort comfort zone here
when you start talking about this
testing method so are you saying that
this pH number may or may not be
completely accurate
I'm saying it can be if you could
actually have it could be masked a
little bit by the salt concentration yes
so it could be in theory lower than it
actually shows on the test yeah higher
lower okay that makes more sense to me
because you get a ph availability chart
and i'll try and put one up on the
podcast page as well and you can see
that a lot of the nutrients that we want
for plant health are more available at
lower PHS and we want to be careful
there too because we start getting too
low and we're gonna get into territory
where some of these heavy metals or more
easily uptake in and that can get
dangerous for people in regards to the
passing heavy-metal testing with their
soil mixes but the ranges we're talkin
are plenty high for aluminum and things
but
that's really that's really really
interesting so
this pH number may not what you're
saying is it may report on these tests
higher than it is in reality yeah
because of the salts because of the
salts now the other thing is when you
look at a pH chart like you were talking
about
remember that that is a static
environment
so you can look at if you look at one of
those you look at a calcium on
pH at five and you say oh my calcium is
not very available but I can show you
solubility tests that there's plenty of
calcium available
what what those pH tests are saying that
if you're looking at a regular soil and
you've got a
this is a soil that's not that hasn't
been modified or changed very much if
you got a pH of five the odds are very
good that you the calcium has been
leached out of it
sure but that makes sense so so those
when you look at those charts remember
that is a that is look trying to say if
this soil is is a virgin soil at pH 7
well the odds are there's more calcium
or more magnesium or potassium there's
more cations there but
that doesn't necessarily mean just
because you have a pH of
5 5 or 5 9 that you don't have enough
calcium well when we used to look at
rain water that was pH 5 5 we saw when
we got a rain we got a real bump in the
in the crop response now at six six we
don't so
those those pH charts are great but
there that that is a
static
static environment that that you have to
look at in perspective on those
so my takeaway would be from this is
that when we look at these numbers - the
other thing to consider is our soil is
not just this nutrient solution there
are all these different micro pores of
aerobic and anaerobic activity we know
that just from the biology we're seeing
the pH is not the same across all of
these areas you have a lot of different
interactions going on frankly most of
them we don't fully understand but
there's a lot of like
biological pockets that are gonna impact
and change the pH right there in there
in that area and so this just gives us a
general I think idea of where we're at
but not really like you said it's it's
not it doesn't mean that certain
nutrients are going to be completely
unavailable and you can't totally use
that chart it sounds like as a way of
evaluating a soil right right
so I mean just just because you have a
pH of 775 you say oh I'm not gonna have
any phosphorus availability know if that
pH is 75 because of sodium or potassium
both potassium phosphate and sodium
phosphate are
very soluble so I mean it's the factor
that's causing that pH to be high I mean
calcium there when you talk about some
guys modifying their water with
phosphoric acid if you got much calcium
in there that's gonna be a problem
because you're gonna precipitate that
out
so
why would that necessarily be a bad
thing if the calcium precipitates if we
have
too much of it
because I did that one time and we had a
well water that we put phosphoric acid
in and with the drip irrigation it got
the nozzles
okay okay so that's the issue with
precipitation is yeah they could clog
irrigation are there any other issues in
terms of the soil itself
over time no what man no I I don't I
don't think so it is once you start if
you overdo it and you get too much
phosphorus in there that you know
phosphorus really ties up zinc so that
that can be an issue
can we look at the saturated pace test a
little bit closer and can you talk so
we've talked a little bit about salt
soluble salts but I think those three
things are really confusing to to
growers in general and when we talk
about soluble salts chloride and
bicarbonate those those three numbers
right there can you talk a little bit
about what those are and how to kind of
evaluate them in your eyes well soluble
salts when I talk to a lot of people
they're saying well I don't think my
sodium is that high sir if the salt is
all the cations and anions combination
so that's you know that's ammonia that's
nitrate that
sulfur calcium magnesium potassium
phosphorus all those things are thrown
into the soluble salts and so
you know it's what happens is when the
soluble salts get too high then it it
causes the plants to have to expend
energy they better have better
phosphorous numbers if the salts are
high because that plant has to expend
energy to pull water in where the
tendency is if the concentration of
salts are higher on the outside of the
root then it wants to pull freshwater
back away from the roots so
and plants in general they have a wide
range in which they can operate in the
in the salts so I mean I look at it I
really don't like to have salts over
over 1200 but you're you're saying that
you're very successful at that well I'm
not going to disagree that you may it's
just
I'm not sure I mean I look at these
numbers here and I think you know to me
these numbers are on the high side but
you're successful at that and and so
well I think one of the other things too
and we're talking about soluble salts
and I've had guys I've seen numbers
3,000 4,000 5,000 on these that they
claim they still have good healthy
plants but what what I would say is like
you mentioned regarding water we're
talking about pretty intensive cropping
so typically there's co2 supplementation
very high light intensity so there's a
lot of nutrient uptake going on and then
the big thing there like you mentioned
with water is irrigation so using an
irrigation system that keeps water
levels fairly high relative to what you
would see traditionally outside you know
to where they're either continually
receiving water like using these blue
mat systems that we use or people are
watering every two to three days to keep
that soil evenly moist I feel like the
the combination of high nutrient uptake
and biological activity kind of offsets
some of these soluble salt levels I mean
what do you think about that no I think
you're I think you're exactly right
salts become a problem when when the
soils tend to dry down and and so
because the salt concentration gets
higher as the soils dry down so this
this 1600 if you'd let it go dry might
might go up to
3,000 okay but so keeping keeping your
you know in the water you're injecting
into this thing is you know maybe it's
got a soluble salts of two or three
hundred so you know you're running that
dilution down all the time you're adding
water but if you let if you let it go
dry then then the concentration really
gets to be a problem
well and the peat the pizza hydrophobic
anyway that causes an issue with a lot
of these potting soils too so yeah it's
a lose-lose when we talk about letting
these soils dry out I think that's a
good but I will also tell you that I
think that you can get your salts
numbers to low I mean this salts are
going to be an indication of nutrient
concentration so if your salts get down
there probably and 500 or 400 you might
not have enough nutrients in solution
that's a really good point yeah and I
think too the other thing to keep in
mind is with these soils the original
concept was that we were doing a
one-time fertigation right at the
beginning when we mix these soils so
that people could literally just water
their plant not continually adding
nutrients so we have to have higher salt
levels you know there's we could we
could debate about whether or not this
is too much or what a maximum amount of
you know soluble nutrients you or
soluble salt levels is appropriate in a
potting soil but it's you know if you're
trying to go a full cycle they are gonna
have to be higher than say someone who's
applying fertilizer you know every
watering or weekly or whatever
application schedule
exactly and I think I think
in virtually all these cases that you're
dealing with or with the cannabis those
are all transplants
that you're putting in there starting
seeds in these kind of salt levels could
be a real problem I
totally agree with you I have people
that start seeds in these soils but it's
not what I would typically recommend I
it seems to work okay they claim but
again I that doesn't make sense to my
brain either I I would agree with you on
that yeah and again some of those
depending on the seeds you know I think
cucumbers or something like that they're
you know they're not gonna take they're
not gonna take high salts like
maybe a tomato will or something I
there's a real variability on the seeds
and I I would have to right I'm like I
can't tell you that exactly what it is
right now but I do that very
significantly can you talk a little
about chloride next
role in here because I that's something
I'm not very strong on so I would love a
little education on on this well you
know now we got about two people that
aren't very strong on chloride I you
know I think that can be a
chloride certainly has a toxicity a
lower toxicity level
much the same maybe it's boron so you
know it's a matter trying to keep that
chlorides chlorides down because the
toxicity where's that toxicity at that's
a good question because of all these
other things that that's entering here
but you know it might be it might be a
250-300 toxicity range and it's just
where you know what's the toxicity range
for
soluble salts you know I might go from
you know might be up there two to three
thousand so it's a lot narrower on
chlorides than than anything and really
really
bicarbonates are
is a fairly narrow range to
because of the precipitating effect
so where where are we picking up
chloride typically in these mixes
well chlorides chlorides are in a lot of
things when you look at I'm sure there's
a fair amount of chlorides in Pete
when you look at standard soils you know
that there's there's a fair amount of
chlorides there I mean we don't measure
them
a lot like we do in these mixes here but
you know that's the that's one of the
anions that balances the cations coming
in to the to the plant I mean nitrate
will do that too but
chlorides if you look on tissue
sometimes the chlorides are extremely
high and that's just the balancing
cation or anion are we picking it up
from our water source ever Oh certainly
we can yeah bet yeah
okay and then moving on to bicarbonate
you mentioned that's a narrow window I
see a lot of it coming in on water tests
how do we manage bicarbonate levels and
what is that number what's the concern
with bicarbonate in terms of toxicity or
chloride really - well I mean
bicarbonate the worry is you get it so
high that again as the soils dry down
start precipitating out calcium and then
that domino effect of precipitating out
phosphorus so it becomes less of a
problem the more you keep the moisture
there you don't let it go dry
but
it's mainly and how you handle this is
just by acidifying that water so that
you can burn off those bicarbonate as
carbon dioxide oh
so we can lower it by applying a
somewhat you know slightly acidic yeah
water shoots into it okay yeah yeah is
that what we're seeing when we see like
on the edges of fabric pots we'll see
like a crustiness or on the top of the
soil you'll see that white cresting it's
not just the precipitate of these
some of these things probably a calcium
carbonate you know that's probably
what's precipitating out there it's a
salt that's precipitating out and I
would I would tend to think because we
tend to have a lot more calcium out
there and calcium will precipitate out
relatively easy
as opposed to say potassium so you know
see their calcium magnesium precipitate
okay so let's we talked a little bit
about these numbers you know moving down
this saturated paste report can you just
touch briefly on you know each of these
major anions and cations and and one
thing I want to you know for listeners
anions are gonna lower your ph cations
are gonna raise your pH that's just
something's I just wanted to throw out
there since we're talking about these
things kind of as a general rule
yeah and and so you know where would I
like to see these you mean is that what
you want what about the calcium and
calcium is going to affect route
development so it's it's it's got to be
there and it's got to be at the root
tips if you're going to get root
development you can't you can't take
calcium out of the top of the pot and
move it down to the roots at the bottom
of the pot if it's not there so calcium
is a huge
factor in there so what's the number
exactly should be I don't think it
should be less than a hundred but how
high it should be yeah that's a good
question especially if you're
if you're trying to do this with just a
watering regime you know it's gonna have
to be higher than 100 yeah I think a
range is fine because one of the things
I'd like to highlight is we don't really
know what all of you know what's optimal
for this cropped adjust the researched
isn't out there yeah that's something
you and I have talked about like there's
still a lot we're learning about
you know what's best practice for
cannabis because it's just it isn't as
well studied of a crop right and and you
know if you look at at a hundred and you
can one of the things we don't know
between the standard test and a paste is
we don't know what the flow rate yes we
don't know what what the flow rate of
calcium is in the solution so once we if
we if we could maintain a hundred I
think one hundred reply but
if the flow isn't there if we don't have
calcium and
right find this or
the right type of calcium that will
continually flow and feed the plant then
we're gonna have to have a higher number
so
that's why you know it's really hard to
determine exactly where you know I can I
can I have a better feeling saying that
that you'll have problems in general
crops if you get down to ten parts per
million
in least in cannabis probably you start
getting down to 40 30 40 parts per
million you're going to get into trouble
so
but 30 40 parts per man is great on a on
a soil in the field if you're if you're
a growing hemp in the field that you can
get 30 40 that'd probably be fine
but it
it's just really hard to nail down a
number but I think you know 100 150
providing that you're going to have a
flow rate and in generally speaking for
watering with well water we're going to
ice have some calcium there
so it depends on what what the water
quality is to but the other thing is
having enough calcium is not only
important for root development but it's
important for cell wall integrity if
you're in these and these enclosures
where you got you can tend to get high
humidity if you if you don't get calcium
in that cell wall you're you're opening
yourself up for powdery mildews and
disease problems
yeah well the traditional response to
like any plant or leaf deficiency is
just it was was always like add some
more cal-mag
which is higher and magnesium relative
to the two it's calcium levels but I
think that's what people were trying to
address with these you know liquid
bottled nutrients but
essentially what I'm hearing you say
regarding these these things is really
yours you're kind of starting with
calcium and then you're looking to make
sure that you know it doesn't matter if
there's 2,000 you know almost 2200
ppm of calcium on are found in our soil
if that is not becoming available when
we do this saturate pace test right
right and and so I do start with calcium
and then what I like to do is run
magnesium about 5 to 1 or are the
calcium 5 to 1 magnesium
so like in this case here if I really
wanted a balance in the solution where
you have 61 magnesium I'm going to need
it I would need about 300 of
the calcium to stay at that 5 to 1 ratio
now I tell people that's what you want
to do but you then you've got to watch
how high you push the soluble salts when
you do that
so if I can get so if I can get the
potassium twice the magnesium and the
magnesium
one fifth of the calcium
then I feel like I've got a pretty good
ratio or balance in the solution and but
but you can't there's a limitation of
how
you just can't keep adding one to
balance out the other because of the
salt problem well and it's gonna raise
your pH as well yeah yeah and magnesium
as I understand raises your pH one and a
half times of what calcium does so you
have to be really careful when you start
adding may knees and it in traditional
soils it tightens the soil I don't know
if we're seeing that so much with
potting soils to be an issue but that in
theory is is what people say is you know
magnesium tightens your soil and calcium
flock aids or loosens your soils in
terms of the till and these in this
situation I don't think that applies and
this real it really doesn't apply very I
mean the reason why Albrecht looked at
the calcium magnesium ratios was -
because it has an impact on soil physics
well you don't really have a slow fit in
in modified mixes or in sands for that
and one that matter you know you get
into sands you don't have the compaction
because of a clay I mean you can have
compassion because of the fineness of
the sand but the magnesium in a lot of
sands I will I will push up to 20%
we're in a heavy clay that might be way
too high but so yeah it's uh
you know the magnesium course if you add
magnesium as magnesium sulfate or epsom
salts that is a strong acid strong base
and that's not going to change your pH
except when you if you get to salts - I
yeah another thing I just want to
highlight is it's much easier to add
than it is to remove and I think that's
important for people to keep in mind
that less is more in a lot of cases
that's true it's really hard to take
that put that out of there once in the
pot yeah and to me that applies almost
more to phosphorus because we I've seen
pm's over over 6-thousand when we're
talking about phosphorus on the Mallik
test
how does that first of all what issues
do we have besides a waste of money and
potentially leeching phosphates into our
water supply from a plant health
perspective what issues does that create
you mentioned zinc
but how much available phosphorus do we
want to see and how do you correlate
those numbers when we're talking
phosphorus
if you're if you're looking at the the
phosphorus on the pace test you know I
think two two and a half parts per
million should be enough but
you know as you as you push them up
higher you're right in this I don't
really see so much problem with
phosphorus other than the fact that then
zinc just drops out of the picture and
the tissue analysis in the leaf tissue
analysis yes yes
because this is one of the challenges of
cannabis is it's really hard to get leaf
tissue analysis done and then if you do
get leaf tissue analysis done most
people aren't sharing that data so it's
it's really hard to find accurate
information but I have heard of you
heard a lot about the you know
phosphorus zinc relationship so if you
were looking at these numbers you just
said we have sufficient phosphorus but
possibly excessive in terms of in
relation to our zinc numbers down below
there that are at point zero three ppm
is that number yet low because the
phosphorus is so high that's possible
yes
so could you relate back to the standard
soil test where it shows six point eight
nine ppm with of zinc and how do you
kind of like correlate that
well you can't
you know you look at six point nine and
and some of the some of the data you'll
see out here from tri-state data and
stuff which is mainly set up for soils
they'll say all six point nine is hot is
is high but yet at 132 parts per million
phosphorus out there all right I say
you've got to run your zinc in a
relationship to your phosphorus in other
words if your Klosters is high you can't
have to have your zinc high and where
that where that number should be I can't
tell you
except that that I really don't believe
that 6.9 is high enough I think at 132
parts per million
you know that zinc could could very
easily have to be up there 20 30 parts
per million you
know this is all stuff that I want to
start playing around with as we learn
more and doing some more controlled
research but it's really hard to find
this information and then the other
challenge is like we're not seeing any
sort of zinc deficiencies in the
facilities that we work with you know in
terms of leaf expression yet I do wonder
if we play around with these numbers if
we would see some sort of improvement in
in overall growth due to the you know
increased zinc uptake but
unless you're seeing it you know and not
all not all of these will display
necessarily as a leaf deficiency you can
still stress a plant without actually
seeing it appear in the leaf tissue
which I think people is important to
emphasize too so
thing they call hidden hunger and and I
think you know zinc a big player in new
growth we tend to we tend to sample
maybe older growth so you know bud
growth I think it will have would be it
more impacted by I think than
maybe maybe the lead
so what do you think regarding foliar
applications is some of these different
you know sulfates or even chelated
versions like that are organic like we
use the biomen products I know you're
familiar with those
what do you think of that because in my
experience when I have worked with
growers that have gone really far down
the rabbit hole with these trace
elements and trying to balance
everything out using these soil tests
typically their crop goes downhill
unfortunately and I don't know and so so
I haven't really messed with these
numbers and frankly I don't want to add
some of these sulfates to because we
want to keep our soil organic and allow
growers you know you could say there's
purported deficiency now on this soil
test if they want to add zinc sulfate at
a certain rate and experiment with it by
all means but I wonder I guess I'm
asking two questions one how how much
trouble can you get in playing around
with these trace elements and then two
what do you think about foliar
applications either of sulfates or you
know chelated versions of these using
humic acids or
you know by almond sort of products well
I I would I much prefer the the AEDPA
chelated traces
there is some
if you do sulfates you got to be really
careful you probably have less of a
chance of burn on metals as much as but
you will have more of a chance of a burn
for a sulfate burn so you know that that
becomes a the issue and when you get
these soils and and they're so rich in
in phosphates and the cations I don't
really worry too much about boron
because being an anion that it's not
impacted by the cations so much I mean
calcium chloride is very insoluble but
boron just seems to be pretty much okay
in a lot of cases but but copper and
zinc I mean I run probably
almost a hundred percent deficient in
copper and I certainly you know I would
not like to
just build these soils up with too much
copper and we used to think that 20
parts per million copper was toxic until
I went and looked at some grapes and
Portugal and they had 300 parts per
million so you know coppers is really
bound up by organic fractions and I
think that's one of the reasons why we
don't see much
copper in these pace tests and why we
probably should be looking at at doing
more more in the in a foliar feeding
with chelate now one thing I do know
that Zink there there is a there's kind
of a
response time here
like zinc is more recent think like the
plants like zinc much earlier than say
manganese
so when I get some work on some of the
agricultural crops
spraying was thanking me early on very
early gave me a better results than uh I
waited but I could wait with manganese
so you know coming in with a spray
program with a chelate I think you can
put together a program spray them every
10 to 14 days and
and just cover a lot of your bases
now you said you prefer key lights with
EDTA
dddd ta
if we want to use products that are
either organic or allowed in organic
production and I know that's a sort of a
tricky minefield when it comes to that
subject but
what are your recommendations there
well when you start going organic you
know there's certainly EDTA sir thrown
out exact there you're there you're
looking at you know I think sulfates
about ends up being about the
only thing you have I don't know of
anything else do you
well the bio main products are approved
for use in organic production
I can't remember exactly what the key
later is it's all it's all a little bit
bureaucratic in terms of what's allowed
and what's not allowed in terms it's not
as
it's not as clear as it should be I
can't remember exactly what they're
using but it essentially they just they
found a workaround in terms of organic
production but I didn't feel like it was
necessarily a hundred percent or you
know anymore yeah but when we're talking
about these sulfates to like you look at
manganese sulfate it's this little pink
ball it's obviously been
you know fairly highly processed by
humans I
just don't know I wonder too about if we
you know if we took some of these
sulfates use a key later like humic acid
would that allow us and I'm not a
chemistry person is that something we
could apply as a foliar application as a
way of getting these nutrients on there
and a semi or you know or a quasi
organic fashion because you know humic
acid has been you know they probably use
potassium hydroxide to extract it it's
not a hundred percent organic either but
it's the same as using like fish
hydrolysate or you know seaweed extract
powder these other these other things
that have some
allowance for chemical inputs yeah I
think anytime you're using the sulfates
using real high-quality fulvic acid is
is to your advantage
now I've seen data that says
we really don't want more than five
pounds of sulfate a combination of
sulfated traces more than five pounds
per hundred gallons
of media
sulfated minerals so if you had this
thing you put a 3 pounds of zinc sulfate
a pound of manganese sulfate a pound of
copper sulfate you're at the limit right
there Oh in a water solution okay yeah
yeah in a foliar spray god oh
you know I'm not sure that that under
those growing conditions I mean pity
sakes or you spray one or two plants but
you know beforehand so you don't get
into trouble but I
think
putting it putting the fulvic acid in is
is a real beneficial thing to get get
those nutrients in and move it in the
plant
yeah that brings up a whole nother
challenge though with labeling issues
around fulvic acid you know there's
there's only one commercially available
purely fulvic acid product that I'm
aware of that's marketed as such
from bio egg but I know we work with
other human asset producers that claim
to have fairly high levels of fulvic
acid in their products but they're not
able to put them on the label based on
the way that they register their
products so it's all a little bit
confusing in terms of what you're
actually getting anyway I
know that New Tech has
an Omri approved
what they call connector oh and that is
a real high great fulvic acid
okay cool off to look into that product
so
just basically you know I I appreciate
you covering a lot of a lot of this in
terms of the testing I kind of want to
go over way some of the major takeaways
from today and from our conversation in
terms of these soil tests so it sounds
like we need to be careful when we're
looking at or evaluating these tests
based on the way the tests are taken
what would be your major takeaways for
people in terms of the the Mallik test
the saturated paste report I want to
encourage users to still get soil tests
I think that's really important
but there's certainly an air of caution
in terms of how we're consulting and
recommending off of them
well that's true and we can make all
kinds of criticisms about you know
whether we're using five five mil scoops
or whatever but the other the other
thing it comes down to is how well are
the growers
mixing the product mixing that sample
and how well are they sampling it if
they're sampling it during the grow
cycle you know are you taking a probe
and probing down through there you just
taking some off the sides off the top
you know you really need to get a good
thorough
representative sample and that's
something I think you know needs to be
addressed -
that's a really good point there's a lot
of room for error in this whole process
either on the you know then we got to
take that into account when we're
looking at these tests
right right so I don't necessarily freak
out when I see a test that looks less
than what people would consider to be
optimal or doesn't look perfectly
balanced I always want to start with how
does your plant look what's going on
there how does your crop finish you know
can't argue with success and that that
plant is successful then you're not
doing all that bad
so one last question I have you know
this is really confusing stuff for most
people myself included you know I'm
trying to look at a standard test the
saturated pace test there's you know
obviously other tests like in methods
you know like like Bray and some of
those others how do we take these
numbers and come up with any sort of
like
quantifiable understanding or
recommendation assuming that these
numbers aren't necessarily the end-all
be-all you know I hear some consultants
that are so confident regarding their
recommendations around these numbers for
crops without ever really seeing the
crop I mean how are we how can we really
do that or can we even do that I'm not
sure we can't
you know it again it goes back to how
the crop is responding and you look at
these numbers
well okay these numbers don't reflect
what what the water quality is and
it doesn't reflect what the lighting is
I mean you've got to you've got to look
at this thing in a holistic fashion you
know this is a part this is a part of
the the the tools that you have to work
with but if you if you
you've got to understand and really pay
attention to what your plants are saying
back to you
and it doesn't take into account the
biological activity of the soil which is
cycling these nutrients and I think
that's one of the things that's really
helped us with our soils is I and that's
something I look at under the microscope
and have a better grasp of is sort of
what's going on biologically in these
soils because that's that's what's
ultimately making a lot of these
nutrients available
right right and one of the things that I
have seen more problems with is people
that's recycling the mix what to be
happening is more and more nutrients are
coming out
during the the group first grow and then
buy time to get into the second grow and
then they want to kind of add their
their normal fertility to that they're
running into a salsa problem
that makes sense so we want we almost
need to look at every growing situation
as its own separate entity and then take
a look at all of these variables
together and then I guess for me and I
don't feel confident making a lot of
like quantifiable recommendations but I
can look at a trend and say hey we're
seeing the calcium is kind of staying
where it's at let's not add anymore this
cycle or we added more potassium at this
rate and we got this response I think
it's something we could up or we could
lower we maintain and that's how I've
been sort of been doing been doing this
but it's it I've I've been wracking my
brain for years on trying to find a
better way of quantifying things and I
haven't come up with it yet honestly
well you know as much and I've worked in
a standard soil well I'm and we're still
not
somebody tells you they got all the
answers they just haven't asked all the
questions because it's certainly
it's not it's not easy thing I
think that's a great point so I'll
definitely keep that in mind moving for
and I hope growers will continue to test
but just test with a grain of salt and
realize that you need to look at this
test in the environments of
humidity temperature watering habits
biological activity all the things that
you mentioned there need to come into
play - yeah exactly well I really
appreciate your time today bill this was
really enlightening for me I hope that
growers will reach out can you talk a
little bit about your role in relation
to Logan and what sort of consulting
you're doing on these tests
well
I'm probably add a bigger disadvantage
than you are I as the consultant to
agronomist to Logan if they request for
me to evaluate the the the analysis
it'll come to me and and I'll write
something up and and send it back to the
Logan and then they'll forward or back
to the client so I mean I and but again
I I am at a disadvantage because I don't
see a lot of
those facilities and I do have guys send
me pictures and look at them and and but
again it's not like being there either
but
we've been fairly successful in helping
people that that's in trouble it's just
sooner PC people do more testing and try
to stay out of trouble
so yeah I'm independent of
Logan but you can either run it through
the Logan or they could contact me
directly and I'll put your information
on the website page but people if they
ask for a recommendation from Logan
based on their test result because what
they'll get back is literally just this
soil report that I'm gonna put on the
podcast page if they want a
recommendation off of it then you're the
one you're the guy that's who's making
that recommendation correct
okay and you're you're being transparent
when you say there's still a lot to
learn about this crop and there's still
a lot that you want to learn personally
regarding these tests and cannabis so
people need to keep that in mind and
that's I think that's every honest
consultant out there at this point in
time and I think a lot of consultants
have been basing their
recommendations off of like you and I
talked about today about numbers that
may not tell the whole story and I think
that's the big takeaway yes exactly you
know and I had a guy i presented down at
a dallas and then i have guy come in
from california who says well we run
tissues every week and and i i thought
wow you know that's a lot of money and
but I'm not sure you can even make the
correction within a week
if you've got the results back and then
you made a application you're going to
be retesting that with the material on
the lease so yeah it you can some people
really go into extreme details I'm I'm
more success driven and saying well you
know how's the plan look I'm like you I
like to I like to know the plants are
healthy they're green they're they're
growing and and we're not having burnt
edges on the leaves or what have you so
yeah and I'm hoping that you and I can
stay in better touch here moving forward
to to improve this process along with
other people that are that are doing
similar things in this industry so that
we can all learn to make better
recommendations down the road but you
know I was gonna say you could look at a
test like this and say oh wow here's
something to watch like I would watch
the soluble salts that could potentially
be the problem that kind of thing yes
exactly and I think there's ranges that
we can work at look at I'm hoping to
work with Logan and and maybe you'd it
to put together a a little ring binder
folder or a ring binder
thing about these soils and what what we
kind of project these numbers maybe
should be or should get into these
ranges and and try to try to narrow them
down for people so we'll hopefully do
that by the end of summer that would be
great I'd love to be a part of that yeah
I know Erica Ryan heimer has been doing
a lot of work around this to coming
working on a calculator around
cannabis as well so I want to mention
her she's been someone that I've really
enjoyed chatting with on this subject -
well thank you Bill for your time I
really appreciate it and I look forward
to staying in touch all right thank you
thank you for the to the listeners who
end up listening to this so alright
we'll take care of we'll stay in touch
[Music]
that was Bill McKibben and you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast i'm your host tad
hussy don't forget to check out our
website at www.kttape.com
[Music]