foreign
[Music]
to the Cannabis cultivation and science
podcast I'm your host Tad Hussey of Kiss
Organics this podcast where we discuss
The Cutting Edge of growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge my
guest this week is Colin Bell Colin is
most well known in the industry as the
co-inventor of Mammoth p
completed his PhD in soil microbial
ecology in 2009 as a research scientist
at Colorado State University Colin
published dozens of peer-reviewed
Publications that were focused on
elucidating microbial mediated processes
that enhance plant growth Collins
academic research includes long-term
multi-disciplinary studies in which
biological chemical and physical
characteristics of soils were measured
to elucidate soil microbial and plant
responses to climate variability he
currently works for microbial Mass a
plant Amendment product comprised of
several unique species of beneficial
bacteria shown to promote plant Vigor
increase plant biomass and enhance
microbial life in and around the root
zone now on to the show
hey Colin thanks for coming on the show
today
dad great to see you it's been quite a
while and happy to be here yeah I'm glad
we got to reconnect and I wanted to just
start off why don't you tell us uh
what's been going on with you a little
bit about yourself
yeah so for those of you that don't know
me my name is Colin Bell
um I'm actually a scientist by in my
background training I have a PhD in soil
microbiology I studied at Texas Tech
University from there I moved over to
Fort Collins Colorado where I worked at
the natural resource ecology Center at
Colorado State University and I worked
for years in all my academic uh and
research background is focused on
understanding the importance of plant
microbe interactions did a lot of
studies uh published a lot of papers
in both natural and agriculture systems
and just basically got a really sound
fundamental understanding of how
microbes work with plants to support
plant growth and in these different
environments including Precision
agriculture systems and indoor growing
awesome you also were the founder or
creator of Mammoth p
so I want to mention that that's pretty
cool
um and now uh you're currently working
over at microbial mass is that correct
yeah that's right so you know I was the
co-founder of Mammoth microbes the
inventor of that technology and a lot of
people probably know me because of that
that's been a really amazing journey and
I learned a lot doing that
ultimately and it was at the very end of
last year in October last year I made
the choice to leave uh the organization
for a lot of reasons one that kind of
got to the size
um where I thought it was going a
different direction that I didn't
necessarily want to go and it wasn't in
the vision but when you get to a larger
size organization and bring people in
and Outsiders and investors
you start to lose control and maybe um
sword from the sort of away from their
original vision and intention you had
for the organization so I wanted to
follow my path and I left it took some
time off and I've done some fun stuff
and you and I were talking about some of
those things ultimately I'm trying to
follow my passion and trying to really
enjoy my professional career to the
fullest and I enjoy that by working with
people that I really enjoy working with
um that are go-getters and that I can
trust and have a lot of fun with and
along with that I have to work with
um
companies that I believe in and not only
from a mission and vision but from a
technology and Innovation point of view
so it has to kind of fit my expertise
which is a microbial and natural
Technologies for agriculture so I'm very
passionate about agriculture Innovation
and figuring out how to formulate and
how to
develop
nature and nature solutions to fit into
conventional agriculture management
practices and the mass microbial Mass
Technologies MIM Horticulture is the
name of the company out of Canada has
done some very interesting things that
intrigue me not only from a team
perspective but from a technology
perspective and so I'm really happy to
be helping them develop their business
in the U.S
yeah I was kind of uh blindsided because
you and I had talked and uh I was just
asking what you were up to and you know
you weren't doing anything and the next
thing I knew I hear from another friend
that you're working over at microbial
Mass so I had to call up my buddy David
David Bernard perone and he was kind of
filling me in and then
um Francois who actually was the one who
developed microbial Mass uh as another
friend of mine who I haven't talked to
in a little while but
um he's an awesome researcher and so I'm
excited to see you guys working together
and
um yeah before we dive into like the
real meat of the podcast tell me just a
little bit about microbial mass and what
you find interesting about it as a
microbial you know biostimulant
yeah thank you and I'll just uh mention
that you know David and Francois are two
of the reasons when I speak up team and
people that I really want to work with
and have fun working with uh was part of
the decision making for me joining this
group great guys a lot of fun I know you
know them both very well and you know I
really geeked out as a microbiologist
and someone that really wants to apply
microbiology in the market uh with
technology and microbial Technologies
and the approach that I took with
Mammoth P was a quite different approach
this group took quite a different
approach which which intrigued me and it
was something I've been trying to do or
wanting to do
um with the grosincia group when I was
you know an operational founder and you
know
a member of that particular team and I
saw this group being able to execute
that well so it's really fun and and the
difference is I think are Precision to
be fair
um there are some certain functionality
that we nurtured in Mammoth P targeting
phosphorus cycling but there was a lot
of unknowns that were occurring in that
particular formula as well and as a
microbial ecologist soil ecologist I
embraced those unknowns knowing that
there's not everything we're ever going
to learn about plants and microbial
function but uh believing that a lot of
those things could enhance
plant success and there could be a lot
of functional redundancies that could
help help plants grow successfully
across the growing season without us
necessarily understanding what they all
are
what I felt like the import culture
group did really well was work with
super defined
carrier super defined formula and really
honing in on the functionality of the
microbes that we're using to not only uh
present a a very specific microbe with a
very specific function uh for the
industry but it eliminates a lot of the
unknowns and it made me think of
something that was pretty common in the
industry now at least from the salt and
the hydro Growers was this aspect of
clean
and a lot of the clean uh speak around
growing plants now and keeping it as
clean as sterile as possible that's not
necessarily something I completely agree
with but I understand it's the Paradigm
and a lot of people want to start
focusing on that aspect of growing
and I felt like if there was a way that
we could incorporate microbes into a
clean grow environment it would help the
grower but we had to figure out how to
do that well and I feel like this group
has done that with this particular
formula it's the first clean microbial
solution where everything's very well
defined and they're using dormant
bacteria to deliver to the plants and so
it works through uh the irrigation
fertigation system completely virtually
sterile because of the dormancy of the
microbes and the microbes actually
activate when they get to plant roots to
stimulate plant growth across the
growing season the mass product in
particular has done a couple of things
they have a couple microbes that they
Quantified really well in the laboratory
and in grow environments to increase the
mass of early stage rooting and then
three of the other microbes in this
particular product are focused on later
stage phosphor cycling and so it's a
really interesting one-two crunch
maximizing the plant's ability to
establish early on and then to uptake
nutrients later on in the growth cycle
to maximize their ability to stack and
yield hmm
so there's you don't have the same
issues with biofilm build up I would
assume if you're if you're looking at
dormant bacteria
um and then this product was developed
uh I believe or discovered uh out of
David's grow when he was at Whistler
Medical on the Cannabis side so the
product was actually
derived and correct me if I'm wrong here
but from that sort of uh relationship
co-evolution of these particular
bacteria with cannabis plants
yeah how how I understand it product was
it developed but the microbes were
identified yes in that environment yeah
and so they were identified then they
were selected and then scaled up and
that's where the product formulation the
product development formulation process
took over where they utilized the
microbes from the cannabis grow to
create a formula a clean formula to
carry them in to make it very compatible
not only for living soil Growers but
also for clean salt hydroponic Growers
yeah I think and I think you bring up an
important Point there's a big difference
between clean and sterile you can have
microbial
interactions going on in your soil and
not be sterile but still have a clean
room and you know we're not throwing out
all the IPM processes around keeping
your area clean
um so I just want to highlight that and
then you know
I'm kind of going off topic here a
little bit but you and I just uh both
attended a uh webinar by uh Dr punja
talking about hop latent viroid and one
of the things that he pointed out around
it was that it damages root mass in in
clones
um he had a lot of interesting points
around it you know in terms of mothers
most mothers being plants being
asymptomatic and and
um just the prevalence of this viroid in
our
in our in the in the plants that we are
currently cultivating
um but I wonder if we could have a
reduction in symptoms if we can get some
microbial products
that potentially could increase root
mass to offset some of the damage that
we're seeing from a viroid yeah I think
I think conceptually that's exactly
right what we heard in that in that
particular presentation which was very
well done
um was that in a lot of cases it
silences genes in the plants among a lot
a host of other things that the viroid
does to the plant to help kind of deter
its maximum success uh limit or
diminishes root growth diminishes
trichome production diminishes overall
yield diminishes stem stability but the
gene silencing which I thought was
pretty interesting also because that's
going to silence a lot of the resistance
genes in these plants and so the idea is
maximizing the plant Health to its full
potential and there's a there's a strong
argument that if you have the beneficial
microbes occupying the rhizospheric root
Zone it's going to maximize the plant's
ability to fend off uh particular
pathogens the other piece of that was
fascinating the the thyroid
populating viroid actually makes plants
more susceptible to bacterial infections
and so you can almost offset that with
beneficials because there's a
probability gain
um life is a probability and if you can
occupy a space with beneficials it's
going to be harder for pathogens to come
in and
affect your plan
yeah well let's
um getting back to the outline that I
had for this conversation today uh one
of the things that I thought would be
really useful to ask you is how do we
grow microbes you know this is something
that you're you've had a lot of
experience on especially when you're
developing your product
um but for the home that the home
cultivator or a commercial grower you
know they're not they're not they don't
have a lab
um they're probably getting things off
the shelf as food sources and and trying
to use microbes like maybe lactobacillus
or maybe extend uh a microbial product I
already have where how would someone
begin to start
I don't know doing this process
it's really simple uh and it can be a
lot of fun I recommend it for everybody
and I used to teach at the University
when I was a student I would teach labs
and we would culture microbes from the
environment and so that's a really fun
way to start if you're thinking about
growing microbes and I've had people uh
like take a sterile swab you can take a
sterile Q-tip and the growing microbes
I'm going to start is not as complicated
as keeping them pristine meaning growing
the microbes you want to grow and
preventing from contamination we talk we
use the word sterile a minute ago and
that's something that comes up sometimes
in cultivation facilities but in general
it's a misnomer there's no chance that
sterility exists in the environment it's
a probability but sterility just doesn't
happen yeah it might be able to happen
for a short period of time but you can
grow there's a a lot of different
food sources that you can make or you
can actually commercially buy and
they're pretty
uh
cheap
to grow microbes and so just like you
and I microbes or heterotrophs they eat
food and they respire carbon and they
take in oxygen and so you can just
create any kind of food source and you
will grow microbes the interesting thing
about growing microbes is some favor of
some food sources over the others and so
there's a lot of different media you can
use to maximize
the success of growing certain strains
there's uh Bibles of microbiology so to
speak it's the methods of microbiology
where they have thousands of different
microbial Medias and they have the
actual formulas for them and so it's a
really interesting book you can
reference you can probably buy online
you can definitely pick up at a library
or a University library for sure and
just look at all these different
ingredients there's typically sugar
sources and there's particularly protein
sources and there could be a liquid
solution or it can be in a solidified
solution where you have an auger gel
from polysaccharide to help solidify
that and streak microbes or streak
something that you've collected from the
environment on a plate or just put it in
a broth and microbes will grow
you can actually leave these plates out
um just exposed for minutes close them
up and you can grow microbes from the
air and you'll see growth in less than a
week easily so it's very simple to grow
microbes
understanding the microbes that you want
to grow and how to optimize that growth
becomes a lot more sophisticated and
with all kind of microbial production
the growing of microbes is typically not
the Crux it's the maintaining the
the purity of that microbial culture is
what becomes very challenging and so the
aseptic transfer and technique which is
your sterile technique of transferring
uh from one one place to another uh your
microbe becomes most of the risk when
you're growing microbes
that's why it's really hard to have a
consistent microbial formula over time
and I imagine most people if they tested
their lactobacillus or any of their
concoctions that we make which is cool
and I love it
and including microbial teas I think
we'll find very different microbial
assemblages in those over time from
batch to batch seasonally there's from
the Water Source there's so many
different sources that can affect that
microbial community in the in the
structure of that over time
yeah so I came into this industry
through the aerated compost tea World
um and what you're saying really holds
true for for my experience too and and
that was that
um
you know every batch is going to be
different we're not identifying these
particular strains or species
but by having sufficient levels of
oxygen and selecting an aerobic
environment and using an a source of
material in this case compost that we
know to be fairly
free of pathogens we're we're hopefully
like tilting the scales in the direction
of more beneficial microorganisms or at
the very least what I think and when I
talk about compost tea you know people
make claims that I think are just crazy
around it
um like for me the idea of disease
suppression and some of these other
things may occur but like like you said
every batch is going to be or like I
said I guess every batch is going to be
different and we can't get replication
consistently so it'd be really hard to
make any conclusions
or even determine any Trends over over
time but what I think is interesting
about is can we get nutrients functional
like nutrient cycling like in a tea that
we can apply to the soil that would
allow us to increase the you know that
microbial Loop that nutrient cycling
going on on some level through sort of
this like shotgun approach
totally and that's I think the answer is
uh absolutely positively yes and it's
because of the way microbes work and
what I would say is the a really
practical goal for a tea or having just
a mixed Consortium of microbes is having
a critical mass uh a number I count uh
of threshold biomass that gets to a
certain level where it can function at a
very high level
and it doesn't necessarily matter
who's in there in every case if you're
trying to get a general nutrient cycling
function out of a microbial group you
want to make sure there are no pathogens
and you can make the assumption that
there's enough functional redundancy
that you're going to have microbes that
under different conditions are going to
step up and perform the function that
may be another microbial group that
performs the same function can't under a
certain environment and I've you see
that a lot in nature I don't see it any
different than in natural systems and I
used to do a lot of work in desert
ecosystems so we used to talk a lot
about functional redundancy because the
environment was so extreme that you'd
find different microbial groups that you
could you could test them and they would
do the same thing functionally but they
would have very different environmental
thresholds and some would work much
better in drier conditions or in warmer
conditions and similar to work better
and colder conditions under pH stress
and so having the functional redundancy
I think is a plus
and the real value in those cases is
making sure you have a certain
concentration so you can maximize the
functionality and so there's going to be
this asymptote if you want me to draw a
line here with my hand where the lower
the concentration you're going to get
lower functionality then at some point
it's just going to reach this critical
threshold where you're maximizing your
functionality as a function of the
biomass or the concentration of microbes
and reaching that without any potential
pathogens would be I think that the
Target that you're trying to go for in a
t or any kind of microbial concoction
that's generally defined
yes so when you say functional
redundancy essentially what you're
saying is uh just as just to reiterate
in a desert system for example let's say
uh Cactus needs
phosphorus and there is a particular uh
strain of bacteria that's very good at
cycling phosphorus when it is
very cold out and then it heats up that
bacteria is potentially going to go
dormant die off well the plant still
needs phosphorus well another microbe
that maybe doesn't function at cold
temperatures but functions quite well at
hot temperatures say over 100 degrees
Fahrenheit is going to reproduce and
cycle nutrients and provide phosphorus
for that plant under those conditions
and all and so they they essentially can
occupy the same ecological niche for the
plant which is phosphorus cycling yet
coexist and and not really compete with
each other because they're functioning
at different
variables and like you said it could be
pH it could be water it could be heat it
could be cold does that kind of
that's exactly how it works in nature
and that's exactly how it would work in
in farming for our Precision agriculture
indoor growing pH is the example that I
think is the most prevalent
environmental Factor affecting microbial
success there's a assault concentration
with nutrients and all the just
conventional management practices and pH
is a big part of that also pH actually
is shown to predicate microbial
diversity and Community composition more
than any other Factor being the
strongest factor to manipulate microbial
community structure across the world and
so you look at different conditions for
different soil types whatever out of all
the factors there might be temperature
water PH others pH is the first
determining factor and I think it's
interesting for indoor growing but as
you can have pH shifts you try to avoid
that but that happens
and so with functional redundancy you
have microbes that are able to persist
and function through those shifts and
kind of uh kind of overall Bridge a
functional Gap where a single microbe
might work really well at a certain pH
let's say seven but it might be very
stressed at a pH of five and so that
would not be the best microbe in that
particular environment and having
another backup microbe that worked well
across the range of that particular
environmental threshold pH would would
serve uh would serve the plant better
that's really interesting
um I think it's important for people to
keep in mind that
we tend to think in like
black and white but the reality of this
the complexity of the rhizosphere is
that like the soil may have a pH that
we're getting but like within that soil
there's all these little micro Pockets
where the pH might be a little bit
different where hydrology might be a
little bit different
um and and that's where these these
little ecological niches occur and it's
hard for me to wrap my brain around
because it they're it's so small and
it's constantly changing like this idea
that you're the microbes in your soil
are always changing I think is really
really important because when we start
getting into these like General
uh the thoughts of like fungal to
bacteria Ratio or
um you know overall biomass if my soil
is always changing how can we use those
metrics to really make informed
decisions
um just due to the variability and
fluctuation of it
that's a great question I'm going to add
to that that you know in soils if you
compare the different types of
substrates let's say that plants might
grow in in agriculture or indoor
agriculture it can go from soil all the
way to soils media then on the far
extreme let's just say rockwool and so
there's different buffering capacities
across those substrates that very
substantially if you think about the
Rockwell scenario as the as the most
extreme other example from soil those
environments are going to change
dramatically with every watering event
because as the ions coming through and
it kind of drains through it doesn't
have a huge buffering capacity and so
you really want to be
um diligent on phing the solution before
you water your plant because you can
stress that but microbes work really
well in those environments
on the whole other extreme I think about
soil where it's more buffered and in the
rhizosphere and you think about
microbiology and scale is a really
interesting topic microbes are
just micrometers you know which is such
a small uh just a such a small size that
obviously it's microscopic you can't see
it with the naked eye but if you saw it
along the tiniest route here
it would just be a speck even from a
magnification and so the environments
that it gets that that it created along
with the root zone or the rhizosphere
are are highly buffered and so I think
that you're going to have an ebb and
flow of different populations but
there's also I think about it as a
probability game where if there's
um successful microbes in that
environment they're going to swell and
Shrink depending on certain
circumstances as far as their overall
population or growth but they're
probably going to remain there and they
might not completely turn over uh to a
completely different group you might
have some additions coming in but I
don't think that the turnover is as
Extreme as much as the ebbing and
swelling would be so it's kind of a
probability game
yeah and then the other thing that
further complicates it is the life
cycles of these microbes the generations
of them are so fast so just within a
given flowering cycle we have
co-evolution happening on a microscopic
scale and so
like and I think I've mentioned this in
previous podcasts but I talked to uh my
good friend Nate Gibbs over at Gold Leaf
Gardens and you know they've had their
soil in their beds for over eight years
now and like that's his intellectual
property at this point that's what gives
him something different than everyone
else on the market because the microbes
in that soil I mean we'll call it
microbes but the nutrient levels the
microbes the pH all of those things are
unique to him it's no longer the soil
that he got from me eight years ago it's
it's his own his own thing and I think
that's really interesting
yeah that's totally cool you know I
think the visual I would use to frame
how microbes exist in any environment in
the in the rice Assurance soil that's
how I talk about it you know as a
community starts off it's just a very
low concentration or a certain single
micro and they call that the lag phase
of the microbial growth curve and at
some point with uh
there's typically a lot of food resource
ultimately that microbial group or that
mass will get to a certain concentration
and they grow really quick and they
reproduce or clone out very quickly they
they split and they um asexually just
clone out and in days they can really
change their Mass but then they'll grow
into an exponential growth phase where
they'll just grow at a 10x rate in a
very quick in that environment very
quickly
and at some point they'll level up where
the food source equals the live death
and so the food source is sustaining
that certain concentration of microbes
and if that that just that longer growth
phase it's a life equals Death it's
called stationary where microbes are
turning over but they're reproducing at
about the same rate they're dying and so
they're maintaining this certain mass
and only when a food source or some
environmental conditions really disrupt
that particular Mass you get this death
phase going down where the concentration
starts to decline rapidly and so that
that stationary growth phase can can
persist for a very long period of time
and it's just indicative of the microbe
being very happy in that environment and
having enough of a food source and a
long enough life cycle
to persist and have a have a pretty uh
predictable turnover if that makes sense
yeah and when you say food sources uh
that could be a variety of things that
could be exudates coming directly from
the plant itself out of the roots it
could be uh a variety of organic
uh matter uh things in or fertilizer for
for that for example it could be you
know a little bit of alfalfa meal a
little bit of feather or fishbone meal
it could be salts let's talk about
mineral salts how do they affect
microbes
yeah it's a great question so
um a lot of people think that mineral
salts actually kill microbes and I'm
here to tell you that's not necessarily
the truth it all depended on time and
concentration for even disinfectant
Solutions I'll tell you what I've I've
tried to kill microbes before a robust
microbial formulas and I've had a very
hard time doing it even with
commercially available products hydrogen
peroxide chlorine Solutions and it comes
down to the concentration of the
solution and the time and over time
those are the two factors that you have
to dial in in order to successfully kill
microbes in general
in in practice I've never seen microbes
really die off through us through um
just a fertigation practice I actually
had a hard time again killing microbes
through just uh recommended practices of
most disinfectants that are recommended
in our industry cleaning lines and
whatnot it has to be a longer time and a
high concentration to significantly
disrupt microbes
so the the idea behind salts killing
microbes is that they raise the uh
you know soluble salt level in the in
either the the media
or in the nutrient solution
um so the EC of that to a level to where
the microbes through osmotic shock uh
die essentially so
um there's there's been this idea
perpetuating industry that
mineral salts kill microbes but yet
there's research out there that I've
seen that shows that uh mineral salts in
low doses actually feed microbes
um they're they're a source for
a food source
microbes
uh consume the same nutrients that
plants do and the only other nutrient
that they get but not from the air from
the from the substrate is carbon and so
this is a pretty interesting
evolutionary uh evolutionary tool of
plants to feed
photosynthate priming into the soil or
to the substrate to feed microbes the
sugars that they take from the air they
consume some of the carbon to create
their biomass but they also shoot a lot
of that sugar into the soil to feed
microbes the carbon they need so the so
the microbes can actively help cycle
nutrients to support their success and I
I used to say this all the time but you
know microbes all plants in nature the
natural ones exist because of that
microbial relationship they have in the
soil because the microbes actually help
them take up nutrients and
if you're feeding soluble nutrients into
a solution and microbes are there
they're absolutely going to take
advantage of those just like the plants
would and so I wouldn't call it a
competition but there is a little bit of
a
cohabitation of utilizing the resources
in that particular environment
yeah I think that's just an important
point I want you to I wanted you to to
make or to hear you say because you know
what we see from when we look at like uh
competition vegetable Growers like giant
pumpkin Growers Tomatoes things like
that they're doing a combination of
organic inputs uh microbial stimulants
like micrizal fungus for example and
then
um levels of mineral salts and that's
where we see the largest yields
um
and I I think like ultimately if we want
to talk about just growing the largest
plant
it would be this sort of this hybrid
method now I'm an organic guy and I
could I could absolutely make the
argument for why I choose not to use
mineral salts but I also want to be
pragmatic about it acknowledge that
you know if we're just talking about
yield or plant growth
um this hybrid method I think is really
the way to go
uh absolutely positively I mean that's
what I've seen also for a couple
different reasons I think that having
that extra canvas if you will from my if
you were going to call microbes a
catalysts and they do uh oh not only act
as a cows but they create other
biomolecules that act as catalysts to
help cycle nutrients to help stimulate
the plants to want to take up more
nutrients I've seen uh the rhizosphere
with beneficial bacteria protect plants
from from infection from other pathogens
that might come in just from ecological
niche Theory by itself
but these microbes can create different
chemical signaling and analogous to
hormones in some cases that they'll
stimulate plant growth which is a very
interesting thing they obviously cycle
nutrients which can become sticky and
not available to the plants especially
in soil phosphorus is a great example of
that or they can actually solubilize
that phosphorus and make it available
for the plant to uptake and so there's a
lot of things these microbes do to help
plants across the growing season uh I I
guess one more one more example is and
this isn't as much in soils as it would
happen and and probably cocoa and in
rockwool in some cases and there's a
lockout event that occurs in some cases
if there's a flooding of ions the plants
aren't able to balance that out very
well and microbes do a really good job
of balancing out plant nutrient uptake
how long the rhizosphere and root Zone
and microbes can actually alleviate the
potential for a walkout events and I
think that's a really really fascinating
thing that a lot of Growers probably
experience just without understanding it
you can have these really micro lockout
events through
just feeding salts the plants won't show
for days and the plants can probably
work out of it but it's a staggering
growth event that with microbes the
plants wouldn't feel that they could
focus all their energies into the into
the upward growth of the plant instead
of the plant being almost stunted
although you couldn't measure that
necessarily just by watching the plant
grow as it's being fed pure salts over
across the growing season and I've had
Growers that have used microbes that
they were just feeding Rockwell's an
example
assaults and they would add a microbial
solution and in two days they would just
see their plants open up and literally
kind of they would call it explode and
like I said their buds just started
really growing and it took me a while to
think through this but I think the I
think the truth is that there's a
lockout that's occurring that microbes
completely get rid of and allow the
plants just to focus on uptaking
nutrients and allocating them without
any kind of stutter
hmm so your your theory your hypothesis
around this is that
even in a relatively sterile system and
we say sterile but there's no grow
that's actually sterile
um right but in a system with less
microbes that's not using soil using a
media like rock wool and mineral salts
um
there's still room for
a micro you know clean microbial
products that that could potentially
increase yield or have other plant
benefits
totally and I I've seen it
I I get it I don't know that I fully uh
understand the mechanism and action
there I'm thinking okay these microbes
maybe could help potentially cycle
nutrients then are they surviving or
persisting in the rock wool or are they
converting nutrients into a form that
allows that addresses some other plant
need are they occupying niches on the
plant roots themselves like
what's what's really going on do we know
I don't think we know completely that's
what's kind of interesting about it I
would say that in in rockwool in a
rockable environment since you brought
that up you know the rhizosphere in
Roots create a very habitable
environment you know it's a sticky uh
nice carbon uh foundation and it's
exuding carbon into that rock wool the
plants are just doing that so the
microbes can live on the roots and and
be very happy quite honestly no matter
what the substrate is and you'll find as
even in soil the microbial concentration
gets greater uh the closer to the roots
or on the roots and so that's the hot
spot that the microbes like to be in
and a lot of uh like microbial science
is still a little bit nascent it's hard
to measure all of the idiosyncrasies and
interactions that occur yeah but I think
part of that turnover that you
referenced earlier where the microbes
are going to die the organized these
cells break open and the constituents of
those cells create a bio food source
that stimulate the plants and the plants
are able to take that up also there's a
lot of simple proteins the plants can
take up that way and ultimately uh what
I've seen is I think the plants just get
more nourished or they are able to get
more resources with that extra Catalyst
somehow obviously we understand nutrient
cycling
there are some other mechanisms
biological mechanisms that are obviously
occurring in a more synthetic
environment and more of a rockwool
substrate where the nutrients are being
fed and we think that they're all
soluble so the plants seem to be taking
them up but I think plants in some cases
are able to take up more nutrients and
so they're able to allocate more and uh
One Last Detail that I think is
fascinating I've seen just uh numerous
times
and said rockwool bro and you can have a
synthetic fertilizer and a synthetic
fertilizer treatment with microbes and
the plants both look good but they're
actually not the same and I've noticed
in many cases the smell the terpene
profile and even resin profiles
anecdotally and quantifiably
are much higher and a lot of the
microbial treatments than just a plain
synthetic and you can even tell by the
smell and going through enough smell
plants that look similar but one smell
like hay or cut grass and one smelled
more like a really interesting cannabis
strain and it was sticky and the only
difference was microbes so I think that
the microbes are not only able to
deliver more resources to the plant but
they might also trigger some type of
signaling that allows the plant to turn
on some of these genes that produce more
cannabinoids maybe produce more terpenes
produce more resins
yeah I mean we know now that some of
these microbes are actually going into
the root tip itself into the plant and
then back out again it's pretty it's
pretty incredible the stuff we're
learning
um so one thing I've been thinking about
lately because we're talking about sort
of
how you know how do we apply microbes or
how do we look at soils and and
diversity
and there's a so I this is not a
complete thought so bear with me on this
the first thing the first part of this
that I want to share that goes into this
thought process is when I make compost
tea
um I'm going for nutrient cycling right
well when I look at it on the microscope
if I brew for
let's say more than 60 hours at the end
of the day I don't have that level of
diversity anymore pretty much what I'm
down to is just like one morphology of
bacteria and one morphology of uh
typically of some sort of flagellate uh
it's like and I give the analogy like
what if I just took a zoo and put out
all this food and opened up all the
gates you know at first there'd be this
explosion of growth and then you'd come
back a week later and you just have like
your lions and your rats your apex
predator and your best you know
survivalist and and they'll fluctuate so
the bacteria will explode and then all
of a sudden you know I'll come back
eight hours later and it'll just be all
flagellants because they will have eaten
all the bacteria and then they no longer
have food so they die off and then the
bacteria explodes again and you get this
like roller coaster but you've lost all
your diversity and so when I think about
no-till you can see where I'm going here
and this idea that uh my good friend Ben
Higgins explained to me talking about
the disturbance hypothesis which is this
idea that when we have
um
you know a new land that has you know
let's just say a volcano
lava forms this land there's no life on
it right we'll get we'll slowly start to
see species get introduced but the
diversity on that you know
on that rock is is minimal
well over time that diversity increases
and we'll start to you know we'll start
to see grasslands and then forests and
soil will obviously develop and then
eventually we'll end up in what we you
know was known as like a climax
ecological niche something like uh yeah
old growth forest and the diversity
declines at that point
so somewhere in the middle there is
where we have our maximum level of
diversity it's not at the end in the old
growth forest it's not at the beginning
you know where we just have bare rock
it's somewhere in the middle and so
this is one of the one of the reasons
like in my brain I think okay maybe a
little bit of soil disturbance is okay
maybe it's good so when we go to reamend
our living soil beds you know we're not
we're not get breaking out of mechanical
tiller and just destroying all soil
structure but we are mixing in nutrients
for the next cycle
is that really as harmful as like people
might make it out to be
um
I think I've already kind of shared my
opinion through my explanation but what
are your thoughts around it
yeah well well I'm kind of hearing this
session here which is a really fun idea
we used to do this in my college class
I've grown fungi soil fungi for years
yeah uh and as a desert ecologist sponge
I really dominate the function of those
soils because of their uh not only the
morphology but their physiology and
they're able to withstand and you can
see that at a microbial scale you can
see this on this Forest scale that
you're talking about in this kind of
peak of diversity before it starts to
dwindle I've always thought of
Agriculture as an inherent inherently
Disturbed system like I don't think
there's any kind of stasis or secession
or this natural environment slowly
the biology and that slowly evolves
in succession so you have this just
climax type of community it's not going
to be that way and so I think that in uh
in agriculture
it's a balance I think it's what
whatever you're trying to accomplish is
really important I I would say that
fungi get more Disturbed than bacteria
just because of the structure that they
form and so if you have uh just in
really intricate involved uh established
fungal mats and you break that apart
that's going to disturb the
functionality of those fun times that's
not necessarily the case in in our
systems bacteria are a lot more
forgiving
through disturbance because their size
allows them not to feel the disturbance
like a uh like a larger organisms might
be
you think about farmlands where the
tilling versus no-tilling has been
argued and I think that you know there's
a practical balance where you'll see a
lot of farms where they have strips of
grass in between every other row and
that's the nurture of the mycorrhizae
and the fungi in the soil where there's
at least a presence of undisturbed fungi
that can help influence the plant growth
every year as they're planting out so
I think it's a really hard target to
think you're not going to disturb uh
Disturbed soils or work with disturb
soils
in in any type of Agriculture and I
think it's important to understand if
you're using biology to understand how
resilient that biology is uh that you're
that you're working with in that
particular environment
so not all microbes would do well you if
you're collecting to go back to your
example if you're working with tea and
you're taking uh samples from nature
well those natural samples a lot of that
biology hasn't evolved through love that
tea environment and so the environment
selects in biology it's almost like
basically a law the environment selects
and so you created a different
environment and now the biology is
working through that environment and you
talk about having the morphology of rods
but I'd argue also that there's probably
a lot of diversities because it's one
morphological group there's a lot of
different species and genus that
represent bacillus Rod shaped they could
be Grant positive they could be gram
negative I don't know if you did those
gram staining so there could be a lot of
diversity but you wiped out the microbes
that couldn't persist in that
environment and so now you're just
forced to work with the microbes that
that will work for you in your tea
environment that will work for your for
your you know for your farm
yeah just qualitatively under the
microscope you see a massive drop in
diversity over time which is got me
thinking about the whole disturbance
thing but one of the things that
um agronomist Lee Brice I had him on the
podcast he's he's he just he turned to
me and he goes Tad
agriculture is not a natural system it's
not natural right and I I have to remind
myself of that because people always say
you know Go Back To Nature do what
nature does well nature doesn't do this
it doesn't select for one you know one
species or one variety plant over at the
exclusion of all else and
so the amount of diversity in a forest
versus what we see on a microbial level
in agricultural lands is quite quite
drastically different and totally
um I I think we have to remember too
like in in an agricultural system every
time we Harvest a plant we're removing
biomass removing organic matter we're
removing nutrients and those have to be
replaced and if we can manage that
replacement to keep us at a level of
stasis that's optimal for you know cycle
after cycle that's really what we're
going for with soil testing and things
like that
um
so I I find it all all really
interesting and fascinating but I don't
get as worried about disturbance and
some more recent things that have got me
thinking about this and and again I'm
talking about indoor beds or pots I'm
not talking about yeah
uh tilling outdoor land I think there's
a lot of reasons not to tell for erosion
and other you know disturbance issues
but if we're talking about in indoor
beds you know hand tilling or hand
disturbing um
we know now that heavy metals tend to
accumulate in the roots and the stems of
the plants more than buds there's
research to support that so if we can
remove those things we're lowering the
amount of heavy metals in our bed which
is a good thing especially in states
where you're regulated uh from the
presentation in the research by Dr punja
we know that uh this viroid is going to
be more accumulative in the roots of the
plant so if we take those roots out
we'll be removing some of that that
Viral viral load so I
at this point and maybe someone will
convince me of something differently
um I'm inclined to remove as much of
that as we can
um so
I just I think it's all very fascinating
um do you think we'll ever fully
understand
all of this
um because it is so complex
listen I don't think we'll ever fully
understand even the human body and it
has an orders of magnitude more research
funding uh thrown at it than
microbiology to be fair and so I think
we'll continue to learn more and I think
20 years from now we're going to look
back and we're going to say now we
didn't understand that at all and that
just like viruses you know we've learned
more about viruses and thyroids than we
ever have before and we know about this
much about them
the techniques and methods and the way
uh the way they just function although
you know coronavirus has helped with
that with the research and funding to
understand that we it's like a drop in
the ocean on what I think we know about
these smaller life forms for a couple
different reasons and we're just it's
still pretty nascent although it's a
it's amazing what we've learned over the
last let's say 15 years I remember the
first time I went to a school of ecology
conference and they decided to open up
the black box of soil and agriculture
was considered soil a black box just a
constant that's how it treated soil and
it said we're actually going to look
inside and we're going to start
understanding the biology and that was
in the 90s and that's when kind of micro
wheel ecology started as far as I'm
concerned there was a lot of work done
before but it was very early and uh and
so yeah we still have a lot of fun stuff
to learn on this
yeah when we talk about the history of
Agriculture I think one of the reasons
we've been successful is like you you
mentioned the pH is the one of the main
variables in terms of influencing
microbial growth
and what microbes are successful well
that's where I think the soil testing
really was was important because I hear
people talk about like you know I'm an
organic grower I don't need a pH
anything and yes soil has amazing
buffering capacities but this idea that
you know
Farmers for years have been targeting
you know very specific pH ranges which
are not beneficial for plant uptake but
also beneficial for these microbes I
think maybe we were inadvertently
getting benefits that we weren't even
aware of on a microbial level and and
also why we why I believe soil testing
is so important when we're talking about
reamending and managing
you know a grow
so you know you're kind of talking about
I think about confidence and I think
consistency is key uh consistent inputs
or consistent practices ultimately yield
consistent results and consistency can
be a predictable range and especially
when we're talking about microbiology or
organic growing or living beds it's not
going to be consistent but I think that
what we want to do ultimately is predict
the range of confidence so we know the
ups and downs so to speak of what to
expect from functionality and and uh
just all the constituents of the soil
and then like you're talking about you
can manage that as long as you can
measure it you can manage it to think
it's static that's just not realistic in
in life at all especially with when
you're dealing with Biology
so that that's exactly right
so rather than what you're saying there
is what we're targeting is a range with
soils in terms of outcomes too yeah it's
not I think that's that's the way to
manage it yeah it's not just this finite
number it's a range of numbers but you
can control that it doesn't mean that
it's it's bad we just have to let go of
a little bit of our our control in these
systems absolutely listen I used to do a
lot of natural studies in grasslands and
whatnot and I used to do annual studies
where I would do quarterly and seasonal
I'd go out and take samples and look at
the Rises for microbes and look at how
the the population or the community
diversity change and it changes every
season depending on the conditions and a
lot of that although the soil was well
buffered as far as pH the plants had a
large influence and then the temperature
had a large influence and sometimes you
know the hydrology had an influence
there also where I could see a dramatic
shift in microbial Community assemblage
and populations or concentrations across
the growing season across four across
across 12 months or four seasons and
then it would come back and so my
predictable range was that annual cycle
where I could pretty much predict what
the microbes were going to be doing on a
seasonal level based on three or four
different parameters
so you can if you take a far enough step
back
you get that consistency or you're using
yeah right yeah totally exactly yeah so
I'm looking at my notes I know we're
running out of time there's one question
I didn't really get to ask you that I
wanted to that kind of fits into what
we're talking about here is
um
from my interview with Dr Michael
brownbridge one of the things he
mentioned was like I don't he doesn't
understand why there's so many products
in some of these uh you know
biostimulants or micro products on the
market you know there's a huge list of
microbes of what they're putting in
there
knowing that a lot of these May occupy
the same ecological niches or compete
for the same space and and like you said
knowing that these microbes are
constantly changing in in the in the
environment like do we want a more
targeted approach where we have one
microbe or us you know like mycorrhizal
fungus or trichoderma or or Bavaria or
do we want a Consortium of microbes in
our microbial product or do we want
um
I I get I guess do we need is it a waste
of money to be buying ones that have all
of these these in there when we could
just be a little more targeted about it
I guess
yeah you know I'm not so sure that cost
is is uh associated with the different
concentrations or the different formulas
of microbes okay
um I would say that
in general
it kind of just depends on the
confidence you have in that product and
what you think it's it's going to do
I've seen companies just throw
everything in the kitchen sink uh add a
product and just have everything in
there because that was their marketing
strategy I'm not so sure how much actual
scientific validation they had for the
formula rather than just throwing
everything in there and saying hey
everything's in there I think that it
does provide for some functional
redundancy if you have more species I am
a proponent of a consortia effect but I
would say uh responsible or a well
thought out consortia effect that's that
was the thought behind uh Mammoth
microbes or Mammoth p
that's also the thought behind the
microbial Mass technology you know you
have microbes you know what the microbes
are your promise is those microbial
concentrations and what they're doing
for your plant and I think that's a
really good approach when you start
seeing a large assortment of microbes I
think I really question the consistency
and I would I would suggest that it's
really hard to to manufacture uh with uh
with consistency a really large
consortia and maintain that in the
bottle over time
I'm not so sure it's bad or good I would
say that it's it's less defined and more
I would consider them much more General
Solutions just to help with nutrient
cycling and I would say that more of the
functionally targeted consortions are
are a very interesting approach because
there's typically a lot of thought
put behind not only the function of the
micro but the redundancy of the microbe
and the environmental resilience of
those microbes and that's why I'm seeing
the products that have a limited
Consortium there's a purpose for them
that's I think that's a good point and
one thing that I think that you and I
just kind of take for granted um and
that I hope other people will start
doing another and many people do is just
set up a trial like um have a control
test to see if this product in your
environment gives you an effect
um and you may be surprised by the
results like I for example was surprised
by the mammoth P results we got a gold
leaf
um I did not think we'd see any sort of
statistically significant difference in
yield and we did
um because I was like our soil already
has all this you know good microbial
activity and and everything so that
surprised me
um
and I think that's worth revisiting to
see if we're still getting those bumps
you know I think this is sort of thing
is you know people have to do this
ongoing don't just do one trial but
replicate it
um and now you know we're setting up a
trial right now now with the microbial
mass and gold Legion I'm excited to you
know hopefully get to document and share
those results
um but uh yeah I think people need to
test it out because I I I feel pretty
confident saying that there's a lot of
microbial products on the market that
give micro products a bad name whether
they just you know took a bunch of
powders out of China that were
supposedly these concentrations mixed
them all together because they saw a
research paper on it that said that they
were beneficial
um you know that stuff's out there and
some of them are quite popular and
frankly I don't think people are getting
the results that they they should be
getting for what they're paying for it
so
yeah totally I think that's absolutely
right and that you know you know I mean
that's the approach I've always taken uh
kind of the scientific approach I like
bringing validated Innovation into the
market to help the success of Growers
that was the whole intention kind of the
purpose I have professionally and and as
a scientist to be fair at the University
and so it's really important to measure
those results and to define success and
talking with the manufacturers to
understand what those expectations
what is the product intended to do and
then you can make sure you can measure
it to get those results you know if it
increases yield if it's supposed to
increase yield is there validating data
that the manufacturers have conducted
studies that shown that it's increased
yield and so you can actually start to
have some confidence that you would
expect that so you can measure it
same thing for a quality metric I've
seen products that you know promise
quality metrics well if you can measure
it and you have validating data that
supports that you know let's use the
product for its intention a lot of cases
there's not a real
purpose there's there's not a lot of
data back products out there and so
there's not a lot of expectations just
use it you're going to see good results
well okay but it's really hard to
measure that if you can't Define it and
so on both sides I think the
manufacturer should set clear
expectations of what the product does
for Growers and The Growers should set
real expectations of why they're using
the product and be able to measure that
and so yielding quality are pretty
pretty simple things if you think about
early stage cloning products or rooting
products let's make sure we can measure
root mass and add these products in to
see more root growth and so I still
think biology should be uh targeted to a
specific function a specific outcome why
am I using this I want to measure it and
it should do it just like nutrients and
everything else you know water does
something nitrogen does something
phosphorus does these things that we can
almost measure if we can't completely
measure we should treat microbes and
microbial Innovations the same exact way
with rigor
totally agree yeah
well I I super appreciate you taking the
time to chat with me today and I look
forward to uh you know some of the new
innovation and things that you have
going on
um and you know following up on this
trial with the microbial Mass product
um so yeah thank you yeah looking
forward to it great seeing you and
thanks everybody
[Music]
thank you
that was Colin Bell and you are
listening to the Cannabis cultivation
and science podcast I'm your host Tad
Hussey if you like the podcast please
leave us a rating in review or give us a
follow on Instagram you can also sign up
for our newsletter on our website
homepage to stay up to date on the
latest research and information thanks
for listening
thank you