[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discussed
the cutting edge of growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge
now before diving into the podcast I
wanted to fill you in on some changes
happening with our company earlier in
the year we received an anonymous
complaint regarding some structures on
the property after meeting with the
county regarding these structures some
other zoning issues came to light that
require us to remove a large amount of
our storage and covered spaces on the
farm due to this change we are closing
down our seven acre farm as a retail
location the feed store edible nursery
you pick and garden center are going
away and we are rehoming all of our
animals we will continue to have the
outdoor preschool on the property and
kiss' organics will carry on as an
online supplier of soil amendments soil
and supplies while it may seem like a
setback I'm excited for the opportunity
to refocus the business and have more
time to spend on the podcast soil
science and working with CAI Zen on the
consulting side maintaining seven acres
and having so many branches to the
business is a lot of fun but it's also
stressful and challenging with my first
child arriving in November I know I will
have my hands full anyway anyway onto
the podcast this week's podcast is a bit
different from my usual podcast i sat
down with Johnse a dedicated cannabis
grower and all around cannabis
enthusiasts who interviewed me on a
variety of topics ranging from soil
compost tea microbes growing philosophy
and much more the goal of this podcast
was to answer some listener questions
and just offer a different perspective
on some topics we've already covered in
past episodes I met Jon through our
patreon hangouts and it's been a lot of
fun hearing about his growing
experiences as well through the process
here's our interview together
[Music]
hey John thanks for coming on the show
today thanks for having me Jan yeah I
know this was gonna be a question answer
well you were gonna ask me some
questions but let's give lists there's a
little background about you before we
get too far into it
sure so I'm from Michigan um I grew my
first plants indoors in 1999 with very
little success but enjoyed the process
enough to continue to learn about it and
from there I had done various gorilla
grows outdoors on and off with also
varying success until 2008 when the
Michigan voters passed the Michigan
Medical Marijuana Act that's what I
became a caregiver and started growing
indoors again so I started using a peat
based medium who assaults fertilizers
and had pretty good success but you that
I could probably do a little bit better
so continued my research and came across
a YouTube video of guy growing in deep
water culture and was very impressed
with his results so I gave it a try
myself and after the first run I was
very happy the yields had improved the
appearance of the buds was nice the buds
got bigger quality seemed about the same
as it was in the heat with salt so I
stuck with it and had very good results
for many years until one ear like a
horrible case of root rot and tried
everything to stop there's different
products methods and nothing seemed to
work so I was in a panic
but luckily right around that time a
friend had told me about your podcast
so after binging just about every
episode I felt confident enough to start
my own organic living so grow so I
looked up a super soil recipe online and
the first time I used it I was sold it
was awesome the quality of the product
had gone way up the yields were just
about the same it was easy way easier to
do and it was cheaper so I
see a reason not to continue doing it
and I've been reusing my soil now for
two years and have been great results
still tweaking a couple things here
there but I am pretty happy with the
results so far and I'm not to say that
you can't grow great cannabis using
other methods but something that's this
easy to do affordable and natural is the
way for me and that's right Matt now
very cool that's so good to hear I look
I actually I really like it because I
beginning emails from people that said
you know this is something I've been
wanting to try out and then the podcast
sort of just gave me that little boost
of confidence to really dive into it and
yeah that's that's awesome I love
hearing that so thank you and for doing
what you do to encourage people to grow
this map it cuz it's great well cool I
know you've and I know you've collected
a bunch of questions here from from
listeners on both the the patreon site
and then also through Instagram and I've
sent you and you've kind of compiled a
list I look forward to kind of answering
some of those and maybe filling in some
of the gaps that that were left with the
different interviews with with podcast
guess so I'll let you take it away from
here absolutely okay we're going to
start with soils so question one what
would be a good starting point for
growers who want to start going fully
organic are there products methods or
Bruce that the average grower can
purchase or make without an advanced
understanding of soil science or
microbiology yeah this is a this is a
great question
and without getting too technical I want
to say first off you kind of have to
identify how you how you define the word
organic because there are certain
products that are allowed in organic
production that may or may not fit with
your own moral code or ethics around
that word so certain things like fish
hydrolysate for example is stabilized
with phosphoric acid which is man-made
or seaweed extract powder is stabilized
with potassium hydroxide and those are
allowed for use in organic production so
like I was just visiting a facility who
was using potassium hydroxide as a pH a
pH up or sorry pH pH up
so I get those confused sometimes and
they're like well so in theory we could
use seaweed extract powder to raise the
pH because that's approved but I
couldn't use put that potassium
hydroxide is so it's all a little bit
silly what I would say though is kind of
do your research on products if you are
going to use products but if you want to
be organic the best thing you can do is
just get started and plant some plants
in the ground don't overthink it
don't overcomplicate it there's a
million recipes out there just pick one
and get started and the you know I've
I've killed so many plants over the
years that's really how you learn don't
don't be afraid to try new things and
just just give it a shot I I would say
put plants in soil though don't don't
don't go with containers if you can help
it if you're in a situation where you
can plant a plant in the ground outside
that's where I would probably recommend
people starting awesome cool actually um
on that note is there a reason to use
raised beds outdoors as opposed to
digging a hole in the ground filling it
with organic living soil and planting
straight yes so this is a question I've
heard quite a bit and I'm a big
proponent of planting in the ground and
we're talking about outdoors and whether
that's directly in the ground or in a
raised bed just giving the plant as much
root space as possible because the one
thing you want to consider with all
plants and in all growing situations is
you have to figure out what the limiting
factor of growth is so is it is it
nutrients is it sunlight is it you're
watering there's so many different
things that can cause or stress a plant
out and so determining what that is and
then fixing that and kind of working
your way backwards sort of like a
priority list it is really important so
when we talk about planting in ground
versus in beds the things I look at
there are what's your floodplain like
how where's your water table at if it's
very high then you may need to do raised
beds
what sort of burrowing creatures are you
dealing with in your soil if you're
gonna have Gophers or something moles
that's going to be digging up
around those roots and causing
disturbance then you may want to put
something down underneath and then put
in a raised bed what is the quality of
your soil if your soil is it's just pure
clay or pure sand it's gonna be really
tough to grow in it but again that
there's no real reason not to go in soil
versus beds in the situation like that
really my big ones are water table
burrowing creatures and then the other
ones would be you know excessive heavy
metals or some sort of toxicity that may
have been caused by by the previous
owners of your land or some sort of land
management issue where I don't know was
there a gasoline stored right above
where you're trying to grow your plants
now well you're gonna want to get that
tested and make sure that that land is
clean because cannabis especially is
very good at accumulating nutrients and
heavy metals into its leaf tissue
there's plenty of research out there
that supports that so we want to be
really careful what were what we're
planting into but all that being said
nine times out of ten just put it in the
ground awesome that makes a lot of sense
cool so um when growing in containers is
there a way to recycle soil
Andrea meant between cycles while
keeping soil disturbance to a minimum
such as with no job yeah this gets a
little tricky so when we're talking
about living soils and reusing soils
there's a couple things to consider one
is the amount the volume of soil so how
much nutrients and how much biology can
really get going in a small container
you know with our soils I recommend at
least a seven to ten gallon container
for a full cycle plant now with all Auto
flowers that are you know smaller
genetics you could probably get away
with you know a five gallon possibly
even smaller I know Tim Wilson who I've
had on the podcast he's one of my first
guests he was back in the 70s growing in
very very small containers of almost
pure earthworm castings in his setup and
he claims to have had really good
success with that for me I like to have
a little bit larger container because
we're putting a lot of nutrients in
there
and when we talk about reusing that now
let's say let's just use a seven gallon
container as an example when we go to
reuse that
soyal the process is a bit more
complicated because that there's not
going to be a lot of soil left by the
time we remove the plant and what soil
is left is gonna be much more depleted
to where you're gonna have to amend if
you want to go water only which is
really challenging to do with a small
container you're not gonna be able to
get all those nutrients back into the
pot if you do add that many nutrients
what's gonna happen is that soil is
gonna thermally compost again you've
essentially just added all this food
that's going to feed the biology that's
in the soil mostly the the bacteria in
archaea and it's going to create this
exothermic reaction where it's gonna
heat up the container itself and plant
roots aren't going to like that so you
actually have to wait for that whole
process to occur so what some people
have done is they'll run two soils so
they'll have one soil in their
containers the other soil will be
sitting and they'll reinvent and then
they'll flip it back in for the next
cycle to me that's still a lot of labour
which is why I really like beds so the
advantage of a bed over a container is
you can have multiple plants in a bed
and if you go on our website you can see
we just did a study with with gold leaf
guard ins Ben Higgins did this and you
can hear about it in my interview with
him a couple podcasts ago and what he
talks about is how planting where you
have communal communal beds so more than
one plant per bed we actually get better
yield and better results than plants
that are you know isolated and planted
by themselves so you get that benefit
and then also each plant has access to
more soil per plant even though in
containers for example in this in this
trial that we did each plant had more
soil all to itself than in the total
amount per bed but it actually worked
out to where the plants able to push its
roots out further because it's not
limited by a container so root space is
not a limiting factor of growth and
these plants are able to communicate
there's a lot of really interesting
research around around there on that and
that soil in that bed is actually going
to be less depleted when you go after
harvest and so you can amend it at a
lighter rate and so what people like
gold leaf or doing and Justin who I had
on the
cast with legit they're just reading
right back into the bed lightly telling
it in and then replanting you know 24 to
36 hours later because they just as a
commercial facility they can't afford to
have downtime what are you doing with
your beds John how are you reading them
well actually I'm growing in 50 bill in
fabric pots and when the cycle is done
I'll just pull the the main stem out and
throw the soil ball back into a pile
chop it up admire iam end mints water it
down and then let it sit for you know
until I need to reuse it again and right
now I'm on a perpetual harvest so a once
a week I'm doing this um but the soil
actually ends up sitting for two weeks
is interesting you mentioned the
thermophilic because I guess the other
day I was checking on the soil and it is
happened to touch some of it and I
noticed it got hot so I sat there with
my iron thermometer and it was it was
only 85 degrees but you know the ambient
temperature was only 72 so it was
literally getting warmer than the air
around it which I thought was
interesting which I had never really
noticed before so what I guess but that
being said I am I'm killing it up I'm
I'm mixing it all up together really
good so all the amendments get in there
is there a disadvantage to that
obviously you did this funny you just
cited right there shows that ideally if
you can't have beds that's the way to go
but for those that for whatever reason
can't have a bed they'd have to use pots
is is a real disadvantage to breaking up
the soil like that and remaining no I
mean I've heard of people doing it so
many different ways there's people that
are topdressing those nutrients and so
rather than putting all the nutrients in
right at the beginning of the cycle you
could talk dress with them which I
actually think based on what I'm seeing
it's probably better but it is more
labour and I think it's a little
trickier to it's a little trickier to do
but if we want to talk about like
optimal plant health I think regular
feeding of nutrients whether we're
talking synthetic or
Organic I think is better for a plant
but it creates more work and also a lot
more challenges I think a lot of people
are still massively over applying
phosphorus we talked about that I'm
seeing it with nitrogen even that's
that's another one especially with
living soils you don't see so much or
hear about on the hydro side but you do
see it I think quite a bit with organics
but what I want to touch on is is this
idea that you talked about about the
soil getting hot so I think it's
important people think about that
because when we're talking nutrients
organic nutrients or when we're
reinventing our soil what we're doing is
we're feeding all these all the
microorganisms you know primarily like I
said that the bacteria and archaea and
when we do that they're going to be more
efficient at accessing that those
nutrients especially nitrogen then your
your plant is so we have to be careful
with how we're doing that so if we were
to put too many nutrients in let's say
we have a pot with a plant in it and we
add a bunch of fish meal so that
bacteria is gonna be more efficient at
accessing the nitrogen in the fish meal
then the plant is and so it's going to
they're gonna start reproducing because
it has all this new food they're gonna
go crazy and it's going to not only just
heat up the soil potentially but it's
also going to be better at accessing the
available nutrients in that soil to
where you may see a plant deficiency
along with all the other stress that
you're causing from the the heat of the
bacteria reproducing so rapidly so it's
important to not when you're when you're
amending soils it's not important not to
add too much so that you have an issue
like that and it's important to be aware
of when you are reinventing in that soil
is sitting that you let it cool back
down to ambient air temperature to know
that it's sort of stabilized and has
good nutrient cycling going on before
you put a plant into it if you're in a
hurry you know getting the soil out of a
big pile and into pots will slow this
process down dramatically so like for
example sometimes we've shipped soil and
even after letting it sit two to three
weeks just the process of begging it you
know
from a pile into the totes and then
sending it you know across the country
or you know on a semi-truck all that
jostling and the reintroduction of
oxygen can cause that so they heat up
again a little bit and when it does what
we want to do I tell people is you know
let it let it cook a little bit longer
is we like to say in the cabins industry
or get it into those pots you know
maintain the moisture content and then
let it sit and then give it a couple
days in and then they'll probably be
fine to plant into you but before you do
you got to reach down into there make
sure it's cooled off and not gonna not
going to overheat so that's sort of some
some questions I get quite a bit that
it's kind of good to clarify so I
appreciate that so if you were to just
say water seaport some cool water sixty
degree water in to that pot that had
been filled with the soil that is
currently cooking and I says no lower
the temperature temporarily will just go
back up as soon as the bacteria gets to
work yeah yeah you're not really solving
the problem with that yeah you are gonna
lower the temperature temporarily but
really what has to happen is that
bacteria has to have the time to work
through those nutrients and slow down
that biological process of consuming
them in cycling them so really it's a
little bit more of a waiting game or
removing the thermal mass so from a
composting perspective you kind of need
like a through a three by three by three
foot pile to really allow it to heat up
you know it's not going to heat up if
it's you just have a small amount even
if you add more nutrients to that just
in general as a composting rule so if we
can get the soil out into pots typically
that that introduction of oxygen the
movement of it slows that process down
and so it just it seems to work pretty
well but if you have a compost
thermometer which is a great tool for I
think a lot of growers to have what you
can do with that is you can check the
the soil temperature and make sure it's
not any warmer than your ambient air
temperature and then if you are cooking
soil you want to stay in that range of
sort of a hundred and three
thirty-one degrees Fahrenheit Fahrenheit
to 160 degrees that's where we thermally
compost material and if you can stay
within that range you're gonna kill off
any pathogens in the soil
you're gonna kill off any you know
insects weed seeds things like that but
you will maintain your aerobic
microorganisms a lot of the good guys
will still survive that process if you
stay under 160 which is interesting
because when I barbecuing or things like
that you know they give you temperatures
that you need to hit it's the same thing
you know how hot do I have to heat up a
piece of meat in order to kill off any
bacteria in it that may be harmful to me
without overcooking it you know so it's
it's the exact same thing it's kind of
interesting oh that makes sense
cool I actually kind of kind of on that
note is it possible to add too much Rhea
meant when reusing soil is there any
particular ingredients that we should be
using the caution like for the kids
nutrient experts yes that's a great
question so the things to be careful of
are phosphorus so things like fish bone
meal guano's I I was just talking with a
manufacturer their day about bat guano's
and he was saying about the process you
know that he's seen in the Philippines
where there you know how its harvested I
think from a sustainability perspective
there's a lot of better sources than
fossil that for phosphorous than bat
guano plus potential for contamination
you know just with the way they're
sourcing it and the fact that it's a
manure based compost so I really I
really like to watch my phosphorus
levels that's that's a big one the other
one I think that's really important to
take a look at is what sorts of heavy
metals are we bringing into our soils
this is one that I've been looking into
a lot more carefully lately and I've
really started to move away from soft
rock phosphate or any rock phosphates
for that reason especially because of
the cadmium contacted content and rock
phosphate other things like manure
sources you hear about supposedly
chicken manure is supposed to be a lot
higher in arsenic I've seen some chicken
manure compost and the arsenic
levels were actually quite good but that
is something I've heard traditionally so
knowing your inputs I think is really
important to eliminate things like
sodium excessive amounts of phosphorus I
mean yes your plant needs some of that
but not very much and then watching our
heavy metals so that's another thing
going too heavy with rock dust is going
to increase our heavy metal load without
giving us a lot more trace minerals
because you know your planet only needs
so much of those so those are the sort
of the starting points for me when I
start looking at inputs is finding out
the source of them making sure they're
as clean as possible and knowing yeah if
I had rock dust I'm in picking up these
trace minerals but I'm also gonna get a
little bit of arsenic a little bit of
cadmium a little bit of chromium
potentially things that I want to keep
it very low levels because like I said
there's research that shows that
cannabis will take those up do you
happen to know it is helps not a bio
accumulator of heavy metals is it
because I know it's a very common
amendment to a soil bit because I use it
myself a lot and there's mostly a lot of
stuff in the ocean that you might wanna
keep an eye out is you know anything
about that yeah I have a good spec sheet
on kelp meal here let me see if I can
pull it up really quickly while I'm
chatting with you but yes I there is
quite a bit in kelp let me look at the
sheet real quick it's just loading but I
would still be careful any time we're
talking about these products that have a
lot of trace elements I think you have
the potential for four things so you
come in there that you may not want as
high of levels of so I'm looking at this
analysis here and it doesn't look like
they show it on this analysis but that
doesn't mean it's on there so that's the
other thing to think about when you're
looking at a label or a spec sheet if it
doesn't have arsenic listed on there is
that because they didn't test for it or
because they didn't choose to list it
because it's not a necessary plant
nutrient alright those are those are
just things to be aware of so I I don't
know off the top of my head the other
one I see a fair bit of is aluminum
that's the other one you want to watch
that I forgot to mention before though
so what are some common sources of
alumina I am it's in a is it azomite is
that the one that contains a lot of
aluminum yes
azomite is aluminosilicate i believe
though the last time i looked at it as
in my test soap for years I was I was
always told that asthma was really high
in aluminum but then the last test I
looked at I don't remember seeing it
being excessively high relative to other
rock dusts but I need to go back and
take a look at that that's a great
question but anyone could go on there
and look at an analysis of azomite on
line
I'm just can't pull it up really quickly
in the podcast but that would be a good
way to check yourself and and you should
check that with all your amendments and
make sure you know I know what our
levels are with the amendments that
we're using in our soils but if you're
mixing your own soil it's a really good
idea to to track that down sure oh that
brings you to the next question
are there any soil tested companies that
you would recommend anything nation or
world wide as you trust or is that more
of a local thing great question so some
of it is it's better to work with a
local lab because they're able to give
you the data information pretty quickly
it's easier to work send in samples
usually they'll have an agronomist there
they can they can help you out the
problem I see with cannabis is one a lot
of agronomists don't understand it
there's just not they're not making the
best crop recommendations from some of
the recommendations that I've seen they
just default to Tomatoes which isn't is
is close but it's not the same the other
challenge I see with it is that
sometimes the labs can be very
inconsistent like this facility that I
visited earlier in the week the the lab
had sent them totally wrong numbers they
day and they just said oh oops weed that
was a different customers test and you
know he's trying to do crop analysis off
of this and making changes on a on a
harvest it's worth you know potentially
millions of dollars I would have been so
pissed off like if you've got to have
consistent results and for me when I get
sent lab tests from other labs that I
haven't worked with it gets challenging
for me because they all do so I have to
find out you know what sort of tests are
they doing how are they performing the
tests what's the methodology look like
what do these tests look like relative
to the
and I'm familiar with so if you take the
same sample and send it to different
labs you're gonna get two different
results there's going to be variability
and sometimes it's quite high so you
kind of have to get you kinda have to
pick a lab stick with it feel good about
it them in terms of the way that they're
doing the process and then base your
analysis on that otherwise it gets way
too confusing and then I would add to
that so the lab that we've been using is
Logan labs just because that's where I
started when I first started with you
know Steve Solomon and the intelligent
gardener back in the day so that's
that's who I've been working with and
those tests I can look at really quickly
and make really fast actionable
decisions which I really like if you do
do that in terms of the Logan test you
want to get the standard plus the extras
and then the saturated pace so the
standard test is a male like three test
it tells you all of what's in the soil
more or less it's an acid extraction
they're not perfect so that's one thing
I want to emphasize I know I've said
another podcast like don't get hung up
on a soil test you're not growing a soil
test you're growing a plant and if that
plant looks great and everything is good
don't freak out and if you ever get a
test back that doesn't look right have
them retested or send in another sample
because you never know like you might
have just gotten a little too much fish
bone meal in that particular sample that
you took in it threw off all your tests
so keep in mind this it's just it's just
another tool the the may like three
tests the standard test will tell you
all of what's in the soil the other test
the saturate paste is designed and again
they're not perfect but it's designed to
tell you sort of like what's available
to the plant right now so if I see just
a saturated paste test that doesn't
really tell me what's coming down the
line in terms of nutrient availability
so if I'm adding nutrients I'm it's a
little bit of a guessing game whereas
the first test only tells me what's
available to the plant right now or
what's of what's all is in the soil it
doesn't tell me what's currently
available so if I just put in a bunch of
you know let's say rock dust that may
not be available to the plant for a
while and so we may not see on the
saturated paste test the same levels of
nutrient availability that we would on
the mail like three tests that's why
people are using both those tests
I see but see you would rather stick
with one company and then get second
opinion for example and go with because
he said they'd be different from
different labs would you why wouldn't
you just send up to two different labs
and then compare the results and then
kind of take it from there or does it
make sense yeah I get what you're saying
so you're asking why wouldn't we take
the same sample and send it to two labs
and then Jesse about what kind of the
differences in the results well the
reason you wouldn't do that in my
opinion is just because it's expensive
because I've we've done that a different
facility that I visited last week did
that as well and they said the same
thing like man these tests are so
different and so how do you know which
test is more accurate you don't really
you kind of got to just pick a lab you
feel good about and then really just use
those results as guidelines so if I get
a test back and it says the pH is seven
point three the plants look great I'm
not gonna freak out I'm gonna say okay
maybe the pH and the rhizosphere is a
little bit lower maybe it's closer to
seven and so what I'm gonna do is try
and mitigate things you know alkalinity
down the road but I'm not going to you
know make any drastic changes provided
my plants look good so I use that soil
test to kind of point out anything that
just looks really wacky so if I start
seeing that over time my calcium is
getting too high and I'm starting to see
less availability of magnesium and
potassium then I know ok no more calcium
inputs even if the plants look good
let's start upping some of these other
cations as a way of improving the soil
over time without making any like
drastic changes ok it makes sense and
since you mention pH approach me to the
next question do you have two pH your
water when growing in the water only
organic living soil good question I like
to still pH my water if the if the pH
range is really far off you know if
you're already 65 does let's say 7/2
range I wouldn't worry about it I would
probably just use that water but I
always like to get a water test and I
like to know what's in my water so I can
manage my soil fertility based around
what is coming in with my water source
and I think that
something a lot of people fail to do
that's important especially if you're a
commercial facility like that's
something you need to spend money on is
is getting these sorts of tests down so
you know all of your inputs into your
soil and into your plant so that's where
I would start when we talk about pH -
like every time I bring it up you'll see
arguments online and people are like I
never pH I don't worry about pH you know
I threw away my pH pen you don't have to
deal with pH when you're talking about
living soils and frankly it's just not
true if we want to talk about optimal
plant health and optimal plant growth pH
plays a huge role in fact my interview
with Colin Bell who is the founder of
mammoth microbes and mammoth pee I'm not
sure which podcast is gonna air first I
have a feeling hisses so this is gonna
be a little bit outdated but one thing
he talks about was the research that he
did relating to pH and microbial
concentration in microbial growth so
when we talk about functional groups of
microbes pH plays a huge role in terms
of determining what microbes are gonna
be most active and and and thrive as
much so if we can create pH ranges that
are optimal for the functional groups of
microbes that help plant growth it's
it's only going to help our plants so it
does it definitely does play a role all
that being said the reason I think
people are successful with throwing away
their pH meter and honestly I don't have
one or use one I'll just get a soil test
what I find with that is just soil in
general especially microbially active
soils like these living soils they're
better at buffering pH than a hydro
system so you know a hydro system if
your pH goes off you're you're screwed
your plants you're gonna see it right
away whereas with these living soil
systems the plants able to control that
that area much better based on the
microbes that selects for with the X
States it's putting out into the soil
okay cool man I love that you brought up
mammoths because that translates
perfectly to the next question that I
had for you so um it's better come very
popular lately that is mammoths teen I
actually started using myself and had
great
results in the first ride but after I
remembered as usual using the regular
RIA Mendez I started noticing what I
thought was a phosphorus deficiency so I
was guessing that the phosphorus fixing
microbes are using up the available
phosphorus from the re amendment faster
than before I started using my in the
right path here is it okay to just add
more of phosphorous containing
amendments every run possibly what I
would probably recommend is is get that
$30.00 soil test from Logan labs that's
going to be way cheaper than buying more
mammoth pee just to start out and also
it's going to give you a good idea of
what your phosphorus levels are now
ideally you'd get that complete test and
get the the may like three the standard
test and the saturated pay so you can
see not only what phosphorus you have in
the soil but also what it's saying is
available to the plant and keep in mind
that that test doesn't take into account
these microbial interactions that you're
getting from mammoth pee so okay if you
have low phosphorus then yes that's
what's going on is definitely what your
what you think the other thing that I
talked to Colin about that we don't
really know is what sort of microbial
persistence are we getting how well are
these microbes surviving you know in
between cycles are they thriving or you
know as as we re amend that soil or are
we killing a lot of them off to where we
need to reapply microbial products you
know more consistently like every two
weeks every month something like that so
it could be a variety of things but I
will say you know I was I was skeptical
of mammoth pee there's so many microbial
products on the market and frankly I
come in was sort of a skeptic sceptical
I like why would I why would I want to
buy these products because one of the
things that Colin talks about to that I
think is really important is it's not
about any single microbe or any you know
particular species of or strain of
bacteria that you're using if we're
talking about pest control that's a
different subject but if we're talking
about fertility and nutrient cycling
it's really this idea of a consortium
all these microbes work together in
fascinating ways that we don't even
begin to comprehend and so we can't just
take out and say okay this particular
strain of Trichoderma has the
you know has this effect but it you know
by itself in situ and that it will
translate when we talk about you know a
complex a complex rhizosphere
into plant growth so one of the things I
like about mammoth P is they found that
when they took the five I think there's
five strains of bacteria in their in
their mix when they took one of them out
and tried it they got some plant growth
but not a lot and then when they added
another one the same sort of thing but
when they got all five together the sum
was greater than the parts so it is this
idea that they work together to create
sort of this this synergy and that's
sort of what's going on in our soils too
so I think that's an important factor to
consider I don't know what was going on
with your mammoth P I will say like I
said I was highly skeptical of mammoth B
but more and more facilities that I've
been working with it are using it even
with living healthy living soils are
seeing really good results so I can't
you know I I can't argue with the
science of it if I'm seeing you know
what weights going up 19 percent at gold
leaf and you know they're doing very
good job of keeping controls to make
sure that there's not some other
confounding factor in there I think I
really do think there's something to it
I was very impressed with my first run
obviously you know keeping the controls
is a little bit more challenging for me
but it was one of the only things I
changed and my goodness it was it was
impressive it's the real deal but uh
that's interesting though so cool cool
alright so I have another question
related to microbes so what are your
compost tea recipes and what stages are
growth you use that so first off I'd
refer people to our blog page on kiss
organics com I've put together a
document called compost tea guide it's
free to download it's like 18 pages and
I tried to fit as much information as I
could in there and there's also some
great recipes in there so people can go
on there
and download that for free and see some
recipes and and really dive into compost
tea so in terms of recipes though I like
to keep them simple so high quality
compost source is really important you
you really have just a few things you
have to focus on we're talking about
aerated compost tea you have to have a
brewer that provides good levels of
oxygen doesn't have any dead zones and
can maintain your dissolved oxygen
levels above 6 ppm for the entire brew
that's that's the goal of your brewer
and then you have to have good inputs so
we have to make sure that we're adding
we're adding a good source of microbes
that's your compost source that's clean
so we're not adding in you know things
that could potentially grow pathogens
and disease causing organisms someone
asked me the other day about you know
the risks associated with compost tea
and and we're talking about that I'm
like well if you're grabbing a handful
of soil outside and it may have you know
potentially you're in an area that could
have root-knot nematodes yes you could
be introducing something to your soil
that could be really really bad if
you're using a something that's gone
through the thermal composting process
then that's much less likely to be a
less likely to be a concern so that's
your biology side and then you're just
adding a food source for that biology so
how do we feed those microbes and the
easiest way on sulfur blackstrap
molasses a little bit of organic alfalfa
meal from my microscope work that's what
I find works really really well we have
a product called microbe catalyst
because one of the things that Colin and
I talked about in the mammoth pee
podcast is how different functional
groups of microorganisms respond
differently to different food sources so
the the microbe catalyst that we carry
it's just a dry granule and dissolves in
water it's a little more diversified in
terms of the amount of ingredients in it
so we're hopeful that we'll get more
diversified compost tea okay you can't
tell that qualitatively looking under
the microscope and frankly I need to do
more trials but there's a lot of
challenges around trying and testing
compost tea because every batch you make
is going to be different no matter what
you try there's just too much going on
there and too much variability sure okay
makes it so you talk a little bit
about fungal dominant teas yeah this is
a question I get a lot or I see a lot
online too like how do I make a
bacterial dominant T or a fungal
dominant T and people feel like they
want bacteria for veg or fungal e
dominant these different things and and
frankly I think to me I think that's the
wrong approach so when we're making
compost tea the whole reason we're
making it is to add increase our
nutrient cycling so what we want is a
bunch of microbes that are cycling
nutrients with good diversity in biomass
in our tea brew and then really we're
gonna let we're gonna let the
environment and the plant sort it out
from there so I look at it a shotgun
approach if I can make a balanced tea
that has good levels of micro of
microorganisms and good diversity then
and we put that out onto the soil then
the plants really going to select for
what it wants in the rhizosphere it's
gonna be putting out exudates that are
gonna feed specific microorganisms that
are gonna either improve the pH or
increase the availability of whatever
nutrients it's lacking or wants and so
we're not really in control of that
process now if we talk about fungal the
bacterial ratios which is something that
I know the soil food web people get
pretty pretty far into down the rabbit
hole yes it's true when we talk about
old-growth forests versus undisturbed or
when we talk about old-growth forests
versus Prairie lands they have very
different levels of fungal activity and
fungal growth and biomass relative to
bacteria but when we're talking about
growing in container media or growing
cannabis in you know in as an
agricultural crop it's a very different
situation and I think what we want to do
there is just put out all the microbes
we can and really let the plants control
that process so if you make compost tea
correctly you'll have good levels of
fungal activity and there's always going
to be bacteria in your tea and you can
adjust all of this based on your brew
length so that's the other thing people
talk about bacterial foods versus fungal
foods really the easiest way to adjust
your
the amount of bacteria and funguses just
to adjust to the length of time you're
brewing so when you first brew that's
first let's say 8 to 16 hours and again
these are these are gonna vary every
brew and also based on your environment
air temperature elevation water source
all these things are gonna have slight
views so this is a very general thing
I'm saying here but 8 to 12 hours or 8
to 16 hours a lot of bacteria is gonna
grow and then sort of that let's say 16
to 18 to 24 hours is when the the fungus
will start to grow and then when we
start talking about going 36 hours or
longer 36 to 48 hours we're gonna have a
lot more flageolets and things like that
taking off and then over time we're
gonna we're just losing diversity at
that point so I don't like to brew
beyond 36 hours because we're gonna keep
you know certain microbes are gonna be
more efficient at consuming the
nutrients or each other you know other
microbes in that tea so Oh after 36
hours diversity drops quite a bit so if
people want to start playing around with
that you know do a brew in 24 hours do
your next beer at 36 hours you don't
have to change your inputs necessarily
okay but in the name of diversity still
want that 8 to 16 hour brew for the
bacteria as well well you're gonna have
the bacteria the bacteria is gonna keep
growing so I don't worry about getting
you're gonna have bacteria in teas no
matter what so even if we talk about
like a fungal dominant II they're still
gonna be a lot of bacteria that's the
thing it's not like a one or the other
sort of thing whereas it's just not
gonna have the fungal content that you
made but the flagellants bacteria or am
i wrong no you're right they do so your
bacterial levels will fluctuate but that
does the flageolets are gonna take a
little longer to get going so at 24
hours 36 hours you still have a quite a
bit of bacteria if you want a tea that's
just going to be mostly bacteria you
know use a sugar source use your compost
and apply it it you know let's say 18 to
20 hours okay awesome
so um kind of on that note is you're a
brand a compost tea sprayer that you'd
recommend oh that's a tough question
I
haven't looked into it recently you know
we have a commercial sprayer that we use
that I tested with a microscope myself
but what I would say is there are there
are companies out there doing that DRAM
is the first one that pops to mind
that's DRA mm I've had there there
heading one of their head guys Kurt
Becker on the podcast they're great they
I'm sure they have a sprayer if you
can't afford one of their sprayers
because they are gonna be more expensive
you know let's say you just had a small
home grill go with a pump sprayer over
an electric sprayer even just something
like a sump pump with your finger over
the end of a hose is a better option
than a lot of these other sprayers don't
put compost tea in those little tiny
spray bottles that you squeeze with your
finger you know they can have a trigger
on them and they may hold like a let's
say a quart of water those will kill
your microbes don't put compost tea in
an atomizer as long as you keep in mind
it's a living organism and we want to we
want to apply a high volume at lower
pressure at lower pressure then you
should be okay so larger drop droplet
size is better than a smaller droplet
size for example you know arcing motion
with the application rather than
slamming the microorganisms at high
pressure into a you know into a leaf
surface or into the ground is going to
be better what I usually do with my
applications if it's not on scale is
just go around with a little bit of you
know go around with a cup and just give
each plant the pint or two of of compost
tea as I'm watering and I don't worry
about over applying it because it's just
beneficial microbes so that's not an
issue so if you are lucky enough to have
a microscope at home is it possible to
use whatever you spray you have sprayed
onto a slide look at it in the
microscope and tell if bacteria is still
alive Oh totally
yeah if you have a microscope that's
really that's the best way to do it I
would spray it into like a bucket from a
little further away and then collect it
out of there making sure that you know
you clean the bucket ahead of time but
that way you want to you want to apply
it like how you'd be applying it when
you applied it to your Lisa
so you'd want to stand a little further
back you know and apply it that way and
try it both through the spare check it
through the sprayer before the sprayer
since you brought up microscopes I know
this isn't gonna apply to everyone but I
want to give a calf you quick little
pointers from Tim Wilson that he shared
with me back in the day that were really
useful so when I started experimenting
with compost tea and using a microscope
in terms of microscope recommendations I
have a guide that Tim Wilson put
together it's on gardening with microbes
calm or microbe organics calm both have
that guide available he put together a
really good description on there and
then what what he taught me is if I want
to test out a compost or I want to test
out how a compost responds to a food
source it's very tedious to make up you
know a compost tea brew every single
time I want to do this you know that's a
lot of brews or a lot of Brewers it gets
really expensive so what what we do is
we take I use a container that holds
about a cup of water and has a lid he I
mean you could do it in something even
smaller and then I figure out the ratios
that I'm gonna be using in my brewer I
add those amount into my container and
that allows me to make up like let's
just call it a mini compost tea now
obviously I can't aerate that very well
so what you'll do is you take it and you
shake it really really well for like
over a minute just get it as much oxygen
there as possible and then take the lid
off and leave it out and then I'll come
back by periodically every few hours and
give it another put the lid back on give
another good shake take the lid off
again and by doing that it simulates
enough of an oxygen response or keeps
enough oxygen in the in the water to
allow us to get a kind of an idea of
what the compost tea would look like and
so I'll set up like you know 12 or 15
different things you know testing it
this if I want to test a compost I'll do
this compost plus distilled water then I
always use distilled water because it's
just going to be the cleanest water
possible and I'm not so I know I'm not
contaminating with other microbes and
I'm not using water that canes
that's gonna kill microbes and then I'll
say this compost + molasses this compost
+ alfalfa meal this compost + our
microbe catalyst and then I can be
surprised when you look under the tea at
you know 12 hours 18 hours 24 hours how
much those teas very is shockingly
dramatic it's pretty cool and that's
where you can start trying out different
iterations and then once you have a good
idea of what direction you want to go if
you're like okay wow you know like for
me and we noticed this using five
different hemic acids we saw microbial
suppression so it actually we got less
microbial growth than we did over just
compost and water and so when we did
that we said okay wow so let's test this
out so then we started doing you know
full-size brews with Hema Casas and
found that we it actually supported that
at that result so this is sort of way to
test things out without having to make
up you know all these different compost
tea brews or if you have a large Brewer
that's you know 100 gallons you don't
want to have to brew up a hundred
gallons of tea every time you want to
try something out that just doesn't it's
just not cost-effective okay yeah that
makes sense
so really the takeaway is the diversity
of microbes right yes that's that's the
big takeaway when we talk about soil
health is diversity and we see it in
nature everywhere it's not just in soils
everything is help is healthier with
diversity when we talk about our own
food and diets they always talk about
diversity you know it's it's so
important to every ecosystem in all of
ecology it's not shocking that we need
to support that in our soils as well
awesome cool well I want to shift gears
a little bit away from microbes right
now I have a question here have you have
any have you read any scientific studies
or very discussion about the intentional
stress in your plants yeah this is a
good one um I've talked about it a
little bit in past podcast but I like
that someone asked this question on
Instagram because it's something that I
hear quite a bit around cannabis it's a
really really interesting topic what I
would say is this so yes there is
research out there that shows that
stressing a plan is going to cause it to
put more energy into
you know certain things that we wanted
to produce like fruit or it's you know
in this case it's flower it thinks so it
thinks it's dying you know our slow Lisa
messing and it's going to put more
energy into those things or the things
that help protect the plants defense
mechanisms which in this case is the
trichomes and you hear these stories
it's so funny as a grill every grower
knows that we're like oh man I had this
plant it looked terrible I threw it out
in the compost pile or I just that
something went wrong this grow cycle and
all my plants freaked out and yield went
down but oh my gosh
this is the best bud I've ever grown
this stuff just finished so good you
know such a common story right and
that's where we're talking about that
plant stress creating a response that's
positive but all that being said I just
can't get behind us stressing our plants
because one I think the most important
thing to keep in mind is pretty much
every grow I've ever been to already has
plant stress going on at some level
there's already there's so much going on
which is so hard to maintain maintain
the optimal conditions that I think most
plants are going to be stressed
naturally so that's something to factor
in secondly we don't really know at what
stage a plant growth or at what point
with what genetics this these stressors
are going to be most beneficial so you
know I know people will drop
temperatures people will water with cold
water or stop watering or stop adding
nutrients and everyone claims different
results the research just hasn't been
there yet in my opinion to really say
that one method is is the way to go so
at this point I just I try to eliminate
plant stress as much as possible
realizing fully that it's still going to
occur and until we can find more
research on it specifically for cannabis
because there already is this research
around other crops I've seen I think
I've talked about this too but it was
really interesting I read a study about
how and I believe it was Italy with
their Tomatoes they would flood their
fields with salt water and that salinity
would stress the tomatoes and create a
much more flavorful higher an
antioxidant tomato and they had the
timing of this all down so it's really
interesting
but do we know where that that point or
how that exists with cannabis at this
point in time I would say no more
research is needed yes sure definitely
ha ha nice cool all right so you can
repeat a lot of really cool people over
the years on your podcast which of the
creative methods have you incorporated
into your own home garden yeah you know
I've I've been really fortunate that
I've gotten I've gotten to interview
some really really intelligent people
and that have done some really
incredible work for me in terms of what
if when we talk about my own home garden
the things that I've incorporated on my
farm
were the stuff from Steve Solomon in the
intelligent gardener so I started
experimenting more with soil testing
Andrea mending to to start balancing out
these nutrients before you know I was
just sort of in that soil food web cam
food web camp where we would just add we
would just focus on biology this idea
that if you got the biology right that
all the nutrients would come into play
and the plant would handle it and you
wouldn't have to worry about it and I
just I just don't I just don't buy into
that anymore
you know when we start talking as I've
gotten to meet a lot of soil scientists
and people that are really active in
ecology and things like that it just
doesn't add up
you know the research supports the idea
that if we can create if we can add
nutrients to fix whatever limiting
factor of growth there is then we're
gonna have a healthier plant and not all
soils contain the same levels of every
nutrient I mean it's pretty it's it's
pretty obvious stuff so we want to make
sure that we're getting the plants the
nutrients it needs and making putting
them in a form that's gonna be
accessible to the plants so it can be as
healthy as possible so the stuff from
Steve Steve Solomon I don't totally
agree with all of his targets when it
comes to cannabis I think it's a good
starting point and I think people can
get too caught up with soil tests so I
don't want to say you know go too far
down any one path but I do think that a
lot of what he says I love the
introduction chapter introduction
introduction to his book if you
read nothing else in the intelligent
gardener or the numbers are too much
just read his introduction because it
starts making you think about nutrients
and soil testing in a way that I think
is really powerful I do I do really
appreciate the work that dr. Ingham did
in bringing attention to soil microbes
in the soil food web I think that that
has a lot of value and that's sort of
like I said where I started my path
because of my father and his compost tea
business so I'm indebted to her for that
I don't I don't agree with everything
that she says regarding bacterial or
fungal ratios and the stuff around
nutrients but again there's a lot of
ways to grow a plant and I don't want to
you know I don't want to come a come
across too harsh when we're talking
about all of these different sort of
ideologies around growing one thing I've
had conversations off-air with people
about is when I think I think when you
get too into any one of these paths
whether it's you know KNF for probiotic
farming or ba dynamics or soil food web
or nutrient dense farming or natural
farming you know there's all these
different groups that are all slightly
different there all of those are on the
organic side too which is awesome
but they almost start to feel a little
more like a religion then like a
methodology and I think that's where I
sort of I think that's sort of where I
separate because I don't think you need
to bury a cow horn on a full moon to
grow a healthy plant necessarily you
know and that's not to say that's a bad
practice like if people want to go on
doing that fine you know but like for me
I'll take bit I kind of take bits and
pieces from all of these guys and then
figure out what fits was sort of not
only just my my growing methodology but
also just sort of my like moral and
ethical code and what feels right for me
in my soil like some people it's really
important to them to you know plant with
the moon and that's great I'd have no
issues of that I don't want to say it's
good or bad what I would love to do is
try it out run a study see do I get
better results you know all other
variables being the
if I plant when the moon is at a certain
certain stage in its cycle so my thing
is let's let's take a critical eye to
all of these approaches and then try and
figure out what aspects of them or what
really makes them successful its kind of
focus on that part of it so for me
Steve Solomon I know I'm getting off
topic here but Steve Solomon was really
big
I think Jeff Jeff's book teeming with
microbes is a really good starting point
for learning about microbes oh yeah and
so he kind of got me thinking about that
I think the one he's had the biggest
impact on me just off the top of my head
cuz I don't know I may I may think of
others down the road would probably be
Suzanne Wainwright Evans so this idea of
entomology and bio controls was just a
whole new world to me
and it really got me thinking more about
insects in the insect world and that's
been really fun getting a dino light and
starting to look at insects has been
just a blast I think Nelson Linsley is
probably the podcast that most opened my
mind to different ideas in this idea of
sort of a hybrid approach using you know
ionic nutrients in a more sustainable
method which I thought was really
interesting you know giant Palmer is a
great friend of mine so having him on
was was a lot of fun and and him and I
have worked together for years on
research side of things so that was
great and then I think what I think
probably the most useful like the most
powerful podcast I did might go to dr.
Allison justice and some of the research
she shared that they've done I thought
that was pretty amazing if I had to pick
like a best of podcast but yeah you know
I learned something from every guest and
it's so much fun so that's I think
that's the coolest thing is I'm always
learning and I hope that never changes
right and as we all should and I think
it's great advice to compile bits and
pieces from all different aspects of
your education to get a method that
works for you you know everybody's
different and you know there's more than
one way to do things and that's that's
an awesome stuff that I love it
sweet so I got one last question here
and it's it's a doozy
so what challenges have you faced
running an independent nursery in an age
when they are rapidly disappearing
how do you stay independent yet relevant
in an increasingly commodified
marketplace while still paying the bills
what books are you reading that relate
to your working professional growth okay
let me come back to the book question
cuz I that's probably the one I'm the
most excited about right now talking
about I know we talked about that pre
podcast but we sure let me focus on the
first one so you asked could you repeat
the first part of that question that was
yes sorry alright so um what challenges
have you faced running an independent
nursery and engage when they are roughly
just spirit okay so when I started kis
organics and set up kis farm I was
getting really into Victory Gardens and
there was no there was no feed store in
Redmond so to be fair that you know we
had the compost tea business I'd started
mixing soils just to experiment from my
own growing purposes but I hadn't really
dived into it that far and we got this
seven acre property back that was
beautiful you know my parents had had a
nursery on there before there was a
nursery on there currently and I wanted
to do something differently well
different with it I was getting into
chickens and free-range animals for for
growing your own your own food and I
thought urban farming was the future so
I kind of tailored the business around
that I didn't I wasn't very strong you
know I'm my mother made me do a business
plan back in the day because it was
their land and they were helping with
some investment money which I looking
back now I hated it but I think that was
really important I wasn't strong on the
business side at all I should have done
more research into how much money you
actually get for lugging around a
50-pound bag of chicken feed it's really
it's really a tough business so I think
having looking back I wish I had been a
little less idealistic and a little more
pragmatic and done some more research so
I think I had a good idea but I didn't
really know
where that idea would take me so I also
thought you know there's all these cool
edibles out there I should offer unique
edibles and be an edible nursery no one
else is doing this
this urban for the food thing is the
future and so I just went with it and so
we got all these we would spend all this
money and got all these really cool
edible plants really really cool plants
and frankly nobody cared so I was like
why did I do this you know and it takes
time too for things to catch on and
things to build and I didn't I think I
over diversified our business so we had
all these animals we had a preschool on
the property we have you know chickens
running around and ducks and goats and
pigs and we had we had this edible
nursery and we were trying to keep all
these plants alive and healthy and I was
expecting a staff to be able to know
about picking pigs and chickens and
ducks and you know gummy berries and
elderberries and apples and it was just
it was a lot and it was also too much -
for me trying to manage and run all this
one of the first things I learned is
like I'm not a great manager or leader
of other people I'm very good at self
motivating and I think I can come up
with some good ideas but at the end of
the day like trying to trying to manage
this huge thing was really really
challenging so looking back if I I think
as if I looked at this business over
again I never would have done the
nursery because I just didn't have the
right staff in place to keep everything
healthy and alive because you really
have to have a lot of plant knowledge to
have someone scouting and really
maintaining that and I couldn't give it
the energy that I needed because I was
too busy dealing with something else all
the time you know so we had we had a
whole greenhouse we plant out every year
and we we would we would do an okay job
but we could never keep up with weeding
because we didn't have enough staff and
then we'd have this whole nursery that
always looked okay but we weren't able
to always you know our irrigation would
break or we wouldn't we wouldn't catch
it you know a pest coming onto the
property fast enough little things like
that or our chickens would get feather
lice so there was always something
happening and so it always
like a crisis you know starting at
business is by far the hardest thing
I've ever done and it's uh I have
memories of you know working until 6:00
in the morning and the roosters crowing
behind me and I'm still making up tea
brew kits in the garage or sleeping you
know in a tent on the back of the
property because I didn't want to take
the 15 minutes it would take me to
commute home and go in my own bed and
then go back to work the next morning
you know so it was a lot and looking
back at it I don't regret a single
minute I think I wouldn't be the person
I am and I don't think I would have the
business that I have if I hadn't done
those things but I think I could have
been a lot smarter about it and I think
that I could have set myself up to be a
lot more successful had I had I been
more strategic like put in a lot more
time on the planning side and less time
just trying to put out fires if that
makes sense
you asked about books right oh yeah yes
sorry the second part of that was um so
yeah well what books have you been
reading that relate to your working
professional growth yeah this one this
is probably the question that's most I'm
most passionate about right now because
my my values and things have stayed
fairly much the same throughout this
whole process like it was always really
important to me with our business that
we had we were an educational center
that all came from my parents mostly my
father he's just so passionate about
organics he's passionate about the
environment he's a big hippie and he
always will be and I love him for it you
know and he really shared this this
enjoyment of nature with me and so the
the ability to allow children and the
public to interact with these animals
and eat this healthy food and see this
growing process it's been invaluable
like I I don't regret that for a moment
and I think that you know the one key
thing I would tell people is like stick
to your values that's the most important
thing like even though the farm itself
has not been particularly successful
relative to kiss organics it's been like
emotionally in
like spiritually valuable - not to the
community and to myself and to the
employees so that's all been really
really powerful and one of the things
some of the things I've learned over the
years now since then in running a
business is a lot of the books I've been
reading so I want to give credit to my
wife because she is a marketing whiz and
she made me realize that like it's not
about having the best product and in
this case I'd say it's not about having
the best cannabis you could be the best
grower in the world but if no one knows
about what you're growing you're not
gonna ever you're not gonna ever sell it
and so I I never I was always like
marketing advertising big deal I don't I
don't need to worry about that I don't
care about that I'm just gonna focus on
what I'm good at and what I'm passionate
about which wasn't those things and I
regret that and for anyone starting a
cannabis business out nowadays that's
listening to this get your marketing
advertising going as soon as possible
that's the best piece of advice I can
get you build a brand and so like this
podcast was my way of doing that and
it's been such a wonderful experience so
I've learned that marketing in
advertising doesn't have to be a
negative thing it doesn't have to be a
drag it doesn't have to be gimmicky I
think if you can if you can find your
message and make it real that's really
really powerful and some of the latest
things on the marketing advertising
piece that the two books that I really
enjoyed was contagious by Jonah Berger
and you can go on YouTube and look him
up he's got a lot of talks so
interesting we talk about science and
what makes ideas
what makes ideas stick and what makes
ideas take off I love his books and made
the stick by chip Heath is another one
along those lines you know you can get a
lot of good gems out of that but then
when we talk about like books that have
changed the way I run my business on the
business side there's a really really
good book called never split the
difference by Chris Foss I think
everyone should read it saved me twelve
hundred dollars within the first week of
reading it it's the it's a good book
about a guy who was like a he was a
terrorist negotiation expert like the
head of it for the FBI
and so he talks about all these all of
his experiences from you know talking
people out of you know talking people
off the edge edge of a building to
buying a car and he just made me
realized that like everything in life is
negotiable
and it or is a negotiation and the book
is hilarious and so powerful everyone
should read it the book I'm reading
right now is called the 80/20 principle
and I think that's another book that's a
must read I learned about it from the
4-hour workweek with Timothy Ferriss and
I don't want to say that you should
necessarily read the Timothy Ferriss
book because it's he's a lot as you and
I were talking about for sure so I don't
want to I don't want to necessarily say
that that's the book to read but the
80/20 principle is fascinating it's this
idea that like 80% of your energy goes
into 20% of the things you're doing and
it doesn't have to equal 100 but this is
just rough things or 80% of your revenue
comes from 20% of your clientele so why
not put your energy into that 20% or
what I would say is like probably like
50 percent of my time goes to 5% of my
clients some people just require a lot
more hand-holding through this process
or they have complaints about your
products or they have all these
questions you're just constantly
spending time like pointing them to
links on the website you know or and
more information and what I'm learning
is like why are my putting all my energy
into those people when I can be putting
my energy into the part of the business
that's more important to me that I'm
more passionate about and that's more
profitable so that's a great book and
you can apply it to your life like if
you know 80% your happiness is coming
from the 10% of the time you're spent
hiking how do you how do you change your
life to spend that time you know
increasing the amount of time that
you're doing doing the things that make
you happy
like that nice so that's a great book
but it's all based for him in an economy
perspective so so that's fun too and
then the last one I have to mention this
sort of a guy who's kind of become a
personal hero of mine over the last
couple years his name is Jesse it's leur
he's him and his wife are a lot of fun
to follow on Instagram she's the founder
of Spanx
which is so she's like a
multi-millionaire in her own right but
he wrote a book called living with a
seal and this book is just it's one of
the best books I've ever have ever read
it's so great it's hilarious and
powerful and he's also written a second
book called living with a monk and I
can't recommend those books enough in
fact if I had to pick one book to tell
someone to read it be it'd be that book
living with a seal by Jessie its lair
because it's just it's awesome it's this
idea that we have the mental power to to
really do whatever you want and do one
big thing every year you know there's no
reason we get stuck in these ruts where
we just go through life and do the same
thing over and over again and he really
challenges that in a way that I think is
really special so I'm now looking at my
life differently and thinking about how
do I you know what's really important to
me not just with my business but with my
personal life and how do I value or take
the things that I value and really focus
on them and and the biggest thing is I'm
getting older I'm I'm 42 I know a lot of
the growers and people that listen this
show are younger than me I think about I
think about my time like where do I want
to be spending my time is it you know
sitting in front of the computer
answering emails which is an important
reality of my job or is it spending time
with my with my wife and our soon to
soon daughter to be that's you know
gonna be born here in November mm-hmm
I'm so excited I know like all right
thank you all these life changes and
like how do i how do i center my life
around the things that are really
important to me so awesome man yes great
yet cool man well hey thank you so much
for doing this I really appreciate it
and thanks for doing everything you do
to educate those out there about the
science of cannabis cultivation thanks
John that was a lot of fun I really
enjoyed it you were a great host and I
look forward to talking again soon
that was John Z and I and you were
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast
I'm your host tad husky of KISS organics
I'd be honored if you can leave me a
rating and review on whatever platform
you're listening on our website is WWE
for all your soil amendment and soil
needs we also work with some lighting
companies like fluence and bios and
offer other equipment for your garden we
are very competitive on pricing if you
want help with glue mats and a custom
design shoot us an email at Ben at K is
organics calm for more information he's
been helping me out with the blue mat
stuff and it's great having him on board
with kiss we are offering consulting to
through our consulting company Kaizen
consulting you can reach us by filling
out the form at ww-with Kai's ENCOM
that's ka i z en comm thanks for
listening