[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss the cutting edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge my podcast this week is with
Virginia Emery Virginia is the founder
and CEO of beta hatch a pioneering
insect farming company that is
industrializing insects for agriculture
beta hatch is fueled by a passion to see
insects reach their true potential in
our food systems the company has grown
to be internationally recognized for its
scientific approach to scaling insect
production and operates North America's
largest mealworm farm for animal feed
production in Washington Virginia is the
country's most Innovative insect
entrepreneur recently recognized as a
Visionary Grist 50 fixer Virginia has a
PHD in entomology from the University of
California Berkeley and has been awarded
over 20 grants and honors and is
published on subjects ranging from
chemical communication to genetics to
insect Behavior her life's mission is to
breed a bug that tastes like bacon some
highlights of frass use in relation to
cannabis production are the following
it's a clean product ideal for indoor
growing because their insects are
growing indoors in climate controlled
conditions on organic feed there is no
risk of pests heavy metals pesticides
herbicides or fungicides coming into the
greenhouse uh it's a highly soluble
source of nitrogen immediately available
to plants their Studies have shown
increases in leafing and fruiting unlike
a conventional mineral fertilizer fras
contains small concentrations of
micronutrients like copper zinc and
manganese studies suggests the addition
of frass stimulates soil microbial
activity especially when it is mixed
with mineral fertilizer suggesting a
synergistic effect between both uh taken
together results indicate that fras has
a great potential to be used as a
partial or complete substitute for
mineral NPK fertilizer their frass is
produced locally in Washington state in
a zero waste system and is omry and USDA
certified organic now on to the
show hey Virginia thanks for coming on
the show today thank you for having me
yeah I'm excited to learn more about uh
insect grass and uh insect rearing and
production can we start off though by
telling uh listeners a little bit about
your
background yeah sure so I am an
entomologist by training so I'm a bug
expert uh they call me the bug lady in
Seattle where I've been um sharing my
business for a couple of years uh my
company is beta hatch and we Farm
insects as a sustainable protein um and
one of the Great um co-products of our
process is fras fras is the word of the
day today it's uh the technical term for
insect poop so we have a saying at beta
hatch that frass happens um and the
company's been a couple years under
development I started working on this in
2015 and we've been operating
commercially for about four years um you
know I got started with the business uh
because as an entomologist you know
about 99% of what you work on is how to
kill bugs we kind of have this very
antagonistic relationship with insects
and it it's really leaving a lot on the
table I mean bugs do incredible things
as far as ecosystem services for us um
and everyone's very familiar with
pollination but you know organic waste
recycling and nutrition is an area that
we we see a lot of missed opportunities
and so that's what beta hatch has been
working on is just making sure that
insects can be part of that um circular
regenerative food system
so when you started beta hatch uh is
there a reason that you chose uh meal
worms as your main uh I guess insect
source of uh frass or for breaking down
material versus some of the other
options out there like black soldier
flies yeah well so I guess there's the
the technical reasons that I could quote
you you know our bugs are dry adapted um
they've got a lot of genome diversity
which is useful for breeding they can
eat all kinds of feed stocks break down
Mich toxins there's all kinds of things
like that I could quote but sort of the
initial start which is probably more fun
for your listeners is that I I started
off growing bugs in um a little shed at
my house in Ballard we called it the
Ballard bug burn it was basically a
little climate controlled shed that I
grew a couple dozen species of bugs in
while I was experimenting at first and
one of the big things that was a first
sign that the mealor was going to be a
good species to work with happened over
the summer when I uh went away and uh
had neglected some of my insect colonies
because I had been out on vacation and
when I came back um most of the bugs
were in trouble you know in the case of
some flies had literally flown away but
the MS were just happy and contented and
uh a few months later I found a box that
I had neglected for even longer and um
you know stuffed away sort of back on a
shelf and they were also doing just fine
these are really Hardy insects and so um
that was the the first um you know I
guess indications that the mealworm was
going to be a really great insect that
um could handle all kinds of the
challenges that we've run into as we
work to scale up production um they're
just really hearty bugs that can um you
know basically withstand very cold very
hot
temperatures um all kinds of humidity
levels and can eat almost anything um so
it's a uh really they're a really nice
uh insect to work with from a you know
if you're a smaller producer just
looking to get started producing bugs
one of the easiest ones to to work with
but then also from an industrial
standpoint where we're working with beta
hatch they're super amenable to
Automation and there's a lot of reasons
that it's actually a lot cheaper to
produce them so yeah I mean I'd
encourage anyone who's um you know
interested in in trying out raising some
bugs me rooms are a great place to start
so I would like to hear from you about
what um or or I guess how uh a home user
may be able to start incorporating meal
worms into their uh you know their goals
for sustainability with composting but
before we do can you talk a little bit
when you said that meal worms are really
good eating a wide variety of food
sources what sorts of things do you feed
your meal worms and what are they best
known for in terms of consuming yeah so
we're um you know pretty focused on
ensuring that what we're doing is is as
sustainable as possible so we've been
looking at industrial co-products and
byproducts mostly from food processing
um at our facility in Cashmere
Washington we're actually one of the
ingredients we use is um a apple
byproduct we're in the wachi valley it's
the Apple capital and there's a an apple
processor just down the road from us
that's probably less than a mile to go
and get that feed stock which is
incredibly short supply chain so um they
can eat actually a huge range of things
um we've looked at over a hundred
different ingredients and there's
nothing we found that they can't eat
they can actually even eat plastic um
and so you know we've been from an
industrial and sort of commercial
perspective focused on feed stocks that
make sense for us um economically but
also from a sustainability standpoint
trying to make sure that as we're
looking at um inputs we're trying to
find the ones that have both the the
lowest cost but also the lowest
environmental Footprints um
and making sure we're not diverting food
from other uh sources such as other
animal feeds um the meal orms are stored
grain pests so they've been living for
Millennia with us in our stored grain
and so you know the common things people
think about are oats and Wheats and uh
those grains that you might um have
found a a stray insect in before and
certainly we've done a really good job
of eliminated eliminating them as a St
grein pests um but the you know that's
sort of their history of how they've
evolved um for eating but because
they've been these you know scavengers
in many ways they have incredible
digestive Powers they're like little
bioreactors and the gut microbes and all
the things living in their guts allow
them to break down all kinds of stuff
and as I said even plastic the only
known way to biodegrade polystyrene or
styrofoam is in the gut of a meal worm
so it's a pretty
incredible um set of things that they
can be eating now is there any risk of
uh pests or pathogens with mealworm
production or
rearing well it's an interesting
question um we're very much farmers in a
typical sense we've got a crop we worry
about you know the pest and disease that
can impact them they can get sick just
like anything else viruses and bacteria
and um you know in our case pest control
of just making sure that we don't have
any other insects coming in is a big
concern and we've basically made
Paradise for bugs everyone wants to live
there so we have to be really careful
about uh ensuring we don't have any um
pests established in our facility um but
it's also very different than a lot of
traditional farming because it's
completely indoors we control every
aspect of production from the inputs you
know the growing process you know the
sort of manufacturing pieces that just
allow us to separate out the product um
it it's lot more like a factory kind of
setting almost like a clean room setting
than it is a farm with soil so it's kind
of an interesting place to um you know
we kind of straddled that divide between
being a farmer and being a
manufacturer um but the beauty of that
indoor production is that because we
have total control over the process and
the inputs there's very minimal uh risk
in our products so that means both from
a path you know pathogen standpoint the
microbial um components uh and then you
know there's no um you know residues of
soils or risk of uh things like heavy
metals in the products so across the
board because we have such a great
control over how we're growing these
meal worms we can actually ensure a much
safer product um for both our feed
products where the meal worms themselves
are being used as feed we can ensure
that there's been no bioaccumulation of
any kind of toxins we can make sure that
it's um you know everything we're doing
is organically produced and so we Source
organic ingredients for um our our Pro
process and so everything is certified
organic and then on the fertilizer side
the FR side of the equation um we can
also ensure there's no pests or
pathogens in there so this is basically
a microm manure where you're not going
to have any kind of risk of um any kind
of insects or other microbial um issues
that might of concern um to anyone who's
using the
products yeah I probably we probably
should back up and talk about what the
end products are from uh your mealworm
production and then also what the life
cycle of a mealworm is yeah yeah there's
a so much um uh to talk about here the
the meal worms I'll start with the life
cycle um the meal worm as it's commonly
known is not a worm at all it's an
insect and the adult is a beetle so it's
you know similar to how a butterfly will
go through this transformation of uh
being a caterpillar to a cocoon or pupil
stage into the adult which is a
butterfly that lays an egg we have a
beetle that lays eggs those hatch into
the larvae also known as the meal worms
and that's the main product we Harvest
and then a subset of our system we are
breeding these insects and so we allow
them to go through pupation they become
Pupa they kind of look like little
aliens in the pupil stage and then those
guys will um turn into adults and the
cycle continues um and so that whole
process can take as as long as a few
months or short as a few weeks um
depending on how we handle um handle
them and treat them and what we're
feeding them typically we're looking at
around two months um from egg to product
in our case um and you know as we're
growing them the main product is the
meal worms the larvae themselves and so
we Harvest those mealor worms as a
nutritious high protein high fat feed
ingredient for Animals we're really
focused right now on backyard birds so
anyone who's got a flock at home this is
a
fantastic uh way to give a big
nutritional boost to your birds
certified organic made right here in
Washington and so the um the larvae are
the feed ingredient they're great for
poultry but also great for fish um um
and increasingly we're we're exploring
all our options in pet food so even cats
and dogs love meal wors so that's the
bug piece of the equation and then of
course as they're growing they're
producing uh FR so just as any other
animal that's growing they'll produce
some kind of manure type products um
some kind of you know we call it waste
of course we have this you know
vocabulary around waste which in my
opinion I think is going to eventually
be eliminated everything we think of is
waste now um there's we're increasingly
finding uses for all of our wastes
because we see um you know anywhere
there's a product that's coming out of
some sort of system There's an
opportunity for someone else and so
that's also where beta hatch has been
really looking at the supply chain
trying to say hey where can we find a a
waste byproduct and take that feed it to
our insects and create something of real
value and so those products are the meal
worms as a a feed and the FR as a
fertilizer
yeah I know uh you know having been a
former feed store owner up until last
year we sold a ton of dried meal worms
uh literally and you know we call it
chicken crack is what a lot of the home
backyard chicken owners called it
because chickens will go crazy for it
very high in protein which is good for
egg production um as a supplement to
their diet but what I didn't realize was
a lot of the ones that we were ordering
uh in our supply chain were coming out
of China which um potentially from what
I was reading and I'm not an expert on
this but there's a lot more risks of
toxins heavy metals from the production
methods that are being used over there
because there's a lot less
oversight um versus say something here
here in the states yeah so I mean it's
pretty um unknown but every single dried
meal worm that's on the market today
except for the products with our
customer chbby mealor worm um is from
China so all of the dried mealor worms
that you see even if they say they might
have been packaged in the US they were
grown in China we're the only domestic
producer of meal worms for backyard
birds and so we have been really trying
to try to bring awareness to this the
fact that you know this treat that a lot
of backyard bird owners are super
excited to give to their flock because
yeah it is chicken crack they they love
it um but that's coming from China and
there are some responsible producers for
sure um but there's also just a lot of
unknowns and I actually have been in
China and visited some of these
operations um you know there's uh just a
kind of different approach and standard
to production so you know to give you a
a case in point even the interpretation
of the rules can be a little
um I guess Lost in Translation um you
know we visited a a facility they said
oh yeah we're only giving pre-consumer
grocery waste to our insects and you
know as I'm Turing the operation it was
pretty clear it looked like they were
just eating garbage there's bits of
glass and plastic and they kept
reassuring me like no no it's all
pre-consumer grocery waste which is what
the rules are for responsible production
according to the FDA um the the thing
that was Lost in Translation here is
they weren't actually depackaging any of
that grocery waste so they were just
grinding up you know plastic containers
and glass bottles with whatever that
organic material was and giving that to
the insects well if the insects are
actively digesting eating plastic that's
getting into the product and who knows
what other kinds of you know
contaminants or things could be getting
in there so yeah there's definitely some
concerns with um you know relying on
that foreign supply chain for something
that people are putting in their bodies
and so that's why we're super excited to
get to Market with our American grown
meal worms they're organically produced
um everything that we're giving our
insects is certified organic so we've
ensured from the inputs to the end
products that we're making everything is
food grade certified organic um and
grown right here in Washington State uh
from waste ingredients so it's a not
only domestically produced but complete
transparency and Trust of you know just
knowledge of what's going into our
insects um and that's something that we
think is really important for anyone
who's grown birds that you know if
you're going to harvest eggs and um you
know enjoy uh having backyard birds you
want them to be as healthy as possible
and so that's why we've seen such great
opportunities with our business and we
actually can't grow fast enough that's a
it's a great problem to
have um and one of the reasons we're
scaling up our production that is great
I didn't realize you were the only
domestic producers I mean I think I met
you uh oh probably five four or five
years ago now at the flower and garden
show and you were still kind of uh you
know getting production established and
things like that so I'm glad we're able
to Circle back on that uh one thing you
you touched on just now was how uh the
feed stock will affect the final uh
product whether it's the meal worm
itself or it's frass uh do you have any
more information about that like uh has
there been any research done or um have
you seen that NPK values for example
will vary based on what you feed the
meal worms oh absolutely we've um you
know this is one of those chall Alles
with marketing any kind of fertilizer
products you have sort of a guaranteed
minimum on your label um but you know we
often are ex you know exceeding those
numbers as far as our mpks we guarantee
a 232 but we've measured close to 555
and and uh with some feed stocks so yeah
what you put in really changes what you
get out um we're trying to you know get
a firm number set for our new facility
so that we can hopefully um adjust some
of those numbers
accordingly but effectively um yeah what
you're feeding the insects is going to
change the quality of the frass um one
thing that doesn't change though about
the frass regardless of what the mpk
value looks like is that it's a a
product rich in Kaiden um and so there's
a lot of benefits to um sort of the the
non those macronutrients that get a lot
of attention but there's micronutrients
and other components that can have these
other benefits um so there's a lot of
know benefits on controlling patod
because you can activate um kiten
feeding uh microbes in the soil when you
are providing a source of kiteen as you
get infras and so then that can help
lead to bio control of things like
nematodes and some of the other um pests
that can affect different types of crops
um you know magnesium is another uh
nutrient that we certify in our products
so the frass has um at least a half
percentage of magnesium which is really
important for the Fring of tomatoes and
other night shades and plenty of other
plants so there's not just the mpk but a
lot of other um I guess interesting
interactions between frass and the soil
when you use it as a fertilizer and as a
soil
amendment that's great so uh one
question I had do you know anything
about the microbial content of the final
Frost have you guys looked at that at
all from a biological perspective yeah
we've started to dig in there a little
bit more um we actually have a
microbiologist on staff and so she's
been um really digging into just all the
microbial interactions with their bugs
and and in the products um we do know
that uh you we certify each batch making
sure that there's no pathogenic microbes
like ecoli that are going to be a
problem um but we do know there is a
rich community of microbes there and
we're trying to learn as much as we can
about how that impacts the soil um we've
done some testing with comp postas we
certainly know that as a stimulator for
compost Frost can uh really help enrich
and feed a compost to to get it started
and producing a healthy microbial um
consortia but as I'm sure you know with
microbes it's just this small world
we're barely scratching the surface up
so we're just you know starting to learn
the importance and value of microbes and
soils um and we're you know part of that
revolution of trying to really think
about
fertilizers and soil amendments and soil
in a more I guess Community focused way
where we're looking at the community of
microbes and trying to think about what
that looks like um so you know I think
this is an area we're really excited in
the next growing season to do more field
tests on um and we're always looking for
testing Partners to um you know help get
some independent thirdparty testing of
the products done oh that's great yeah
no that's wonderful um and and one of
the questions that uh I wanted to go
back to was also how do people um if
they want to say rear meal meal rear
meal worms themselves uh how would you
go about doing that um any
recommendations for uh I don't know
websites or books or even just a quick
how to right now over the podcast yeah I
mean there's tons of great resources
online I've seen lots of really
interesting YouTube channels people
getting really uh elaborate in their
home setups um meal arms are really easy
um you can grow them in a shoe box
basically although I wouldn't recommend
a a cardboard shoe box because they can
eat through the
cardboard um but the uh two resources I
would Point people to um one is uh a a a
group Karine Katarina angers a great
entrepreneur who's done a lot of work on
um insects more of the food Focus but
absolutely there's an opport Unity for
those insects to be you know they've
been really interested in helping people
get in in their diet directly but just
you're not ready for that getting it
into your bird's diet um and so her
company on Farm has um actually a little
desktop version they call it the hive um
which is a little ready-made kit for
growing mealor worms so that's a great
place for people to get started um there
was also a project called open Bug farm
that um the current
folks that were working on that project
um have moved on to other things but I
believe that's still an active resource
with a lot of online um uh different
forums with questions and they had an
active community of people who were you
know on this sort of small scale looking
to grill bugs contributing their knowhow
and so that's another resource that I
would recommend people check out um but
the internet is full of great and
wonderful things and uh certainly the
wealth of knowledge around um farming
bugs at home has has really grown so uh
I'd recommend yeah know YouTube's got
plenty of of interesting great
explainers as well so in theory like a
an average you know residential family
four could create a a small little
mealor worm setup and recycle some of
their waste into potentially a more
useful uh product I guess for their
Garden
yeah it's it's possible I will say you
know one of the challenges and this is
true of any kind of home compost kind of
operation or you know any setup you're
trying to do to recycle your waste um is
is a question of volume and just sort of
time and ability to you know take care
of whatever it is that's helping you
break down any kind of organic waste you
have um you know I would say meal worms
are they can eat almost anything but
they still need to be fed in a
particular way away and they're animals
they need they need Care on a fairly
frequent basis and so absolutely would
encourage anyone who's interested in
trying this out to give it a go but you
can also just buy our meal worms if uh
it's it's something that you're finding
a little intimidating um as far as you
know thinking about how to get a little
home setup going I would actually
suggest um you know if you're looking
you know composting is a great way to um
I think be be looking at recycling some
of your organic waste um and there are
some interesting there's some
interesting stuff going on with black
soldierly which um handles a much more
wet waste which is typically what most
People's Kitchen waste is like um and
that's uh another you know the the black
soldier fly is a type of fly so they
produce a larvae that um as I said lives
more of this kind of wet feed um the
challenge is of course that they're fly
so they um you know getting a reliable
breeding system going for black
soldierly on a home basis can be a
little challenging especially in the
winter um but there's plenty of um
different uh suppliers that you can buy
animals from both the black soldierly or
meal worm or any other type of bug that
you're interested in growing there's um
a pretty active live market that's
actually seen a lot of growth um through
the last year because there's been this
huge surgeon interest in uh backyard
birds and
homesteading so I'm very excited to see
that Trend I hope it continues into 2021
and
Beyond yeah I got to tour a facility up
in Vancouver that grows black soldierly
and produces uh oh nice an insect frass
and it was it was pretty cool to see I
didn't you know when I first started
looking into this I didn't realize that
black soldier fly adults when they're in
the fly form they don't eat so they
don't transmit the same diseases that
your traditional house fly it gets
attributed to um which was really
interesting and so I actually I tried
uh raising um black soldier flies I
bought one of those uh protopod larvae
uh things and I had no luck uh getting
any naturalization here in the Seattle
area but apparently some people have I
tried for a couple seasons and uh
finally gave up on that but um I know
some people in certain areas are like oh
black soldier flies are everywhere they
contaminate my compost pile is how some
people look at it but um yep they are
pretty amazing creatures and I just want
to mention so we do you know through
through kiss Organics we do have a black
soldierly frass that we offer as well as
we're going to start offering uh your
the beta hatch mealworm product as well
which I'm really excited about too um
after looking at
it yeah well and it's interesting
because the the word fras is just you
know it's a term for bug poop um but you
know slightly different process here so
so the uh meal worm frass is actually
pure frass we sift it out in a way that
we're basically getting little tiny
granules of bug poop people used to ask
like how do you collect it I made the
joke well we just have lots of tiny
little doggy
bags and uh but it looks kind of like
sand right so this is a podcast people
aren't really seeing what we're talking
about um you can kind of just imagine
you know probably people are imagining
um you know when they've looked at their
compost pile and what that looks like
with a bunch of you know maggots in
there and that kind of thing it's it's a
very clean operation inside and
controlled the products and just so that
everyone again can sort of imagine what
they look like the meal worms you know
it just looks like a little about an
inch long uh a little larvae um very um
kind of like a little half half you know
cresant Moon uh inchon little dried um
they almost look like a snack um like a
cheex mix sort of ingredient yeah and
the frass the frass um the mealor frass
is is basically like a sand so it's
really easy to apply because it's that
pure frass um it has a really good and
consistent nutritional value um black
soldierly frass um you know sometimes
has a mix of other inputs in it um
because the the diet is harder to
separate from the fras but it's also a
great ingredient for any kind of soil
amendment or
fertilization so yeah I mean I would
definitely hope that your listeners are
um stress than trying it out in their
Gardens yeah it's definitely a larger uh
larger sized um and and more varied
amendment in terms of the way it looks
compared to the insect frat that we're
talking about with the mealor worms your
product is is much finer I it's very
obvious when you look at them side by
side and they have slightly different
NPK levels as well like you mentioned um
and I assume a different consortia of uh
microbes when we yeah you know I had
oh go ahead go ahead I was gonna say I
haven't seen any um work on it yet
comparing these two kind of the two
products but there's some really
interesting work coming out of Europe
and parts of Asia as well um where
there's been a lot of good independent
science and data on frass both me worm
fras and black soldierly fras and like
you're asking about the microbes this is
kind of like all the things that we
can't see that are in there um having
these benefits and um you know they've
been finding some really interesting
compelling um I guess value to fras
that's beyond just the mpk so one of the
studies um was published actually in
nature um as as part of their group of
journals um and they looked at me FR and
found when you take a control group
where it's just you know exactly the
same NPK profile and you take you know
the fras group The FR group
outperforms uh the NPK group so you know
when you look at a nutritionally
equivalent control that's not derived
from frost there's something that sort
of inex inexplicable something and
there's definitely that question of is
this a microbe is it the kiden what is
what's happening that's you know
basically creating this bio stimulant
effect in the plants and that's
something that Mech mechanistically is
still being looked into but you know
it's pretty clear from all the growth
trials um that there's something there
that's um causing
better plant performance um and we've
seen that in our our tests too we just
did a bunch of field trials one of my
favorites I I grew a bunch of
jalapenos at my house this summer I have
way more than I know what to do with so
I don't know if you have any good salsa
recipes yeah I'm I'm flush with
jalapenos now because of this growth
test um but one of the surprising
results is that we actually got twice as
many fruits that were twice as large
with our fres treatment and we ran you
know a negative control and also a
positive control against a couple other
just commercial products that are and
and did a you know made sure everything
was nutrient similar as far as mpk goes
and we got this extra fruit production
and so it's kind of again hard to
pinpoint why but we know that that's a
real effect that we're seeing with the
use of
frass yeah I think that's a really
interesting point when we talk about the
biological aspects of it and uh one
thing i' I'd like to touch on is that
that you mentioned at the end is is that
you do need to take into account the NPK
value when you know formulating or
adding it into your soil but um assuming
you're doing that I think you guys are
recommending around a cup per cubic foot
uh is a safe
rate I mean as far as yeah as far as the
safe rate because it's got this you know
um pretty mellow uh nutrient
concentration this isn't a fertilizer
that's going to burn your your plants or
cause any issues with over
application um in the same way that you
would see with say like a a synthetic
fertilizer so yeah typically about a cup
per cubic foot is a great application
rate um but even a teaspoon or
tablespoon in a cubic foot can have an
impact based on some of the work that
we've done so yeah again that that
intangible I mean oh man I'd love to do
a follow- up next year after we've done
a little more research and started to
understand the microbial component
because yeah there a lot to look into
there um we're one of the tests we're um
going to be doing this coming fall is
actually looking at frass in Martian
soil so we're really interested in the
application of what we do to space
travel um thinking about Clos Loop and
enclosed food production systems and so
we've ordered some uh simulated Martian
soil it's developed by the jet
propulsion lab and we're um going to be
using our frass to fertilize it and and
get a sense of how it performs as a uh
basically a source of nutrition and
otherwise sterile uh kind of soil so I
should have some updates on that that
trial in a couple months for you oh
that's fun yeah I look forward to
hearing that that's uh that's really
cool um I know that from working with uh
some researchers in the lab up in Canada
they looked at black soldierly frass and
found in this particular produc are uh
good levels of calcium solubilizing and
phosphorus solubilizing bacteria so I
think there is a lot to be said for the
you know the the microbes that are being
you know excreted or the gut microbes
from these insects as as like you said
that sort of intangible benefit that
we're still I don't know that we'll ever
learn all the mechanisms of soil science
or or insects for that matter but uh you
know there there is something to it
Beyond just
the NPK values of of the product itself
for sure yeah oh yeah and we're
definitely really interested in nitrogen
fixing bacteria we've um we know like
basically we've done some genomic
analysis we know each of these players
are there and present it's just that
question of how abundant are they what
are they doing in with the frass and the
soil those are the kind of questions
we're trying to dig into a bit more and
trying to figure out if we can boost
those beneficial microbes a little bit
more in the product um but yeah lots to
learn it's it's a really exciting time
to be involved in insect
agriculture yeah so when people are
using it with their plants are they just
uh you know you said teaspoon tablespoon
or even a cup per cubic foot are they
mixing it in uh prior to planting or are
people using as a top dress are there
any like best practices that you've seen
with this particular
fertilizer yeah I mean I definitely
recommend if you can blend it in that's
great it will work as a top dress as
well um it it has a fraction of the
nutrients of course that are soluble and
we'll sort of water in um but you'll see
of course some of that uh it doesn't
dissolve completely so it'll stay uh on
the surface um as you water it in over a
few few days or few weeks um but the
nutrition from the frass is still
getting into the soil even with a top
dress um so it's a a fairly flexible
product in that sense um you know we've
done trials even at larger scale with um
traditional uh Field farm equipment for
uh dispensing fertilizer and that's a
top dress application and it's gotten
really good results that way so um we
know both you know blending and mixing
if you can at the beginning of the
season is the best way to make sure that
the those nutrients are near the roots
where you really need to have that
nutrition but a top dress um also just
sort of as a mid-season um addition is
also a great way to to use FR us as well
um and I should also say we've used it
indoors uh fairly often it doesn't have
really any kind of odor um and you can
um be using this we've I Ed it on my
indoor plants so um there's a lot of
broad ranges of applications for the
fres that we produce um and we're really
excited to be able to start making more
in the next year as our new um big bug
Factory I guess opened up in cashmir so
we're very excited next season's going
to be uh lots of frass out there um
hopefully growing lots of great food for
people here in Washington and
Beyond I'm looking for to next season as
well uh for a variety of reasons with
everything going on in the world these
days uh next year will definitely be a
better year um one question I wanted to
ask you do you see with these top
dressing applications uh due to the
biology in the frass are you seeing like
melal growth or um mold over time
growing from we've never seen no we've
never seen that um in the test that
we've done um I'm sure it's it's a
possible uh effect because you just
never know what's in the soil that might
get activated but from the frass itself
there's never been any growth like that
so um that's not typically been
something that we've noticed in any of
the trials that we've done and the
microbiology that you're seeing in the
fras is it uh strictly bacteria or maybe
ARA in in the there's some there's some
fungal um microbes as well um yeah man I
wish my microbiologist Ola was able to
join us so she's a done a lot of work on
you know everything from what's inside
the mealor worms so then of course what
ends up outside in the frass and um yeah
we've seen all kinds of fungal micro
microbia um it's kind of a cross spans
you know the whole Spectrum uh of what
you might expect um and we don't have at
this time any particular treatment for
the fras we we're trying to maintain as
much of that natural microbiota as we
can so we're not doing any kind of heat
treatment or sterilization because we do
know that there's some of that um you
know certainly it's something we can do
for a customer if they're concerned but
we see a lot of value in maintaining
that natural good microbial consor that
is valuable for
soil yeah I think one of the main the
biggest benefit is probably the
biological aspect so I'm glad to hear
that it is microbial active um yeah and
you're not sterilizing it right well and
I think that the kiden uh component as
well is something that we're very
interested in continuing to explore so
that's not necessarily it's not a you
know something live in of itself but it
nourishes naturally existent microbes in
the soil um to help defend against some
of these pathogens that can impact
different um types of plants and so
that's another area that we're going to
be working on doing some some future
testing um and we have ways in our
process of kind of increasing how much
Cen content there is in the in the frost
and so we see that as an interesting
opportunity down the road as we you know
start to learn more and more about the
products that we we have which we know
are great just finding ways to make them
even better is something that I'm really
excited
about yeah now uh I think was most of my
questions was there anything else you'd
like to share regarding uh your company
or mealworm frass or meal worm
production before we sign off well I
would just remind everyone they can uh
always check out our website betah
hatch.com if they have a query um or or
want to find out more about getting some
product right now chubby mealworms is
our um key customer on the mealor worm
side they've they're carrying our
American grown meal worms so that's the
best place if you want to buy some meal
worms they'll also be carrying FR as in
the next uh few weeks and so um great
place to buy our products and yeah we're
very excited for next year we we've got
a facility we're building over in the
wachi area that should come online early
next year and hopefully by next summer
we'll be producing uh close to a ton a
day of meal worms and several tons a day
of frass and so there'll be uh a lot
more of that product available we're
we're really excited to be getting this
out to um folks to be growing some great
food next year and getting their Gardens
and their compost piles started yeah
that's great I know we received some of
the frass in as well for our inventory
and I look forward to getting it out to
you know some of our some of our
customers and listeners as well um but I
think it's a really exciting product and
I love what you guys are doing from a
sustainability perspective and uh I
thank you for your time
today yeah thanks D it was a great
conversation I'm so glad that uh we were
able to connect thank
[Music]
you that was Virginia Emy with beta
hatch and you are listening to the
Cannabis cultivation and science podcast
we are now offering beta hatch frass on
our website if you want to try it out in
your garden don't forget to check out
the podcast page at www kis organics.com
just click on the learn Tab and then
podcast
and please leave us a review on whatever
platform you listen on I do read them
all and appreciate the feedback thanks
for listening