[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge as you
know rules and regulations are an
important aspect of cannabis cultivation
in addition it's important to note that
the products we purchase to use in our
garden are safe and providing the
nutrients or microbes that are listed on
the labels my interview this week is
with sunny summers and Matt Haynes with
the Oregon Department of Agriculture the
Oregon Department of Agriculture have
been leaders at the state level in
regards to product testing and
information sharing for consumers I was
very excited that they accepted my
request to come on the podcast to talk
about some of their findings and to help
growers better understand pesticide and
fertilizer product labels and some of
the challenges around policy enforcement
to give a little background on my guests
at a personal level sunny summers is the
cannabis policy coordinator for the
Department of Agriculture sunny has a
degree from Oregon State University in
bio resource research
she worked in pesticide regulation and
enforcement for 12 years before making
the leap to cannabis when not scratching
her head over cannabis regulations she
can be found napping in the woods
kayaking on the Willamette or chasing
one of the bruiser brothers around the
Sassi sunflower house Matt Haines is a
graduate of California State Polytechnic
University Pomona with a BS in agronomy
he has been with the Oregon Department
of Agriculture for 20 years at the
department's fertilizer program for 18
years Matt reviews product labels for
registration conducts marketplace
inspections collects and compiles
tonnage data and reviews laboratory
sample data prior to joining the
department Matt was with the JM Smucker
Company and mission Resource
Conservation District
hi Matt and sunny thanks so much for
coming on the show today good to be here
tad yeah thank you yeah can you tell me
a little bit more about your roles at
the Oda and some of the programs that
you're involved in yeah I'll start so
this is sunny I am the Oregon Department
of bags cannabis policy coordinator so
for me that involves marijuana and
industrial hemp I currently am helping
write the rules for our industrial hemp
program I also work really closely with
the Oregon Liquor Control Commission
which has the primary Authority for
adult use cannabis in Oregon I also
liaison with the Oregon Health Authority
who does all the medical as well as
testing rules in relations to adult use
cannabis or medical cannabis and then I
also work with the industry helping them
figure out who they need to talk to may
not be our agency or who within our
agency they would need to talk to great
and Matt I know I've actually worked
with you in getting some of our soils
registered in Oregon a couple years ago
can you tell me a little about your role
with Oda sure dad I am with the
department's fertilizer program
fertilizer regulation is quite old
actually much much older than the
cañada's program here it goes back to
prior to the creation of the agency
which was in the 1930s but my role here
is as a fertilizer specialist so I'm
reviewing product labeling that is
submitted for registration I'm
conducting marketplace inspections so I
go out in the field and see if folks are
compliant
I also review a lot of lab data that we
generate here internally in the
department for product that's been
sampled in the marketplace ultimately
the program's goal is consumer
protection we want to make sure that the
consumer receives what they what they
pay for and that they don't get things
that they shouldn't have in there
that's great I definitely wanted to
touch on that a little bit later in the
podcast but I wanted to start off with
sort of a general question what sort of
challenges do you see for cannabis
growers within you know this relatively
new regulated market and sunny I know
there's probably been a lot on the
policy side and Matt I know you've seen
things with with the fertilizer side is
there anything that that that sort of
sparks in terms of particular particular
things that you're seeing I I think
there's a lot of challenges from the
perspective taking a step back of the
agency we kind of have a dual purpose
here and I think we do it pretty well in
Oregon but the department is tasked with
both regulating the agricultural
industry as well as promoting it and so
the reason my position even exists is
our former director Katie koba was
pretty forward-thinking and really
wanted to treat all things cannabis the
same as any other agricultural crop as
much as we could so that's where some of
the challenges are I prefer to reframe
endless opportunities come into play
you know the olcc for example registers
all growers so we we aren't the ones
that are licensing those those marijuana
growers but yet they still need to work
with us on pesticides and fertilizers
and agricultural water quality programs
and so having having to work with
multiple agencies for some people can be
really difficult especially if they are
not coming from an Ag background I think
that's one of the really awesome things
about the cannabis industry is that it's
brought together such a wide range of
people who are interested in the new
industry you know I tell co-workers here
we've got our typical tie-dyed
Birkenstock wearing folks running the
gamut all the way to you know former
investment bankers and insurance brokers
people who understand money but don't
necessarily understand that agriculture
is not a witch
so I see some some opportunities for
learning in the industry because of
those those situations that's great and
Matt was there anything that you wanted
to add from the fertilizer perspective
well what what we see over and over
again in this in this market is that
you've got a long history of folks that
operate it outside the law and they
historically have done this forever and
they have now brought that attitude in
or continue that attitude as the legal
framework has been built around the
production of these crops so they
continue and this isn't the grow I don't
really work with growers particularly
but I work with input manufacturers and
they're continuing a lot of them
continue this outlaw or bad-boy attitude
and they do things they really should
not be doing
but for part of it it it's the way
they've always done business another
part of it is it gives them some street
cred hey look our our product works
better than everybody else is because
the the government doesn't know what we
do to it so that it's troublesome I
think not in quaint yeah yeah I know I
vented to you in the past about this
because it is really a challenge and I I
really appreciate the level of testing
that you are doing I know if we just
talk about fertilizer you released lab
analysis and you've been doing this for
years
even before I believe in before the
cannabis industry came under your your
per your your jurisdiction but some of
the some of the products we see what you
talked about there you mentioned is
someone will say yes you know I have
this product it's a oh I don't know
three three two I'm actually looking at
one of your old ones from to in 2015 and
they may say you know our product has a
proprietary phosphorus source that
releases the phosphorus much more
efficiently than another another product
so you're comparing two three three two
products for example only to find out
that the avail
phosphate that's actually in the product
maybe you know instead of three percent
it may be eleven percent so they're
they're essentially making claims around
a much higher percentage of nutrient
than what they then what they're telling
you and from a grower perspective that's
really confusing and it's really
challenging because if we're trying to
regulate our nutrient and fertigation
program to the plant itself we really
can't do that based off of numbers that
are so far off of what we think we're
getting well yeah I would agree with
that wholly the fertilizer industry
regulation is it evolved over the last
hundred years really was based on making
sure the grower received the minimum
amount that was guaranteed the thought
being that nobody's going to give
product away so as long as they get the
minimum if they go over well nobody's
going to do that because you're not
going to give product away that's losing
money but that has changed that dynamics
change quite a bit and there is over
formulation and non-disclosed
ingredients whether they're nutrients or
pesticides and products that may give a
particular product an edge over a
competitor again as Sonny noted with
kind of the wink wink attitude hey check
it out it works we're not going to tell
you exactly why but hey it works and it
works well so what you guys are doing as
an agency is going in and sampling these
products because when I submitted my my
product my soil and registered as a
fertilizer because I made plant growth
claims saying you know it would help a
plant grow therefore it need to be
registered as a fertilizer when I did
that I also had to submit from a lab a
guaranteed analysis saying that there
was at least this level of nutrient in
there and then I would set my product
label you know slightly below that so
let's say we used an example of three
three two that would be something where
my analysis might be three point two
percent three point one percent and two
point two percent I would say my
products at three three two and then
what you're doing is going back in and
sampling that product at some point to
see if I if I met those guarantees is
that correct yeah that's correct
and again like
stated previously the the process has
been to make sure
okay tag your product met the minimums
and much of much of state regulatory
activity has been based on that but
we're also starting to go the other
direction now to make sure that you've
not over formulated simply for in a
large degree water quality issues if
you've got product that's not accurate
as to the label and it's being applied
over a large swath of ground that can
impact water quality I think that's a
really important point especially around
the use of phosphorus and phosphates I
know that's a big challenge in the
cannabis industry as it's something that
in my opinion that we tend to massively
over apply and so I think it's great
that you're looking out for water
quality is there anything else around
fertilizer registration that you would
think is important for growers to know
from a grower perspective like something
that pops into my mind is I wasn't aware
that oh you only have to put something
on the label if you're guaranteeing the
analysis of it for example when we're
talking about macronutrients I just know
from my label its NPK and calcium I
didn't make a guarantee around sulfur
for example so you're not going to test
the sulfur in my product is that correct
for the most part yes unless there's
some reason we would think that it could
be harmful sulfur typically wouldn't be
but you get an element like boron that
if that product was well over formulated
with boron you could create some
cytotoxic effects that could harm a crop
so we will sometimes look for components
nutritive components that aren't listed
but we may suspect might be a problem
well that's interesting I didn't know
that and is this all just random
sampling or is a complaint based as well
how do you go about choosing which
products are sampling a lot of it is
random as we're in the marketplace
conducting inspections will pick up
product and then we have a history on
that don't necessarily meet their
guarantees and we're going to focus in
on we're going to focus in on that
manufacturer more if we find that
repeatedly they don't meet their
guarantees and yeah occasionally we do
get complaints whether it's we don't
think they're formulating with as much
phosphate as they should or they're
using a different form or hey by the way
I used to work for this company and
they're putting SF on in this product
you may want to go look at it
Wow okay and so take me through what
happens if you do find a violation well
it often depends on how far up the quote
ladder they are it will start to the
point where we take some very low-level
enforcement action as if they repeat we
can go up to civil penalty if they
continue to repeat we can cancel product
registrations and place stop sales on
the product found in the marketplace oh
so it doesn't start with a stop sale
that's more on the that's further down
the road for laughs yeah for lab
violations we always give folks the
benefit of the doubt but as we continue
if we continue to sample and see it
violate violate violate yes we can issue
a stop sale which would legally prohibit
the the sale or distribution of the
product in Oregon okay so that's talking
fertilizers now if we move to pesticides
does that change on the stop sale side
of things well so I used to be in the
pesticide program it's been a couple of
years usually what is going to happen is
if we run into a situation where we
think a pesticide is contaminated or has
an active ingredient that isn't listed
on the label which i think is kind of
what you're getting at we're going to go
pull a few bottles ourselves and have
those analyzed so a lot of times we've
received a complaint maybe a grower used
a product something to happen they have
their plant material tested and it came
up positive for an active ingredient
that they didn't use and they
narrow it down and think okay this is
the product that it might have come from
we can't rely on their test results for
enforcement purposes it really needs to
be something that we sampled ourselves
we know what the chain of custody is
from that point of sale to our lab and
then the lab analyzes it if we get
results that are positive for an active
ingredient not on the label at that
point we would issue a stop sale now
aren't you the agency that found
Guardian might spray I know that was a
big one that hit the you know I got
samples of that back in the day and I
fortunately didn't apply it to my plants
but a lot of growers were using it and
so in Oregon and and I think the the
Washington rules are quite similar all
cannabis has to be tested for about
fifty nine different pesticide active
ingredients the Guardian was under our
old testing rules for just medical
marijuana but there was a grower who was
taking his plant material in and it
tested positive for an active ingredient
that he didn't expect and it was
actually the private lab that contacted
us because they had a number of
different growers who were saying that
they were testing positive for this none
of them used it and they were starting
to point fingers at him as having lab
contamination and so he took it upon
himself to kind of sit down with him and
figure out what all of them were using
and it turned out Guardian was the
common common thread had it tested came
up positive referred that to us we went
out like I said and purchased our own
new bottles of that and determined that
it did have that that chemical in there
and so that's a really positive thing in
my mind that the cannabis industry has
brought to all of agriculture is we've
actually had a handful of those
situations since the testing rules went
into place and that's really important
to not have products adulterated with
another active ingredient it's not just
cannabis that that affects especially
some of them were Omri lifted so they
were ones that people expected were
legal and
appropriate for use on organic crops and
the active ingredients that they were
contaminated with are not allowed under
the National Organic Program so it's
really opened up I think all the
regulator's eyes and the manufacturers
eyes throughout the country oh I think
you bring up a really good point
I totally agree with you we need this
level of testing we're putting way too
money too much trust on manufacturers to
be delivering what they said they were
delivering and it's been proven over and
over again I mean Guardian is just one
example the other one that pops to mind
is my tea wash this this you know
alkaline water that was supposedly
killing mites well turned out that there
were other ingredients in there like I
believe that was pyrethrin x' in that
case but this level of trust you know
we're assuming that as a grower we're
assuming that the manufacturers telling
us the truth
and then we're assuming that all these
products are being tested by the
government when in reality you know
they're it's sort of something it's a
little bit more of a grayer it's kind of
something in between and when you do
catch people like this I think that just
shows the need that we have for agencies
like yours to exist because it's just so
important I totally agree the the other
piece that I always tell folks when I'm
when I'm giving a presentation is and I
use Guardian as an example it was four
hundred and ten dollars or so I think
for a 16 ounce bottle it was what the
EPA calls a 25 B product so it had
naturally-occurring ingredients I think
it was like lemon grass and cinnamon oil
and they listed all the other
ingredients that's kind of the
requirement to to fall underneath that
25 B which means they don't have to go
through the full registration process so
we're paying four hundred and ten
dollars for Thai food that if you read
the reviews on the website works the
first time against mites I don't know
about you but my BS meter is off the
scale for that and if something sounds
too good to be true it probably is
well that's similar to the wash products
the wash products typically have a
pretty pretty steep price on them
they're kept often in the glass case in
the front of the shop and most of the
product at least disclosed on the label
is in active ingredient hmm wonder why
it works
yeah yeah and for listeners that aren't
familiar that's as I understand it and I
hope you correct me if I miss state
anything the 25b list is any product
that's considered safe for humans things
like lavender
would be the first example that pops
into my mind that may have some known
pesticidal properties but then by using
those sorts of products in your product
you don't have to go through the full
EPA registration which is a really
challenging long process so if something
has that EPA registration they've
already gone through all that but a lot
of these products just fall under the 25
B list and my I will tell you some of my
entomologist friends we just will not
use products on the 25 B list for the
most part just because they're not as
well tested and they're not as well
reviewed in terms of their actual
effects on insect populations and things
like that yeah you're pretty close
there's actually a very set list of
active ingredients that are allowed
under the 25 B an exemption from Federal
Register yeah I'm not sure if lavenders
on there but things like thyme oil
cinnamon oil some zinc I mean it's a
pretty limited list they put it together
back in the late 80s they're not ever
going to add to it is what they've told
me in the past and so not only do they
have to pull an active ingredient off
that list they have to pull the other
ingredients or inert off of what they
call the for a list which is minimal
risk and then unlike other pesticide
products they have to tell you
everything that's in the ball so most
pesticides you'll see the active
ingredient and other ingredients but
they don't ever tell you what those
other ingredients are in order to
qualify for 25 B they have to tell you
everything that's in there and you're
right they don't go through the full EPA
registration they do how
have to be registered at least in Oregon
I think Washington also registers 25
bees and so our staff review those
labels to make sure they're not making
wild claims they can't claim to control
public health pests which are typically
going to be things bacteria and such in
hospitals and mosquito control clay no
vector vector type insects so they can't
be for those but yeah and and there's
some question in folks minds about how
efficacious they are how well do they
work against whatever pests they say
they're going to work on yeah that's
really interesting thanks for clarifying
that by the way and yes you see a lot of
25b products at trade shows for example
for the cannabis industry that's where I
see most of them and they all claim
they'll make pretty amazing claims
usually you know verbally to the grower
that's standing there so I would
encourage people to do their own
research on a lot of these products
there's so many of them on the market
right now and part of the reason that
you're going to see a lot of 25b
products are there is no EPA registered
pesticides for anything cannabis it
specifically lists that crop I mean
there's there's actually listed
pesticides to kill right ditch weed
marijuana but to control a pest
specifically listed doesn't exist
yeah and so that's one of those those
situations you were asking earlier about
challenges the the federal government
hasn't recognized cannabis as a legal
crop therefore research as to what
amount of residue you can have on it
when you harvest hasn't been done what
rate do you apply it that was talking
about
phyto toxicity that could be a really
big deal with cannabis
especially indoor grown where they're
under those those very strong lights you
know how long does that active
ingredient stay on the plant material we
don't know those things that is what is
done in order to get a product
registered with the EPA and so in Oregon
we came up with a list of products that
would not be illegal for use on canvas
and that means they have really broad
label language they're allowed on food
crops so some of those 25 B's they just
say you can use it on any food crop and
food crops are really the most
restrictive outside of public health
pests for how you use a pesticide the
EPA traditionally would set what they
call tolerances
that's a residue level that can be on
that crop and they look at potential
exposure in the short term and for the
long term
what is our potential for chronic
long-term health effects if we were to
consume that that active ingredient over
the course of my lifetime and so they
have models that they put into place
they take into account more sensitive
populations young children the elderly
pregnant women and then they come up
with a value that they feel is
protective of human health none of that
has been done on the cannabis side have
you seen any research on how these
pesticides are are affected when
combusted and inhaled through the lungs
at all versus you know food products
that are obviously you know consumed
yeah no that's a great question
sometimes I get people saying well why
can't I use what they use on tobacco
first of all there's very few pyrolysis
studies ie what happens when you burn it
so yeah there's not a lot of information
available we do know something like
michael--ah butanol based on private lab
studies turns into hydrogen cyanide and
that's kind of one that the cannabis
industry needs to be aware of because my
club you know is a fungicide that
historically would be used off-label on
cannabis it's fine on your grape leaves
that you're not rolling up and smoking
hopefully but may not be so great when a
Bic lighter is hot enough to convert
whatever my club you know is on there
into hydrogen cyanide and you're now
breathing that into your lungs
and one even with tobacco the EPA has
looked at it and said well if there's
pesticide residue on tobacco that's
probably the least of your concerns
you're inhaling a known carcinogen into
your lungs if there's a little bit of
residue pesticide again not your biggest
problem at that point so they've kind of
taken a hands-off approach even there is
way they absolutely stopped looking at
chronic long-term exposure on tobacco
they only regulate it for acute exposure
for those folks who are applying it
while it's in the ground or working with
the plant material when it's harvested
and the other thing I like to throw out
I don't give tobacco juice to medically
compromised children we are giving
cannabis to medically compromised
children and so we need to be protective
of the most vulnerable population that
might be using this crop yeah and for
those that don't know the the most
common Michael butanol product is Eagle
20 just a consumer name
that's the name people are most familiar
with and I have heard the argument that
well it's used it's used in vineyards
and grapes so why wouldn't it
which is an edible crop why couldn't we
use it on cannabis and we're using such
a small amount that it really isn't
gonna have any effect on the final
product and yeah it makes growing a heck
of a lot easier when you don't have to
worry about powdery mildew and botrytis
but it's so dangerous and I'm glad that
that information is getting out there
and people are becoming more aware I
think that really relates more to the
consumer side than the grower side
because there's a lot of trust there on
the part of the consumer that these
growers are following all the rules too
which is a whole other side of
enforcement that we could talk about too
that's a challenge well something to
consider too is the routes of exposure
you may have a you may have a pesticide
material that dermal exposure is very
it's not water soluble it's not going to
get into your skin but if sunny
mentioned you combust that you
chemically change it and that route
through inhalation could be a huge huge
impact on your health where again having
some on your skin may not be a problem
all and eating it might not be an issue
because you have your stomach helps
break down those chemicals before it
gets into your bloodstream when you
inhale something your lungs are an
immediate conduit to the bloodstream and
so I don't know that we can say it's
going to be horrible but the
precautionary principle says we haven't
studied that we don't know and the
likelihood is that that could be a very
toxic exposure and yeah I think the
customers are you know interested in the
cannabis industry because it is
regulated and they feel that folks are
following those directions and you have
a more if there's a sense of confidence
when you walk into a regulated store
versus meeting the guy on the corner and
so speaking of pests from from
pesticides how how are you what do you
see in terms of lab results in regards
to concentrations of these pesticides as
cannabis gets concentrated down into
things like wax or rosin or oils are you
seeing much higher levels of pesticides
in those products well Matt and I don't
see those lab results so I'm not sure I
can speak intelligently to it obviously
anytime you concentrate the cannabinoids
you're going to concentrate any other
chemical that's on there including the
pesticides which is why most states have
a pesticide testing program in place in
Oregon the raw plant material is tested
and the bulk oils would be tested for
pesticides it's limited we have 59
different active ingredients it's not
CSI it's not like we can just put
something in a little vial and say tell
me everything that's on there you know
there's I don't know 1300 or more
different pesticide active ingredients
registered and products in the in the
country so trying to find all of those
they're not easy lab samples to run in
addition to that so the state the state
kind of had to limit what they were
looking for so in theory if a grower was
using a pesticide that was not one of
those 59 you were testing for it could
still be making it through the process
that's correct yeah we do like like Matt
was talking about earlier employees who
do not have a good working relationship
with their boss or who have left a
company many times will call and let us
know if there's something potentially
hinky going on at a facility so we do
follow up on those kind of complaints as
well and not just the the test result
well that's good to hear is that a
confidential process just out of
curiosity it can be it depends on how
that employee presents themselves if
they want to remain confidential we can
do that they need to let us know and
then we will not be able to follow up
with them usually we can provide them
with a case number though if they want
to call back and say tell me what
happened with case number such-and-such
then we can provide them with the
information and is that public
information if you do have violations on
the cultivation side like that yep all
of that our information is public
available so I just have to make a
request in order to receive it okay and
since we're talking about pesticides
I saw you have an alert right now on
your website about pyrethrins and I
think you what do you say hi PB oh yeah
PP yeah if you prefer nail beet oxide
thank you yeah that's a tricky one so
pyrethrins are naturally occurring
pesticide derived from chrysanthemum
flowers the PBO is what they call a
synergist
it has some pesticidal activity meaning
it kills insects but it's primarily
included in there because due to the
fact that pyrethrins are naturally
occurring they break down very quickly
in the environment
and insects can kind of develop some
resistance and so the the PBO is
included in that formulation to help the
pyrethrum be more effective against the
insect it's a nerve agent in insects and
the PBO helps keep the insect from
metabolizing it so that it actually is
effective the in Oregon the Oregon
Health Authority established what
pesticides cannabis is going to be
tested for they looked at what products
were were folks in the industry likely
to use what products did we know had
been historically used like the Eagle 20
and that's how they came up with with
their list
well OTAs list of what products are not
illegal to use are ones that have either
no tolerance some of them like
pyrethrins EPA has said it's low enough
in toxicity you can use it up to the day
of harvest and we're not going to be
concerned about residue levels on the
crops that it's used on so it got onto
our list because it met our criteria so
the products that that have that in
there that have label language that is
broad enough that we can allow it for
use on cannabis are allowed on our list
this is one of those situations where
not having Extension Service or
companies doing research we don't know
what happens on cannabis when you apply
pyrethrins we know what happens on
squash and cabbage and all of those
things and we know it breaks down very
quickly cannabis is a cool unique plant
it's possible that it doesn't happen the
same way and so some growers have sailed
for pyrethrins and or PPO
who use the product according to the
label directions and we don't know why
that is so that's why we have the allure
out there use it your own caution there
are some remediation options available
just for pyrethrins and PPO that are not
available for other active ingredients
if they can show that they used a
product
the guide lists and according to the
label direction but it's it's kind of
kind of a gray area and until we get
research into the plant you know good
agronomic research we're not going to
know why that's happening great and all
of this information is available on your
website I'm actually looking at it right
now there's a there's a PDF you can
download on the differences between
pyrethrins and pyrethroids you have the
alert on there I would encourage all
listeners to go and sign up for the
email alerts you get all the stop sale
information whenever new analysis come
out I really appreciate the work that
the AODA is doing around sharing this
information with growers so I wanted to
I wanted to change direction though a
little bit and ask a question for Matt
regarding the microbial analysis that
has been done by the oda as well I'm
looking at tests from 2015 and I can
tell you that these tests have been
highly debated in forums online based on
the results you're getting is there
anything you can explain a little bit
about that program well is bacteria and
fungi have been guaranteed in for lack
of a better way of saying it fertilizer
products for a number of years now and
unlike the chemical constituents
nitrogen boron zinc etc no state had
been actively looking at these
components during marketplace sampling
so while it's common for a product to be
tested you know somebody finds in the
marketplace I find in the marketplace I
bring it back send it to a regulatory
lab we want to see if it's got all of
the available phosphates it's guaranteed
again boron zinc copper whatever it is
but no state had been looking at
microbial components so back around 2013
Oregon right now we're the only state
that is looking at these components we
started to do some very rudimentary
testing using simple very simple
dilution plating to look at bacillus
trichoderma Pseudomonas can we find the
is bacterial and simple fungi and the
product at the levels that they're
guaranteed and overwhelmingly we're not
we also retained a well-known mycologist
in Corvallis Oregon to look at vesicular
our bus killer mycorrhizal fungi such as
Glomus or giga spora
he's looking at are the spores there are
the root fragments there does it meet
its guarantee of spores or propagules
doing a little better there but for the
most part products are not meeting their
guarantees for the microcell fungi
either so i think a lot of it is for
years and years folks have been able to
make guarantees unchecked we're calling
them on it now and i think it's it's
it's going to shake up the way the
industry promotes and guaranties
products have you found that bacteria or
fungi that are of human health concerns
as well well right now we're looking at
such a high level for example oregon
oregon law requires identification by
genus and species and strain if if
relevant but right now we're looking at
just the species level so for example if
they guaranteed ten combos of bacillus
so bacillus subtilis bacillus cereus etc
etc all the way down all we're doing
right now is looking at how many
bacillus are in that sample and they're
failing again almost universally we have
the ability to look at at the species
but if you can't crawl yet there's no
reason to see if you can run if it gets
to a point where products meet their
guarantees we can go to the species
level and see if they have harmful
potentially human pathogens in there but
right now we're we're not they're not
even close to be in there that's a
really interesting question sunny we
just assume that these products are safe
because they're being packaged and sold
by a
a commercial company it didn't even
really occur to me that something might
have human health impact really my my
initial thought was just I was amazed
that these products weren't being
detected you know are these microbes
were being detected on the products I'm
looking at the label right now from 2015
for piranhas with advanced nutrients and
they claim to have you know micro aisel
fungus Pseudomonas and Trichoderma you
know 55 million CFU a Trichoderma and
you didn't detect any of those things in
the product at all and people are paying
through the roof for these products it's
amazing how expensive they are I know
you touched on that or with on the
pesticides things so I'm hoping we're
going to get more accountability of of
these manufacturers on the products that
they're providing to the industry so we
do need more of this microbial testing
and where we don't where we're not
entirely clear right now is again let's
let's make the assumption of a benefit
and I'm not positive that there is one
yet right now again we're looking at
content not necessarily benefit but I'm
not sure that we're going in the right
direction in terms of guaranteeing for
example trikha derma at a 55 million
colony forming units per per milliliter
is that the right thing to do you know
we enforce law that is written by the
legislature sometimes with assistance
from the the department but it's drafted
by the legislature that law says that
these products have to guarantee genus
and species but there's more and more
evidence that points to it's not
specifically trikha derma horsy annum
live fungi that you really want to buy
it's the stuff that trikha derma hardy
Anam secretes as it's growing and living
and dying that you want to buy what is
that stuff no clue no clue whatsoever if
that's the case then we're barking up
the wrong tree by saying
okay you have to have a genus and
species guarantee but on the other hand
if the magic stuff that these bacteria
and fungi secrete is unknown then how do
you make a level and fair playing field
amongst products so it's it's a struggle
right now yeah that's a good point I
think the challenge I see is as a grower
or someone who's be purchasing these
products
I need something quantifiable that I can
compare so when I'm looking at two
products and one you know offers me the
gloma Center a disease or rise of Vegas
and Terada sees it say 50 spores per
gram and another one guarantees 500
spores per gram and they're the same
price my initial thought is to go with
the one where I'm getting more
essentially what seems like more product
for my money but what you're finding is
that maybe these claims on the labels
are really not all that accurate to
where what you're getting is nowhere
near what you thought you were paying
for I think that's the challenge yeah
it's a little different though so you're
talking what you mentioned we're my
kreizel fungi and the processes there
are much more well known in that you
need to so if it's AG Lamas or Giga
spore or whatever happens to be the idea
there is you want that fun fungi to
infect a root so you need that spore or
that propagule whether it's an infected
root fragment that you add but you need
specific infection it infects you get
that awesome Mike Mike rival Association
the soil of expand your root zone etc
etc those products are a little more
easy to quantify because we're counting
spores were counting root fragments
whatever to make propagules we
understand the process with the bacteria
such as bacillus or Pseudomonas or what
we refer to as simple fungi like trikha
derma they're they they all can excrete
VOCs volatile organic compounds of
whatever nature they are this is much
less clear
there's lots of ways they can promote
plant growth some of them are pesticidal
they actually act on other passage
pathogens in the soil they can excrete
compounds that can soluble eyes let's
say iron or phosphate they could excrete
compounds that could actually get into
the plant and signal in different
pathways metabolic pathways in the plant
we just don't have a good understanding
of these compounds they secrete and then
if you don't understand the compounds
how do you quantify them so sense what
you're saying is maybe the cure the Cure
current way that we are regulating these
products because we don't know the
effects of these microbes or or how they
act on plants that really for certain
species it may not be the most accurate
way of labeling or quantifying them and
that's yeah that's correct
we're we we enforce statute we enforce
Oregon law and that's the way it's
written right now it may not be the best
way or it may be the best way we just
don't know again we're starting if this
quantification stage somebody says
there's bacillus subtilis we want to see
if there's bacillus in this product we
still don't know Tad's are these
products truly effective or is it a
placebo effect
hey this is two hundred and fifty
dollars a litre
it's got 55 different genus and species
this stuff's awesome I don't know I
don't know how much good work has been
done out there
I don't know that any has really been
done with off-the-shelf product to to
look at to evaluate the content first
didn't meet its guarantees and then
let's let's use it per the label
directions are we seeing an agronomic
benefit to this did we get a better crop
yield did we get some other quantifiable
effect or again is it just placebo hey
the grow magazine say this is what you
use for whatever whatever results you're
looking for the science the hard
peer-reviewed science just isn't there
yeah I think another point that you
bring up that's that's good dimension is
that just because a product it makes
your list of something that's approved
for use is not in any way condoning it
in terms of efficacy or the ODA saying
you should use this product in your in
your cultivation practices it's just
that it according to the way the the its
structured from from a legal perspective
you're allowed to use it correct yes
that's true on pesticides fertilizers we
do not have a list for fertilizers just
to be clear we have our registered
product list right and we say that they
these products have met the requirements
in Oregon law but again you're right
it's not it's not a endorsement that hey
this will work or give you some benefit
at that point yeah so what's to keep a
company then from putting out a product
and just not listing any microbes I'm
putting out a micro product and just
saying there's microbes in there without
listing or making any claims in terms of
the guarantees well they can if they're
gonna claim microbial content in any way
shape or form whether it's on the
physical product label or the you know
web presence or brochures or fliers they
can't unless they make a guarantee now
it doesn't stop them from putting on
microbial component in there and saying
nothing about it because we won't know
but if they're gonna say microbes and
they have to guarantee microbes okay
that's interesting that's good to know
so I feel like we've done a good job of
talking about the test results I wasn't
wondering are you guys going to be
coming out with any new lab tests like
this I know it's been a little while
since the last sort of series of these
is there any more in the works that we
can look forward to yeah yeah we have
them in the works continually every year
we take samples but our processes to
make sure that all enforcement actions
are completely wrapped up because any
enforcement we take the recipient has
legal rights and they can challenge the
results we get so we have to make sure
it's they've exhausted all of the rights
that they wish to ex
sighs before before we post anything but
yeah we can we test every year and we
have we have reports for 17 calendar
year and 18 calendar year that are that
are written up just waiting for
enforcement to wrap up I can't wait to
see that and I would encourage listeners
to go on the website if they haven't
seen these results it's freely available
there's no reason you shouldn't go there
and see if the products are using are
have been tested and see what results
you know the Oregon Department of
Agriculture got when they tested the
products you're using I mean it's it's
free information out there and I think
people need to access it I will tell you
it's gonna be more of the same though
same him different verse okay so like
different companies same same accounts
yeah results are not getting better
let's put it that way okay well that's
good to know
that's good to know is there is there
anything else that you guys wanted to
talk about or share with wid listeners
you know Sonny on the policy side or
Matt on the fertiliser side that we
didn't talk about yet it's just looking
at cannabis in general it's still
evolving and I know in Oregon and I
think it's true in other states every
time our legislature is in champ in town
something changes and then the agency
has to go into rulemaking so so taking a
step back the legislature passes a bill
that becomes the law how is the agency
going to implement the law that's the
rules
that we put forth that goes through a
public comment period it's a public
involved process and then ultimately
that's what Matt's program is enforcing
off of is the rules and you know it's
been a wild ride with cannabis and it's
going to continue to be a wild ride and
our legislature will be starting here on
the 22nd of January and that this is a
nod here so it's a full session so that
means hang on to your your hats and
we're going to be working at the
legislature until June so the goal is
always consumer safety and consumer
protections you're always working
towards that goal and it's sort
of evolving as it goes it sounds like
from what you're describing yeah one
specific related with cannabis you know
there's all kinds of other other moving
pieces with the other agencies and you
know law enforcement concerns and
federal concerns and and that affects
the industry and it affects you know it
feels confusing and it feels like things
are changing all the time the agencies
are feeling that pain as well it's it's
not easy and I think it's going to be an
involving process for a number of years
as we start something that's brand-new I
think that's also why I call it you know
opportunities rather than just
challenges is when do you get to be part
of a brand new industry like this yeah
that's a good point it is is this
exciting to be involved in something
that is an emerging market and an
emerging industry and we're all we're
learning so much every year that about
this plant and optimal ways to cultivate
it so I do appreciate that perspective
I'll throw in a couple of comments here
too you know Sonny's talking about
emerging industry but yet on on my side
of the aisle the fertilizer side we're
seeing a definite contraction in the
number of grow shops that are open lots
have closed we're seeing suppliers
smaller suppliers of products that are
no longer renewing their registrations
or are out of business completely the
industry took a big at least on my end
of things took a big hit in 2018 do you
think that was just due to the over
oversupply of cannabis to the
recreational market by growers and then
also the the movement towards online
sales for hydro shops and and going
straight to the manufacturer I think
it's a little of both I think if why why
would I grow a head of lettuce at home
go through all the effort of growing a
head of lettuce at home when I can go to
five different stores within a mile
radius in my house and buy it cheaper
than I can
can grow up myself you're always going
to have folks that home garden and want
to to do it themselves but I think
there's just a lot of folks that are not
buying those input products because
they've either reduced their operation
size or like you said there was a big
oversupply of product in 2018 so the
markets change we had one of our our
registrants here in Oregon when I was at
an inspection a couple years ago who did
not want to see legalization happen
because he felt it would impact his
business and sure enough it's impacting
his business yeah I I agree with that
but I hope maybe people listening this
podcast today will realize some of the
importance behind possibly growing their
own in the sense that they can't
necessarily trust everything that's on
the market as it stands right now from
what we're learning but I do appreciate
you guys working towards keeping keeping
products safe and and really trying to
push you know manufacturers to provide
safe product and accurate product and
then cultivators to do the same with
with the actual cannabis itself so thank
you for that yeah it's never it'll never
go away I mean I grow tomatoes at home
because I find the tomatoes in the
grocery store disgusting so you're
always going to have folks I agree with
you that you're always going to want to
do it themselves too either because they
like to grow things or they want to grow
a variety that they can't find or they
want to fiddle around in many many ways
that they can control but yeah I don't
think we're going to go back to the mid
2000s where the crop was totally legal
and if you wanted a reliable known
source you were gonna do it yourself
yeah well I just want to say thank you
for your time today I really appreciate
you guys your willingness is a
government agency to come on the podcast
and share this information with with
cultivators and take time out of your
day was there anything else you wanted
to add before we sign off I would just
add like you said have folks go look at
the website
Matan eyes contact information is there
or you're welcome to provide our contact
information on your website so if folks
have follow-up questions send them our
way yeah we're
happy to chat with people that's that's
the best way for people to to know what
is happening and get the the true
information because I find there's a lot
of rumors that go around in these
industries a universal for at least my
program is the more folks talk to us the
less problems they have so you would
rather have someone reach out to you at
the beginning before applying a product
before getting to a situation than where
they might be in trouble rather than I
mean the legend absolutely please we
want to we want to help you on the front
end we don't want to come no Blackie
what's a stick on the back end well I
haven't met yet sunny but I can tell you
that Matt was very helpful for me with
on the fertilizer registration side
because as a new company trying to
register a soil and I know soil sort of
for this new part of the within the
fertilizer industry too it was a huge
challenge for me and Matt was very very
helpful and spent time on the phone sort
of explaining label claims and how to
structure everything and what needed to
be on there and what didn't and I really
appreciate it made the process so much
easier so thank you that was sunny
summers and Matt Haynes with the Oregon
Department of Agriculture please do go
to our website and add yourself to the
mailing list for all updates regarding
new information stop sales and their
testing results I posted the links to
the ODA site and information related to
this podcast right on the podcast page
at WWE is organics calm just click on
the podcast menu on the top of the home
screen please reach out with questions
either on our Instagram page at kiss
organics or through our website contact
page thanks for listening