[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge just a friendly reminder for
folks who enjoy the content and want to
support the podcast that we have a
patreon for the podcast where we do book
club Hangouts and share private content
that we don't share on social media we
also offer a wider range of products
ranging from living soils LED lighting
beneficial insects organic fertilizers
and professional Consulting at
www.k organics.com my guest this week is
George Grant George has has degrees in
horiculture from the University of
Georgia and the University of Florida he
is the ggs pro technical service manager
with Griffin greenhouse supplies ggs Pro
assists ornamental edible and hemp
cannabis Growers across the country with
their cultivation issues ranging from
sanitation IPM fertility lighting and
water quality ggs Pro Fields over 17,000
grower related calls and emails annually
this amount of valuable interaction
helps Griffin colle collaborate with
chemical vendors academic researchers
and plant producers to implement change
within the green industry now on to the
show hey George thanks for coming on the
show
today thanks Dad I really appreciate the
opportunity yeah now you're a good
friends with Michael Alden who's a prior
guest who uh talked a lot about a
variety of topics lead around photo
period um intern node spacing and some
of the
cultural uh practic that could uh
influence those things uh light light
restriction
um and he said that you were you're a
good friends from college can you tell
me a little bit about your
background sure so uh yeah Mike and I go
way back um I have my background is in
horiculture from University of Georgia
and the University of Florida so I am
from the south don't really sound like
it too much um I currently live in gold
in Colorado
um I'm fortunate I'm fortunate because
I've been blessed with really good
mentors
um basically right after grad school I
met a man named Ricky Ates um and he's
very well known in the ornamental
industry um he was the head of the
technical department for Griffin
greenhouse supplies Griffin is a
nationwide distributor for plant
products both in the hard goods and live
Goods side of things um we've been very
heavily involved with CA ornamentals and
cannabis over the last several years um
and Rick basically just took me under
rer wing and um showed me that it's
showed me all the things I didn't know
and all the things that I could
potentially know so I've got a a great
team around me
um couldn't don't have enough so many
things great to say about Griffin and
the family culture that they they bring
um but what I really love about my job
is I and I tell Growers this and they
don't really like it but I I get to
share all the success but none of the
stress of growing I I realized quickly
in grad school that I just couldn't I
couldn't sleep at night knowing I had a
crop in the greenhouse um but I realized
that I do love the problem solving
aspects of of of helping Growers it's I
have no idea what's going to happen when
that phone call Rings or that email pops
up it could be anything and that's what
I love about this job so I get to learn
a little bit about everything relates to
crop protection nutrition uh cultural
practices you name it and also at the
same time we get to understand what are
the new trends that are developing
across the various Industries so I'm
very blessed and very grateful for my
position yeah that's awesome so you get
to hear all of the challenges that are
happening uh with the Growers that you
work with um
what what sort of commonalities do you
see around that are there you know
common issues or problems that seem to
arrive arise
consistently yeah absolutely I mean it's
growing plants in general is not c as
cookie cutter as people may think every
operation's different every every
culture meaning the people that are
involved the stakeholders everything is
different also the state in which
they're growing is different so I would
say as far as the major source of
problems that we typically get is people
people uh have a problem and that could
be pest or disease related and they
don't know what tools they have
available and when I say tools I mean
both from a cultural aspect as well as a
chemical aspect as you know cannabis is
still relatively you know even though
people think it's it's got a very
defined culture and in some ways it does
but for most of the country it's still
relatively new crop and from a legal
side it's very new so uh state
governments are still trying to figure
out what pesticides can and cannot be
used I I often times see Growers trying
to use a product that isn't approved
legally and then again they might use it
in a way that's that's not that they
shouldn't be using using it on I mean if
we you mentioned Mike in his research I
think is very groundbreaking a lot of
the research coming out of Academia
relates to fertilizer and cultural
practices nowadays but there's hardly
any research coming out on the crop
protection side of things specifically
to cannabis so um I'm I'm I'm fueling
that whenever I get the opportunity to
speak I'm trying to tell Growers to do
internal trials control trials as well
as our vendor Partners we work with B
basically every major vendor from a crop
protection standpoint Under the Sun and
so I'm I'm urging them to do do
controlled trials on cannabis
specifically because Growers want to
know what is working what is not what is
safe and what is not so phyto toxicity
concerns are very common practice a lot
of times we grow in an indoor
environment and Growers don't understand
may not understand how to apply a
pesticide correctly in a very uh
controlled environment versus a
greenhouse or even outdoor so um each of
those each each of those contexual
factors
play well let's cover that a little bit
then so if we're talking about a
pesticide and I guess it doesn't really
matter what that pesticide is um and
correct me here as we go uh but want to
make sure we're always applying to the
label rate where we've read the uh MSDS
or SDS around that product to know what
how to use it safely um and we have the
proper PPE and protection in place and
that the application rate is established
to give you maximum efficacy at the
lowest concentration and the least risk
of photoxicity so it's always important
to apply to application rate to avoid um
creating insect resistance to that
whatever that chemistry is assuming it's
a chemistry and not an oil um anything
anything you would change in that those
statements or anything you would add to
that no but I would definitely agree
with you the label is law and that's
something we stand behind all the time
um and I'm not afraid to tell Growers
that as well it's just frankly it's it's
just you know it is what it is um
resistance is a major issue regardless
of what plant you're growing I think
what's advantageous for cannabis Growers
is most of the products that are
approved for cannabis use are what we
call quote unquote soft chemistry or
microbial based chemistries so your
Bavaria your aeras your Aid duratin um
so illus very important so those those
Mo those active ingredients typically
don't deal with resistance issues like
we do with hard chemistry or
conventional chemistry so I think that's
advantageous but that doesn't downplay
the fact that we should be rotating um
depending on the situation I mean when
I'm talking I work with Canabis grows
almost every single day and I can tell
you the main ones are going to be it's
going to be uh either it's going to be a
root AIT it's going to be a cannabis AIT
it's either going to be a thrip
spidermite um powder M or Bettis
and so there's a lot of overlap from
what an ornamental grower will deal with
as well as a cannabis grower
unfortunately the toolkit is just much
much smaller when we're working with
cannabis yeah well you listed a whole
bunch of different um challenges in
cannabis do you want to dive into any
one of those in
particular
um yeah absolutely I mean just let's
just talk about microbials for a moment
so most of the microbials that we use
they do very well in high humid
relatively cool temperatures high
humidity environments and that's almost
exactly opposite of what we're trying to
achieve in an indoor grow operation um
we're usually shooting for highl very
low extremely low relative humidi um and
so things dry out um and that microbials
work the same way so if I do when I'm
working with a grower it's very
important they understand how to manage
their agac system so and this actually
kind of goes back to phto as well so
when I a general rule of thumb when
applying any type P side is I want it to
be less than 80 degrees in that growing
environment and I want relatively
relatively low humidity so it dries
relatively quickly U microbials work a
little bit differently though they they
do want to be applied at a a cooler
temperature but a slower drying
condition or greater relative humidity
allows for them to do better if it's
fungal based they're going to sporulate
if they're bacterial based they're going
to populate more um and they're going to
stay on that insect for longer so I want
I try to work with Growers and make sure
they understand when they're doing an
application or a series of applications
that they're they're managing their HVAC
system so they maxifi maximize the
efficacy of those
pesticides yeah o oils are a great
example of something that can easily
burn cannabis and that's that that
temperature and light intensity sort of
parameter needs to be dialed in um
that's why a lot of Growers are going I
mean not just the only reason but one of
the reasons why people are going to
dimable LEDs or adjustable intensity
LEDs is is they can lower the light
intensity so there's less actually light
intensity or light stress potentially on
that plant when an pet application is
made until it's
dried yeah I just want to remind folks
too that oils and sulfur do not mix um
and frankly I think there's better
options than sulfur uh in cannabis in
most cases but um I just want to throw
that out there as well and and one thing
that you touched on with humidity I
wanted to talk about a little bit
because um I'm seeing people running a
higher RH now that we're as a community
more informed and learning and
understanding VPD um so like I use the
VPD chart from Dr Greenhouse Nadia Dr
Nadia SAA um I know there's a lot of
great ones out there but given that
we're running you know slightly higher
humidity at least in veg and through
most of flour does that allow for better
usage of a lot of these pesticides then
yeah I would say from my cral standpoint
absolutely
um we don't want to I mean it I wouldn't
be surprised if we have heart we have
greater pest pressure and disease
pressure when we run relative higher
relative humidities but it's much better
just it's going going we were going from
like 20% 40% relative humidity
incredibly low relative humidities to
Now 50 is 60 um and even a little bit
higher if especially in a greenhouse
situation um so I think it's it's better
um just because we're not not stressing
out the plan as
much yeah as a side know I did a
interview with uh Nicole go I'm actually
following up with her she's a
pathologist at the University of
Kentucky Kentucky and she was saying
that one of the two species of powdery
milder that in infects in cannabis can
actually sporulate at 40% humidity um so
even lowering humidity you're now you're
stressing the plant and you're still at
risk if you have this particular species
of PM um you're creating optimal
conditions for it to reproduce which I
thought was really interesting
um but um I believe it I mean we get
pattery Milo here in Colorado and people
think we're incredibly dry the i i
people need to think about and I think
we I love how the cultures between
ornamentals and cannabis is going at fir
at first I believe there was quite a bit
of tension but I think now we're we're
starting to to learn from each other as
we get closer into integrated in the and
and I think it's important because
cannabis Growers are going to need to
learn more about Greenhouse production
as that becomes more of a norm I mean
for example with powdering mildew we
know just from Greenhouse production
that it's typically it rears its head
most on the shoulders of the season so
from Winter to Spring and then basically
summer to fall it's those transitional
times where pow Mill just tends pressure
just tends to a Skyrocket so I I like
that we're learning from each other and
communicating yeah yeah no that's great
and I want to just also touch on you
brought up a really good point around
light intensity because a lot of the
research coming out by Dr Bruce bugby
now is is showing higher light intensity
can increase yields um and he's pushing
the envelope pretty high in terms of uh
par or
ppfd I would assume that as people start
running higher light intensity we do
need to dim it down to avoid
phytotoxicity because I like when I do
an application of like seoil X for
example um I don't always consider what
my light intensity is uh because I have
never really pushed it that high but if
I were to run a higher light light
intensity I would want to you know
potentially dial it down and and also do
you want to talk about when we should be
spraying during the light cycle I think
that's another important aspect
depending on absolutely actually there's
exact question up today it in general
ideally if I was in a greenhouse
situation I'd be I ideally wanting to
apply in the morning hours so light
intensities are relatively low they're
increasing but they're relatively low
humidity is rela it can be can
definitely start high and then start go
go down as the as the sun rises but what
I it's preferable to be in the morning
because we still have cool enough
conditions for phyto to be reduced but
then also we we ensure that we're we're
going to have it dried out we're not
going to go into the evening hours or
dark time hours with wet foliage or wet
flowers that's never advantageous now
the the flip side of that the the reason
why it logistically doesn't always occur
in the why spraying doesn't occur in the
morning hours is because of REI so you
know T depending on the pesticide it can
range from anywhere from four hours to
12 hours or even four even 24 hours
depending on the chemistry luckily most
of our organic or softer chemistries
have very low Reis so that does kind of
free up the the situation but if I spray
something still have to follow the REI
and I can't handle that plant for x
amount of hours until that REI is over
uh and for those unfamiliar REI stands
for return entry interval so it's the
amount of time before you can go back
into that space after spraying
whatever the particular pesticide or
spray was so just want to let folks
know um well interesting
so like you said you you get a lot of
stuff around um it sounds like pathogens
what about with pest pressure like are
you seeing a lot with um
I don't know hempress it right now or or
any uh any particular might
pressure someone once asked me if you is
there ever a situation when you're an
indoor grower where you can completely
100% eliminate pests um and I told them
it's most likely not feasible because
somebody is either entering or exiting
that building or product is either
entering or exiting the building and
that's the sole reason reason why we end
up having an infestation a lot of these
indoor operations are very buttoned up
very very tight but unfortunately
employees do do a great job of kind of
transferring pest um into a facility I
mean broad mites spidermites hosam might
they're all great hitchhikers they will
jump onto or whenever an employee rubs
up against that that plant that has that
pest they do a great job of clinging
onto them and then moving throughout the
the production space so um obviously
sanitation and are trying to prevent any
type of pest entering facilties is very
important
um yeah I mean hemp Russ might has been
around for some time I mean it it I
think it was a really big issue maybe
two years ago um when it started really
affecting everyone but the reality is is
once you have a hessit might issue that
what I'd like to tell Growers similar
with broad mites broad mites are just as
hard because you can't see them H might
very difficult to see broad might same
way you typically see the damage first
and then you like realize you have then
have an infant station so a lot of what
I don't and this is going to probably
really make some people not feel good
but the best way to start out with a dis
an issue like that infestation is is
coing plants and when I say coing I
means throwing out plants that have the
highest pest pressure you are going to
spend more money and resources and have
an much uper battle trying to solve an
infestation when you've got just a
select few plants that have the are the
source of that problem you really need
to throw out or destroy those plants and
then do start your pesti side
applications a lot of people don't don't
consider doing that because they want to
they want to try to save every plant
they can but it's just something to
think about especially if you're growing
a large amount of plants um feel free to
throw away a few plants if they're the
most symptomatic physically reducing
aulum is actually a very powerful tool I
don't see enough Growers
use yeah you don't hear that suggested
very often so you're saying if there's a
hot spot in a room rather than trying to
spray it or or let's just say you're in
flower you know midflower to where you
can't really pistol pistol growth is
already happening you can't really spray
anything um beneficials take a little
bit longer I mean um the classic example
is by the time you have webbing if
you're in flower with spidermites it's
already too late like you're not you're
not GNA be able to fix it so you're
saying just take them out reduce that
overall pressure and then come up with a
plan for the rest of the
crop yeah absolutely I mean you said it
you said it very well
um it it works on the same in the
ornamental side of things and cannabis
is not necessarily able to do this but
on ornamentals let's say I've got a
sweet potato vine very common ornamental
um that is an attracted to a lot of
different pests that also affects
cannabis so when I've got broad mites
and Broad mites and mites in general
really interesting because they what
you'll see when you look at the damage
is that the older growth more
established growth doesn't seem that
symptomatic or damage but as you move up
into the plant to the mor static areas
you actually see the damage get worse
and worse and what happening is the m
species are actually moving up to the
new growth they're reproducing in
Greater number and causing more damage
but what we sometimes do in ornamentals
if it's allowable is I cut off the
affected portions of the plant where
those mites are present and just
basically destroy that material by and
essentially I'm pinching it I'm pinching
that plant then allowing the lateral
growth the underneath growth to then
expand and the mites are not present
there so that's just a that's a small
cultural method and it doesn't really
make sense for most cannabis situations
unless I was talking about mother stock
that might make sense in that
situation yeah if you're early enough in
veg too that you can just kind of lower
your canopy I could see that if you did
across the board um but yeah I've always
thought of uh hempd or broad broad might
damage is sort of that Twisted new green
growth a little bit lighter green
coloring too almost like a iron
deficiency but then the leaves will do
this sort of twisting Distortion to them
um and then you really need to get out
scope um and make sure it's you can't
just use your phone you need like a dino
light or something that's going to give
you a little better magnification and
and a little better Clarity to really
see it at least in my
experience oh yeah 100% um you know we
work a lot we work a lot off photos and
and and phone calls and so people get
really creative on their adjectives they
use to describe symptoms um and some and
some Growers aren't comfortable um
sharing photos which is perfectly fine
um but what what I like to think about
what I like to ask the Growers what's
the uniformity of the issue when I walk
into a situation first thing I want to
know is is it an abiotic issue or a
biotic issue well everything we've been
talking about thus far are biotic issues
they're they're caused by living things
and typically when we have a biotic
issue it the uniformity is not not
incredibly uniform so if it was a
fertilizer issue or a nutritional issue
it's going to affect all the all all the
plants relatively the same way because
they're all receiving the same input if
same with phyto like a phytotoxicity
event if I sprayed something and the it
was way too hot or I played something
and it wasn't a correct rate it's going
to damage those plants uniformally thus
that leans me that makes me think okay
this is going to be an abiotic issue
whereas biotic issues tend to be much
more localized or spread out more
randomly throughout a production
area yeah that's a good point I just
want to point out some um other things
to consider like uh it could be an aoic
issue if you had like a fan for example
in a corner that was creating a
different air pocket that maybe allowed
pm to start uh growing uh so your
abiotic issue could be creating your
biotic problem to a certain extent and a
lot of times plant stress whether that's
from fertilizer uh deficiencies or
excesses can lead especially around
nitrogen can lead to higher pest
pressure so uh these things are all
really interconnected just making it way
more complicated but I but you're right
you have to be detective when you walk
in the room just like if you're looking
at it from a nutrient perspective we
want to know where is this issue
occurring is it the entire plan is it a
mobile nutrient is it an immobile
nutrient like um I always like people to
send me photos of the issue and then
also the whole plant and even the whole
room so we can really get an idea of
what's going
on I could give you an entire album of
poor photos I I don't know what it is um
but we just get I mean and it is what it
is but it's amazing some of these one
leaf photos on the hand or uh just a
very blurry photo but if you're ever
working with us or any tech technical
specialist please just take the time to
send a few clear photos and like you
said Ted whole plant photos we want to
see the tops we want to see the bottoms
oftentimes if something especially
nutritionally if something's affecting
or disease related if something's
affecting the top we want to look at the
roots immediately to see if it if that's
like you said the primary issue leading
to a secondary issue that we're seeing
yeah that's another great Point people
should absolutely kick a pot out of the
out of the container and take a look at
the roots or dig into their bed or their
or their container and see what's going
on there um I think people forget about
that a lot of times I forget about it
sometimes um but there's a lot of root
pathogens that we need to rule out um
and so that's that's a great
suggestion um cool well what um what are
you seeing around uh so we've talked a
lot like pest pressures and things like
that but what sort of cultural practices
are you seeing uh being implemented that
are being most effective or or giving
Growers the the best chance of
success let me tell you what not is not
being implemented um because I think
that's more important the things that
the the these are standard practices
that are used in the ornamental side
that I believe should be utilized or at
least adopted and tri on the Cannabis
side of things one is called dip and one
is called diff so we have dip and D if
I'll first talk about diff first so we
can manipulate plant stretching or
architecture by adjusting the average
daily temperature daytime temperature
and average nightly temperature the
difference between those averages if
there's a more positive diff meaning
there's a greater day temperature than a
night temperature the greater that
difference the more we're going to get
imp plant stretching the less difference
we get so if I had a diff of zero
meaning that my average day temperature
and average night temperature are the
exact same then we can we can basically
reduce stretching or even in situations
this is primarily done in indoor
situations where I can have a negative
diff I can have I can actually have a
higher night a higher night temperature
than my daytime temperature and I can
create more of a stunted plant I not
seeing that Tri and I would love to see
how that affects plant basically
vegetative uh vegetative architecture as
well as flower architecture so that's
diff and that's a very common practice
used ornamentals something that's a
slight offset of that is called dip di
dip and what happens is and this is
primarily more important for uh
Greenhouse or outdoor situations is that
we know from research that the first few
hours about three hours as the sun is
rising lower light intensities and the
quality of the light is different and
majority of plant stretch actually
occurs in the first three hours of
Daybreak and so what Growers will do on
the ornamental side is they will
actually drop their night their their
their temperatures in the greenhouse by
about 5 degrees lower than what their
average night temperature is so we've
got the sun rising for about three hours
and during this time the plant is
starting to wake up it's starting to
become photosynthetically active but
because of the light intensity itself
and the quality it's wanting to stretch
very very much so and so we can reduce
that ability or that plant's ability to
want to stretch by dropping the night
dropping that temperature and creating
sort of a cold stress to prevent that
stretch from from happening so those are
two cultural practices I don't see used
and I don't even see it side in in
literature related to cannabis yet but I
do I foresee that happening in the
future wow yeah that's really
interesting I I'm familiar with diff
though I haven't really thought of the
implications within cannabis which is
kind of crazy when you when you say it
like that because it it does seem it
does seem worth trialing um and the dip
thing I haven't I had even heard of so
yeah I hope people would take that up as
some research because I think that could
be that could be really interesting um
I I don't know of anyone running a
negative diff in
cannabis and I also wonder how CO2 plays
a role if any in that in the fact that
we have such great amounts of CO2
production happening at night um
especially in these living soil Beds
which is sort of the realm that that I
work in
um yeah yeah I think that's interesting
I need to think about that a little bit
thank you for sharing
that um what other what other cultural
practices are you seeing really being um
maybe done wrong or things that you you
hear
continually that are just little
mistakes that you think people could
could
avoid well I think uh overwatering
cannabis can easily be an issue and
underwatering cannabis can easily be an
issue um I a lot of research that's
going to come out in the next couple
years is they're going to use certain
crops as model crops for cannabis poia
like you said Mikel Alden did a good
he's equated kind of poinas as a model
crop for poincettia for cannabis and
they do have a lot of overlap but
poinsettia is is a crop that doesn't
like a lot of change I when I I work
with a lot of can a lot of poinsettia
Growers and I tell them if you're if
you're going to be a drive grower be a
drrive grower if you're going to be a
wet grower be a wet grower do not change
your T don't change your tactics um
really Midway through the crop now I
know a lot of people do deer do dry down
steering and there's there's a lot of
information regarding that but in
general if we're talking just mass
production of
cannabis you're you're safer being more
more routine in your irrigation
practices and I think one way people are
sort of getting around there are
providing some buffer to poor irrigation
management is converting to Pete I mean
Pete Pete Moss as far as a growing media
has become much more accepted over the
last couple years as as the before the
traditional ways of growing and still
are very prominent as core and grow down
or Rock W and obviously living soil as
you said that's a complete different
complete different situation but I do
see a lot of Growers converting to Pete
both from a moisture management
standpoint reason as well as from a
nutritional standpoint it obviously has
a much higher CC um or cation exchange
capacity meaning it holds on in
nutrition much more heavily compared to
something like core or groden which is
relatively in
nerd I I mean I like P just because the
lower pH allows me to front load a lot
of nutrients into the into the soil mix
uh prior to planting which is something
with core where you're already starting
at seven most of the inputs that are
have I want to add or cat ions or their
alkaline it just uh pushes my pH out of
range that's my biggest reason for
liking Pete and I I think it's more
sustainable Than People realize I've
seen some interesting uh research around
the replenishment of pee pogs I'm not
saying it's perfect but I I think you
could easily make the argument for it
over cocoa core in a lot of ways with
the amount of fossil fuel and
ecological uh damage Associated around
core
production yeah well whatever prod
whatever input you use for your growing
media it's it's it's one of the most
important ones so whoever you're buying
it through it needs to be a very quality
product it needs to go through a very
rigorous QA QC process um because you
don't want product that event
unfortunately let's say I mean core for
example there are some core core sources
that that would not be buffered meaning
they haven't been leeched typically with
either clear water or calcium nitrate to
basically rinse out the excessive salts
that are in that media during the
process of the processing of that media
so it just I think Pete in general it's
been around for so long and a lot of the
major producers of Pete they have very
good processes and typically the quality
is reliable I do like that I like that
as
well yeah I think the quality of cocoa
cor has gotten a lot better over the
years um I think some of those
inconsistencies have have improved but
uh yeah I've never been wanting to use a
lot of cocoa core in any of my mixes so
it's um it's not something I have as
much experience with I've looked into
other options and you are seeing more uh
options showing up from like wood pulp
the wood pulp industry but I I haven't
been able to get the same quality of
growth or production that I can with
Pete Moss and until I can get something
to to replace it I mean there's
somewhere you could potentially reduce
the amount of Pete Moss they can replace
say like 20 to 30% of the Pete in your
mix um but they're not they're not able
to fully replace it yet but I hope we
get there with with a you know new
substrates yeah I would say I mean we're
getting off topic here but Brian Jackson
from MC State I mean he is spearheading
the research for um I would say um
uncommon amendments I don't know if it's
specifically I've got a good very good
relationship with Brian um but I don't
know if he's specifically looking at
cannabis but he is if anyone's
interested in Wood fiber or anything
that's non-traditional Pete um
amendments or or Soul Media or soless
media products definitely it's worth
giving him a
research yeah I'll have to hit you up
for an introduction later after the
podcast yeah absolutely I'm sure you'd
love to him he's a great guy that'd be
great um very cool
well then what
um I guess I I want to dive a little bit
into what sort of products do you
find uh you tend to recommend the most
for folks that are that are interested
in in utilizing you know products in I
realize this that's not for everyone we
kind of talked about some of the more
General things but what if we got a
little more specific into some of the
things that you tend to generally
recommend more frequently than
others um we're talking about from an
IPM standpoint or or nutritional
standpoint I mean we could we can do
either really uh why don't we start with
IPM because we've kind of been talking
about talking about IPM sure um well it
once again depends on the state so a
couple of examples of really good States
um that are doing an active job of
updating lists and providing publicly a
publicly available list of active
ingredients or specific products that
are approved would be like New York uh
Colorado Oregon those are kind of the in
my mind they're the role model for I
would hope Most states eventually move
to actually publishing lists and
updating them of products that can be
used a lot of the time it's it is a wild
goose chase I mean we we're trying to
we'd have to sometimes call in to state
government or Regulatory Agencies and
it's really hard for them to want to
give us an answer because frankly maybe
they don't know or the law hasn't been
been written enough with guidance to for
them to be able to to give us a
recommendation so and I I hate that I
hate that that sometimes we can't the
government's not helping us to help
Growers and sometimes the Growers have a
have a problem they don't know what
solutions they can legally use so that's
never a good situation but that aside um
the mo the most of the products that I
see that are on these sort of approved
State lists are going to be your Bavaria
bassiana products your iseria fosa
products um all your billus products so
B basilla subtilus pumilus am Fashions
I'm using all these scientific names but
these are the kind of the main staple
active ingredients that are utilized by
cannabis Growers and when we take kind
of microbials out of the equation then
we have oils and soaps those play an
incredibly incredibly powerful tool um
mbgs aren't really a major issue in
cannabis hardly ever seen them but soaps
play a major role for for mbgs and then
for oils those play a major role for
pretty much all of our insects Under the
Sun and all of our Midas sdes I mean
there really is no good MDES out there
other than oils and so that's that's
going to be a staple in every Grower's
operation um taking all those microbials
out of the situ situation we still have
oxidizers and this is more on a disease
prevention standpoint but your sanates
zerls any your hydren peroxide parasitic
acid products those are incredibly
valuable both from a biofilm and algae
prevention standpoint we got to remember
wherever there's water and fertilizer
there's going to be algae and biofilm
and that I don't care if you're an
indoor operation or outdoor operation
that's going to be a problem and it does
it becomes a literally a physical and
Equipment problem for anyone using
drippers or hoses or piping ET so
injecting continuously or periodically
injecting our sanates of the or sanidate
or zerol or hydrogen peroxide parastic
acid products it's a good way to prevent
that algae and bile from coming in but
also they're incredibly versatile
Fungicide and bactericidal property so
um I do see some Growers solely relying
on something like zerol or sanate or
sanate 12.0 because sanidate 5.0 isn't
La for plant uh plant contact but zerol
for example very broad label see that
used a lot both in fogging applications
foler applications and drenching
applications as their sole sort of
product for um disease
prevention and
uh with the with the fogging and things
like that are you seeing any
phytotoxicity with those types of
products so actually zerol is fairly
safe it's amazing I mean it it's um I'm
not going to drop any names but um do
know some very reliable Growers um who
have Tri done some internal trials with
zerotol and I mean they're spraying it
all the way to harvest and not having a
degradation on on THC levels or
cannaboid levels um would be curious how
it I would like to see some controlled
studies though because it is an oxidizer
it does have to have some chemical
impact on tpin um and canid content but
I would just love to see where that
threshold is and what it actually does
um but as far as phto is concerned I
mean it it's all about rates so it's
important that you read the label and do
I I always try to preach this but doing
small scale Tri small scale trials can
save you a lot of money and
unfortunately Growers don't do that they
don't just mix up you know one gallon
here and there spray a few plants see
what happens but I do encourage Growers
to do that especially as they're just
establishing rates that work for them um
but in general zerol can be fairly safe
if the rates are or the rates are
correct and the application process
correct I mean I mentioned fogging you
brought up fogging fogging or ulv ultra
low volume equipment or applicators it's
becoming very very popular it's been
it's been I mean drram is I'm not going
to lie dram is spearheaded this um
they've got the best quality Foggers on
the market and they are doing the the
due diligence to understand how to
actually apply it in a safe way um and
I'm seeing a lot of indoor Growers use
like an autof fogger or mini autof
fogger by dram I mean I don't know a
grower who's invested in one and not
liked it it's just great because you
basically mix it up set the timer set it
in the room and you're you're good to go
it reduces es quite a bit from that
employee safety standpoint that that
hits home there but also it's just not
labor intensive uh it's nowhere near
labor intensive as getting on PPE and
getting a backpack sprayer on and
spraying plants in the evening no one
really wants to do that so you all the
technology is I think it's we're just
kind of in the the the beginning stages
of
it um but I think it can be very good in
a lot of different situations it
typically tends to reduce the chances of
phyto because we're using less chemical
per square footage and the particle size
itself is much smaller so we're not
getting when I look phyto for example um
what oftentimes happens is you have a
Congregation of liquid or active
ingredient on the edges of the leaf
because it's all kind of just dripping
down into that area accumulating and
that's where the phyto damage can occur
but when you fog something it's
uniformly getting those particles at AI
across the entire Leaf surface and we
don't have that puddling effect so that
that in essence does prevent phyto in
that way
now you have to be careful with what
products like you mentioned a bunch of
microbial Solutions at the beginning um
I'm not aware of any that can go through
a fogger uh just to let folks know and
maybe I'm wrong here but in my
experience the Foggers pretty much
destroy all even the basilis species
from what I understand um so luckily
there are different types of Foggers
some are thermal-based and some are
basically used using so such high
pressure and putting it through such a
fine screen that it's kind of creating
that small particle effect um so many
autof Foggers for example pulse fog or
biopulse Foggers pulse Foggers are
thermal but there's a biopulse fogger by
dram that basically I'm not going to go
into but basically allows us put
microbials through it autof Foggers
they're not they're non-thermal they can
be used they can they can use microbials
in softer chemistry now we put together
um fogging charts for Growers so if you
buy a a dram some sort of fogger through
Griffin we'll put together we put
together a customized chart for you so
you tell us the square footage of your
production space and we can tell you
what products are properly labeled for
fogging and the rates to use them at um
and that's something specific to Griffin
that no other distributor does um but
that aside um it we can it just depends
on the fogger itself and we can use
microbial some some do get broken down
oh that's really interesting uh one
thing I want to touch on with microbials
um because you mentioned you know a
bunch of different species everything
from Bavaria to iseria basilis things
like that there could be a big
difference I think in quality and
efficacy uh based on not just where you
Source it but also the species itself so
we can assume that all bavar is the same
all basilis subtilus is the same um and
I think that needs to be taken into
account I mean just looking at just
taking bavaria's an example I know like
um the bioer product for example has a
very specific uh range of you know
humidity and and heat and cold
temperatures drought conditions that
they can handle and thrive in and then
you could look at a different you know a
different Bavaria product and say okay
well maybe because it's a different
species it may do slightly better or
worse in you know a given environment
so I think as we're trying out different
ones kind of be looking at sport camp
and not taking it to be you know the the
Bible because what says on the label is
not always what's in the package but it
get least give you an idea of whether or
not this could be a viable
product I 100% agree with you I mean for
me I'm not I'm I'm not a sale I don't
work in sales at all I only just try to
provide Solutions and try to be unbiased
as possible um just given the situation
so often times a grow will ask us okay
well we see you you know we see there's
a lot of different Bavaria products or
Aid duratin products out there whatever
it may be um which one should I go with
and well I go okay well how much is
let's look at Cost that's always a good
parameter to look at so we like to do
cost and use analyses so what's the cost
per gallon or cost per pound of AI or
whatever it may be um that's something
that's a very quick calculation we do
all the time just to get a grow just to
let the grower understand okay well this
is more in my budget range um and I'm
willing to maybe jeopardize some maybe
level of quality quality to make sure
that I still applying the right amount
of active ingredient given my price
range yeah that's a good point and I
think about like what do I want to have
in my pantry as a grower this is
something I've been thinking more and
more about lately what sorts of tools uh
let's say let's say with IPM would you
want to keep in your in your
pantry uh well I would say definitely an
oil um with what's available i' I'd have
a basilis um for a as my fungicide I'd
have also trichoderma so like root
shield for example very common sort of
inoculant um for and when we talk about
all these microbials they should they
should really be used preventatively um
I mean it's like BCA biological control
agents we should go into this with the
mentality and perspective of this is
going to be I'm putting this out to
prevent anything that that
develops these software chemistries
they're just not really meant to be a
come from behind product or a knockdown
product some of them do have some of
those characteristics but it's always
better to be using these preventatively
um proactive proactively rather than
reactively um but I think we've named
some of the major ones I would
definitely have um there's a lot of
conventional chemistries U that I wish
would be accepted in cannabis use just
because they would I think be a
GameChanger especially on the fungicidal
standpoint I think with insecticides
there there really isn't there's there's
very there's a fine line between hard
chemistry and soft chemistry but when we
move to fungicides there's definitely
some that are in that kind of gray area
that are are currently used or labeled
for edible use that I could easily see
um be used in cannabis
use H yeah so you you mentioned you'd
want an oil
um like for for example for anab basilla
so like for me um I I would put uh an
oil a Horticultural some sort of
horticultural oil like you mentioned um
I really like Bavaria I really like
traderma um I haven't used a lot of
basilis species from a from a pesticide
or uh prevention aspect I've only used
them for like nutrient cycling and and
those sorts of like benefits so that's
interesting that you mentioned that um I
will say yes there are kind of you'll
see these sort of um soil and they it's
labeling is very is an interesting art I
will say um but there are certain things
that are labeled as soil amendments or
soil inoculant that will have variety of
different vasilla species that you will
see do have um they do have pesticidal
properties if you look in other
fungicides that have those active
ingredients the the the producer of that
product just cannot legally make those
claims or they'd have to change the
labeling itself um sure but I will say
with Bavaria and this is actually with
oils too A lot of these microbs can be
tank mixed and there's s there's symbiot
like symbiotic relationships I'll say
synergistic relationships with each
other so Bavaria tank mixed with aid
duratin aid duratin is an extract from
neem oil and it's an igr and insect
growth regulator pairing these are
really ites a very powerful and
broadspectrum application the reason why
is that most of these microbials either
they either bavar either fungal or
bacterial based is that we're trying to
ultimately coat the insect or MIT or
whatever we're trying to go after we're
trying to coat them and get as much of
that active ingredient on them as
possible because what happens is that
it's fungal based it's going to
ultimately sporulate inside that insect
and kill it if it's B if it's bacterial
based typically what happens is they
actually um if if they get wet then it
can dissolve in and dissolve in through
a membrane like that but also what I
like about bacterium or bacteria based
pesticides is that when they eat the pro
they eat the foliage that has the
bacterium in it they're ingesting it
that way but either way if I pair it
with an ACD duratin an igr insect growth
regulator it keeps that Spore on there
for longer like aphids for I mean any of
our major insects they're going through
molting processes I mean they're
continuously trying to mol to ultimately
come adults but if we can use an igr to
prevent them from molting they can't
actually physically shed the spores or
inoculum we're putting on them and so
that's why it's a great combination
that's a very common program we
recommend and typically we're doing that
on a five to seven day interval as far
as read
application yeah that's really that's
really useful uh one thing that I was
thinking thinking of while you were
talking about this that we haven't
mentioned is nematodes um I did a recent
podcast with Julie Gres from bioworks
talking a lot about nematodes and I just
recently made a recommendation of the SF
or Steiner NE feler mispronounce it uh
nematodes uh specifically as a
preventative because
um especially in living soils or when
you have any compost fraction you're or
any organic matter in general you're
probably going to at the very least have
fungus SS um not to mention the numerous
other things that these neod work so
effectively on they play nicely with
Bavaria and other microbials um so like
for me that would go in my pantry too
now that we're talking about things that
I just I love to have as a part of a
maintenance IPM
program yeah absolutely and don't get me
started on BCA that' be a whole another
talk I me Julie's Fant Julie is
fantastic um that's why I love also
about my position I get to interact with
all these really good professionals and
these different vendors um but like you
said Stein feler and there's other
different beneficial nematodes out there
depending on what we're after I love NE
beneficial nematodes specifically um SF
specii because it goes after the thrip
pupa so we don't a lot of people don't
understand this but when thri they
basically have two laral stages and then
when they want to pupate meaning that
they want to become an adult they'll
actually drop to the soul surface and
it's at that point the nematodes
actually become very beneficial there um
so they play a very key role for both
fungus net um both both fungus snap even
Shor flies and um thrip control now this
is a tool it's not chemical but I'm
seeing Growers not enough Growers use it
but I'm starting to see ornamental
Growers massive ornamental Growers use
it and it's yellow sticky tape not cards
so yellow sticky sticky cards everyone's
probably familiar with that they've seen
it in an operation on a bench right
above the canopy and it and they it that
a yeli card is meant for scouting it's
really meant to see what is present
that's flying around okay but yellow
sticky tape that literally comes in hund
several 100 foot rolls you can wrap that
between benches and then we have
actually a physical way of reducing the
disease or I'm sorry the insect pressure
and that works really well I mean it
really really work works well I wish I
could share my screen I'd show you a
photo of of of a of several operations
using it especially in the Southeast
where fungus net fungus Nets are just
out of control they fill every square
inch of that of that sticky tape so
that's a that's a cool little C tool I
don't see enough Growers using it
beneficial inory produces it and they
also produce these clips that are very
helpful to attaching them to structures
but definitely something to look
into yeah we work with catchmaster who
makes a lot of these type of of cards
and uh I I've seen the roles um in
facilities though actually Mass trapping
kind of what you're describing uh the
one I was in it was it was primarily rud
aphids at the time and they were uh very
prolific and you could see them all over
the uh all over the tape um in fact oh
that's a big issue then yeah we were
brushing them off of ourselves our our
tyac suits as we were walking out of the
room it was uh it was a lot and one
thing I learned on that one that was
kind of interesting is they they
couldn't figure out why there were dead
winged adult rude aphids on um on the
buds themselves like on what people call
Sugar leaves you know the and um
essentially I talked to Suzanne about
this what she said was happening was
they were actually going up too close to
the light dying and then falling back
down and Landing there so it wasn't any
sort of IPM practice that they had that
was killing these which was they they
had guessed some different bacterias
possibly or other things um it was
really just the mechanical action of
flying up into the lights and coming
back down and Landing but uh yeah yeah
pretty crazy to see on that scale
um tough rud AIDS are tough like I mean
it's it was a good facility I'm not
throwing them under a bus like it it's a
problem that's once you have it it's
very hard on the commercial scale to get
rid of I absolutely it's uh the best way
toe the best way to solve it is prevent
it um rude aits can be a really bad one
the problem is they don't they they they
create an economic loss but they don't
kill the plant typically they're just
really they never allow your plants to
really reach maximum yield or maximum
progression because they just they
stress out the roots from day one um
what I see as far as primary control
mechanisms for that if if allowed would
be a batan guard or a Bavaria product
that's labeled for drenching tank mix
with an Aida and that's also labeled for
drenching and doing a full volume
substrate drench literally to to almost
leech basically to leech um in some C
some certain situations in States pyin
can be used and now and you would never
catch me recommending a pyoid for Aid
control on the ornamental side because
there just so much resistance to that
sort of chemistry but on the ornamental
on the a side of things we haven't used
pyu rins again and again and again on on
rud Aid so um there are certain states
that do allow like a pyoid drench and
that there's only a few pyoid products
that I'm aware of that actually have a
drench label so Panic would be an
example of one that that is I have seen
that be
effective yeah I've never really messed
with pyrin um I will say that I'm
excited for this granulated uh Bavaria
product from from bioer it's actually
something using right now in my garden
uh because it can be mixed into the
incorporated into the media and then you
get a slower release of Bavaria and and
the issue with the rud AIDS is I mean
that's a great suggestion with the
botanigard but I I I don't feel like the
spores the Bavaria spores are really
making it to the bottom of the container
and it's really those uh holes in the
bottom of the container where the water
seeps out that that's the pro it's same
with fungus snats like that's the real
problem location that there really isn't
a great solution for I feel like
um in a lot of cases so I I I think
incorporating to the media might be a
good option for really getting Bavaria
down in throughout the whole container
to help with the root AIDS but I I don't
know what are your thoughts on
that um well with fungus Nets we
typically see them in the top one one to
two inches of soil and so when I'm
talking to a grower who's new to
nematodes for example I don't tell them
to drench the entire media because
really the thri pupa and the fungus not
they're in that just top layer of soil
so it's just more of like just a quick
quick watering I don't want them to
waste chemical or product um but when it
comes to rids like you said they do
easily easily and that's how they
they'll use as a transport is when
someone's a heavy waterer or they're
leeching or whatever it may be they'll
flush out the bottom of container
between of the holes and then they'll
just work their way to another pot what
I do see some Growers and this I don't
want to harp on pyrethroids because it's
not very commonly used in in cannabis or
accepted in cannabis um but what grows
will do is they'll they'll for they'll
physically do that they'll they'll Lee
their pots to force the aid to want to
leave the exit holes and then they will
spray between the pots and this is
really I don't think this makes sense
for a large scale but for a smaller
operation I I can see that making sense
somewhat I never heard of that that's
interesting yeah well um I feel like
we've been talking for a little while
was there anything else that you want to
touch on before we uh sign off for this
one no no I I'm sorry I get really
excited um but uh yeah no I I really
appreciate the opportunity and um you
know if anyone ever wants to just reach
out to gjs Pro which is the technical
arm of Griffin um we're happy to help
you in any way we possibly can and um
you know we try to learn from you as
well I what I I've talked about all the
great things in my position and the
people I work with but I also get to
work with every different type of grower
um I'm I try to be an educator at heart
but honestly we continue learning
because the things we learn from Growers
so um if you just want even want to call
and pick our brain we're GNA just be
prepared because we're going to ask you
questions so we try to understand what
you're doing and what's working and
what's not so um please feel free to
reach
out yeah I love that that's really good
to know as a resource for for Growers
and just to kind of piggyback on that I
find that when people reach out to me
like a lot of times I I may not have the
answer but um just having that Network
within both cannabis and horiculture and
be able to reach out to people at these
other companies or universities you know
your network is is obviously very
valuable uh to be able to find an answer
is is really the the best thing because
then we everyone
learns yeah there's a lot there's a lot
of people smarter than me out there and
um I'm just uh I'm glad I get to to
interact with them on a daily basis
sometimes yeah are there any available
resources like you mentioned this that
you have these fogging charts are there
other things that are like like I could
go to the website right now and check
out or are they all things that you
guys yeah until the grower reaches out
or yeah how do how do I find out about
this yeah absolutely so um feel free to
go on to the Griffin greenhouse supplies
website we have a tab dedicated ggs Pro
um the technical team and we we talk as
we try to talk as much as we can as far
as public speaking events um all the
major trade shows as well as we're
writing as well well um so we put out
pretty much have a bulletin for every
major problem you might run into and
some of the more obscure ones as well so
um there are on loan articles I would
definitely start with the website but um
you can also just email us at ggs proot
techg Griffin mail.com um easiest way to
get in contact with
us cool well thank you again for your
time today I really appreciate it and I
hope we can stay in touch yeah
absolutely I really appreciate you
[Music]
that was George Grant and you are
listening to the Cannabis cultivation
and science podcast if you like the
podcast please leave us a rating and
review and give us a follow on Instagram
and YouTube and don't forget at kiss
Organics we have a wide range of
products we offer on our website ranging
from soils amendments beneficial insects
soil test analysis and Consulting thanks
for listening