[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discussed
the cutting edge of organic growing from
a science-based perspective and drawn
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge I'd
like to thank those of you who have
contributed to the patreon for the
podcast I really appreciate the support
you can check out the link on the
podcast page if you're interested I'll
go directly to wwk tree on Comm
backslash kay is organics my guest this
week is Reggie Gaudi no Reggie is the
chief science officer for steep hill
laboratories dr. Godinho oversees all
scientific research and development for
steep hill and is the driving force for
steep hills genetic research program
doctor Gao Dino directed a team of
researchers which led to the development
of Gen KITT the first cannabis DNA based
sex kit the research from dr. Gao Dino
has been peer reviewed and published
linked to important new discoveries in
the cannabis industry
dr. godina received his BS in molecular
biology and a PhD in molecular genetics
from the State University of New York at
Buffalo and he conducted four years of
postdoctoral research at Washington
University in st. Louis
studying transcriptional regulation of
our RNA Reggie was one of the first
african-american molecular biologists to
enter a ph.d program in the United
States in 1985 I really enjoyed my
conversation with Reggie and we ran out
of time to discuss steep hill and some
of his current work I plan on following
up with him for a second part to this
interview anyway on to the show
hey Reggie thanks for taking the time to
come on the show today I really
appreciate it thanks for having me Ted
appreciate being able to come on and
talk to your clients or rather your your
listeners yeah well I know we've already
started chatting prior to starting the
show here but I wanted to really dive in
talking a little bit about your
background and how you came into sort of
this role in the cannabis industry and
let listeners know sort of who you are
and what you're doing okay so I guess
I'll start by officially who I am I'm
Reggie Dino I'm now the president of
steep hill I've been there going on
almost five years I came in believe it
or not as a intellectual property
consultant which was at the time what I
was really doing for a living I had been
I have been for the last 22 years
in the intellectual property field going
from litigation to prosecution which
means that I started kind of prosecuting
biotech patents or sorry litigating
biotech patents
I was hired because of my scientific
background where there was early
technology in the in the biotech
industry was centered around certain
things like moving genes from one
organism to another that was what
Monsanto did big time and a number of
other early startup biotech outcome
companies and there's a technology that
requires that you kind of take a gene
and re-edit it and by that I mean
different organisms use different codons
for calling for an amino acid and by
that I mean certain amino acid let's say
alanine which is makes a lot of the
proteins that we have in our body there
are six different DNA triplets that can
code for an alanine any one of them will
bring that amino acid into the into the
protein at that spot but different
organisms use the codons with different
efficiency so sometimes when you try to
take a gene from one organism you put
another organism you get very little
expression even though it should
theoretically work and the way you can
get around that is by taking the codons
and optimizing the codon so that they
look more like the codons that you would
have in the recipient organism so in my
PhD work I had done that to build gene
expression systems to study what I was
trying to study in my PhD and it became
a big thing in early genetic
modification early GMO plants and that
was what Monsanto was you know best at
at the time and so my my I went from
basically being a scientist to being
more of a intellectual property
consultant for biotech and then I ended
up working at a number of law firms
while I was working at law firm play
ended up getting back into biotech
because I went in house at a company
called sequin elm which was a big
genomics company and they were the ones
that invented non-invasive pregnancy
testing that used the blood draw from my
mother to be able to give it a digital
karyotype of the the fetus and there was
a really you know big technology because
it helped kind of eliminate
amniocentesis which I don't know if
people know but can have a spontaneous
abortion rate of up to like one in 25%
so it was a big deal and and while I was
there I was still consulting for
portfolio consulting for IP and think
steep hill actually called me initially
to do a review of their intellectual
property or potential intellectual
property on their chemistry side and and
at the time they were that they had
produced the first near-infrared potency
device called the quanta can and so I
was reviewing their their science to see
whether or not they had anything that
was still patentable while I was doing
that I found that they had this treasure
trove of chemistry they had so much
chemical data because they had been
around since 2008 and I was floored
because when I asked the question hey
what do you guys doing all this data
this is I
you know what kind of research are using
or what kind of pants are you filing
based on this and they looked at me like
I had a third eye hey David
and so I was like well this is you know
this is where your IP lies and and I
said in on top of that you could be like
you know you know using this to trend
cannabis to identify markers and and and
so they actually offered me a job to do
that instead of being intellectual
property so and that's how I got its
seat belt I didn't hurt at the time that
the company does it without that I was
with that sequin elm in my opinion had
made some some really grievous errors in
handling their intellectual product
property portfolio and I saw that my job
was probably going to be diminished
there in the near future because of
those bad decisions so it was an
opportunity for me to leave and to go
into something really exciting I was
given the opportunity to come in and be
the director in lesser property for them
but also the director of R&amp;D and which
is kind of the dream job if you're a
scientist right so there is no more
powerful or better position than to be
the director of intellectual property as
a director of R&amp;D when you're a
scientist right so and so I jumped at
the chance and you know it's it's been a
really really beneficial kind of pairing
right so I got I got a bunch of data I
got there was already some very good
scientist at stevefell that were willing
to to come and do part-time work with me
cuz I started you know they wouldn't
give me them completely so they had to
do double duty they were punished to
actually for being good so they they had
their full-time job and then on weekends
or evenings they got to come in and do
extra work for me on the R&amp;D side we
came up with the gen kit which was the
first really successful sex test for
cannabis and the rest is history you
know we were able to do some really good
work and and I think that's what brings
me here is is trying to share some that
knowledge you know a lot of our data
that we that we publish all in fact
first of all all of our data is actually
academically oriented right so
so we we have a very deep desire to
share what we have learned and what we
learned with the industry right so
obviously we have to pay for R&amp;D and so
we build more core tests and stuff like
that that people can use to help
themselves breed now ultimately all of
our data is published in academic
journals and and and then on top of that
once we release data academically we put
it all for anybody to get to on OCP so
you know it we are all about sharing our
data with the industry and making
everybody better because of it and
helping people understand the power of
that science and what it can do for them
so what I wanted to ask you was these
genetic markers that you're talking
about essentially what you're saying is
the with using utilizing these markers a
grower with the help of a lab like
yourself is able to go back in then and
identify specific traits so there might
be a marker associated with a trait
relating to let's say resistance to mold
or mildew or yield or plant height is
that is that sort of correct in
describing what you're what you're
saying yes that's absolutely correct
so let's take it a step further so and
anything that you can observe in the
cannabis plant has or is tied to one or
more genes right so every observable
trait which we call a phenotype right
can be it has the potential I don't want
the candy but has a potential to be
controlled through a breeding program
okay now a plant height so let's take
you know if you look at the classical
definition of sativas and indicas right
there's the height the height difference
right so there are genes that are
responsible for internode lanes then you
know everything you know flowering time
you know trichome development how many
trichomes you get per per square
centimeter
all of those things have some genetic
basis now not all the time do you have a
legalize variation so what do I mean by
allelic variation allelic variation is
the difference between the two right so
if you look at a strain that typically
only makes 14 to 18 percent THC versus
other newer strains that now make
typically always 25 to 28 percent right
so that's allelic variation it's a
difference in the same gene that has a
measurable quantifiable difference right
so now if you can find that number or
that observation or that color
difference right those are all markers
that you can use to be to breed with now
the way you tie that back to the genes
in the DNA is through something called
genome-wide Association right so you now
you take that marker right and you take
the differences that you oh sorry that
you take that that allele that's
phenotype and then you take the
differences in the spectrum of that
thing that you're looking at and using
you know bioinformatics and statistics
and some other stuff when you get large
enough populations you can say ah look
more often than not if we if it looks
like this it has that DNA that DNA
sequence in this particular region if it
looks like that it has a different one
and now that's suddenly a genetic marker
right so you now assigned a function
right which is the either the the color
the the the amount of THC whatever it is
you that's the function and you've
assigned it to a nucleotide and so now
as long as you can file that nucleotide
which you can through a number of
different ways and they're you know
different ways of looking at DNA
sequencing qPCR you know you know
sometimes you can even look at it
through a non direct methodology right
so sometimes a function is is linked to
something you can see but not
necessarily it's not really directly
related so sometimes you get lucky and
that's
it's called a linkage disequilibrium and
so that means that more often than not
you would instead of a random
distribution you see that this thing
here always travels with that trait
right and so these are all tools that
the scientists can use to be able to
build a breeding program because now
when you get DNA from the plant you
don't have to wait for the plant to
exhibit that marker like when it's you
know flowered already or you know you
don't have to wait for weeks to be able
to see whether or not what the internal
length is really going to be right you
can say oh I know already because it has
these gene sequences that tell me
already clicked on the Association that
I can follow that now and so that's the
accelerated format and now that's my
genetic modification that's just that's
just good intelligent use of tools using
traditional breeding methodology right
so we haven't done anything to the plant
we're not doing any genetic modification
we're not we're not doing anything that
God wouldn't want us to do with the
plant right so but we're just doing it
in a more efficient more intelligent
manner right so and so that's the beauty
of what's called marker-assisted
breeding now here's this the dirty
secret that that if more people had
better understanding of true of true
agriculture every cannabis farmer for
decades has been building their own
mapping populations the most powerful
tool that you can use as a breeder and
not even realizing it right so everybody
who's been at it for a long time has a
strain that they've umbral added to self
they've picked the best fie nose they've
they've taken that one they've grown
that one they've allowed it to self that
you know and so what they've done is you
know traditional breeding they that you
know breeding for a specific you know
unique variation amongst the population
when they've done crosses between
different things they that cross is the
base for what we call a mapping
population you take two things that you
know you put them together and
and you look at the offspring from there
the different phenotypes and you
categorize them you grow them you you
you you you then do other things with
them well that's just the same as
crossing back crossing intercrossing
right and so every time you do something
like that and you have the controlled
observation you have built yourself a
mapping population that now if you have
the right amount of observational data
you can pick you can usually find a
measurable marker that after a couple of
generations of interbreeding if you can
find a trait you can usually do two or
three crosses and and identify the
marker you know pretty pretty well so
realistically people have been doing all
of the groundwork for their own
marker-assisted breeding populations all
they need now is to take what they
already have in terms of observation and
familial relation and then get some DNA
sequence behind it and they're done off
to the races so essentially the the gene
sequence II it just allows for a more
precise scientific tool and quantitative
analysis of what we're seeing already
the breeders have been doing visually
for years yes absolutely right so but
but again it's that visual observation
that forms the basis right so it's the
data the data always forms the basis for
the utility of the gene sequence gene
sequence at the end of the day is just
AG CT right we and it tells you nothing
even when you know what the gene does
right it really tells you nothing in
terms of breeding yes I know I have a
gene that makes you know THCA synthase
right well but then now I have 14
varieties of that same gene that all
slightly different sequences well but
they all make KC a synthase so what's
the difference right and so now by
taking that observational data and
overlaying it onto the the variation the
genes
sequence that's where we see the power
of genetics where we can say ah they all
make the same thing but that one makes
it ten percent more efficiently so
ultimately if you have that gene in
there instead you're going to end up
with ten percent more THC yeah that's a
you know an oversimplification but but
that's but that's basically what it is
right so so the gene sequence ultimately
is how you follow all the things that
you see and because you can follow it
without having to see it because it's
coded in the DNA you can now crack a
seed and at the first true leaf you can
tell yourself everything that you want
to know or need to know in terms of your
breeding program does it have the allele
I want yes keep it no throw it done move
on to the next one right so and so
that's it brings efficiency it brings
speed think about generational you know
propagation so you know we have would
typically you know until we're you know
ready the the plant flowers we really
don't know where we're going with the
breeding program you know I've got three
I got three fiy knows which one's gonna
be my best one when I cross this well
you know nurture plays a great amount of
that about in that you know and so we'll
talk to touching that a little bit
because because there's this nurtured
you know in nature you know genetics
versus environment right so those two
things have such a key interplay in
cannabis to a degree that is probably
not seen in many other plants if any
tell you the truth right so but now as
long as you have consistency in your
growing regime right so let's just let's
just throw that out there and then we'll
deal with that later as long as you have
consistency in your growing regime right
you can do the all the hard work without
ever seeing the outcome of the plant you
can pick the ones you want you can force
flower them and breed with them with the
known breeder pair right because you
have the DNA on that one you know get
some seed you know crack those seed and
do the same thing never seeing a flower
but
your traits for four or five generations
right and then finally getting to a spot
where this is the genetic combination
that I'm looking for now let me let me
grow these out and see what I got right
so so now you are you're not waiting
months to breed you're breeding in weeks
right and because of that you're getting
four or five generations and so now
suddenly inbreeding and black back
crossing looks like it doesn't every
other agricultural setting right it
doesn't have to be you only get two
crops a year because you know you got to
see what the flower looks like and
picked from the flower to get the next
generate no you don't have to as long as
we know what trait matches what what DNA
sequence all of this stuff becomes you
know wrap a generational cycling and
then you just look for what you want at
the end and now that is the way to
maximize profits maximize useful space
right it and and now if you think of the
palette of genes yes you mentioned
earlier you know powdery mildew and
other and other pest resistance those
are all things that we have by looking
at other agriculture we already know
that there are genetic markers for that
like powdery mildew in a rabbit Optus
and other in other plants it actually
tracks to trichome development there's a
mutation in trichomes in a rabbit
obstacle mildew well how does that work
in cannabis would that be good or bad
for us if suddenly our trichomes are
different where all the chemistry
happens so those are kind of things that
you we have to you know look at as we
tread down these pathways but but you
know agriculture is built on agriculture
we already know what genes do what in
general other than the cannabinoid
synthase ones because all these genes
exist to other plants we can look to
other plants and say hi in that terpene
gene if you make that change it makes
these terpenes if you make that change
to make those terpenes and we can go and
we can look for things like that because
we we have homology in the gene
sequences because mother nature doesn't
reinvent herself right she uses the same
stuff as much as possible and so if you
look at a chirping gene from basil you
know it will
a lot like terpene genes from cannabis
sure there are some differences but at
least now we've been able to use those
terpene genes from other organisms to
find all the terpene genes in cannabis
right so so all of this information ends
up making breeding and and you know just
even phenyl hunting much easier much
faster you know and and that's how we
need to be if you think about it because
in a very short while when things are
our legal big AG big tobacco big alcohol
they're all going to come knocking on
the door and though these are the tools
that those people use right they use
this kind of stuff so if we're not using
that kind of stuff when they get here we
will be in a much different situation
and we'll be in little bit and we will
have lost because we don't know how to
do this you bring up a lot of really
intriguing questions I've got a little
list here going but I wanted to touch on
this idea that you mentioned here in
terms of how how agriculture is already
utilizing technology and one of the
things that sparked my mind is I have an
edible nursery so we sell a wide variety
of vegetables and fruit trees and things
like that and when I am selecting for
plants for my region here in the Pacific
Northwest I'm looking at apples and
they'll have a list of traits that are
consistent across that apple variety so
I know that I'm getting scab resistance
when I'm getting this particular tree
and I know that I'm getting say a
certain flavor profile when I'm choosing
a Honey Crisp apple but I may have a
little less resistance to mold and
mildew so these are all things that we
can know very consistently and it's very
helpful data for a grower who wants to
grow out that plant now and I love that
we can eventually have this sort of
thing in cannabis - but my concern I
guess my question would be if I'm
approaching this from a growers
perspective
the two things that really stood out to
me is one what am I giving up to this
lab by sharing this data like my wife
for example did the 23andme
thing giving up you know essentially
finding out about her ancestry and
everything by giving up her genetic IP
and for me that was a that was a
non-starter at this point in time I was
like I'm not gonna pay a company to have
access to my you know own personal genes
at this point in time you know maybe
that'll change down the road but what is
a grower giving up when they give you
this data you mentioned the OCP for
people who don't know that stands for
the open cannabis project and we're
gonna be talking with them here soon as
well hopefully as well as candor I have
an interview coming up who's approaching
it from a slightly different perspective
but could you just touch a little bit on
on sort of what what that looks like
from a growers perspective approaching
this like if you're not a geneticist and
you are someone who's just been loving
this plant and passionately growing this
you know a couple phenotypes that you're
really proud of and you want to you want
to preserve how would you use this use
this sort of the science-based data so
wow you you've like opened up not one
but several cans of worms so you've
touched on things that relate to
intellectual property and and protecting
plants okay and and I think maybe you've
touched on a bunch of these things
without even realizing it because
they're so tied together so you know
let's start with the laboratory and
client relationship I think that's
that's that's as a as a the guy who's
doing this work right like you know XD
bill this is a very important thing and
so you know a lot of it has to do it
with integrity and upfront transparency
right so I tell everybody up front if
you come test for me I use your data and
you and you allow me to use your data as
I will to do trending metrics and
investigational you know kind of things
so that I can understand cannabis in
general that data is anonymized so these
are all things that are in the in my in
my intake contract right the data is
anonymized I never I never tried to
claim
or take control of because again it's
not mine and this is where people have
to understand the patting process if
somebody doesn't it doesn't invent
something they can't file a patent on it
so somebody comes to me with the strain
and tells me to test it even if I take
that data and I use it in a general and
a anonymized way to look at cannabis in
general and to try to trend things in
cannabis like you know Varon production
or you know CBD versus THC ratios know
something so that data by itself does
nothing in the larger group of data it's
very valuable because it allows trending
right so so in that respect putting one
data point into 10,000 data points means
absolutely nothing and it gives us no
power over that that piece of that plant
anyway right so now in return for that I
if I find that something is unique I let
that client know and say hey here's
something interesting you should
probably do more investigation because
we found this about your plant when we
looked at it versus everything else you
have something unique right so without
that ability to look at that we would
never have been able to find THC v we
were the first to report HCV right so
and that says that we did Doug Veron
Doug Ferran became a thing because we
went to Doug and said hey you don't you
may not know this but this is a really
special plant you should do something
with it and so that's and that's the
power of being able to use the clients
data to be able to trend but then giving
that client the information back say we
used your data we found there is
something special about yours here it is
go go down right so there has to be that
ability to do those things for anybody
to get any usefulness out of science in
general in the cannabis industry right
if everybody if everybody if nobody
wants us to do that kind of work then we
can't help them do better right so
unfortunately there's also you know a
whole integrity responsibility thing
right so anybody who would then try to
monopolize that information and then try
to do their own work you know to go
around is somebody who brought them data
you know I think is we're having a
different conversation we're not talking
about science now we're talking about
the integrity of an individual and their
philosophy and and I think you know one
one needs to be asked the question you
know what are you going to do with my
data right yeah I think that's a
perfectly valid question for anybody
going to a lab to ask and and that lab
should be transparent and it's answer
and I say I'm going to do research with
your data to be able to help you know
build markers so people can do
marker-assisted breeding right so you
know and and there's also you know
whether or not that person then would
would be interested in and and doing a
release of their data so if I have
actually asked clients said hey you know
using some of your data in conjunction
with everything else you know we have
noticed that you guys happen to have
something very unique you know we would
like to be able to publish on it you
know we would like to make you
co-authors with us because this is
you're fine so you know so that is
something that again you know we did all
the work we did all the investigation we
did the sequencing on our own dime right
so a lot of this work we've done on our
own dime because you know so that we
could build an offering right I want to
start at 23andme for for the cannabis
industry right so but to do that right
you know I have to have a base of
information like there was with you know
the human genome project right so there
was thousands of human genomes that that
were had to be sequence before 23andme
could start a 23andme you had to have a
reference genome so we're in the process
of building that reference genome as are
no other of other labs right to be able
to do exactly these kind of things which
will overall end up benefiting the
industry right so there's this
give-and-take and people have to be able
to buy in at their level if you want
your data to be included then you you
you approach the lab and say hey
like to work with you you know and then
back and then and you know and there are
ndas we don't share in the feel of
things so so anybody that I think Phil
deals with there's NDA is we don't tell
anybody else we don't show anybody else
their data their data is their data they
get to do whatever they want with their
data and then we put their data in an
anonymized form into our overall you
know kettle that gives us the stuff that
we do which we then do go and patent by
the way right so now after I have all
this data I now build tools
I build methods of of being able to
follow different genetic markers like
you know using HRM or you know or qPCR
or their deep DNA diagnostics it's like
the bracket 1 bracket 2 so I'm not
patenting the DNA sequence
I'm patenting a method to identify this
particular trait that we have gone
through and I tend and with all of the
other work that we've done been able to
pull out of the ether right because
again at the end of the day it's AG CT
and until you put chemical data in
conjunction with DNA data and you do
advanced biostatistics and
bioinformatics you have no answer right
so that's the invention that we put into
it right and so and and we share that
information by making it public now
everybody who would like to breed for
that trait can breed for it you know
using this tool and we help people build
their own unison and and this is where
it can go one step further where it then
becomes something that's very private
and doesn't go to the populace right so
now when somebody builds their old
mapping population because it's their
mapping population and it's only related
to the crosses they've made when we
define markers for them it is their
marker because unless somebody else has
built that same exact cross that
information won't be useful to anybody
else so there's there are different
levels so there's the what comes out
that is generally useful for people and
then there's the other stuff that will
only ever be useful to the person who
actually contracted for that work does
that make
I think so so in an effort of full
transparency you're a full for-profit
company you are you know this equipment
the science all of these salaries this
all costs a heck of a lot of money and
so what you're looking to do is collect
as much anonymous data as possible with
the goal of creating these markers and
then like you said once you have let's
just say in theory our marker for
powdery mildew resistance you've
discovered this genetic marker you could
then use and sell and patent that marker
as a way of generating money by saying
ok hey I can analyze your plant and tell
you right away if it's going to have
powdery mildew resistance because I've
I've established this this particular
proprietary marker is that is that
correct so so I cannot so I can't patent
the marker because the marker is a gene
which is a natural thing what I can
patent is a is a unique process of
identifying that gene and that alleles
on that gene right so what I do is I
build a very specific fluorescent tag
that identifies that allele right and I
say ok my patent is on a method of
identifying this allele using this
methodology and making this this
consulting or or making this you know
outcome call which is you know
recommending to use certain plants that
have that marker to in a breeding
program right so that's a very specific
thing that I can go after I cannot go
after the actual marker in the gene
because it's a naturally occurring thing
that occurs in the plant
unless of course I use gene editing and
make that make a change but then I would
have to show that that change did not
already exist in nature to be able to
claim that I made it and I could claim
that because that would be an artificial
DNA sequence at that point so so that's
where this conversation with tools like
CRISPR come into play then with gene
editing is that correct yes exactly and
that's where you get into
genetic modification right so now and
even that is a kind of gray area right
because in the old days GMO meant you
took a gene from one organism you put in
another organism you put a non
naturally-occurring gene and then orgasm
right now
genetic modification CRISPR you are
changing a naturally-occurring gene to a
form that either augments or fixes you
know mutations and so it is it really
technical at a-- fication you know I'd
say at this point it's it's out of
regular regular breeding now you're
actually manipulating with DNA and so
that is genetic modification but it's a
different genetic modification then we
we originally thought of when back in
the day when then clean CRISPR didn't
exist right so but yes it's a completely
different set of tools one is an
identification set that allows you to
make intelligent breeding choices but
you still use traditional breeding
methodology the other one allows you to
go in and say okay I'm gonna do this
differently I'm gonna go in I'm going to
rewrite the entire code so that it's
only what I want I'm going to do a
single a single pass
you know stabilization which is
something called half-half lloyd haploid
or double haploid kind of mating and
that's it works in some plants
apparently it may or may not work in
cannabis I've heard different reports
but it allows you to go from a unique or
a phenotype to a truly stabilized strain
in not what we not what we call
stabilized but truly stabilized as in
you know it will only ever produce one
set of germ plasm you know overnight
basically and in in in one double
haploid mating you get you go to
complete stability and in one one-shot
so which is a tremendously useful tool
and we can get it to work in cannabis
because that has been the traditional
drawback of in the cannabis industry
anyway right so we we kind of exist in
the periphery of agriculture and
cannabis believe it or not right so when
we when we talk about a hybrid and
that's one hybrid in cannabis we're
actually using a very bastardized form
of what it is done in real agriculture
and real agriculture and f1 hybrid comes
from taking a stabilized father and a
stabilized mother right and then making
that cross from two stabilized parents
well that almost never happens in
cannabis right so we're breeding we're
breeding hybrids with HUD with other
hybrids that have no characterization
and then so now we really have no clue
of the mess that we've made in the
cannabis industry right but we do not
really do traditional agriculture as as
you would come from big AG right so so
what we cannot do is we cannot become a
seed company based industry until we get
to that point where we have the ability
to say parent a when bred with a parent
B will only give you this set of
outcomes right now we can talk about
stabilizing through breeding stabilized
means that when you breathe when you
sell cross a stable I truly stabilized
strain you'll get four or fewer
phenotypes back right and a true
breeding strain means that you know when
you when you do cross a and cross B you
will only ever get offspring you know C
there is no possibility because they are
so stabilized now that double haploid
thing allows us to go to that true
stabilized in one fell swoop right which
is awesome if we can get it to work in
the industry and and that will allow us
to now do something that would would
otherwise take us a long time and that's
build a a seed population now where we
can become a seed based industry and so
where we can now take a bag of seed
throw it out in the field and everything
we get back we'll look
almost identical right that's where we
have to be to be able to transcend this
clone based industry we will not exist
as a clone based industry it is not
possible to scale that right even with
tissue culture clone based industries
would be hugely expensive to the point
where almost being prohibitively so ok
and the you know and and that's why big
AG exists as a seed based economy right
so and cannabis at some point will need
to get there for us for scalability
right now there will always be the need
for these these you know craft craft
breeders the ones that are coming out
with new varieties and then taking the
time to breathe and stabilize right so
there's there's still this underlying
breeding cultivation innovation portion
that we'll have to then adopt some of
these techniques to be able to produce
in a in a way that will allow us to
maintain our relevance in this industry
right again this is the backdrop of this
is Monsanto and down all these big AG
and Altria and all these guys they know
how to do big AG they do it better than
us and if they get us there first
they will cut us out of this industry
right having done research in a monsanto
building in Saint Charles Missouri in my
post-op let me tell you it's a scary
thought to see what we do and think of
as agriculture and what they do and what
they think of as agriculture you bring
up a lot of really good points and one
of the some of the things that I'm
struggling with here with this is one as
we become more stable you talk about a
stabilized male or a stabilized female
or you know stabilized seed how much
genetic diversity are we potentially
risking on losing that we don't know the
medical benefits of still I know like
you said you just discovered THC v
well how likely would that plan have
survived in a big AG scenario and how
much of a the medical community are we
potentially doing a disservice to
by moving too rapidly towards I guess
that that direction so those are awesome
questions let me tell you so let me
answer by it by saying we already are
facing some of that because we don't we
already don't know what we've lost so a
paper was recently published that showed
that there are certain subspecies of CBD
lineage compounds that so by that I mean
minor cannabinoids that come off of the
CBD synthase tree that we do not see in
the THC side and that is most likely
because of the intense breeding form or
THC has lost some of the minor
cannabinoid genes along the way right so
we've already done that because of the
way we have gone about breeding in the
cannabis industry there's no reason why
we wouldn't see the same minor
cannabinoids across the board in both
CBD and THC because we see some of the
same minor cannabinoids already like we
see Varun's on both the CBD and THC side
we see or seal on both the TAC and CV
so that means that there was a mimicry
or symmetry in the two trees and some of
that has been lost because we have not
used chemistry and or science to do our
breeding we've used the seat of our
pants and I think I said this earlier in
the talk where you know you know when
when the only metric is did I get higher
than before you know there's only
there's only one way to look at it right
so and so you have no idea what has been
lost along the way already so the other
part of that would be so yeah again it
would have to be an intelligent
science-based you know project where you
you use chemistry to identify the
different classes and make sure that in
these in these breeding programs these
classes weren't lost and then you you
and and establish libraries where you
can go back to land races and other
things like
and then try to keep breeding back going
back far enough where before the loss of
these things right so as long as you
have a stable land race or you know
ancient stock population right consider
it like the heirloom the guys who still
breed heirloom tomatoes right so you
know as long as you have that part of
the community still there or a
repository for that you'll never really
lose it as long as it is maintained and
it is what you know at least you know
you do see increases and you and you and
and that gets back to traditional
agriculture as well at some point you
have to back cross to an original parent
because you do tend to lose things or
you do tend to lose resistances and that
kind of stuff right so you always mean
to you know you always give it a booster
shot of original DNA kind of thing right
and to kind of bring that the vigor back
up because now you've created a hybrid
again but you created a hybrid going
back to the one of the original parents
so you're keeping it all in the family
but getting some of that hybrid vigor
back by going to an older to an older
you know ancestor right so so as you
know I mean so agriculture has learned a
lot on itself I think you know over the
evolution of Agriculture as we know it
right I think we've seen some of these
things and and if you look at white
peaches inside the United States right
so that that industry almost died for
exactly that reason everything became so
interbred you know and they lost the
original stock that white peaches or I
think there are more white peaches grown
outside of the United States than there
are in United States and in the United
States was you know I believe is where
white peaches originated right so you
know so you know so we hopefully have
learned enough I'm somewhat making an
assumption you know but I think you know
as long as we maintain ancestral
populations we won't have to worry about
the loss of diversity you know and and
now you know it it also becomes
important for us to begin to educate
to force people in the government to
allow more medical research without
without understanding what the targets
are right we have no reason to move
forward right there is no reason to do
advanced medical Rita or chemical
analysis if you know we're going to be
told that you know well Big Pharma's
taking it away or you know or it'll
never be a medicine because well you
know then we might oh just keep it
recreational and and then we should
focus on things like terpene and
experience right but um but you know we
already know that there's medicinal
benefit so now we have to have science
catch-up right it cannot be the steep
hill or the Philo's or the medicinal
genomic think about it the entire
industry has been has been supported by
bootstrapping it right the reason why I
have to patent and and build tests and
charge money for it is because I can't
get federal grants to do the basic
research that was done in the human
genome project or with Brassica oleracea
which is you know and other oil rape
seeds and broccoli and cauliflower and
all those kind of things right so
they've done genome sequencing they've
done terpene profile they know all of
the the important chemicals that come
out of different plants except for
cannabis and so without that impetus for
federal federally funded research right
we will always be behind the 8-ball and
it's going to be really difficult for us
to to understand this plant in its
entirety rapidly right and I think at
this point that's what we only we as an
industry to come together and kind of
find a way to to you know put the final
nail in the prohibition coffin right
make this let's blow the lid off of it
and get money into it because you know
there are so many avenues right so there
is not a single part of the of the
cannabis plant and now when I say
cannabis I mean hemp and or you know
recreational varieties the roots have
their own set of compounds we find
terpenes and other cannabinoids that are
only expressed in the roots right there
you know and if you go back and look in
the history of cannabis
there are you know there are Shama
shamanic or you know medicine man kind
of stuff where they do make poulos's of
the roots of cannabis or or a
combination of the leaves in the roots
right so because they understood then
that there were medicines that came out
of different part of the plans right I
know in this kitchen said the genetics
right so why is the genic so important
well you know we can now start to breed
very specific cannabis plants for very
specific maladies if we have the
corresponding medical research the kind
of soap that's going on would cancer
cell line work in Israel that kind of
stuff right so you know and then after
taking flower and or whatever else in
extracting now we have fiber and even if
we don't have fiber we have pulp to make
chem creat or or some of the best best
paper in the world right so there is so
much there are so much that can be done
with this plant right and to not be able
to exploit every avenue of this planet
including high-tech right at one point
you know we there was a big push on
graphene as a superconductor well guess
what graphene died when they found that
the best graphing came from hemp like
four or five years ago a paper came out
that said there's the graphene from hemp
is unparalleled and so and so now you
know it's funny you don't hear about
graphing anymore so so they're they're
they're there's a lot of work to be done
right and and the chemistry and the
genetics is just part of it because you
know in order to exploit it in order to
get optimization for growing and this is
where I had said I was going to throw
something out there before and get back
to it but now if you take the same
genetics and you grow at ten different
ways you're going to get a bunch of
different answers right so there's
enough plasticity in the genome of the
plant that you already see right you
already see that you have to have
nurture being very well controlled to
get a to get the semblance of a
consistent product on the outbound
flower right if you in two different
rooms change temperature change you
you're going to end up with different
terpenes in this even though they had
the same genetic base so now that that
leads to a whole other level of stuff
which is more science based
investigation to optimize rights and so
that we can get consistency we can start
to look like a real medical industry if
we do it the right way yeah that's
that's great I was hoping you would
touch on that because I just did an
interview with Jeremy plum recently and
that was something that he mentioned in
as a goal of him and his company over at
proof and so essentially when you're
getting a genetic marker establishing a
gender marker genetic marker what you're
looking at is a range because like you
said the chemo type expression can vary
across these different environments so
you're just looking for a marker that is
most likely to create a certain outcome
is that right yeah so it's about
potentials right so at the end of the
day you know we have we might have an
allele that then you know says oh this
is gonna make you know it's always going
to be I'm a higher end of production of
THC right but you know but that higher
end is a relative thing right so if you
take plant a implant B with different
genetics and plant B is the high
producer yeah it will be higher than
plant a but if you grow it the wrong way
it'll be higher than plant a but it'll
still not hitting this full potential
right so so ultimately genetics is about
identifying potential right and the
nurture is a big part of it so there has
to be you know an understanding of that
interplay so we can identify which
alleles for each gene gives you the best
potential now we have to back it up with
optimization of that growing potential
that's a really good explanation I
appreciate that
so changing direction a little bit here
you've talked about you've talked about
science you talked about Monsanto big
egg where this industry is headed and I
don't think there's an answer to this
it's a big ethical dilemma but for me
personally you know I'm an organic guy I
struggle with a lot of what's going on
right now and
egg already but I see tools like CRISPR
and I feel like it's an avalanche I I
know they're going to be used I mean
we've already seen it be used in a you
know human female in China illegally and
I know it's gonna happen with cannabis
at some point down the road it's
unavoidable it already did so tweed has
a patent that they submitted on a
genetic app knockout of THC that was
made using CRISPR the patent ready been
filed so it's already been done cannabis
wow I didn't know that yeah so how do
how does someone with like say my values
or my background around genetics and
genetic modification how do how do we
approach an industry like this and still
say relevant or is it even possible to
stay relevant with what science is doing
well so again there there are there are
different levels of genetics right so
you know not all genetics ends up at
CRISPR right so a lot of the tools that
you know that I'm talking about you know
you you you use them to screen your
seeds right and then and then after you
find the population you want to work
with and everything else is the old way
look wait the way that you're saying the
organic way right so I don't you know I
think it's a level of comfort and a
level of understanding and I think I
know this gets back to the you know
understanding the science talking to the
labs and and and trusting the people
right so at the end of the day we're
we're really just people right so we
decide we're geeks and whites in white
coats right but you know we love the
plant - that's why we're doing the
research and so you know not everybody
is out there to steal somebody else's
thing right so and and and again a
better understanding of the patent world
would help as well so so so as long as
you have documented evidence that you
created this thing and you went to
somebody to ask for genetic sequence
right as long as you have that
interaction you can prove that they
didn't do it and at that point so they
can't patent it
even if they try to patent it you can
beat it so so that there's that level of
understanding because also to the level
of understanding that you know you know
good science helps make better better
plants it doesn't have to be taken to
the I'm trying to use CRISPR and gene
edit and it doesn't have to be taken to
the level of you know you know I want to
put some other gene in cannabis to make
it you know I want to put the psilocybin
gene in cannabis right so I'm sure I
believe it I'm sure somebody's out there
trying to do it I'm sure you know but
but um you know so so it there are
different levels of genetics right and I
and I think that's an important
distinction in industry because you know
it allows people to buy in at the level
that they want and and that means that
you know it's possible to use tools to
become a better breeder to increase your
your generation time to be able to
improve you know your Fino hunting right
to be able to keep good notes and say ah
now I have a genetic lineage I know
these guys do these things I have
something that I can follow that trait
and now you know it also allows you to
handle larger larger amounts of projects
you know one of the things that that
we've been told a lot is it's tough to
work to do because the pheno Hutton gets
so large well now you can manage ten
different crosses if you're only dealing
with a few things because you can screen
for the right answer right so you know
but again it's you're plugging in
science on top of traditional breeding
and growth right you know we didn't even
touch on tissue culture but so where
this tissue culture fortune fit end is
tissue culture to biotech for the
industry I see a lot of people talking
about that so but tissue culture is like
the gateway drug for genetic
modification believe it or not right so
you have to have tissue culture to do
genetic modification so you know so
where do you draw the line and I think
that's an important distinction and I
think the the industry really needs to
understand the what is available
what the things do and how they can be
used so that they can be comfortable
with what inevitably has to happen or we
will be sitting on the side watching
Monsanto and those guys do it because
they use all of this and on top of that
they probably will use CRISPR - yes so
essentially not all science is bad we
need to understand that science in order
to make the right decisions in how we
move forward as an industry and realize
that there are people that will come
into this industry from big AG to have
no problems utilizing whatever tool is
available to allow them to make money
and be profitable right and I would just
add so you've kind of created these
levels so level one would be hey this is
an analytical tool that you're giving us
it's like a microscope or a shovel or
fertilizer it's just another way to make
a decision about your plant in your in
your environment and that's sort of what
you guys are doing right now it's steep
hill it sounds like in terms of this
data collection and then if we go to the
next level we could talk about you know
something like CRISPR where we're not
taking frog DNA or psilocybin II said
and putting it into cannabis but we're
you know we're making changes within the
DNA code itself and that's something
that I don't know quite how I feel on I
have a lot of feelings and emotions on
it but I haven't sorted them out yet but
then I guess the last level would be
what you're talking about we're
inserting entirely foreign DNA into the
plant and that to me doesn't doesn't
feel right I don't know if that'll ever
quite feel good but I realize that it's
still gonna happen someone's gonna do it
right like I said I'm sure somebody's
thinking about it right so but but but
but I went to weigh in too because I
feel like you so I'm a traditional
flower guy dude I'm not a big favor I
mean I Drive vapor I'm not a big you
know oil guy I'm not a big animal guy
you know and so I'm and as a sign so I'm
traditionally pretty much a purist as
well as a traditionalist right so so I
believe that the tools the first level
is acceptable right I in my opinion do
not think we need CRISPR in the industry
I think we can accomplish everything
that we can we want including knockouts
without CRISPR right so will it make it
faster absolutely
but I also know that CRISPR isn't
unproven science and there are papers
out there that suggestion to use CRISPR
you make mistakes elsewhere right and
I'm completely and I'm completely you
know well I mean I don't want to say I'm
completely against but but I would I
would say that I weigh in kind of group
to it with group three as well
I don't think that's necessary I don't I
do not think that we need to be taking
other genes from other organisms and
putting them in cannabis maybe there
will become some gene that and the with
when added to cannabis makes cannabis
like this one or drug in that a case
like that maybe maybe alright but but
the you know that would have to be some
hugely you know you know beneficial
thing you know that we find right so but
again you know there's nothing wrong
with using a little advanced science to
augment traditional breeding methodology
so unfortunately we had to end our
interview a bit abruptly due to other
time commitments I wanted to get more
information from Reggie regarding the
process of how a grower can begin
testing their plants if they were
interested as in what's required how
long it takes how much it costs and
learn a little bit more about steep hill
I plan on following up with a second
part to this episode in the near future
but that was Reggie Gaudi know and
you're listening to the cannabis
cultivation and science podcast I'd like
to thank everyone who has donated to the
patreon account I really appreciate the
support of the podcast you can check
that out at patreon.com backslash k is
organics and don't forget to check out
my website where i put up a ton of
information and also offer a wide
variety of organic soil amendments soils
and other gardening products at WWE is
organics calm thanks for listening
you
[Music]