[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge my guest this week is Chris
Castle Chris is the co-founder and CEO
of Floren flame out of California
currently the largest vertical indoor
living soil cannabis farm Chris is a Bay
area native who's been cultivating
cannabis for 17 years with the last six
solely in indoor living soil now on to
the
show hey Chris great to have you on the
show thanks for coming on we met uh
years ago actually at photo X in in a
fluence conference I don't know if you
remember way back in the day was that
Chicago or
Texas it was in Texas yeah I think I do
and then I kind of uh lost touch and
then reconnected here in the last couple
years so at at the soil Summit yeah no
it was uh it was great to reconnect and
um we've also been working with you guys
for a little bit now too so uh yeah man
I I it's uh it's it's fun to work with
you guys and it's been a great
relationship uh that we've been building
so far so
yeah well Chris you built this company
uh Flor and Flame which is a cultivation
facility in California can you talk a
little bit about a little bit about
yourself and then a little bit about
Flor and Flame sure um so I'm a Bia
native uh born and raised how'd you get
into cultivation yeah uh let's start
real quick there so how I got into
cultivation uh I was I think I was 18 or
19 um living on my own uh I got kicked
out of the house for smoking
weed when I was 16 so uh yeah started
growing when I was like
1819 um and then had a break for a while
uh got back into
cultivation when I was 24 25 working for
other people and then uh started doing
my own thing again with Flor and Flame
with uh within the last seven years
now so what would you started floor and
Flame really from the ground up um from
from nothing what was your vision going
in to this you know project um so I was
I was bartending at the time um this was
like
2016 and I knew you know cannabis was
going legal uh in California I wanted to
take a bet on myself and um I pitched an
idea to do a small license grow in
Richmond or Oakland like you know a 20
or 50 lighter or something something
very modest um to an investor I knew
that we wanted to do soil uh soil uh
style cultivation because I knew that
was going to lead to better quality
product just from personal
experience um I didn't know anything
about living soil at the time or any of
these terms um but yeah so we we p i
pitch this idea to a real estate uh
investor and broker and he's a good
friend and Mentor as well and um he had
the vision to want
to uh take this project to the next
level really so
over um the course of you know I don't
know 6 months or so we were looking at
different properties for sale uh we came
across this building in Oakland that was
on the outside of the green zone um as
soon as uh Peter the owner uh as soon as
he saw the building he was like we're
going to buy it uh he he had this vision
of his head in his head to uh do this
this huge buildout that's just kind of
how he thinks um and I remember over the
course uh of the development of the
project where I went to him and I was
like are you sure you want to do this
because like the buildout just kept
getting bigger and bigger um and that's
just the way he thought and he wanted to
stick with it and do it he found it
really exciting and challenging um I
don't think he anticipated what a
challenge it would be especially post
construction which I always told him I'm
like the real work is going to begin
when we're actually have plants in the
building like yeah it's a lot of work
with research and development and
Architectural in the construction phase
and startup but I'm like yeah the real
work begins when you when you get plants
in the building but um yeah and then the
the name Florin flame that was uh
founded by uh my fiance she she kind of
came up with the name when we were
brainstorming and the name was uh
conceptualized in
2017 and um we started off with uh
a very
small um we called it like our our trap
lab essentially but it was
this illicit uh facility that we set up
where we had um where we were testing
different
LEDs and
k&amp;f and uh living soil and learning all
these different terms and taking courses
and stuff uh but that's really kind of
where we cut our teeth and and figured
out how we were going to scale up what
we were doing to what you see now with
400 plus lights and I think like 8,500
Square ft in our uh state-of-the-art
facility yeah and I want to ask you some
questions about that but I just want to
let listeners know um we are going to be
talking about this from a commercial
perspective here at the beginning but I
do plan on uh getting some information
from Chris about how he would approach
hom grows too because I know there's a
lot of people that listen that are not
commercial cultivators and I want to
make sure the information applies to
everybody so uh if you can stick around
through the commercial stuff and the
vertical uh talk that we're going to do
about uh grow in vertical then we'll get
back into the you know all all
applicable cultivation information that
really goes whether you you have five
plants or 5,000 so
uh just want to throw that out there but
let's talk a little bit more about what
you're calling this trap room or trap
facility at first um how big was it how
many lights what were some of the
lessons that you learned in there
because you just kind of threw out a
bunch of terms of things that you tried
out like k&amp;f and living soils what what
were your experiences yeah so that was
really interesting so it was it was
about we had six lights three 4X by8
beds um two of the 4x8 were initially
really shallow so like maybe four 5 in
of soil so not a lot of soil depth and
uh this was a uh gas station property
that we we modified to uh to this to
build out this grow essentially for us
to uh figure out what we were going to
do um so over the course of 3 years um
we were working on and when I say we it
was me and my colleague Alex who still
works with us at Flor and Flame and I
worked with Alex at another grow you
know 10 plus years ago so I've known him
for a long time it was really him and I
that developed our our Sops if you will
so uh we actually built our own soil mix
initially um that was a good learning
experience um and then uh I don't even
remember where we first heard about
k&amp;f um initially but I remember we took
an in inperson like crash course we
drove up to you know somewhere in humbl
up in AR near Arcada and uh this guy a
World's Last Hope was his Instagram
handle and he was one of the I know so
he was one of the few people um you know
basically talking about knf and ferments
and all this and I remember going to the
class and he was passing around the fpj
and having people drink it and you know
it was just fascinating at the yeah it
was I didn't wow I haven't heard that I
didn't drink it but um uh you know it's
like a kombucha or something but um sure
sure or you know semi quasi but um yeah
it was just fascinating learning or
hearing all these different terms and
seeing how there was different uh
methodology of living soil if you will
um or soiless media indoors and um so we
took that crash course I even bought um
you know a Cho's book and me and Alex we
made all these ferments and did all
these recipes and we applied them at our
our little lab that we had and fantastic
results I mean just
unbelievable um Tricom coverage
and beautiful structured flower and
flavorful and the feedback that we were
getting from people on that first run
was just unbelievable it was like oh
okay we're we're like really on to
something with this but it had its
challenges too indoors and because I had
so little experience with it but um we
saw that it increased pest pressure
indoors um was causing other issues and
we were concerned with with um using
those methods in a licensed uh uh Market
where we're going to have to go through
lab testing so we were worried about
microbials or other failures and you
know keep in mind this was like
um and we see people in today's market
using k&amp;f like Moon Valley that are able
to pass testing so I think we've learned
a lot since then um but yeah we we moved
away from
k&amp;f um and the reason we we pivoted was
uh you know concern for testing but also
I went to a soil conference down in
Santa Barbara and heard Steve kwell
speak and I think this was like 2017 or
18 and uh was completely blown away by
what he was doing indoors in a license
Market uh with living soil I was it was
just unheard of and um yeah I I could
relate to him and his story and I
introduced myself and kind of helped me
along the way and then with that timing
I was able to take a um a soil food web
course with Dr Ingam she was uh she had
her last in-person course that she
taught um at this ashram in Castro
Valley it was a week long where we uh
yeah it was just a crash course of of
you know her talking every day for 8
hours we're building compost piles we're
using a
microscope and uh that was another like
just huge eye openening experience for
me too and and uh we use a lot of those
methods but um indoors it's different
you know and uh I use a microscope but
maybe not to the extent that some other
soil food web enthusiastics enthusiastic
uh use because I don't think it's it's
quite that important I think you've
you've mentioned that too like it's not
a NE necessity to uh to use a microscope
to do living soil
indoors yeah I mean I have my microscope
literally right next to me here I'm
looking at it uh but I don't use it in
most cases for making any actionable
decisions in terms of my soil or
fertility management but I I think I've
shared my opinion on here already about
that um I do want to just say that I I
Steve has been such a wonderful
representative and voice for the living
Soul Community um he's really done an
amazing job of of straddling you know
this the differences between folks that
are in the so food web or k&amp;f or soil
testing uh he's been so open-minded and
accepting and um just a really great
person to to really show what what the
potential of this methodology really is
is so I'm I'm honored to consider him a
colleague and friend and and know him
and have seen his property like his farm
is beautiful um so yeah shout out to
Steve for just really doing a great
job and just the person that he is he's
a fantastic person and friend and yeah I
definitely feel lucky to to know him and
uh yeah what it's it's a
huge Testament as far as how big of an
influence he is to the living soul
Community just based off of how good of
a person he is and how open-minded he
is yeah and that's the thing that him
and I have talked about like he may not
agree with everything I say but he says
he'll listen to it because if he can't
come up with a good argument against why
I might be saying something then he's
probably going to try it out or he's
probably going to adapt it you know and
or adopt it so same the same thing for
me like I don't necessarily agree with
all of the things that he does uh in his
facility some of them to me seem like an
IPM risk and we've talked about this uh
actually on the podcast even uh but that
being said like he pulls it off very
successfully and he's very thoughtful
about how he does it so he's not just uh
you know scattering cover crops and he's
not just um you know doing the things
that he does without putting a lot of
thought into why he does them and I
think that's the the most important part
of all of it so definitely yeah well
let's let's get back into your uh
buildout here so you had a very uh tall
building that kind of it's if if I'm
remembering correctly sort of forced you
into going more vertical and and doing
uh a tiered grow or vertical grow can
you talk a little bit about that process
yeah so I I remember uh when we started
the like architectural rough
architectural phase of the project um we
were just trying to so so people can
picture we bought this building the
property is 50 feet wide by I think 110
ft long uh big open inside uh 28 ft tall
um inside so we were just trying to
figure out how to design the facility
and fit all the different you know
processes that we need to fit within
that space like you know drying uh
trimming uh curing just everything
um and
initially I remember we were we were
just trying to fill how much how many
how much flower space could we fit in
this in this space That's how little we
knew we were just trying to fill it out
with with just
flowering um and lights flowering rooms
and lights
um and then we figured out we needed to
build up to fit just everything we
needed to do from Veg uh to curine so
with that um I remember I we came across
a uh a bad advisor um but not all it was
not all bad but um he was familiar with
vertical
farming uh through a farm actually out
in Nevada as well called The Grove I
don't know if you've heard of them but
but they were a
two-tiered um uh they were growing in
soil and auto pots but they were a
two-tiered LED grow in outside of Las
Vegas or in Las Vegas so uh he advised
us to look into vertical
farming um we eventually got rid of that
advisor I was introduced to Michael
Williamson uh I think he works he's
worth pip now um but he he cut his teeth
in the industry doing
um managing big grows like big outdoor
grows as well as vertical farms and
helping people set up their facilities
so I was introduced to him through
fluence and he really helped us out with
the facility uh design and layout um cuz
I just I've never managed a facility
that big we wanted to make sure that we
were going to get the dry room sizes
right uh the veg room the mother space
all that um the equipment selection y um
so he was huge in helping us develop
those vertical farming Sops and just
helping us uh wrapping our head around
vertical farming so really uh we came
across or we needed to do vertical
farming just purely out of necessity of
being in a urban dens environment and we
could only build up and we had to fit
everything that we needed to do so it's
purely out of
necessity
yeah and I think you brought up a good
point in terms of facility design
there's a lot of other aspects that need
to come into play and we haven't even
talked about like HVAC and and
electrical and things like that but just
even like I I know with your facility
having places to Stage
material uh was in something that you
had to consider I always like a facility
to have a quarantine and or R&amp;D space
because at some point in time if you're
bringing in new genetics you don't want
to bring them directly into the facility
it'd be nice to have a space where you
can grow them for a month or two and
make sure they're truly clean that's
separate from everything else before
they actually go into your production
portion of your facility um any sort of
before we get into the vertical aspect
what what do you feel like you guys
really nailed with this buildout um in
terms of considerations and what things
do you wish you know in retrospect You'
done differently uh well I think overall
all uh because it's a purpose you know
groundup uh facility it's it's truly
state-of-the-art and one of one of a
kind um so I think there's a lot of
things we did do right I think HVAC
equipment selection our environmental
controls and
sensors um and just the layout and
design overall um cuz it it it's working
um as far as things that can you can you
touch on that really quick like uh what
brands you're using even for HVAC and
and some of the things there that were
really you know because you are
stateoftheart like can you describe some
of the things that you guys have in your
facility that you know most facilities
may not have or even be aware of yeah so
for HVAC equipment we went with a
company called cultiva um I can't
remember who's their main manufacturer
could be train or something but these
are you know specifically designed
packaged units uh that are meant to De
DEH ify first and then cool second um so
we have I think well over 200 tons of AC
just on our roof um and then our
environmental control system so we use
all industrial grade sensors um and then
the whole system was custom designed
with myself and David uh luou he was
formerly of grow remote so grow remote
uh is the company he David doesn't work
with them anymore just because uh
they've had to shrink their staff and
stuff but um yeah we we did a custom
custom catered built design with the
environmental control system so is me
and David working on every aspect of
that from water
irrigation um you know our reverse
osmosis condensate reclaim uh what types
of sensors placement of sensors um yeah
just basic basically everything from
start to finish um I would say yeah our
equipment and then the environment our
environmental control system are like
the two main things that make us uh
stand out from other
facilities I remember in your talk there
was something related to airf flow that
you wished you had done a little bit
differently in at least one of the rooms
uh could
you go into that really quickly yeah so
uh you know five five six years ago we
just didn't know what we know now in
terms of vertical farming and
HVAC airflow room design so in our
design we have the supplies at the top
of the room and we have one one return
per room uh kind of on the on um ground
level tucked away in one of the corners
well now that we we've learned a lot I
ideally you want
the um the supplies on the ground on one
end of the room on uh floor level and
then on the opposite end of the room
towards the top of the room is where you
want your returns so you're able to pull
that cool cool air completely through uh
your canopy and then as far as inner
canopy Air Flow Design um we've tried
duck socks and oversized you know fans
that are pushing large CFM but even in a
40 foot uh row which is the length of
our rows in most of our rooms it's still
not enough so um ideally you would want
to be running fans from either staggered
on opposite ends of the room or you
would want them in the same row facing
each other because you're not going to
have enough cfms to push that entire 40
ft no matter what you think with the
duck sock it just it doesn't work so we
actually just went back to oscillating
fans for the inner canopy air flow cuz
that just works better um that could be
the space of our um tear it could be the
fact that uh we're doing living soil in
these beds and how much you know
moisture uh that's perspiring into the
air um could be a a number of different
things but we found that um our air flow
and humidity is lower obviously on the
top tier but it's easier to control than
the inner canopy so it's really hard to
achieve um inner canopy airf flow
without uh just the right equipment or
design yeah in my uh homow I'm doing a a
poor man's version of uh duck socks
essentially because you can't get them
you have to have a certain commercial
scale to make it even worthwhile you're
not buying 10 feet of them for example
yeah or whatever so I used um Greenhouse
convection tubing that had prepunched
holes in it and hooked that up to a fan
and that's I I've been pretty happy with
that um in terms of the air flow that
I'm getting um so that's been kind of a
fun thing if people want to check it out
I've put it up on Instagram and I'll
I'll be starting another cycle here now
that I'm home from the soil Summit so um
yeah that's that's really interesting I
appreciate you sharing that
um other than the HVAC is there anything
that you would have done differently in
terms of the build
itself yeah I I think we would have
gotten um well one also reheat uh we
should have gotten reheat in the HVAC I
think that makes a big difference in
preventing temperature swings during the
lights off period um I would have gotten
better drain placement as as well in the
rooms I think that would have helped
more
um that's pretty much it I'm pretty
happy with their buildout and design but
those those are like the few things that
we would have done
differently what where is your current
drains in in the rooms and why where
would you move them to I I actually
don't know so yeah I I don't know that
about your so we have and this is from
part partly push back from the owner too
you know it's it's a tough balance with
a big project
um getting your needs across and then
also making that argument with the owner
or contractor so he was kind of against
uh getting any floor drains of any kind
in the room but we just have small uh
Corner drains maybe one or two in each
of the flower rooms but I would have
done a um I can't remember the the name
the style of the drain but I would have
got like more of a continuous run in the
front of the room so you have a bigger
drain to like clean your floors and
stuff that also has its challenges
because you have to keep that drain
constantly clean um but yeah it just
would have helped with just cleaning
more with with better drain
placement you're even lucky to have
drains honestly a lot of facilities work
with don't have drains and then trying
to retrofit that sucks so it's expensive
that that's
good yeah so moving on to the vertical
farming aspect are there any tips or
pointers uh for going vertical uh I know
you and I talked ahead of time that you
would not have you would not in
retrospect go vertical if you weren't
forced to based on your building um what
are the what are the challenges and what
are some tips oh gosh I mean a lot of
challenges it takes it takes longer to
do certain tasks
um because we're we're us utilizing
scissor lifts to work on the second tier
just because it's it's safer than maybe
putting up some type of temporary
catwalk system um or something like that
but so we use scissor lifts um so tasks
take longer in that respect uh there was
a little bit of a learning curve with
that and um just getting getting the
team
to um to check out the second tier
enough to make sure that it's getting
adequately watered uh scouting for uh
pest pressure um stuff like that so it's
easier to manage stuff that's on the
ground floor cuz we're just walking on
it all the time it's it's much harder to
get your team even two days a week to
spend all day up on the second tier
making sure everything's getting taken
care of because because of the style of
um growing that we're doing we have to
give these plants that extra attention
to make sure that we're we're getting uh
Boutique quality cannabis otherwise it's
just impossible to compete in the
established you know California Market
um so yeah just
workflow
um
tips yeah I would I mean I wouldn't do
it if you don't have to do it that's
that's that would be a big tip but uh um
God yeah just making the time and
scheduling
appropriately um also I've noticed on
the second tier with airflow um the beds
can get uh more of a dryback or just
less water so you just have to make sure
they're getting watered adequately and
uh the humidity is just a little bit
lower too so um that and I would grow
strains that are easier to manage so
strains that you know um that trellis
easy or um you don't have to thin out as
much um yeah just less canopy management
you would want to put those on on your
second tier or third
tier have you not well I have two
questions so the first one would be if
you had to guess at a percentage of
time uh how much more time would you say
that second tier costs you because you
have to utilize scissor lless you have
to go up and down um it's just harder to
get to and
access great question
uh I mean we probably have versus like
another grow that wasn't growing
vertically we probably have to have two
to three more staff full-time staff than
what a nonvertical grow would need just
just to for that extra time uh needing
to spend on on grow tasks so like if you
had a task
yeah if you had a task like let's just
say like def
defoliating how long if it were to take
you I don't know half a day to do the
lower tier how long would you budget for
that upper tier sort of a
thing maybe it would take you know 3/4
of a day or something cuz what what we
would do in that instance we would try
to get at least two scissor lists in
that room so we're having two people in
each lift maybe working on opposite
sides of each of each other or in that
same row so I mean it might add an
extra you know two to four hours
depending on what the task
is okay and uh how much of an issue is
stuff uh dropping down onto that lower
canopy you know your plants down below
with disturbance or dust or or Leaf
matter when you are defiling things like
that is that an issue at all for for you
guys yeah no definitely uh you know you
get some when you're de leafing you get
some leaves that drop down so just
having to go through the bottom canopy
and just grabbing those making sure that
they're not stuck in that canopy on the
bottom tier um oh I guess another point
I should have brought up as far as
things uh or tips for people with
vertical grow or things we would have
done differently is drainage for runoff
on your second tier so we accounted for
it
but we didn't account for cracked trays
because of the weight of the soil um
there's uh that was probably the biggest
thing so even if you do have drainage
for runoff we would still get some
cracks in those trays so we get
sometimes if there's too much runoff
which obviously we try to avoid um but
with the blue mats sometimes floods
happen um so we've had to hang like 5
gallon construction buckets under those
points where the tray might be cracked
just to capture any possible runoff to
prevent that from dripping onto the
plants on the bottom tier or dripping
onto the lights or the floor and more
importantly the plants cuz if you're
getting that runoff water on those
plants you might run into Bettis or some
kind of um fungal issue later in
flower yeah that would be a challenge uh
let's let's touch on that for people
because um how I know someone had asked
me like how deep are your beds oh gosh
ours are at least 14 inches
now okay they're about 14 inches deep
and okay and uh oh shoot I had another
question just based on it um oh are you
in
4x4 beds 4 by eight beds what are the
length the sizes of your beds
4 by8 this is a question I have because
I'm always trying to talk people into
4x4 beds o over a 4 by8 bed because I
think it gives you one more replication
so it's a better it's a smaller data
point and or end value higher end value
and then also if you have an issue like
a cracked tray maybe you could only
remove a half yard of soil instead of a
full yard assuming a 10in depth so you'd
actually have more than that anyway but
are there any advant to a 4x8 other than
a slight savings and
cost um what what are your thoughts on
that that's a great question um I don't
know if I've put too much thought into
it I think the biggest difference
between like a 4x4 and a 4x8 as you said
it would be like costs like you know you
might be spending more on uh components
for your irrigation system in a 4x4
versus a
4x8 um so maybe more points of failure
or you're just needing more
parts
um yeah I don't I don't know I mean I
just felt like a 4x8 was was the right
move um and in case there was an issue I
felt like it would be easier to deal
with that whether it's like a pathogen
or some kind of pest in the soil like a
root feeding nematode or whatever it may
be um yeah but yeah I think it would
just be excuse me just more cost from uh
for more parts for like
irrigation yeah I definitely like a
smaller like you said a 4 by8 even I I
don't want a 40ft row of soil if I can
avoid it just because if you do have an
issue like a pathogen or something let's
say the fertility gets wacky in a bed
you can always just pull out a smaller
section of soil if you ever did have to
replace something so that is kind of
future proofing yourself you mentioned
irrigation
that's an interesting point and I let's
let's start talking about blue mats
because our the design that we use for
blue mats uh that we've come up with is
a 4x4 design that's modular so it would
be the same for me in a 4x4 as it you
know we just d double it in a 4 by eight
so the number of Parts wouldn't change
what is I know you use blue mats as well
because I I saw your presentation we've
talked about it
um what is what are what does your
design look like uh for blue mats let's
start there and then we'll talk about
your overall feelings about blue mats
pros and cons for people who haven't
haven't considered them so I've done all
kinds of different layouts with blue
mats I've been using them or working
with them for at least six years now um
initially we started uh off with uh like
the the drip not the drip tape but like
the the little drippers we use two
different carrots uh we used a 6 in and
a 9 in at different points in the bed um
so I've tried that I've tried the blue
soak tape in a variety of different
layouts currently or what we did
initially with the
setup uh gosh I think we started with
6in carrots and then um we kind of did
like almost like a figure8 type design
around the plants um and then we moved
to a 9-in carrot um and kind of modified
the tape so it it would be touching uh
the corners and the sides a little bit
more um and then recently Cooper from
bloat he stopped by with their new
design which is using blue soaked tape
it's four rows of it running the length
of the bed from corner to corner with a
one prep pressure reducer manifold I
think it's at like 10 psi um that design
has been working great so the new layout
and design that they came up with um I
don't know if you were a part of that at
all um but that that worked out really
well um so I'm happy to see that room
working I might fluctuate on the side of
overwater versus underwatered but I'd
rather be overwatered in living soil
than
underwatered um
and
then yeah it's it's been a challenge
though with the blue mats
but we need we can't hand water all of
our rooms there's just we have six
flowering rooms 8,500 Square ft of
canopy with you know the two tiers it's
just not feasible so um I needed the
blue mats to work I think they've worked
overall but also you know just to be
frank I've also baned my head against
the wall dealing with these because it's
um you know we go in into rooms where
there's floods and water on the floor
and now I'm having to pay staff to you
know shop back water for three or four
hours or drain the the lines um
underneath the trays um the drain lines
so um it's it's been a challenge but
also I'm trying to work with them
because I I need this to work and I've
seen good results with it too where
we've hit really good metrics in living
soil with with uh some of the cultivars
we're growing so um yeah some good some
good and some bad but uh I like the
direction that they're heading in um I
don't want to spend more money though
we've already spent enough
money
uh you know installing it that's that's
my only complaint with the new manifold
design is that all those parts and
pieces are more expensive and there are
also potential fail points that being
said um I think I think it's a perfectly
good design we
use we use with the blue mats when we
recommend them we use kind of a spiral
similar to your s design but just a more
of a spiral with the I I like the
shorter carrot I want to read the depth
a little short a little shallower than
the Maxi but
um it'd be interesting to do uh to AB
test this because I haven't I have
haven't done that yet um but I thought I
think your review of blue mats is very
very honest I think folks going into
them should realize that there's a
learning curve and there are challenges
but also every irrigation system has the
has the potential for leaks and floods
and these things so there's no perfect
solution out there the only upgrade I
would consider would be a a
commercial system like something from
dram where you have uh uh you know a
very
industrial built-in tensiometer that's
reading the moisture content in the bed
and then irrigating that bed
specifically for that similar to what
the blue mats do um but this would you
know require electricity it would be ex
ex very expensive compared to the the
cost of Entry the blue mats offer so
unless you have the budget to really go
you know all in on irrigation management
um I think the blue mats are a very good
entrylevel solution for facilities or
even for homeg Growers I'm G set them up
for my next run at my house here
um that that are that that make sense so
I don't know anything you want to add to
that no I think I think I think you're
you're right um I think it's blue matat
is great for hom Growers um and and it
could be great for a commercial setup
too um yeah there's there's definitely a
huge learning curve I think they've
learned a lot um they're always making
improvements um I like their sop that
they've developed with the hanging drip
um yeah but also we're we're looking
into implementing a different style of
irrigation in one of our rooms too
because uh something similar to what you
just described because we already have
that capability with our environmental
control system so for us it would
probably be pretty cheap to set up in
one of our rooms and get something like
that going uh cuz we already have the in
infrastructure in place so um we're
going to look into that uh when we get
some more money and can afford to do
that interesting interesting yeah I have
to give credit to the guys over at
sustain of the village for really
continuing to innovate with the product
and come up with new Solutions so um
yeah and I really like I really like
what they're doing we also sell blue
mats like they do uh we just have a
slightly different design philosophy but
it's very close and I think either
system would work so yeah uh let's move
on let's talk about soil and fertility
management um you you mentioned you
started with k&amp;f and had good results um
that's really interesting I I didn't
know any of that part of your journey I
didn't meet you until or really connect
with you on soil management until much
later um what what did it look like when
you first opened the facility then and
then how did you get to where you are
now oh man yeah the last year has been
huge and just um learning a lot about
soil F fertility especially you know
living soil or soilless media indoors um
I didn't realize the challenges as far
as making sure that um that soil remains
fertile because we're trying to you know
get four and a half turns a year per
room so um it's it's not it's not as
idealistic as one might think with
living soil indoors and trying to be
sustainable and
um yeah so uh we started off with fully
charged um soil uh from a well-known
soil
company
um had you know really really good
results good yields at first um and then
um gosh I'm just trying to think back uh
we were mulching at the time we did some
cover cropping
diondra
mustard um barley stuff like that and uh
you know learned a lot about companion
planting and cover cropping too what not
to do uh what you can do I kind of lean
uh more
with with where you stand on on
companion planting indoors I think it
can be more of a problem um than
beneficial um I think no matter what
you're going to attract pest even with
diondra I've seen it um I think it could
be good or uh or utiliz to maybe uh to
capture pet pest kind of like a banker
system but um we primarily rely on a
mulch layer uh to keep our you know
risos spere going and and um keeping
those microbes and fungi alive I see
better results with that um We've ran
into pill bug issues like Steve has
talked about with the chop and drop so
we've definitely moved away from that um
we've learned a lot about um making sure
to test all of your inputs uh in your
soil and where your sourcing your soil
um cuz you don't want to contribute to
heavy metals because of you know how
good a bioaccumulator cannabis is it'll
pick that up no matter what you do um so
we've had to deal with heavy metal
issues uh due to some inputs in our soil
um I've thrown the kitchen sink at it
we've tried manipulating pH adding
biochar pulling soil out adding new soil
in um
utilizing mushrooms I've planted hemp
before we planted cannabis to try to get
it out um we've done a variety of
different things um you my experience
with heavy metals there's literally
nothing you can do unless you want to
replace the soil or after so many rounds
of just pulling it out naturally with
with cannabis so we've had it yeah we've
had some challeng es with that um but
also we've had plenty of rooms that have
passed just fine and where we haven't
had to deal with heavy metals um yeah
but soil fertility overall
um I've learned not that we weren't
testing our soil
before but I I've just come to the
realization how how important it is to
test your soil at the same time like so
we test we kind of follow what your
guys' sop so just for the audience we
work very closely with Tad and his team
with Brandon uh we submit a soil sample
around uh after 8 weeks in flower so
we're kind of getting the same snapshot
in time of where rooms are we try to
take different points in the room just
to try to get a general idea um and then
we go off of uh Brandon's
recommendations or working with them
being like hey we need to get our yields
up can we bump you know X Y or Z up um
so I think it's uh super critical
especially in a commercial setting where
you're trying to hit certain metrics um
you need to be doing soil testing and
you need to be making sure that the
inputs that you're using are uh clean
and
tested yeah I I mentioned this a lot you
know when we Harvest a plant we're
pulling out organic matter and we're P
pulling out nutrients and those things
need to be replaced every cycle so it's
important that uh that we take that into
account when we're when we're thinking
about Harvest and um yeah Also to
clarify for listeners um you you
originally did not have our soil in the
facility that wasn't um contributing to
your heavy metal issues when you were
dealing with that in caseing you was
listening we've we've been pretty
successful at at sort of mitigating
heavy Metals I would say uh but there
are all the challenges that you listed
in terms of understanding your inputs um
and knowing that that tests can be um I
don't want to say tests can be
manipulated but it's important to know
what it's important to do your own
testing and one thing that you and I
talked about off air beforehand was I
had done some testing with a lab um that
was using xrf technology instead of
icpms um and it wasn't I did not fully
understand it at the time and what I did
not realize was that the the detection
limits for that technology were not
stringent enough to give me the
information that I needed to make a good
decision so for example and I'm I'm
going to make up some numbers here but
it'll they'll be close for arsenic it
might not detect anything under 6 PPM so
it'll give back a non-detect
non-detectable level as an answer or for
lead it might be 10 PPM and so it comes
back non-detectable so if I had 9 PPM of
lead and 5 PPM of arsenic in that soil
or in that product it would come back
nondetectable as if it was not there and
those levels are just frankly too high
in a regulatory Market to feel
comfortable passing so you have to
understand the test and I would just
throw out as a guy don't trust test you
see on social media to necessarily
reflect what's in the actual product
that you're receiving um that's just
advice for folks do you want to add
anything to that Chris or I I mean move
on no I mean I think that's fantastic
points um yeah you have to understand
the method of testing or the equipment
that you're using and making sure that
it's accurate enough so you can feel
comfortable with um the decision that
you're making making sure that the soil
or inputs you're using are clean and
just to add on yeah you can't take what
someone posts on social media as just
truth or accurate accurate when it comes
to testing like like Tad said you have
to do your own testing in due diligence
it's uh I can't stress that
enough and now you're you've got a
program that seems to be working um you
have some of our s in the facility now
but not exclusively and uh it seems like
youve figured out how to manage and pass
successfully now which is awesome so
because California has very tight
regulations around heavy
yeah no no things are looking up and and
much better and and we're we're happy to
be yeah working with you guys you guys
are providing all the soil for our veg
and and Mom program so that soil is
getting put back into our our flower
rooms and we're using other inputs that
you provide as well but um yeah things
things have been great man so uh but
yeah lot lots of learning um cuz again
it's like we have to hit certain metrics
because it is a business um
and we have to make sure that there is
enough fertility in that soil to uh to
hit those metrics and it it's just
different in a soiless media
setup are you adding any nutrients
midcycle any T's k&amp;f ferment stuff like
that I don't actually know the answer to
a lot of these questions so it's good
it's great to hear um we do uh but that
we try to do low low cost input so we
definitely utilize comp compost extracts
and teas and that's compost Source from
Catalyst bio amendments um their
material is amazing um so we use those
and then we do some uh soil drenches um
some foiler
feeds um but again it's it's like a cost
perspective it's like okay uh cuz if
you're doing soil drenches with all
kinds of Bio stimulants or you're trying
to add pottassium or calcium um
or humic or fulvic um or aloe or coconut
or whatever it may be well that costs a
lot um the more you're scaling up so uh
we try to do at least one or two
drenches of some of those things I just
mentioned um and compost teas and
extracts we try to keep it really simple
um after hearing Eli speak at the soil
Summit and what he's doing with knf and
and fermented plant juices I am going to
be looking back into that uh cuzz he has
been doing testing um on his input so
I'm going to be looking into different
fermented plant juices as like a
potassium Source or just a good sugar
Source because it's always good to get
sugars um into your living soil system
because I think that makes a big
difference in your end product and uh
doing all these little things it
definitely adds up and you can you can
see uh how much of a better product you
end up getting
that's awesome and I I have to say I've
heard really great stuff about the the
Cannabis you guys are producing from uh
Nelson over at poetry plants and then
in-house with Brandon Hudson our uh our
in-house agous grower guy so uh Kudos
kudos to you guys for producing a
quality product appreciate it
man and um one thing I just want to
mention when you mentioned the fermented
plant juices for folks uh you can
absolutely make those yourselves there's
plenty of information on how to do that
you don't necessarily need to buy it um
if you do go down that route keep an eye
on sodium and chlorides those are two
things that I would want to test because
we I've been seeing a lot more sodium
and chlorides on my test results and
those are two things that you want to
keep low on a soil test and compost is
probably the biggest source for that
possibly water when if we talk about um
that as well
but uh I have seen pretty high sodium
and chloride levels in some um
commercially produced fjs so just keep
an eye on it and make sure if you are
adding it because that's something
that's going to impact your soil long
term and is may require flushing or
leeching out of your beds at some point
but um yeah I enjoyed Eli's talk too you
know hearing about how people are
successfully using these techniques to
save money I mean I think you're trading
l
for money at that point CU you're kind
of making your own nutrients and if that
makes sense then I fully support it um
some places you just don't have time to
to do that kind of work but um I I think
it can produce a very high quality
flower you know has has been shown so
that's great yeah
definitely um okay couple last questions
for you Chris I appreciate this um let's
take a look at this from uh homow
perspective you know I'm sure
cultivating commercially has changed
your views on cultivation so what
principles would you apply if you were
setting up a hom grow like what what's
sort of the same and what's
different well a lot a lot would be the
same in terms of just you know moisture
Water Management um that's always the
number one thing I'm looking at is
making sure that uh the soil is
adequately watered
um and we're not underwatered or
overwatered and I'd say you know 90% of
Growers probably overwater or new
Growers
um and then um as far as what would be
different it would be my ability just to
give more attention to you know less
plants or just a smaller grow so with
that you can do a lot of the smaller
things like I mentioned you can do a lot
of these inputs of humic fulvic you know
every other day even if it's just a
light drench um or your fpj or your aloe
your coconut um stuff like that over a
period of a flowering cycle it's going
to make a big difference in your home
grow um and that's why you know like I
think what we're doing we are producing
some of the cleanest and some of the
best flour in the world but I also know
that a small homeg grow or like a six
lighter 10 lighter they're going to have
better better batches and probably
slightly better flower than us just
because they can give it that much more
attention or they're just giving um
those inputs you know over a period of
that flowering cycle and there's certain
you know um measurements or things maybe
we can't measure yet as far as what what
makes a living soil or soiless media um
product better than a synthetically
grown because you know a lot of people
um say well the plant doesn't know the
difference between you know a
carbon-based um nutrient or Amendment
then versus a synthetic one okay that
may be true but what's happening with
that microbial or fungal life um that's
leading to a superior product you know
um you can't say THC percentage or even
tping necessarily um so it's it's other
factors or variables that we're not able
to measure yet
um yeah so it's it's just interesting to
think about too like what what is going
on in the soil uh cuz like you see with
hash competitions or even flower
competitions and the people that win
those it's it's usually living soil
Growers indoor or
outdoor yeah and um you essentially said
a lot of what Bryant Mason Soul doctor
says in regards to um cultivation and
this idea that if we can just keep
feeding small amounts of carbon to our
plants which is what a lot of you know
most of these amendments and tees are
are just little bits of carbon then
we're we're creating um an optimal
environment for soil health and plant
health so yeah I feel like you really
nailed it with that
um yeah is there anything else you'd
like to share regarding uh from a
cultivation perspective
um um otherwise I guess yeah I'll let
you answer that and then I have one last
thing for you uh I guess one thing I've
noticed with um ppfd and light intensity
with LEDs um in a smaller setup when
you're able to do those you know small
inputs over um the course of that
flowering period I was able to increase
my
ppfd um much more than in a commercial
setting um um and I think that's um
based off of like what's actually
available for the plant to uptake and
use and I think in in our commercial
setting we're relying on you know that
that macro micro and macro life to kind
of break down what we're putting in to
make it available and then with those
small inputs on a smaller
scale I think those inputs are available
more quickly you know so I think it's
it's um a different different
perspective when driving ppfd in a
smaller setting versus a commercial
setting at least in my experience with
living soil or or soilless media cuz in
in the facility currently I I'm not
going to push more than 800 or 900 ppfd
depending on the strain and that's even
with you know 1200 PPM CO2 um I've just
noticed uh a lot of strains can't take
that much ppfd but in our R&amp;D facility I
was able to push anywhere from 12200 to
1500 ppfd without seeing any um negative
uh drawbacks or negative uh effects on
the
plant and you were doing a lot
more applications of of fertility
applications too at that time right all
the k&amp;f stuff and other T's it sounds
like and I assume you're supplementing
so when I think of ppfd I immediately go
to CO2 so I would assume you were also
supplementing CO2 in the other facility
because as a homerow if you're not
suppling CO2 I would not play around
with levels over 8 or 900 um your plant
just can't keep up yeah there's just no
way um cool well then last thing uh Flor
and Flame I think you guys have a fun uh
slogan sort of uh company company
Mission that you put on your containers
you want to your packaging you want to
share that with folks yeah sure so uh we
came up with
uh this phrase when we were uh going
through our rebranding which I regret
and we're actually going back to our old
logo but we came up with this great
phrase that kind of represents who who
we are as a brand in a company and uh so
that phrase is a small batch indoor
flower grown with love in living soil by
humans who give a [__] um so uh I I
wouldn't have started this brand if if
one I wasn't a cannabis user and two if
I didn't believe in you know the
medicinal qualities of the plant and uh
wanting to uh produce a product that not
only that I consume myself on on The
Daily but um something that I can stand
behind and be proud and want to share
with people to uh to use so yeah I think
it's a great slogan um you know I I tell
people well we're the largest vertical
indoor living Sol Farm currently in the
world but also
we're only a small you know Mom and Pop
owned facility like we're only 80 you
know 8,500 ft of canopy it's not like
we're this big you know
conglomerate uh glass house so uh yeah
that's that's our uh that's our
phrase or slogan awesome well I hope
folks in the Bay Area will will try it
out if they're ever visiting or or
something when they go to dispensary and
I appreciate you sharing you know that
was the one thing thing about this Soul
Su that I really appreciated is that
we're a we're a community and even
though we might have slight differences
in how we cultivate at the end of the
day we're all trying to push a a what we
think is most sustainable or
regenerative um and environmentally um
friendly and appropriate so yeah it's a
cool community of folks that fall on
into this sort of living soil camp for
sure yeah it's uh it's definitely a
challenge we're the minority but you
know like we said we uh we believe in it
and uh
we think this is the most you know
sustainable way to cultivate indoors and
the most regenerative way to cultivate
uh
Outdoors awesome well thanks man I hope
you have a good rest of your day and uh
thanks again yeah Tad thank you for
having me I I hope uh I hope the
audience you know could get something
from our talk but uh yeah it was a
pleasure being on and uh I continue to
uh uh I continue to uh look forward to
Growing our relationship and working
with uh you guys uh as we grow
[Music]
too that was Chris Castle and you are
listening to the Cannabis cultivation
and science podcast if you like the
podcast please leave us a rating and
review and give us a follow on Instagram
and YouTube and don't forget at kiss
Organics we have a wide range of
products we offer on our website ranging
from soils amendments benefit icial
insects soil test analysis and
Consulting thanks for
listening