[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
i'm your host tad hussey of kiss
organics this is the podcast where we
discuss the cutting edge of growing from
a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge
my guest this week is dr abby wick abby
is
a north dakota state university
extension soil health specialist and
associate professor
and has experience working with farmers
on soil health building practices like
incorporating cover crops into rotation
and transitioning to no-till systems
since 2012 she has had her hands in over
50 000 acres of soil
and influenced management on over 200
000 acres of farmland
in the northern plains just with the
personal relationships she's developed
with farmers
there are many other farmers she
influences through her bi-weekly
magazine articles and television segment
along with
discussion-based extension programming
she focuses on goal-oriented approaches
so that farmers can maximize the
benefits while reducing the risk
associated with incorporating new
practices
she has been featured in successful
farming magazine q a and bonus sections
for her work with cover crops and
ability to connect with farmers
she was also senator hovind's selection
to represent north dakota for the senate
ag republicans women in agriculture
campaign in 2018.
now on to the show hi abby thanks for
coming on the show today
yeah thanks for having me yeah i'm i'm
excited to talk to you about soil and
soil health
today can we start off telling people a
little bit about your background
yeah i am an associate professor and
also an extension soil health specialist
at north dakota state university
so i've been here eight or nine years
kind of working with farmers
working with our county extension agents
also programs like with the nrcs
or the soil conservation districts to
get some of these full health practices
uh better understood and then
implemented on farm here in north dakota
so that's kind of what i've been doing
now i have a you know i guess i've lived
all over the country i've
um you know i got my training in wyoming
i was at virginia tech prior to coming
to here
worked in colorado for a bit and grew up
in ohio so
i feel like i've been around quite a bit
just looking at soils and always
interested in soils and
and it was kind of fitting that i ended
up here working with farmers because
it's just it's a lot of fun and i really
really enjoy working in soil health in
this area
so what aspect of soils or soil health
do you feel
like you fit into most strongly i know
when we talked before
you mentioned that you work with a team
of people and you know
everyone sort of has their specialty you
have a soil biologist and a few other
uh folks that you work with what's
what's your
sort of niche in all of this oh
gosh you know i try to fit in wherever
the farmers need me and
um you know i was pretty fortunate when
when ndsu started this soil health
program
gosh eight or nine years ago they hired
six different positions and so
um so i'm the lead extension for the
state here on main campus and there's a
researcher
kaylee gash who is a soil ecologist and
so she's
she runs the research program for the
state she specializes in all those
microbes in the soils
soil carbon and organic matter
nutrient cycling soil biogeochemistry i
mean she's she's really
specialized in a lot of different things
but mainly you know having to do the
soil
soil ecology and then there's some other
um let's see one of the other
specialists here
that's up in langdon he does the the
salts
so we have fairly young soils
geologically and so we have a lot of
salinity and also sodicity so we're
managing salts that are reducing our
crop productivity here
so he kind of specializes in that and
then we've got a fertility person and
then also a wildlife biologist
which is kind of neat that they saw that
perspective of soil health as far as how
it
influences wildlife so a pretty diverse
team we've we've also had one
that was um he was working up in minot
and he has since moved to be the
director
of one of our research extension centers
but um but it's been a good program i
kind of fit in
you know with the keeping my finger on
the pulse of what farmers need
or want to learn about or apply to their
farms
and then i try to direct the program and
that
in that way um so yeah i don't know it's
hard to say what i truly specialize in
but i love
like soil aggregates or something i've
worked a lot with infield assessment of
soil health and what are we seeing how
do we
how do we choose practices that fit our
goals on farm which may be
different for every single field that
the farmer works with
so yeah i don't know i just kind of
float around and try to make sure that
the program stays relevant and is is
answering farmer's questions
yeah so when you step onto a new field
uh
and you see you know this their soil how
do you
what's going on mentally in your head in
terms of the steps of sort of evaluating
that soil um you know the
the first thing when we step into a
field and i love doing this with the
farmer is
is hearing the history of the field from
them uh getting their
take on what they need to accomplish in
that field and maybe how soil health is
going to help them get there
you know in some cases we go into field
and a farmer may just say you know i've
tried everything else and what have i
got to lose
and um and trying slow health practices
so sometimes they're open to anything
because
we sometimes go into their worst field
that they have on the farm that they've
just
they've deep ripped it they've chisel
plowed it they've
you know done all these different
practices trying to get that soil into
shape
for planting and now they're thinking
well
why not try reducing tillage why not try
something like cover crops
so we usually have that conversation
first and you know find a little bit
about their logistics
of their operation what what it can they
do with the time that they have i mean
we're working with farms here that are
gosh you know 1500 acres to
40 000 acres so fairly large operations
and
and do they have the manpower to seed a
cover crop
or uh to run a strip till machine and
the expertise to do that
um so you know we kind of look at the
logistics and then
i kind of like to see what the farmer
thinks of the soil first
you know do they think that it's healthy
do they think it's pulverized
do they you know what what's their take
on it and then we kind of talk through
it
um before i tell them anything about
what i think of their soils we kind of
talk through what they think of their
soils
and um and then i'm kind of sneaky in a
way i kind of slip in different ideas
and i let the farmers kind of come to
their own conclusions
um so yeah that's kind of what's going
through my head is is how am i going to
learn about this field their operation
and you know what they want to do with
this field before we even really
start talking soils
yeah i would think as a as a farmer
uh they're probably uh hyper fixated on
nutrients and this is just pure
speculation how often do you find
a nutri a particular nutrient to be the
limiting factor of growth
or do you find like
you know i don't know something to do
with the physical
you know makeup or aggregation of the
soil to be
limiting crop health
ah you know that's that's a great
question and i think um
you know the fertility is definitely you
know
one of the primary concerns you know
what what's limiting in that system and
you know oftentimes though when you know
if a farmer especially has an
independent crop consultant or somebody
they're working with on their acres
they've probably identified that issue
or they've looked into the ndsu research
or something like that and they've
they've kind of
figured out that it's a sulfur
deficiency or
you know something like that that's
causing their crop to not perform
i guess um and so it's it that seems to
be
the part of soils that farmers can
really wrap their heads around or they
have the resources to
um to address already um and the soil
health stuff is just a little bit more
fuzzy because it's
it's a little less understood and it's
so based on you know the soil
bio biological component and how that
interacts with the
chemistry of the soil and the physical
properties and you know so sometimes
it's harder for
for farmers to pinpoint the issues that
are associated with soil health
um but you know when we start talking
about it i'll ask him about
you know how's your traffic ability at
planting you know can you get
your your tractor across this field or
what's it like when you're planting
um or at harvest you know do they have
issues if it's a wet harvest
or a late harvest getting that getting
their combine across the field and so a
lot of it just comes down to you know
how's their equipment
going across that field and then we can
kind of back that into relating it to
soil aggregation
as being the structure in that soil that
holds up your equipment
or the water management part of it that
says you know
if you're using water in the soil with
something like a cover crop or a longer
season crop
how is that influencing the way the the
water dynamics of this field
um and how's your water move into the
soil
so i think you know i always try to kind
of go back to
especially with solar health because it
can be so difficult to kind of
you know learn and understand as to how
is your performance on this field
you know with your crop but also with
your equipment because we can relate so
many of those things back to
back to soil health and how's that soil
um holding up that equipment or
managing managing the water in that
field
that's really interesting i i think that
your your comments really highlight how
complex
of a system soil health is and also
how that relates to each farmer's unique
situation
i would think even with similar soils
just with you know different
different water management different
equipment
or different crops you could have wildly
different outcomes
in in terms of yields and you know
i guess farmer satisfaction
yeah i mean it is so based on that
because you know there are farmers that
we have some very sandy soils in north
dakota and
and some farmers are raising corn on
those sandy soils and well corn is a
long season crop and most of the times
it runs out of moisture
but you see a farmer across the road
shifting to something like a
pea crop and so the peas go in early
they come off early before the moisture
is limiting and there's just two totally
different
management approaches just in the crop
that you select for that field so
um so yeah it is pretty interesting it's
so customized and i think that's why
these conversations in the field
you know with farmers and kind of an
outside perspective or just somebody
else looking at their field with them is
is really important to identifying some
of these approaches that can be used
so you know we've you've touched on
cover crops a little bit
in relation to some of their benefits
um can we talk a little bit about that
you know some
some of the things that cover crops add
to a field in regards to
you know fertility biomass some of those
sorts of things
yeah yeah i you know we're so we're
north dakota
or i am you're not you're in some place
probably much nicer in the winter
but in north dakota we have a really
short growing season our crops pretty
much are the
the main thing that's growing during
that season and um
and then we have this long long long
winter
um so we have a pretty limited amount of
time to get something to grow
um to do a job for us and so
oftentimes with cover crops which you
know are are the
our management tool to grow something
between your cash crops
um between you know planting a harvest
or interseeding it into those cash crops
is is pretty challenging for us um so we
do end up doing a ton of
of planting a cover crop into a cash
crop harvesting that cash crops and then
that cover crop is already established
and it starts growing
and we get a few extra weeks of growth
because of doing that approach
so we're always trying to find new ways
to do things
um and we have very few cover crops that
actually overwinter
in our winters here so we're you know
our basic tools for overwintering our
cereal rye or winter rye
and um and there's also this winter
camelina oil seed that we're kind of
looking into and exploring here um you
know as well as other places like
maryland they can get clovers over
winter because the winter is mild and
you know sometimes the like the clover
seeds that come out of oregon they say
well they'll they'll do well they're
winter hardy and we get them here and
it's like dead as a door now
right in the spring by the time spring
comes so
um so we kind of you know we have a
limited window we need to pick things
that fit well with our cash crops in
rotation which we have
dozens of cash crops that we grow here
in north dakota so trying to
to fit them into those you know the
planting time and harvest time of those
and to make sure we don't transfer
diseases
between cover crops and cash crops um
and just kind of making sure that it
works for the for the farmers with their
with their herbicide applications too so
um
it gets pretty tricky pretty fast but we
have some just basics that we go to of
you know cereal rye radish has worked
really well up here
oats work great winter wheat spring
wheat
we just kind of go to those basics
turnips if you're grazing them with
livestock we'll
recommend some of that and flax has been
really good for us too because a lot of
farmers here have grown flax so
to put it in a cover crop mix is it's
just fine for them because they feel
like they can manage it so we try to
choose things that are easy
that kind of do the job and then we
figure out how to get it going
in a cash crop by interceding it versus
waiting till harvest because
because we just don't have time after
harvest here
so you know with cover crops it sounds
like there's a lot of
different options and it really depends
on
what the farmer's goals are you know
if i miss any some of these benefits
please please jump in
cover crops can work to help with weed
management they can help
with water management they can help with
reducing erosion
they can help with increasing your
organic matter in soils on scale that's
you can't just bring in compost
if you have 1500 acres that you're
managing that's just not very practical
in a lot of cases i would think what are
some of the other
potential benefits of cover crops
in terms of targeted goals yeah i think
um you know for us here erosion is a big
one and i think keeping
those fields covered especially after
like little residue crops
of for us soybeans are pretty low
residue crop peas are low residue
so getting something growing there to
protect those soils from erosion is
usually number one
on our list you know the water
management having something over winter
like that cereal rye
or winter camelina that can use water
both in the fall and the spring
can really help us here too or you know
building up a residue
with something like oats that can reduce
evaporation from the surface
and actually retains the moisture in
those soils is pretty important and you
know
the weed control like you're talking
about is excellent for us too we we're
starting to get
different resistant weeds up here um and
so having that early spring growth of an
overwintering cover crop
competes with weeds and can help give
farmers a little extra time to get out
there and
manage the weeds on that field um and
then like you mentioned the increasing
organic matter is a big deal for us
especially in our sandy soils
we do have some composting that occurs
around here but you have to be close to
a dairy
and like you said the logistics of
getting it on a lot of acres can be
pretty challenging
um you know one of the things that seems
like a pretty hot topic for a lot of
farmers or interesting cover crops is
this you know
this catch and release idea that cover
crops take up
nitrogen and then they release them for
next year's crop
and we're not seeing a lot of that here
um it's pretty complex
you know we're talking about before it's
a complex
soils are complex and you know if we if
we oversimplify them to think
that we can grow a cover crop it'll take
up nutrients which they do
um we've measured that and they do take
up those excess nutrients in the soil
but then assume that they're going to
release them when a crop needs it the
next year is is a pretty big assumption
and
we're not seeing those nutrients
released for for several years
um we're just it's being bound up in
that organic material and it's not being
released for
a cash crop in the short term of you
know four to five years
um and that's okay right it's still in
the soil at least it hasn't been lost
from the system
but but i think there's some you know
some of those benefits are have been
oversimplified a little bit and we just
need to kind of fine-tune that but but
that is one that farmers are interested
in because they want to reduce
fertilizer costs and get it down to you
know
more manageable return on investment for
each acre
so when you reference that i think
immediately of clover when we talk about
um you know nitrogen fixing
legumes and uh the bacteria that
fixes atmospheric nitrogen how
but what you're saying is that you're
not actually seeing that end
in a form that the plant can can access
uh as quickly as you would have thought
but you're not losing it too i know we
touched on this in another conversation
can you kind of elaborate on that a
little bit
sure yeah we um so clovers are really
popular for
nitrogen fixers and and we're you know
north dakota they don't fare very well
for us because we need 60 days of growth
on clover as a cover crop to actually
offset the cost
the high cost for the seed and most of
the times we don't get 60 days of
prolific growth to really offset it
so we use some other legumes in our
system peas or fava bean or something
like that that's a little more cold
tolerant and does a little bit better
as far as growth and so you know you've
got the nitrogen fixers doing that and
what can you expect from those and then
you have the other ones that capture
nutrients um you know the radish or
oats or you know any other basically
living
cover crop is going to capture some of
those nutrients and hang on to it and
and we're just you know when you have
decomposition of that
organic material in that plant i mean
you have to have the right temperature
and the right moisture
for the microbes to work on that organic
material and to release it
or for plants and oftentimes
when our crops need that
those microbes may not be as active as
we need them to be to release some of
those nutrients
they might go after different forms of
organic material in the soil and maybe
not going after those
those cover crop forms i don't know how
you'd even measure that but
um but you know we're also so it's a
timeline of saying it may not be ready
um the conditions might not be right for
the microbes to be releasing that
nutrient to the crop when it needs it um
but then also we've got these
um shrink swell soils here these high
clay soils
that we're seeing some of the um
some of those nutrients get caught
between the clay layers
which is getting even more complex right
i mean this is soil maybe that's the
theme of this whole thing is soils are
complex
but we're finding some of those
nutrients get actually caught between
the clay layers and they don't get
released
for the plants to use them so um so
there's all kinds of places that these
nutrients are going
or being stored in the soils and and we
just don't know
kind of when they're going to be
released yet whether it's from a
nitrogen
fixing cover crop or one that just
captures nitrogen in the soils
so we're working on it we'll try to
figure it out when we you know when we
can but right now we just tell farmers
to
put on you know whatever rate of
fertilizer you need do a check strip on
the side that's a full rate of
fertilizer and then
come back and side dress with nitrogen
if you feel like it's deficient and if
it's not then the
organic matter is turning over then then
you're good you save some money
okay but you're not seeing uh that
nitrogen
leech out either then necessarily you're
saying that it's still there
it's just not accessible right
yep that's exactly it it's we're not
seeing it leached but we're also
not seeing it become available that's so
interesting
somewhere you know everyone in their
heads they think clover
nitrogen and you just assume it's going
to be available
but it sounds like like you said the
microbes
temperature sunlight of crop timing all
of these things
actually make it quite a complex process
yeah i think so it's it's you know it's
not just this catch and release
or i'm gonna plant clover in my corn so
that
you know it fixes nitrogen for my corn
you know i mean some of it's just that
these these nitrogen fixers are really
beneficial because they're
their dead material is so highly
desirable by microbes that it stimulates
the system
um you know there's some leaky weakness
happening there with the nitrogen coming
out of the roots and whatever else but
a lot of it's just that material that
dead material of
a legume is just really desirable for
microbes to decompose so
um so yeah i think that you know there's
been some oversimplification of these
systems that i think
you know makes it challenging i
understand that you know not every
farmer
needs to be like a super soil
microbiologist
you know or into soil biogeochemistry to
to manage these things but i think there
are just some things we need to be aware
of to make sure that
that we're you know getting the most out
of our crop in each field
uh and not relying too much on some of
these practices or ideas that
that you know we can catch it and then
release it
uh using a cover crop yeah you know that
that is one other benefit
of cover crops that you touched on there
that we didn't i didn't mention before
and that's uh
sort of microbial health in soils and
how you know
bare soils just don't fare well compared
to stools that have
plants in them and i think that having
you know roots available these microbes
obviously increases your
microbial health
you know we had talked about how
you know my micro microbes get
oversimplified too
to things like fa uh you know fungal to
bacterial ratios as a tool and that
you know your research there found that
that wasn't as
useful i believe can you can you touch
on that a little bit too
sure sure yeah the um yeah microbial
health is
is extremely important and we try to
focus on that right and we try to
measure it right we're humans we want to
measure everything
and know if it's working or not or what
we have and
and you know with microbes it's just
tough to do that and so like you brought
up that fungal to bacterial ratio
there's there's been a ton of emphasis
put on that and you know i know how they
do it
it's all these phospholipid fatty acid
analyses they're plfa
and you send the sample off to a lab you
pay whatever and get the sample back and
it tells you you've got
this type of bacteria and this type of
ectinom i see you're
just generalizations of like
gram-positive bacteria or gram-negative
bacteria or
you know this is how much fungal hyphae
you have in your system and then they
create this
ratio of fung you know fungi bacteria
and if you're only sending off one
sample
from one point in time it's just going
to tell you about that point
that location where you pulled the
sample at that moment you know it's
it's not telling you about the whole
system or what that looks like across
the field or the variability that may
exist
or any of those things and and so we've
run you know thousands of samples
and it's like the variability is just
huge with that analysis
and it doesn't mean that it's not
worthwhile but it also means that
if you're sending off one sample and
you're gonna make you know
huge management decisions based on this
analysis of one sample from one point in
time on your field
that's pretty risky and it's not
something that we want that we're
prepared for farmers to be doing
or to be interpreting really i mean
sometimes i look at that data and i'm
like i don't know what that means
so um so yeah i mean i think it's just
you know using the general practices
of reducing tillage you know to create a
home for these microbes and these
diverse
microbes do exist giving them a food
source
right with with your cash crop and your
diverse rotation
and then adding in some cover crops to
fill in the gaps
and have something growing you know food
and shelter is number one for these guys
so
so just kind of creating that habitat
for them is is probably the most
important thing you can do and then
just make the assumption that they're
there and that they're diversifying and
that new
new microbes are coming in that maybe
weren't as prevalent before and
they're all kind of interacting with
this community under the soil surface
and and hopefully doing the job that you
need them to do
so what i'm hearing is that that test
doesn't necessarily give you a lot of
actionable data
because because you're going to be
trying to do things to
uh in terms of like best practices for
microbial
health and soil health anyway and the
diversification
that you see i mean the standard
deviation that i've seen on
these tests can be so wide that i look
at them and kind of scratch my head and
say
you know how can i how can i really use
this or does this allow me to make any
changes
in my garden or in my field and i just
don't see it as a tool at this point
um i i don't know what are your thoughts
on that
oh i i agree with you i wouldn't make
any you know
management decisions on these biological
tests
you know at this point because they're
so variable and they depend on when you
pull the sample
and where you pull the sample and how
many samples you pull and
um you know i think it's neat stuff to
know
um but you know i think a lot of this
you can just make these assumptions and
i know people get freaked out about
assumptions because
you're not collecting the actual data or
you know something like that but we have
collected the data we've run
all these soil health analyses on
you know one field we had 180 points
across that field and we
sampled it multiple times and looked at
these things and
and it's just um you know
you learn as much about your field and
the health of your field by using a
shovel
as you ever could um by running all
these analyses
and so sometimes it's neat to know and
you can use it as a baseline but i
certainly wouldn't make management
decisions
based on that you know on a fungal
bacterial ratio or
you know any of those things uh at this
point we're just not there yet and
and we'll get there maybe you know but
in the meantime it's just good to know
that
that you're creating a good home for
microbes you're covering your field and
reducing erosion
you may be getting better traffic
ability um
you know whether it's a garden or a
field you can see these changes
that's that are occurring as you build
up your soils and maybe it's just good
to be to be happy with that
yeah i like that um
i i guess you know for me with the
with the with the microbes i i kind of
feel like like you said like let's just
let's just take on best practice i'm not
convinced we'll ever fully understand it
because it's such a
complex process and i'm not sure that we
necessarily need
to ever you know completely understand
it
um but i do think that uh is it's an
interesting
thing to continue to explore but you
know one of the things is like
if you have a fertilizer application if
it rained recently
if it hasn't rained all of these things
are going to affect
your microbial populations pretty
quickly
to where i think it would be really hard
to make like you said a long-term
decision
yeah yeah i like that i like that
approach so it's
so you're just kind of looking at what
management practices you're using are
they achieving some goals and maybe
microbes are just kind of coming along
with it and
you're getting those benefits as you go
yeah so jumping around a little bit here
i kind of want to move back to
cover crops because we talked a little
bit about the benefits of them but we
didn't really touch on
all of the comp complexities like when
you talk to a farmer
it sounds like the first thing you're
looking at is their
their goals so like um can you give an
example of like uh
a situation with a with a particular
cover crop in terms of a farmer's goals
and how you and
how you meet that yeah
um let's see so maybe i'll do we've got
some crazy high clay soils here but
um they're pretty specific to our region
so maybe i'll talk about some sandy
soils
where um you know i came in a little bit
after the fact on this one the farmer is
already doing these great things because
he's got a crop consultant that's very
interested in soil health and very good
at making recommendations there so
um so there's you know there's a farmer
over by jamestown north dakota and he's
got some very sandy soils that he works
with
and um it's kind of like the tale of two
fields so he has one field that he's
been managing with no-till for
15 to 18 years probably added in cover
crops to that system
changed his rotation on it to grow
shorter season crops to be better suited
for those sandy soils
so for example corn and soybean would be
you know
kind of king here in north dakota in
that area you know that's just
that would be the rotation well he grows
wheat on that field so it comes off a
little earlier
he grows peas on that field so again it
comes gets in early comes off early and
gives them a chance to plant a cover
crop
in that field and so he started doing
that he
um he'd follow it with like an oat cover
crop or something so it'll winter kill
and he doesn't have to worry about using
too much moisture in the spring
throws in a little radish some flax um
let's
you know some of the volunteer from the
cash crop come back
and he gets pretty much another growing
season out of that field and
and what he's doing with that is that
he's increasing his organic matter he's
not only covering he's increasing
organic matter so that it holds more
moisture
on that in those sandy soils but then
he's also getting better cover on that
field
going into the winter to reduce erosion
and so he's been doing this stuff for a
while
and you know happy with the performance
on his field well he took over a new
half section of land um kind of kitty
corner to that field it's the same soil
type
and that field had been corn and soybean
and it had been chisel plowed and ripped
and whatever else
and as you started farming that first
thing you put on it was a short season
crop like peas followed it again with a
cover crop to get that organic matter
built up and that first year
we grabbed some soils from from his
existing field where he'd been using
these practices for 15 or more years
and grabbed some soils from that new
field he took over and just
put him side by side to look at soil
color
and the practices he had been using with
the
reduction of tillage the incorporation
of cover crops the changing of his crop
rotation
his soils that he'd been managing for a
long period of time were much darker
than those in the other field he'd just
taken over and so that tells you there's
more organic matter and he's probably
getting better
moisture retention on those fields
especially in a drought like we are in
this year
he's probably got the moisture there
that he needs to get that crop going
and um and he was pretty happy he he
hadn't
ever looked at those two solos side by
side and it was kind of for him it was
like okay well
now i know that what i've been doing is
working and i can just kind of see it
visually
so he's doing the same practices on that
other field to get it back in shape so
um so that would be you know one example
of where some of those changes have
really made a difference
um for field and and you know kind of
evaluating it too
um but i think that's that's pretty
common when farmers change the the
system
um and suit it to those soils i think it
can make a big difference
in how those soils perform
yeah what do you see when farmers first
start
making changes like this let's say you
had a farmer who was farming fairly
conventionally
you know a lot of soil disturbance a lot
of chemical fertilizers
um how how does that look switching over
in terms of cost and also
yields as they make a change because i'm
making the assumption that you have a
farmer
they really work the land the soil is
fairly depleted they're seeing their
yields go down and down and down and
then they finally reach out to you and
say
abby help me fix this like what can we
do
what does that look like
boy um you know it looks again different
for every farm but
but in general you know most of them
have the equipment to no-till
right i mean their their cedars and
their planters can all
can all perform well in in residue um
can you you know before you go any
further can you explain
what that means on an agricultural level
because
i think that a lot of people that list
this podcast don't know what
no-till and minimal till really means
agriculturally because it's a little
different
i think terminology i guess in that
regard
oh good yeah thanks thanks for that um
so no-till
for us is you know just not making a
tillage pass with a chisel plow or
you know anything like that in the fall
or the spring and so
literally when you harvest that crop and
leave that residue behind the combine
that's what you're going to plant into
the next spring you're not going to
disturb it at all with any kind of
tillage
um there's also kind of these you know
ideas of using vertical tillage uh which
is another management tool so it's not
as disturbing of the soil as like a
chisel plow would be
um which you know goes several inches
into the soil but a vertical tillage
would be you know goes maybe two inches
in the soil and it just slices and sizes
residue
and so farmers will use that practice
generally you know in the spring
before planting if they feel like like
they left that field
we're going to try to go to no-till but
the residue just you know
they're going to get not get a good
stand uh with their equipment so they'll
run this
this tillage tool prior called vertical
tillage and they'll they'll kind of
size up that residue and create
something they can plant into a little
bit better
and then there's strip till which some
farmers use here
which is a whole different expensive
piece of equipment
but it creates strips in that field
where you're going to plant your cash
crop
and so generally you do that the fall
before and you get your fertilizer down
in those strips and
you're only disturbing a third of the
soil so you've got the the tillage
happening where you're planting a crop
and then in between you're leaving
residue
similar to like a no-till situation
where you have good residue cover
between but you've got these berms or
these strips
that you're going to plant into that
would be like chisel plastic so it's
really kind of a hybrid type
tillage practice so so that's you know
kind of what farmers would be looking at
there's all kinds of other variations on
this but
but those are kind of the general you
know no-till
reduced tillage which would be kind of a
vertical till and then um
strip till okay
yeah so um that's that's helpful so
you're you're trying
to reduce that um when are instances
where you may encourage tilling does
that
does that occur yeah i mean
there's you know in a wet harvest or
something i mean farmers
may cause some ruts in their field
whether they're no-till or
full tillage sometimes you just you have
to get the crop off and it's wet
and equipment gets stuck or you leave
some
some tracks or something in the field
and you don't have to work the whole
field or do
the whole you know till the whole field
to get it back in shape but
but if you don't want to keep driving
over those ruts for the next 10 years
you know you need to
go in and level them off with something
um and kind of
get that soil back to where you know you
can harvest uh
you know with your header close to the
ground and
not catch dirt or ruts or you know
something like that and also i mean
yeah farmers don't want to be bounced
around in their equipment all the time
so
that's why i recommend tillage you know
mostly is if you've
if you have some ruts in the field from
a wet harvest or
wet planting or something like that you
need to get them out then that's an
appropriate time to do tillage
um you know i always ask farmers if
you know if the tillage are doing what
is the
reason for that tillage you know if they
can identify a specific reason to do
that tillage
and can you know a specific timing for
it
i think it's important to ask yourself
that every time to make sure it doesn't
become a habit
and something that you're just doing
because you've
been doing it a while or you know
is the field too wet to plant in the
spring and you need to do a vertical
tillage pass then then do it
but if the field is dry the next spring
and you're out there doing a vertical
tillage pass and you've lost that
original reason for why you're doing it
then
then maybe you don't need to be doing it
at that point so
you know i think it's always good for
farmers to kind of check back in with
why they're doing something on their
farm
and you know if they can't identify the
reason anymore then
maybe they don't need to be doing it
yeah
i could see where you just get into a
habit of treating your soil the same
every year
or your land uh what about like uh
um if you have residue that's just not
breaking down fast enough
the microbes aren't you know breaking
down whatever cover crop you'd run
through the winter
uh come planting time what do you do in
scenarios like that
uh you know that would be gosh i suppose
that would be something that you could
run a vertical tillage passover
or something if you feel like you've got
a lot going on out there and a lot to
plant into
then um then yeah you may decide to do a
vertical tillage pass and
and kind of knock it back and size it a
little bit um and that would be okay but
i you know before even doing that
i encourage farmers to get their their
planter out there and do a couple strips
into it and just see
see what it's like to plant into you
know i mean sometimes when you look at a
field
you think it's going to be a mess but
then you get out in it and your
equipment does really well
or you're not even seeding anything but
you're just running your equipment
through to see how it performs
um i think that's okay too you know and
maybe you don't need to
incur that cost of of doing some kind of
you know additional pass so i'm always
kind of encouraging farmers to try
something first
and if it's if it doesn't work then come
back in with that
you know whatever tillage path or
adjustment or something but
but give it a shot first and see see how
it goes and and then
kind of adjust from there yeah so all
that residue
is you know little little fertilizer
bags
and little water retention holders for
you
i would say what about the risk of
disease though
you know potentially having more fungal
issues or things as
or bacteria as those uh residues are
breaking down
definitely we're pest habitat i guess
too yeah
yeah i mean you're changing the whole
system right so the the diseases and
pests that you may have had
or weeds you know with full tillage are
not going to be the same
as in a reduced pill or a no-till
situation so
i mean gosh you can look at things like
goss's wills and corn
um that's you know transferred on
residue i believe hopefully i'm not
wrong on that i keep trying to remember
all these different disciplines i work
with and sometimes it works sometimes it
doesn't so if i'm wrong let me know
um but that can be an issue right i mean
if you have that
bacteria on that residue living there
and if you go to the crop the next year
and it transfers over that can be an
issue
or you can have diseases transfer
between cover crops so for us
radish is also a host for club root
which is a huge problem in canola
production
so it's you know you have to be careful
of those things
as you change your system you're
changing your management um and for sure
like weeds
you know in a full tillage system
they're kind of an annual weed issue and
then you go to no-till and it's a
perennial weed issue and so you're
spraying at different times and
you know trying to figure out how to
manage those weeds in different ways so
it's definitely something to keep in
mind that if you change one part of your
system you're probably going to change a
lot of parts of that system
and just be prepared for it and keep
your eyes open to it
and talk with other people who have made
that transition because they know what
to expect
or at least to give you something to
watch out for um
but yeah don't i think a lot of the you
know failures that we see
in people going to like no-till for
example is that they just stop
tilling but they forget to use the water
after a wheat crop with a cover crop or
they forget to
[Music]
do different herbicide passes or
you know change their rotation things
like that um that's where we see those
things fail because they're taking one
practice and not treating it as a system
and then adjusting you know the entire
system for it
so it's not as simple as just not
tilling your field and then treating
everything the same
yeah right right i think we would call
that direct seating right where
you know you're just doing everything
the same and you just kind of plant into
it and
it's not a system at that point it's
just a practice um
and so yeah i think yeah anyway anyone
making changes or doing something new
they need to treat it as a system and
figure out what they can do
um to make that system work
um especially for different soil types
so yeah it sounds really complex and you
hate to
make it complex before somebody even
tries it but um but it's certainly
you hate to see failures also
yeah so as someone and i got you off
topic this is my fault when we started
talking about tilling
um as someone makes this transition to
sort of this soil health perspective
you know we talked about switching from
a you know very conventional
agricultural model to something that's
you know looking at soil health and and
reduced tillage and things like that um
what what do you typically see and i
know every situation is going to be
different but what do you see in terms
of yields
is that first year sort of a little bit
of a transition and then over time as
that soil improves do yields typically
go
up what does that look like
uh yeah that's you're right it looks
different for everybody and you often
hear with
you know if i'm gonna go to no-till i'm
gonna take a yield hit for x number of
years you know
and and that's just kind of the general
idea of it and how do i prepare for that
and
and i always remind farmers to look back
at what's their return
their roi you know what what's their
return per acre
are they doing you know swapping a
tillage pass for herbicide pass or
um you know what are they doing that's
gonna
change those costs and and all the way
down to labor and
maintenance of your equipment or hours
on your tractor or
um what it costs you to have a specific
person out in the field doing a specific
job
um i want them to kind of look at all
those different things
and then decide if it's a success or not
because oftentimes you know the
the farmers i work with for example i
mean they would love to have a 200
bushel
corn yield on their field right i mean
that would be kind of
average and and they'd be perfectly
happy with that and some years they do
get that sometimes they get 220 bushels
you know
um but they sometimes their their
yield goal or what they want to achieve
is 190
and if they can consistently get that
based on their inputs and the way they
manage that field
for corn then they're happy because
they're they're having reductions in
fertilizer inputs
that are kind of feeling that out to see
how much they can cut back on fertilizer
editions and
and that could be a huge cost savings so
so maybe they're only
they only getting maybe they're only
getting 190 bushel corn and the
neighbors getting 210
but if they're applying less fertilizer
they have less passes
they're using different management
approaches and it might just be that
they're coming out ahead
you know cash wise on that field that's
a great point
um so we've kind of covered how complex
not just soil health is but also just
farming in general
um and a lot of this uh what are some
resources out there for farmers
i know you have this website can you
talk a little bit about some of the
resources that you guys offer for people
oh absolutely i'd love to um so we have
you know
ndsu soil health if you search that
anywhere you'll you'll find our webpage
which is ndsu.edu
soil health and um you know the things
that i focus on providing to farmers
are mainly videos um because they can
they can check those videos out while
they're in the tractor in the combine
and
generally they're less than three
minutes so you can watch it in one pass
on a on a quarter
of land it takes you about you know less
than three minutes to get across the
field
so they can watch videos we also have a
podcast
called um soil sense and also a soil
sense field check
and so we try to you know kind of
highlight the things that farmers are
doing the research that's being done
um you know kind of different places
that you'll find soil health
and and those collaborations that make
it work um
so so we've got some episodes there and
then we did like this
field check podcast that was a 10 minute
episode
with a question and answer type format
so you can get a lot of information in a
very short period of time as well
and then i'd love to host meetings so
we've got a ton of meetings coming up in
workshops and now with everything you
know being virtual last year now going
back to face-to-face this year
everybody wants a hybrid event so we're
doing some virtual
and some you know with face-to-face
components and
just yeah the complexity too of our
programming has gone way up but
but in a good way because it's just a
lot better access so
yeah all that stuff can be found on that
ndsu slow health web page and
you can just probably get lost in there
in a rabbit hole
there's a there's a ton of information
on here it's it's quite impressive
uh one question i had can anyone join
these sorts of things you don't have to
be a farmer in north dakota to
utilize you know some of these more uh
some of these resources that are more
interactive like the
events i guess for instance oh yeah we
love
having people from all over join them um
you know a lot of it is going to be kind
of geared towards the farmers because
that's our general audience but
but there's so much that you can pick up
on
you know not everything would make sense
sometimes like say you're not
you know you're just getting exposed to
agriculture or something like that but
but you can pick things up i mean when i
started my job here at ndsu nine years
ago i didn't know
a combine from a tractor um i had never
really set foot on a farm
and so i'm always kind of keeping that
in mind that there's a lot of people
like me that want to learn about
agriculture
and maybe don't have the chance to but
if you're listening to episodes on
farmers and their stories and how
they're
working with neighbors to achieve these
practices or you're learning from some
of the researchers
or the extension people you know we're
pretty
good at trying to share these messages
in different ways for different
audiences so
um so yeah i would encourage anyone to
hop onto these events and
i usually try to keep them fun and
entertaining because there also has to
be that kind of element to
it can't just be all a bunch of eggheads
you know talking about
soil nerd talk and whatever so we try to
keep them fun and entertaining and
um and you know what if most of them are
free so if you get onto the event and
you're like
uh that's not what i thought it would be
you can always just get off and it cost
you nothing so
so that's kind of the other good thing
about it too is a lot of flexibility
yeah i'm looking at some of the topics
here on your on your soil health page
and you have one on uh
you know a quick video on incorporating
cover crops
building soil health grazing cover crops
there's a lot of really great
topics on here so i highly suggest
folks check it out can you talk a little
bit about what extension services offer
for people in various states and sort of
what
what that really is for for folks
yeah i sure can because i had no idea
what extension was until i got my job
here
so um so yeah i mean extension is
usually it's a branch of the land-grant
institutions right so
ndsu is a land-grant institution here
like ohio state would be for ohio
um colorado state university for
colorado
and so so there's a branch of the
university that gets information
out to farmers but also to the public
and our job is to it's to not
necessarily do the research but to use
our colleagues who are doing the
research to get that information
pre repackaged and into a format where
it can be used and so
so any of those land-grant institutions
have this extension branch
and oftentimes you know extension is you
know there's certainly a
main campus presence so there's faculty
that do this kind of stuff but
like in north dakota we have county
agents that are in every single county
and so they they go out they interact
with farmers with
gardeners with kids in 4-h
and just general the general public and
and they're providing information all
the time too so if you
if you live in a state where you have
you know county extension you can sure
give them a call and you know find out
what they have to offer i mean
it could even be that you have a disease
on your trees
and you need to know what it is or a
pest or something like that and you can
send a sample into your extension office
and they can tell you what it is and how
to manage it so
it's really it's a really diverse
organization because it
it also you know there's stuff in
agriculture but then there's all kinds
of stuff
in in community as well and
building leadership skills at the
community level or
you know food preparation even for
canning and how do you do that
keep yourself safe skin cancer i mean
there's there's all kinds of resources
available through extension so
um so i i really value this part of the
universities i think it's a great way
for them to interact better with the
community and with
with other people and um and to just get
get the information
out from this you know these kind of
ivory tower campuses it's
we got to get this information out
somehow so that's what extension does
so it's sort of that bridging the gap
between
infield farming and and then academic
research
i guess is is what i'm hearing yeah
yeah we're kind of the you know if you
look at the campus and the faculty on
campus too
we're kind of the extroverts and then
you have the introverts that are the
researchers so
so we're the ones that like to be out
chatting and whatever about stuff
and getting to know people and and
sharing some of that information
so um yeah that's definitely that's
definitely how it works there's there's
stuff
you know different faculty for different
different jobs here for sure
so since this podcast is generally
speaking to people who are growing
you know cannabis or hemp what sort of
resources
or relationships might someone be able
to form with a county extension
in that regard because i realize like in
your case you guys don't have a lot of
hemp growers in
in north dakota i think i think you had
said
but where do you think you might still
be able to plug in and help someone if
they were
if they reached out oh gosh you know
yeah we don't have a ton of hunt
production up here
um but you know the other thing with
extension with the university is that
we're great
for connecting people and so you know
for example if i don't know anything
about hemp right and i have a farmer
that wants to grow it
i know at least a consultant and then
also a researcher on campus that
that works with hemp or i also know
somebody that was
an agronomist that was you know
taking on cbd you know hemp for cbd
production which i know very little
about but i know
those people and i know how to reach
them and so um
so oftentimes you know if the extension
person doesn't have the answer on a
specific thing they can certainly find
someone who does and that's kind of what
they what we specialize in is our
our contact list and our cell phones and
who we can call to help you get the
answers you need
and i would add that you you know soils
really well and you know a variety of
crops
in different soils that might you know
respond similar to hemp and you know
i think you could also probably make a
cover crop recommendation
to at least get someone started in the
right direction or at least what to
avoid as a cover crop based on your
experience so i think there's a lot
there that
you may be able to offer someone
to at least get them pointed in the
right direction as research grows on
you know this relatively new crop
yeah i absolutely and i think you know i
love learning about new crops too and
kind of problem solving so
that's certainly an area where we can
help and i mean she was just at a
vineyard the other day
and they want to do cover crops between
the vines and i was like i don't know
anything about vineyards other than i
like to drink wine
so just like you know how am i going to
make a recommendation but i can sure
listen to the issues and when
they need something to flower or not
flower or attract pollinators or you
know i mean
and then we can kind of come up with
some solutions together so i would think
you know it's the same deal with hemp
and what can we
how can we help manage even the residue
on hemp um
because i understand it's pretty tough
right so it's you know how are you
managing that and
you know what's your rotation look like
or um yeah i think there's all kinds of
ways that we can help and and
in general when you want to learn about
something or you're curious
uh you seem to find the answer somehow
yeah and i think you're vineyard
comment was really interesting because i
know when i visited some vineyards and
got to speak to
the um the people in charge of of the
soil and the fertility
there i learned a lot from them on how
they manage
grapes that's so different than other
crops but then also coming with an
outside perspective i had all these
things i kind of wanted to try
or at least look into as someone who
didn't come
you know traditionally trained in in
viticulture which
you know i think it allows for sort of a
synergy of ideas
and uh and things like that too as we
talk about different
different systems and different crops oh
absolutely that's pretty cool
yeah i'm sure you brought a lot to the
table just you know
i i you know i don't think i did in this
case but it definitely got my brain
thinking like oh
gee i'd love to i'd love to try this or
experiment with this or
you know really dive in further and
learn and and see if there were things
that we could
you know that we were trying in other
crops that might make sense with this
crop or you know vice versa
so yeah absolutely
well cool well i really appreciate your
time today i had a lot of fun chatting
with you and i hope folks do
uh check out some of these things i mean
i'm looking at your
uh soil sense page here you know you
have soil health on the farm how to dial
in fertility
precision of soil health stuff on
dealing with salts
building soil and cool and wet climates
like just so many great topics
and it's free so i highly suggest people
take a look oh thank you for
for that i appreciate it uh well thanks
for your time today and
i i look forward to chatting in the
future and have a wonderful rest of the
day
all right thank you
that was dr abby wick and you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast
i'm your host tadd hussey of kiss
organics don't forget to check out the
podcast page at www.kisorganics.com
for links to the websites and topics we
covered in today's podcast
just click on the learn tab then podcast
also if you haven't already please take
a moment and leave us a comment or
review on whatever platform you listen
on
i do take the time to read them all and
appreciate the feedback you can also
follow us on instagram at kis
organics to stay up to date on the
latest podcast releases and information
thanks for listening
you