[Music]
so
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host
tad hussey of kiss organics this is the
podcast where we discuss the cutting
edge of growing from a science-based
perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge
this week's podcast is a bit different
though it's not a podcast on cultivation
right now we are facing unprecedented
times here in the united states and
around the world
many people are suffering either from
economic hardship or the racial
injustice that's bubbled up over the
past couple of months sparked by police
brutality
now i'm not here to tell folks what to
believe there's enough of that going
around these days
all i would suggest is that for those of
us who are fortunate enough to still
have jobs and making ends
meet it's a very good time to give back
to your community and there are a lot of
good causes out there
pick one that speaks to you and try to
give something back
along that vein kiss organics is going
to be contributing this year to the
flint unity farming project the founder
delma marshall is my guest this week and
i was excited to have him on the show to
share more about the organization that
he has founded
now on to the show hey delmond thanks
for coming on the show today
hey thanks for having me yeah i wanted
to start off can you tell me a little
bit about yourself
and then we'll talk a little bit more
about flint michigan and the unity
project but but tell me a little bit
about yourself first
okay well as for me uh i'm an
army brat uh child uh my dad was in the
service
his last uh post was michigan so
michigan became our home but we're
actually from
vicksburg mississippi and uh
jackson mississippi so and there we
had a farm so farming was just something
that
we were always around but far
away from so i'm a three-sport athlete
my dad was a tennis coach i played
tennis basketball football
uh and sports is made like part of
my my life and agriculture is like the
other side of it you know
yeah you know i was kind of the same way
i got really into sports in college
i played in college myself and then uh
it's funny because most people don't
associate
athleticism with agriculture they don't
typically go together i mean they're not
opposed but it is a funny that there is
that sort of
gap there between where our food comes
from and people that are really
interested in exercise and nutrition
right and it seems like they would go
together but
no oddly not so with at with uh
athletes their optimal thing is what
what they're eating in order to enhance
their performance so if you're in
agriculture you're growing what a person
would be eating so
it's pretty much along those same same
lines like they
go together so our pro program
our youth gardening and fitness program
is to do just that is to teach kids how
to eat properly
and then exercise to fight uh child
obesity because uh the overweight
problem is one of the biggest things
in the united states with kids and so we
want to teach them how to be
responsible with their weight and with
fitness at an early age
yeah now you started the flint unity
farming project and i want to talk about
that but before we do can you
give listeners a little background into
i mean the flint michigan so
most people have heard of the water
crisis in michigan and i'd like to if
you could just
kind of uh give an overview of what that
is but then also tell us what it's like
in flint
also you know through the the water
crisis and even now as you guys are
still battling that
um can you talk a little bit about the
about the water crisis
oh yeah well definitely well uh flint
flint michigan
is uh probably one of the third
largest cities in the state of michigan
and
it's a lot of problems that come along
with it and
you know there's a communities of people
here i'm from
you know was raised here in michigan
and for whatever reason it is uh
you know bad things happen and that the
community itself needs needs help
flint used to be a haven for nba
players uh nfl players like back in the
early 80s
90s with glenn rice and andre rising
and it seemed like since those star
people left
the city is is still here and it's in
uh shambles like it's in economic
shambles i don't know who's to
you know who's who's supposed to blame
for
what what happened but there's still
people here
and and everything is bad like the
school system is bad they don't have
enough money to keep the schools open
like it's just a real like
messed up uh situation but you still
have people who do not have enough money
to
move away that's here and then those are
the people that we're
trying to help the ones that here trying
to inspire them
through the bad uh basically
eight years of uh slim water crisis
so take me back to the to it started
what in april of 2014
uh flint changed they began drawing
water directly from the flint river
for the hundred thousand residents there
instead of water coming from detroit
and uh residents started complaining of
the water changing in smell and taste
and they were reporting rashes and hair
loss
uh what was that like uh back in 2014
what happened when it all
started it was bad like i mean i i can't
think of any other term to use it except
bad and then again you have people who
have no other
ways of getting uh water
or clean clean water because it was
through the whole
city through the whole pipes uh
and so it was it put people like
you would have to have lived through it
in order to have seen it
in order to to know how bad it has has
been when you have kids who
can't drink water out of their faucet
they can't
bathe with water that's running through
the pipes and
we're five years in now and
it still hasn't been cured yet you know
like it still hasn't been
fixed yet for the city on other holes so
it was i it it pains me
to think about you know like some of the
the things that i saw like from you from
working the slingy new farming project
i used to bring water in the jugs
and arizona jugs to feed our plants
in flint because we can't use the water
in flint because the water was painted
so i used to bring water to feed the
plants and then bring water for some of
the family kids of our
uh kids that was in our pro program so
just imagine that water like you you
would think
clean water is something that everyone
has
flint michigan hasn't had it for six
years now
yeah i mean it seems like a universal
human right it's something that
i've always taken for granted here in
the pacific northwest we have
really amazing water and i've been very
fortunate
and it sounds like from from reading
articles on this to refresh my memory
that
the water in the river was so caustic it
actually uh stripped the lead
out of the old plumbing systems and
caused very high lead levels
which doctors were seeing in the blood
of children you know five
ten times higher than what uh was known
to be
safe uh based on the uh
on the levels so so people were being
forced to
shower and use these and then try and
find other things to drink or find clean
water
to drink and you know getting back to
your nutrition thing
this is speculation on my part but was
there a lot more people than drinking
soda
and arizona teas and a lot of these
other really cheap
um yet unhealthy uh beverages
oh yes definitely because you have to
find something to
to drink because it's it's very
unnatural to
try to go without drinking water you
know like from a natural source like you
automatically think you come to the sink
and get it
but in flint you had to learn different
ways of
of drinking or of getting water because
clean water wasn't uh
accessible to you and so people pick up
and started
drinking cokes or drinking sodas or 99
drinks since they like that was their
water
which i assume contributed to obesity
and diabetes and a lot of these other
challenges
so this inspired you to start the flint
unity farming project
and i don't know how i found out about
you i think it was through instagram
i i think you've started following me
and then i went and checked it out
and uh you know you're posting a lot of
photos i highly suggest people go
uh you know give them give them a follow
and check out the flint unity
farming project can you tell me a little
bit about what that project is and how
you got it started
oh yeah definitely uh the flint unity
fireman project
is a army inspired youth gardening
and uh program as i uh said uh
this was the idea of my dad my dad was
in the service
he was in germany back in 65
and he was working and he had a vision
of a gardening school
and so he wrote some notes down about it
and
he came back you know was
in the service and then he got out the
service and then he became a
school teacher and so this garden thing
was always something that
he did because we used to garden around
the house like
i couldn't play the atari video game
unless i had logged in three hours of
guarding time with him
outside so if anyone remember the atari
video games the 2600
pole position all of that i just
couldn't play it until i got tired i
actually had to work
doing out agriculture to earn credits in
order to play the video game because my
dad was just dead set on you need to
know what my life was like
growing up so that's where the
agriculture came in so
december uh christmas uh december of 201
15 my dad we were at mclaren uh
hospital he was in hospital and he said
damn do you remember i
talked to you about that garden class
well i want you to try to start it now
and i don't want you to quit and i want
you to see how hard it's gonna be
to set up things and so from
my dad and i talking in the hospital
that's how the flint unity farming
project actually uh
started i gave it a name we wrote down
the core things that that we wanted to
accomplish with it
and it was actually a business uh side
to us so
it was big so when we wrote it up it was
actually
for us to get everything that we needed
so far as buying the trucks
and getting everything like on a big
scale it was
close to 750 000 like the starting in
order to get everything for us to have
it started
we knew no one was going to give us that
so what i did was i scaled everything
back uh to where we don't even have a
building but to where we would be able
to teach
kids and so that's the uh business
model that we moved out on and so
that's how we got us started so today we
have been able to teach
upwards over uh over 350 children
free of charge and we're just hoping to
con
continue we just need the resources in
order to be able to do it
because my brother also a military
veteran
army he and i run the pro program
together but i'm the more vocal focused
uh one in it
and he just comes in and work and then
leave so
yeah we're that's basically our pro
program
of teaching kids how to be able to grow
vegetables to help offset their exposure
from the
flint water crisis and then for them to
just learn how to be able to eat and be
healthy
yeah now when we were talking before you
had mentioned how
the there was quite an outpouring of
interest in the community when
people found out about your program can
you tell me about
uh sort of what that what that was like
um i i know you did some you know you
put up some ads and stuff initially for
it
but you got a really good turnout you
said and then what what did you teach
the kids what were some of the focuses
around
the program when everyone was showing up
well well for our uh gardening pro
program
what the basis was to teach kids where
uh plant life what is plant life and
then how to
grow vegetables so i kept it elementary
so far as
how to what vegetables that that we grew
because
uh i taught them how to grow tomatoes
and how to grow i'm trying to remember
the
herbs but i thought chives and something
else that was known
to if you eat it it can all offset a
lead
in in your your body so i basically
taught them how to grow
basic vegetables and then how they could
grow
other uh things and so i kept it in a
one like like a abc
format and i tried to give them
something to take home
uh the summer class was for eight weeks
so i tried to have them with something
that they could take home every week
and keep growing and then they could
take pictures for the kids to have
phones to let me see them or
and so that was basically my teaching uh
method was just teaching kids the basics
of how to
uh in npk level like i teach them
in npk and i tell them like a simple way
of knowing what that means
is up down and all around so
so i'm basically teaching them uh
gardening
but just doing it in such a way to where
they can understand
what they are doing yeah and you
mentioned that a lot of the kids
are were setting up gardens at their
house or even in the
abandoned lots or houses oh yes yes
yes it's a lot of uh abandoned houses
around so a lot of the plants that i
gave
kids they took them home and planted it
either on their
uh yard in their backyard or it's
hundreds of vacant uh homes like there's
a house then there's five vacant homes
and then there's a house so
they could easily go and plant a
vegetable in a vacant lot
and let it grow and that was another
part of our program was to beautify the
city of flint but of course that fell on
deaf ears
no no one was really concerned about
beautifying flint
but that was another thing that we
wanted to gear the kids up to where
to not only feel good about yourself but
feel good
about the community which you are from
and do things to better it
you know and you had mentioned that
uh a lot of the kids didn't know about
vegetables
oh yes yeah oh yeah
i mean and it's just funny because if
you don't know if you're not exposed to
it you don't don't know
uh i was at uh the amazing grace church
i was speaking at a church
and i just happened to ask the kids uh
where the vegetables come from and they
said
not even trying to be funny walmart it
comes from
walmart it comes from myers and i'm like
no
it where where does it come from and
they
stuck at the store not even
understanding that
green vegetables green uh peppers come
from the ground that you can grow on
from the ground they didn't even make
that connection
and so it's good that our program was
able to help kids make that connection
that
you can grow your own food like it's
something that they don't even
think think man about you know and
living in this computer age
everyone is basically thinking in the
com computer mind
mind frame as opposed to what they can
actually do
for them themselves you know and it just
takes hard work
to to do it that's the other thing
gardening is not easy
it's a delayed satisfaction thing but if
you can learn how to space it out
and do it then you will be better off
and once you learn how to do it
then you will always be able to to do it
so you could always provide
food if you put in the word
yeah what are your goals for the future
with the flint unity farming project
oh the the goals is vast for what it is
that i want uh
to to do we want to basically get our
program
uh sponsored or partnered with the
nfl uh the nba
and uh mbbl with the base
base baseball we would want to have
flint unique farming projects in
every city possible and you and i spoke
about before
i had a friend that was out in seattle
and we were supposed to try to get one
set up in
seattle when he was there but he got
traded uh traded to another team
so we weren't able to get that set up
but
the ultimate goal long term is to have
this set up
in 32 cities and have kids learning
uh gardening and learning fitness sports
training because
i want to tease them tennis you know so
tennis is gonna be a part of our
pro program uh i used to play tennis i
actually played
semi-pro tennis a couple years man ago
and my highest finish was third
uh i'm old like i'm old now i'm cool
with
coaching but i want to teach kids how to
be able to play tennis how to
uh baseball you know basketball and also
how to eat
in order to uh be more
better of a player and be in better
health
well i think that sounds like a very
ambitious but worthy goal
and i i hope you're successful in this
and
for our part with uh kiss organics
i'm gonna send you a pallet of material
from us
uh we're shutting down our garden center
here and so i have a lot of extra
gardening tools and
and supplies so i'll uh i'll be sending
that your way
as a you know sort of appreciation for
what you're doing from us
but um before we sign off i had a couple
more quick questions for you
okay what's your favorite vegetable to
grow by chance
do you have a favorite actually my
favorite vegetable
to grow has been the uh pale
peppers because i cook with them
so so much i use them in uh like a lot
of the things
that that i make bell peppers is my
favorite thing
to grow you must get some hot weather
out there
because uh they're a lot tougher to grow
here in seattle
i mean no and they're actually tough to
grow grow here too because it doesn't
get that uh
that that warm in in order for them but
i
try try try my best to
i try try try my best to grow the uh
green the organic green bell bell
peppers
and i've been having a uh six success
with them
and they taste meant wonderful like you
know because i i grow a lot of stuff
that i don't even eat you know like i
grow
straw strawberries i am allergic to them
but the grandkids love them
so i gotta make a strawberry patch you
know for
for them yeah that's great yeah
in our family uh my my father always
plants a garden that's way too large for
us because
it's his favorite thing to go out in the
community and share with neighbors
fresh vegetables right that's that's his
way of connecting with people and his
way of sort of giving back
um and it gives him a lot of a lot of
joy
yeah and that and that's our thing
at the the three years that we've been
able to run our pro
program the vegetables that we grow i
give them to the kids and to the
families of the kids that's in our
pro program and then any of the other
ones i normally
give them away to people or sell sell
them to people in order for us to be
able to have
resources to do something else but yeah
the
giving of the community knowing that
you're
helping someone giving someone substance
giving you know food like
there's not any thing to to me i think
that's better
you know then doing that for someone
especially in this
you know today's climate and time you
know it it shows
it's giving compassion to humans and and
it almost seemed like that's like a lost
part of actually
caring about someone like now it's
you just hit like on something and then
that's justification
or that's uh oh well i i haven't done
enough i didn't hit like up on your post
but it's actually you're doing something
to help a another person i i think it's
life changing
i'm so glad man my dad talked talked to
me
and asked me to do this i don't know
what to do with myself you know
that's that's great i love that it's uh
it was inspired by your father
i think that's really cool that you have
that family part to it
one other last question i have for you
is uh
when you and i were talking you
mentioned you also have a role in the
cannabis industry
uh did you want to mention that for the
listeners oh oh yeah definitely yes uh
is uh area 72 botanicals on
uh instagram like that's my other job i
do
work in a cannabis industry and i've
started a
a peanut butter uh brand
uh business uh in
uh cannabis and i've been running it you
know for the past
a year and a half now and i see that
there could be some great things done
uh you know with it as again as funds
come to get everything
set up yeah i see great great things
coming along with it but uh
i started working uh growing
cannabis for uh this dispensary uh
five years ago so that's how i learned
about
the nutrient uh growing
you know from that that job
well that's great that's great well i
thank you so much for your time today
and appreciate what you're doing for
your community
and i just want to say thank thank you
so much
thank you hey i thank thank you for
having me and
please anyone with any questions any
suggestions please give us a follow
on instagram at flingynityfarming
project
or for cannabis at a72 botanicals on
instagram
that's me
that was delmar marshall with the flint
unity farming project and you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast i'm your host
tad hussey you can check them out on
instagram at flintunityfarmingproject
or through the links on our podcast page
thanks for listening
you