foreign
[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad Hussey
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge my guest this week is Dr
Carrie Peters she's the vice president
at J.R Peters and the formulator of all
products and development of new
fertilizer formulas that provide crop
specific solutions to Growers
nutritional issues she has too many
honors and accolades to list here but I
will put them up on the podcast page
Carrie has a PHD in plant sciences and a
Masters of Science and Agronomy from the
University of Maryland as well as a
Bachelor's of Science and biology she's
the third generation of Peters in the
family business which was founded over
72 years ago now on to the show
hey Carrie thanks for coming on the show
today
hi thanks for having me Tad
yeah I know you've been on before
talking about J.R Peters and Jack's
fertilizer and some of the you know
formulation process uh today I wanted to
talk to you more about uh testing in lab
analysis so tell me a little bit about
about your lab that you have over at Jax
oh yeah well one of the things that I
feel super lucky to be able to have here
in Allentown where we make our
fertilizer is actually the lab on site
so like you know like I was saying you
need to come visit but people that have
been there they always kind of say like
wow this is unbelievable like in the
middle of offices is this laboratory and
it really is like the backbone of what
we do
um to manufacture fertilizer obviously
to make sure we are are making what we
think we are but also to get like really
data driven information to Growers out
there like any Growers not just Growers
using Jacks but like people that are
interested to see how their plants are
doing and how to improve and optimize
their their crop health and yield so
really depending on the crop that
they're growing but it's a pretty neat
facility it's like smack dab in the
middle of the offices and Manufacturing
and we just completed a renovation so
the company was formed in 1947 I know
you knew that from before but our
facility was built in 78 so the lab was
like a
monster-sized tribute to the 70s Chic
you know
so this renovation this renovation kind
of took us into the next well the 21st
century for sure in the way of appeal
but we had all these state-of-the-art
equipment and it looked like a 70s
throwback
so this new renovation has allowed us to
like utilize space better and really be
able to
increase the throughput of the amount of
samples that we do every day here at Jr
Peters it's kind of like Groundhog Day
our results are out in 24 to 48 hours
and then you repeat that over and over
again for tissue testing water testing
media fertilizers of course and pretty
much anything nutrient nutrient
concentration
yeah
so I want to I want to dive into that
um much deeper but before we do
something that you and I talked about uh
in previous off-air conversations was
the amount of testing that goes into
your products and because
um part of our conversation was about
how you know when you get a label made
you have a guaranteed analysis and so if
you're guaranteeing five percent
nitrogen you have to be above five
percent right and and you were saying
within a certain range of that too right
um in theory especially on the chemical
side so
um
and also that all your inputs are free
and clean of heavy metals
yes
I'm guessing
chemical nutrient companies have Labs
um what what have you guys found over
the years in terms of consistency in
order to maintain consistency what does
that look like
yeah I mean that's a great question and
I always wonder to myself like
do people know what kind of
qualifications their company their their
nutrient companies or anything in life
you know like anything we put into our
bodies what kind of testing goes on
there
um for our products having the lab on
site is awesome because people always
ask can you send me a certificate of
analysis for your finished Blends and
I'm like can do because that's what
everybody thinks that they need which is
super true you definitely do but more
important than that we
do a lot of qaqc at at the step before
that so because we have so many
different raw materials and make so many
different blends for ourselves and for
others we look at the raw materials as
inputs so as soon as they're brought
into the facility they go through a like
Suite of tests one being as easy as is
it clear and soluble I mean that sounds
silly but like you do that two seconds
later if it's cloudy you don't have to
do anything else you know you just like
reject that lot
but so we look at each individual raw
material before it gets housed with the
rest of them because we have some
large-scale containment facilities you
know and if you put in if it's going to
hold you know fifteen thousand pounds of
something and you put in 2 000 pounds of
a lot that isn't wonderful or within
spec then you've just contaminated the
rest of your material so we take it to
the step where we're doing these qaqcs
at the beginning stage so then you know
when it's Blended we know a hundred
percent that it's going to come in Spec
in regards to heavy metal
calculation and additive value of all
the different raw materials for for the
end formula certificate of analysis but
if we didn't have that on site
I don't know what you do I guess you
just like pray that the it is what it is
you know the paperwork says it should be
this and you can't always go by that
yeah I think that's a good point so
I I mean it makes me wonder as a grower
who's using
you know mineral salts what questions
should I be asking my manufacturer to
assure that what I'm getting is a
quality product inconsistent
yeah I mean the certificate of analysis
is the number one key I mean if that
needs to come in clean so that your
heavy metals are going to be within the
AFCO minimums the American Association
of plant control
plant food control officials gosh that's
what it is AFCO it needs to be within
their acceptable range so and you it's
listed in many different states you can
look up fertilizers and see to say I
hear people say things are heavy metal
free it's like almost impossible for
that you're gonna you always see some
sort of background noise by the time you
get to a blended a blended product so
that end product certificate of analysis
is super important the other questions
that I would ask would be like ask the
technical support people like what type
of grade material do you use because
like a good example is potassium nitrate
I mean potassium nitrate is a super
important nutrient that's used as a
source of nitrogen and potassium I mean
as a great source of mineral nutrients
for plant growth in all different types
of situations there are so many
different grades of that material like
um and it's it's under this umbrella of
technical or Greenhouse grade that's
what you should be looking for but even
within that there's like a B's and C's
of that that leads to
um you know heavy metal content and it
also leads to solubility and appearance
and that affects pH so you can even see
some variation in that so if you could
get some clarification from the
manufacturer on what grade of at least
the macronutrients that they're using I
would that would give me a big boost of
confidence as a grower I would think
cool I think it's not my world so I
don't really have a have any comments on
this but um no that's good to hear
because I know there are people that are
using mineral salts that listen to the
podcast and I want to make sure we're
not
just talking to organic Growers out
there or addressing the concerns of
organic Growers because
it's a science-based podcast
um
moving on though
the the main thing that I want to talk
to you about was these different methods
of testing specifically
tissue testing so I just did a podcast
I'm talking about soil testing with
Bryant Mason who's a wonderful
agronomist um and so we really we dove
into the Malik 3 the saturated Pace test
and talked about what information on
there and how that applies to soilless
Media but um
how does tissue testing play into this
and why did you guys go that route
well
as a company well the whole company
started as this lab and the lab was able
to give us connections to Growers and
when we saw the problems that Growers
had that's how my grandfather was able
to kind of figure out oh my gosh like I
can help them grow by bringing back
these blends of mineral
nutrients and this was back in the 1940s
right so a long time ago when when they
didn't even blend things together and
people were just like putting down
whatever they want and had no regard for
sustainability or or anything really I
was just like whatever
um
but so we kind of based our whole
philosophy and and company Philosophy on
this scientific approach and kind of
having that connection to data that the
plant can can show us so Mo it all
started in the beginning with soil
testing back in the day like true soils
with Malik 3 and all of that but as we
moved into a fertilizer company in the
70s that's when they they really did a
lot of the saturated paste extracts and
tried to understand the connection
between the nutrients that were
immediately available in the root Zone
and then the nutrients that were
concentrated in the plant tissues and
then taking that information and using
database decisions to formulate mineral
blends to kind of optimize plant growth
by forming these like nutrient targets
so you know like they were then they
were doing a lot of cut flowers so it
was like how do we make the best Cut
Flower so that it lasts longer and it
blooms longer and it it fulfills all of
the you know characteristics of this
Perfection of a Cut Flower and you know
through the years all the different
crops that we've worked with from
vegetative animal in annuals to like
just regular bedding plants to petunias
to Corn soybean cotton I mean you name
it we've tested it in the laboratory and
kind of it gave us like this full
picture of like what's going on in the
plant what's the root seeing and what
gets translocated into the plant tissue
is there always a correlation between
the saturated paste which is sort of
like what is in the media and
immediately available
and what is in the plant tissue and is
it the same across various crops is that
correlation the same across different
crops
yeah I mean it's useful to have
a database built where you can have
long-term data so because varieties
change and like the varieties like if
you take a poinsettia
um varieties from you know the 1940s to
something that you see today technically
it's still within the thing of
poinsettia but it is slightly different
according to these new traits that they
have been breeding for very much similar
to the things we're seeing in cannabis
you know you're you're dealing with the
idea of what the original species that
you you had back in the you know 30s 40s
50s to the things that are even coming
out you know each year here as we you
know Venture into this awesome
crop you get to see some of the
differences so
we've always been able to look at
correlations between saturated paste
because in in the view of our how we
build nutrient targets the saturated
paste extracts gives you a really
great like snapshot on what's
immediately available to the root Zone
it's like the nutrients
and and all of the great stuff that's in
the small and large pore spaces of the
of the root Zone and that's what's
immediately available to the roots so
just saying that that's what should be
able to be immediately taken up and
translocated in the young healthy root
tissue root tips root hairs immediately
into the plant up the xylem and should
be for a nice healthy functioning plant
translocated into the shoots the leaves
the growing tissues of the plant that
way so yeah we've always seen a
correlation between using that
information and concentration in leaf
tissue for for plant health
oh and I just want to add that watering
environment
transpiration all of these things are
going to affect how well those nutrients
are taken up but
um yeah that makes a lot of sense so so
I asked that question because I have
heard a couple of people say that tissue
testing doesn't correlate well with soil
testing and I I don't believe that to be
the case and sounds like what you're
saying is that's
there's actually a really strong
correlation there that we can
one of the things too though is maybe
people say that because you do have to
take into a consideration the timing so
what you're seeing immediately in the
in the soilless in in the root Zone you
know of the saturated paste
isn't going to be exactly what's in the
tissue right now there is like a time
delay so I know people like understand
that and they're like oh wait a second
so normally we do a tissue test
is what was in in the media like five to
seven days ago depending on the crop too
it depends on the crop and the stage and
all of that kind of stuff but there is
some sort of time delay that you have to
consider
okay can you give me a quick like 30
second one minute explanation of how
what the actual mechanical process is
associated with tissue testing like what
you're actually doing when you receive a
sample
yep so we do like total concentration
based on Leaf tissue so people send us
you know
they send us several different versions
of things like healthy tissue that
they're just trying to figure out what's
going on and then problematic stuff like
burnt deficiencies you name it you know
just like not healthy that they're like
holy cow what should I do
um they usually send that in as like a
like fresh tissue so it's wet
um in a paper bag or wrapped in towels
or something like that like paper towels
and then we dry it overnight
um that is dried at 80 80 degrees
Celsius kind of like a dehydrator type
thing you know what I mean just to get
it nice and crunchy and really get it
down all the water out and then we grind
that tissue
um into like it's not a true powder
but it's like a pretty pretty
um small kind of grind that's like 40
mesh goes through a 40 mesh screen and
then we weigh out a certain amount and
then it gets ashed overnight so that
ashing process really just removes the
carbon from the sample so so that's you
know the purpose of that and
um it gets ashed at for I think it's
like four hours at like 450 degrees
Celsius something super high it's done
overnight so this is why tissue testing
takes 48 hours because there is like the
first drying and then the overnight
drying and then that after that it gets
in our lab the process that we do is um
we digest it with a weak acid for 90
minutes so that breaks down some of the
you know stronger bonds and materials
even a little bit more into a solution
and then that gets filtered to remove
some of the bigger debris and stuff and
that sample gets run on the ICP
um which is super useful
um we have an Agilent ICP at our lab
here at Jax and
um that basically gives you within 80
Seconds a
um total nutrient concentration so it
doesn't give you nitrogen but it gives
you phosphorus potassium calcium
magnesium sulfur and all the micros
and also silica
um aluminum and sodium so and that's how
it's done
very cool and
so I'm seeing more people talking about
sap testing
can we talk about the differences
between
tissue testing and sap testing
and and why
why you have a preference towards tissue
testing am I using the right term there
do we want to call it tissue testing
that's what I've always heard yeah I
don't know that's what I that's what we
call it yeah tissue testing okay
if you aren't a plant person then people
get confused but if you are they know
what you're talking about like today
um yeah I see a lot of people like at at
our company we do tech support
um to utilize our products but also to
help Growers
um really get an idea of these nutrient
targets that they're trying to hit and
we run into some people that that take
into consideration sap analysis
um and
at this point you know we we always lean
towards our version of tissue testing
because we have such a strong
um background in knowledge on how it
relates to the nutrients in the root
Zone and to what's being held in the
plant tissue and how to relate that to
fertility
but you know you do see people
taking a look at sap analysis to try and
optimize plant nutrition
at a specific time in the plant's life
trying to understand can you know can
they predict the way nutrients are going
to move and is that going to help kind
of
allow the crop to hit its Optimum before
it's there tissue testing does have the
limitation like what we do is you're
kind of seeing things that already
happened you know so you can you can
make
really great inferences of knowledge on
the nutrition of your plant Health but
it's kind of like looking in the rear
view mirror and making choices for the
future from that in the way of plant sap
testing people are saying if you could
if you can get that information
correctly and consistency you might be
able to make some database decisions
right away
you know I I have yet to see that work
well in a in a successful cannabis
cultivation facility that that I've
worked with yet but you know I do hear a
lot of people are are starting to lean
that way
yeah so that so that the two main
concerns are one there isn't really an
existing database that would take in all
of the information that we would need
because it is just a snapshot and then I
guess there's three so then how do we
use that information to make a
data-driven decision moving forward
and then and then lastly I would think
we would have to test
quite frequently because that value is
constantly changing
yeah
yeah you would think so I mean the in
the cytosol which is the water inside
the cell the sap right that's what they
you want to try and get a an idea of
what that is plant cells are different
they have also
juice or water sap inside of the cell
wall
so in order to make good database
decisions I would think you really also
have to pay attention to how the
extraction procedure for the sap
analysis is too
because you really would not want to get
the the sap that's in the cell wall
because that's not movable
you know water of nutrients sugars all
the other great stuff in there that we
want to consider we really only want to
consider you know the the cytosol
um
and
it's hard to know how the labs do this
we actually look at looked at it several
times here at Jr Peters and you know the
the extraction process is something that
can be compromised very easily and then
then you have data but what is that data
going to give you you know it could be
misleading in that it's not
really giving you the right information
that you need to make a decision but
you're making a decision on it and is
that the decision going to be the right
one so it just hasn't been
it just hasn't been around long enough
to do some Perfection but I mean people
definitely argue this point with me all
the time
so I'm sure people will hear this and be
like Oh Carrie
So when you say cytosol is that
essentially the the cytoplasm is that
the same thing or is it something
different
okay
yes
it's the it's the water inside the cell
the water consisting of water nutrients
sugars organic acids I mean amino acids
there's even like remnants of enzymes in
there and those enzymes are the things
that catalyze those the reactions like
photosynthesis like there's a lot going
on in there besides just nutrients you
know it's like everything that makes the
cell go in liquid form
so so this is a question for I think
tissue testing or sap testing
um Mobile versus immobile nutrients
where are you sampling on the plant and
how does that impact your results
for either case where you sample on the
plants extremely important for what we
do in tissue testing we recommend
getting a the the leaf that's most
useful is one that is most recently
mature so when you're trying to see the
state of health current health of your
plant you want to recently mature tissue
so not the oldest one not the newest one
the one that's basically just reached
its maturity and that's what you're
looking for
um and then if you're having a problem
situation or you see like obvious
deficiency or something then you sample
from those parts but if you're just
really trying to get the like best
status of of your plant's Health it's
the recently mature tissue that exact
same
um thought process would apply to sap
testing
you could make an argument that if you
would take more of the tissue from the
newest leaves the Mary stems the flowers
you're going to get some
nutrient data that's showing movement
through the plants phloem which is a
different method than if you would take
it from older leaves or several
different leaves in the plant that is
mostly xylem Fed so like normally when
you bring
nutrients and water into the plant it
goes Roots xylem into leaves and then to
move it around the leaves it moves
through the phloem but
um you know not everything moves through
the phloem and that's when you get into
Mobile versus immobile elements but you
can tell both of them from Total tissue
testing and sap analysis
okay okay
um
great I so it's a lot of picturing there
is
well my brain was jumping around because
whenever I hear the word flow I'm now I
remember from my botany class that my
professor was like phloem equals food
and so I have that like equation stuff
yeah
fake equation but no what I was going to
ask about was I was picturing so
from like in like grower terms the
larger the most
that the fan Leaf that's like
highest to the top that's the same size
as your other fan leaves
um so it's fully mature so you're not
talking about the top of the plant we're
not talking about the bottom of the
plants somewhere kind of in the yep I'm
guessing middle to the upper third of
the plant that you get that like fully
mature Leaf is that yep that's like your
sweet spot yes yeah that that is
definitely your sweet spot for tissue
testing in cannabis
and that's where when you see some
ranges from places you'll see
if they don't kind of say okay this is
New Growth or old growth and they're
just giving you ranges it's always from
that typical area of the plant
regardless of the species or variety
okay so I'm I'm a grower I'm thinking
about tissue testing or just doing more
testing in general
how affordable is it and then how useful
is that data
like let's say
well I guess first tackle that first
question of affordability
yeah at what point does it make sense
so we you know we are a full production
Horticulture lab we get between
I mean December and January are one of
our slowest because the end of December
I think people are just enjoying life
with the holidays and then back at it in
January
um at that time we're getting like a
hundred samples a day but in the
the thick of it all like depending on
Seasons um but getting into like spring
you know typical spring will get up to
250 a day
um for us the sample is 46 dollars
um for each sample for tissue testing
and
um I always say and that price has gone
up over time like when I started I think
it was yeah I've been with my I've been
actually getting paid by my parents
since 2004.
but you know I've worked there forever
um but back then it was like 30.
and now it's 46 and um
but I remember saying like oh yeah it's
the best 46 dollars you're all you'll
ever spend to get your before you start
for like before you start growing a crop
is to do a media test just a saturated
paste to make sure your your cocoa or
um your living soil or any combination
of the things that you're trying to put
together is making sense and is hitting
what you want to and then we see this
with cocoa all the time I mean so many
people get burned with like cocoa that
isn't rinsed so you have a ton of
potassium and chloride in there
um but if you would do that 46 dollar
media test you'd figure that out in a
second super easy to remedy but you have
to remedy it if you put if you put um
your your clones in there they'll burn
up in a matter of hours
um so we always say like that 46 dollars
is the best crop insurance you'll ever
find the the thing with tissue testing
is you have to be ready to look at the
data I mean I and and I don't know I
guess I'm just one of those people like
let's just not
sample to collect data and never look at
it let's try and figure out a nutrient
Management program that has timed
testing to points where decisions need
to be made so you know for cannabis
obviously they're they're knowing what
you're starting with boom that's super
important but then taking some samples
at each stage of growth before you're
making any adjustments or changing your
watering practices or your environmental
conditions or your light levels take
some smart data points there so you can
see what you're starting see where the
plant is before you made that change and
then two weeks after that change so
really at the end of the day for people
that we are really helping establish
their own nutrient Target it might be
10 samples over the crop cycle
um
at the most and then when they have
their data kind of dialed in it can be
down to like four samples based on how
much effort they want to put into
looking at the data
um
so okay it's not overwhelming at 500.
yeah
all right I think because that at least
gives people an idea of the cost and
then so let's say I get a test result
back on my
tissue testing and and we discover that
it is low in pick your nutrient uh
so many things potassium yeah let's say
potassium
um just because that's a fairly easy one
from the organic side so let's say your
your tissue shows low in potassium what
do you what do you do and how do I know
it's low in potassium like when I get
that result back from you is it gonna
have some
targets or or what does that look like
yeah I mean I don't know if every lab
does our lab has normal ranges
um that we provide and that's based on
rolling data that we collect here from
the samples that are sent in that we do
data based kind of analysis over time
um
and yeah it'll say oh this is outside
the normal limit or it's low or we have
a tech support team so people normally
when they get their result they'll give
us a ring and be like hey do you want to
talk about my results
and we say yes that's what we do and
then one of our tech support team you
know basically talks it through like
okay why this is low why is that is it
something I should be concerned about we
spend a lot of time which I'm sure you
do Tad too because this is what it's all
about is looking at ratios like is this
balanced if I make a change in a
potassium source to increase potassium
is that going to throw something off
that I don't want it to so it's a
conversation
um just getting the results and looking
at them and going oh yeah I'm not sure
what does that mean then you just
totally wasted your time and money
pretty much you know you have to be able
to look at it and say
all right this because of this I choose
to do this we see it a lot with people
that have problems too it's like
they'll and this is more like we'll take
a
um I don't know a petunia grower growing
like a billion Flats of Petunias right
and they're coming back yellow
so the grower will send all our things
and then I get the tests back and and we
say okay let's help and maybe it's you
know the pH is too high so it's iron
deficient and that's why they're pale in
the new growth so I'll talk to the
grower and go okay well this is what we
see and then they'll go oh man
well I already leeched
and I already did this and I already did
that so again you missed the opportunity
to make a database decision and you
already did things to switch the switch
the scenario
so it's hard it's you know especially
with a high value crop of cannabis it's
like the last thing you want to do is be
like let's see something starting and
then have to wait so choosing a lab that
can get you the results quick is is very
important for your sanity and your
non-gray hairs but also being able to
utilize the data and go oh my gosh okay
so I would have never expected this
result how do I fix it and having
someone to sit talk it through with you
and make some recommendations is is
really the key
and you don't have to pay a consultant
to do that like people should do this
for you that make products I know you do
and I know we do and I know a lot of
other companies out there do too and
that's what the cool thing about being
in cultivation of any plant is we're all
here to work together and sometimes that
doesn't happen and there's more like
competition and this and that and the
other when in reality growing plants
should be a community of love
[Laughter]
I love the idea about it I don't know
that it works out that way in practice
but I love the idea it doesn't always
yes
but yes I like you I love it when people
reach out because we want to work with
them and I want to know before they do
applications of things because the
hardest thing like you said is when they
see a problem
you talk about the problem and then you
find out they already done everything
because because when I when I see a
problem the first thing I want to do is
reduce the number of variables in my
garden because then it allows me to
figure out what that mechanism is that's
causing the problem and like when we
were talking about potassium back there
my first thought was oh it's low
potassium well maybe we have a watering
issue that's leeching out more potassium
than we want out of that soil so
that conversation I think can be really
helpful and we're not testing just for
the sake of testing like we want to make
sure that that testing is productive and
allows us to make a data-driven decision
like you said in our garden ultimately
because that's the whole reason we test
and not everyone can afford to test you
know if if you have a small garden of 10
plants five plants or a vegetable garden
for example it may not be practical to
do a bunch of tissue testing
um no so there's other there's other
tools visual tools that we'll use in
that case or maybe you know you have a
you have a pH meter a good pH meter or a
way to test your EC so there's other
other forms of testing that don't
involve lab analysis that's not going to
give you
the same Precision of information but at
least they're all tools that we can use
I guess as a gardener
oh yeah and I feel like if you don't if
you discount any of that the visual
Factor the environmental Factor the the
whole picture you're really selling
yourself short on how to grow an Optimum
plant I mean I think of this all the
time like now that I have um I use Waze
on my phone you know that like that you
know to get around ways
um like Google Maps or whatever when I
drive around I'm telling you if that app
ever doesn't work I cannot figure out
how to go anywhere and I used to be able
to be really good at being like okay I
make a left over by that church you know
and go back this way and know the
landscape and I kind of think of that
all the time when I look at people that
really dive into so much
um specific nutrient information and and
don't take into account the whole system
as a whole and how it works together so
I do feel like tissue media water
nutrient testing as a whole is really
useful but if you're not really plugged
into your whole growing environment and
everything together it's not going to
work into helping you grow your Optimum
plan it just isn't it's it's all kind of
pieces to a puzzle
I I say this every podcast and I'm just
gonna say it again so maybe it'll just
get drilled in everyone's head the the
way to approach a garden or a plant is
to look at what as a detective what's
the limiting factor of growth and
everyone blames the nutrients as you
know they blame the media they blame the
soil but if you're if your light levels
are 500 ppfd in flour it's probably not
your nutrient program that's causing
your problem you know if your VPD is way
off uh as as Nadia will tell us then it
doesn't really matter because your plant
can't translocate that calcium that it
may need effectively if you have a
massive pest issue as Suzanne talks
about
um those things can all of these things
can create plant stress and manifest as
nutrient deficiencies or toxicities so
you really do have to be a detective and
I can't tell you how many conversations
I've had with commercial cultivators
where we talk about their grow and they
've not intentionally but they'll omit
information they'll forget things that
happened oh yeah our gardener applied
this or oh yeah we've also had a massive
spider mite infestation like and these
sorts of things are important data
points to be aware of when we're really
trying to look at the plant holistically
like you talked about
yeah at Jax I mean the people that do
tech support are tech support team
people that were here and people that
were here in the past and moved on to
other positions they always say that the
most fun is talking to people and being
that little sleuth you know trying to
figure out like
what could be the issue or how can we
tweak this just a little bit to hit it
perfectly and it's a lot of fun
um and the background and people ask all
the time like how do you get into
knowing this type of stuff I mean I got
my PhD and well my Master's in soil
science so I learned Agronomy you know
from that side of it and then went into
Plant Nutrition but you know you really
just have to have like a love for like
science and there's a lot of chemistry
involved but a lot of it's investigative
reporting so we need more of these
inquisitive Minds to join tech support
for people because
um it's it's fun and there is a huge
need for knowledgeable individuals that
aren't out there to like
make a buck for themselves and just help
you know and that's that's what we're
about here at Jax even though we do make
a lot of fertilizer
yeah and I think that's why
um you can't really diagnose a problem
from a photo
um yeah it's a deeper conversation
obviously it's better if it's you know
accompanied by some some test results uh
but we need that holistic picture to
really make a determination what's going
on with that plant
um these people that you know and I do
this on my Instagram I'll post photos I
I hope people
but more just a way to get your brain
thinking about like what could be a
possible
source of this rather than what the
definitive answer is I guess so yeah I I
enjoy it you know I think it's it's it's
fun it all started with one with wind
burn that uh Nadia explained related to
transpiration and calcium movement which
I thought was a really fascinating
plant physiology answer
um
so yeah that's been a fun thing but it's
not really a diagnostic tool so that's
where testing comes in and uh for our
company because tissue testing
traditionally hasn't been available to
the Cannabis Community we've done a lot
of our recommendations based off of the
saturated paste and the Malik 3 and
we've had good success with that I love
the idea though of adding in tissue
testing where where people can do that
and I think there's a lot that I'm
excited to learn around that side of
things too
yeah and it's really useful that
universities have been able to you know
do what they are able to do now in in
their research settings which isn't
always like 100 applicable to like
actual like each Growers is different
but still being able to publish these
studies that have been you know repeated
and validated it's going to be really
really good for the community to be able
to get true
um verified data so every single year
you see all these researchers coming out
with fabulous things and I'm just blown
away with the science behind it so
that's it's gonna every like I said it's
just getting better and better
yeah so when we talk about tissue
testing how much you know you said
you're giving a range how much
variability based on genetics within
cannabis do you see on these tissue
tests because I think that's another
thing that we should probably talk about
a little bit
yeah that information for us is hard
because we don't always have
like when we talk about customers
sending in samples to us we don't
have the information specific to that
unless we're setting up research trials
that we're collecting that information
you know what I mean so if a if a grower
just wants to get data for themselves
they're going to be calling their sample
names whatever it is and we won't have
any idea
what it is or what genetics or
much besides you know lumping it into
this General thing of cannabis so
um yeah it's hard it's hard to make
comments on the variability because we
really
can only do what we do with the samples
that we get here at Jr Peters
so as a grower
I'm just thinking out loud here we
probably wanted
to dial in some of our cultivars over
time like as we take these data points
and say this is a this is the this is
the reason we test with healthy plants
is so if we have like a Target then we
can say this plant is just vigorous it's
healthy it yielded really well we'll
call this my target for this particular
cultivar and then we try and replicate
that essentially close to that Target
that's what we do approach it yeah
that's what we do with Growers so
they'll you know they have their
phenotypes that they're trying to figure
out and then they're like
um varieties that are just like their
number ones so we'll dial in that to
you know try and establish nutrient
targets to hit
um and the variability when we do
something like that still can be
a lot like
I mean I was just working with a grower
I can't even remember like I don't even
know if I should say that what it is but
hey um
the calcium concentration over time was
so variable and I've seen this quite a
bit in in cannabis that there's been
many many situations of like almost like
hyper accumulation of calcium in the
leaf tissue which is just like
unbelievable because you don't expect
that but even within like targeted and
many many crop cycles of of repetition
we still see variability from for these
secondary nutrients most NP and K are
pretty consistent from what I've seen
micronutrients they're less variable but
they still can vary slightly but it's in
the secondary nutrients calcium
magnesium and sulfur that we see the
most like swings Within These data
points
um
and again it's just watching it over
time because these are healthy plants
that are hitting their yields and
hitting every single thing they want to
do and the grower is just trying to
figure out how to repeat that again you
know
okay so you see variability in healthy
tissue too yep oh yeah interesting
so so that makes me competition just
like sorry one little aside to that that
makes me think like when I work with
Growers that are like I would like to
hit magnesium in solution at
23.75 parts per million I'm like well
you really don't have to do that let's
do between 20 and 25 and you're good you
know
um you know because
yeah
sorry I didn't mean to cut you off
no no that's good that's good uh I had
one last tissue testing question before
moving on to another topic here and that
was getting back to that hypothetical of
that tissue test that showed low
potassium
how do we approach that in a organic
versus a hybrid versus uh mineral salt
program
because that I I assume they would be
different because in my head I'm
thinking okay as an organic grower
I know there's more potassium
potentially coming down the line
from my Malik test whereas if I'm
growing in Cocoa with mineral salts I
would think or in Hydro I'm like okay I
I'm out of potassium I need to just
apply potassium but what what do you do
as an analyst on something like that
normally when you have to remember
normally I'm doing mostly mineral and
hydroponic situations
um like regular cocoa to yeah but
um
we always look at the total environment
so if we see a tissue is low in
potassium then we would immediately look
at and it and it's not like it's like
low over time and you're like we can't
figure out why this is happening we
would look at the the root Zone make
sure that there's no like environmental
situation that's holding potassium kind
of Hostage or back or you know bound
with something else so make sure the pH
is right make sure that they are hitting
the moisture content so that they're
able to provide a nice soil solution to
the roots
um and then also look at the nutrient
input if we're using a fertilizer or
nutrient solution like do you actually
have potassium in there that you think
you did but now you really don't and
that's the problem
um for Hydroponics it's it's a little
bit quicker because you're dealing with
water so you can almost eliminate
certain things and grow directly back to
your nutrient Source like okay what are
we doing and why isn't the plant able to
get the potassium that it's needed so
it's really just backtracking to see
where in the in the system there could
be some issues of concern
okay and and correct me if I'm wrong in
this but as an organic grower I just
want to be aware of what my inputs into
my media were
at the beginning because if I added
not that I use this product much but
granulated kmeg sulfate of potash
magnesia
I and it was Grant in a granular form so
it wasn't immediately available I'm not
seeing it in a tissue test yet but I
will know that it's it's probably being
broken broken down by microorganisms by
water and that it's going to be coming
down the line I want to be a little more
conservative with adding
something like a soluble potassium
sulfate that's going to be 50 potassium
and I I don't want to overdo it I guess
would be my concern there that's exactly
that's exactly right you have such the
potential in every situation to react
and overreact that can almost cause more
harm than good like in the case that
you're saying with the granular sop
sulfate a potash sometimes I've seen all
that is is a factor of like surface area
like the particle size was slightly
bigger than they they were used to
before so like you're saying it's coming
it's just taking longer it's there but
it's just not following the same release
pattern that maybe the last time you had
more surface area and it was like
quicker so yeah you that's why
consideration of everything is so
important before making a a rash
adjustment that you can't take back
you know
great great so I had two other topics uh
the next one being Brix testing now I'm
aware of Brix testing in um grapes and
other crops where the the sugar level of
a crop provides greater value to the
to the grower but I'm hearing claims in
cannabis around bricks testing being
useful higher bricks means that you have
a plant that's going to resist pests
which
if Suzanne was on here she'd be shaking
her head and saying that's not true
based on what entomologists are finding
so I'll throw that out there but there's
a lot of claims around brics testing is
this like pansia for like
optimal healthy plants you raise the
bricks your plants healthier
what's what's really going on there or
what do you what do you think
yeah I mean
unfortunately I wish I had more like to
contribute here but as a horticulturist
that does mostly nutrient testing we
don't really look at the bricks testing
this and consideration of like trying to
devise the most Optimum nutrient health
um I mean obviously when you're thinking
about what what is the cytoplasm what's
that's what is the cell filled with
what's the cellular water components you
know sugars is a huge part of it
nutrients sugars organic acids aminos
enzymes they're all in there and and
having them balance together is what you
know boosts a healthy plant metabolism
um is that something that a Brix test
can
can say okay if it's a higher Brix test
than your plant is has a more
functioning metabolism kind of like a
human you know do you want your boosted
metabolism is that going to be a
healthier plant yeah I don't know
um I feel that
for just making sure the plant can
complete its life cycle
really having a grasp on the nutrient
concentration of the plant tissue is
super super important because if you
like you go back to your limiting factor
if you have one of those Essential
Elements as missing the plant won't be
able to complete its life cycle that's
not the case with sugars
um you know but
they all obviously work together so yeah
I don't know if that was the answer you
wanted to hear Tad but I don't know
that's what I got no I don't I don't
have a I don't have a perfect answer on
that I'm always open to learning more
um I I the way I hear from you is it's
important that we have sufficiency for
optimal plant health
but um
as I understand it from Long
conversations with Suzanne and then with
other agronomists is there's no
fertility Target
from a brics perspective with this crop
um it just it doesn't exist to my
knowledge
um but there are there are people making
basing all of their decisions management
decisions around brics levels which
at least from what I've seen may not be
I mean if it's working for you great but
it may not be the best management tool
compared to these other tools that we
have like
tissue testing soil testing things like
that yeah
I mean plants have been grown for a long
time plant and high value crops have
been
extremely important in the history of
our world you know from The Spice Market
to you know the beginning of our
history here in America to this stage of
what we're in now like and it's I feel
thankful to be able to be involved with
with a crop that's exciting and has all
this energy and passion
into its cultivation like cannabis has
really been
fun and energizing for I think our whole
Green community
but I do feel somehow like we get down
these wormholes of like
just making it more difficult than it is
and uh when in reality
like database decisions science quality
consistency
you know being able to repeat what you
do and eliminate your variables of
problems
no matter how you're growing will lead
to a more Optimum grow like higher
quality product because you're putting
the time into consistency and if that
means you want to go down your pathway
of figuring out these little bricks and
this and that that's great but
um sometimes I feel like it's a little
more complicated than it needs to be
um
as a scientist I say it a lot
well because it is a high value crop
because it is a medicinal plant
and be because people
care so deeply about how they grow this
plant I think we see
uh we see two things we see a lot of
marketing that you and I have talked
about that that may not reflect
necessarily the quality of the product
or the necessity of a product
um but also we see
um
we just see folks that want to do a
little bit more
you know you think okay well my plant is
this healthy right now what can I add to
make it even more healthy and a lot of
times I think that ends up being
detrimental but you get these like
highly complex feeding schedules that
are product based around
you know I I said like there's a lot of
buzzwords out there nowadays between
amino acids and ferments and enzymes and
and and these things that um
maybe over complicating the process
um and that's that's my concern is is
it's not so much that you're not going
to have a healthy plant which can happen
but more that you're just you're
spending money you don't need to spend
to grow this plant I I told you before
the show that I was talking to a grower
and he was so excited he just started
this new facility at this new facility
um going to be using a combination of um
and Jacks and and actually Beanstalk and
um he sent me a text saying that they're
they're going to save over a hundred
thousand dollars on their fertility
program this year which blows my mind
um not just the scale but also just that
that massive amount of cost that they're
spending for essentially the same
nutrients like which is one of the
reasons I always push against bottled
nutrients is because why are we paying a
company to add water to our product
um water when we can do that ourselves
you know we're shipping it we're
shipping water around it's crazy so
um you know from a sustainability
perspective not just for the environment
and like I said in shipping water but
also for
um our you know our pocketbooks it's
just not very practical so I appreciate
you know even though I'm organic guy I
appreciate that there are companies out
there that are looking at more
sustainable ways to grow plants
foreign
and it's important it's important to to
help people grow their crops I mean
efficiently and that's what it's going
to come down to because we all need to
improve and think sustainably and and
and not in a wasteful manner so I'm
happy that even though Jax is a
fertilizer company we do spend a lot of
time in formulation to to deliver the
ratios that are not wasteful and not
snake oil like truly scientific based to
try and you know deliver what it says
and that's the end of it so people
always say well why would you make this
fertilizer it's you know because of its
efficiency your you know cost and use is
like three cents per gallon you're only
using one bag in whatever 3 000 gallons
it's like if you did it differently you
could sell more it's like well
we have at the end of the day what what
does this mean you know what I mean like
I don't know so we just have a little
different kind of mode of operation here
in Allentown PA
yeah so so last topic and we're already
kind of going along as I nearly probably
would
um but I just wanted to touch on heavy
metals so yeah
um do you have time for that real quick
yep yep
Okay so
uh heavy metals as you know there's the
appco standards so and we'll see those
in the wsda Oda
um Omri
cdfa especially
um I'll follow this standard
um States however with cannabis do not
follow that same standard they have they
they have a tighter standard regulation
in a lot of cases around heavy metals in
in flower in the final product
um
it appears we don't really know exactly
how much
is too much arsenic or cadmium or lead
in a media or in a fertilizer program to
cause a fail because of all the
variability whether that's you know like
we talked about lighting environment
watering pH all these things are going
to affect
heavy metal uptake
um yeah
so first question how are folks doing in
Jax fertilizers in some of these more
stringent States and how do we how as a
grower do I avoid
potential risk around heavy metal
failure
um
so
the cool thing about
you know just being able to have a
watchful eye over our manufacturing
process is that we get to really you
know make sure all of our Blends are as
clean as possible
um
so for the Growers that use Jacks I feel
like we get the comment quite a bit like
they have a little less stress on their
lives because they know we're paying so
much attention to our inputs you know
it's a global market where we're getting
all of our raw materials you know and as
covid life really put a strain on
you know the timeline to get things the
sources that we could get things from
um the supply and demand and even still
today you're running into some issues I
don't know if it's still covid life but
maybe some of the Russian Ukraine
conflict that is still causing some
issues but what for Jax the Jax
customers you know we spend a lot of
time in qualifying these raw materials
to get as little heavy metals as
possible into our raw materials and we
see it all the time like we have a
wonderful supply chain person on staff
that's been here for three years so
thank goodness she came before
um and kind of took over from from one
of the longer term employees and was
able to kind of
really understand how important the
quality of our our raw materials were
um and and that was just wonderful
because
you know we you could get sources from
all these different places all over the
world that looks like great product it's
soluble it matches your pH it's a
hundred percent within spec of the
nutrient that you're looking for
but if you went by their paperwork
you'll be like great this looks like
wonderful you know there's no heavy
metals in this whatsoever but if you
don't test it yourself we test everyone
in outside Labs we test it in our lab
and an outside lab and we've come back
with things with like 15 parts per
million of lead in a micronutrient
source well my goodness if we would use
you know our micronutrients is a package
of like you know eight different things
at a minimum if every single one of them
had 10 parts per million lead in there
you would be over in a second
so you know it's super important to kind
of qualify those raw materials and so
what I hear a lot just circling back to
that is that the Jax Growers are happy
that they know that we're paying
attention to that and we've had many
many successful you know end products
and and it's been fun to be involved
with people being happy with their
success but you know we have had people
fail
and it you know we've helped them go
down the path of like is it the
nutrients or is it other things and like
you said you hate to point fingers
anywhere but we just try and help them
figure out where it could be from
did that answer your question or did
that answer one of your questions yeah
yeah yeah I mean there's no there's no
perfect answer there right
um
I had a grower in Massachusetts recently
that failed
um they were growing in seven gallon
pots using our soil and also using a
cocoa product and then they were adding
a
they were feeding on top of that with
another nutrient A Part B nutrient
essentially and
it was an organic one but they uh
they failed on some of their crop and
the variability on the test results was
all over the board and it was
interesting
um so first of all like people
automatically blame the fertilizer or
the media because it's a very common
source for heavy metals
um yeah but we do like you said you have
to be a detective so like we got on a we
got on a call with a long call going
over all their inputs and then we went
back and we started testing all their
inputs because at the end of the day
like and no offense to you I shouldn't
take Jack's word on it I should be
testing my product because it's it's
um it's it's I'm the one on the hook as
the grower and I I say the same about
kiss organic stuff like when people tell
me they've tested my product I
good job like let's let's talk about the
results do you think they're high do you
think they're low how is this going to
impact a crop like it's it's a good
conversation because especially in
Organics we're we're going to have heavy
metals probably in levels higher well
definitely in levels higher than you can
in mineral salts so it's All About
Management how much
are we how much is being taken out by
the plant how much are we putting in
initially and then if we're reusing that
media
what what can we add to stay below the
withdrawal rate of the plant and still
pass for whatever the regular regulatory
body is and just even since the last
time um I posted on social media about
this we found out that the pH Down
product they were using was actually
causing
um or being a heavy contributor to the
overall failure of their crop and I've
seen this twice now with PH down so I
just want to caution folks on that um
yeah the other one something you don't
think about you know
yeah no and I've heard that with some PH
down products and then also the one we
see quite a bit is gypsum sources people
that
um add in Gypsum as either a soil soil
stabilizer or as a source of calcium and
sulfur that doesn't change pH
some sources of gypsum
um are
um you know it's a function of the oh my
gosh I'm blanking out the Home Building
um industry like what is that oh drywall
you know drywall drywall is made of
gypsum yeah whatever that's called
drywall wall board or whatever and
um you're right yeah right you know
obviously I'm not like renovating
anything in my house here but
um yeah so it's a function of that and
that market doesn't care you know really
about the low levels of cat it's mostly
cadmium cadmium and arsenic in there and
um but then when you take it in those
fine particles you know and that's back
to like particle size and surface area
you can see a significant release of
those materials into a crop so we've
seen that in like nutrient charges and
whatnot so um that's another thing to
watch out for out there
yeah all of these mined products
anything coming out of the ocean is
going to have some heavy metal load and
it's so it's just all about managing it
really and keeping it lower and and keep
in mind too like if I if I register my
product properly as a fertilizer with
the wsda with cdfa
um and then I you can go online and look
at those levels keep in mind that's
that's
manufacturer submitted that's not a test
that the wsda or the cdfa did that was
independent it's a lab test that I sent
in to a lab of my product they sent it
back as as a certified analysis and then
I sent that on to the regulatory
certifying agency
no one's really checking that process
they're kind of taking your word for it
which
is scary ultimately is a little scary
depending on how much you trust the
company but I've definitely seen levels
that are different than what is on the
test that they're that's been submitted
I guess to the cdfa or what people are
showing on social media versus what
you're seeing in um
you know yeah from the certifying agency
so
yeah and that's that's a shame that's
you know you have to choose to do
business with people whose character
should be reflected in their their
products so yeah it's the same at
fertilizers we we do a lot of off-site
testing and we send it into different
state all the states we have to register
our fertilizers in all the different
states same type of thing and then they
post the results we do it at an off site
lab and then just send that in so I
don't know how we would mess with that
but I guess you could if you really
wanted to
you know
yeah it's just something for people to
be aware of that a lot of this stuff is
self-reported
um the Oda Oregon Department of
Agriculture does do some independent
testing that they publish which is
wonderful the wsca has done a little bit
of it too but they're testing like one
percent of the market maybe
um
so we're not really seeing everything
that's out there
um but yeah no I I really appreciate you
talking a little bit with me about heavy
metals and soil testing and tissue
testing uh was there anything else you
wanted to add anything that you're
really excited about
um upcoming in the next year
well I don't know I love having
conversations with you Tad as you know
that I feel that sharing information and
you know talking from different
perspectives really helps everyone kind
of broaden their knowledge and growing
any type of crop you know and
contributing to Horticulture as a whole
um no from Jax I mean we're we're on it
we're constantly looking at ways to
deliver the most efficient
science-based mineral fertilizers out
there I always say like I can't wait in
life till I get to go down the path of
like a more organic thinking I always
like you know I have a garden my house
like I do things a certain way here too
but being the chief scientist for my
family's company it's kind of like you
know blinders on moving forward in this
direction but
um yeah it's just it's been it's been a
great 2022 and I can't even tell you
like I feel like our whole company is
just so optimistic to like see the the
wonderful things that is going to happen
in 2023 so I really appreciate this time
to chat with you and anyone that's
listening you know I love I love these
conversations so thank you so much
yeah thank you for your time I uh I
think it's wonderful when we can come
together as a community at the end of
the day we all are super passionate
about growing plants and uh hopefully
that like you said shines through over
all the other stuff going on so and I I
love the idea that you're you're looking
into Organics down the road I would I
would love to collaborate with you on
something or figure out ways to bring
more science to the organic Community as
we uh move forward so that's wonderful
yeah there's a lot of potential out
there and I feel like you know this is
something that just would be a lot of
fun to get our brains going in that
direction together
yeah all right well thanks again I I
really appreciate it and I'm sure we'll
talk soon
all right thanks a lot have a great day
[Music]
that was Dr Carrie Peters with J.R
Peters and Jack's fertilizer and you are
listening to the Cannabis cultivation
and science podcast don't forget to
check out the podcast page at
www.kisorganics.com just click on the
learn tab then podcast and if you want
to support us or the podcast we do have
a patreon with bonus content and also
offer a variety of soil amendments soils
lighting fixtures and other growing
products on our website we carefully
research all the products we offer and
manufacture to make sure they are
science based and meet our standard of
quality thanks for listening
[Music]