[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge my guest this week is my good
friend Suzanne way wri Evans also known
by many as the bug lady she's an
ornamental entomologist specializing in
integrated Pest Management Suzanne has
been involved in the green industry for
more than 25 years with a primary focus
on biological control and using
pesticides properly she is a graduate of
the University of Florida with degrees
in both entomology and environmental
horiculture Suzanne has been on the
podcast multiple times and I highly
suggest folks go back and listen to some
of her other podcasts if you haven't
already now on to the show hey Suzanne
thanks for coming back on the show I
really appreciate
it hey Tad how are you doing I'm good
it's so nice to be able to catch up with
you uh it's been way too long and I know
we've gotten requests to find out more
about what's been going on in the bug
world in relation to cannabis uh
ornamental crops um what do you what do
you have to share with us today well I
guess it's partly my fault I have not
been back in a while because last year I
was everywhere on the planet um I had um
I went to a bio Control meeting in
France I was at another bio Control
meeting in England along with
crisscrossing across the US and Canada I
think there was one day last month I was
home uh like four days last year it was
like I think it was like November I was
home four days out of the month because
I've been traveling so much uh between
conferences and uh working with Growers
and their pest issues so I I'll take the
blame on not being around but I'm glad
we have today before I take back off I I
just got back from um the man show in
Baltimore last night and I'm heading
down to Florida on Monday for the tpie
show but along the
way um I picked up some really
interesting information and I've seen
some cool things that I think would be
good to talk about and one of the new
things I'm super excited about and know
this is not a paid advertisement and
know they're not paying me money is that
byw works has this new product called EP
shield and I'm super duper excited about
it um because one of the The Stumbling
box we have with pesticides always is
re-entry intervals after you apply a
pesticide you can't go back in for so
many hours for worker safety this
particular product does not have a
re-entry interval so that means you can
spray it and your workers can go right
back in um without having to wait
because it's considered very safe for
humans to be around
um the other thing that I'm super
excited about is you can dip cuting in
it um you know we've had a lot of
challenges with seoil X because you know
I love that product and it does so many
great things but we do not technically
have a dipping label for the United
States Canada does have a dipping label
but we do not in the US with the EP
Shield uh you are going to be able to uh
dip in it and since it is on this 25 B
EPA registration exempt list you can
adjust your dipping rates uh that are
appropriate for your crop so that if you
find that your crop may be more
sensitive you can lower it or if you
want to try to get higher efficacy you
might be able to raise it a little bit I
mean there's a window to work in there
which bioworks has done a ton of
phytotoxicity testing with it they've
been testing tons of crops to see if
there are any issues and they have um
lists available of all the crops but for
the most part it's looking very safe um
to dip your products in uh the main
target for it is two spot spidermite and
one of the things I'm excited about to
is it does kill all live stages of two
spot spidermite including the egg which
some of the other Botanical oils do not
so that's a huge Advantage there and
also the rates on it are super duper low
um it's like 10 times lower than some of
the other oil application rates so that
reduces the risk of phto that keeps your
cost down and so there's just you know a
lot of benefits to it um it's one of
those things that's looking very
compatible um with a lot of the
beneficials in the sense of yes if a
predatory might sitting on a leaf and
you douse it in it you're going to kill
it but uh some of the trial work that's
been going on actually at Growers um one
particular ornamental grower that's been
releasing
californicus uh and they've been using
the EP Shield injunction with the
californicus they're still finding
californicus running around in the crop
even with using epip Shield uh to kill
the spidermites and so we think it has
to do with how uh predatory mites
deposit their eggs on the undersides of
the leaves in the Doma and it's very
difficult to get spray coverage there so
they're kind of out of the way of of the
spray but uh I'm I'm really excited
again especially with the uh no REI and
and the dipping on this I think this
product's going to be a really good for
bioworks
yeah so I recently did a post on why I
am using seoil X in my garden and there
was a little bit of push back from some
folks regarding um the fact that it's a
petroleum based product I know you and I
talk about how we use Vaseline and
there's a lot of other things that we
should probably be more concerned about
um in our lives than a petroleum based
uh or mineral mineral oil based product
but um the the EP Shield I just Dr
Michael brownbridge just sent me an
email not that long ago about it and the
the things that stood out to me were
it's a 25b product I believe it was
clove oil I have to go back and look was
the main ingredient um but the coverage
on it looked um like the particle size
was smaller so the coverage looked
better and so like you said there's less
residual on the leaf surface and um
normally with 20 Vib products I tend to
be more skeptical mostly because coming
from you I realized that there tends to
be less research on efficacy around them
but bioworks has such a wonderful
reputation in this industry for the
level of research and data that they
bring to the table and um yeah I'm just
really excited about it I have a lot
more confidence in it I have a couple
samples in the mail right now on their
way to the farm and I can't wait to
start playing around with it and using
it because um personally I would feel
better using a you know a clove oil
based product um if the efficacy is
there over you know even suff oil X or
something like that and the dip rate
thing I didn't know so that's really
exciting yeah and it's a combination of
peppermint clove and a surfactant in
there um
and um the entomologists that developed
it uh tried lots of different you know
it's finding that sweet spot of killing
insects without damaging plants and he
worked very hard on developing this and
as you said
bioworks they will not just you know oh
here's a product they ran trials on this
for an extensive amount of time to make
sure they have all the data all the
research and that it works um they're
not just uh you know we'll bring
anything to Market kind of company um
they're very particular about what they
do sell and with their team of experts
like Dr Michael brownbridge and and
Julie Gres and Dr Chris Hayes I mean
they've really got an amazing lineup of
people there uh because they it's their
reputation and they're not going to
bring a bad product to Market and
I I I am I'm so always skeptical about
essential oil products you know we call
them salad
dressings and this one has actually
changed my mind a bit more on some of
these products because of um of just
mainly the efficacy and they've done
work on cannabis aphid and it's uh for
Target P two spot spidermite is what
initially was the main focus but they
definitely have efficacy on apids and
you know they've done some work on
cannabis aphid they've done work on
whiteflies it does provide some efficacy
on thrips but it it it's not like the
home run on thrips like it is with two
spot spidermites so more uh work will be
coming looking at different rates uh
looking at different species of thrips
different aphids and everything so uh
there will be a lot more information
coming um and also the product it it it
it smells
like like like
clean Dental mint kind of thing so it's
not a overwhelming smell which sometimes
can be an issue um so it it's not an
it's almost like a a super light winter
green maybe it's it's hard to explain
the
aroma so could this in theory for for
Growers
potentially be something they could use
comparable to suff oil X down the road
in terms of the efficacy of it
and use use rates spidermites I'm
believing so um aphids probably not sure
about thrips yet because again
um it's it's not quite as strong as a
thrips product um but again you have to
look at your crop and you know look at
all the the differences between the two
and decide which one's best for your
application and what you're
doing
but yeah well I might do something with
Michael talking about it here soon
anyway that was on my list of potential
upcoming podcast topics so I'm glad we
were able to talk about it now yeah no
I'm excited because again it's in the
hands of um you know a bunch of my
Growers now and you know getting
feedback from them so that's uh super
exciting um on that so um so uh I guess
we'll move on from EP shield and the
other thing which may not be as exciting
for everybody but again I still think is
um super exciting is uh you know biob um
the in you know they're one of the uh I
used to think of them as not one of the
big boy insector but now I'm definitely
inking them more into you know this big
boy category um because of their product
line and uh the team they put together
um but they are now actually selling a
blower which I'm super super excited
about because for a lot of people when
you have to apply over large areas
people were having to hand sprinkle out
predatory mites or you had to build your
own blower you had to buy a blower you
know get PVC pipe attach a funnel on it
with a ball valve and try to get you and
work all this out but biob now actually
has for sale a blower that they've
essentially kind of calibrated for you
it's adjustable and so people don't want
to build this and they want to be able
to blow out things like predatory
mites um lacewing larvae and things like
that over larger areas which not
necessarily something you're going to do
you know for um you know well spaced out
cannabis plants but for propagation or
for people doing ornamentals vegetables
we're really excited to actually have a
blower for sale now um and it's working
really well I've gotten feedback from my
Growers and they've all been pretty
happy with it um and again they have
like application chart showing which
beneficial you're using how to dial in
the adjustments on it and everything um
and so I'm pretty excited about that to
have a new piece of equipment for
application because you know application
for a lot of my Growers the application
of beneficials is the limiting factor
because of the cost of application of
Labor because applying uh beneficials
can be very labor intensive especially
when we have to te treat 10 20 30 acres
and having these automated things are um
you know pretty exciting which includes
and again it doesn't affect your people
as much but uh biob besta Europe uh now
has uh a piece of equipment called the
enomatic and it can attach to the back
of tractors to go out and do large farm
fields to apply predatory mites at an
incredibly fast rate so they can you
know go down the middle and they've got
these long booms and the air flow
carries the predatory mites and they're
applied out like on the Strawberry
Fields so it's going to going to allow
for larger acre applications of
beneficials that we uh were struggling
to do and you know the Drone
Technology's been coming along parab
bug's been doing amazing thing with
applying beneficials but not everybody
can use drones for applications because
if you're near the
airport um or if you don't have a
licensed person near you or if you don't
want to get a drone license this is
going to be an option for large scale
application uh the timatic um if you
can't use drone applications because you
know again not everybody can uh do that
I don't know if you've seen any of the
videos online or anything of
those I have yeah I've seen the drones
actually at trade shows at bio controls
conference or bio Solutions conference
what they call themselves now yeah yeah
uh on that note I just want to add we've
been working exclusively with biob now
for a couple years offering their
beneficial insects shipped direct from
insectary and uh they've been wonderful
to work with I really love the quality
of the insects they arrive in great
shape um just a friendly reminder to
folks whatever your bug provider is I
hope it can be kiss Organics but if it's
not make sure that you're getting them
directly from the insectary shipped to
you so that they're not being repacked
just to maintain viability I'm just
saying what Suzanne has said over
multiple podcasts over the years um on
that note I I want to also mention
because you mentioned Cool Tools one
thing that that's been around for a
little while now that I know you're a
fan of I recently applied SF nematodes
in my tiny garden at my house I don't
need a tool but for a facility the uh
nematode um bucket I don't know the
actual name of it I know that I've seen
that and it's something that you really
like uh I don't know if you want to
touch on that since you mentioned a you
know a grower tool for applying
beneficials that uh is kind of unique
and and interesting you know what's
funny is I call it the nimod bucket it's
made by a drram and I honestly don't
know the real name which is terrible
because I've demonstrated it at
workshops and I was just talking at the
man show this week with Kurt Becker um
and we were talking about the nematode
bucket and in the back of my mind I was
saying you guys need to put a vinyl
nimoe on the bucket like a cutout to
make people think about that but then
I'm like oh my gosh that sounds like
such like a like a a girly thing to do
so I didn't tell it to him because I
think you know it it I think it'd be a
great branding thing just to call it the
nematode bucket because that's mostly
what people use it for it can be used
for fertilizers also um and
biopesticides and stuff but the reality
is is most people that are using it and
it's and it sounds simple but let me
tell you it is not simple necessarily to
engineer it's it's a bucket that has a
motor in the base that not only arates
but circulates nematodes in a Vortex and
it keeps the water oxygenated so that if
you're applying nematodes uh they don't
drown and they don't settle out because
nematodes will settle out pretty fast in
water and I have had some Growers try to
build their own systems and the problems
they ran into is uh sometimes the motors
heat up too much the compressed air gets
too hot and they end up cooking the
nematodes or what can happen is you if
you get like a dead spot in your bucket
or container the nematodes can get
caught up in those corners and you don't
get um all the nematodes out at an even
application and uh they worked on wanted
a couple years to get the design right
for it um so uh yeah no I think that's a
a great tool it it's a little expensive
but if you are are putting out your
nematodes more evenly um more um alive
and more viable it's going to pay for
itself because I remember one of the
first n i mean first cannabis meetings I
went to I heard somebody talking about
using beneficial nitot or fungus net
management I'm like yeah awesome and
they were talking about well but we
struggle we can't get even distribution
and we're using a ladle to Ladle them
out of a container I'm like why aren't
you using an injector with you know an
artion bucket and they didn't even know
what I was talking about um and this
this is why I think it's so important
for cannabis Growers to come to uh
traditional
Horticultural conferences and trados
because sometimes the problem you have
another industry is already solved it
and you can pick up on those tools so
again this this bucket that dram
designed was designed for you know the
floriculture industry but now I see more
cannabis scers using it too so it can
definitely uh cross over the markets but
the reason I was talking to Kurt if
we're do you have any questions about
the nimod bucket or I want to touch well
no I want to talk about SF neod so like
for me the smallest amount I could order
was quite large uh and that was fine um
so I was just my goal with my
application I mixed it in a five gallon
bucket I was over applying it because I
only had like a couple yards of soil and
two 4x4 beds so it it wasn't a big deal
for me to over apply it so like for the
home grower could you just go over
like a a quick version of like what why
SF nematodes are so wonderful um how you
receive them apply them for someone
who's not going to get the Nemo bucket I
just think that would be a good just
review to have well um just so you know
on like the try nematode products the
reason why it doesn't come in small
small packages is because the viability
goes down you you need to have a certain
Mass to maintain temperature and the
right moisture and everything and when
BASF was testing this they basically
can't go much smaller without affecting
a viability so that's part of the issue
there and for storage where you can put
them in your fridge and have them for
several weeks you can find suppliers
that will sell them on very small
amounts on sponges and those sponges you
can take and literally ring out in a
watering can and walk around and if
you're doing house plants water them
that way or you can mix up in a 5 gallon
bucket but the challenge is is you got
to get them all stirred in and you got
to move real quick so that they don't
settle down you need that constant
agitation the number one way I see
people killing nematodes is they take
Nim out of the refrigerator and put them
in twoo warm of water you want to make
sure your nematode temperature and your
water uh temperature are pretty close I
mean not exactly close but you know be
within 10 15 degrees is uh kind of thing
because they're kind of like fish you
know when you bought your fish in the
bag you brought them home you don't dump
them into your tank you let it float so
the water gets uh pretty close together
in the fish bag and your tank water so
that you don't shock them so you can
actually take your nematodes out of the
fridge an hour or so before applying
them and let them kind of warm up to
room
temperature if depending on what your
tap water is like right now my kitchen
tap water is crazy cold um because of
it's being wintertime but I'll be in
Florida next week and there's no such
thing as cold tap water in Florida
everything's warm to hot that comes out
of your TAP so you have to look at your
water temperature how you're storing
them which should be you know around 40
41 degrees and then try to you know
either get your nematodes warmed up get
your water cooled down let your water
warm up and kind of get them you know
closer together uh for application but
the main thing is is you want to make
sure they don't settle out so you do get
an even application now if you're doing
like what you did or what I do at home
same thing you get this giant package of
nematodes and you need to treat a small
amount you're over applying them anyhow
so it's not as much of a a deal to make
sure that they're so evenly distributed
but when you you got to go treat large
acreage you've got to make sure that
everybody's you know getting their
nematodes out there um and you know
they're very uh compatible with most
insecticides uh products even the
microbial products you can actually tank
mix them together the beneficial
nematodes are actually once you get them
in the soil they're pretty hard to kill
but they're easy to kill in the package
and when applying
them and what are all the the targets of
the
ASF
nematodes for the most part our industry
is using Flor culture cannabis
vegetables they're using them for fungus
naap management uh and they are also
using them for control of certain thrip
species not all thrip species but thrips
that pupate in the soil number one
Western Flower thrips uh you can
definitely get some onion thrips but be
aware you know there are other
beneficial nematodes carpo caps bacteria
4 those will also actually infect fungus
snats they will infect thrips um but the
initial research has shown that the
felta works better for the fungus snats
and Western Flower thrips um where
bacteria 4 and carpac caps we use for
other more agricultural
pests and we you tend to see Western
flowers the dominant thrip species in
cannabis no onion no I onion is the
predominant one um also see a Kyo thps
um less to or less extent um but I very
rarely rarely and personally I've still
never seen Western Flower thrips in
cannabis not to say it can exist but I I
have not seen it yet everything I've
seen all the samples I've looked at have
been onion
thrips um and can you talk a little bit
about onion thrips uh life cycle while
we're at it I'm I'm this is more for my
own edification again because I have I
guess I have thrips because I had I
spotted them on my young plants so I I
haven't found any real damage but I'm
I'm not going to say they're gone um
generally I'll tell you what I did first
and then you can tell me about the life
cycle to tell me if I addressed it
correctly that might be a good way to
approach this really quick before we go
on with the latest stuff
so uh grower called me said hey the
Clones you gave you I found some thri
damage not a lot but you probably have
thrips so then I went back through my
plants sure enough I found a couple
their hard to spot but I have I did not
get them identified by you other than I
knew that they were thrips I but I don't
know the species you're already probably
shaking your head um what no so uh I did
a couple applications of sufff oil x uh
in the form of montere horiculture oil
because I could pick that up locally or
on Amazon um in a small enough size it's
the same product um I don't need a 5
gallon bucket of suff oil or a gallon of
suff oil so um I I did two applications
of that two to three days apart I
believe um and then I followed that up
with a release of SF nematodes and um oh
here's where I got to go back and
remember my list of um beneficial
insects because I always forget this one
strul about
insect no or cucumeris was it on the
Fage or
sski on the foler I did a foler of sersi
okay um and that was those were my along
with the
nematodes and I think I might have also
released some Rove beetles at the same
time but um yeah that was sort of my
preventative approach towards dealing
with this issue and I haven't seen any
insects in the room I know I had some
fungus gnats at the time too and I
haven't um I haven't had any uh fungus
snats showing up on my sensor cards the
yellow sticky cards since the you know
it's been a month or so now month month
and a half at least since I did all this
but um how would you have approached it
I
guess I would have identified what THS
it was but that's okay so was this was
this outside or is this like indoors
indoors indoors okay cuz and I think
most of the Growers we work with are
indoors that listen to the podcast so it
would be good let's just take this from
an indoor perspective well I mean some
people you know will grow a few plants
and pots in their backyard you know kind
of thing um but oh I've gotten them
outside too for sure outside is probably
a different species um especially when
you go down to California outside they
have a completely different species in
cannabis outside but for what you were
dealing with I'm going to guess without
seeing it was probably onion thrips
onion thrips biology is very similar to
Western Flower the adult flies in female
she inserts her egg into the planto
tissue it's in there a couple days it
hatches out starts cruising around they
have asymmetrical mouth Parts they kind
of more I didn't to use the word grass
but they kind of like damage the cell
surface there um and that's why you get
that white silverish kind of color to
them because they're removing the
chlorophyll and if you look they're
through when they're in their early in
Stars basically toddlers And even
teenagers they're they're kind of
yellowish clear but you can see the
green chlorophyll from the plant in
their in their gut and you know they
poop it out this kind of greenish color
from the chlorophyll but they're going
to cruise around and feed and this is
kind of and it it you know I always hate
to say things because people take it
like oh my God that's it's black and
white but no it's not but generally
onion thrips tend to feed more on
foliage Western Flower thrips yes they
can feed on foliage but generally they
are more of a flower problem because
they really like pollen and so Western
Flower thrips are what we see a lot in
pansies and we see um in patunas and we
see um you know in lies because they
have a lot of pollen onion thrips tend
to be more foliage
feeder and so when you're growing
cannabis guess what you don't have
present pollen so um and and I think
people because they they don't do their
due diligence and take the time to D
which I don't expect Growers to be able
to tell species of thrips apart you know
that's my job that's extensions jobs you
know people that that can do that stuff
um but people guess and they do the
matching photos online and you cannot
just match photos of Western Flower
thrips and onion thrips necessarily for
ID from a distance you have to look at
the length of the hair on the prot nooms
you have to count in tenel segments you
really have to get in
there but but but but the good thing is
is generally for onion thrips and
Western Flower thrips the management is
basically the same because the biology
is the same you know they're they're
young they're eating on the plants then
they drop to the soil to pupate and then
the adults emerge back up where it gets
sticky is when you're dealing things
with like Ayo thrips who do not drop to
the soil to pupate it's also a much
larger thrips the predatory mites can't
take out aino thrips so you generally
have to spray for aino thrips but when
it comes to onion and Western flour
the the BIOS work really well the
predatory mites and all of that when it
gets into chemicals um Western Flower
thrips have more resistance issues than
onion thrips um but that's not something
canos people necessarily have to worry
about because those kinds of pesticides
you're not going to be using
anyhow so how do you feel about the SF
nematode sski approach following up you
know a couple days after a a couple
suff oil applications so you can spray
your critique my yeah so um suff oil is
fine once suff oil is dry you can
re-release your predatory mites but if
you're going to do like you know two or
three sprays of suffoil x two to three
days apart yes that's smart to wait to
release the predatory might from an
economic standpoint I generally go with
cucumeris more because it's a lot less
expensive and it works just as well um
in cannabis on the thrips as sworski
does sski tends to be you know a little
more expensive um so but no I think
that's that's a perfectly fine program
and using you know your sticky cards uh
you know to monitor I think is a very
you know good good tool for that so yeah
I'll give you I'll give you a that so
one thing you mentioned was how they eat
the
chlorophyll so one of the ways I just
Scouting For thrips when you see that
like I always called it like the shiny
leaf surface yeah is how I see it like
it just has a different gloss to the
leaf where the damage is is that unique
to thrips because I to me thri damage
looks very specific compared to other
things and one of the things I look for
is that shininess we damages lace bugs
can give you that kind of look too um
now lace bugs aren't a big problem in
cannabis but it has lace bugs have been
reported in cannabis but it's not a huge
economic issue I mean it's hard to ever
say always but generally also um you
know spidermite damage sometimes can
look a little similar um but they don't
have
that silverness but I don't always see
that silverness with thrips damage but
you do see it sometimes that's good to
know that's good that's a good piece of
advice okay all right well I totally
interrupted you as you were going
through some of the latest and greatest
stuff on a tangent on thrips but I
really enjoyed that um what
um what else did you want to share in
the last uh year that you've been well
what I was going to say because we were
talking about the drram bucket Kurt
Becker I had a conversation with Kurt
Becker so for the cultivate show this
July in Columbus Ohio amazing show it's
it's it's awesome the education
everything and someday Tad we're going
to get you there um I'm teaching a a
full day workshop on the Saturday before
the show starts and one of the things
we're doing talking about equipment is
I'm going to have dram come talk about
their Foggers because more and more
people are looking at Pulse Foggers cold
Foggers and things like that so that
they can apply for for ornamental
Growers conventional pesticides but also
microbials things like Bavaria things
like Corps things like meisum where you
can put it in there close the door have
the timer kick on and basically air
quote fog your facility with these
microbial products so you don't have to
worry about Reis you don't have to worry
about you know you doing the spray
coverage and all of that and dram is
going to come and talk about and show
the equipment and we're going to show
about how they do the efficacy testing
for microbials going through these
things and I I think it's going to be a
really that's just going to be a part of
the day there's a whole bunch of stuff
we're we're going to be doing we're
going to um be talking about some other
other products I'm about to talk to you
about we're going to be demonstrating
how how to use them um and I'm going to
be doing some more how how
to basically kind of take cuting off of
plants washing plant cuting and how to
find pest in them for early detection so
we're going to have a bunch of good
stuff at uh cultivate this
July all right I have one dumb question
then before you move on um so as someone
who is like very conscious of my health
probably have too much anxiety around it
in general uh one thing I think about
with our eyes when I go to visit
facilities and some facilities are great
about it and some are not as I'm sure
you've seen um in terms of pp or like
hey let me show you this room and I
don't know when they last sprayed um I
get a little nervous about that but if
if you were to use like let's just say
as a hypothetical you were to use a
fogger to spray a microbial um I don't
really want to be breathing that in my
lungs um how you know with no REI does
that just does that just settle so
rapidly that you can go back into a room
relatively soon it will have an REI but
what happens is they set these to go off
when nobody's working so it will fog and
then while your REI is why nobody is at
work okay but let's just say they're not
doing it that way because I'm sure that
is the case in more facilities than you
realize so let's assume that they let
off a you know they set off the fogger
in the middle of the afternoon um how
long does it take for those particles to
settle back down to where you're not
breathing the product particle size and
how much venting you have cuz there all
these venting rules that go along to
it's a very variable thing um but if
you're just going through there one time
probably not going to kill you if you
work there probably over time not a
great thing because breathing in
anything I mean it's just like you know
breathing in anything to your lungs is
not good even if it's something that
could be
benign yeah I'm not I'm not worried that
like the microbes are going to like the
bacteria is going to start growing in my
lungs necessarily anything like I know
we breede these things all the time in
yeah much much lower concentrations but
I feel like just getting anything in
your lungs isn't healthy so it just it
just concerns me sometimes when I don't
know the grow quite as well that I'm
visiting um well and that's why and
stuff you should also carry gloves with
you because you don't know what's been
sprayed on those plants um but I mean by
law they have to label you know what was
in sprayed and the time and in theory
that's what they should be doing um so
that people to go in now here's the
crazy thing the REI applies to their
employees not
you so there's no legal REI for someone
randomly walking into a room is what
you're saying versus okay an employee oh
that's that's interesting I
guess scary but interesting um okay so
as a general rule for people who are
listening to the podcast just make sure
you're following all the instructions on
whatever product you're applying and uh
yeah just be careful out there I it's
something I I just read about uh I just
heard a thing about a a new confirmed
death actually in cannabis um relating
to a girl who was working in a cannabis
facility and developed essentially
anaphylaxis from um the the turpine in
the Cannabis uh an allergist posted
about this and it was a confirmed
documented case where she developed an
allergic reaction to the plant itself
and in being working in areas that were
poorly ventilated she eventually
um went into anaphylactic shot and
passed away sadly
so I don't know because sometimes when I
go in these rooms I do it it is almost
overwhelming the uh the smell and I'm
allergic to everything myself so uh it's
something just really sensitive too but
we're getting off topic yeah no well and
and as Wendy cornberg will tell you that
she she tells me I'm allergic to
Butterfly farts because I am so
sensitive to everything and I have the
same problem Sometimes some of the
cannab facilities it's it's quite
overwhelming and I will say it's not
just cannabis I mean if you ever go into
a field of like five acres of gardinas
in full bloom it it it's almost hard to
breathe because it's just those plant
volatiles can be so overwhelming and if
you're smelling them you know it's it's
coming off the plant and it it is going
into your lungs and it it can be kind of
sensitive so just you just have to be
smart about it um and and and don't be
afraid to say something I I will say I
was at a um a floriculture facility one
time many years ago and they wanted us
to go through that and I looked across
the greenhouse and they were spraying
pesticides while we were in there and
I'm like what and then this poor little
bee flew past me and literally fell on
the ground and died in front of me and
I'm like we need to leave right now
because we should not be in here and so
I think sometimes Growers because
they're so used to being around it to
get desensitized to it and especially if
you don't know anybody that's had
pesticide poisoning or something you
don't think about it as much but your
health is not worth not saying something
air on the side of caution always um
because you only get one body and you
need need you know you need to take care
of it um but don't be scared don't be
afraid to say something um and the label
is the law you must follow those labels
and if you don't think the EPA will
catch up with you eventually or your
state Regulators if you're doing
something legal they will eventually
catch up to
you yeah and on the note of the label
one thing that Eve taught me is It's
always important to spray at the label
rates because if you underpray the pest
May survive and develop a resistance to
it and so you may be creating a fur
problem so always important to fall to
spray at full strength or whatever the
label says yeah cuz people think I'm
going to be environmental I'm not going
to use as much but it just sets you up
for failure there's a reason why
products have labeled rate it's because
the research has been done to show that
is like where you're going to get the
most efficacy but still safe for the
plants and you know there's that's why
it takes so long to bring products to
Market these days because you have to
have so much scientific information to
back all this up
um out there
so great okay well that was a wonderful
tangent um what else did you want to
talk about um in the past year that
you've uh you've been excited about so I
have these here uh catch
Masters has come out with a new sticky
card shape now if I can get it out of
the box um they are doing and I'm super
excited about these especially for uh
smaller gardeners um
smaller production and I'm excited to
have these for my house because yes
Suzanne gets fungus snats too they
are preut because I had so many Growers
cutting sticky cards to make small ones
for monitoring um when you don't need a
full-size sticky card and it's got a
pointy tip so you can stick it right in
the soil peel it off you can write on
these the information and Away you go
I'm they um they never told me about
that I will reach out to Alex about that
here after the call so um because we do
sell catchmaster sticky cards um those
these are the shape of a plant marker or
a pot stick it depends on what you you
know them as but that's what she's
holding up right now for those of you
that are listening to the podcast yeah
sorry
and yeah I was going to add one side has
adhesive on it so that you can peel it
so it looks like one side is sticky and
then the other side you can write on is
that right yep very cool that is
exciting for
propagation um for homeowners for
interior scapers um I'm I'm really
excited about these um um I'm actually
they're going to be at the show in
Florida next week and so we'll be
talking about these down there um I'm
excited about these because again so
many of my even large Growers were
cutting the cards and then you're nobody
wants to sit and cut sticky cards trust
me and your scissors get all gross with
the goo and so yeah that's something I'm
excited about too two things I want to
add to that about sticky cards um one
what you should be writing on the back
is the date so you can keep track of how
long that card's been in there or that
pot stick uh and then two one thing I
found with the catch Master cards is the
whatever adhesive that they're using
because I've I've actually talked to
their uh head guys about that and I want
to do a little not a podcast but maybe a
shorter little snippet with them to put
up on uh social media but
uh the glue on it is is it's not as
sticky it's much easier for me to get
their sticky card glue off of my hands
when I touch it or it doesn't
necessarily come off on my hands
compared to what I remember from a
sticky card like 15 20 years ago where
like if you so much looked at that thing
like your hands were going to be gross
for a while do you know what I'm talking
about so there's different kinds of
sticky cards these are called dry sticky
cards and they're designed for catching
things like thrips and um whiteflies
smaller insects what I have seen sold at
a lot of the grow stores and the
Cannabis industry I've been using are
they're for catching larger insects and
they have a heavier glue to them because
the thickness of the glue depends on the
size of insect you need to trap if you
saw um you guys don't have it on the
West Coast but Emerald ashor which is
torn through the East Coast um they put
these giant purple traps but has really
thick glue on it because those beetles
are like 3/4 of an inch so you need a
lot of glue so you get different levels
of glue depending on what you're
targeting and trying to do and the idea
with these is if you put your hand on
and peel off you really don't get your
hand stuck to them I will say if you
have a sticky card on your desk and you
lean down and put your head on it it
will stick to your hair done that a few
times um but these are designed for
trapping small insects not big ones um
if you do ever get the sticky on your
hand just vegetable oil would take it
right off your
hands that's great I didn't know about
the glue thing but that makes sense um
I've been using the catchmaster cards
now in my garden and like I said they're
a little tacky when you end up touching
it but it doesn't stay on your fingers I
don't feel like I have to go wash my
hands immediately or like my hands my
skin stuck together so that is really
nice yeah it kind of got sold on their
cards when I I wanted to do like a a
photo shoot of people putting out cards
and I I used catch meas cards and the
grower hung it up and we were standing
there talking and I literally was
watching thrips fly into the cards um
and don't get caught up in this idea
that you need to have blue cards if
you'll read that online um a friend of
mine Sarah Jan drisk in Canada has done
some research showing yellow works just
as well and if not better for trapping
thrips the the yellow over the blue so
don't spend the extra money on the blue
the yellow work perfectly
fine how so should we be using blue
cards at all in your opinion
it depends on the situation sometimes if
people are releasing high levels of
parasitoids they may move to blue
because the parasitoids seem to go to
the yellow more than the blue but
generally people are putting out high
levels of parasitoids they take their
sticky cards down so um that for for
what you're doing in cannabis generally
I would I would think no so um but I we
talked about this never don't I want to
say never but generally no for the most
part you don't need them unless it's a
special
circumstance okay and then what about
the mass trapping uh
roles those are great if if you're
having massive white fly issues if
you're having massive thrips especially
flying thrips this is we do this more
with vented green houses or green houses
that open their sidewalls and we have
massive influx from outside and we have
these massive sticky rolls to do m M
trapping um I have never an indoor
indoor cannabis seen thrips numbers so
through the roof that you would need the
the mass trapping rolls necessarily I
mean it's not going to hurt to have them
up um but what I have seen is because
you know cannabis Growers love releasing
ladybird beetles and I've seen numerous
times they have those massive yellow
rolls out they dump out the ladybugs and
then the ladybugs just all get stuck on
those big yellow rolls
and just a friendly reminder to folks
we're not buying ladybugs because they
are wild harvested they can bring in
diseases and there's just much better
options though they do look cool and
they seem to have become the face of B
controls that they really shouldn't be
right by the way K my friend Kim Horton
who you've met um she was out hiking in
California and she came across a huge
mass of over wintering ladybird beetles
and she sent me pictures I am so so
jealous that's on my bucket list is to
see the overwintering sites in
California for where you have millions
of these ladybird beetles all clustering
together yeah can you paint the scene
here because I don't even know what that
would look like other than I know that
they're that's how they're harvested but
well is it is it literally like a giant
they're just they they cover the ground
they cover the the trunks of the trees
sometimes they'll you know get into
crevices and rocks so on the East
Coast bunch of our ladyb Birds here over
winter under and leaf litter so you
don't necessarily see them these are
these are more vertical overwintering
sites in California I I'll share the
pictures with
you that's cool that's cool yeah um
getting back to the mass trapping thing
I just want to touch on so a lot of
times what I see is people are mass
trapping for fungus Nets but really
maybe that money would be much better
spent then on like SF nematodes as an
approach or bti or something else rather
than
trying to catch the adults I mean it
depends on how they're Mass trapping
because remember fungus Nets gener are
going to be low down near the soil and
if you've got your sticky ribbon way up
high you're not going to get many up
there up high is you're getting more of
the flying in white flies flying in thps
if you were going to do I would say Mass
trapping for fungus Nets I would use the
traditional Square sticky cards down on
the soil surface like a billboard
because you want it low where the fungus
Nets are hanging out not way up
high could you run a strip along the
edge of the facility though for example
lower down closer to the soil May okay
all right
cool all right moving
on all right um okay we just did the
sticky guards um so lace Wings love lace
Wings in cannabis they've been super
helpful you know lacewing larvae we know
will feed on aphids um they'll snack on
spider mites um they'll definitely feed
on some some percentage of thrifts
they're not what you go to for the rips
but they're a good generous Predator the
problem we've had is
application um because you generally buy
eggs or you buy the larvae how do you
get them out on the plants where you can
buy those lacewing egg cards that you
rip and tear and hang which I do love
for cannabis but if your plants are well
spaced trying to rip all those and put
them around sometimes can be challenging
there is a new product called egg jent
um copert is selling it if you buy the
eggs from them but if you read the label
um it's xantham gum and basically what
you can do is you can use a PumpUp
sprayer or a backpack sprayer you take
the filters out you put water in you put
your xantham gum egant in and then you
add the lacewing eggs stir well you stir
up the xantham gum first get that
dissolved then you put the lacewing eggs
in and you literally can spray it on
your plants and the lacewing eggs will
stick to the plant leaves
and then they'll hatch in about two days
and then they can go walking off across
the plant so you can spray out a lot of
lace swing eggs getting really good
coverage on a lot of the crop pretty
fast and it's a pretty economical way to
do this we did tests in the fall on PO
cetas to see if it left any kind of
residue or discoloration on the plant
and it doesn't and sanm gum is you know
something we eat it's it's a it's a food
not well you don't just eat streets it's
anthm gum but it's a gumming agent so
it's not like you're spraying a
pesticide you're spraying you know a
food grade something on your
plants can can since you brought up Lace
Wings can you touch on uh what instances
you might use them in cannabis and um
what uh what their their target pests
are so number one aphids number two just
generally any soft bodied insects that
definitely feed on two spot spider mites
they um will definitely feed on thrips I
mean there's some work that's been done
looking at them for Ayo thrips but they
will definitely snack on thrips if they
find them on the plant I I just think
they're a good cheap insurance policy to
put into a lot of crops because they'll
feed on just about anything if they find
it um and they're inexpensive to use um
and there's plenty of supply of lace
Wings here it's not something that they
have shortages of and it's hard to get
so is this something you would sort of
tack on if you were already ordering
beneficials it's just kind of an added
what I it depends on attacker yeah well
it depends you know every program
depends but if you had well spaced
cannabis plants where there's not
bridging between the foliage where you
know you you could put lace Wing larvae
on one plant and they're going to move
to the other plants through the canopy
of the plant if you have them spaced and
if you have a lot of area to cover
because again you know if you've got
5,000 plants you're not going to be able
to go out and hang egg cards on every
plant this is a way you can mix them up
and just go out and spray them over top
and you're
done this is not something for small
production this is something that's
going to get you a lot of lace Wings
eggs out fast and an economical way of
doing
it yeah I guess a better way to phrase
my question is for since the majority of
people listen there probably aren't you
know super large scale Growers when and
how would they want to use lace Wings if
well for them you if you're a smaller
scale home hobby um you know I would go
with the egg cards and then just try to
have your plants touching the egg cards
are little strips of cardboard with a
hanger on them and they have lacewing
eggs glued on there that you just walk
along and you can hang on the plants and
then when those eggs hatch they walk off
the card and then they go up into the
can to be the plant but you're going to
have a concentration of lace Wings
wherever you put those egg cards which
may be okay because if if you really
want to concentrated it in a place you
could do those and we use those a lot on
uh tropical foliage um when we have
outbreaks but if you're larger and again
need to get lacewing eggs all over the
place the egg jent might work for you
and it's it's amazing you know you can
mix those eggs in you have an hour and a
half to get them out those lacewing eggs
can survive underwater for 90 minutes
and as long as you keep your PR your
pressure below like 40 PSI you're good
and you know take out your your filters
cuz you don't want to try to cram Laing
eggs through filters but yeah it's just
I'm really excited about this um for for
application methods um I'm interested to
see Outdoors you know is this something
we can use you know we are concerned a
bit about rain because if you put them
on if it heavy rains it's going to wash
them right off so for outdoor or
overhead overhead irrigation you're
going to have to think about your timing
and I don't think there are clear
answers yet of when you spray them on if
it misss will they come off you know how
much rain does it take to wash wash them
off but I think for indor production
drip irrigation you know they're going
to be
fine that brings up another question um
I saw and this is a little unrelated but
the lacewings got me thinking about it
so I saw a post recently where someone
was uh sort of against beneficial
insects because they feel like they just
end up in the buds the final product
with cannabis
specifically um
what I I guess how would you address
that and what Ben beneficial insects um
are less or predatory insects I guess we
should say are less likely to end up um
getting stuck in the tricomes um
relative to other
ones so when it comes to insects
beneficials and flowers it can be kind
of a a touchy thing because um there's
certain insects definitely like I I have
definitely over the years changed my
tune on uh Ro Beetles the atheta in
Canada can abis because I've had too
many cannabis Growers contacting me
asking how to kill them because they do
get in the bud and flour especially if
they're not happy in the soil there's
not enough food they go to disperse or
you have too much food for them and
their population explodes they can fly
and get up on the flower so I I
personally don't recommend it anymore
and even using them in like vegetative
because if you put them in vegetative
they're still going to be there in flow
so that's one example of one another one
ladybugs I've got a million pictures of
ladybugs stuck in cannabis buds I think
as long as you stick to things that are
smaller predatory mites um you know
generally they like to go to the
undersides of leaves because they're
looking for their food sources there um
that's not going to be an issue uh you
do have to be careful though with using
insects um because it's not only can
they get stuck in the bud they can get
stuck in the tricomes on the actual Leaf
surfaces um so if you have uh a variety
that's very tromey and super sticky your
beneficials may not even work especially
for things like will swing if you're
getting a few weeks into flour you
generally don't even want to use
lacewing larvae because they can get
stuck in those tricomes but predatory
mites because they are so small they can
navigate their way through and you know
I don't know if his issue is is like you
feel like he's going to fail or is it
you know the the gross factor of like oh
I may consume an insect because we all
know we all eat insects all day long in
all our food that's the reality of it
it's just another protein Source um but
considering the Alternatives you don't
have many other Alternatives but this is
why you need to start your management
programs in propagation continue them
heavy through vegetative so you
shouldn't have to treat heavy in flower
but generally people wait till they have
a problem and then it's too hard to
clean up yeah a God to start your bios
in
propagation yeah I think the issue was
insect Parts insects and insect frass
their poop ending up on the buds
themselves that you end up smoking um or
having to pick out of your uh okay you
know finish buds mites like don't have
little poops it's more like a liquid and
you're not picking those out ever you
know if you get caterpillars those will
leave giant honk and poop poops in in in
your bud I mean yeah there are some
caterpillars have giant I mean
grasshoppers have giant big salid poops
but a lot of these insects more they
don't create I don't know I'm trying to
be very delicate around words they don't
have solid bowel movements they just
have liquid because they're more feeding
on plant juices so depending on what
they're eating because caterpillars
consume all the fiber caterpillars
grasshoppers consume all the fiber mites
and thrips are more sucking the contents
of plant tissue out and not actually
eating the plant tissue is that if that
makes sense so there's not going to be
poops to pick
out okay yeah that was just one of the
complaints with beneficial insects that
I thought would be interesting to
mention today there's always going to be
when we were chatting there's always
going to be people that have complaints
about something and on the scale of
issues I deal with every day poops from
beneficial insect being on the plants is
not
one well it's probably more it's
probably more the bodies to be fair to
you know accurately portray the argument
um yeah you don't I mean no one wants to
be picking you know fungus knats out of
their out of their buds and things like
that but like you said there's not a lot
of great options in flour we don't want
to be spraying anything that's going to
be leaving a residue on the tricomes
anywh or damaging them so beneficial
insects are really about it and if you
know you see photos online of people
with like webbing from two spot
spidermites you know three qus of the
way through flower and they're like what
do I do you know or you get that phone
call and it's like there's really not
much you can do at that point safely
after you punch yourself in the face for
screwing up get in your time machine and
go back and do your preventative program
when you don't think you have a problem
to prevent that from happening because
that literally does not happen overnight
it's been building and building and
building and uh you weren't being
preventative in your program you cannot
wait till you have a problem great I
don't have anything to add to that so uh
moving on was there anything else uh
that you wanted to talk about regarding
sort of I guess this has kind of turned
into like sort of a new product podcast
of things that you found that are
exciting is there any new research
that's come out in the last year in
relation to cannabis that you might want
to share too um on actual
cannabis um no but it was very
interesting I'm just don't even have to
comment on this but I so when I was at
the meeting in France I was at the
international organization of biocontrol
um conference um in breast France late
fall and it it was a very intense
meeting uh we started it like 8:30 in
the morning and went to about 6:00 every
day with presentations on um basic kind
of what's going on around the world with
biocontrol um what research is happening
who's doing what and of course cannabis
came up and when I talk to the European
people about the isus with Aspirus and
cannabis they're like what and I'm like
well you know this is a thing in the
states where they're doing all this
testing and they're like what and most
of them had never even heard of this
phenomenon of Aspirus and the crazy
thing is is so Aspirus um the genus um
there were actually presentations on
using different
species of Aspirus as biocontrol agents
and we were talking about this and I
said because in the US and Canada there
is such a a negative connotation with
the word aspergilus that even if you
came to the market with Aspirus that was
the best biocontrol microbial ever
because the name aspergilus is in there
nobody will use it but it was just
interesting how the Aspirus thing is not
even on their radar for European
cannabis and it has been such a big
issue here the
states H yeah that is interesting I
don't know that I have any comments on
it other than I didn't realize how
serious of of the mot toxin is produced
by the species that can show up on in
cannabis or in you know edible crops
corn and just
how yeah how just how dangerous it was I
had kind of always just you know sort of
pooed it like yeah you know molden mil
do is probably not a big deal you know
if you have a healthy immune system um
but when I listened to the presentation
I learned that like this is actually a
really serious thing that's why like you
talk mentioned corn I think of like
peanuts and AFF toxins that are produced
um potentially with that like with the
production of them like it's
uh it's it's a serious thing and so I'm
glad that that we're looking at it I I
don't think the testing has caught up
with it to the point where we're
actually accurately testing what we need
to be testing but that's a totally
different issue all together well but
but you look at the food industry you
know and if you have not seen that
webinar it's funny that webinar that I
think it was Oregon State University or
was it was it the state of Oregon day
that was the one was it OSU I can't
remember but that was I I want to say
OSU but I it could have been the state
of Oregon but that was the one that we
were both on yeah and I was watching
that while I was waiting to get on my
flight to go to Europe at the airport
and I didn't realize how much money the
corn industry spent testing at you know
for if you've not seen that webinar you
need it it was really interesting and it
was interesting because right after that
webinar was it Oregon and I think was it
New York State dropped the aspila
testing didn't they for Canabis I can't
speak to New York but Oregon yeah Oregon
put a a hold on that for a while because
it was another state followed maybe it's
not New York I'm watch but if you not
watch that it's just even from a food
history standpoint it's super
interesting I'd kind of like to go back
and rewatch that again to process it all
better because also I didn't realize
what a diverse group Aspirus is because
you know we're taught you know Aspirus
bad and then they go to Europe and
they're talking about look at the
benefits of Aspirus I'm like what um and
it just shows you like how much we don't
know and how fast we are to paint with a
broad brush when we really don't
understand all those detail details but
I would highly recommend to go back and
anybody to to watch that cuz it was
super
interesting yeah my complaint with it
with it though was um basically all they
were saying is like we need to test for
it it's really bad it can have all these
negative human effects we don't know
what combustion does in relation to this
um or or into your lungs um we don't
have any solutions for how to manage it
they didn't give you any management
options um no but I found the history
that was what was really interesting to
me cuz I didn't know that it was this
big thing in in
food yeah yeah but if you're going there
to try and get Solutions it's not no
from a historical food standpoint it was
interesting speaking of microbial stuff
the other thing I am super duper excited
about I move my camera I feel like I'm
sliding down on the sofa as the
conversation goes on um put my head back
on the the middle um is uh okay so there
is a company in Canada called
anius and they produce a product called
bioceros which contains Bavaria basana
that is the
same type of fungus that's in botanigard
but it is a different strain this is the
entt strain that's in bioer was isolated
um in Canada by the research oologist at
anius so we've had the wedw powder of
bioceros for a while on the market here
that's not new news what I am super
super super excited about is they now
have it in a granular
formulation and the idea with this is
you pre-incorporated it into the soil
and I think for cannabis for rude Aid
this is going to be the game
Cher because the problem with drenching
uh these microbial products whether
using Bavaria or aeria or even
meisum um is when you put it on the soil
surface soil Sur soil is a filter and
the spores you don't get enough high
enough Spore concentration deep down in
the pot where the root apid can be so
yes if you're in a propagation cell
probably yes but if you start getting to
a three gallon s gallon pot or or bigger
you're not going to get enough spores in
there but if you can pre- incorporate
this so it's homogeneously mixed the
bavar throughout the soil you're going
to have as much Bia in the bottom of the
pot as the top because the root apids
are all through that soil profile so I'm
super excited that there is this
granular product I'm also excited for it
for Turf for things like chinch buug
management and grubs so there's a lot of
potential with this um and also to be
super excited is another company called
Lolly um they are the producers of the
metrium um it used to be sold as as um
met 52 but now they have the metum also
in a granular
formulation don't ask me which one's
going to be better for rude AIDS yet um
there needs to be side to side trials I
do know um some companies are trying to
get rud Aid colonies going so that they
can look at um you know how these two
different fungi perform it may come down
to you know your soil type what other
microbes you have in your soil there
could be a lot of variables but to have
the options to pre-incorporated two of
these
fungi either one you know into the soil
so you don't have to hand wrench and
they're there as a preventative I'm
super excited about we also know um from
uh research several years ago um at the
University of Vermont they've shown that
if you have Bavaria either on rice or
Mill it as a carry and pre-incorporated
in the soil it will just kind of fill
your soil with Bavaria and then when
thrips drop to pupate it will actually
kill the thrips pupating in the soil so
I I think we're going to see a lot of
benefits from this and I'm super excited
for these
products can you back up a little bit
for us and talk about what um yeah what
Bavaria targets as well as meisum and
what maybe those differences are between
the two for grow so Bavaria um
and when you start reading about Bavaria
you read a lot about beetles um and uh
it does a good job on beetles but for
protected indoor egg it's mostly used
for thrips management it's used for uh
it's really good on white
flies um aphids you you kind of have to
tank mix it with an insect growth
regulator so we don't recommend it a lot
for folar aphids root aphids are
different um but for folar aphids you
need to have an igr tanks with them but
really we target you know thrips and
white flies is is the main target you
can infect other things um now the
meisum traditionally again that's a bit
more of a a beetle product it used to be
used heavily um for uh management of
things like black Vine
Weevil Cornell has done great research
on that with pre- incorporating it into
the soil and showing it how it persists
and persists in the soil but it can also
infect other pests and this is again
don't ask me which one's going to be
better for rud Aid because that we don't
have the answer yet um but you are going
to be air quote a little technically
limited by the labels because not all
these pests are on all the labels and
again the labels are the law um for them
but almost everybody has thrips so um
you know pre-incorporation as a pre
thrips preventive I think is a good safe
place to to recommend these
products and one thing you mentioned I
want to go back and and just highlight
is you mentioned it's a different strain
between banard and banard and
bioceros and you know we when we talk
about these microbials like uh micro
isal fungi or Bavaria uh there is going
to be a difference so whether it's and I
talked about this in a recent podcast I
did but like uh you know Riso fagus or
regularis is not the same from different
companies they're one might be slightly
have slightly more drought tolerance or
perform better at this PH range or um
you know deal with a certain temperature
better so um don't you know we can't
just use the word Bavaria and assume
that it's the same product and I just so
people have to do a little research or
maybe try one Bavaria in your
environment if that doesn't work don't
assume that all Bavaria won't work try a
different one too so uh yeah just just
something I wanted to add yeah so
currently on the market to make things
clear as far as strains of Bavaria
basana that is EPA
registered there are three different
strains on the market there's the GHA
strain that's in uh banag guard which by
the way so everybody knows is not sold
by bioworks anymore so you cannot go to
bioworks for help it has been given now
to op chemicals um and the next one is
the entt strain um and that's the one
that comes from anitus um that uh they
they discovered up in Canada and then
the third one is uh bavia basana and
that's
5339 um that is um a strain that is sold
that's in
velifer velifer is a liquid product B
tanard comes as well wable powder and
liquid the bioer comes as liquid
wettable powder and
granular so it can be kind of confusing
I've actually put in at several meetings
to do um I'm actually going to do it I'm
going to be in Colorado Denver in three
weeks um which by the time this is
posted it may be then um but I'm going
to be at the pr Green Expo and I'm doing
a whole talk just on these microbial
products what's the difference different
formulations when you use what and
really go into depth on that so again on
the the Bavaria there's basically three
different
strains now when it comes to what used
to be called called iseria which is now
the genus has changed to CPS and it's
firmer Roosa which I always struggle
over that there are in the US market
currently two strains there is the apopa
strain that was isolated by the
University of Florida in Apopka and that
is what is in Anora and pfr 97 and then
you have the
9901 strain that is from pretty sure
it's from Spain um and that's where it's
produced and that is the active
ingredient in noly and isid um and isaid
is the one from copert noly is one
that's uh generally sold by several
different distributors so even inside of
the um ctis seeps iseria there's two
different strains and then with the
meisum currently on the market in the US
there's only one strain and that's the F
uh 52 and that's being sold under lard
and that is from
lont if you can keep that all
straight have you seen different
efficacy with different
strains I don't even know to answer that
because the problem is every every media
is different and I've asked several
times if researchers would do
head-to-head comparisons under the same
soils the same pest the same environment
and nobody's really done research on
that yet um so we don't have good
answers but I will say generally as what
you said is what we do we try one if it
doesn't work then we try another one if
that doesn't work we try another one
until we find one that works for your
soil your moisture and also your
microbes because I do think there's some
competition between all these microbes
going in the soil and some of these inop
pathogens and some of them are being
outcompeted or even eaten up by things
you're that are already in the
soil because you could do a trial let's
say in a in a soilless media you know
let's grow even like a sterile perlite
and throw rud AIDS in there throw you
know cannabis in there and throw each
one of these products in there and one
may outperform it but then if you go to
your greenhouse and actually do it in
your so type you may get a completely
different result that's a that's a good
point and unfortunately with pesticides
that are EPA registered you get the
strain you get that strain name
separated out but with uh something like
microle fungi or other you know some of
the other basilla species you don't see
that so and to further complicate things
you know there may only be a few there's
only two Manu three manufacturers of
micro risal fungi like Endo micro risal
funi when we talk about like Riso Vegas
regularis glomus inates um that I'm
aware of currently and so if you're not
buying from you know dinico RTI or
Premiere um you're probably buying from
a reseller that's buying it in and and
relabeling it so you don't it gets even
more complicated to figure out what
strain you actually try it I guess is
what I'm getting at on the my microbial
side when we talk about you know
fertilizer bio stimulant products versus
pesticides where at least you know you
know the strain The Strain name of what
you're getting so that's that's one
advantage yeah yeah and I mean this
whole thing about these bio stimulants
um you know bu or beware because they're
really not being regulated at this point
uh one of a mutual acquaintance of ours
did he got a package of a product
calculated out the Spore size calculated
it out according to the number that said
it was in there and when he did the math
the number of spores they were claimed
were in the package would physically not
even fit in the package they claimed
that was in
there yeah yeah no you have to be very
careful especially where you're getting
your microbes from for sure yes just
like your beneficials you have to be
very careful with all of that
so great well anything else that you
want to touch on here well today you
know I could go on forever but you know
we've kind of already eclipsed over an
hour and we don't want to keep people
too long um but uh I I will apologize I
am trying to get social media content
out but I say this all the time and I
just when you're out in the field
working you don't have time to make
posts and I have ideas great posts in my
head but it's just with with traveling
you know almost every single week I I
struggle to keep up with posting on
social media I just I'm too busy to post
so I'm going to try though part of my
newers resolutions Tad said I have to
make three posts a week according to a a
scientific one a personal one and of
interest and I've gotten none of that
done yet so far I got one post from the
show this week a picture of me and some
friends yeah you said three posts are
like the thing you're supposed to do to
stay active
oh oh I don't remember that I I'm
probably the last person to talk to when
it comes to Social Media stuff um but uh
that sounds like good advice to me now
that I'm hearing it so I'll take credit
um one thing that you you were helping
us with that I want to mention um that
we we're I think we just have to get one
more look over by you before we release
it and and and the reason I'm mentioning
is because um I think it brings up an
interesting point so we see these these
beneficial bug guides that say you know
this this this predatory might or
beneficial Targets this pest um but it's
so much more complicated than that as
I've learned from you so they may they
may Target this pest they may they may
have a secondary pest that they'll
they'll eat um but not as effectively or
they may eat something this other pest
but only if there's no other food
sources around and they're in a Petri
dish and so it really isn't effective in
real life to buy you know say this
particular insect to deal with this
particular pest so so uh you helped us
come up with a guide that kind of breaks
that down a little bit more saying you
know this likes to eat this it might
feed on this and even though there's
research showing it does occasionally
eat this other bug don't count on
getting any sort of suppression or
protection from it did I phrase that
yeah because I mean there's a difference
of does it eat it or does it control it
and one of the the new okay I wasn't
going to go into any more information
but we're going to go into more
information that ties into this
something that is really come to light
with us uh working on this new um
invasive thrips this parvy spinus um
thrips it's thrips parvy spinus thrips
is the genus parve parvy spinus is the
species is
that how looking at
biocontrols you get different results on
different plant species due to the leaf
structures of the plants which makes it
even more complicated so what they're
finding and what I have seen anecdotally
out in the field on multiple crops is
that really smooth leaf plants uh Ficus
croin predatory mites tend not to like
to want to be on those and so they they
like Doma on the undersides of the
leaves they like to lay their eggs there
and so things like cucum mares and
swerski will tend to leave those crops
you look at crops like peppers and even
cannabis they've got all those hairs
they like to be on them so if you're
targeting a th
species those mites will probably stay
around better on thrips I will stay
better around better on things like
cannabis and peppers where when we try
to control that same thrip species over
on let's say croin or Ficus it might not
work because the mites don't want to
stay on the plant because of leaf
structure so not only is it getting more
complicated just does it eat it looking
at plant structure is making a
difference on management selection these
days
I I didn't know that but that makes
sense when you say it like that um so
yeah yeah I is there anything else uh
shall we end yeah I guess so and you
know hopefully I will see some of you
around at some of the shows please don't
be shy about coming up and talk to me I
try to be as open as friendly as I can
and like I said I'll be down um next
week uh which I don't even know like the
like the 14th I'm going to be down at TP
in Florida and then um the following
week I'm going to be up in Minneapolis
at um there's a big uh Nursery
Greenhouse trade up there and then I'll
be out at the pr Green Expo um and I'm
going to be speaking there on mic
crobial I'm a cultivate every year um
the bio controls conference which is now
called
biosolutions um I'm going to do a
workshop at that on uh regenerative Pest
Management focusing more on a bit more
on outdoor production and talking about
you know attracting in beneficials
conservation of beneficials and you know
sustainability for Pest Management out
of the bio Solutions conference so I'll
be out there in California that's I
think I think the first week in March
maybe um I'm going to try to get my
schedule yeah they dropped their uh they
dropped their hemp cannabis track I I
honestly kind of have to say I had a
little bit to do with that um because I
I I will have to say I think the
learning curve for cannabis the Cannabis
guys have gotten a lot
smarter um and um have they're getting
it I mean the the the level of the
questions I'm getting are much better um
and the Cannabis industry has grown a
lot but I think for the geographic
location of where the meeting is uh I
think it's the Selenas Valley which is
mostly big a I didn't think you would
get a lot of cannabis people coming up
for it but that's not to say cannabis
people cannot learn from it because
Michael brownbridge is going to be
lecturing there Julie grash is going to
be lecturing there I'm going to be doing
another talk there too so I mean there
is plenty to learn because you could
always learn from other Industries and
learn about all the new products and
this is really the only bios focused
conference in the US that incorporates
you know Pest Management bio stimulants
and biofertilizer
we're going to put together our own
conference here it's going to happen um
one of these days and I'm so excited for
it because there's so many wonderful
podcast guests and between the two of us
I know we could get some really great
speakers out there yeah no that'd be
great um I I I think it should be like a
thing like a festival weekend you know
and
um well we needed we need a loc we need
some location so if anyone's listening
to this and knows of a good place that
we could host the meeting preferably
near some green houses or grows where we
could do some onsite stuff um that would
be a good starting point so yeah I love
doing the Hands-On workshops like I said
I I just did one in December in Michigan
um with Michigan State um where we went
through you know beneficial applications
and dipping and washing cuting for pests
and how to Scout and all that and I love
doing those handson things instead of
everybody just sitting in the chair
staring at a screen for a long time so
yeah having facilities to work at and do
Hands-On things would be super
awesome that was Suzanne way W Evans and
you were listening to the Cannabis
cultivation and science podcast if you
like the podcast please leave us a
rating and review and give us a follow
on Instagram and don't forget at kiss
Organics we have a wide range of
products we offer on our website ranging
from soils amendments beneficial insects
sticky cards soil test anal is and
Consulting I also recently add a patreon
for folks interested in supporting the
podcast directly lastly you can sign up
for our newsletter on our website
homepage to stay up toate on the latest
research and information thanks for
listening