[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge if
you're catching this episode near the
time of release I wanted to mention two
upcoming events that I'm excited about
first I will be speaking in the cannabis
breakout sessions at bio controls USA
conference in Portland Oregon March 4th
through 6th along with Suzanne
Wainwright Evans and Justin McGill two
of my former guests on the podcast and
good friends of mine you can sign up on
the website at www.clemson.edu/peach
Ecch it out at cultivation classic dot
CC my guest this week is Paul Coxon Paul
has been working with plants since 2008
his love for plants was a lifelong
passion that developed and grew through
the Nebraska Master Gardener program and
through his involvement with human nurse
nursery Paul received his Bachelors of
Science from NC State during which time
he published five journal articles
received the International Society for
horticultural society for horticultural
science young minds award say that ten
times fast published over 20 extension
and outreach publications and published
three ebooks Paul has a passion for
scientific investigation with the end
goal of providing growers and producers
with applicable and impactful production
knowledge and practices Paul is
currently pursuing his master's of
science and horticulture at NC State
under the direction of dr. Brian he whip
ker hey Paul thanks for coming on the
show today hey thanks for having me I
really appreciate this
yeah let's go ahead and start off giving
listeners a little bit of your
background and how you came into this
role that you have at the University
yeah for sure
so I have always been interested in
plants ever since I was a kid they were
a passion of mine and that passion just
kind of grew and evolved over my life I
was involved in the Master Gardener
program went to numerous extension
events and just through kind of a
roundabout way ended up at North
Carolina State University and I actually
got my bachelor's here and it started
working with plants under dr. Brian whip
Kerr doing floriculture work with him
and continued working with him through
my bachelors and the opportunity came
for me to sign on with the Masters for
him and I'm currently you're into that
and it's been one wild ride and never
expected to be doing work with cannabis
but here we are yeah you told me a
little bit about that off air how you
guys applied for a license and we're
able to get one and have started doing
some research with cannabis or more
specifically hemp do you want to talk a
little about some of the papers that
you've there's some of the research
that's happened at your university yeah
sure
so yeah it's the way that we got
involved in cannabis it's kind of a
roundabout story dr. Wilker and I were
just kind of talking one day in the
greenhouse just you know shooting the
breeze and I joked with him and said you
know hey let's you know work in him
because hemp had just become legalized
in our state you know he kind of laughed
at it and then two months later he
contacted me he's like hey I've just
applied for a license we're gonna be
doing work with him and you know ever
since then it's been just one crazy
research project after another and it's
opened a lot of amazing doors for us so
we're really glad that we got into it
but as far as some of the work that
we've done we got into cannabis and you
know normally when you are looking at
researching a new area you know you jump
on
and you'll do a literature review and
look at you know published literature
and you know I got on and jumped on
Google Scholar and typed in either
cannabis sativa and I think I used the
all in title function and I got 12
results and it was then that I knew that
we were in for one wild ride so we
basically had to start at the foundation
as far as research goes because you know
we wanted to establish some baselines
for nutrients for lighting for growing a
pH work etc so that's that's kind of how
we got started I can go more into the
specific projects that we've done if
you'd like yeah let's do it why don't
you tell us about your first foray into
any cannabis research and just for
listeners to let them know I do have one
of your papers in front of me the
characterization of nutrient disorders
of canvas sativa so we'll probably spend
a little more time on that I'm gonna be
kind of flying blind on questions as I
don't have the access to the other
papers at this time but yeah if you want
to kind of describe some of the research
that you've done and what some of your
findings we're I'd love to kind of go
through that in a little more detail
yeah for sure um so one of the first
things that we did was starting from the
ground up basically or the soil up the
two first projects that we started doing
we were looking at optimal routing
through clonal cuttings because we
realized quickly that sourcing through
seed was just not the way to go so we
started clonally propagating everything
but we were experiencing a huge variety
of reading habits and successes when
trying to clone root cannabis clonally
and in the floriculture industry we've
had a long time to kind of standardize
things so that variability that we're
seeing really intrigued us so one of the
first two studies we did we did a
reading study and that has been
published
we looked at these a bottom heat and
also the diameter of the cutting the
caliper
looking at how those two factors would
impact reading bigger and routing
success and then the next piece of work
that we did was looking at optimal
substrate ph's and that was in tandem
with another lab here at NC State doing
work there
the substrate slab so those were the
kind of the foundation that we did and
then from there we kind of went into the
nutrient deficiency work that you have
in front of you trying to characterize
nutrients and nutrient deficiencies and
then we've also had another study
published where we went into lighting
and photo period a bit we're looking at
daylight extension lighting regimes
versus nine interruption of lighting
regimes and I guess I should back up the
very first study that we did was a
baseline hemp nutrients leaf tissue
survey because we had no idea what
optimal nutrients were so we traveled
around the state to different growers
operations and we took samples off of
their plants and something into the lab
here NC da and got some values back and
established the baseline and that work
has also been published well I kind of
want to talk about the findings from
each of these because I think they're
all really interesting but let's start
with what you were just describing
they're in court of just surveying and
establishing sort of ranges for cannabis
using tissue tissue analysis what can
you talk about the sort of the
methodology of that and that process and
how you determined what a healthy plant
look like in terms of those ranges yes
so this was kind of the the dirty mucky
science that very few scientists will
actually want to reveal it's very
foundational work most of the time when
you're dealing with a new crop or a new
discovered crop it's kind of
shotgun approach so one of the reasons
that we went through multiple different
locations to try and find healthy plants
is because you know fertilizer types
were different and growing conditions
were different and you know the kind of
you know management strategies were
different irrigation was different and
that that introduced a lot of
variability so we were trying to
homogenize the landscape by taking a
general survey and that is not to be
used as kind of like the golden rule of
you know this is what adequate leaf
tissue parts per million
looks like the survey was just not to be
more of an informational guideline to
growers saying that you know these
plants which appeared healthy and were
growing vigorously had adequate
nutrients and from what we can infer
from other crops they appear to be
within the healthy range and that work
that kind of springboarded into the
nutrient disorders work which is getting
closer to establishing fertility
guidelines for cannabis got it so you
know what you're essentially what you're
saying is you don't want people to draw
too many conclusions from your
preliminary work they're that paper
other than to see that there may be a
possible range here of a tissue of
elements in the tissue that maybe allow
you to grow what appears to be a healthy
plant correct yeah so science is a very
additive process and the more and more
experiments you do in a specific
research direction or research question
they begin to add together to form the
whole picture and from that then you can
start inferring and making guidelines so
we're getting close with some of the
work that we've done but it's like like
I said cannabis is still very new for
research and so we're still just you
know beginning to green gained traction
with the research I think that's a
really good point that you're making
there so that people will consider how
you know how
this may point them in in sort of a
direction of a trend but there's still
so much research than me to be done I
mean if you were talking about a you
know an established crop like corn you'd
find thousands of papers just on
nitrogen that could discuss this and a
lot of tissue work that's been done
across a variety of different scenarios
and environments to where you you can
start really drawing strong correlations
but we just don't have any of that work
so it's it's still very preliminary like
you like you mentioned exactly yes I did
want to you mention propagation I did
have Dr Kaplan Darren Kaplan on from the
Guelph he did work with dr. Zhang on
propagation already now I don't know did
your work come before or after their
paper which was released in I think May
of 2018 and is there any correlation
there or any anything that you found
that sort of fit or didn't fit with the
work that they did yes
so Kathleen's work came before ours ours
was just published at the end of I
believe it was 2018 is when ours came
out so his work came before ours and as
far as the the correlations between the
two works there were some similarities
but for the most part we were also
exploring slightly different things you
know for example he used rooting
hormones and his work and we did not
look at rooting hormones we were looking
more at the caliper bottom heat so when
you say caliper just for people who may
not be familiar with the term you're
talking about the measurement of the
diameter of the stem correct and when
you say sorry so you were measuring
you're measuring the caliper in terms of
the routing success of that particular
cutting is that correct yeah so
basically when floriculture
when you're trying to establish a more
vigorous cutting
a vegetative cutting you'll apply heat
to the bottom of the tray or bottom of
the bench or close to the bottom and
that increases the temperature of the
substrate and what that does is it helps
speed up the routing across us in some
species in others that will have little
to no effect so we were trying to
explore that and then the other area
that we were exploring is the caliper
which when you take a tip cutting from
another stock plant and you kind of take
the tip portion and you point it away
from yourself and you look at the end
that you cut it and then you were to
measure the diameter of that that would
be the caliper and the theory was that a
thicker caliper could potentially have
more surface area for the callus to
increase route proliferation and a
thicker caliper could also potentially
have more reserves so more photosynthate
etc that the plant could draw on to help
with the healing and reading process was
kind of the line of thinking that we
went down and did your research support
your hypothesis yes so what we found
that was that we divided calipers into 3
differents sizes small medium and large
as far as the caliper was concerned and
we did find that there was a
statistically significant difference in
routing between the the small caliper
and the large caliper but not between
the small in the medium or the meteor in
a large caliper and so what that means
is that when we actually looked at the
date of routing the bigger of routing
and we actually then screened the
routing through a visual scale that the
larger caliper produced more vigorous
roots rather than when compared to the
small caliper and when you say enlarge I
assume you're still talking about fairly
immature vegetative plants I do know
that cannabis can develop a woody or
stem over time which can it appears to
inhibit cloning or
propagation I can you talk a little bit
about your how you established your
experiment and what what you really were
comparing there yeah so to answer your
question how we kind of went along the
lines of exploring how to quantify the
size of the confetti or the caliper we
actually went in to mother stock plants
we took some other stock plants and we
took vegetative kind of things off of
those and the paper goes into a little
more detail on how we quantified that I
won't bore you with the details here but
we divided all of the cuttings kind of
did a survey and looked at the different
calipers and the different caliper pools
and from that we came up with the sizes
that we used for our study and the small
size was 1.7 to 2 millimeters medium
size was two point three to two point
six millimeters and the large caliper
was two point nine to three point two
millimeters and so that's that's kind of
the general process of how we approached
categorizing what a typical caliper
would be on an arm other stock plants
that we were managing and then how we
divided them up for the study
now did you look at where on the plant
itself that the cutting was taken from
in terms of from near the top of the
plants near the base of the plant
was that something that was factored in
it all in this particular study yeah so
we only took from secondary tertiary and
quaternary branches and basically what
that means is you have the central stock
from which all the other branches come
off so that's considered the primary and
so any branch that comes off of that
would be secondary any consecutive
branch that comes off and that would be
tertiary so on and so forth
and like I said the paper which is
freely available through Murray State
University the Journal of agriculture
agricultural hemp research
has a wonderful diagram in there on how
we actually took the cuttings and
quantified the branches but as far as
looking at say an interior canopy
cutting versus an exterior canopy
cutting we were only taking shoot tips
from the exterior portion of the canopy
and what I mean by a shoot tip is only
the terminal growing portion of a
cutting so it terminated in a growing
tip that makes sense yeah so you weren't
you weren't taking more than one cutting
off of that that branch so in theory you
could go down another few inches and
take another cutting but you didn't do
that for this experiment okay I get were
saying were there any other findings
from this particular study that you
wanted to share besides what you just
shared regarding caliper
larger caliper reading better than
smaller caliper yes so like I said that
there was a statistically significant
difference between the small caliper and
the large caliper and as far as the
percentage of cuttings that had rooted
at 14 days versus 28 days there was a
statistical difference in this study
between adding root zone heating or
bottom heating versus not utilizing
about a bottom heating so that was
another interesting question interesting
finding from the study rather what was
your control temperature and then what
did you raise it to with the the root
zone - with the bottom heating and how
statistically significant are we talking
across adding that heat matter heat
source yeah
so the what we did is we measured the
substrate temperature so the substrate
temperature was twenty seven point eight
degrees centigrade without root zone
heating and then it was sorry that was
with root zone heating and the average
temperature was 25
six degrees centigrade without so we
increased the root zone temperature by
roughly 2 degrees centigrade okay just
to save all of us Americans who are
terrible at Celsius I'm gonna do this
calculation for people so 28.7 Celsius
is eighty three point six six degrees
Fahrenheit
that was your heated temperature what
was your sorry what was the control
again yes
sorry that's 27 point eight degrees
centigrade for the treatment oh okay so
the treatment was 27 points so 82
degrees Fahrenheit correct and then for
the control it was 25 point six degrees
centigrade
correct
you
correct yes
yeah
so when when doing a study like this you
don't want to raise the temperature the
read zone temperature too much because
you don't want to potentially desiccate
or damage any roots that are forming or
even the catalyst as it forms so that's
why the temperature differential wasn't
overly large yeah I would have thought
that maybe the control temperature might
have been lower rather than the heated
temperature be higher but no that's
great yeah we this experiment was
conducted during the summer so we were
in a poly house and the cooling
coefficient on a poly house is much less
so that's why the temperatures were a
little higher for the control that makes
sense that makes sense okay great so
let's move on to another one of the
papers that you mentioned prior to you
know prior to talking about this
nutrient disorder paper okay
our use the substrate pH work the other
one that we did kind of on that ground
up approach we're still in the process
of publishing a paper so that one has
happened at least yet those results will
be forthcoming okay I understand so
maybe we do dive right into the nutrient
nutrient disorder paper that you wrote
or co-authored okay now one of the
things you talked about with this paper
was that you guys really are a team
there at the University is there any
anything you want to mention prior to
starting talking about or did you want
to kind of as we go through the paper
mention the people that were involved in
different aspects of this work yeah
that'd be great yeah so in our lab we
have been really blessed to have a group
of fantastic researchers and
collaborators that we've worked with on
all of these projects both the projects
that we have completed have published
and are doing so yeah
gabi Barajas Patrick needs the david
logan matthew davis kimberly McAlister
our collaborator dr. Nichelle Schroeder
Moreno or other collaborator dr. Brian
Jackson and my major professor dr. Brian
Becker we all form a fantastic team of
collaborators some of these people have
been involved on all the projects others
are collaborators on some projects but
research definitely does not take place
in a vacuum and as far as the research
process goes we've been really blessed I
had some amazing collaborators and
people in our lab that's great I mean it
really does take a team and I think it's
important to recognize that when you see
a name on a paper that's not the full
story of the work that went into it so
thanks for highlighting that now this
paper itself
it's called characterization of nutrient
disorders of cannabis sativa it was
brought to my attention recently I mean
it's only was published in October 18th
of 2019 do you want to give a quick
highlight or sort of a rough idea of
what the abstract was with this paper
and what your goals were when you first
started doing this research yeah so like
I said the first paper that we published
was that general survey paper and that
one is published and that's meant to be
kind of a shotgun approach to guidelines
you know these were the ranges we saw in
multiple different cultivars across
different growing conditions this one is
trying to be a little more targeted and
kind of narrow in on optimal fertility
recommendations for him and trying to
figure out what kind of fertility
cannabis plants need in order to balance
the nutrient cost input to growers and
maximize the you know CBD content and
flower content depending on what you're
growing for so for this specific work we
were looking at nutrient deficiencies so
what that means is we were trying to
stress the plants down to a level where
we could visually see symptoms
of nutrients stress and then we could
take foliar leaf tissue and send that
off to a lab and compare that to plants
that we grew with a complete fertility
machine and that complete fertility
regime is based off of what's called a
modified Hoagland solution it's a
standard hydroponic water-soluble
nutrient fertilizer regime that
basically balances all of the cations
and anions and is supposed to provide a
plant with everything that it needs as
far as its macro and micronutrients are
concerned so we were trying to withhold
an element from a plant from that recipe
to induce our deficiency and they
compared those visual symptoms and the
leaf tissue analyses back to that plant
and that plant that received everything
was our control now are there is there
research out there showing and success
and growing with this Hoagland solution
or formula with cannabis or were you
kind of going into a little bit of new
territory with that in terms of is
making pulling from other crops yeah so
dr. wicker myself
numerous other scientists have used the
solution to provide fertility for a wide
array of plants so as far as specific to
cannabis you know we were the first to
kind of pioneer a Hoagland solution with
cannabis but as far as the general
literature is concerned it has been
tested on numerous different plants
numerous different crops and proved to
be adequate okay so and just out of
curiosity
so as you started growing with this
toquyen solution is this baseline for
fertility just anecdotally you found
that it seemed to be providing
appropriate nutrient levels across the
board for macro and micro nutrients for
for cannabis correct yes and so
kind of how the research logic goes as
we took a broad survey approach that was
our first paper and then we kind of
wanted to see what would happen if we
took away a singular nutrient from the
plant and what that would do to the leaf
tissue value is compared to the survey
that we had and what that would do to
the you know control plant that was
receiving adequate fertility that has
been proven to the adequate for multiple
different crop species and then
currently what we're doing and I know
we're getting off track a bit but
currently we are then modifying the
Hoagland solution that solution for all
macro and micro nutrients at different
rates to try and get a fully relief
tissue curve if that makes sense
so from you know say like zero parts per
million to 2.5 so on and so forth to try
and establish a curve for fertility as
far as foliar analyses are concerned
okay yeah that makes sense yeah I was
just I was just kind of curious where
you came up with this for you know a
baseline for your control because I
think that's important for people to
understand when you start talking about
what you're removing it's good to know
where you were starting that's all okay
I want to get into a little bit of the
methodology here but just I had a couple
things in the introduction that you guys
mentioned in terms of relating back to
prior work that had been done that I
thought was kind of interesting and I
didn't know maybe it's something you can
touch on maybe it's just something that
pretty much the sentences that you put
in there say at all but I kind of wanted
to bring him bring him out in hemp
forever in hemp fiber varieties Bosca
itaú
reported higher levels of nitrogen
increased plant leaf weight and
decreased leaf THC content presumably
due to THC dilution can you touch on
that at all yeah so that work in
particular like I said once when I
actually went into this and was doing a
literature review and trying to get a
good feel for the kind of research that
had been done there was not much out
so this introduction is quite bare-bones
when it comes to a normal introduction
and literature review but essentially
what we're trying to say there I think
what the article was trying to get out
is first I would like to draw your
attention to the fact that this is a
fiber variety so we were growing a high
CBD clone so the growth habit and growth
parameters are different for fiber
varieties you want them to be very tall
you're trying to get you know plant them
very densely they're in a field
condition typically and the CBD variety
is that we were growing you know you
want those big beautiful flowers they're
more compact they were grown in a
greenhouse but essentially what we're
what we're trying to get out here is to
draw on previous work showing that
nitrogen increased the total production
of leaf biomass and that's important
when looking at leaf tissue analyses you
know because you're comparing how much
nitrogen is in that leaf it's a larger
leaf you know you can potentially have a
dilution effect and also that increased
plant size could have resulted in a THC
dilution effect so if you have a larger
bud but the same amount of THC in it
because most things are calculated off
of a percentage dry weight you can have
an artificially low dilution effect
however I am unsure I can't recall off
the top of my head which methodology I
actually used to test THC in this study
whether it was a percentage dry weight
or a percentage concentration so on and
so forth that could be really
interesting for people in growing hemp
that are looking to stay below a given
THC percentage in order to have a legal
crop I'd be curious to see more research
coming out on that around nitrogen
levels yeah I would - any research at
this point is just gonna help that
additive scientific effect so that we
can get a clearer picture for what's
going on
okay so one thing one other thing I want
to ask you about was at the end of
introduction you mentioned that no
visual guides of nutrient deficiency in
cannabis supported with leaf tissue
analysis and documenting a progression
of symptoms II have been published so
essentially what you're saying there is
when I go online on Google Images and
type in you know nitrogen deficiency
cannabis or whatever a particular
element I'm looking for there's no
research that's been published that
actually correlates that with a tissue
test the leaf tissue analysis to show
that that truly is the deficiency is
that correct
along with symptom ology so different
stages correct as far as I know and have
seen and was able to tease out in the
work that I did there have been some
leaf tissue analyses reported I believe
the plant analysis handbook has tissue
values for cannabis sativa
but as far as correlating those visual
symptoms with an actual leaf tissue test
and what I mean by actually correlating
I don't mean just providing low
fertility when we withheld nitrogen from
the plant the plant received no nitrogen
of any form so we can say with relative
certainty that the symptom ology that we
saw based on the leaf tissue analysis is
truly nitrogen deficiency because the
plant received absolutely no nitrogen
fertility well let's dive right into
nitrogen I'm not going to get into too
much into your methodology it's all
there in the paper people want to read
it it's it seems fairly straightforward
to me let's just talk about what your
findings were relating to nitrogen so
traditionally when you think of nitrogen
deficiencies you think of a yellowing on
the lower leaves the plants putting more
energy into its upper leaves lighter
greening over all of the plants what I
mean you have some actual photos here so
people can see initial intermediate and
advanced stages of nitrogen deficiencies
but can you talk about about those
findings relating in nitrogen
yeah so exploring nutrient deficiencies
is kind of a fun I guess you could call
it a bit of a puzzle certain elements
within plants are mobile and what that
means is the plant has the ability to
remove those from certain tissues and
portions and translocate them to other
portions of the plant so for example
nitrogen is Noble so what that means is
when the plant is nitrogen stressed it
will draw nitrogen from those lower
leaves which is why we kind of you know
drew upon the fact that the symptom
ology developed first on the lower
portion of the plant and it will
translate locate that to the you know
other portions of the plant that you
know need that nitrogen you know for
example the meristematic region as its
developing new leaves and putting on new
shoots so and like you said typical
symptom ology of nitrogen deficiency is
going to be that yellowing or paling
specifically at the lower foliage other
elements that we looked at you know are
immobile which means you're going to see
symptomatology on the newer leaves
shoots near portions of the plant yeah
that's a really good point regarding
mobile and immobile nutrients how
related is that to the hydrology in
terms of your watering habits nutrient
mobility or nutrients that are mobile
yeah so the the whole flow and dynamics
and flux of nutrients within the plant
as is much more complicated than we went
into in this paper like I said we're
trying to get some more foundational
knowledge out there but yes so for
example some plants are Tran
taken up by the plant through a process
called mass flow and that's very much
related to how much water essentially
the roots can
into the plant and get those nutrients
in and then there's other ways that the
plant can obtain nutrients scavenge
nutrients etc so as far as through this
study on all of the plants were on an
automatic irrigation system and received
the same amount of liquid at the same
intervals throughout the day the only
thing that changed was which nutrients
we were supplying to those plants in
that solution okay
and one of your one of the things I want
to before we dive too far into any one
element or nutrient here is in a
traditional cannabis growing environment
you're gonna see multiple symptoms
typically it's not ever just a nitrogen
deficiency or a phosphorus deficiency
it's usually related to your watering or
your environment community your
temperature your lighting intensity
insect pressure there's so many
variables so I hope listeners will keep
that in mind when they're utilizing a
guide like this that it's not as simple
as just picking out one of the photos
and saying that looks the closest to
like my plant and so that's what's going
on you have to add a little more history
into how that plants being grown and
what's going on in the room but just
want to throw in that little caveat so
sorry
getting back to it when you talk about
nitrogen one of your findings was the
plants growing in nitrogen deficient
conditions produce 50% less biomass when
compared to the control I thought this
was an interesting finding I mean it
seems expected the plant doesn't have
nitrate it's not gonna be able to grow
as as efficiently but you didn't find
that across all of the different
elements that you were testing with so
is there anything in relation to
nitrogen that you want to touch on
regarding that yeah so we have done
numerous nutrient efficiency studies
with multiple different crops and this
trend of dry weights being variable in
their statistical significance your kind
of holds true across most of those
studies a lot of it is just dependent
upon the plan
and how they uptake nutrients how they
utilize those nutrients their growth
habits you know you can imagine
something that stays in a rosette form
is going to have very different nutrient
needs and utilizations than something
that has a very upright and leggy growth
habits but as far as nitrogen is
concerned we expected to see a
statistical significance between no
nitrogen and nitrogen supply treatments
specifically because nitrogen is a
macronutrient and what that means is the
plant uses more nitrogen and other
macronutrients in greater quantities
than say the micronutrients both macro
and micro are still needed by the plants
but as far as the amounts that they need
it means much much much more nitrogen
than say the phosphorus or potassium or
calcium and that's one of the reasons
why there was such a strong
statistically significant decrease in
plant dry weight when compared to the
control now in this test you were just
dealing with vegetative plants correct
so you never really looked at
cannabinoid content THC percentage any
of those things is that correct that is
correct the current work that we're
doing we are looking at like I said the
nutrient rates for all macro and micro
nutrients across the plants different
life stages so the experiment that we
are doing now we're looking at leaf
tissue nutrient concentrations in the
vegetative state we then again sample
once we have turned off our lighting and
initiated those shorter days to start
flowering and we harvest at pre flower
which is typically a week to two weeks
after we shut our lights off and then
we're waiting until they go into full
flower maturity which we're targeting
about eight weeks for full flower
maturity and then we're again sampling
leaf tissue so we're getting this nice
not only nutrient
rate curve but also total plant life
cycle and how the nutrients are changing
accumulating moving within the plant
this isn't an uptake study or a
translocation study it's a nutrient rate
study over time but like I said there's
this additive effect so that's kind of
the next step that we're going on to so
on and so forth yeah I think that'll be
really interesting because it's it's
fairly easy I think to grow a healthy
vegetative cannabis plant but as you get
further into flower as the plant starts
senesce Inge
you see any particular stress I think
becomes much much more apparent so even
though as we move through some of these
elements in your in your study here and
you said you note that there isn't
statistical significance in biomass I
think as we move into flower that'll
become a lot more apparent in terms of
the those deficiencies reflecting either
a loss of THC or cannabinoid percentages
or terpene values or even overall yield
of flower biomass so I'm really excited
to see that work as you guys come out
with it yeah and kind of going back to
what you're saying with the
statistically not the statistical non
significance in the plant dry weights so
for example for phosphorus while we did
not see a statistical significance and
rank the weight between the plants that
did not receive phosphorus versus the
plants that did you can look at the leaf
tissue values and see that they were
statistically significant and very
statistically significant actually so
even though that phosphorus treatment
may not have produced a smaller plant
per per se it definitely had less
phosphorus which means that it will be
stressed and won't be as healthy and
consequently could potentially produce
you know a bud that would be suboptimal
sure that makes sense
and you know I'm of the opinion that
most most growers over apply phosphorus
in flower I'd be curious are you going
to look at what sort of what sufficient
sea levels are needed for phosphorus in
flower versus the overabundance that I
think is applied throughout the cannabis
industry in general when it comes to
phosphorus yeah so one of the things
that we'll be looking at is when we take
that final leaf tissue harvest so we're
going to be looking at okay at the end
of the plant's life how much phosphorus
did it accumulate over these different
rates but then we will also be looking
at cannabinoids cannabinoids however you
want to say it and how that can
potentially relate back to the different
rates that we're applying so for example
in our phosphorus provided at let's say
hypothetically ten parts per million
what would that bud total dry mass be
but then what would also be the you know
level of THC or CBD CBG in that flower
very cool I can't wait to see that
research that's I think really exciting
I would love to have you back on once
you have you know gotten a little
further along and published that yeah
we'd love to
we'd love to do that cool so let's let's
move on to calcium it looks like that's
the next nutrient that you talked about
here I did notice that you put in
dolomite lime into your substrate to get
some calcium and magnesium in there
Keith can you touch on that and then
also what your findings were with
calcium yeah absolutely so for the
rooting substrate that we use because
these were vegetative cuttings yes some
of that did have the limited climb
amended in it but those levels would be
negligible on the scale that we're
looking at especially as the plants
continue to grow and there's you know
more biomass and consequently less
calcium and you can see that in the
statistically significant results from
the leaf tissue concentration that we
saw but as far as symptomology for
calcium goes calcium is an immobile
element so when you're looking to see
calcium stress or deficiency on your
plants you're going to be looking at the
growing tips the newly expanded leaves
the portions of the plants that are
actively growing and expanding so
calcium the plant isn't able to
requisition any calcium reserves from
old cells or old plant parts and
translocated so that's why you're
looking at these new portions and
another thing with calcium is that it's
involved in cell wall stability and
basically what happens when a plant goes
through a calcium deficiency is it
cannot adequately develop so you'll see
this severe distortion and stunting that
we saw and you can see in the photos as
they progress and that's one of the
reasons that we were able to see such
beautiful I say beautiful but if you're
seeing the symptomology it's not
beautiful when it grow up
but beautiful symptomology that we
induced it's quite dramatic it's it's
very apparent which i think is is what
you're referring to there and it is
great to see and you can't see it it
just it almost looks like it had a lot
of light stress I think in a lot of ways
it's it's I was quite shocked with just
how dramatic it is because it's funny
because in the in the cannabis industry
there's sort of this old mantra that if
your plant looks at all sick or
deficient you just apply Cal meg and
it's kind of become a running joke in
the cannabis industry I've just you know
put more Cal mag on that product but in
reality I think it's rare we see these
sorts of calcium deficiencies that they
do occur at least I don't see them as
much with the
that I work with I tend to see more
nitrogen or potassium deficiencies but
yeah I really liked seeing those photos
so that was really great to see was
there anything else about calcium that
you wanted to add I love that you're
kind of describing a little bit of how
these nutrients work in a plant because
I think that's really important so I
appreciate that too what if you're okay
with it let's move on to sulphur and you
can talk a little about that too yeah
I'd like to touch on one more thing on
calcium real quick okay so calcium and
boron will have very similar symptom
ology and they're both in mobile
elements but one of the reasons and we
have completed the micronutrients
experiment run for that nutrient rates
by lifecycle portion so I can talk a
little bit about some of the symptom
ology and results not true results yet
we haven't run statistics on the full
study but because cannabis wants it
initiates its reproductive phase that
growing tip will become the flowering
portion calcium and boron are extremely
important in that development because
you know when they finally are initiate
the reproductive cycle and start
producing that flower bud it's going to
be at that growing tip that you see
across the plant so if you do have
calcium or boron deficiencies you will
not have a properly developing flower
bud because you won't have a properly
developing an expanding growing region
and so you know we saw that with our
boron plants you know we had almost no
flowers produced on our boron zero rate
once we initiated flowering just because
there the plant was physiologically
incapable of expanding and growing
because it did not have the structural
components needed to build those cells
and expand those cells that's really
interesting and people can go and view
these photos to see what what Paul is
describing here on on
paper itself there's some great photos
associated with every one of these
elements yeah so you wanted to move on
to sulfur next is that correct yeah
we'll just keep working our way through
I think this is great thank you
wonderful yeah so for sulfur again it
was one of those elements where we did
not see a statistically significant
difference in the dry weight between the
plants that did not receive any sulfur
versus the control however when you
actually look at the leaf tissue
concentration it was statistically
significant so the plants that received
no sulfur had much much lower leaf
tissue concentrations than plants that
received an adequate level of sulfur
fertility and again I want to kind of go
back to what you said a bit earlier on
you know making sure that you take a
holistic approach to diagnostics in your
plants you know I that was great that he
said that leaf tissue analysis is just
one way of trying to tease out problems
that you may experience you know it's
like you said it's this holistic
approach that you have to take it could
be another abiotic stress you know it
could be ozone damage it could be water
stress you know so taking those leaf
tissue concentrations from your plant
actually going in taking the leaf tissue
samples sending it off to a lab ensuring
that you can do that and that the lab is
licensed and that the laws and
legalities in your state allow you to do
that to gain this information will be
extremely valuable if you think you have
a nutrient deficiency you always want to
go that extra step if possible and check
to ensure that what you're seeing
visually is also reflected in the plant
yeah that's an interesting topic because
because cannabis is federally illegal we
cannot ship any leaf samples even if
there have a bed
a plant with zero THC content in the
mail so most cannabis facilities are
very limited in their ability to do
tissue testing so a lot of what we do is
sow testing because we're primarily
working with organic soil growers where
we where we have certain levels of
mineral content in every soil mix that
we're working with in native soil and
then it's just a matter of trying to
balance those based off of like a male
ik3 test which is not ideal I'm fully
aware of that but it's one of the limit
limitations within the cannabis research
at least from a facility perspective
because we are limited not only just in
the ability to mail leaf samples to
reach a lab to even find a lab that's
willing to look at a cannabis sample and
then also just the cost associated with
testing for businesses is is really
tough so it's great that the university
is doing work like this to at least
allow growers to have access to some of
this information yeah that's that's a
great insight and again you know we're
we're learning as much as we possibly
can so honestly the exchanges that we
get with growers and the kind of
challenges that they're experiencing it
only helps us do better research so who
knows maybe down the road we're going to
look at possibly correlating some of you
know the nutrient work that we're doing
to you know some of those soil tests I
know that there's researchers out there
who do a lot of work with that and I
think they jump at the opportunity to do
some work like that if it's needed yeah
that'd be great I mean I'd love to see
more correlation there between like the
may like three and saturated pace tests
with these tissue tests so we can have a
better idea of how we're of nutrient
availability in these soils because the
other challenge there too is how much of
those those nutrients are really
available to a plant and and how well is
the biology it's cycling those nutrients
so if we're talking about organic
systems there's so many variables
involved it gets quite complex
I think it's gonna be a long time before
we have all those answers but by using
you know chemical nutrients or mineral
salts like you guys are you're really
able to isolate out these various
minerals or nutrients which really makes
a difference in seeing these these
symptoms so that we can we can still
apply some of this knowledge towards you
know are more complex organic soil
systems yeah the one thing I will say
with sulfur that I see is I tend to see
it in very high levels and organic soils
primarily because people either applying
sulfates or gypsum as a way of
mitigating the alkalinity of a lot of
the cations in in soils so I tend to see
like excessively high sulfur levels
however from all the research I found
it's very hard to reach sulfur
toxicities in soils or more specifically
in cannabis plants to where I haven't
really seen it be a big issue it's been
one of the best tools for lowering pH
that I've found in soils is anything you
want to add you mean you would touch on
regarding that comment yeah it's very
difficult to produce a sulfur toxicity
and without going too much into the
details of physiology of that
essentially the plant is very good at
requisitioning utilizing or excluding
sulfur within the soil one thing that
you can see and some things that have
come out of literature is that elevated
sulfur level is just like any other
element being elevated above others in
the soil profile can potentially impact
and I will call it qualify that by
saying can potentially impact the
microbial community and especially in
say an organic system like what you're
working with you know looking at how
those microbes can take those nutrients
and turn them into you know a
mineralized core form that is plants
available you know that relation
[ __ ] between the organic matter the
microbes and then the production of
those mineral plant available forms is a
very important Network and web to be
maintaining and monitoring so down the
road maybe there could be more work done
specifically with regard to microbes and
say elevated sulfur levels and nutrient
cycling and organic systems yeah it was
really what I would like to see
regarding sulfur is information on how
sulfur impacts of biology cuz when we
talk about sulfur it comes in a lot of
different forms so when we talk about a
sulfate form or it's you know we talked
about potassium sulfate calcium sulfate
in the case of gypsum it appears to have
in this is anecdotal very little minor
impact on overall soil biology and
nutrient cycling but I've heard when
using agricultural so for which is
associated with lowering pH it can have
a more dramatic input impact on soil
biology but I haven't I haven't seen
enough research and I haven't seen
enough data to really show how much
sulfur would need to be added to lower a
pH level this much in a given volume of
soil and how that impacts so about those
are things that I would love answers to
down the road or if that research exists
someone send it to me because I haven't
seen it yeah some research like that one
would be fantastic especially with
regards to organic forms of sulfur
there's like you said there's definitely
very much need for more information to
help perpetuate that adequate of
scientific process okay but let's go
back and and why don't you tell us a
little bit more about magnesium I know I
got off topic there for a second
yes so magnesium deficiency magnesium is
involved with chlorophyll and
essentially what a plant will when a
plant experiences magnesium deficiency
chlorophyll essentially doesn't function
in the way that it's supposed to
and what that means for the plant is if
you have a magnesium deficiency the
photosynthetic activity of the plant
could be much lower and that will impact
the resources and photosynthate that the
plant has and is able to then throw at
the developing bud and other developing
portions of the plant so if you think
about it and a typical life cycle you
know every organism wants to reproduce
and especially in plants as you touched
on a lot of times with the reproductive
stage of the plant you'll experience
much more pronounced stressors and that
will be when you start seeing those
symptom ologies for nutrient
deficiencies over you know other
stresses that the plant may be
experiencing because it's dumping so
many of those resources into that
developing flower bud with the end goal
of trying to reproduce and so especially
my magnesium you can potentially have
huge impacts to your yield and again
like I said we have not explored the
full rates and life cycle analysis yet
of this element throughout the plant but
it's one of those that you want to keep
a specific eye on given its importance
to plant health overall
and then also touching on the the
symptomology by location on the leaf and
how it develops and progresses like you
said they're very similar magnesium and
potassium deficiency symptoms are very
similar and so understanding that leaf
anatomy and how it progresses you know
is important in the visual diagnostic
checklist that you kind of go through
and obviously in an ideal world we would
identify a nutrient deficiency early
before it gets to these advanced stages
so that you know we don't have to wait
until it we see advanced entomology to
determine you know magnesium versus
potassium
yeah now I'm excited to talk about
potassium because I think potassium is
one of the most important elements when
we're talking about cannabis and I don't
have the data to support this yet at
least I mean I have you know hundreds of
soil tests I've looked at relative to
overall plant growth but they're not I
haven't had any plant tissue analysis
but the trend that I think I'm seeing is
that potassium deficiencies occur at a
much higher rate in cannabis as in they
need more potassium than most
agricultural crops and I think potassium
has a high correlation with bud density
and overall weight so essentially
talking yield based on the soil tests
that I see correlating with plants the
plants that appear to be our soils that
appear to be K deficient or even just
case sufficient like barely sufficient
tend to produce lower yield and lower
weight yeah lower weight and overall
lower yield and lower bud density than
these then plants that have what most we
consider an excess of potassium but I'd
be curious to have you talk on it and
also talk about what your findings were
with potassium in this particular paper
yeah so the interesting thing about
potassium especially with regards to on
say a soil profile as opposed to some of
the you know soluble fertilizers that we
were using here is it's a mono valent
ion which means it's charge is it
essentially has a charge positive charge
a singular positive charge so typically
what happens say you have a heavy rain
event those mono valent ions will be
leached through the soil profile they're
readily then say you're diving Lent
and so that means that potassium can
move into a plant relatively easily but
it also moves through the soil profile
relatively easily as well but that's
kind of a side note and as far as the
research findings that we found we also
found that you know limiting potassium
had a huge impact on the the obviously
it had an impact on how much potassium
was uptake was taken into the plant
because there was not supplied but once
it was supplied the potassium levels
were quite high in the plant and we
referenced our survey values in the
paper as well and those were within the
reference values that we had in our
initial study but I would agree with you
that more work definitely needs to be
done in potassium as far as its role in
the developments and etc as you touched
upon I am uncomfortable addressing that
given you know we have not yet explored
the potassium rates and the lifecycle
but once we do that's definitely
something that I will be specifically
looking for and comparing in our study
so that's extremely helpful I can't wait
to see that because what I so I'll get
from a grower I may like three tests for
example at the beginning of the grow
cycle and then wanted to end and what I
find is in terms of how far the
nutrients have dropped in the soil
you know nitrogen and potassium are the
two that see that typically appear to
drop the most and as you mentioned they
are very mobile they could be being
leached out of the soil from a flooding
event but a lot of the guys that we're
working with too are using blue mats
which are essentially an automated
watering system that only waters as that
soil dries out so it's it's controlled
through osmotic pressure by the soil
itself and so we tend to not have
a lot of leeching going on through that
bed so in theory if nothing's leeching
out the bottom of the bed then that that
potassium is being taken up into the
plant and as we see potassium levels
drop to let's say around five percent or
lower of the total cation exchange CC of
the death of total the total plant or
sorry total of what's available in the
soil I start to see smaller buds lower
yield that sort of thing so I'd love to
see research on that and see what really
is going on there in the leaf tissue
itself it's actually really interesting
I have to keep that in mind when looking
at the study when we run the
micronutrients like I said we ran the
micronutrients we have yet to run the
macro nutrients so I'd love to talk more
with you just off air about that that's
actually very fascinating especially if
they're using a blue mat system that
could potentially mean well we can talk
later
we can we can speculate about that later
I appreciate you hearing me out let's
move on to your micronutrient disorders
cuz you you had some interesting stuff
going on there too yeah so like I said
one of the nutrients that I'd like to
specifically highlight would be boron
and again that is involved in the
essentially cell wall development and
stabilization and so especially if you
experience a boron deficiency and then
you're close to your initiation of
reproduction and you don't remedy that
like I said one thing that we saw is we
have little to no flower bud formation
due to the fact that meristematic region
was not able to properly develop and
expand into the developing flower bud
and as far as I guess we can cut talk
about how copper was there specific one
that you want I do address no I think
what your your the overview your giving
is great I will just caution listeners
that when we're talking about these
micronutrients we're talking about very
very small amounts
typically parts per million you don't
need a lot of boron for a plant to be
sufficient so you know don't go out
there and buy borax and apply a bunch to
your soil and think you're fixing a
deficiency because you'll probably kill
your plant I just want to highlight that
for people when we talk about
micronutrients we're talking about
typically pretty small levels of
nutrient that's actually needed yeah
that's a fantastic point and to add to
that
in this experiment we added a boron
toxicity treatment so essentially what
we did is we took that modified
Eggland's solution we took the boron
levels and we increase them tenfold of
what the Hoagland solution requires and
we did that with manganese as well and
the reason we do that is because we
often see like you said it's very easy
to over apply a micronutrient so we also
wanted to try and capture some of those
toxicities and phonologies because not
every nutrient issue that you run into
will be a deficiency sometimes you're
over applying something or something is
too available or the plant is taking up
too much of something or you know
another element may be in such high
quantities that it's causing another
element to the plant unavailable yeah
and it's what's interesting I'm looking
through these photos right now a boron
initial boron toxicity looks almost
exactly like your initial potassium
deficiency they're very close correct
and I think that's interesting for
people because I've seen people walk
into a grow room look at a plant and
immediately say oh that's nitrogen
though that's potassium oh whatever
and that always makes me nervous because
there are there's so many variables
associated with this I mean a lot of
especially in soils a lot of your
nutrient deficiencies and excesses can
be related to hydrology or the way that
you're watering by just under water in
your plant you can cause a lot of
nutrient deficiencies because the
microbes aren't able to cycle nutrients
effectively due to a lack of water so or
due to lack of osmotic pressure move
those nutrients throughout the plant so
I think that's really important
highlight I just want to point that out
while we're while we're on the topic
yeah I think that's a great point I find
one of the most helpful things you can
ask any grower of any crop is first and
foremost for a crop history because most
of the times you're seeing something
that is an issue that was created
sometime in the past it is now
manifesting and so that's a fantastic
point and I'm glad to see that there's
other people out there who are you know
stopping and thinking and taking a more
holistic approach to you know diagnosing
issues yeah was there anything else you
want to touch on regarding the manganese
or boron toxicities that you saw or
either of those elements in general in
relation to plant growth or plant health
yeah one thing I will say is when
looking at toxicities and you can see
this in the photos and I hope that this
photo also gets posted so the listeners
can reference it you will often see that
toxicity Centron ology regardless of
element follows a very specific
progression where you see that you know
marginal chlorosis so that yellowing of
the margin first and then it will
progress to the marginal necrosis which
is that burning or that the browning of
the leaf margin and you'll see that and
you can see that and you know the
comparison image that we have between
manganese toxicity and boron toxicity
you know that the marginal symptomology
is very pronounced in almost any
toxicity so just kind of as a side note
you know being careful and cautious when
you know dealing with the leaf margin
especially if it's going chlorotic or
necrotic yeah that's that's excellent
advice I that wasn't something I was
aware of or had really ever thought of
honestly when I think of toxicity so I'm
glad you pointed that out yeah did you
want to touch on did you want to move on
to your what looks like iron and zinc
were the next two
on in your paper yeah we can live on the
iron so again as I stated magnesium
toxicity our magnesium deficiency
manganese deficiency iron deficiency
they all kind of have this intervene all
chlorosis symptom symptoms that develop
on the foliage and so you know doing
work like this we're trying as best we
can to develop these criterias and
checklist suppose visually and with leaf
tissue to help people diagnose things
but a lot of times the symptom ologies
are very similar so being careful that
when you're looking at these that you're
taking again a holistic approach and
trying to utilize the tools that are
available to you to help diagnose these
the iron deficiency again you'll get the
severe inner vein of chlorosis and those
more advanced symptoms and hopefully you
know we can identify and remedy iron
before it gets this level but letting
the plants go out this far that's one of
the reasons that we allowed you know the
plants to grow in these deficient
conditions for so long so that we'd have
that gradient the beginning I mean in
advance entomology and as far as iron is
concerned it is another immobile element
so for this particular opponent if
you're seeing symptomology on the new
expanding leaves the growing portions
the plants that the portions of the
plant that are actively growing this is
where you're going to be seeing that you
know intervene or chlorosis and so
looking at where on the plant these
symptoms are occurring will help you
identify and you know kind of utilize
that as a checklist you know is this
iron or is this you know a mobile
element and there's some wonderful
charts online that you all can utilize
if you just look at nutrient mobility in
plants it will tell you which there's
some charts out there that have you know
categorize mobile elements versus in
mobile
and we'll help you identify more it's
it's a tool a diagnostic tool that you
can utilize to figure out which element
you may be experiencing which nutrient
may be limiting in your fertility regime
that's great
yeah I think you covered it anything you
want to touch on regarding zinc or icy
you mentioned even molybdenum I have
done zero work on the lib to them I
really don't know much about it overall
there's everything you want to share in
particular relating to either of those
yeah we utilized molybdenum because it
is a plant essential micronutrients but
as far as plants that often display
symptom ology and molybdenum deficiency
it's kind of hit or miss most of the
time I lived in um is more important for
nodule aiding plants so plants that will
form associations with bacteria to form
root nodules to fix atmospheric nitrogen
such as your lagoons but for example
poinsettias poinsettias will often
display a molybdenum deficiency so it
was kind of hit or miss we kind of threw
it in just for fun to kind of see what
would happen but like I said and you can
look at the the composite picture not
much symptom ology occurred and we did
not have statistically significant
differences in dry weights even though
we did receive a statistically
significant difference and leave tissue
concentration of molybdenum so basically
there was more molybdenum in the leaf
tissue in your treatment versus the
control however that didn't display
visually or in turn
of your overall biomass when you measure
the two plants it sounds like from what
I'm from what I'm getting one thing I
will say is because we use you know kelp
things like kelp meal and rock dust I
have never really worried about
molybdenum I figure we're picking some
up through those because they contain
some of those elements but I'll be
curious to see as you move through
flower looking at molybdenum if you
start to see statistically significant
differences in overall yield or
cannabinoid content that that might be
interesting because I'd like to maybe
start playing around with the addition
of molybdenum to see if it makes it has
real any real growth impact or plant
health impact yeah that's definitely
something that we'll be looking at with
regard to our statistical analysis on
the micronutrient study that we just
completed the rate over life cycle
experiment that all all of these
micronutrients it's going to be very
interesting to see what happens with the
different rates over the life cycle of
the plant cool well I think you covered
all my questions I know there's some of
the discussion explains some of your
findings which really fits with I think
we already covered most of that just in
our discussion of the elements but was
there anything else you wanted to add
regarding this research before we sign
off yeah just again to reiterate that
one of the most valuable things you can
do whenever you're looking at a problem
is utilizing the tools that you have
available to you you know looking at
what you did in the past to try and
figure out you know is for example you
used water am i providing enough water
and is that causing a nutrient issue de
facto or you know did I apply something
that may now be in interacting and a
negative effect in the soil profile and
causing another element to be plant
unavailable and again this this work
where we're still in a process we're
learning we're producing science it's
additive process so this is you know
visual symptom ology is correlated to
leaf tissue and you know these these
pictures are very helpful and useful but
again some of the symptomatology is
similar so looking at you know the
progression of the symptom ology
comparing that to the pictures and then
also looking at where on the plant those
symptoms are occurring will be extremely
useful oh I look forward to seeing
further research out of your University
and and you personally and I'm really
grateful for your time today and I look
forward to staying in touch and
hopefully we'll get to have you or
someone when your colleagues back on
soon to talk about some of the latest
research and use some of your findings
absolutely yeah we're definitely very
excited for a lot of the research we're
doing and definitely even more excited
to continue talking with growers and
producers to you know understand the
needs that they have
as far as research is concerned it's
very much a two-way street
what the industry needs and does and the
issues that they're experiencing helped
us do better research that's more
applicable and helps the industry as a
whole
so this bilateral exchange is extremely
important and definitely is something
that needs to continue in greater
quantity for all researchers that are
going to be doing work in hemp or
cannabis
[Music]
that was Paul Coxon and you were
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy don't forget to
check out our web site at
www.extracareanimalhospital.net
[Music]