[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of kiss organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge now
before starting this week's podcast I
have a couple of quick announcements
this is episode 44 at the time of this
recording it's been an amazing journey
and I've met some incredible people the
goal was to really create a platform to
help bridge the gap between cannabis
cultivation and science so far I've done
all of this for free putting in hundreds
of hours with the goal of sharing this
information and also helping people find
out about me and my company it's been
really rewarding
however due to work demands and
financial constraints I'm reaching out
now for two reasons in order to keep the
podcast going for free I'm adding a
patreon page and also some short ads in
the podcast themselves the patreon page
allows listeners to donate at a monthly
tier level starting at only $1.00 with
other tiers offering a monthly private
Google hangout group and even the
ability to co-host an episode if you've
learned something from this podcast and
want to support it this is your chance
go to WWE tree on Comm backslash ki s
organics to check it out I'm also going
to be adding short sponsorships or
advertisements to the podcast itself to
help cover the time and costs I'm going
to be really selective though about what
companies I work with and we'll only
have products and services that I would
use in my own personal garden thank you
for understanding and support of the
show let's get back to this week's
interviews my guest this week is Eleanor
Koons Eleanor is a trained herbalist and
geneticist bridging the gap between
traditional herbalism and modern science
she is co-founder of candor the people's
herbarium the first herbarium committed
to documenting and preserving cannabis
cultivars and varieties
along with the collective knowledge
gained through a community engagement
you could read more about Eleanor's
extensive educational and experiential
background on the podcast page as it's
more than I can share in this
introduction I was honored to get her on
the show to talk about the importance of
her variants and how they relate to
cannabis
hey Nora thanks for coming on the show
today
hey Todd thanks for having me it's great
to be here
yeah can we start off giving listeners a
little bit of a little bit of a
background into sort of your life and
how you came to have this role with the
with candor yes oh my my life has been a
walk through a lot of different jobs in
the plant world I started off as a
florist in high school and I've kind of
been chasing various realms of the plant
world since then I did my undergraduate
degrees in BA and biology at Smith
College and then went on really to do
some work fundamental work on
systematics through a really nice
internship at Q garden and that sort of
set the stage for my interest in plant
taxonomy and plant biodiversity and how
that biodiversity is spread across the
globe and from there I did a lot of kind
of odd jobs and things but then found
myself back in graduate school focusing
on plant genetics in particular plant
population genetics really looking at
how populations of plants are influenced
by movement so invasive species biology
and how our cultivated plants in
particular are affected by movement of
weady sister species and pests so a lot
of different things so you have a
bachelors in biology with a focus in
botany and then you also have a pH PhD
it looks like to in you said genetics
yes and my PhD in genetics and my focus
has always been on plant systems now in
addition to this you also apparently
graduated from the sage Mountain School
of herbals
so you have a background in herbology
too is that right yes before I went back
to graduate school I was unsure of
exactly the direction I wanted to take
and I took a wonderful little detour in
queue the herbal world and in a very
focused and pointed way studying to
become a trained herbalist I really
deepened my connection to the plants
through that particular educational
experience there on sage mountain and
he's knowing myself and looking at
myself I realized that my love of the
plant in the herbalism world really came
from the perspective of the plant
whereas I I enjoyed the power the plants
have to heal us my particular interest
wasn't in helping sick people but was in
helping those plants which helped us
become well once I really started to
focus on the health of the ecosystems
and the plants that we were sourcing for
our herbal medicine
Wow so you have this fascinating
background and education level and from
that it sounds like you founded this
company called candor yes so can ya
candor is a nonprofit that we started
actually and mostly spending my
day-to-day running a company called leaf
works which is a botanical
identification company so we really
focus on identifying plants for the
natural products world and for
compliance and you know fidelity not
only in packaging and labeling but also
in supply chain security so are you
really buying the plants you think
you're buying and that's where we sort
of came to the party about five years
ago when we were doing a lot of
identification and realized that with a
lot of our friends and some of my deep
family members that had been working in
cannabis for a long time a lot of the
tools and reference materials that you
would need to really make good science
happen and to make good identification
happen weren't available
Corino many many reasons which we can go
into and so that's how we came to the
necessity to found
gender really as a landing place to
understand the diversity and types that
we have within the cannabis community
okay so what exactly is a herbarium so
an herbarium is a repository it's a it's
a location and a place that holds
collections of preserved plant specimens
and then associated data that are linked
to those plant specimens and they're
used for mole of you know multiple
purpose the most primary purpose is when
you find a new species or develop a new
cultivar an herbarium is the repository
by which you would press a sample of
that plant describe that plant and then
that would be used as the reference
sample to then move forward with any
kind of research so you know if you
discover a new species of flower you're
going to make a species description and
that species description is going to be
linked to at least one preserved plant
specimen and herbarium pressing of that
plant and if you are then looking at how
that plant is distributed across space
so let's say you're looking at dandelion
and it's all across the you know Europe
in addition to North America you can
look at how dandelion differs from place
to place based on voucher specimens that
have been taken in different areas so
there's kind of two levels of utility
for an herbarium the most prime areas
you know defining type and sort of
getting everyone on the same page so you
know when we say gala Apple everyone
knows what a gala Apple is and how it's
different from something like a Granny
Smith you know I'm making that name have
meaning in a biological sense and then
on that second level we can then see
okay if we grow Gala apples and 17
different kinds of environments how do
those environments affect the Apple
itself yeah so that kind of you kind of
answered my next question which was sort
of like how do when we talk about
different chemo type expressions of the
same cultivar which cannabis is shown to
expell
express itself quite differently across
different environments what your what
you're doing then if I understand
correctly is sort of giving us a context
for that conversation by giving us a
starting point absolutely absolutely so
in that first level just making
definitions you know we have individuals
that have been stewarding plants and
have been doing breeding and I've been
caretaking particular clones for a very
long time and individuals who've worked
with specific plants really have an idea
of what is the essence of that plant
what is the chemistry what is it
structure what is the production
qualities what kinds of environments is
it excel in like we have this knowledge
and so it's really a repository by which
we can link that information to a
physical representation of that thing
and then we know that if we move that
thing from place to place it does that
you know the chemistry is going to
change in a lot of ways like that a lot
of the flower color changes right we
know a lot of different kinds of
cultivars or cannabis types that will
express these beautiful purples and
pinks if they're exposed to cold
temperatures and they won't if you you
know grow them indoors and a more even
in mild climate so monitoring how those
particular tacks are the Jeanette's very
across the environment the herbarium
itself is that physical repository so
that we can really catalog how that is
occurring and really understand that G
by E or that genetic by environmental
interaction that gives us that really
rich and very sometimes complicated
phenotype that we see with cannabis so
what are the legal implications for a
grower in terms of preserving genetics I
know I'm somewhat familiar with what the
OCP or open cannabis project is is
attempting to do on there and with
intellectual property what what sort of
I guess how does how does an herbarium
fit into this whole landscape well an
herbarium is actually the most
fundamental and basic way in which we do
this with plants right so when we were
describing roses and then you
than peonies and all of the rich history
we have with all of these these flowers
um you know we weren't using anything
beyond an herbarium and physical
descriptions of these plants to really
dictate type or dictate you know what is
a Queen Anne Rose what is a you know
lady slipper pink tea rose you know all
of these different kinds of roses and so
the herbarium acts as a very fundamental
basic step by which a breeder can define
their material make a physical
representation of that material like an
actual tangible object that is then
linked to a description a different
chemistry or genetics or any other kind
of information can be layered on top of
that voucher specimen but the voucher is
actually the physical unit that grounds
that information in reality and one of
the things that that physical
representation does much like in other
arenas with legality it offers a point
of prior art such that you can actually
reference back to type and see if it is
or is not a unique object so when you're
talking about legal forms one of the
things you really need are arenas in
which you have information about you
know prior art what is in the community
what already exists so that you can move
forward with patenting or refute
patenting based on uniqueness so from a
breeder perspective by getting the their
plant classified with someone like your
your company with an herbarium they're
essentially preserving their preserving
their genetics and allowing them
potentially a way to to defend or refute
a patent on that on that final flower is
that essentially what you're saying yes
and it's actually a much more powerful
way than using genetics because of
course with genetics with all of the
genetic service genetic services that
are out there they're giving you a panel
of snips or a very short and small
window into the genome and what
you're working which is not an accurate
representation of the entirety of the
plant the plant itself is the most
complete picture of what you're trying
to preserve and so that becomes a
reference point on which all of this
additional information can be layered
you know if you imagine you have a
hundred thousand base pairs and you're
only looking at a hundred of them it's a
very small window into what that genome
is and that can be deceptive in
uniqueness and so the herbarium itself
you know grounds that in reality within
an object that is tangible and real so
really what an herbarium does is it it
gives you sort of a historical context
like I'm I'm thinking of Linnaeus when
you say herbarium sort of this taxonomy
process of identifying really dating
back historically quite far and that
would be sort of the foundation then for
which intellectual property or genetics
could then come into play around a
particular cultivar exactly yeah that's
exactly the case and I think it's an
interesting thing when we talk about
cultivar because in plants it's it's a
very difficult concept to even wrap my
own head around but genetics does not
define cultivar it never has and it's
actually a very inappropriate way to
define cultivar because we have many
cultivars that have disparate genetic
backgrounds that are that are considered
the same cultivar and so banana is a
really good example of this where the
ladyfinger banana that we grow you know
in many different locations across the
globe and is what services our banana
intake I think the bananas we buy at the
grocery store is this cultivar banana
you know in in the majority and that
particular banana is a cross between two
different kinds of banana and there's a
lot of genetic diversity and mom and dad
and it doesn't matter you know which
individual from those populations you're
using it's the cross itself that makes
banana and so the genetics behind that
cross are exceptionally variable so you
have the situation where different Jin
medic backgrounds produce the same
cultivar and then you have the converse
example where I know most of us have
witnessed this where we have a rose or
some kind of plant in our garden where
all of a sudden the single sector of
that plant will look different
it will either have modelled leaves or a
red rose we'll all of a sudden turn into
a rose that has white stripes on it and
it'll low it'll be located on the same
plant and if you take a cutting of that
sector that is different you know it's
the same genome it's the same individual
it's almost the most identical you can
possibly get and you can clone that
differential sector and call it a new
cultivar right cuz it's different than
the parent even though the genetics are
99.9 percent the same and so genetics
itself is a very is not the most
reliable way to define cultivar
cultivars this entire picture of a plant
not just as its genetic background so if
I understand you correctly you're saying
that a different genetic expression of
essentially the same genotype with maybe
just one small mutation would create a
whole new cultivar and so yeah in your
second example so I'm just trying to
wrap my brain around all of this because
you're throwing a lot of information out
so all that being said essentially what
you're saying is that a cultivar is not
a cultivar is not its genetic makeup in
in holes only so there's more to it than
that
mmm-hmm there's much more to it than I
and the cultivars is is driven by human
selection and human definition which is
why the mission of the herbarium is so
much found in the mission of kandar's
really founded in taking the knowledge
from the community to define the
cultivars that they've enduring because
they know those plants better than
anybody else and genetics alone are not
the units that define what those
cultivars are
and in the context of cannabis I'm sure
we can all think of certain plants you
know are going to be clone only you know
there's only one Harlequin if you want
Harlequin you have to have a cutting of
that plant to have that cultivar but
then there are other plants where you
know it's a it's a cross it's a certain
cross that happens over and over and the
exact in those background of that cross
isn't what's important but it's who's a
mom and who's the dad and how that cross
plays out within that seed stock becomes
a cultivar so it's tricky
yeah well cannabis is this it's this
beautiful mess of diversity in genetics
right now I feel like and we don't have
any idea really what what we have as an
industry and I think we I think we're in
desperate need of some classifications
in a lot of ways because even even the
known genetics that are out there you
know people are constantly breeding
there we're getting new expressions of
those genetics
we're losing genetics all the time so
something like this would just would be
a way to take sort of a snapshot of one
particular are you calling them
cultivars then is that the best
nomenclature when talking about us yeah
I'm a plant biologist so I default to
that because for me that is what you
called a plant type so I I called them
cultivars I know that the the community
itself really likes the word strain for
me that's a microbiological organism so
I have a hard time calling the plant
that but I think we're all talking about
the same thing those units that hold
together as you know an essence of a
thing you know what we say chem dog we
know what we're talking about when we
see Harlequin you know what we're
talking about and you know in the
diversity that is surrounded in that
name I think really is the community's
job to come to that assessment okay so
can you explain to me how can there
might help the cannabis community sort
of document this biodiversity that
they're holding on to absolutely so
right now we're really pushing with our
our breeder allies and our breeder
friends who's been doing a bulk of you
know both of the work to really generate
new types and then also distribute those
types
differential farmers you know so we're
those those units are being developed is
our first entry into definition until
working with them to define their plants
make vouchers and then really follow
those types through the community and
different growing arenas you can you can
track not only that the sort of gold
standard of what that cultivar is but
then how growing it amongst different
farmers affects the type and the
herbarium itself becomes the resource by
which we can sort of hold that
information as a community and learn
where those boundaries are and how you
know we do get this diversity when we
grow things in different areas but the
herbarium itself is exactly as you put
it the container that holds that
information so that we can do not only
good science but also have names and
titles that make sense and are grounded
in the history of what happens with
those plants so can you take me through
the process of how a grower would would
work with with candor with this
herbarium absolutely so we visit farms
and right now we're visiting a lot of
mother rooms and we're taking cultivar
intake would include taking a vegetative
cutting of about 10 to 12 inches of the
plant and then physically pressing that
vegetative cutting it's done in a very
special cotton paper that's going to
preserve that plant for a very long time
you meant in Linnaeus earlier and he's
actually the human that did the type
specimen for cannabis and that pressing
we actually have up on our Instagram and
we'll probably repost it in the BIC so
it's a beautiful example of an art very
impressing but that's exactly what we do
we take a vegetative pressing and then
we'll also take a flowering pressing so
nothing you know you can't
once they're big glorious colas you know
it's pretty hard to get them into a two
dimensional form but you know that early
flowering
you can see flower color internodal
spacing any of the important
morphological characteristics that would
really define the type and will make a
pressing of that as well if we have
individual there's certain breeders that
we're working on like sub pools of very
active participant in the herbarium
right now and working with candor a lot
of his seeds our mother you know
specific mothers across the specific
fathers and so in that case we'll take
pressing or barium vouchers of both the
mother and the father and then a panel
of the of the F ones that are
consistently produced from that cross as
the definition of type and so whenever
we can we also include that pedigree
history to just preserve the entire
lineage of the plants as we have a
deeper understanding of where that plant
come from and how that plant holds
together as a unit
once those pressing their main the
breeder themselves will fill out some
informational forms about it you know
sort of basic stuff their flower color
spacing structure you know all those
characteristics about that plant that's
fine who that individual is so there's
some authorship in there too so you
mentioned that appeal I think and so it
would it would be his name on that page
associated with that particular flower
yes yep and then we have certain
individuals who know that our steward in
plants and it's you know maybe the
original breeder has since passed or
maybe it's been held in community so
long it's really hard to tag who is the
quote owner and we have a little visitor
plants this is a very typical thing the
carrier plants with us so it's almost an
odd thing to assign ownership to plants
but with those individuals that have a
more historical presence in the
community what you basically are doing
are offering stewardship and so you
might not be saying this is my plant but
you're saying I have skewered in this
plant since 82 this is where I got this
plant this is the history of this plant
this is who you know so you can
corroborate type in that way too and
historical framework where you know
whoever is donating that Wouter
aside you know signing their name that
they're donating it but then you know
that doesn't have to be the original
breeder it can be someone who's really
just worked to steward the plant as well
okay and so what is the cost associated
with something like this
oh goodness well right now we are all
user input so there is no initial
upfront cost to donate vouchers to the
herbarium the herbarium itself is a
resource that is open to anyone who
wants to contribute and the work is done
by that individual to make that
contribution and we facilitate that work
at the herbarium there is no auxilary
cost right now and structuring sort of
data basing and things to make the
information more accessible there will
probably be a membership fee but that
will come once we have a platform to
really share that with so we can you
know open it up to the community to have
a little more access right now it's
really about amassing that fundamental
information from that you know voucher
that like breeder level to really have a
running start to get the you know the
resource to a point where it has a lot
of utility for the greater community so
you're right now you're in the stage of
collecting samples it sounds like and
what is the end goal of the herbarium
that once you have sort of a mass this
this huge library of genetics in this
form the end goal is really to have a
resource by which that we can have
cultivar convention and have you know
select panels of people who've been
working with these plants or who are the
original breeders really come to the
table and make coats of our conventions
such that we can move the the community
itself can move their own their own
naming system forward and really be in
control of that much like you know the
Westminster Abbey dog show does for dogs
or canines where there's judgement about
who
Best in Show who's best in each class of
dog breeds it's kind of the same thing
that we're trying to grow the structure
around so that the community can do the
same kind of work where we have you know
our different breeds or our different
cultivars in in units such that everyone
has some basic agreement okay getting
everyone to agree is always a challenge
but getting to the point where we at
least have classes of you know what our
Hays is what are our cush types what our
you know all of these different groups
and then that resource itself can be the
functional tool to solve maybe disputes
or to really come to terms with what is
appropriate you know it's it's much
easier to have an argument or move
discussion forward when you have
something to point to something to
reference and so the herbarium wants to
act as that touch to move the
conversation forward in a productive way
based on real things as opposed to your
sand story
so you mentioned Hayes's so let's let's
use that as an example so in theory if
you had say five hundred or a thousand
samples of various Hayes's you could
then take an unknown cultivar or unknown
sample and compare it to that and say oh
this is this is of Hayes ancestry most
likely based on these morphological
characteristics like inner note spacing
or leaf shape or growth habit or that
sort of thing absolutely that's exactly
what you do and you know the more
historical Hayes accessions that you
have or vouchers that you have that
links back to particular breeders in
particular collective then you can go on
and do exactly what you say take an
unknown and then compare it to really
figure out how does it fit into that
context into that framework is it is it
a member of that group or not yeah so I
see I see this as being really
fascinating and I think it's something I
would that would be wonderful to look at
in a museum especially getting to see
all of these different samples
throughout various generations and just
how many
different ways this plant has been bred
and expressed I still don't feel like I
have a complete grasp though of how this
how this relates to breeders in relation
to intellectual property because I know
that's a huge concern right now in terms
of preserving genetics either from the
perspective of profiting off those
genetics or from the perspective of
sharing those genetics like what the OCP
is attempting to do how does that relate
cuz it's still a little confusing to me
yeah
so the OCP is really focusing on data so
the problem with data is that data
ownership is not truly linked to the
individual that generates the data for
example any one of us can go to a
dispensary and buy any number of plants
in the form of flower and sequence them
that does not mean that any of us own
those plants right we've just like if I
went to the grocery store I bought a
gala Apple and I sequence gala Apple
doesn't mean I own gala Apple and so the
amount of sequence data in the general
populace on GenBank or NCBI
through the oakland cannabis project or
whatever gives information to
individuals about the diversity of
cannabis that's out there but it does
nothing to link genetics to tangible
plants there's no reference point so if
I would just to take a step back as a
scientist if I'm going to go and study a
kanesha the first thing I'm going to do
if I want to make some kind of
assessments about the genetics of a
Canisius I'm going to go to an herbarium
and get a bunch of different akinesia
vouchers from you know the eight most
prevalent species of a kanesha's are in
my area and I'm going to use those
tangible voucher specimens as my
reference point for the science I'm
doing and that's what's missing is the
tangible reference point that links
abstract data which is genetic a CPG
kind of data to a real living organism
and so that's that's you know there's a
lot of different ways to encourage
emetic or you know IP but having the
genetic data linked to a real plant is a
fundamental importance to generate IP
because without the ownership of the
plant like genetic data is just genetic
data anyone can generate that does that
answer your question at all I think so
I'm still trying to wrap my brain around
it so it's a little confusing in my head
no matter what but essentially if I
understand you correctly what you're
saying is there needs to be a link
between what we're getting is from a lab
analysis and then the actual physical
plant itself so what I'm trying to
figure out is if I'm if I'm a breeder
and I want to preserve these genetics
from let's say let's say purely a
financial perspective
profit off of these genetics because
I've created a plant that has these
characteristics or this particular
genotype mm-hmm how does I guess how
does the OCP fit in and then how does
Kandor fit in what's sort of the
difference is there and what's the
importance well candor is going to be
the location where you would physically
define that plant and then make her your
physical pressings of that plant to
define type and then from that point on
any any definition that you know in the
individual breeder who's making that
accession is gonna keep copies of those
vouchers as well right so if I make it
let's say you have made you know purple
cherrybrook drop number two that's your
new plant you're gonna you're gonna make
a voucher I'm gonna keep one of the
herbarium it's going to be held in
posterity as a reference point and then
you're also going to keep that voucher
for yourself and then as these vouchers
build up it becomes a resource to the
Patent Office that when they are looking
for definitions of type 2 C is a unique
and plant I am not a lawyer and so the
intricacies of plant patenting is
exceptionally difficult and
it is very difficult to patent a plant
normally to patent a plant you have to
genetically modify it if you want to get
a varietal patent so that's the
difference between a cultivar and a
variety a variety is just a flavor of
cultivar that has a legal framework
around it like gala or arctic apple
would be a genetically modified variety
and so it's it's actually very difficult
to patent a plant itself but if you
wanted to define that cultivar the
physical representation is your first
step and then if you're going to do any
kind of genetic or chemistry you would
layer that on top of that physical
voucher as you know definitive of that
voucher right because you can have two
very different plants that if you're
just so that you're just looking at
chemistry can come up the same you know
and it doesn't mean that those plants
are the same just because the the
handful of 10 chemicals you're looking
at in a you know pantheon of the 500
chemicals happens to be similar so the
Oct is really from my understanding
really amassing data such that there's
more information in the academic
community to really get at diversity and
you know those types of questions well
I'll have to get Beth on the show here
to sort of explain a little more about
the OCP so I won't know I won't expect
you to explain about another program but
I do think that's really interesting so
you've mentioned apples
you know I would just I would say let's
stick with that example maybe with a
Honey Crisp apple for example so if I
created Honey Crisp you know I would
then go to an apple or barium and give
them again a pressing or a voucher of
that Honey Crisp apple and then from
there would I also go and get the
genetics done on an apple and at that
point what I own that particular IP or
how does that work I guess it's not
really
at that point yeah so what you do is you
would really so yeah so the PME society
has a really good forum if you google
keone society and they have new varietal
submission or new clothes of our
submission and basically what you do is
you would describe that Apple you would
describe why it is different what are
the unique attributes of that Apple so
you know maybe sugar content it might be
time to flower it might be height of the
tree you know if it's not a grafted
apple with most of them are you know it
might be of course flavor profile color
of the skin shelf-life time time to
ripening all of these characteristics
would be included in that definition and
then your consortium or your your group
so for peony that's the peony Society
for apples I'm sure they have their own
Society and they would make a judgment
is this a unique thing that deserves a
title in enough of itself right does it
deserve to be a named thing that is
unique and different from the rest of
the cultivars that we have in that Apple
come you know in that Apple group and if
it's deemed to be unique then it would
have its own name assigned to it and
those definitions would then be attached
to that name there is no need to do
genetics genetics is never in the
history of cultivars been a definite
defining and like the way you define
something I mean genetics is really
modern and cultivars and a concept of
cultivars is really old so it's kind of
a we're in an interesting place in time
where we are using modern technologies
for things um it's kind of overkill in a
lot of ways and not just Edmund I mean
I'm a geneticist it's not to pooh-pooh
genetics genetics are amazing and
powerful we can learn all kinds of
things from genetics but they aren't the
primary tool to do this work and they
never have been so from an ownership or
property perspective they're an
herbarium makes a lot more sense yeah it
makes a lot more sense especially as a
first pass because it's very very basic
and it is very attainable for anyone
there's no big cost there's no special
equipment there's no relying on anyone
elses analysis or data panel you know
marker set it is very very
straightforward this is my plant I'm
going to voucher it and then any of
those other technologies that you may
feel are beneficial to additionally
describe your material just as you know
it's just like icing on that cake just
adds to your definition that makes more
sense
so you're the foundation and then having
other things like the genetic makeup of
the genotype of that plan and even it's
maybe even it's chemo type expression
would be more assertions to support your
ownership of this unique cultivar
exactly exactly
and when synthetics I mean most of the
time like to get ownership of plant
material you actually have to physically
change the genetics of the plant and
most of our breeders aren't doing that
we're not using modern genetic
techniques to and in in most of our
classic community breeding to do that
and so I think that there's also like a
little bit of false hope that genetics
gives to people of surrounding ownership
that isn't completely based in reality
ok so just thinking this through what's
to prevent someone from bringing a
cultivar to you that maybe they did not
breed themselves maybe it originally was
a haze or a blueberry or something like
that and then claiming authorship of it
because they were the first ones to get
it into whatever accepted herbarium
becomes you know conventional standard
for the industry yeah well that's a
really good question that question kind
of persists over any of these ownership
modalities or is it the first-to-file is
it the first sequence I mean all of
these issues are very much the same the
beauty of the herbarium is because it is
a community run resource those
accessions those inputs are vetted
against the panel and the entire group
of
inputs right so if we look like Hayes
for example or chem dog maybe is a
better example you know if you have
someone who's submitting something and
they're calling it you know by a certain
name and we are comparing it to another
thing with the same name you then look
to history and the community knowledge
of that plant to make the decision about
which type is actually accurate you know
and I am very much not the person to
make that decision just like I don't
think you know anyone in the genetics
community I don't think it's their job
to make that decision I think it really
is the community itself coming together
and arguing or whatever it is to come to
consensus about where these plants come
from and what plants are what and the
nice thing about the herbarium is those
those accessions remain and then you can
come back to them and have dialogues
about what is real and what is not based
on tangible pieces of evidence and
tangible units so I see it being much
like the American Kennel Club model
where you have a group of individuals
that have been breeding dogs for a long
time and you have consensus about what
is a terrier type you know if you're
going to come to them at a Casey and say
I'm bred a new breed of dog you have
that entire group that you have to then
interact with and justify why this
particular group of crosses and your
dogs justifies becoming a new breed and
so in the same thing in the plant world
you know if you have someone coming a
thing this is you know the original haze
and it just doesn't match up with the
other ten you know accessions of haze
then you start looking at your you know
we have partners that do the historical
aspect like the 420 archive is a partner
for us or a collaborator where then you
know the historical context news stories
and the history of those plants come in
to really help parse out what's real and
what's not real it's not easy and it
in a straightforward answer to that
question no I really liked I really
liked that answer I thought I thought
you really captured it and I think that
the dog-breeding example really sort of
solidified in my head exactly what
you're describing there with a new breed
or a new cultivar so it sounds like
everyone who has a plant that they think
it's special or that has unique origins
they really should be reaching out to
you to contact you yeah which I want to
I want to give you that have you give
out that information but before I do I
didn't want to forget one question I had
is you keep mentioning the word voucher
can you talk a little bit about what a
voucher exactly entails yes a voucher is
like the gold standard of the type and
so if I've made a new new cultivar that
that voucher is the collection of those
vegetative pressing in the early
flowering pressings in concert with in
any of that additional information that
goes along to describe that that flower
that entire packet or that entire unit
would be considered the voucher of that
pays or of that 10 dog or you know of
that cherry pie number 10 whatever it is
so the voucher is just that gold
standard thing that once we've come to a
consensus this is the plant that worked
you know the name and the plant have
become solidified that voucher is the
sort of gold standard by which we can
compare other things to it to see are
there are they not that thing so you're
keeping the physical you're taking one
sample pressing that and that's the
physical sample that stays with the
herbarium but then I assume you're
creating a sort of a replication I'm
picturing like a color piece of paper
like a color printed version of this
that then would be considered the
voucher is that right so the the voucher
is actually the physical plant and then
those are digitized and they're
beautiful I mean it's just amazed I'm
eeen they're gorgeous the physical
pressings of these plants if you weren't
in love with cannabis already this will
make you just love them even more
because
you know their art and that's that
physical pressing that becomes digitized
and then the voucher of Hays would then
be that gold standard and then let's say
that I'm growing in an indoor grow in
Southern California and you're growing
outdoors and humble we could then each
donate to the herbarium field accession
so a version of the plant grown in the
field so I'm not saying I'm the original
breeder I'm just saying I know I'm
growing this plant and I'm growing it in
this environment and then you add to the
panel of information that really
surrounds that G by E like how do those
plants interact with their environment
to have that flexible phenotype that we
see so often in cannabis so then that
would be the the field level the field
accession and then all of those also
become digitized to become a resource
for the community that is contributing
to the project so if someone wanted to
get a voucher of Khem dog for example
from the herbarium down the road that
would be a digital copy that they would
be receiving it's not a physical thing
that you have to keep this tissue yeah
so so what you would do is you the the
voucher itself lives in the herbarium
and if you have reasons and because that
ear material then you would use the
voucher as the reference point but you
wouldn't actually get the voucher you
know you'd be using it as your reference
point much like you would for in this
science I'm like if I'm going to the
Smithsonian looking for those echinacea
vouchers because I want to do a project
with met in this space of
differentiation in you know how Kenisha
across you know the Prairie I'm not
they're not going to physically give me
those samples they may give me what I
need whether it's a reference point to
go back to or if I'm doing chemistry
they can give me some chemistry
profiling or if it's genetics they can
give me some genetic profiling so that I
can make sure that I'm looking at what I
think I'm looking at and based on that
voucher that they're holding about
yourself lives in the herbarium and is
digitized so all of this data once you
have collected sufficient amount is this
something that's going to be published
online or is going to be publicly
available down the road
and no it will not be publicly available
at the moment it is a hundred percent
for the community itself so if you are a
contributing member of the herbarium you
have access to the resources of the
herbarium and that's really important
it's it's not for us to you know sell to
any other outside group that's not the
point the point here is to really make
definitions for and about and by the
community such that they can own their
material and they can leverage the
information that they're collectively
gathering through the repository their
burial itself okay so if i donate
material would i have access then
specifically to just my material or
would i have access to other material in
there a barium that relates to my
donation yes so you if you are giving a
voucher of a particular type then you
have access to the voucher set like all
of the vouchers that are in the
herbarium if you are giving here a
farmer and Mendo and you're growing in
that area and you are contributing field
accession like these are the plants I'm
growing and I'm gonna give you these
accessions in my fields then you have
access to the Mendocino herbarium to
really understand how those plants are
expressing themselves within your area
so that you can utilize the resource
that you are contributing to okay so
this really is a community resource in a
sense even though it's not a public
resource I just I want to clarify that
because yeah if people are giving you
essentially this you know these genetics
or this this data just finding out sort
of what the long-term goals for that
data is and the mission of your you know
of your nonprofit I think is really
important yeah the mission is really to
help the community to find their own
cultivars that they have the power to
not only maintain access to those
cultivars but you know own those plants
and the names and the history of those
plants any other you know all of our
partnerships that would surround you
know chemistry partnerships of genetic
partnerships would really be all
done in alignment of defining cultivar
types so that those individuals donating
those types have ownership of those
types so there's no there's no in the
herbarium is not is not set up to do any
you know we don't have the financial
prowess to you know genotype all these
things or chemically analyze all these
things all of those bits of information
would come from the breeders and the
cultivators themselves submitting that
information to support the cult of our
definitions that they're defining so
essentially what you're saying is
they're not you're not giving up any
ownership of your plant by sharing this
and creating a voucher but what you are
doing is sort of adding to the richness
and history of this plant and preserving
essentially doing the opposite
essentially preserving your your
property and/or your you know what the
work that you've done in this greater
you know semi public forum or collect
yes and you're actually yeah you're
actually increasing your legitimacy of
ownership because you have a third-party
herbarium that's holding the material
that actually defines your type and so
it's actually a very effective way to
create precedent and ownership precedent
that is linked to you as the owner of
that material so if anything it actually
contributes to the lineage of ownership
by contributing you know it's it's
that's a stake in the sand you know I've
had this plant and this is the plant
then and this is how it's fine and it's
mine like the the passing of that
ownership is not is not anything but
solidified like it's only solidified for
that individual by making a contribution
well this sounds wonderful it sounds
like something everyone should do how do
people do this though if they're not
located near you yeah you know how do we
deal with state lines and and other
challenges like that around around
getting into their barium well this is
real grass roots so we you
we got herbarium scattered everywhere
we've got a very mean New England we
have many across the state of California
we got some talks of people who are
relate to house or variables up in
Oregon and Washington and so the state
line issue will become hopefully knock
on wood less of a problem as we marched
forward into sanity with our government
but as it is now the vouchering process
is happening everywhere and local or
barians are working to house that
material so that the entirety of the
community can really reach in and dig
into this resource and utilize it as a
collective so right now we're running
around to a lot of different places or
having press parties and different
things where people can come together
and start vouchering their plants in a
very social environment we have a lot of
farm meetings set up and we're touring
around in particular in Northern
California and the the northwest at the
moment and so it's really contacting us
and figuring out when we'll be in your
area and how we can connect because you
know state lines are really fake in the
trade of a plant so giving everyone
access as much as we possibly can right
now is a huge priority great so I'm
gonna post links and information on the
podcast page but can you go ahead and
just tell people where to find you and
how if I'm a grower how I can go about
getting getting my plants into their
Berrien absolutely our website is Kander
org CA nn dor org and our Instagram
handle is just candor herbarium and
either way Instagram is a really great
way to get a hold of us and we announce
a lot of our travels and where we're
going to be on the Instagram but both of
those media outlets are quick and easy
ways to get ahold of us great well
thanks for your time today and for
explaining a little more about this it
sounds like a wonderful program what you
guys are doing so thank you for your
work does there anything else you wanted
to share with podcast listeners before
signing off oh my goodness it's just
been so fun to talk about this it's
that's a lovely
to be able to talk about science and the
fun kind of cool aspects of what's going
on in the scientific community and how
it intersects with all this wonderful
history and just love of plants so it's
super exciting so thanks for taking the
time to listen to what we're doing and
yeah motivating us to continue on with
the work hey guys so the end of this
podcast is a little different than
normal after signing off I continued to
chat with Eleanor and learn more about
candor and herbariums I thought what she
shared off air was valuable and really
solidified my understandings so I'm
including it as bonus material at the
end of this podcast yeah I'm interested
to see you know how much it's so hard to
get momentum around anything you know
like I'm thinking about certifications
like trying to get an organic
certification for cannabis has been such
a challenge and I kind of see this
falling into the same category there if
just if you can get enough people around
to create enough momentum to hit that
tipping point then it could be it could
really be this amazing thing not that
it's not amazing already but no no the
snowball needs to get bigger to roll
down by itself right like that's
definitely true and that's why it's it's
just been such a lovely time in this
last year too we've really been
connecting with a lot of those you know
the breeders that are really selling a
lot of the proper tools in the market
it's just a really good entry point in
doing that because those are the places
where farmers are getting their material
if they're not generating their own
material and so that's a really good
layer to start with and then from that
you get a lot of the more home town home
home cultivated material starting to
come and people start and get interested
in realizing oh what I have is unique
and different and you know we had this
Renaissance in the you know Victorian
era with breeding of roses you know it's
not much different it's really the same
and it's really just harnessing the love
of that plant as a community and then
moving that forward so do you think
potentially we're setting ourselves up
though down the road for at least maybe
not so much me but maybe with you with
like a big legal fight with
to growers or even a corporation's
getting involved just because this
industry is worth so much money
this isn't podcast stuff by the way I'm
just curious like it's almost and less
or unless you're genetically modifying a
plant it's almost impossible to get
plant pests because you can't patent
life and I think most of us agree with
that statement you know we don't want to
patent plants in general like that's
ludicrous and so but we have plants like
for example I so I have an edible
nursery we had a plant that came on the
market a few years ago called raspberry
shortcake and Monrovia was the one
selling it it was part of this brazzle
berry series and it's this thornless
container raspberry did self-fertile is
awesome plant and yeah you're not
allowed to propagate that plant legally
I mean in theory I could but legally
you're not allowed to do that they own
the rights to that plant how does that
happen or like because that's a varietal
patent so they have a varietal patent on
that plant and that's because the
thornless trait so this is a great
example of that it's the same plant as
the next-door neighbor it just got a
mutation it's and no longer producing
stores but everywhere else in the genome
it's probably exactly the same as the
mother plant and so because of that
because it's unique and different enough
you can get a varietal patent but a
varietal patents a lot like a what is it
like a pharmaceutical patent they're
only for a certain amount of time and it
doesn't say that I can't grow that plan
it just says I can't sell propagule okay
so I could in theory propagate I just
can't make money off of that
exactly and that's because it has a
varietal patent associated with it and
so that's a lot like all of the you know
there's a really great example of like
blushing beauty pretensions we just what
ISM in English there's like base
hydrangeas so blessing Beauty hydrangea
it doesn't matter how much acid you put
on the soil you know hydrangeas turn
blue if they're in acidic soil this one
there's something wrong with a gene that
makes it blue so doesn't matter how
acidic your so your soil is that
hydrangea will always be pink and so
they have a varietal patent
it's called blushing beauty and like
loath has an exclusive right to sell the
plant okay and you know that is I think
their 15-year patent salt like 15 years
protections and they're not patents and
like on the plant
it's a varietal pest it's the name
associated with the type associated with
the ability to sell the profit you'll
huh so how do we end up with seed stock
then I I get what you're saying but I'm
wondering too like you know every year I
go out and buy Sakura red tomatoes or
you know whatever a variety of tomato
seed that is someone's making royalty on
that who created that original yeah they
have a it's a varietal patents and I
think it's like kind of a semantics
thing but it's not because a patent on a
plate you can get a patent on a plant
such that no one can do anything with
that plant is it the GMO plants but if
it's a variety like either
naturally-occurring are based on
selection that patent bets like perky
and all the seeds like Silver Queen corn
and all of the stuff the reason why they
have a Riedel patents well they have a
Riedel patent and so you can only buy
the seeds from them but those only are
certain breath of time for which those
varietal patents are valid and then
after that they're kind of like eminent
in the genetic germ plasm of the
community and you can't have ownership
anymore and it also doesn't mean that i
can't breed with that thing and change
it and make it different it just means i
can't sell that particular tomato oh but
if i took it and bred it with another
tomato dave the original person wouldn't
have ownership over it it would be
different right oh I just want kids like
when I was at the Emerald Cup this year
there was a huge line for one particular
breeder seeds and he was making a
killing on selling the seeds but then I
was I got me wondering like if he has a
plant that's considered so valuable to
this community that they're willing to
wait in line for five hours just for the
seeds because it's the latest and the
greatest
what other
does that plant have them what is he
giving up by you know selling a Caesar
essentially sharing these genetics and
that's kind of what got me thinking
about all this yeah and I mean and then
there's a coke bottle right where you
don't ever give up that recipe or you
never give that clone out you grow it in
house and you only saw the product
because you don't have and you held it
as a trade secret that's actually the
way to hold IP more tightly than any
other way mm-hmm it's just not to let it
out but it's hard to get traction
because you've got to be able to make a
market and supply the market without
letting it out yeah yeah and plants are
just weird and like plant IP like my god
please have a plant patent attorney on
your podcast I mean that's the person to
really ask because it is not easy or
straightforward and there are different
rules whether you are genetically
modifying a plant as to what you can do
as compared to if you're just doing like
normal selections from populations of
naturally occurring plants so do you
think that basically what's going to
happen is all these legal nuances will
come out until it actually becomes a
case like an actual case and then we're
going to see what what the law really is
around this stuff I think I think that
is definitely going to happen and I
think that having resources like the
Open cannabis project which is like data
dumping and herbarium where you have
physical repositories of plants that are
defined well then all of a sudden their
importance is going to really come up
when the PPO has to say oh we didn't
look at all of the all of the prior art
that's out there nor do we understand it
that's one thing that I get told
repeatedly with patent lawyers or you
know in conversation with us about how
can we utilize the herbarium in our
patent searches is they don't even know
where the resources are to know how to
analyze that right like that's a bad
situation to be in when the patent
examiner's don't even know where to look
to know how to approach the bat just
because nothing exists currently on it
yep it's a hole because it's a whole new
market yeah they won't just use the
framework from other agricultural crops
or industries well the problem is the
frameworks rather
they look at the herbarium look at the
society that is in charge of definitions
and we don't have that oh and so you're
trying to create that yeah got it that
makes more sense to me sorry
yeah and the community itself should be
in charge right it shouldn't be all
these genetic companies are saying oh
we're defining groups it's like yeah but
you're defining this is how I look at it
they're defining groups based on going
to the dog pound and sequencing every
dog in the pound and it's like well
that's making an assumption that all the
dogs in the pound are purebred and
you're making types based on those and
that's not true
ninety-nine percent of those dogs are
mutts and so you're kind of confounding
the issue by doing that and you're
actually making a lot of false data
which is not helpful to anyone so with
enough samples and enough vouchers we'll
have the community we'll have a concept
for what the actual genetic lines look
like and what what you're like
essentially what a purebred plant or our
dog would look like in your example
absolutely and then if we have arguments
about it you have reference materials to
go back to to actually answer questions
based on data as opposed to hand waving
and you know non data huh okay that
makes so much about Hays all of a sudden
you can say okay these are a thousand
hanging examples that we have out of
these thousand these hundred come from
vetted sources or these hundred are
corroborated based on more than one one
line of evidence and then you can you
know you can tear data you can structure
questions to answer them correctly you
can't do that without a resource you
can't you can't do good science without
tool that's another tool to do that
[Music]
that was Eleanor Coons co-founder of
Kandor the people's herbarium I posted a
ton of links and information relating to
this podcast right on the podcast page
at WWE is organics calm just click on
the podcast menu on the top of the home
screen and if you can please support us
on the new patreon page at patreon.com
backslash kiss organics even a dollar or
two helps stay tuned for our next
episode where we catch up with Michael
Bowman also known as mr. hemp Co author
of the 2014 farm bill to learn what's in
store for hemp in 2019 thanks for
listening