[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge as you
probably already know very little
research exists on cannabis and much of
it is not shared openly I was so excited
to see these papers and doctoral thesis
from my next guest you may wish to check
out the publications prior to listening
to this podcast or if you want to read
them after you can go to the podcast
page go to WWII s organics calm and
click on podcasts on the top of the page
and while you're there don't forget to
sign up for our newsletter on the
homepage to stay up to date on the
latest research we are doing as well my
guest this week is Darin Caplan Darin is
a horticultural scientist and the
director of plant science at flower in
Kelowna BC that spelled FL OWR he was
the first person in North America to
earn a PhD with research focused on
cannabis production Dr Kaplan has
written and published several
peer-reviewed articles on cannabis
production focusing on irrigation
growing media fertilization and
propagation he has testified on cannabis
production before the Canadian Senate
Standing Committee on agriculture and
forestry and has provided expert
commentary on cannabis for a variety of
media outlets including CBC nature and
Rolling Stone magazine now onto the show
hi Darren thanks for coming on the show
today hey thanks for having me yeah why
don't we start off giving lists there's
a little bit of your background and how
you got into essentially cannabis
research in your PhD yeah so I've kind
of always been interested in plant
science and horticulture specifically I
studied environmental science and
undergrad and when I was looking for
graduate research it was about the time
when you know they were talking about
legalizing cannabis for recreational
purposes in Canada
and I was talking to some perspective
advisors and one of them was considering
doing some research in cannabis my who
became my advisor doctor you've been
saying at the University of Guelph and
what was so exciting to me about
cannabis not that I was so involved in
the in cannabis specifically but there's
no research on the horticultural any
horticultural production aspects of
cannabis and you know for for a new
scientist starting in an industry where
you could kind of learn so much so
quickly and kind of decide what you want
to learn was was incredibly exciting for
me so it was kind of an obvious choice
and kind of the rest was history I got
deep into cannabis and I've been in the
industry for about five years doing and
a nothing but yeah that's so cool that's
the thing I love about it too is there's
so much to be discovered there's so few
horticultural plants and crops that are
even out there anymore that don't have
quite a body of research around them so
I I too am really passionate about the
fact that you you can do a lot of really
exciting work and really discover stuff
pretty quickly with cannabis yeah it's
really amazing yeah well you know what
why don't we just dive right in with
some of these papers one of the first
ones here is entitled let's see here let
me make sure I have the right one in
front of me Oh optimal rate of organic
fertilizer during the vegetative stage
for cannabis grown in two core based
substrates do you want to talk a little
bit about that study and kind of give a
give listeners little background and and
just to be clear I will put links to all
of these studies that people really want
to dive into the details of them they'll
be available on the podcast page okay
yeah so the the first study that I did
in my my graduate research was on
growing substrates and on organic
fertilization and so because there was
so little research there was almost
nothing on fertilizer or on growing
media for that was cannabis specifically
kind of started from ground up so we
looked at determining optimal fertilizer
or fertilization rates for cannabis
during
both the vegetative stage and the
flowering stage and we also custom
formulated growing substrates for both
of those stages to coincide with those
fertilizers and we were working with a
licensed cannabis producer in Ontario
called vivo cannabis and they were
supporting all this research and they're
using you know they what kind of wanted
to improve their systems and so we
tailored our research somewhat to try
and help them but also just trying to
increase the you know the body of
knowledge on these topics great so tell
me a little bit about sort of how you
establish the the methodology here and
what you were what you were exactly
testing so you mentioned you were using
cocoa core based media for your
substrate and then you fed different
levels of organic fertilizer can you
talk about what that organic fertilizer
was how you fed it and a little bit
about maybe the growth chamber yeah for
sure so all of these trials were in
controlled environment growth growth
chambers and these are just very large
kind of walking growth chambers that you
can really tightly control the
environments and that's very important
for making these results applicable to
no other growing environments because if
you have a lot of variability elsewhere
it's hard to kind of tease out the
effects of the fertilizer or if the grow
growing medium which you know for
example if the lighting is not uniform
the lighting will probably have a much
stronger effect than the fertilizer
so we custom developed these two growing
media with different container
capacities so one of them was with a
higher container capacity meaning that
it holds more water after it's saturated
and then one with a lower container
capacity so these are often considered a
high porosity or you know there's promix
HP which is a high porosity growing
medium that's an example of one so we
formulated these two based on their
container capacities to see if cannabis
prefers a dryer growing medium or a
wetter growing medium and we did that in
both vegetative and flowering stages and
then as in a full factorial experiment
we applied five different fertilizer
rates to each of these growing mediums
and
we did that during we did a whole
experiment during the vegetative stage
and in another publication we did it in
the flowering stage with two other
growing mediums that we also developed
and from that we teased out what the
optimal rate of a complete fertilizer is
for both of these stages in these
growing mediums okay and one thing I
want to highlight from your paper this
is a direct quote actually from that you
pulled out relating to the work of dr.
Zhang your adviser he mentioned
different substrates have different
physical and chemical properties
therefore it is essential to fertig
eight plants accordingly a to ensure an
adequate root zone environment so the
big takeaway I think is that we need to
realize that this study is very specific
to coco coir in the environment that you
had created and we can't necessarily
extrapolate this data across peat moss
and rock wool and and ebb and flow
systems and things like that but that
you were able to get you know a good
foundation for some possibilities for
NPK levels for for cannabis and during
the vegetative state that's right it is
one thing about these papers these these
publications or any horticultural
research for that matter is that they're
designed in that they're there they
should be widely applicable but
obviously there's limitations so
depending on your growing system if
you're using like you say you know a
hydroponic growing system with rock wall
compared to something like what we used
with organic nutrients and coco coir
you're gonna have a very different
effect but the general trend is probably
applicable so what we found is that
there is you know there is a maximum
yield at a certain certain nutrient
concentration of this organic nutrient
so you're going to find decreasing
yields after a certain rate and you can
use the you know the salt content in the
substrate maybe as an indicator of that
and also we found that if you fertilize
too much then you're actually getting a
dilution effect on some of the
cannabinoids and that's probably
applicable kind of across the board it's
because it's likely a response to high
salinity in the growing media
yeah I saw that I thought that was
really interesting so what would you say
based on your you know the environment
that you created here with nutrients
what did you find to be the optimal sort
of NPK level for cannabis based on this
test result in cocoa core with your Seco
so we didn't actually look at different
NPK levels this was one complete
fertilizer from the vegetative stage and
a different complete fertilizer for the
flowering stage and what we looked at
was the the rate of that fertilizer so
basically we're determining if cannabis
was a you know heavy feeder a light
feeder in general in this one cultivar
specifically and we weren't actually
looking at all about the the NPK ratios
okay so you had a specific NPK
fertilizer and you weren't look you were
looking at just the concentration that
you fed that fertilizer what was optimal
that makes sense so you're not
necessarily looking at how to adjust you
know nitrogen phosphorus potassium and
the variety of other anions and cations
to the plant can uptake but rather just
whatever concentration was best in your
environment that's right so based on
that I wanted something you mentioned
there I just wanted to highlight you
mentioned that you think salinity has an
effect but that you actually saw a
decrease in certain cannabinoids and THC
when you hit a certain level of
fertigation can you just talk a little
bit more about that that's right so we
found that up to a certain point the
increasing fertilizer would increase the
yield would increase cannabinoid content
and and that was positive but after a
point after a certain point there was
decreasing returns and then after at a
fairly high rate we'd actually found a
dilution of we found th c th CA and CB
GA in this cultivar those all decreased
when you that's right
certain concentration and you know just
to kind of expand out on that I'm
curious why you chose organic fertilizer
because it's so much more common in you
know in academic research to use mineral
salts or chemical fertilizers for the
you know ability to really control
uptake can you talk a little bit about
that yeah that was a fairly difficult
choice one one part of that was that the
producer that we were working with was
growing organically so we wanted to
match what they were doing to help to
you know they were fighting the project
we wanted to help them as much as we
could but we also had a you know
environmental aspect to this we're using
cocoa coiour because a lot of growers
are are moving towards cocoa coiour as
an environmentally sustainable
alternative to peat I won't get into
that that argument but it's some
consider it more environmentally
sustainable and we want to have that
angle and yes it would have been more
widely applicable if we did salt wood
for information we're actually doing
that now at in the same lab but we want
to focus on you know this being
completely organic and sustainable okay
yeah I mean the coco coir versus peat
argument could go for an entire podcast
and I have my opinion and I'm sure you
have one too so we won't get into that
too much but I guess my question really
not to is how how do you feel nutrient
uptake relates to the ability to do
these research this research with an
organic nutrient I mean a lot of what of
the growers that I work with are doing
and I know you're good friends with
David David Bernard Peron who's a friend
of mine as well the idea of putting in a
lot of these dry amendments in meal
forms directly into a living soil and
not really having as much control over
uptake you know that you have that
nutrient cycling process that's being
really driven by plant exudates and you
know microbial activity how does that
factor in when you're trying to do
research or how that might impact I
guess the results of you know of a study
like this using organic fertilizer yeah
studying organic fertilizer is
incredibly complex as I'm sure you know
because from listening to your podcast I
know you're very familiar with that
would that work it's there's a million
factors and it's very hard to control
for them and so my opinion it's at this
point it's impossible to control for a
lot of those factors it's really kind of
just finding a solution that works and
understanding that we're not going to
understand why it works at this point in
time and you know leaving that for a
little bit later when we have some more
time to tease apart you know the
microbial interactions how nitrogen
breaks down and the different forms of
nitrogen and other macro micronutrients
it's fairly complex but growers still
need to have answers to these questions
now because they are growing organically
and they still need these you know
practical practical research to support
their activities I like that so
essentially what what you're doing is
looking for trends like you mentioned
that can be sort of possibly
extrapolated are used across other forms
of growing I know with with the work I'm
doing with Ben Higgins and Nate over at
gold leaf gardens what we try and do is
say okay living soil this microbial
diversity that's just one variable and
we can't control it we can't fully
understand it but we can control for it
and say that all you know all of our
replications are going to be in a
similar soil mix with you know similar
microbial levels and biomass and then we
can make one change in say lighting or a
cultivar or our nutrient levels in that
system and then try and figure out sort
of a trend based on that but we're not
like you said we're not going to fully
understand exactly how the process is
working and and that's one of the
challenges I find with any organic
research is a lot of a lot of
researchers don't want to do that work
because they can't control every aspect
plant growth you kind of some of it is
up to sort of that microbial response
and interaction exactly it becomes much
more kind of applied science than than
pure science and that for a lot of
researchers that's fairly difficult
because again we don't know much about
cannabis so you know why not start from
the beginning but we also you know all
of North America jumped into this
industry and we have hundreds of
hundreds and hundreds of growers who are
already it will already need this
information so giving them something
that's useful for me at this point is a
little bit more important than really
understanding every single aspect of it
yeah I love that so what would be your
you know I know we've talked about a
little bit but what let's just say what
were your big takeaways from this paper
and then we'll you know also the
flowering paper so essentially a very
similar trial but looking at organic
fertilizer rates during the flowering
stage what would be your big sort of
like highlight points for growers
looking at the the research that you did
yeah so I'll break it down by growth
stage so in the vegetative stage we
found that cannabis can tolerate a range
of growing media parameters so we had
the wetter substrate and the drier
substrate performed well in both we
found a relatively high rate of organic
fertilizer to be optimum so if you're
looking at milligrams of nitrogen per
liter
you know equivalent of a complete
fertilizer it's on the high end compared
to most other crops so if you're looking
at if you know your your nitrogen rates
for tomatoes for example an organic
fertilizer you can probably fit it in
with that or you know maybe even a
little bit higher so that's as a general
rule that's I think that's fairly
applicable kind of across the board in
terms of the flowering stage we had some
more complex results so again we had
increasing fertile increasing yield with
increasing fertilizer rate and that was
for both growing substrates but we found
that the dryer growing substrate the
higher porosity one produced 13 or 11
percent higher yields and
also larger plants so it's likely that
cannabis in the flowering stage prefers
a drier substrate and to put that in
context because it's a drier substrate
it needed to be irrigated more
frequently so it's hard to tease apart
whether it was increased irrigation
frequency that it likes or whether it
likes drier substrate but either way
you'll have the same effect by using a
drier substrate and anecdotally we've
been doing a lot more with blue mats
which is an osmosis based system that
regulates moisture temperature moisture
level in soil and keeps it even so it's
a sort of a drip drip irrigation system
that is based off of the moisture
content of the soil so you're
maintaining it within a very small range
and we've you know again this is just
some some really preliminary work with
gold leaf but we found actually
substantially increased yields by that
more frequent watering and were the
hypothesis is that we're getting better
nutrient cycling because the microbes
are being held in a range of moisture
content that is optimal for them to
cycle these nutrients for the plant but
again this is all really preliminary
preliminary research that makes a lot of
sense to be honest and kind of looking
into the literature on this subject I
did quite a bit of research on
irrigation for cannabis as well and I
think we'll talk about that later but
increased frequency that has a lot of
benefits not just under microbial
populations but also just in making
nutrients more available because most
nutrients are actually transported
through mass transport with with the
water so it's if there's more water than
more likely that the plant can uptake
nutrients so that makes a lot of sense
okay that's interesting so one of the
things though about your about this to
studies that I I thought I noticed that
you highlighted was that the yield
increased with the increasing fertilizer
rate with one of them the what you call
you to HP your yield rich reached a
maximum
and in the you to yield increased
literally do you want to just touch on
that a little bit in terms of your
yields and I know you mentioned that
your yields were a little bit lower than
what you've seen as an industry standard
or what you were using for an industry
standard that's right so in terms of
that that kind of plateaued that we saw
in the dryer substrate and that's the
you to HP in general the yield was
higher so we believe that it was able to
reach a plateau and and so there was you
kind of see more of a maximum at that
point and we don't think that the the
letter substrate actually reached that
plateau so that is kind of how we or how
we explain that difference in the trend
with increasing fertilizer rate and on
unyielding on pH to a little bit can you
talk a little bit about sort of your
what you noticed in terms of pH range
and how that might have affected yield
off the top of my head I can't recall
the ranges that we found were optimum
but we generally found that during both
growth growth stages that cannabis had a
fairly wide range of pH tolerances and
we didn't character we didn't do
nutrient issue nutrient analysis to
quantify that but just being
horticultural scientists we have a
fairly general idea of when our plants
are are their nutrient deficient so
they're showing signs of high or low pH
and it's generally believed that you
want to keep cannabis a no play tight
range of pH especially with hydroponics
but we found that there was almost no
difference with a higher or lower pH
range quite a bit outside of the normal
range
yeah anecdotally I've found the same
thing with a lot of a lot of different
soil tests that I've seen I've seen some
soil tests where the pH is quite high
very alkaline and yet visually and with
with growers their yields are still
quite good it seems to tolerate like you
mentioned quite a wide range of pH
in your paper here you say within the
measured range of substrate pH with a
means of five point one to seven point
four in the flowering stage there were
no visual signs of pH induced disorders
this observation overlaps the acceptable
range cited in Caplan at all 2017 of six
point seven to seven point two for the
flowering stage yeah I'm glad you have
that in front of you yeah yeah so we
yeah we could get quite high in pH and
again there was no visible symptoms of
nutrient disorders though I just thought
that was really interesting so I didn't
want to touch on that but I mean there's
a lot more in these papers I know we're
not gonna cover everything was there
anything else you want to talk about
those two before we move on to the other
two which I think are even more
interesting in terms of some of the
results yeah well in the flowering stage
I just want to talk about how the
increasing fertilizer rate influenced
some of the cannabinoids and so I
briefly touched on this in the beginning
but it wasn't all the cannabinoids that
had a dilution effect with increasing
fertilizer and it was it's not a
dilution in terms of absolute
concentration in the flower but it's a
dilution in terms of the grams of THC or
THC a or CBG per plant so it's a
function of yield and of concentration
and effectively if you're trying to you
know if your target is to produce as
much THC as THC as possible you have
decreasing returns if you are increasing
your fertilizer rate passed the optimum
that we figured out and you'd have to
figure out your own optimum in your
production environment but there's no
benefit in terms even if you're in
seeing a little bit you know increasing
yields it's not always better to keep
increasing the fertilizer rate because
you're not increasing your THC or your
THC a or your CBG a that's really
interesting yeah and the fertilizer that
you used I don't have that part in front
of me right now I it's somewhere in all
these stack of papers but I think it was
around like a four one two four one yeah
that's right
for the vegetative stage it was a four
one point
31.7 okay and then for the flowering
stage it was a 2.8 and sorry 20.8 3.2
that's that's really interesting because
I saw another gentleman with a
fertilizer company at a small scientist
convention or Society meeting and he was
saying for one one was the levels that
he targeted one thing that I found which
seems similar to the fertilizer you're
using his potassium seems to be more of
a controlling variable for overall plant
yield than phosphorus because I know
that in this industry everyone thinks we
need more and more phosphorus for
flowering but it seems to be massively
over applied based on the research I've
I've seen I can you touch a little bit
about I know we thought we need to talk
about nitrogen too but let's talk about
phosphorus and potassium and sort of
what your findings are with cannabis yes
I'm not a mother
I'm not incredibly familiar with this
but in my kind of general impression is
that phosphorus is often over applied in
agriculture and that's because it
doesn't do all that much damage if you
over apply it but there's a certain you
know there's certain low range that
you'd probably have equal equal results
with but I'd say if you were to double
or triple it you might have the same
results and you know for a grower
doesn't make much of a difference but
for the environment for example
phosphorus is one of the most damaging
components of fertilizer and so it
really does have some implications if
we're over utilizing phosphorus yeah
that's a I'm glad you mentioned the
environmental impacts because to me
that's the that's the biggest reason for
us to limit phosphorus because we are
the cannabis industry is a big culprit
of that can we talk a little bit about
nitrogen because I asked you a question
off air about how when you read these
papers it's all correlated around
nitrogen or and
per liter get in and you kind of
explained that to me a little bit
further can you kind of reiterate that
for listeners yeah so in both of these
publications we express nitrogen in in
milligrams or we express fertilizer rate
in milligrams of nitrogen per liter and
that's a common terminology in these
types of papers and it's basically just
if you you have to look back at the
analysis of the fertilizer and it's a
relative amount of that fertilizer it
doesn't really have to do I'm not you're
not actively changing the amount of
nitrogen in in the ratio it's just how
much of that how much total of that
fertilizer are you applying so it's
important to keep that in mind and these
papers are not about rates of nitrogen
there were about rates of organic
fertilizer and they're not about
identifying the type of nitrogen you're
not distinguishing between nitrates or
ammonia you're looking at that's
strictly total nitrogen you said that's
right but the ratios are available in
the publication of ammonium and nitrate
yes and then the other thing I noticed
when looking at that fertilizer mix it
was quite low in trace trace minerals
the you know copper manganese right yeah
of those do you think that could have
had some sort of effect on the on the
trial itself or overall plant growth or
yield to my recollection we actually had
a micronutrient additive in both of
these in all the fertilizers and I I
know for sure you had one in the
flowering one you might have been
vegetative and I just totally missed it
that's probably the likely culprit yeah
and even if it was if there wasn't one
in the flowering stage it was only a
period of maybe 20 days so it's very
unlikely to see micronutrient issues in
such a short period but in the flowering
stage definitely it was necessary it
would have been necessary at least we
didn't try without it but just based on
experiences like you necessary so we
could do further there's plenty of
further research to do in general but
but around like optimal NPK levels
optimal fertilizer concentrations
various substrates and optimal trace
mineral levels that you know for for
cannabis yeah
oh there's honestly so much to be done
I'm very interested in looking at the
different NPK ratios and looking at
people you know actually teasing out
ideal pH ranges and substrate salinity
levels is really important you know
irrigation all that and and keeping it's
really important again to reiterate it's
important to keep in mind that it's kind
of a whole system's approach where you
have to if you change your fertilizer
you also have to adjust your irrigation
and your growing medium and your your
lighting and the vapor pressure deficits
in the environment and the co2 and
everything has to kind of be understood
as a whole and if you do portray the
research in a way where you're
expressing all those things it's easier
to take that information and apply it
elsewhere that's a really really good
point yeah I'm glad you mentioned that
and this is a little bit of a sidebar
but I just want to remind listeners that
there's there are people out there that
claim they know you know the optimal
amount of manganese a cannabis plant
needs or the optimal amount of zaker
or all of these different all these
different minerals but really the
research just hasn't been done and so if
they're that confident I would be a
little bit concerned about about what
they're actually saying or sharing
because I know you didn't know quite a
bit of research trying to find research
and they're just it just doesn't exist
so I would just caution listeners around
in that regard when people make
conclusive comments regarding this crop
or this plan yeah that's really
important and that's the number one
issue I run into working with growers
like I do now so it's just for context
these two publications were there put a
couple years ago they were the first
publications on fertilizer rage and you
know in indoor cannabis pretty much ever
so there's really nothing out there
that's you know in my opinion of any
validity other than these and whatever
comes next and for for fertilizer
companies to be basing their claims off
of unless they're doing really rigorous
R&amp;D
yeah which is possible and and there are
people doing research and a lot of it
they'll just claim as proprietary and
not share it but most likely at least
what I've seen in the fertilizer bottle
nutrient industry around cannabis is a
lot of it is just speculation and claims
and snake oil versus actual science to
support what they're doing and I'd love
to talk to you about that as well after
the fact because in my current position
I'm working with
Hawthorn gardening company which now
which is acquired general hydroponics
and botanic air all sorts of other
companies that service the cannabis
industry and my role is going to be to
do exactly what we're talking about and
try and figure out what makes these
products work how can we make them
better and how can we develop new
products that are based off of good
science rather than just claims well why
don't we just touch on that now and then
come back to these last two papers you
mentioned at Hawthorn you know they are
they I believe they're a subsidiary of
Monsanto now of Scots yes I apologize
you're right of Scots no association
with mums
that's true i yeah you're you're 100%
correct on that I apologize
well they do sell they do sell Monsanto
products right so there is a partnership
there but not yeah they have a license
for Roundup I believe yeah for the
glyphosate yes okay so I'm glad we rated
that but when we're talking about these
companies that are coming into the
cannabis industry like like Scott's yeah
and funding around research in terms of
who can afford funding how do you see
you know one of the questions I had for
you that I mentioned off air was what do
you see is the future of academic
research with cannabis is funding going
to be an issue and who's going to drive
really that funding once you have
legalization both here on the federal
level both here in the United States and
in Canada yeah you know it's a very
exciting time for research in cannabis
in my personal opinion I've never found
there to be limitations on funding in
Canada specifically on academic research
for cannabis we have lots of working
with the University of Guelph we had
lots of growers approached us and also
vendors of specific products that want
to prove their claims and coming to
university is a really great way of
doing that and supporting a graduate
student or supporting some independent
research to be able to actually you know
make the claims on your bottle or on
your container make them mean something
and so that's happening a lot and I
think there's a lot of potential for
both both companies and for academic
researchers to to bring some validity to
some of these products and some of these
claims and there's a lot of work to be
done and it seems to be happening so I
know that Scott's in acquiring all these
companies they you know they're a
company that that backs all of their
claims and you know that's a very
established company and if they're going
to say something on their bottle they
have to they have to be able to
substantiate it and so now we're doing
that work for all of these these
products they're being marketed to the
cannabis industry and so we're gonna
have that kind of like level of rigor in
in the products that are being sold by
Hawthorne okay and just to be totally
transparent here as someone who's not a
huge fan of some of these larger
companies you know like Scott's and
Hawthorne in terms of their role in the
industry which is separate from the
quality of their products or the
research they're doing I want to make
that very clear I'm not a huge fan of
glyphosate for one but if we're talking
about if we're talking about university
research around products and let's just
take you know a general hydro grow
formula for example I think it's awesome
that research is being done to improve
the quality of that product how do you
other companies compete and not be run
out of the industry assuming that they
can't afford you know the hundreds of
thousands of dollars that may go into
setting up a university trial so there's
various ways you can do it you know if
you if you hire a scientist on your team
who's you know a well-respected
horticultural scientists to do trials on
your product and you can produce white
papers or even publications yourself and
prove that they're valid then that's
just as good there's definitely an edge
and having you know we have a 40,000
square foot purpose-built research
facility with dozens of grow rooms and
you know all these resources which you
know in in our purposes and for Hawthorn
and for flower which is the company that
I actually work for you know there's
obviously an edge and we're gonna be
able to answer these questions faster
but it doesn't mean that it's impossible
for some of the smaller players to be
able to do the same work to the same
rigor I think that's a really good point
so there's no there's nothing to stop
other people from doing you know
research collection or data collection
their own research I mean we're doing
our own research down and gold leaf
through through that facility but you're
told you're totally right about that and
I think well I just I think it's great
that there is more research and you know
where that money's coming from can be a
little bit challenging for people but
the end of the day like as long as that
research is published it becomes useful
information that everyone can kind of
draw from draw from and improve our
overall body of knowledge around this
plant do you see all the research though
being published on the sorts of work
they at least what you're doing there in
Canada yeah there's definitely gonna be
some some of Italy released a lot of it
will be kind of for the technical
service reps to be able to inform the
the people that were selling to or the
Hawthorn is selling to you know what
they're using and how to use it
but right now it's you know we haven't
we haven't been any of this work yet
still coming up but there's definitely
plans to be to put some of this out and
to do some peer-reviewed peer-reviewed
publications and really to increase the
body of knowledge because it you know in
my in my opinion if you if you have
these resources it's kind of a
responsibility to be increasing the body
of knowledge for everyone not just you
know making claims on bottles so would
you say as a scientist you're more of
like I guess um I don't know a product
atheist in the sense that you're you're
most interested in just furthering
the amount of research and knowledge in
the industry around around this
particular crop and and Hawthorne is
able to provide you with a level of
funding that allows you to do that
research yeah let me clarify my position
and with the the Hawthorn flower and
everything like that so i'm i'm the
director of plant science at flower
which is a licensed cannabis producer
and basically Hawthorn has partnered
with flower to build this facility so
we're experts in facility building
management cultivation specifically for
cannabis and we're probably the foremost
experts in the world in that area so my
specific role is not necessarily to to
be doing the the Holford research but to
ensure that everything like to work with
them to make sure everything they're
doing makes sense for in terms of
cannabis and not just you know not moms
or ornamental is that maybe they've done
research with before and so yeah so I'm
not I'm not stuck with any products or
anything that I just want to make sure
that science is being done well and that
it's you know widely applicable and that
people can actually gain something from
all of this yeah for sure please don't
take my comments is trying to give you a
hard time about any of this I don't know
I'm not okay well cool I'm glad we I'm
glad we touched on that because I think
that's important and I think that's
something this is a little bit of a
tangent but when we look at research and
how its funded I think that's something
that you should always consider to when
you're looking at research is who's
paying for that study and why are they
doing that can sometimes create a little
bit of bias around results but at the
end of the day it's still more useful to
have that information out there and have
something be peer reviewed I think is
really important yeah I agree
so alright let's dive into these other
papers that I'm actually really excited
to talk about do you want to do the
propagation one or the the stress
testing that you did let's talk
propagation first cool okay well you
want to just give me the some of the
what she set up with this trial and and
what some of the highlights were kind of
abstract yeah so so this trial came
about basically you know working with
vivo and working with other cannabis
producers and observe
some of the horticultural practices that
they were doing as we were doing other
research you know we're working on the
fertilizer stuff and working on the
growing media work we found that some
things maybe didn't make sense to us as
a horticultural scientists and just with
you know basically understandings in
plant physiology and propagation for
example is and what with this paper we
looked at propagation so we found some
interesting practices
one of those was that growers are often
cutting the tips of their of the leaves
off of their clones before they're
cloning them we also found that there
was a lot of kind of widely held
strongly held beliefs that you had to
take cuts from a certain area of the
plant and we just wanted to kind of you
know test it out and see what's right
because a lot of these growers have been
doing it for decades and they're their
knowledge is incredibly incredibly
valuable especially in the absence of
what the literature there's no
literature so we really have nothing to
base to base our horticultural knowledge
on so we wanted to kind of tease apart
some of these factors that growers were
regular regularly choosing to go with
and so we did a fairly large trial on
how to improve the success and quality
of cannabis stem cuttings or clones
looking at four factors we looked at the
number of leaves on the plant on the
cutting we looked at whether the tips of
the leaves were removed or not and we
also looked at the position of the
cuttings so are they're from the top or
the bottom of the plant the apical or
the basal region and we looked at two
rooting hormones one was an organic
willow based extract and one was a
traditional IBA rooting hormone yeah
great so what did you find and when you
say the cutting the tips of the leaves
you're talking about you define that as
removing 30% of the of the leaf from the
outside most growers are going to know
exactly we were talking about cuz I mean
it's something I did the very first time
I cloned because I was told that's what
you were supposed to do exactly yeah
yeah what did you find with this so I'll
start off with the most interesting
finding basically we found that cut
the tips of the leaves in pretty much
every situation reduced routing success
by about 20% and as a as a plant
scientist it makes sense here you're
damaging the plant you're causing a
wound and you're reducing the
photosynthetic area in a way that's
that's also that's also think you could
decrease the the area the number of
leaves which is has the same effect of
removing the tips of the leaves if
you're just looking at leaf area but
you're causing a wound as well so it
kind of made sense and it was really
interesting and you know we've talked a
lot of growers and they've already
change their practices based on this
publication so I was really really happy
to find that some of the other findings
are also interesting we found that in
terms of rooting qualities so not just
if they root it or not but kind of how
many roots the plants produce after they
rooted we found that two leaves had
quite a bit higher rooting quality than
sorry three leaves had higher rooting
quality than two we also found that the
ivy a based rooting hormone drastically
increased their rooting success which we
kind of expected but that doesn't mean
that there's not an organic alternative
it just means that this specific project
product didn't didn't work very well and
yeah the biggest finding there was the
the cutting of leaf tips yeah that's a
huge one so the way it was described to
me was you want to cut the leaf tips off
because you want the plant to focus its
energy on rooting not so much on
photosynthesis and and trying to grow so
that's that was why you're supposed to
do it yeah but what but what you're what
you're saying is you do not science
shows based on this study do not cut the
leaf tips that's right so there's two
there was two reasons that I've heard
for for doing for this practice the
first is exactly what you just said is
focusing the energy if plants don't
focus energy that's not really how
plants work and but I've heard that a
lot the other one that makes a lot more
sense is just reducing clutter in the
propagation environment so if you're
growing in a dome if you're if you're
rooting in it under a dome of high
density that's using a rock loss
for example then you're going to run
into issues with dancing off and and
root pathogens and if the leaves are
really congested and shading each other
or touching each other then it's more
likely that you're going to proliferate
these root pathogens and so reducing the
leaf area makes a lot of sense in that
situation but if you have fewer leaves
we found that you don't have a lower
rooting success rate you'll just have a
slightly lower root quality so that's
kind of the way to mitigate that problem
is just to have fewer leaves instead of
actually damaging the roots because then
your even your opening wounds to let the
pathogens in and it's a whole other
situation so it's better to remove an
entire leaf than it is to cut the leaf
tips if you need to reduce it and then
you didn't really touch on humidity that
was the other thing the other reason I
heard now that you kind of reminded me
was that it'll reduce the amount of you
know transpiration and humidity under
that dome situation yeah so when you're
when you're taking cuttings they don't
have any roots so if with vegetative
stem cuttings literally all the moisture
to keep those plants from wilting is
coming from the environment and so you
do want to maintain very high levels of
humidity but with that humidity comes
higher instances of root pathogens
because they also like that high
humidity so you just want it to be you
want to be humid with good air
circulation and you don't want the the
plants to kind of be touching solid
surfaces or touching each other because
then you have these pockets of
condensation on the leaves and that's
really the worst situation for for root
pathogens so maybe we need to design our
propagation spaces to be a little bit
better spacing in between the clones
rather than that's right
other other options for controlling that
yeah so that's what I've seen a lot of
growers and move towards that in just
spacing out they're clones more but then
you need you know 2 or 3 times larger
propagation environment so what I've
been working towards the flower which I
can't discuss too in too much detail but
it's just ways of
mitigating control in the environment
such that you can have those high
densities and still produce very high
quality cuts and all you have to do is
you know control the environment a
little bit now from an organic
perspective what do you think about the
possibility of testing other types of
organic rooting hormones things like
what would I be found naturally in kelp
or I know people use a lot of micro
eyes'll fungus which I'm not convinced
makes any difference on a in a cloning
situation but I know some people have
made claims around that I'd be curious
to hear your opinions around micro
eyes'll fungus and then aloe is another
one that I've seen a lot of people
moving towards with cloning can you talk
about any of those as options for at
least some some new research or anything
you know about them so all I can say is
that I didn't find anything in the
literature to suggest any other organic
alternative rooting hormones that
actually work and obviously don't work
because especially with organic just
like we talked about previously that
there's very hard to research on that so
often people will just find a product
their practice and it'll work and those
continue doing it and you know that kind
of gets overseen by the by by scientists
so there's probably something that works
I haven't seen anything else that that
works anywhere near as well as as a an
oxen based burning hormone but I would
love to see it if someone if someone
figures something out so we need further
research on that sort of thing is
essentially where we loaded first for
sure yeah cool well any other highlights
from the the propagation one I know we
didn't touch on it for very long but I
think you really nailed all the big
points there was anything else you
wanted to highlight from that um the one
one small point that I didn't touch on
was that there was no difference in in
rooting success or route quality from
based on where you took your cuttings so
from the apical region of the basal
region to the top or the bottom and
that's really interesting because again
that's a commonly held belief that
taking cuttings from the top of the
plant will give you a better rooting
success and that's that
actually found it on something in other
plants that is the case but in this
situation to play was not the case for
cannabis that is really interesting you
know one other thing I want to touch on
to that you mentioned is and this is a
quote from the paper cuttings from
juvenile plants generally have improved
rooting over those from mature plants
Altamura in 1996 and juvenile plant
materials sometimes has a higher content
of endogenous auxins and other rooting
promoters compared with mature material
and you quoted houston and pal 2006 on
that yeah that's basically what it's
like what I said so other plants have
more distinct mature and juvenile
regions that have again more distinct
levels of hormones such as auxins that
will influence the way that they root
when you when you take stem cuttings
from them so again that didn't appear to
be the case with cannabis but it is a
case with other plants so do you think
that there might be a case for keeping
other plants for shorter amounts of time
based on any research that you've done
in terms of you know keeping a mother
plant for six months versus changing out
your mother plants more frequently any
thoughts on that I'm based on my
research nothing now I haven't seen any
preference either way out like from
experience there is a definitely a
difference that your if you're working
with a two three year old mother plant
there there always if there appears to
be difference but the reason for that
I'm really not sure I'm not sure if
there's some kind of you know genetic
reason or if you just have you know
increased viral load in in the plants or
the plants just have these kind of
accumulated levels of stress which
changes some of the hormone levels
there's that's another research question
to be honest okay great
well let's talk about this paper that
I'm probably most excited about I mean
they're all really really great and
interesting but you know stress is such
an stress response is just such a
fascinating topic when it comes to
cannabis do you wanna talk a little
about the the trial that you set up or
the study you
you worked on here sure yeah so
basically it's it's pretty well
documented in the literature that
drought stress specifically is a major
stimulator of secondary metabolites in
plants and so a recognizable example of
this is in herbs and spices that are
grown in regions like the Mediterranean
that are semi-arid so they have
intermittent drought stress and lots of
sunlight and those factors are linked to
more aromatic herbs and abundant
essential oil in the literature we
didn't find obviously anything on
drought-stressed cannabis because it was
again nothing but we wanted to see if we
could apply apply a controlled level of
drug stress to cannabis and see if we
can elicit some some positive response
in terms of cannabinoid content in the
in the dry flour or terpene content
that's the general gist of what we
wanted to do okay and then so how did
you determine the parameters of this
because one of the things he touched on
is how drought stress timing is also
really important in terms of minimizing
yield or dry weight loss and maximizing
your essential oil yield and
concentrated these metabolites how did
you come up with the you know rates that
you did yes drug stress is an incredibly
complicated complicated stress to apply
as I found in doing this research so
there's a lot of ways you can applied
your out stress and I'll talk about the
timing as well but in terms of just just
application of drug stress you you want
to reach a certain level you want to
quantify stress which is a difficult
thing to do
and you can also apply the stress in
different ways so you can like you were
saying you can control the moisture
content like the project that you're
working on you control the moisture
content to a certain level and just
maintain it at that certain level and so
that's one way of applying trout stress
the other way is growing your plants in
a solution that has a very high level of
salts and that that mimics drought
stress because the plants can't actually
uptake water
but if you're trying to replicate how
drought stress is I know happened in
nature it's true gradual substrate
drying so the soil for example would dry
to a certain point over time and the
plant would experience stress
incrementally over that periods with you
know experiencing starting with very
little stress and then more and more
stress until eventually the plants re
watered and so that's what we wanted to
mimic and in terms of the timing we
forget you know again the preliminary
trial it's the first of its kind so we
wanted to do you know one treatment that
we thought would have the most effect so
we looked at when in general
cannabinoids you know how they
accumulate over time and we picked the
point of maximum accumulation to be the
point when we applied the drought stress
and that was fairly late in the
flowering stage for the called for that
we use called nebula so when is that
nebula cultivar typically typically
harvested that what sort of day of
flower and when did you apply the stress
level the drought stress yeah so it I
believe we harvested at nine weeks after
changing the light cycle and we applied
the drought stress at week seven okay
yeah cuz I've seen you know it's a
common thread around growers well
they're well they'll stop watering for
the last week or the last few days or
they'll do make massive changes with the
lights I've even heard of people you
know changing the conditions in their
grow room quite dramatically in terms of
temperature all these different ways of
triggering stress so you went with at
seven weeks you allowed the plants to
visibly wilt I believe that was one of
your drought stress indicators and at
least the most practical one for growers
to look at what did you find when you
did that so okay in terms of the drought
stress threshold it's actually
determining when the plants were
stressed we looked at wilting which
again is something that growers can
actually see but wilting wilting
response is not the same between species
so some plants will be very damaged
before they
and some will wilt way before they
experience any permanent damage so it's
not really a you can't just assume that
it's a good indicator of stress we did
find that it was a good indicator in
cannabis which is useful now but before
we couldn't make that assumption so we
use these these pieces of equipment
they're very high-tech and pieces of
equipment called in situ stem sigh
kilometers and this is something that
was invented by one of my advisers it's
it's a device that connects directly to
the vasculature on the stem of the plant
and it measures in real time the plant
water water status which is effectively
kind of like that the pulse of the plant
so if it really needs water that the
water status will change and you can
even you know flick a leaf and you'll
see in real time a change in the water
status it's that sensitive so there are
regardless of wilting there's standards
in water status that will tell you if a
plant is stress then we used that as our
drought stress threshold and then
applied that to welding after the fact
that's so cool I wish I wish I could
play around with one of those so it's
measuring essentially what's going up
and down through the xylem is that right
or am i it's not it's not necessary yeah
that there's someone there there's some
SAP flow meters which measures flow but
this is more measuring water status so
it's a it's a metric of kind of the
water pressure a plant experiences which
the function function of the environment
law every kind of any change in the
environment will affect water status so
if you're you know if you change your
increase your lighting there'll be more
pressure on the plant to transpire if
you change your temperature your
humidity or you know your vapor pressure
deficit all of that it all of that kind
of relates back into the water status of
your plant so it's a very good
accumulator of the plants response to
the environment is it's the best that we
know of right now that's really cool
yeah I didn't even know that something
like that existed yeah so you also
looked at relatively fango as that's
something that growers might be able to
do as well as waiting so so based on
your research
now you're saying that cannabis does
allow you to use wilting and leaf angle
to show or demonstrate drought stress
which is important out to know it is it
is and it was a way too difficult to
figure that out but we did figure that
out so yeah so we found that when when
the leaf angle of if you look at a
secondary branch and you're looking at a
fairly large family if the leaf when the
leaf angle of that fan leave went from
decreased by about 50% from its original
turgid angle then it was at a level
where was actually experiencing a
significant level of stress so when we
talk about pete prance we talk about
plant spraying you know with their
leaves pointing up like that across you
know most cultivars that I've seen you
know really it's the turgidity of the of
the of the standard leaf how does that
correlate with plant health or is that
something that you can talk about at all
yeah well I can I can speculate there's
again there's no research on that but in
general that's a sign of just really
heavy transpiration and transpiration
where the plant has enough water and is
actively transpiring you know there's a
very high VPD environment and it's
really pushing out water and often
you'll see a correlation again
speculation but between that and just
very healthily transpiring plants cool
so there there may be a correlation
there usually may be but I've also I've
also seen cultivars that do that
regardless so it's okay
not sure what it means that's a good
point that I'm glad you mentioned that
cool so let's I want to talk more about
stress responses and and the numerous
stress stressors that can be in an in a
given grow environment but before we do
let's talk about your results just
relating to drought stress so what were
your findings in this paper okay so
after we gradually let the substrate dry
in our drought stress treatment we we
found that the the photosynthetic rate
was
drastically reduced over the control so
the plant was really suffering and weary
wet it and we measured you know all
sorts of parameters during and after so
we confirmed that there was drought
stress and the most interesting result
was that there was no difference in in
the yield between the control and the
drought stress plants and there were
some increases in some of the important
secondary metabolites so we found that
THC a concentration in the drought
treatment increased by 12% CBD a
concentration by 13% and if you look on
on by yield of the specific cannabinoid
so grams per plant or grams per unit
area we found even even higher increases
so TB da was increased by or CBD a yield
by 43% CBD a yield by 47% and so on
there was a lot of very interesting
increases by just applying you know
drought stress once at week 7 in the
flowering stage that's fascinating I
don't have much to add to that other
than I think it it shows just what what
effect drought stress can have on your
overall yield I mean we don't I don't
know quite how to apply that across
other forms of cultivation but I think
that that's just that's just fascinating
that you got such a strong result yeah
and you know what I'd love to talk about
kind of the intricacies of that because
like as you say to apply that elsewheres
in this situation is even more difficult
because it's the accumulated stress that
the plant perceives so it's you know the
stress like I said it increases over
time and it starts from very little to
quite a substantial amount of stress but
it's the it's the accumulation of that
stress that the plant actually perceives
so if you were to go to wilting point in
a you know in a 4-inch Rockville cube
for example it would take a day and the
accumulated stress would be vastly
different from if you're working in a
three gallon pot with you know a
peat-based growing media that takes a
week before it gets to the same wilting
same
in point so it's very important to
consider that you know don't just let
your plants wilt because it's not
necessarily the wilting that does it
it's that it's a certain amount of
stress over a certain period of time so
if you apply you know if you get to the
wilting point in six or seven days
you're more likely to actually see the
benefits that we saw rather than doing
it in a couple of days for example yeah
so how do you feel that drought stress
is the best type of stress for cannabis
or do we even know I mean so one of the
things I wanted to talk about with you
was there's all these different forms of
stress in any given grow environment for
a plant whether its environmental with
you know humidity and temperature and
VPD whether it's lighting watering the
pest pressure you know how how do we as
cultivators what sort of applied science
or knowledge is there out there for how
we sort of control these stress
responses and which may be beneficial
and which may be you know detrimental to
yield health all of those things yeah
it's a very interesting question and
I've been very very interested in that
for a long time
stress ISM is a kind of dangerous tool
to play with as a grower because it's so
easy to do damage it's it's intuitive
that stress can be damaging to your
plants and you know even if you're doing
it late stage after it's fully grown
I've seen decreases in yield decrease in
cannabinoid content if you're over
applying stress you know late in the
game or you know especially if you do it
too early if you do it during the
vegetative stage almost across the board
you're gonna have decreased yield
decrease everything so you really have
to be careful and do it in a really
controlled way only apply one stress III
don't believe anyone who says they you
know they can apply cold stress and felt
stress and drought stress all at the
same time and know how that's affecting
their plant it's it's vastly more
complicated than I think anyone
understands right now so if you're gonna
play with stress I would suggest one
thing just you know just work with one
stressor and be good oh yeah I was just
wanted to add
so what I found from visiting a lot of
different facilities and such is that
every facility has some form of stress
already occurring fairly regularly
there's no perfect environment you know
these growth chambers that you're
creating are very hard to scale for for
growers when we talk about commercial
production of cannabis yeah so how does
that when we talk about you know you can
be mentioned applied science how does
that come into play when we're talking
about a facility like if you were a
grower listening to this talk and you're
like wow I hear you mentioned stress I
want to start playing around with stress
what would sort of be your I mean you
mentioned some cautions already and just
trying to go with one form of stress but
I don't know what do you think about
that yeah so the the grow rooms that I'm
currently operating in are kind of like
large experimental growth chambers
they're you know about 1,500 square feet
of grow area and they're very very
controlled so I kind of have unfortunate
that I can play with these but if you're
operating in a less controlled facility
the plants perceive a lot of the
different stresses in the same way so
salt stress cold stress drought stress
they're all effectively just a different
form of drought stress so they're just
limiting water uptake by the plant so if
you have high levels of salt water
uptake is restricted if you have that
there's less water so if there's drought
water uptake is restricted if you if
it's cold the planets can't transpire as
much so it's restricting water uptake so
all of it a lot of them are effectively
the same stress then you can just apply
it in different ways so the easiest way
I think is in using the salt content in
your growing media so if you do want to
apply a drought stress or you can just
increase the you know your fertilizer
content whenever you want to apply that
drought stress so for example if you
wanted to do it in week seven like we
did in this paper you could increase
that to a point where you're fairly
confident that the plants will have a
restricted uptake of water you can even
you know get let them get to wilting
point that way and then you can relieve
the stress after the fact so working
with your fertilizer or even if just you
know adding salt into into your
irrigation mix
that could be one way of doing it but
again it's kind of playing with fire and
it's it's best done in a very controlled
setting and then scaled ups later on so
I would never recommend to a large scale
grower to just go and start playing with
stress yeah and one thing about your
trial that I thought was an interesting
decision you made was you were using the
same level of fertilizer in the water I
believe if I read it correctly and then
the plants that were drought stress just
received less water so overall they
received less fertilizer yeah can you
give talk a little bit about that and
because you said yields were the same
across both could there potentially have
been over fertigation in the other crop
or does your other trial that you did
sort of validate the fact that the
fertilizer level was appropriate yeah so
again that's one of the intricacies with
doing drought stress trials because if
you are so for example if you weren't
fertig ating and you just didn't
incorporated fertilizer in both
treatments and you drove stress to one
and not the other then when the plant
when the substrate has less water in it
it also restricts nutrient uptake
because again nutrients are mostly taken
up with water so you can do it that way
or you can further gate where you're
adding nutrients every time you irrigate
and that way again if your fertig ating
your control more frequently it's
getting more fertilizer but there's I've
never seen a drought paper that has any
way of mitigating that problem because
you're always those two factors the
fertilizer uptake and water uptake are
very very tightly connected so our only
kind of way of negating that effect was
to look at the other publications that
we've done and we saw that cannabis
responds similarly to fertilizer rate
within a specific range and we saw that
both of our the control and the drug
treatments fell within that range so we
were fairly confident that it probably
did not influence the yield plus the
fact that the drought tree
which received less fertilizer actually
had higher yield and cannabinoid content
which we were we would have seen
probably based on our other publications
that it would have been the opposite
because we weren't over fertilizing to
control in any way so okay yeah I mean
like I think this kind of just goes into
some of the intricacies of trying to
design sort of a rigorous trial there's
just so many variables that you have to
look at down and yeah you have to
consider that kind of thing it's it's
it's there there's definitely a lot of
variables to consider in any
horticultural experiments so yeah and
you have to when you're looking and
evaluating an experiment I think before
you know jumping to any conclusions
you you have to look at the methodology
that they chose to because as a
researcher you're constantly making
those types of decisions into how you
how you're setting up a trial and they
have effects on your overall results so
I think that's great right so when we
talk about stress you know anecdotally
I've mentioned this on the podcast you
have the guy who has throws out an old
clone or something or not plan on to the
compost pile and it ends up growing
massively and doing way better out in
the this horrible you know weather
conditions versus their control indoor
plants or it turns out being the sad
looking plant but maybe has the is the
best cannabis that they've ever grown
you know in terms of a crop so we know
that stress has an impact do you feel
like besides drought stress there's
anywhere any other areas of sort of
stress response that we can look at for
increasing you know some of these some
of these cannabinoids yeah I think that
like there's a lot of different
stressors that can have some positive
impacts but isn't it in most of these
cases you'll see a reduced reduce yields
but higher concentrations of chemicals
and that's if that's what you want if
you want like the most potent cannabis
possible then you know grow it healthy
for a little bit stress at it you'll
have lower yield overall so you're
taking that as a loss but then maybe
you'll have more potent more potent
flowers so it's a cost benefit for most
growers so yes it's something
play with but if you are selling your
flower by yield which generally you are
maybe it'll sell better if it's a higher
THC content but still total volume is
buy it is buy yield then sometimes it's
not it's not best to apply stress but
it's really up to the grower now kind of
what they want to grow and how they want
to do it yeah so for me this is
challenging so my my thoughts on this
are every facility has a lot of
environmental stress already for plants
just as a general rule there's no
perfect facility out there that least
that I visited so I'm assuming that
every plant is receiving as much stress
as it probably wants or needs and that
the goal as someone who works within
cannabis is to reduce the amount of
plant stress we see healthier plants
less pest pressure you know less less
drought stress all of those things in
terms of increasing yield because I'm
just assuming that the plant is going to
receive stress from you know because
there's a lot of things that aren't
natural stressors in in the environment
we want to talk about a cannabis you
know life cycle outside of cultivation
we're looking at a plant that's not
cloned it's not transplanted it doesn't
have its light cycle switch in a you
know for in 24-hour period to something
completely different in the light and
intensity ramped up so quickly how do
you think that factors into plant stress
or you know cultivation from a practical
perspective yeah I think the general
rule is best to first reduce all the
unwanted stress in in your growing
environment so like if you're working in
a greenhouse that has variability and
humidity from one side to the other get
rid of that variability first get rid of
the differences in light intensity
across your your canopy make it as
uniform as possible once you get to a
point where you're fairly confident that
you know your canopy is uniform you are
growing you're not overly stressing out
your plant when you don't want to be
then there might be benefit in applying
control
stress but until that point like you say
there's so many stress stressors that
are already occurring to your crop that
are unwanted it's it's not worth
applying one more okay so just your
exercise caution at this point in time
exactly yeah so what do you think about
natural versus sort of artificial
stressors and in relation to genetics so
I was talking about with Ben actually
earlier today about this in relation to
your work so we have these natural or
sorry unnatural stresses in terms of
transplanting cloning light changes that
wouldn't occur in nature but plants may
have you know certain cannabis plants
may have been you know evolutionary so
evolutionarily selected for this based
on the way that we have been propagating
and breeding them you know indoors under
these lights for numerous you know
decades now how do you think that
factors in when we talk about it from
like say a genetics perspective yeah I
think it's a dangerous game to start
comparing how plants want to grow
naturally compared to how we can grow
them to controlled environments so the
lab I worked with or I studied with is
controlled environment research facility
and we grow learn how to you know we
study how to grow plants and harsh
climates and space and in very very
controlled environments and basically
decades of controlled environment
research have told us that plants if you
can control the environment to be
exactly what the plant wants all the
time it will grow much better you'll
have much higher yields you'll
completely beat up nature there's not
even any question about that so I think
it's a dangerous game to start trying
mimic to trying to mimic exactly what
nature does or how nature apply stresses
or how date your you know how plants
grow in their natural environments
because once you have a general
understanding of how a plant grows and
you can start tweaking things like the
co2 concentration the light intensity
you know the light uniformity the the
when plants receive light the
spectrum of the light all that if you
can optimize all those parameters in a
system that makes sense
you there's no question that you can
beat out nature and that's been seen
with you know NASA research trying to
grow tomatoes to the best of their our
wheat to the best that it could possibly
grow its vastly superior to you know
yields you would see in the field
it's like steroids with humans so what
about photo periodic plants have you
seen anything any research relating to
that in terms of in terms of genetics so
that's I know that's more specific to
cannabis than most horticultural crops
but yeah I'd just be curious cuz because
I get what you're saying you're saying
that we can't really necessarily assume
that mimicking nature has any sort of
advantage in terms of yield or plant
health and that we're able to do it
quite well in these unnatural what we're
calling unnatural environments but how I
guess for plants that may be genetically
or evolutionarily brought up to be grown
under a certain environment that seem to
thrive in this environment is there any
sort of relation there in terms of other
crops that have been found too that are
photo periodic that have been found to
also maybe over time have their genetics
change for the better when we talk about
a specific type of cultivation yeah I
think it's been kind of regardless of
that it's been more kind of selection
breeding selection for cultivars that
perform well in the environments that
we're growing them in so mm-hmm
it hasn't been done really in a
controlled way for cannabis you know it
compared to crops like wheat or corn but
it's still been done for decades and
decades where growers will will find a
cultivar that really responds well to
being triggered in 12 hours so I you
know in a big phenotype in project that
we're doing now flower we we've seen
that some cultivars will will switch at
just 16 hours and some will only twitch
at 12 hours and so
it's likely that breeders of the past
have kind of just selected the ones that
respond well to the way that is easiest
or you know safest or most efficient to
grow them in that's interesting cool
well I know we talked about a lot today
was there anything you wanted to add
regarding the the research that you've
done or anything you want to touch on in
terms of upcoming research that you're
really excited about that you can you're
able to talk about yeah well in terms of
upcoming research I'm definitely that's
been kind of on the forefront of my mind
and so right now I'm acting as the
director of plant science of flower and
I'm working with a team of plant
breeders engineers growers other
horticultural scientists and kind of the
potential and the backing behind
improving this crop even just in my kind
of close circle is incredible so there's
so many people so interested in learning
about this crop and improving it and
there's so much value in doing so for
for a large scale producer like flower
we have production facilities all over
the world and one small improvement can
mean huge increases in yield or in
quality you know you know in our
Portugal operation where we have you
know 165 sectors of outdoor space or in
our in our local Kelowna production
facility where we're growing indoors and
also in Pali tunnels and so there's a
lot of effort being put into research
and there's so many low hanging fruit to
grasp for and that's kind of what I'm
what I'm doing now and what me and my
team is working on is trying to
understand this plant and how to grow it
better if there's gonna be so much to
learn and in such a short period of time
yeah well I really I really appreciate
the research that you've done and
i-i-i-i thank you for sharing it so
openly and getting it peer-reviewed
because I think that has a lot of value
and like you said you're just on the the
cutting edge sort of the tip of the
iceberg for the amount of research that
is that is going to be done and
I just I'm really grateful that we're
starting to see this type of thing and I
hope I can have you back on to talk more
about it and some of your new research
and maybe debunk some more of these sort
of myths or practices that may have not
been beneficial like you mentioned with
the the cutting the leaves and
propagation so yeah thank you yes I'd
love to and I really appreciate you
having me on and giving me a platform to
to share that was horticultural
scientist Darren Kaplan and you were
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy don't forget to
check out our website at
www.mataharicourse.com since