[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
i'm your host tadd hussey of kiss
organics this is the podcast where we
discuss the cutting edge of growing from
a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge
our guest today is nelson linsley of
poetry of plants
you can check them out on instagram
under poetry of plants
nelson has been cultivating cannabis for
over a decade and working in the
industry for over two decades
an artist by heart and an innovator by
trade he has worked with the majority of
leading grow room technology and
techniques that are available on the
current market
and studied their application for
efficient large-scale cultivation
over the past three years he has
consulted on cultivation sites in
washington oregon colorado pennsylvania
and california
after working with nelson we have added
a couple of products to our product line
at kiss
we now have lighting from science leds
as well as offering beanstalk nutrients
on our website
you know i put a lot of thought and
consideration into carrying this brand
because it's not an organic nutrient
line
and while i'm an organic gardener myself
i realize that there are many folks who
are not and i want to offer what i
believe to be one of the most
sustainable chemical options for growers
and we discussed some of those reasons
in this podcast
if you want to try beanstalk after
listening this podcast you can get a 25
discount with free shipping on our
website or by entering the coupon code
kis on their on their website page
this promotion will be in effect for the
next three weeks from the podcast launch
and if you're a larger facility we do
have access to bulk pricing and options
along that route too
anyway on with the show hey nelson
thanks for coming back on the show hey
todd how are you
i am good you know we haven't talked on
air in
a fair while now uh but you've been a
popular guest
do you want to fill in listeners on kind
of what you've been up to i think they
all kind of know your background a
little bit already so
what's been going on sure so
um the last year i've been working on
getting
a roughly 30 000 square foot canopy
indoor canopy up in pittsburgh
pennsylvania with a company called my
tree genetics
uh that's been about eighty percent of
my focus
as far as uh things on the cultivation
side i've been working
uh so that's number one number two is
i've been working with
a lighting company called science
lighting doing some grow trials
with their spectrum controllable lights
and number three i've been
working on getting visibility for
beanstalk agriculture
which is a controlled release fertilizer
that i was a part of co-developing
and bringing to market with a few other
great guys
so you've been really busy is what i'm
hearing and i want to talk about all
those things
so um why don't we start off talking a
little bit about
your experience uh with this facility
what's it like setting up a new facility
in a you know what it sounds like a
fairly challenging state
uh you wanna just touch on that a little
bit sure
uh so in general
startup is uh is really challenging
you know because you're built you're
building something right that's kind of
how we're looking at it is you're
building something
and you're not operating necessarily so
you're even when you're starting up
operations you're still
in in building mode uh dialing things in
i kind of liken it to like building a
guitar and then
once you have the guitar built you put
strings on it and then you have to tune
the strings so
we're in the tuning the strings uh
mode and we did things a little bit
differently with this company is we
started out with a smaller canopy
we were required to do that by the state
that they have some funny rules
where you have to once you get your
occupancy permit
you have to have a harvest within six
months which doesn't factor in all the
things that go into
building things out and getting
everything kind of ready so we staged it
in a few phases so last year right
before
covet hit we started this phase one
grow which was about a thousand square
feet of canopy
where we did a bunch of seed hunting
while we were cleaning up all of our
genetics and tissue culture and testing
everything
make sure it didn't have a vibroid or
bacteria so a lot of preliminary work
on the tissue culture plants so we just
started with a bunch of seeds from
compound in cannerado
and then hunted those out did a couple
of drops and
trained the core team and your covet hit
and all of that so it just you know
essentially everybody here became
like an extension of my family because
we were
existing and living in a bubble uh
you know which is because i've spent the
majority of the time out here not at
home
because travel has been tough and the
last
four to five months you know and this
all the building and the construction
was happening for the
uh first six larger flower rooms and
then as of last month we got those
flower rooms
up and going and uh you know it's
challenging
enough uh to get everything
operational on a timeline
that everybody uh sets up and it's it's
even harder
uh when things go wrong and you've got
uh incredibly long lead times now
because some of these parts come from
china
some of them are calling coming from all
over and uh we've had
we have to we've had to become very
creative on
getting to this point with all the
challenges
uh with supply chain with everything
else
so it's been a lot of fluid movement and
pivoting
and in hiring so we've we've created
around 40 new jobs
in pittsburgh with this startup and then
going through
training and educating a lot of
non-cannabis
experienced individuals kind of bringing
them into the fold
and you know it's been great for me
because i've been doing this for a
little bit
and coming to an area like pittsburgh
and working with a great company
that's focused on you know hiring uh
diverse individuals trying to create
like a male female balance
of 50 50 in the garden across the entire
company
you know it's been great to come in to
this
this company with that kind of that kind
of thought process
and you know mission statement to be
inclusive in their hiring
and then also be in a
community that cannabis has not been you
know it's been tightly regulated and
for the last two years it's only been
you know legal medically
but it did not have you know 20 years of
medical like california
so for everybody here it's really new
and really exciting
and it's been you know really refreshing
to
participate in that excitement and and
how exciting is for these people here to
be able to work with this plant
uh that's been probably the most fun
i've had
uh with the whole process so that's kind
of it
long and short of it i mean it's it's
it's challenging but rewarding is the
best way of putting it
yeah and i realize you know a project of
this scope
is probably more than we can really dive
into too much on the podcast
but are there any highlights or things
that you would you know
looking back like things you wish you'd
known at the onset
that uh you know you could maybe pass on
in terms of advice or
information you know to a listener
that's more broad possibly
yeah absolutely i would say that the
number one thing in having a successful
startup
is having open communication
uh on all levels of your staff and
management
i would say that anywhere that we've had
um
a failure has been because we haven't
been communicating effectively
and creating those paths of
communication
where it's you know you have a hierarchy
as far as responsibility goes
but we're really trying to create an
open forum for anybody to kind of
communicate when they catch something
or something doesn't seem right some of
that can become challenging also when
you're working with third parties like
uh contractors or consultants or things
like that
where they're not necessarily um as open
internally as you would be in if you're
within the same company to like just
communicate when things are coming up um
but that also highlights like why your
core team has to be
uh really in in a high level of
communication about every little detail
and there's ways of doing that without
having to have a thousand meetings
because meetings can take up your entire
day and then
you're just burned out and you can't you
then you have to move into action you're
already kind of
you know gone through all the brain
damage of like five meetings so we've
set up a lot of
uh we've got a handful of social media
apps that we use for our communication
and we have just systems that we set up
for communicating
all the little details that are coming
up all little questions
and i'd say that that's that's the
biggest challenge is just getting
everybody on the same page
because you're gonna have you're gonna
have un
unknown challenges that pop up uh
getting things commissioned and the
commissioning process in case you don't
know is
you've got the facility built and then
you have to go into turning on all these
systems and ensuring that they're
meeting your set point
and when you're a cult if you're a
cultivator setting up a facility
what you have to provide the engineers
is your environmental set points how
much water is going in the room
you know all of these things that the
people that are programming
your environmental controls and if you
have a chiller plant something like that
you have to program
in what that how that particular plant
is going to operate based on your
desired set points in the room
and you have to provide all this
information then you have to make sure
that
it's all working right and you know with
all the challenges you know
sometimes you don't get to have all of
that time to do all that testing
and you know certain milestones kind of
overlapping others
so when you're trying to do multiple
things at one time
it's you know it's really important that
you just over
communicate with everybody and that's
been probably the biggest lesson that
i've learned
is just to constantly communicate try
not to
micromanage uh you know we've kind of
dissolved
the hierarchy approach as far as how
information
gets to the owners of the company and
we've created
you know channels for anybody to bring
things up as needed as we're getting
things started up
yeah i mean i think that communications
the biggest thing especially challenging
too for people who really are growers
and are used to growing around plants
you know things that don't talk back
pass on emotions and and have like you
know life experiences
and it can be really hard i know uh for
us
shrinking the business down was actually
the best thing we ever could have done
uh from a stress perspective from a
communication perspective i mean i talk
to everyone in our company right now
every day
pretty much um you know sometimes it's
little but
uh you know we only meet once a week and
to me that's
enough but i do think i totally agree
with you that
communication is key because if you're
not all on the same page it's
uh it's nearly impossible as the scope
of the project grows to
really be successful or get anything
done
yeah i agree with that uh part of the
you know
you know what i've been doing in the
past is you know consulting or having my
own garden
and i have a couple of guys that i work
with but
having to be responsible for the
coordination of so many people
so many more people uh you know really
really requires uh having dialogue and
really connecting with everybody and i
look at it as
you know the staff here is watering the
garden
you know metaphorically and literally
and i'm
i'm here to water their garden and what
i mean by that is i'm here to help
support them
find purpose find their own skill set
find their own leadership
so they can um you know
improve their quality of life so it's
it's
it's looking at not to minimize human
beings you know i'm always kind of
comparing everything into the garden but
i'm just you know there's a different um
skill set that i'm learning that really
has to do
with um cultivating relationships
cultivating communication and helping
people that are coming in that are
younger
that want to be in the cannabis space uh
that are hungry for that they're excited
to be a part of it
and really helping support them in their
journey
in this space and doing it in a way
where it it
it's it's an awesome path forward
because i've seen a lot of
a lot of gardens and a lot of growers
where people are just burned out and not
happy
and i think that you know that's always
going to reflect in the final product
and one of the issues with scale is that
there's a lot of big gardens with a
bunch of unhappy people
and what we're trying to do here is
we're trying to
figure out how to scale the garden and
and create wellness with people where
people love coming to work they love
they they get to experience the joy of
working in the garden
um every day you know and and
that's that's really what i think we're
creating here
and i've had the support of this company
to create something that i've hoped
would emerge out of this space whereas
it's really been kind of a bumpy
initial road um i think culturally and i
think business wise and i think part of
that is because the focus the target has
been off it's been about profit
it hasn't been about uh quality of life
people
or quality and i i think that
in the long term and probably in
the short term having shifting the focus
away from just short-term gains and into
creating just an epic place to be and
work and do good things and create
quality products
is going to pay more dividends and then
trying to come in
you know inflate your value and run that
whole kind of game
um you know with the stock market and
everything else we're kind of starting
to see get exposed now
uh but you know that's been present in
the cannabis industry for the like
last eight years where it's just been
pretty awful and
that really will uh that really rolls
downhill
to the employees and they feel that so
we're trying to you know with my tree
we're trying to do something different
i'm learning a lot i've got great
mentors here
that are teaching me about how to be a
you know a better people person
and a better leader and you know leading
from the heart and leading from
communication so it's cool to see that
in an actual company in the cannabis
industry say the very least
yeah i know for for us uh
that's been the that's been the biggest
challenge slack's been a really cool
tool
for us to use in terms of that's what we
use
yeah having these different channels you
know so like we even have a random
channel where right now we're discussing
what's going on with reddit and
uh the stock market and you know talking
about things
along those lines or you know current
current events i guess
and that's optional not everyone has to
participate but it's a way to connect
when we're all so disconnected right now
with covet going on
uh and then we have other channels that
are around you know what's going on with
research
what's going on around you know sales or
customers so that like if we have a
customer issue we can put it up in there
right away and we can all address it now
i realize for a cultivation team that's
a little bit different in terms of what
channels make sense but uh it's been
it's been a great tool for us
i i don't know what you said you're
using slack too it sounds like
yeah yeah because i'm sure people are
gonna be curious so
uh the software or the apps that we
found that work the best
is slack for all the communication and
then
mondays uh for the scheduling and
project management
and they you can pro you can populate
changes in mondays into slack so mondays
uh
you know as a module for slack that's
awesome so if i go in and slack is you
know
just really intuitive easy to use
project management software
that's like colorful and intuitive it
kind of looks like a kids app but it has
a lot of functionality
and so it's easy for anybody to kind of
jump in and be able to see where
everything's at there's a bunch of
different viewing modes
from just a basic project overview to
calendars and timeline and gantt charts
all that it's very deep and then when
you
are making adjustments to the schedule
uh you know it lets you you know even if
you're in a task and you get stuck or
it's completed or get
auto populated to the slack channel uh
that correlates to uh that monday's
project so i basically set up different
project boards for each room
and uh those will auto populate to the
channel that we have on slack that's
dedicated to the room so we
we organize it uh we organize our slack
and our mondays based off of spaces
and then we have management channels so
anybody that
uh has activities or objectives and
those spaces will have access to them
then we have like a scouting channel and
of course we have
a meme channel so the staff can meme
each other
and i asked the staff to uh you know
right now that
say there's one employee that we have
that has like topped my memes
but we we we have like a friendly meme
challenge where we'll
meme each other and it keeps everything
kind of light-hearted
and we're you know we can't take you
can't take yourself too seriously when
you're growing
you know cannabis like the whole part of
this is for us to
enjoy life so we create that place for
people will be creative and kind of uh
you know walk the line per se which is
kind of what i i do all the time
yeah so this is where you and miami
mango are getting all your ammo
it's this yeah meme champ right totally
the meme channel yeah yeah the only
thing i want to add to this
is uh you know if you are cultivating on
it with a team
of growers and you are in a position a
leadership position
um i think the two biggest things i
found that helped me are kind of
really obvious but giving people a sense
of purpose and a sense of ownership are
the two things that i found have really
made a difference because as your scope
of company or
or cultivation uh expands you can't
do everything you can't be the one
watering the plants so you have to give
people not only the structure and tools
and the sops to do it well and do it the
way it should be done but also the
ownership
and you know the sense of
sense of value in what they're doing to
where they want to speak up and they'll
want to do a good job
and and realize that their part in this
company is is really important
so i just want to throw that in yeah
yeah i know that
i'm i'm 100 with you on it um
and that you know ownership and purpose
those two things work hand in hand
and that's gotta that's gotta carry all
the way through and the company has to
have that commitment to the
staff of the employees as well i would
add one thing is i find a lot of
companies
especially in cannabis uh we're always
chasing yield numbers
cannabinoid percentages well those are
results
uh and what i've learned is if you chase
uh you tend to fail but if you chase
information
results follow so uh if your
communication is
is solid you'll be able to have access
to all the information
that will end up leading to the results
that you desire but if you're constantly
chasing results
and not collecting the data and the
information that's typically where all
the mistakes
occur and where the failures occur as
well
great i think that's a good segue off of
the facility stuff because i wanna i
wanna save some time to talk about
uh nutrients specifically
what you're doing around with uh
beanstalk
um talk a little bit about what that is
and i want to talk to you a little bit
because you guys are growing using
you know essentially a chemical nutrient
and you and i have had
long-winded discussions about the merits
and sustainability of chemicals
versus organic production and i talked a
little bit about
actually last podcast that i just put
out
today on with carrie dr carrie peters
about
um you know the difference is there too
but
i would love for us to just spend like
maybe five ten minutes just touching a
little bit on that too
absolutely um and i've met kerry she's
awesome i've spoken to her a bunch men
are at a convention
i think peters is a great company uh and
i've used their products
um a whole lot in the past uh so
just a little of the background on
beanstalk uh
2016 2017 i was
introduced uh to a few individuals that
were trying to get this
product off the ground which is a
controlled release fertilizer
that's a little bit unique in its coding
the same technology
that they developed that this company
behind the scenes these chemists
developed for
the nasa space international space
station and the nasa food program
it took them about 10 years to get
approved for nasa by the way so it was a
long path
and not anybody can just kind of jump in
and
the reason why it's unique is it's it's
really geared towards efficiency
and you know not having an excess and
waste
so i i thought i would i thought i was
interesting i was interested in the
technology
i wasn't really sure uh i wasn't really
confident
that it would work for cannabis because
i'm so used to
creating a cocktail of of different
organic
and chemical fertilizers and
so i gave it a i gave it a shot i built
a small room in my garage
like an eight lighter and then did did a
few trials
with different control groups and uh
overall
the fertilizer uh beat out everything as
far as yields quality and growth rate
morphology
so i i you know went to the
the people behind the company which
ended up becoming beanstalk was called
something else then and said hey i'm
really interested in being a part of
this
uh i think i can help improve where this
fertilizer is at
and uh and and bring it and bring it to
the next level and help bring it to the
market
and essentially the fertilizer is a pril
which looks like uh like nerds like the
candy nerds
so some people call them space nerds
which i think is a cool name
and that prill is a polyolefin coating
and the minerals are on the inside of
that prill
and it's a single layer coating whereas
other time to release fertilizers which
is a little difference between control
release and time release
time release can have upwards of 15 to
20 layers
of polyurethane polyurethanes half-life
is very long
polyolefins is a fraction of that also
there's certain
uh fungi and mushrooms that will
degrade if you add that into the compost
pile
it'll chew up that polyolefin coating
and use it as food
with zero uh with zero impact the
environment so there's
this process is in place where you can
completely remove
any of that coating you know
after it's been used uh the thought
behind it is
that what we put in the plant is what
the plant uses so
uh how it works is when uh moisture or
water
hits that membrane that membrane of the
peril the polyolefin coating
through osmosis it will pull out the
mineral salts and feed it to the plant
and as time goes by different pores
open up in that coating allowing for
more minerals to come through
at different rates based on how the the
fertilizer
is formulated so it's essentially the
the thought behind it and
also to remediate you know the majority
of your lead jada runoff
so in a small container so containers
that are large smaller than
seven gallons i've been able to irrigate
with zero runoff and have successful
results if you're
using larger containers you probably
still will need to uh purge the media
once in a while
to reset it but it's a little bit better
than or a lot better than
you know running a um you know straight
water soluble
fertilizer and having to get five to ten
percent runoff every feeding
uh so if you go to areas like central
valley and california
you know the the ppm coming out of the
tap there is extremely high and
a lot of that has to do with or from the
well water a lot of it has to do with
just so much runoff going into the
uh going into the the water table that's
you know 2 000 parts per million a lot
of nitrate a lot of phosphate
so the thought is that not everybody's
going to switch over to organic
organic doesn't work in all
circumstances for instance
here in pennsylvania pennsylvania is so
tightly regulated
i've had to cut out all of my organic
inputs for the most part
because they don't differentiate between
beneficial
and pathogenic bacteria uh there's a
very tight aerobic bacteria count
um you know fungi you know
you know mold they call it all bold even
if it's a beneficial
fungi so we're in an extremely tightly
regulated
environment and using organics is
extremely risky
so you might be in a circumstance
situation where
you have to pass testing and you have to
try and keep it as clean as possible
and that might involve limiting
organic inputs or you know really being
careful with them
also with some of the issues we're
seeing with kelp and and animal waste
having high levels
of heavy metals and arsenic which i've
run into
you know you know the organic inputs
might be
you know might have different levels of
things you don't want in the flowers so
there's
you know i'm looking at it as okay well
most farms i go to are not growing
organically you know that i've consulted
or worked with most of them are running
some kind of assault
how do we make that paradigm more
sustainable how do we reduce that waste
so when this product landed in my lap i
really like that idea but then
if it didn't grow good weed then why
would i ever use it i mean it got to go
back to the drawing board
so in the end you know we've we released
product has been out for about a year
now
um it's a slow start because it's a new
technology and
people sometimes are confused on how
simple it is but you're just mixing this
pro into the soil
essentially feeding water whatever
organic biostimulant you want you can
you can
stack certain other things on it as well
it's just basically going to give you
your fundamental
nutrition for the plant and that's
confusing to a lot of people
it was confusing to me when i first was
trialing it out but it really works and
we've had a lot of early adopters with a
lot of success
uh you know we would run you know 500
000 square feet of canopy
on it with one client and it was
extremely successful and they
they've kept using it and most people
that have switched over
and have just been really impressed with
it and then they you can add whatever
you want on top of it
i would stay away from any additional
nitrogen because there's
all the nitrogen you need and you
wouldn't want to add any more latent
flour
in my opinion uh but overall we're
having great results i'm using it here
um we're testing extremely high in the
cannabinoids
you know if you look at the mitral
genetics flower that just drop
or you know between 28 and 32 percent of
the cannabinoids
with three and a half you know anywhere
2.8 three and a half percent terpenes
um so great great results there i think
most of that has to do with
genetics but if you don't have the
proper nutrition in the proper
environment
you might not see that expression so
everything is really doing its job it's
producing a flower that's desirable
and i'm pretty stoked on the product in
the future of the product
yeah i mean to jump in here obviously
i'm the organic guy
i've been organic my whole life i eat
organic food i
you know i've never grown using chemical
nutrients
um it's not really my world but i i want
to be pragmatic about this and realize
like you said that
you know i don't know what percentage of
growers are using
chemical nutrients i would suspect it's
a higher percentage than those using
organic nutrients still
though organics has made a huge push i
think in the last decade
just this is all anecdotal i don't have
any numbers here
but that's just sort of what i've seen
on my side of the industry
i'll continue to be that organic
advocate but i want to realize that like
people are going to grow using chemicals
and if they are going to if this is not
going away how do we
how are we how can we be more
sustainable about it and i think
you know companies like jax ideas like
beanstalk are
are really great in that aspect um and
i'd like to
further those technologies further that
information so that we're reducing
runoff
um you know reducing water usage
potentially like you were saying in that
um and and really simplifying things for
growers so that we can get
better quality product out there too and
frankly i root for the little guys like
i don't
i don't want and more general
hydroponics and scots
and and big egg uh taking over industry
so
these small companies or smaller
companies i guess are really where i
would uh
throw my hat in on this so i just want
to throw that out there uh one other
thing i want to mention
for people who are not can i can i
comment on that real quick though before
you shift gears
yeah yeah i would just say that
um i'm i wouldn't say that i'm in either
camp
like uh as far as what i would prefer i
really look at it as what's going to
work the best for that scenario and the
best for the goals
and i i love organically grown cannabis
and i i try and eat as much organically
grown produce and food as i can
and uh you know there's it just
really what it is is we have these
containers we have to operate and the
containers are like the rules the
regulations
the limitations of the environment and
then also
scale right scale is another container
uh that we
that in general i don't feel like the
cannabis industry is really figured out
yet
uh we're getting there but we usually
hit like a point where things
the quality dramatically drops after a
specific
amount of square feet of canopy so how
to
uh how to get to that next level so you
can figure out all those problems part
of that just
involves simplifying everything and i
just find that sometimes
i've run into issues where more or
organic inputs have brought in another
layer of complexity
that makes the other uh aspects of
scaling
really challenged challenging to manage
but i do know that there
are people working on that right now and
focused on that and they might be in a
market where they have
margins where they can afford to take
that chance
uh just not everybody is in that
position and i
love seeing what people are doing uh
with organic inputs
and you know frankly some of the best
cannabis i've ever smoked has been
you know organically grown and i think a
lot of people agree with that
but yeah i just wanted to say that i'm
for i'm for organic
100 but i'm also i'm also for the
transitioning and sustainability
and sometimes that means not necessarily
picking a side
but really looking at like how do we
progress further away from things that
are so wasteful
sure and i think that you know the
organic industry has its
dark side too which um you know we
talked about actually last
last podcast with carrie it's not it's
not perfect either
you know some of the mind products some
of the uh
i i think taking advantage of some of
the um native populations around
harvesting of some of these things
whether it's it's guanos
or uh coco core things like that are
really important to consider when we
look at environmental impact
and at the end of the day like nitrate
is nitrate and we have to recognize that
from a plant
um you know a plant physiology
perspective
as an organic grower i i have to realize
that
the plant honestly can't tell a
difference
on where that's coming from and i think
that's a hard
lesson or a hard answer that we don't
necessarily
want to accept we want to think that
organics is special and
where i think organics is special is in
the sense that
it's um i i don't think that we
have completely mastered what
microbiology brings to the table
um yes soil brings to the table
this idea that we can grow a perfect
plant with a limited number
number of chemical inputs i i don't
think we're there and i don't know that
we ever will be there because it is so
complex
so that that's where i think organics
has a slight
edge but you're right you are adding
complexity and
and one of the things we talked about
with uh with kerry was that um
you know research that's being done
right now is all being done with with
chemical nutrients
it just because it is easier to control
for variables it makes
the scientific methods so much simpler
and so it's really hard to get good
organic research and it's hard to get
replicable organic research because
every soil is going to be a little bit
different
so there's there's definite advantages
to
you know using mineral salts or
chemicals and i
i want to acknowledge that even if
that's not my path
but if on my path i can help encourage
people
to grow more sustainably even if it is
with chemical nutrients then
um i'm on board for that
so right on yeah what i was going to get
at though
uh was regards to beanstalk uh this
controlled release fertilizer for people
who aren't as familiar with it because
i'm
wasn't um but as someone who's you know
owned a nursery we get plants in with
osmocote in there
that has these little you know bluish
green balls
that slowly you know break down over
time i realize that what you're saying
here time release is different than
control release but
just to give you a visual of sort of the
concept behind it um
i thought that might be useful for
people yeah that's
yeah that's where the space nerds comes
from because they they look like little
little yeah they look like tiny little
balls or a little male form
i'd say the big the big difference with
um
the the big difference which also
reflects on the price uh between
osmocote
and beanstalk is the type of coding uh
having a single layer higher quality
coding
uh with the with the beanstalk that's
the biggest difference so it's the same
technology that they use
um you know for nasa and the reason is
that the poly
uh polyurethane is in its
there's a there's other issues with the
polyurethane one of the
uh temperature affects the release rate
and what we found is the polyurethane if
you have a soil temperature fluctuation
the fertility can dump out so the
polyolefin coating is going to be more
stable
and it's just overall just a higher
quality product from a chemistry level
without having you know the poly uh
polyurethane is gonna you know
essentially break down into
microplastics which is
a problem uh because we don't know what
the impact of microplastics is
uh with with soil biodiversity you know
they could shape
the evolutionary path of the microbes
there isn't a
defined way of remediating that so
that's something that we're seeing
in soil and it's something that we're
seeing in the ocean
and it's something that i'm exploring
and and how we can
ensure that even though we we do have a
much shorter half-life with the
polyolefin coating
as a way of remediating and processing
it sooner um
so it's not hanging out having some kind
of
you know negative long-term impact that
we can't see
so in theory uh what you're talking
about is having a media that at the end
of the growth cycle would be essentially
depleted to the point to where your your
ec and everything is back at where you
started
is sort of the ultimate goal there
correct and that there's no residual
coding left
and so if you so if you were to use like
for instance the osmo code you could
deplete everything
but there would still be that residual
polyurethane
and we don't know the impact of that
right so that's the dangerous like you
part of the issue that we have
with scientific discovery is that we
might come up with something that solves
a short-term problem
so it creates a problem 200 years from
now that we can't see or even
sooner than that and that's where we
have had such an ecological impact with
so many things that we've done with
technology
there's always a consequence there's
always a cost like where there's a
benefit there's always a consequence or
a cost
there's it's never separated there's
always this balance
and so part of the challenge with new
with with
utilizing new sustainable technology is
finding
systems to continue to create balance so
you don't have a long-term path
and we don't i've looked into the data
i've looked into the research but it's
really just beginning as far as
microplastic
uh content in in the soil so one of the
things that i look at even with this
product
and you know being a part of the company
be putting this
this product out is really doing a deep
dive on any possible thing that could
have an ecological impact
uh you know that we wouldn't see
right now right so i've i look into that
and i look at all the
the benefits but i'm also looking at the
cost and that led me to
specific types of fungi that can break
down polyolefin they've already started
doing trials on it so there's a way of
taking all of that spent media right
and then composting it and inoculating
it with this fungi
so it would basically use that polar
also encoding
as its food source then break that down
and turn that into
something that would be beneficial
so you're not recommending or at the
point of reusing the media
at this stage of the game
i know i've been we've been using
reusing the media um
i'm just saying that if you're if
i've been reaching the media in indoor
environments or
out primarily outdoor environments like
i try not to reuse media indoors unless
you heat treat it
but i would take the media out and we've
used it for outdoor gardens and had a
lot of success
would i till it back into the soil
that's the question
right like i want to have all the
products we're having be able to be used
for multi-purposes so whatever the waste
is how do we turn that waste into
something that
doesn't just necessarily have one home
after it's been used for
our purpose but could be used for
multiple different things
so part of what we have to create with
sustainability is fluidity and
flexibility
with our waste if it's only going to
create one product or one purpose after
it's being used you might hit a
bottleneck
where you meet the demand for that one
one purpose
and then it just sits there and it
becomes waste again so
part of looking at it is like what are
we we're using pete or coco
you know is there a way of reusing this
in multiple different applications
with the lowest environmental impact
possible and i'm getting pretty granular
on this but this is how deep i look at
it
uh part of part of what's happened you
know and part of that came from
just my my family uh you know family
background
where my grandfather was in the
insulation industry
in the 30s and 40s and 50s and 60s all
the way through
and they were using a lot of asbestos at
the time right and at the time
asbestos was widely accepted and you
know then
the 80s hit 70s 80s hit and then they
found out that it was pretty toxic
and uh everybody that was involved in
manufacturing distributing or selling
asbestos
was considered liable for what happened
to the people that got mesothelioma i
believe that's what it's called
so looking at that i look at my
grandfather's
life as like a lesson where he went from
doing incredibly well in life and
essentially had to pay out everything he
had
made in his life to out to uh you know
all these lawsuits so
i wouldn't want to ever run into
anything like that i wouldn't want to
ever be a part of
a product that would have that long term
impact and i think that
if if companies in if we start thinking
about that way
it's like it's like like being a
conscious company like thinking about
all the possible impacts that your
product can have
and then figure out a plan to remediate
it or don't put it on the market
if there isn't a way of remediating it
and i think that would solve a lot of
problems overall for everybody
on the planet so just thinking about it
a little bit differently
all right so take me through how to use
it so
uh you know starting at the beginning
the growth cycle uh you know i've
watched
i've watched in horticultural
greenhouses you know when we're doing
like when they're doing like massive
propagation
uh you know you poke a hole and they
throw like a handful of osmocote down in
that hole and then that
plant's done and they go on to the next
plant and it's really really fast but
what are you guys doing with
with your mix here how do you use the
fertilizer
you you could you could use it in the
same application
um but as that fertilizer releases it's
going to be concentrated in one point
so what we recommend is to integrate it
in to this substrate or medium
i prefer a specific type of peat moss i
like this peat moss
formula by a company called pin strip
doesn't have any perlite in it
it's got a lot of oxygen so i prefer
that but with any like type of
loose substrate it won't work in rock
walls doesn't work in rockwool but for
any kind of loose substrate
you can either mix it into the pot or
you can subdress it so you could
transplant
and then you could add the layer of the
pro the crf
on top of the level of substrate then
you have to add an
inch of substrate on top of it so you
you want it to be
in contact with media that's been
irrigated or has a moisture content
level
i have top dressing for it works fine
but it you're going to create a better
balance
of ec in the media
if you integrate it in or subdress it
okay so you'll put some in i then take
it
fairly early on are you putting some in
with like a new seedling or do you wait
a little bit
um
yeah so so if you're starting from clone
or seedling
uh most people are starting with some
kind of a rooting cube
or a rock wool it's not going to work
for that so
this would be on your you're potting it
up so if you're taking it to like a
uh you know quarter gallon or a half
gallon container you would add the veg
uh the b basis which is the bed veg
fertilizer
uh if there's a specific rate per gallon
so for v basis it's 25 grams per gallon
uh you know for a little starter three
and a half inch starter pot i usually
just throw a teaspoon in there
uh and then when you're bumping it up to
the next phase up
then you would you know add in
your complete blend of the fortify the
absolute flower
and the k boost and that's going to
finish out the rest of your veg time
and with enough fertilizer to finish the
70-day cycle so roughly 90 days so i
like to do that last stop pod at least
two weeks before i'm moving into flower
and then it carries through
now i did notice you had like a k boost
or a couple other
things there are those just top dressed
at targeted times
um you add them all in at the same time
so they release
yeah you add everything in at the same
time uh
that will carry through flour if you're
just going to be doing nursery
production you just need
you know for moms you can use uh the v
basis or the absolute flour
absolute flour is going to work great
for vegging it's just the timing
and the formulas um formulated
with the k boost with the fortified so
the k boost has
your basically a high level of potassium
with some magnesium in it fortifies
essentially calcium nitrate
and then the absolute flower is an
aggregate
of your macro and micronutrients so you
add all that in at the same time and
you're done
you don't need to add anything else so
other than that starter pot
uh you re you know if you're going in if
you're taking a plant from a starter
plant
into flour you're just going to amend
that
um that fertilizer into the soil
and you're good to go and if you're
doing a longer veg time
uh it depends on how many up pots you
have
you know i i don't know if people are
doing like three or four up pots maybe
they are
uh but you would just add as the volume
needed
and so let's say you have a one gallon
pot you would add
25 grams of the v basis and let's you
take that one gallon
into a five gallon well i would only add
uh
fertilizer for those additional four
gallons not for the total five because
you've already added
in for that one oh that's really easy
that makes sense
um yeah so i just want to mention to
folks too
uh so this was something that i had to
put a lot of thought into um i'll just
be transparent about it
uh you know knowing you uh knowing the
guys over at beanstalk
watching your process and formulating
and improving this product
thinking about you know being an organic
based company
um knowing that this is not an organic
product but yet more sustainable
it is something that we're adding to our
product line so we will
be people will be able to order it
through our website
but it took a lot of thought on that
because i realized i'm probably gonna
get some backlash on it knowing that we
are an organics company and i
i want to stay an organic based company
but i do want to promote technologies
that are more sustainable than what's
currently available on the market and
that to me was more important than
being you know this organics versus
chemical nutrients debate
but it took a lot of thought or you know
it was it was a it was not an easy
decision yeah
so i just want to throw that out there
to people to just kind of stave off
some of the comments or uh questions
that people may have and i'm happy to
you know elaborate on it but um yeah i
just want to
i appreciate i yeah i appreciate you for
i mean we've you and i have had some
great conversations
um on you know just about life and
sustainability
and and this product too and i just
appreciate you
doing the due diligence and even
considering it you know so it's exciting
to work with you at any level in that
sense
and i hope you don't get any backlash
and i hope people understand that
um you know we're all trying to figure
out the best path
forward and uh you know it's not black
or white
it's it's somewhere in between on
getting the whole world in a better
place
yeah and i want to have solutions for
people in some of those challenging
environments where
uh like you said i can't um you know
organics isn't always a good fit
um and some of that is just poor
regulatory practices
i would i want to blame you know that
some of the some of these
that's a good place to start they're not
good um so we could start there but uh
you know knowing that we do have to fit
into this box
there are there are definite advantages
to running
a facility with less uh you know less
microbial
inputs and uh you know you know a media
that's a lot that's either sterile or a
lot more controlled
um i agree yeah
i mean the amount yeah the amount of
challenges just with getting all the
systems working right and uh you know
teaching all these new people uh how to
do the fundamentals
and then you factor in that you could
have
a really uh gnarly explosion of
you know bacteria that you don't want in
your flower that could happen late
flower i mean it's it's just not
it's not a fun place to be especially
when you put a bunch of time
into a crop and it looks great and then
you fail testing that's like the worst
feeling ever
yeah so you've speaking of testing um
you've done testing on heavy metals with
this product
yep is that something that's publicly
available
um i don't know if it's on our website
but i don't have an issue sharing it
with anybody
so we're all within um the right we're
in there all in the right limits i know
there's been people that hit have hit me
up
about it and i've sent those results
we've had uh
testing by batch so we're maintaining
the quality control
as it comes from the manufacturing
partner and uh
yeah so it's all been acceptable and i
haven't seen anything bioaccumulate
that cause a failed test and anything
that i'm doing here which has been
uh this is the type the tightest
regulatory
system i've worked in in pennsylvania
it's pretty it's pretty crazy
yeah you know so on the organic side
when it comes to heavy metals
well first of all in order to register
as a fertilizer which is something we
the path we went with
with the soil and our products legally
you're supposed to do that i know not
all companies have
there's one selling you know bloom kits
and things like that that are
that haven't registered i hope they do
but essentially what that does is it
gives you
access to you know publicly available
heavy metal levels too like you can go
on the wsda website and look at my
company and
see the heavy metal levels in our
products that's a requirement so i'm
sure you know as you you know you're
registered in these states
that uh that's publicly available too
because i know that you guys were
working on uh
in regards to heavy metals and organics
i know you mentioned
kelp meal um dr kerry peters mentioned
gypsum
uh you know these are things that you
have to test uh
soil doctor consulting bryant mason's
been doing some testing on that
which he shared some of that with me um
so we're
this is something we're constantly
working at but i don't want people to
freak out and think that
you know kelp is going to cause their
plant to fail for arsenic it's just
it's about management so not over using
any of these things and just knowing
what the
heavy metal load is that we're adding
and also managing our ph in a range
where those
things may be less available and then
running cultivars that are going to be
uh
better at at navigating heavy metals
than others you know not
not as efficient at taking them up so i
just want to throw that out there
that that last one's so important
because i have definitely
run into cultivars that do like to
bioaccumulate everything you throw at
them
so that is an interesting note
yeah i you know people i've seen people
fail for
for some crazy things in their rooms and
i'm i'm working on putting together
a better guide for that because there's
just so many variables that can
contribute from dust
to water to your plumbing to your soil
to your other inputs
i heard one and this is still
speculation but i heard one lab
claim that the ph down that this person
was using was particularly high in
certain heavy metals but i'm waiting for
those lab results um and i wouldn't
share that anyway because i'm afraid of
this
company but uh just the idea i want
people to be aware that like oh shoot ph
down i never even thought that might be
something to consider
so in regards to heavy metal because i
think heavy metals is really the next
hot topic you know we're not
um we're not testing our vegetables at
this
level which maybe we should be or or not
but um
we all have to pass if we're if we're
growing in a state that has these
requirements we have to fit into these
requirements so
you know yeah it doesn't it doesn't it
doesn't matter
i mean the impact matters but if the
state has these regulations
whether they're for good reason uh an
ignorant reason or there is some
scientific basis
uh that's just on you know not available
to the rest of us
uh we have to work within these these
guidelines and it's
extremely difficult you know it's like
oh man really you can't use
this product why not you know we we have
certain things i mean i don't want to
get in trouble by
blasting all out but like there's
certain things that like we can't use
peroxide for certain things that just
is it just it's mind-blowing to me like
it makes zero sense and peroxide's
fairly safe
just on like cleaning rockwell up or
anything like that it's
there's just a lot of restrictions a lot
of tools that they take out and there's
no reason for it
and sometimes if you if you even ask
them why
uh they get upset and then just won't
pick up the phone for you anymore
you know like because they they just
might not have an answer so
in some of these states we really really
i wish that
in general i wish that scientists and
people that study
uh things at a granular level i mean i'm
not really a scientist i'm a cultivator
i just play a scientist on tv or on
instagram
and i like to hang out with real
scientists and ask them a bunch of
questions and i feel like
i owe um you know a lot of my success
to a lot of people that
have a lot more understanding about
granular things than i do
but we really need i'm just if there are
scientists listening to this podcast you
know
people in special specific fields i know
that most of you
and speak to you right now i know most
of you um
don't like to be out in the limelight
and and you know vocalize your thoughts
but right now we have so much crazy
information
i implore people that are experts in a
field to be courageous right now
and to you know help all of us that are
trying to operate in this world and that
this is across everything please just
you know be more vocal we need more
scientists that are more vocal
um you know i think there's a huge void
right now where we could have a lot of
people coming out and talking about
things and educating
you know cannabis the cannabis community
and everyone else
on what the science and the data is
telling you
yeah i'm working on tracking down a
really good
chemist who specializes in water and can
really
explain the interactions between
different types of water
and how they affect uptake of some of
these
specifically heavy metals but nutrients
in general i might
i might be able to help you with that
all right well let's talk off because
i've got i've got some calls into dram
and uh you know suzanne and some other
people that are working on tracking down
that like perfect
podcast guest so that's that's in the
works okay cool
um yeah in terms of science oh go ahead
i was just going to say that i'll just
give a little shout out um the water
treatment company that we used for this
facility
uh was called advanced treatment
technologies and
they've put in a pretty cutting edge
water purification system
uh we're able to deliver a high level of
dissolved oxygen to plants
and then use ozone for all of our
cleaning protocols and keeping the lines
clean
and uh you know that was this was a team
member here that recommended this
i was coming from the tissue culture
side and uh
i have not i've i'm incredibly impressed
with that system
and with the amount of knowledge that
they brought to the table on this
project
and i would i would say you know bark up
that tree they're doing some interesting
works
and you know on the on like a scale
level for agriculture
and on like a laboratory level and
charlie over there advanced treatment
technologies really came through for us
here
with my tree and what they're doing with
water
purification and plants is pretty
incredible and i'm seeing the results
now
couldn't be more excited very cool
yeah i just want to touch on your
science comments so i i think science
is a little bit dogmatic you know
there's a lot of people doing
what they think of as science
and research and that gets a little
tricky because
you know i found people throwing out
stuff that doesn't fit with sort of
their
world view and that's one of the reasons
that i i'm trying to have
you know people like uh dr peters and
yourself
on the podcast is to try not to get
stuck in that
sort of you know dogmatic view where i
only look at
one path to growing this plant because i
think we can all learn from each other
and i think we have to do a better job
as cultivators of discerning
and really listening to what people are
saying and running kind of that
[__] meter on it uh yeah you can
have a fancy graph
you can have you know different counts
of things but at the end of the day
you know if the if the overall premise
doesn't add up or
if they claim that this is the only way
to grow a plant then i think we have to
we have to take a step back and and see
why some of these things haven't made it
into horticulture
um not to say that if it hasn't been
horticulture it isn't good
but that is a good test of sort of that
bs meter in a lot of ways too
um just uh yeah throw that out there
yeah yeah and if we're not
following the data we're not following
uh you know scientific method and and
you know from hypoth you know moving
from a hypothesis to a theory
uh for not following uh the system of
science
and we're just leaning heavily on
anecdotal
and and story right uh that's
where uh you know that's where
con man and hucksters thrive and i think
right now in the world
we just have a lot of people that are
that can be very charismatic
and uh convince a lot of people that
things work based off of an idea
uh they might mix in some spirituality
in that which i think is a real abuse of
spirituality i don't think you need to
sell spirituality
i think that's just like spirituality is
like a representation of how we're
connected to everything that's alive
and uh that at some point science will
be able to explain that but maybe not
right now
uh but i it's you know the cannabis
community is you know ripe for being
taken advantage of
uh by a lot of people that are coming in
and selling products that really
really don't have any evidence uh of
them being effective
and just because there's a white paper
written about something doesn't mean
that it's proving
uh a claim it means that there's an
abstract and there's an exploration
and that's just the beginning but i see
like people posting abstracts up
but not not posting any of the data to
support claims that they make around
specific methods or technologies or
products and uh yeah
like that's not how you know that's
that's not how you know if something
works or not so just be really careful
uh
and take your time if you're making big
purchases or investing in anything and
and know that there's there's not data
behind it well you know
who knows really so be wary
and i i just hope that more people that
study the data
are a little bit more vocal about it and
can do it in a way
where they can communicate
even if people are getting you know
upset or triggered
for like a better word that this data
might conflict with their world
view like just we just don't take into
that personal it's where people are
right now but it doesn't mean you
shouldn't
say something and just understand that
you're working you're going to be
communicating a bunch of people who just
don't know
or have another narrative in their head
or another story of how things work
and that's a real challenge but you know
i love talking to scientists that study
things on a granular level i've learned
so much and that's improved everything
that i do
in this space as a grower
yeah i feel like we're at a time in
history where there's never been more
polarization in our society and i feel
like the last thing we need in the
cannabis industry right now is to be
fighting over
you know dogmatic views at the end of
the day we're all trying to grow a plant
as to the best of our ability and
sometimes i think we lose sight of that
but in the name of science i agree i
first off i just a quick plug we do have
some white papers
on our website feel free to read them
read the methodology
run your own experiment we're sharing as
much data as we can
trying to get stuff published but that's
hard to do
be partly because we're running things
in a commercial facility and
a lot of the research uh journals don't
want that
you know they want stuff done in a
controlled lab which we don't have the
ability to do so we're doing research at
you know with legit we're doing
research with gold leaf gardens here in
washington state because i have access
to both those facilities
and that's really good but this brings
me to my next question so i want to do
some research at home
i'm limited uh here within washington
state
to anywhere from six plants to 15 plants
i might be able to get up to 30 if i can
do a cooperative at my location but i'm
i'm researching the laws because i want
to be legal within the medical program
here in washington
but how do i set up the ultimate
tent grow from a scientific perspective
because i want to test out
science lights i want to test out you
know your fertilizer versus our soil mix
and do a comparison there
i want to look at how different mbar
levels
you know using the blue mats that we
like with our soils will
create different results so there's all
these different things i want to test i
mean the list is
longer than my lifetime but i want to
start doing this and documenting it
and getting some trends going so i can
figure out
hey this is this is worthwhile send this
over to
uh you know gold leaf gardens but
because i can't do that like the some of
the more
exciting projects i can't really run at
these facilities because i can't risk
the crop loss
you know they're mixing it up this is a
for-profit business
i have to be really cognizant of that
but you know we're formulating new
soil mixes some new uh growing bloom
formulas things like that
and i'm really excited about that side
of things but i
i want to i want to be able to do some
of it in-house myself and i miss growing
the plant like it's been
a few years off now uh i've been focused
on kiss
i've been wanting to be a you know a
good law-abiding citizen
as we were going through all these
different law changes in washington uh
i've been too busy
but now i feel like i'm at a point where
i'm ready to start uh growing again
so yeah
and i think i saw i think i i think i
saw your last garden actually
um if i'm correct i think that was your
garden because i don't know if you want
me to talk about it
but uh i think you saw some no that was
just some outdoor plants
uh for my dad to make into a texture
yeah well
yeah some outdoor monsters i remember
that
those were purely uh for my dad's
neuropathy we don't
you know i don't care if they at the end
of the cycle they have a little bit of
pm or something it was it was cool
it was cool uh so that uh if you're
gonna set up the ultimate tent grow to
do comparison i guess you have to choose
you know your sample size of plants um
if you could get away with the sample
size of six plants
that would probably be great and if
you're just going to do a side by side
so six plants from the same cultivar uh
so you'd want that to be consistent i'd
probably take
two to three times as many clones uh
that you would use and then select the
ones that are the most homogenous
so you're getting a good comparison
meaning they have similar root
development
similar health levels going in um
and then you would randomize them
technically
and then yes distribute them but my
thought would be
so here's what i'm thinking and then
maybe that would be easier and then you
can tell me what you think so i want
i want to make sure that the environment
is the same so so
essentially we're trying to control yeah
i was gonna get to that for a variable
so
my thought was let's just say i can do
15 plants so if i register with the
state
medical card i can do 15 plants i would
get i would get them from a licensed
facility
i would get them as clones and then i
was going to run two
at least if i want to trial the soil
stuff i would run two four by four beds
in a four by eight tent
and then let's say i wanted to test
lighting i would just run something down
the middle to kind of
limit some of the light overlap in the
beds
but i didn't want to have two initially
i started with like i want two separate
tents
because i want to make sure everything
is very controlled in that regard but
then i started thinking about that and i
was like there's no way i can keep vpd
exactly the same environment in in two
separate
tents they really need to be in the same
tent
um well i wouldn't do i wouldn't do a
fertilizer trial and a lighting trial at
the same time
no no no totally one thing or another
i've kind of jumped around there i'm
talking about multiple cycles at this
point but let's just say
let's just simplify it so let's say i
wanted to do
a fertilizer trial so same lights same
cultivar from clone randomized
uh in the same well okay let's see
let's let's let's make it even more
specific let's run beanstalk versus
uh you know our biochar soil i would
have our biochar soil
um well this would get a little trickier
because i'd want to grow it in a bed
because we've seen better yields with a
bed
but i guess we could look at this you
can
but you could grow beanstalk in the bed
too i wouldn't necessarily need to
though i could grow it in
you know a seven gallon pot and say this
is you know the nelson program versus
the dad program i guess
and we could come you know we could
compare that and talk about the pros and
cons of
uh you know weight but well why not do
it
you could do it in the bed it would be
interesting to do it because you're
gonna have
a different you would have to do your
bio
char soil in the same pot so you have to
keep the container consistent so if you
want to do it in a bed
i would i would recommend doing the
beanstalk in a 4x4 bed too
i don't think that's necessarily a
as as a variable that we'd have to
control as much but we could so let's
say even then we had
two beds so what am i so assuming the
light's the same
how am i controlling an environment like
that ideally if i want to keep it within
the tightest conditions would i even try
and run like a small like co2
sort of thing because because the other
thing is this garage is insulated but
it's not heated so my outdoor air is
going to vary like this time of year
it's
probably around 50 degrees yeah um um
well if you run if you don't run co2 it
doesn't i mean it doesn't
the co2 factor is just going to give you
a higher yield uh and you'll be able to
run
more light right so uh you'll be able to
probably get above 800 ppfd
without having you know some big issues
uh if you were to run the co2
so but if you're going to keep the
environment stable you probably you
needed some sort of an environmental
controller and sensor
like a hydrex pro from trollmaster works
great
then you need a way of feeding cooler
air in
and if you kept that tent closed i would
that would positive pressure the tent
um with some with like an inline fan and
some
some carbon filters on the inline fan
and then you could
uh use filters on the airline
yeah well you know if you're pulling air
in you want to make sure it's clean
oh so you're just cleaning there you're
not you're not talking about from an
odor perspective then
i mean unless you have to but no i don't
but i've always wanted negative pressure
because in the past i had to
okay yeah so for this trial it's better
if you're running positive pressure and
if it's in a room i mean you wouldn't
really be able to inject co2
if you're using that fan to control that
air speed unless you're adding co2 to
the room that was
that the tent was existing in basically
sealed though that was sort of what that
was what i was wondering can you run a
sealed room that small
maybe that's a silly question i don't
know
uh not not really because you've got to
have some kind of
uh you've got to have cool air coming in
right sure so what you but what you
could do is you condition the room
outside of the tent
and then you use uh like a voltage
control
like a potentiometer to control the
speed of the fan that's moving the air
into the tent you don't understand so
you use that fan the same way that a fan
from an air handler
and then you would get your room
temperature uh that the tent is sitting
in where you want it
and then you push that air in and then
you could add co2 into that room
but uh you know but you have to steal
that challenge is i i
can't do that because it's a garage that
error is just
then i then i wouldn't then i wouldn't
run co2 so i was wondering like could
you
run it sealed you know more or less
quote unquote but then just do
controlled air exchanges every so often
to uh to bring your fresh air that was
that was kind of what i was
i was thinking of and again i've never
done it on i've
you know on scale sure on a room but
i've never i didn't know if anyone's
done an attempt
or if that was you could but then you
had you could but you'd only be getting
uh you'd only that co2 wouldn't hang out
very long because any time
so let's say you have uh you you know
control a brain a little control brain
like hydrox and then
whenever the temperature gets to a
certain set point you're gonna kick that
fan on and it's gonna suck the cold air
from outside of the tent and push it
through
you could program it to when that fan
turns off that the co2 uh
then would release into the tent uh
but any time that fan turns on you're
just going to be pushing that co2 right
out
so you're not going to get you're going
to get some benefit
but it's not going to be the same thing
as like a sealed room running it at 1500
parts per million
yeah i wasn't sure how well that would
scale down
to something that size i was just
curious um
yeah it's i mean i a lot of people have
played around with that i've played
around with it
i just intense if i'm doing testing i
just don't run the co2
and i and i try and stay below 800. i'll
hang out between 600 800 ppfd
okay okay yeah i do have a light meter
um i'm i'm curious to try leds because
the last time i tried
every time i tried a tent in the past
i've i've pretty much failed
um usually because i ran too strong of
lights
and uh just could not control the heat
no matter how much
air flow or um you know even with like
an eight inch
air cooled ducting with a massive fan on
there i could not get the heat down low
enough
to where um was it with leds or where
were they no this was a long time ago
this was back in the day with like
single-ended hbs and i remember i just i
roasted some plants they actually
survived better than i thought they
would have considering the heat pressure
they were on
but um yeah i uh you know i
way way back when i first started and
people will probably laugh at me for
this i
i threw a thousand wad in a in a tent
and
uh ramped it up and
came back down did you run it did you
run it 100
oh yeah yeah i had a lumatec ballast
going i had it all the way up there
it was cranking thing was so bright oh
man
and i came back and opened up the tent
and it was like i just stepped into like
tropical paradise
it was so hot
but you know that's how you learn my
mistakes yeah that's
totally no i've i've made all those
mistakes before
um 100 so so i went from that to like a
400 watt cmh
and that worked fine but um yeah
you know that wasn't it just wasn't
enough ppfd that i felt like i was
really getting the growth i wanted so i
usually just ended up
saying screw this taking down the tent
and then just setting up my garage
is really what ends up happening how big
how big was that tent that you had the
400 watt tmh in
that was a four by four if i remember
correctly
yeah so that one was a four by four and
that was okay
but then i just i ended up being like
screw it i'm just gonna take everything
out into my garage
and hook up the thousands and really let
it
let it go to town and and that's what
i've done every single time i've done
the tent i've taken it down
halfway through the grow because i just
get fed up with it
so we'll use so so do this ted use like
a 300 watt
led uh use like the veg light
you know but i don't like fluid has a
vet i want to go with you
yeah but you don't need that much light
especially if you're not running co2
and you're gonna have like a moderately
controlled environment
um you if you get that like a 600 watt
led or 650 watt led
you're gonna probably end up just
dimming it down
because it's that it's going to be
pretty tight to the canopy and i've
grown
under the veg lights like from spec
grade and from fluence
and i've gotten you know an ounce and a
half a square foot
you know without co2 you just don't need
that much light
especially if you're just doing a trial
um you don't need that much light for
something like that
you you do need more light if you're
trying to like maximize
every square foot that you have and
you're trying to optimize everything
but in a tent for personal use i mean i
don't know
i mean you could go ham on it but it's
not necessarily needed
in those kinds of circumstances and if
anything that extra light without added
co2 and environmental control
is just going to cause uptake issues and
then balances in the media and then give
you
uh you know probably not as accurate of
a trial as you desire
you know yeah i'm curious to to start
playing around with it
and you know ultimately this
tent set up would just be for me to get
trending and
and some numbers so that i could then
take it to a facility and say hey run
this again in your facility
um on a little bit bigger scale with a
little bit more controls but
this is something i've been wanting to
do for a while and you know i think uh
you know kiss has really been focused i
feel like overly focused on the
commercial side of things like
commercial growers
and i don't want to discount people that
are growing at home
you know i think some of the ways that
we grow have a lot of
applications for home and i think the
science that we're using in our soils
and things like that can definitely
apply to someone with six plants as much
as it could to someone with
you know 600 or 6000 so and
and if somebody wants organic product um
they might have to grow it
at home if their market is so tightly
restricted they can't buy it
you know that's the other option right
so someone's really hellbent on
on only consuming organic products that
might have to be you know in their tent
in their garage or room somewhere yeah
so i'm sure there's people listening to
this podcast that are a lot smarter than
me that probably have feedback
feel free to send it to me um i haven't
hit the dm
purchased anything yet for this tent
grow but i'm i'm getting ready to pull
the trigger i've already got
a few lights lined up that i'm going to
run for one thing that i know i want to
trial we've already trialled a few of
them at
um at gold goldleaf
and i've got that data but i haven't
wanted to publish it just yet because
it's such a political market around
lighting and i don't really want to uh
you know have people run to too many
conclusions based off of
these trials and and also feel like i'm
you know bashing one company and
promoting another so i'm trying to be
real careful around that i guess
i will say that the led trials that we
ran all
three led companies crushed the
double-edged hps
in yield so yes yep that was well i can
tell you this
i can tell you this too like 90 of all
the leds on the market are like coming
out of one factory in shenzhen
so it's like there's there's not a ton
of differentiating factors
um there's nothing like the warranty
yeah
price the warranty uh and then the
architecture of the light and then
there's a few companies
um that are doing things differently and
doing a lot of
like well i i like science a lot because
they they have a manufacturing plant in
texas and they're building these lights
putting them together in america and i'm
super stoked on that
but most of the lights are coming um
from a few
factories in china and they just put a
little bit of a spin on the casing
so it's tough to unless you really
kind of dive in and open up the light
it's tough to know what's different
about all of them in my opinion
well i based on your recommendation and
a few others i
that is one of the lights that i'm
definitely it's top of the list to trial
um it is one that uh i was just talking
with cindy about adding this to our
website today
to be able to offer its customers so we
will have that as something if you're
looking to try science like
you can get them through us so we're
going to have that um
and then i you know bios is another one
that i've worked with for a few years
and have a good relationship with a good
company
um yup i i don't know what's happening
with my relationship with fluence right
now but um
we're not currently offering their
lights at the moment but they're still
around in a a good company too for
people
uh and then there's like a whole bunch
more i i was talking with ben about this
like
i would not want to be in the led space
right now because there's a million
companies
out there it's oversaturated literally
just mailed a light to my
door the other day for no reason so
like isn't that awesome i'll try it like
i'm gonna give you a ride
they were a spin-off yeah of a
well-known company um
so i don't want to say anything about
them until i've actually tried their
light but
uh yeah uh there's a lot of great
options
out there now under lighting for full
spectrum lighting so it's wonderful
because when
when we first started there was there
was nothing like there wasn't anything
it was blurple lights
and then people were laughing at full
spectrum like it was a waste of money
and now we've seen that's not the case
and and then there really wasn't a lot
you know
initially the only two companies i ever
heard about were fluent in bios and now
you know i know that some of the some
companies have had supply issues but
there's just so many more options
really it really is and i would say that
both
fluent and bios really kind of paved the
way
uh for that market and it's crazy how
quickly it
it exploded um i mean
we like the jungle boys has an led room
now
and they have their own led light and i
remember
like six seven years ago uh that they
just
they were never going to switch over to
led and it was like this whole thing and
you just seen people all over uh
adopting this technology
and figuring it out and just crushing it
and just absolutely crushing it and
there's all these new
uh you know there's companies that are
doing all kinds of crazy things with
leds now so it's cool to see
and i think all that competition is
hopefully going to inspire
uh you know more offerings and more
features and
and and cooler stuff and uh i'm excited
to see where it goes
you know i
i totally grabbed nothing to add to that
yeah
yeah cool man well i awesome i feel like
we're already running a little long on
this podcast
i i know you and i when we get a chance
we can usually talk for a fair bit of
time
um though our conversations aren't even
about growing it's pretty crazy the
stuff that we end up talking about i
know
which next podcast we're doing though um
yeah next podcast chad i'm going to
interview you
[Laughter]
there you go and you know since we still
get asked and we're both on here
i do have hopes for dope history i'm
trying to track down a sound engineer in
production
uh i've got a few leads i'm working on
but i'm really looking for someone that
can
uh buy in on this concept at the groud
level and help us get it off the ground
i know
nelson you've been really busy but
you're hoping to plug back in
um on it too so if you're someone that
willing to do a little bit of sweat
equity and help get this thing off the
ground um
reach out you know please help but if
that's your backyard i've already got
some interviews
we've got the connections we have an
audience
it's such a great idea i want to i
really want to crush that one so
just throwing it out there yeah please
yep thanks ted
yeah i didn't warn you i was going to
bring that up so there you go
no it's fine i would love to see that
get uh revitalized and
it's pretty much all my fault is why it
hasn't happened so
uh you can blame it all on me i got too
busy i
i wasn't going to go there it's all good
you know life throws i'll own it i'll
own it
so i'll own it it's all on me
sorry guys i i appreciate the chance to
catch up with you
i know you're super busy i'm excited to
hopefully reconnect with you on even
this dope history
thing once this facility is really up
and going i know it's really consumed
your time
and uh yeah i hope folks will check out
beanstalk
on like i said it's going to be offered
through the kiss organics website or the
beanstalk website directly i'll have the
links to that as well on the podcast
page
as well as a promotional offer for
people when this podcast comes out
if they want to give it a shot awesome
i think that's that's it for today you
got anything else to add before we sign
off
no it's it's good man it's good talking
to you thanks again for the time
and lots of love to everybody out there
that's uh
that's crushing it during this crazy
moment in the time
uh we're all we're all doing it together
so uh
you know best of luck for this year and
hopefully your gardens are green
[Music]
that was nelson linsley and you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast
don't forget to check out the podcast
page at www.kisorganics.com
just click on the learn tab then podcast
beanstalk fertilizer is available for a
limited time
at a 25 discount with free shipping on
our website
and we have added a bunch of new
products including led lights plant sex
kits
new surfactants and much much more we
carefully research all the products we
offer and manufacture to make sure they
are science based and meet our standard
of quality
thanks for listening
you