[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discussed
the cutting edge of organic growing from
a science-based perspective and drawn
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge our
first guest in 2019 is Jeremy plumb
Jeremy is the director of production
science at proof cultivar one of the
most technologically advanced cannabis
cultivation facilities in all of North
America at proof
Jeremy combines decades of cannabis
horticulture experience with cutting
edge technology to deliver previously
unattainable consistency in both product
quality and consumer affect prior to his
leadership at proof Jeremy was a
co-founder of pharma recently acclaimed
by Rolling Stone as one of Oregon's top
dispensaries jeremy has served as a
cannabis consultant to Israel medical
cannabis researchers as a cannabis
policy advisor for us members of
Congress he also serves on the OLC sees
rulemaking Advisory Committee in 2015
Jeremy co-founded cultivation classic
Oregon's leading craft cannabis
competition he serves on the technical
advisory board of the resource
innovation Institute and is the
co-founder of the open cannabis project
he lives in Portland Oregon with his
border collie Lucy and when he can finds
few greater joys than sailing on the
mighty Columbia River I had a ton of
questions for Jeremy after hearing him
speak at numerous events like photo X
Emerald Cup and the cultivation classic
in this podcast though Jeremy really
shares his background and passion for
cannabis as medicine at the end of the
podcast you'll hear some of the
questions I had for Jeremy for a follow
up podcast but please do reach out with
any questions you may have and I'll read
my favorites in the next podcast with
him you can email me questions at tad at
kis organics comm or post them on the
Instagram post for this podcast enjoy
hey Jeremy thanks so much for coming on
the show today I really appreciate it
it's a joypad thanks so much for
inviting me yeah well I met you a couple
years ago now at photo X but I'd been
aware of you and the work you're doing
but I loved I loved what you talked
about on stage I just I was just sitting
there in the audience totally engaged
and nodding my head to just about
everything you were saying so I'm really
excited for this opportunity to talk to
you could you maybe go back and tell us
a little bit about yourself so we can
let the audience know who you are and
what you're up to
absolutely thanks for the compliment I
really love that event that it's great
to have a moment with you I'm a little
bit about my background is that I've
really always been involved with this
amazing class and doing my best to serve
what I believe hurts you know in
creating credibly growing in exciting
expressions in the world that of course
things are changing fast so there's a
lot of fronts that I'm working on and
that really I started in Sonoma County
and really had a lot of time in what we
sort of affectionately thought was the
southern tip of the Emerald triangle but
what I was surrounded by really
experienced craft cannabis growers and
was lucky when I was 15 after reading
the Emperor wears no clothes to be able
to reach out to Chris Conrad and Mickey
Norris and sort of say hey I'm really
excited about the work you guys are
doing and to be taken in under their
wing for a while um I got to go and
Oakland and sort of spend time with
Chris especially as he was doing a lot
of different advocacy work this is pre
prop 215 in the Bay Area and there was
just this hotbed of a lot of the people
who are sort of most fundamental and the
ideation room medical cannabis movement
and just the modern hemp and cannabis
movement in general um but one of the
first projects I was involved with was
actually Nikki's project where she had
these sort of a-frame signs with big
posters about shattered lives and
people's lives that had been negatively
affected by the drug war and then there
was these anecdotes and we would tour
around and take them to various places
like college campuses and
sort of tell these stories of shattered
lives and illustrate that just painful
outcomes of the drug war during that
time was when I got really turned on to
the medical movement in earnest became
aware of people like brownie Mary and
Dennis Peron a little bit later but
earlier became aware of a clinic and
Santa Cruz called women advocates for
medical marijuana or Wham and this was
really a team that I believe Rick Doblin
from Maps helped to connect Israeli
researchers after the government was
shutting down their efforts but they
were exclusively devoted to cancer and
AIDS patients and to providing medical
cannabis at that time in the day which
is sort of early 90s there was of course
this really horrible fallout with the
AIDS crisis and watching sort of what
looked like scenes from The Walking Dead
at point um in places like the
Tenderloin in San Francisco on you would
see AIDS patients on the street with
wasting syndrome really just
experiencing unbelievably low quality of
life and then in their community you
would see kind of a completely different
story happening where people's quality
of life was really clearly improved by
their reliance on cannabis and having
administered in a consistent way so that
was really where the lightbulb was going
off and then eventually being exposed to
like Dennis perón's compassionate buyers
club and just that whole movement um so
as I became aware that the properties in
cannabis that helped me to deal with
pretty high levels of anxiety when I was
young and felt like a far more creative
and productive alternative to alcohol
consumption and being in Sonoma County
which is also the wine country and I was
surrounded by heavy alcoholism and some
of that in my family as well and so
cannabis just felt like a healthful and
exciting alternative but little did I
know it would become you know really a
life's work and something that
increasingly fuel can really improve the
quality of life for a huge array of
people around the world as we're all
working on this endeavor but I'm anyways
I moved from the Bay Area up to Portland
in
thousand so Portland Oregon is where
them ever sent and I got involved
immediately with the medical marijuana
program here and I'd already had you
know a lot of years experience almost 15
years experience in the bay before
coming up but then really became
involved with a lot of patients and in
the work with patients over time I got
better at sort of gathering cultivars
from around the world and really I'm
finding different sorts of medicine and
being able to administer that
effectively through my gardens and a
small network was really the foundation
of my work in Oregon over time I found
some incredible patients who had benefit
and experienced pretty good outcomes by
being able to work with them and
ultimately I found their support was
able to help me eventually become
involved in the dispensary program when
we became aware of the fact that there
was going to be a dispensary program in
Oregon
it was clear that actually I didn't have
the resources or ability to kind of
pursue that sort of opportunity without
partners but one patient in particular
this amazing man named Steve Bennett
really just got behind my work and let
me use a lot of resources um really to
be able to categorize chemo VARs
effectively at the time when I was
actually a pre dispensary program in
Oregon as a medical grower there were
very few people pursuing chemical
inventory of their product and I knew
that there was clearly a wide spread of
different outcomes in the work I've been
doing the patients and was desperate to
kind of categorize the qualitative
attributes of these plants I was very
fortunate that a good friend rich chrome
one who goes by one eye and this breeder
up here he's associated with dog-walker
strain and others I'm introduced me to a
man named Pat Marshall that Marshall was
the leading chemist at sunrise
analytical looking back I now believe
that Pat Marshall was likely one of the
most important cannabis chemists in the
country because he'd been going since
the mid 90s
and he was a really senior scientist who
had been the top scientist and city of
Portland's water quality control and so
he was a master of gas chromatography
and he was a patient activist so he was
really turned on to the idea that
cannabis was helping people and so he
worked to kind of crack the matrix I'm
in a sort of solo effort looking very
little outside of his own work and in a
disciplined way pursued sort of mapping
all of this and then would be able to
produce analytical results that had 64
compounds so seeing this level of
chemical diversity i'm produced by a
really rigorous scientist in a
consistent fashion was a huge
transformation in my work and my partner
Steeve really helped me - in addition to
inventory all of my own cultivars even
we paid for lab results for other
people's cultivars to start to kind of
wet I am going to borrow some language
from a friend dr. mark Lewis I'm I was
unintentionally beginning a survey of
the chemo scape in Oregon and trying to
find what were the most useful
properties and in a sense how did those
combine with my production environment
one of the shocking discoveries that
happen first when I started getting all
these lab results with it essentially
when I gave four skillful producers the
exact same genotype or the exact same
cutting taken from a mother plant that I
provided after the course of growing
them out and going to past lab and
testing them thoroughly and even
retesting them we were able to validate
that there was a huge range of chemical
diversity from the exact same plant so
in one sample there was like 28 28 point
something milligrams per gram of beta
mere seen in another there was - and
those two plants were clearly going to
have very different outcomes for
patients and have different therapeutic
properties so then I really keyed into
the fact that the production environment
was a huge variable that the phenotypic
diversity of cannabis
for the interaction between genes and
the environment as a producer was really
as important to me as the actual
genotype or the genetic material of the
plant
so I began creating quadrants I had at
the time three different Medical Gardens
I was associated with and would divide
them into quadrants where I would be
trialing different sort of media
different lighting solutions different
environmental conditions and producing
analytical results additionally I've
always been involved with hybridization
and I say that I you know it was
specifically not intentional plant
breeding I did not have known traits
that I was trying to kind of advance in
the early days but had them on a team of
friends that had produced cultivars that
were pretty famous and Portland in the
early 2000s but really um I was able to
start to kind of look at all of this
genetic diversity and see that in
addition to the variables of the
environment that the genes really
mattered as well and that both of those
have become you know this long-term
exploration that I'm just really
grateful to have had with the resources
and time and partners to be able to work
with all in the hopes of eventually
being able to have a spectrum of
products that really are targeted to
particular patient outcomes of course
many people are talking in those terms
now but I had about eight years of data
prior to the advent of like analytical
testing as a result of compliance
testing in the regulated cannabis
industry and had worked with so many
diverse environments that it really was
a lot of insight about what these
environments and the role but things
like what kind of we're using mineral
salt fertilizers or we're using you know
living organic soil eventually we're
using a variety of different organic
inputs rerunning you know high VPD or
low VPD strategies you have high
pressure sodium Zoar in the old days
where you flowering under metal halides
and looking at all these variables I
sort of had low level observational
study data that was able to help me to
start to key
into trends where I could optimize the
expression of cannabinoids and
terpenoids I'm what was really exciting
was over the course of time using this
kind of feedback I was able as a
producer to really become much more
sophisticated than Arneson high levels
so I know that I there was a group of us
that were growing a dog walker for
example and I think only about five of
us had that plant for many years and it
was easily one of the most important
therapeutic plants that we were working
with especially for oncology patients
people with chronic pain and people who
needed really strong effect and we're
looking for kind of relaxing calming
effects that I noticed that as I was
sort of competing with the other
producers who are our friends I mean I
definitely was hitting extreme levels
and was able to produce because the most
terpenes I've ever seen in a lab results
and that was all through the course of
kind of getting insights in the
observational studies and optimizing the
production environment
of course in those variables you
mentioned photo X one of the things that
stood out after nutrition environment
that was probably the most singular
important variable was lighting and the
quality of lighting so one one of the
things that I was able to start to
experiment with was using the very first
generation of LEDs that were available
with custom spectrums and I ordered
these bars that would have like Deep
Purple's and violet lights and I
witnessed a complete transformation in
the morphology as I used different
lighting spectra and lighting intensity
and so the evolution of lighting I've
really written all the way from like
there was literally mercury vapor bulbs
and you know that turned into metal
halides and fluorescent lights and then
later single-ended HPS lights and then
double-ended that one thing i notice is
when the lights shifted from
single-ended HPS to double-ended hvs
suddenly there was an explosion and kind
of more resinous cannabis and higher
potency
this so it was very clear that the
lighting was you know a giant
differentiating factor and producers who
didn't have access to the HVAC equipment
were the ceiling height or the various
things that required double-ended HPS to
perform well simply had a competitive
advantage that was massive
um I feel that same kind of scheme is
happening with LEDs and I'm sure we'll
talk about this a little bit later but
that ultimately LEDs have provided a
massive competitive advantage for those
who can understand how to unlock the
power of using targeted wavelength and
much more intense lighting and much more
consistent lighting and dimmable
lighting as well as directional lighting
I mean it's just full of advantages but
in any case all of this put in into
motion allows for me to create a range
of products that I felt
stood out and were really special and I
was getting that feedback from patients
that I was working with that was the
genesis of the ideas behind the
dispensary I co-founded with my partner
Shem a wood called Pharma Pharma is a
dispensary in Portland spelled with an F
and the idea was you know we're really
excited about whole plant cannabis
therapeutic products we want to be
sophisticated and representing and
curating those products and really took
almost all of my servant ition for how
that product mix should be curated I'm
based on the early research of dr. Ethan
Russo I've also traveled to Israel and
met chemists like Lumiere and spent time
with Professor ma shulam and a variety
of other people but it was really Ethan
Rousseau who I think gave me the tools
to understand that in that first paper
the taming THC paper I'd read there was
15 compounds people at that and was
giving them a particular value and that
we wanted to be able to curate from that
perspective as opposed to kind of
pseudoscience indica and sativa
perspective or a lot of the other
language and misnomers that came along
with a probe
era and cannabis culture so we for
example tested everything at the
dispensary through one lab through
summarize analytical I actually produced
that all 24 cultivars that we had for
roughly the first year and a half and
while we were still a medical dispensary
but I was unable to continue to keep up
once we became a adult use dispensary
so we then had to bring in a lot of
different producers but during that
first year and a half it felt like
something magical happened where we were
the only dispensary in the world at the
time to post terpene data and to both
feature overall turkeying output as well
as specific terpene content and i came
up with an algorithm that essentially
was able to sort out what all consumers
were coming in with which was this
notion of indica and sativa and being
able to sort of put on a spectrum with
six point relaxing and calming effects
on one side focusing and reforms effects
on the other with a meat week medium and
strong gradation for each of course this
is as much art as science because the
science of looking at the ensemble or
entourage effect at the time and even
now is of course far behind where we
ideally want it to be we can talk in
some depth especially with new
publications by dr. Russo and others
about the individual components and some
of the drug interactions that the
pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic
insights that are still elusive that we
need to understand the really
complicated effects with these whole
plants um is simply not mature yet but
it felt important to sort of draw a line
in the sand and say um the Prohibition
era is coming to an end and it's time to
really honor and respect this plants in
the way that we can sort of like share
the diversity and nuance of traits and
without making it a comparison to
alcohol look a bit like other craft
industries and and be able to sort of
make it more useful to patients but
further we insisted that
everybody we worked with and I was
really at the lead of this in the
beginning I became highly trained and
professional and representing a
science-based vision of how to apply
cannabis therapeutics and work with
products like RSO and especially with
people who were you know late stage
oncology or end-of-life care or seizure
disorders or some of the most important
kinds of patients we were serving and I
think it was just a miracle that I met
Sam Haywood who had the unbelievable
business acumen and marketing ideas and
strategies to be able to kind of help
Pharma to bloom in this way that became
a really unique resource and we really
attracted a lot of attention at national
and international media had just a lot
of support for this model and we worked
our faces off I literally was working
seven days a week I would often do more
than 12 hours a day there were many
16-hour days back-to-back I would be on
my feet the whole time and the
eventually that sort of led to kind of
burnout around trying to operate Gardens
and work with patients and operate the
dispensary and being a tiny team and so
Sam really with the rest of the Pharma
team have continued operations with
Pharma well I took some reflective time
and worked to establish a garden that
would be a bigger scale garden and of
course you know that I love your podcast
and I'm so grateful to be on because one
of the things that you have done is
helped to really emphasize and underline
the importance of ecological production
and sophisticated perspectives from
organic crop production and that's
something that's really really near and
dear to my heart I feel that if at scale
this whole industry employed the kinds
of practices that you espouse from many
people on your show have brought forward
you know ultimately we'd take a bite out
of climate change we'd take all kinds of
sequestering of atmospheric carbon
practices into motion with even further
influence agriculture and horticulture
on the whole and you know there's just
so many wonderful aspects to this notion
that regenerative farm
it's really going to make a huge
contribution to the quality of life on
the planet and I'm really behind that I
also know there there's another priority
that has probably even become more
important for my personal work as I've
gone down this path I really want to be
able to create targeted consistent chemo
chemical varieties that are reliable for
patients and that illustrate a path
towards being able to have a long-term
relationship with whole plant derived by
the chemistry and not simply you know
leave the sort of really serious
patients in the hands of pharmaceutical
companies that are developing you know
through clinical trial work maybe sort
of single varieties of cannabis
chemistry and trying to provide even
from a synthetic cannabinoid perspective
you know totally consistent compounds
but that are not being produced from a
plant or are being greatly refined after
being reproduced from a plat because I
have always had and even more so now
than ever have a just unshakable belief
that there is wisdom in a plant that is
sort of more than we can quantify with
an analytical testing result and
certainly at the resolution of
analytical testing we're at now and
there is also a folk medicine revolution
aspect to relying on whole plants which
means that really we're in a situation
where people internationally can grow
plants and take care of their well-being
and take care of their family and loved
ones and communities well being with
plants and not be entirely reliant on
pharmaceutical companies to be able to
provide that relief but that we have to
become very mature quickly to be able to
command some part of the market share
and to inspire and illustrate a path
forward where people can continue to
relate with this ancient plant in a
really meaningful way and in modern
times find the kinds of health benefits
they would expect to find from even
pharmaceutical drugs but without having
to go through that an entire part of
yeah I guess that part of the economy so
that said I I've become increasingly
focused on targeted chemo bars so I was
trying to build a farm it was going to
be called nucleus nurseries it
essentially balanced the ecological crop
production methods with targeted chemo
chemical varieties so not actually after
raising a lot of money quite a lot of my
a big team and being a CEO and a year
and a half of development that effort
was going to fruit and the campus called
the Oh hub which is the Oregon science
and research campus that Philo's
bioscience Cascadia analytics and a few
other partners we're going to have on
some land south of town but
unfortunately we're actually in
hindsight very fortunately shortly
before Trump got elected when it was
clear that things were starting to go
away from an Obama era into an era that
looked less supportive of the cannabis
economy to flourish um I sort of had to
deal with dissolving a company because
the landlords and the investors started
getting cold feet and things got shaky
and and so really for about eight to
nine months I ended up having to
dissolve nucleus nurseries and this was
a really hard time for me because I'd
worked with people from around the world
to create what I felt would be the most
ecological production environment that
had ever happened we were talking about
like 12 acres of solar panels to run all
led on super high-tech glass house that
was based on Dutch green house design
that was had a variety of considerations
epic scale rainwater catchment and
regenerative living soil program and a
sort of food forest in polyculture
landscape that was featured in anyway
servers this whole vision that was very
compelling I had completely bought in
but after it had to be dissolved
actually that was the best thing that
ever could have happened to me because
that effort wouldn't have been able to
survive in the Oregon market as
market has shaken out with massive
overproduction and really as a producer
your survival depends on being able to
access shelf space and retail so I
became a consultant for a period of time
and my partner Sam and I founded a
company called agonist consulting
agonist then engaged with the now
Governor New Jersey Phil Murphy and I
became involved in emerging regulatory
markets after having had paid dues
already in the organ market which I
didn't mention I was on the OLC see just
the Oregon Liquor &amp; Control Commission
rulemaking Advisory Committee I worked
with the governor worked with the mayor
I worked with members of Congress I
worked with congressman role bloomin our
and actually co-founded the very first
regenerative cannabis event with
congressman Earl bloomin our and in
partnership with the Willamette week
started an event that was really meant
to support sort of the kinds of insights
that are what you're curating on your
show and that's actually become the
largest craft cannabis event in Oregon
and is really doing some exciting things
I'd like to talk more about but I'll
save that for another subject they I had
a lot of experience with sort of working
to try to find a way to bring the best
ethics and practices forward for this
emerging industry that I cared so much
about and to also try to protect the
craft producers and the people who were
clearly in a position that looked like
they were going to be left behind
and so there was a lot of battles and
some of that got played out in the
consultancy but then I landed a client
that is called groundworks industries it
owns proof cultivar and this was the
most fateful moment in my story because
really proof cultivar is a very
high-tech facility in Northeast Portland
it's all controlled environment I'm sort
of precision AG modeled on environments
it has 16 different chambers that are
tightly controlled and it allows for my
original work back to testing
in environmental strategies and huge
amounts of genetic diversity and working
with hybridization to really do this
work at scale in a mature way and it's
really just being a dream come true
where rather than having to manage
investor expectations now there's people
who are really sophisticated at that
that they can deal with that task and
rather than having to do all these other
things that I had to do as a CEO for
nucleus
I found a team that was really strong
and able to support me to do what I most
wanted to do which was to go back to
solve the problem I saw at Pharma which
was there is a huge amount of product
consistency issues in the market the
product variability that I worked with
at the time would mean that if I was
working with a patient and they found
just some miraculous curative
relationship with a very particular team
of our and really whether they were
using flour or concentrate if they were
to come back a month later it was almost
inconceivable that even if we had the
exact same team of our or rather the
same flour it was going to feature the
same chemistry um we just saw huge
continuing diversity in the expression
of cannabis and I really wanted to be
able to provision patients with
something that was more consistent and
closer to being a research grade because
to me this is the critical line in the
sand we have to cross to enter into a
more mature relationship with the
patients that we seek to serve it's to
be able to consistently produce a
diversity a phytochemistry that's
maximally useful and therapeutic and and
life-changing so I've been working on
that project that proof it's almost been
two years now and I've finally produced
some really great results I mean it's
just amazing what we're doing in this
facility where I counted as a team
called Innovation Lab and there are
three main focuses in my research and
effort at this point to make this
research great output and I think that
producers everywhere would be wise to be
thinking about these variables above
many others but the first variable
is to be able to do a phenotype
discovery at scale to be able to
audition a huge amount of genetic
diversity knowing how diverse cannabis
is as being the most out bred plant in
history I'm being able to accommodate
the unique needs of all these different
plants but to just audition in lots of a
thousand all of these different seeds
that ultimately we're looking at from
high level resolution genomic science
like fifty thousand genotypes nips for
every plant a machine learning platform
called proof OS that I've designed with
the team it's really mature data science
team from big AG it helps me to create
an environmental control system that
essentially has sensor arrays and every
environment and that's tracking all
factors related to plant growth in a
pretty dense sensor array that gives
really clear visibility to real-time
environmental experience trending data
and where the machine learning comes in
is to correlate all the way between
genotype to chemo type these
interactions between our cultural
practices and all of the environmental
inputs so taking my early low throughput
chemical genotyping or low throughput
phenotyping into a more high throughput
phenotyping mode we spend one of the
most exciting things about being
approved but so the first discipline is
really phenotype discovery and then that
builds the palette of traits
we're working on in our breeding work
and we have a variety of partners that
we're working with that tylose
bioscience is the most important one for
the phenotype discovery work and we're
participating in a breeders innovation
network that they've helped to
facilitate I think it's a really
exciting collaborative approach with a
lot of ethics to kind of build an
unbelievable new plant stock and both
from like agronomic perspectives and
chemo typic perspectives so the second
discipline that is a core focus for the
Innovation Lab
is actually called photo biology and you
mentioned photo X so one neat little
fact is that Nick clays who is a founder
and CEO past CEO for fluence
bioengineering from Austin Texas was up
visiting me in Portland with his partner
Jerry and one night in front of my
driveway in a rental car you're doing
the same thing I often do and kind of
rattling on about chemo types and the
importance of Adam and how their
technology was intrinsic and you able to
unlock that potential and Nick founded
that night the photo X conference which
has also had for years now and photo X
became an invite-only really special
conference where brilliant academic
resources could come into the cannabis
conversation because it was framed as a
photo biology conference so we would
actually have like people from very
high-level universities working on non
cannabis research that was relevant to
cannabis things like looking at
carotenoids research which is a
secondary metabolite that's important if
you're concerned with nutrition and
produce and how that relates to photo
biology or the effect of light on life
really but specifically looking at
wavelengths and the different functions
wavelengths of light are playing as well
as the intensity of light and exploring
for the first time with these
cutting-edge fixtures that allow for us
to really in a very precise way I'm use
wavelengths strategically to optimize
plant growth of course nASA has been
doing some work on photovoltaics and I
believe the late 60s early 70s for space
travel and there's been all sorts of
early assumptions like red and blue
light or own two wavelengths that are or
that are principally associated with
photosynthesis um of course we've gone
to a much more complicated world now
where we understand that all spectra of
light interacts with both plant
morphology and phytochemistry production
in very interesting ways so at proof we
have two different chambers that are
being used and a single factor variable
research to illustrate currently we're
working on the impact of far red light
being included in a broad spectrum
fixture versus more of a near red light
and I know that you were at photo X this
year and we had the kind of godfather of
photo biology Bruce Bugbee from
University of Salt Lake there and he was
presenting his findings about the
inclusion of far red light and this
turns out to be a massive variable where
he's seen things and basal crops and his
reproduces work with other scientists
that you could like increase that little
bit of for red light and then greatly
decrease all of the rest of the ppfd or
the photosynthetic photon flux density
and still see increased biomass
production and increased secondary
metabolite formation so that is a big
deal because we're always working
towards in controlled environments
what is peak efficiency look like how do
we reduce our carbon footprint to the
absolute you know smallest it can be but
for those of us were focusing more and
on a biopharmaceutical perspective and
needing to have consistent chemistry
needing to use these controlled
environments is absolutely imperative
the diversity in fuel drum cannabis is
pre tremendous and I'm in love with it
and I love to consume it myself and want
that to be the lion's share of the
industry but I think there's a very
special place for these kind of more
targeted solutions that the LEDs can
provide but energy becomes the biggest
concern in consideration which is why
I've been on a technical advisory
committee for the resource innovation
Institute and REI has been working to
really for the first time map the
footprint of producers and to become
very fine toothcomb analyzing the
producers inputs especially related to
lighting and HVAC and both for indoor
and outdoor producers as well as
greenhouse and that's that's been really
useful but
- this new research and photo biology is
illustrating a path by which we can use
greatly less energy which of course led
is compared to high intensity discharge
features fixtures greatly reduced the
overall energy I mean something like 50%
less energy than 1,000 watt HPS for our
current LED solutions and 40% less
energy for the HVAC because we have way
less thermal load and then when you add
dimming in which we use lots of dimming
so that we're using targeted you mole or
targeted ppfd for different
developmental stages you see a net
reduction around like 70 to 80 percent
beyond a thousand watt HPS and if you
look at our footprint as a facility at
proof we only have about seven thousand
square foot of blooming canopy then
though we're in a 60,000 square foot
controlled environment warehouse with
all these chambers we have a much
smaller carbon footprint than all kinds
of other industrial warehouses that are
our neighbors and our close proximity in
Northeast Portland so I'm proud of where
we've gotten to but I promised that in
the very near future we're going to go
much farther being able to combine with
batteries and photovoltaics and even
more efficient light emitting solutions
like the newest generation of fluence
tech like the Viper tubes and spider
Suz it gets to a point where you really
really are using nominal amounts of
power to be able to provide these rich
environments but that's actually not the
most exciting part of photo biology
although it's a really important thing
for me and Troy I know a lot of the
people who listen to your work but
probably more exciting is really that we
can greatly affect morphology so the
structure of the plant which when you're
dealing with plants that are very
compact and very lanky in a spectrum and
you want compact plants in an indoor
environment that allow for you to have
consistent canopies with as little
intervention as possible lighting can
play a very significant role in the
structure of plants clearly broad
spectrum from very early on as a
resulted in just a level of vigor that
is
you know like what you'd expect to see
in a Sun grown crop I'm unlike relying
exclusively on orange light from HBS
fixtures which never look quite like
some grown crops again the most exciting
pieces the photochemistry and it's
what's happening at the end stage so
we're seeing really fascinating things
with using broad spectrum wavelengths
the inclusion of specifically green
light to create broad spectrum and fill
out what you're often missing and the
other fixtures and actually one of the
interesting things is we've my best data
around turkey production from the early
research and of the garage and basements
actually Illustrated that ceramic metal
halides we're producing the best
terpenes of any lighting solution that
we had access to at the time it really
ceramic metal halides are kind of an old
technology again relying on gas filled
bulbs that are really not consistent in
their expression the moment you plug
them in like any other gas filled bulb
it's already on a gradation where you're
losing intensity as well as wavelength
and so if you want to spit or further
they're using a lot of electricity and
they're producing a lot of heat and they
just and they're distributing light in a
way that needs reflectors it's not
directional and you can't dim them and
there's all these huge issues that those
were by far the best terpene producing
lights so we work to emulate that they
know that the physio spec spectrum that
you see influence is really emulating
that but now we're going well beyond
that or I know that what we're doing at
proof will illustrate paths forward for
targeted phytochemistry paired with
particular cultivars and cultural
practices and environmental strategies
that become recipes for chemical
varieties
that's so photo biology given that light
once everything else is in balance I
would argue it's likely the most
important variable the quality of light
and the intensity of light as well as
the consistency of light and producing
consistent kheema bars and so you really
have to get dragged into this discipline
if you're a careful cat
know this producer and want to know how
to do that you really you have to learn
a lot about physics and light it turns
out so photo biology is the second
discipline in the Innovation Lab the
third discipline is the one most true to
your podcast which is that we're
passionate about organic crop production
I've worked a lot with living soil I've
had the blessing of working with some
incredible people as I have worked with
all sorts of different raised beds and
shared root zones and hyper complex
Rises fears but required no additional
nutrient input beyond green mulch and
some teas and I've really worked with
that I've had about four years
experience with living soils I had some
of the best candidates I've ever
produced in my life unquestionably come
out of living soils and I also had some
major crashes where I was even with my
best resources and I'm calling on people
that are brilliant and a lot of
resources present and trying to do
analytics and everything I have
literally watched an entire garden just
crash and burn I that said I know that
there are we are much more sophisticated
thanks to you and many other people who
are on the frontier of educating and
bringing popular education and rum the
dynamics of working with living swill
and yet still I realized that proof I
needed a kind of a modified approach it
is unfortunately currently producing a
bit of effluent and that we are not
reusing our media we are custom mixing
all of our own organic inputs and we do
some very scientific process to organize
our organic crop production in a way
that as close to really consistent
reliable results as possible so that
whenever I'm interacting with scientists
who say come on if you're doing that
kind of research the only way you'll
establish a meaningful baseline is to
use mineral salt fertilizers and I am
adamantly opposed to using mineral salt
fertilizers other than in very limited
expressions for very particular kinds of
research but in general for
our product it's just imperative to me
that be both clean green certified and
go way beyond what most people consider
normal organics and then go more into a
precision AG modality so how I've chosen
to do that this incredible team that
proof is really to test each individual
input we source most of the things that
we can locally and then we actually do
analytics through a lab in South Florida
called QA l as quick turnaround really
affordable big AG lab and so we test the
inputs consistently then we custom mix
it and currently we're still hand mixing
for our whole facility although we're
bringing on automation for the mixing
over this year um then we measure the
substrate the leachate and those are two
independent things that we're testing
and when we can which is not always
consistent right now we measure the
tissue as well and we're looking at
micro and macro availability of
nutrients and we're able to through all
four of those analytical processes which
has not been cheap and has been a huge
blessing to be able to finally get
insight into we are getting really
really good at understanding what
particular team of ours need to flourish
and learning that there is a broad range
of diversity in the solutions we need to
employ additionally we have a
fertigation system that took me seven
months to design where we do apply some
liquid nutrients that are of course all
organic but that allows for us to deal
with some of the crop diversity issues
where there's never a one-size-fits-all
solution in our facility we're really
targeting for groups of cultivars
they're grouped together by length of
maturing time which is one huge variable
compact and lanky plants is another
another axis by which to look at them
and also looking at specific nutritional
requirements outside of those things
because if you obviously have a longer
maturing plant versus a short maturing
plant that changes a schedule of inputs
but for
there are plants that we found that are
clearly more acid loving and plants that
are more base loving plants that need in
our six part dolomite lime input you
know more of the medium grade less of
the fine grade or these sort of
strategies that don't result on you know
kind of the classic put more cal-mag in
this one just needs that orb it's like
actually formulate in a targeted way
from our initial media mix the lion's
share of what the plant will need and to
do that for all of these groups of
plants in this complex facility were you
know we could be between 14 and 20 mm
plants so being able to use analytics to
validate the nutrition and availability
of nutrition as the fundament and then
to work on enhancing that with biology
through a variety of practices has been
the sort of mainstay of our organic crop
production program and that is the third
point of research which is actually a
really excellent in-house soil scientist
who's on our team in Meg Haussmann who's
been doing that work I'm a person who's
actually leading or indeed for me for
the Innovation Lab is an amazing plant
scientist named she's me Kylee Mendonsa
and so we've got some increasing
scientific Pro s working together along
with lean I our grower and Todd saucy
or operating director but what's been
incredible is having this facility that
can essentially facilitate all three
kinds of research that I've just
described at scale as we are a
commercial producer and that as I
brought my own plants into the facility
which are things that I've been working
on hybridizing based on analytical
results and I've developed sort of
cultural practices and environmental
targets for over the last decade we are
seeing amazing results tab some of which
I just texted you earlier today because
we just I was happy to see the beginning
of 2019 a review of the best smoke and
organ of 2018 and to happen to see a
two of the five reviews about new chemo
boards that we produced one of which is
a type 2 plant which I believe people
should be ready for the fact that type
2s are going to be far more desirable in
coming years and I think type ones
you're currently you see high THC plants
receiving the most attention in the
commercial market but type 2 plants are
unbelievably versatile and that you can
produce a huge range of sort of ratios
of THC and CBD as the engine of this
plant but then bring in really novel
chemical varieties by crashing type
warms in the type threes and so forth
because type threes and twos are vastly
less likely to be bottle necked right
now in the way that type ones are you
know there's a notion that when you're
selecting plants for hybridization in a
population of less than 200 you're going
to create a genetic bottleneck that
essentially is losing a huge amount of
traits that are very important if we're
seeking to adapt to changing times or
make these new vigorous you know early
maturing pathogen resistant exciting
chemo VARs but I know that type twos
actually have been winning cups secretly
like there's stories that you can
Rousseau told me recently about the
rainbow gummies that one in a type-1
category a high THC category in the
Emerald cup was by far the most desired
cultivar and it was a Terp Emmaline
dominant type 2 which is rare because
most type twos and type threes are
you're seeing dominant so this is a less
relaxing sedative form of Medicine and
similarly astral works has become real
people's choice in Oregon it's been
written up as the best CBD products and
Leafly and so forth and a bit really
after works as a turpentine dominant
anthro seinem flush like deep deep
purple brilliant flower that's just it
smells like nothing I've smelled before
it's in that hazy serpentine just
perfuse brightness and then it's also a
under
we've oblivious heavy yielding early
maturing plant it's got an array of
other compounds like a minor
cannabidiol Varon with CBD v feature and
a lot of Turkey and diversity and
intensity it's coming in very high oil
I'm over 3% oil and so any case these
are things that are starting to be
accepted in a market it otherwise is
driven to my horror entirely by THC
percentage if you look at BBS analytical
data which is the best market-based
analytical perspective on what products
are selling in Oregon or California
Washington etc um you really see an
Oregon people are buying and paying more
for high THC cannabis but the problem
with this is that you know in the
biosynthesis of these cannabinoids and
terpenoids
you actually have a shared pathway
between the path that produces
cannabinoids in the plant from group
glucose and the class that produces
terpenoids and this is the Geron o
pyrophosphate which you're going to have
limited resources to make all these
drugs you're choosing do we send all of
those resources to this one note you
know that we can make synthetically or
that looks like marinol or just be huge
THC products or you do diversify and
start sending more of that energy
towards turpenoid production and more
poly chemical perspectives because one
day soon we're not just going to be
talking about terpenes and cannabinoids
we're going to be talking about
aldehydes esters ketones flavonoids and
all of the other important therapeutic
agents that this plant is so willing to
produce so the bottom line is I'm
excited to see some consumer awareness
growing around the fact that it's very
likely you will have more pleasure and
much better effects from the next gen
type 2 plants coming online after the
amazing work of people like Lawrence
Ringo of soham and Jamie from resin and
you know people who have really changed
the world by bringing type threes back
and type twos back but I expect in the
Maine
retail sector as people start to get
more sophisticated type 2's are going to
play a much bigger role because they're
just very desirable but we're seeing in
addition to really exciting type twos
like Astra Works which is by the way a
hybrid they produced from tangerine haze
mail that was unbelievably vigorous and
imparted Turpin lean and vigor and
anthocyanin to anything that was using
that in a hybrid with and worked with
Laurence Ringo's Carly sue which was the
earliest maturing heaviest yielding most
desirable type 3 flower I personally
found after auditioning something like
25 varieties in it and a year and a half
and just as something that's worked
really well for patients the particular
variety I had clearly had the CBD V
feature working with seizure disorder
patients the inclusion of CBD V clearly
anecdotally increased the odds of
efficacy and success and working to
suppress the frequency of seizures so
that plant is I just think a legendary
plant but then being able to create this
hybrid was this was it like exactly the
outcome I was looking for
I found a bridge between those worlds
and have a type two that it's not you're
seeing dominant and that it's just
amazingly useful but we're also seeing
just in Turkey in production and the
type one's huge concentrations of
terpenes one of the problems with
measuring terpenes is that we have a
huge amount of inter lab variability and
in Oregon we have a program called or
lap which is meant to govern the labs
and ensure consistency and the approach
and process that they're using I'm going
back to Pat Marshall one of the amazing
things that he did was resolved to use a
method 8270 which is the it's a method
that's been used by the EPA for
measuring organic solvents for more than
40 years and the very mature method with
lots of lots of redundancy and quality
control built into it so he used a great
method these are the three things I
think are important when you're looking
at a lab what is the level of experience
and the credibility of the practitioner
number one number two what methods are
they using number three what equipment
are they using and I think when you get
sophisticated at looking at those three
variables you find that actually even in
the regulated economy there are a lot of
labs that I do not consider to be
passing muster but Pat was special and
that he had a great method was
unbelievably experienced he was mainly
focused on GC at the time which is why
we got such great terpene data the
bottom line is the range of what
terpenes are being reported it varies
widely but I'm saying anywhere between
you know an average sample in the market
or in the cultivation classic data it is
produced with 160 entries from single of
skilled producers in Oregon an average
of like maybe one one and a half percent
oil
I consider 2% and up to be high oil
I consider the cultivars coming out of
proof to be among the highest I
personally seen in the market using
Cascadia analytics as our baseline who
have demonstrated a pretty visionary
approach to being market leaders and Al
both in California as well as in Oregon
providing a pretty unique approach to QC
for producers but I've not seen anything
over 5% um I am seeing in our varieties
a about a third of our current varieties
that are new ones that I've bred in the
4 to 5 percent range so hitting us high
oil as I've seen and these are plants
when you harvest them literally with
like plastic gloves you just see oil all
over your hands they're just it's
unbelievable I mean and I find that
really desirable and the effects are
really quite strong that we think about
high THC in a way actually for anybody
who is at the Emerald cup this year or
who wasn't there
you should go online and look at dr.
mark lewis's talk and is he just did a
brilliant simple sort of expression of
what's happened in the industry with
chemo bars and we see that over the
years we have been more successful
producing higher levels of THC that was
not just through breeding by the way
that was through light intensity and
production environments we were able to
evoke that because I've been able to
evoke very
hi THC from inbred lines or landrace
cultivars that were clearly not not as
intensively hybridized and just by
adding really intense light I would seem
lots of THC and very little other
compounds but as that's happened we've
seen consumers have increasingly
negative effects and so we know that
we're really good at serving this core
superuser market which is what the
existing product mix is kind of
dominated by but being able to expand
into this utility where we're more
effective at serving say more women than
men because right now if you look at the
BBS market data we're actually losing
women as the regulated market is growing
we're serving less women than we were
before that's a really big issue if you
look at fact that everybody stands to
benefit who has an endocannabinoid
system from using cannabis products that
are well formulated and balanced and
interesting and their profiles but for
some reason our product mix is driving
women away we're going to be more
effective in serving aging boomers and
this kind of end-of-life population and
all these other populations when we
cease to only have this kind of high THC
metric I'm but there are many ways to
ameliorate the negative effects of the
psychoactivity of THC which you I love
THC and I'm I'm a happy type one
consumer I really love type twos and
threes as well but I've always consumed
type lunge but I I'm really concerned
that if we don't produce more terpenes
which is a great strategy to change and
affect the expression of the THC for the
patients or more cannabidiol rich
cultivars or more minor cannabinoid
featured cultivars and we're simply not
making the right products that the world
needs the world needs a diverse array of
products and that's a really important
theme that I see going forward both at
proof and for the industry on the whole
um so gosh can I just talked at you for
a long time I hope that that was
reasonably well organized because I
don't think you've been able to get it
word in edgewise I apologize my friend
no I have so many questions for you but
I know you're also out of time so I
wanted to propose this what about if I
save my questions and maybe had you back
on another time but also opened it up to
listeners to ask them questions cuz you
I mean we you touched on so many really
important topics ranging from anything
from terroir and chemo type expression
I'd love to find out you know what
generalizations can you make based on
you know the type of lighting or
nutrients or methodology around the
round growing that you might be able to
make for growers how this changed from
high Mersin plants over time as it has
affected patients or people who are
using it for medical purposes I wrote
down what chemo type expressions are
most beneficial for for different
different uses there's just so many
questions I have for you oh and like how
stress response may affect chemo tipica
as well as one that I think that just is
a fascinating topic so I want to save
these questions would it be okay to have
you back on another time when you have
more time and we could we could just do
a little quick short answer QA
I would be honored my friend I would
love to be on in the near future when it
works for both of us and yeah have it be
more fun and having to give you an
opportunity to respond to your questions
and anybody else's but and all of those
questions you just mentioned are really
important and there are a lot of
thoughts so yes and it's a joy to have
time with you today and I know you have
a lot of other exciting content coming
but I'm looking forward to chiming in in
the future as soon as you're ready great
well thank you so much for your time
today Jeremy great to talk to you and I
look forward to coming down and actually
checking out proof it's it's been on my
list and after hearing more about it I
really can't wait to see it well I can't
wait to have you and thanks for
everything you do Todd thanks for this
podcast
thanks for the community that you bring
together around it and for all the
inspiring visionary solutions that are
proposed
I certainly have gained a lot and really
appreciate the content and I know that a
lot of
people do too so thanks for all the work
we do again that was Jeremy plum
director of production science at proof
cold bar I posted a ton of links and
information relating to this podcast
right on the podcast page at WWE is
organics calm just click on the podcast
menu on the top of the home screen and
please reach out with questions either
on our Instagram page at kiss organics
or through our website contact page
thanks for listening