[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
i'm your host tad hussey of kiss
organics this is the podcast where we
discuss
the cutting edge of growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge
my guest this week needs very little
introduction if you've ever studied
lighting you've probably read some of
his research
bruce bugbee is a professor at utah
state university and president of apogee
instruments
he is internationally known for his work
with nasa to design food systems
for people living on mars and has been a
frequent speaker at conferences on
indoor food production on earth
in 2011 he received the governor's medal
for science from utah governor gary
herbert
he has recorded several videos on
photobiological principles
just search for bugbee agriculture
perhaps his pinnacle achievement is
summarizing everything he knows in a ted
talk entitled
turning water into food
hi bruce welcome to the show i'm great
to be here
ted yeah can we start off uh talking
a little bit for listeners who may not
be as familiar with you and your uh
your work in research could you tell me
a little bit about yourself
i'm a professor at utah state university
and specifically a professor in the
college of agriculture and more
specifically
my classes are plant physiology
and plant nutrition those are the things
i teach in the
research i do uh about
close to 40 years ago now i get funded
very early in my career i got funded by
nasa to
for plants in space and living on the
moon living on mars
and that got my students and i
into doing photobiology
way before there was any leds but we
still had different types of lights and
filters and
we started to study the effects of
spectral quality on
plants and that's now become a big part
of the
research in my lab
now for listeners who may not be
familiar with the term
uh correct me if i'm wrong photobiology
refers to the effect
of light on uh organisms
or correct like humans plants yes
all these things it's a broad it's a
broad term photo is light and biology is
all of biology
so it can be effects of light on
microorganisms
effects of light on animals my part of
that is
heavily focused on light on higher
plants
and even more narrowly effective light
on food crops
we're not studying um ecology
of uh in in a forest my colleagues study
those sorts of things but
my work is very heavily focused on
economic plants which of course cannabis
is an example of an
economic plant well when it comes to
lighting
everyone talks and looks to you it seems
like in the industry
for research and expertise so you have
quite that reputation of being sort of
that leading expert when it comes to
lighting and uh and so
i was really excited to get you on the
show i've i've heard you speak
multiple times as well as online there's
some great youtube videos
that i'll put links to in the podcast
page that you put out with apogee
you also have a role over at apogee do
you want to touch on that too and
mention the company a little bit
yeah in 1995
i started to make light meters and and
it was really it was in my garage and
i was modifying voltmeters and putting
photodiodes in
them to measure photosynthetic radiation
and then i subsequently started a
company
and the company now has 30 some
employees and you know quite a nice
building here in
logan utah and i'm still
intimately involved with the research
and development
in the company so i
i guess my day job is at the university
and my weekend job is
my company but the company makes
instruments
to measure light not surprisingly
because that's a spin-off of my
research and different wavelengths of
light spectroradiometers
quantum sensors for light so that's
given me an additional ability to do
research to help
growers i want to spend the majority of
the podcast
talking about i think led lighting and
and some of the research and knowledge
you have around that but
let's talk briefly about the equipment
that apogee sells and what some of the
tools are for measuring light
in a growing facility and how best to
use them
you know dad i might start this by just
saying
you can go for probably thirty dollars
you can go and buy a
lux meter or a foot candle meter
and those are real cheap and they do
give you relative levels of life
but they weight the colors all wrong
they wait green and not blue and red and
people buy those and measure lights
for plants and they can have very
significant
errors
but even beyond that most of us
most people think they can tell how
bright the light is
they look at it and they say that's
pretty bright and a little brighter over
here
but our the human eye when when there's
the light is high the iris contracts
to with just a pinhole and it
regulates the amount of light getting to
the retina
so if you are inside and you look at a
very well-lit room
and you say is this brighter or about
the same as outside or less and
most said no no no no it's a little less
in here
and then you take a meter and
a well-lit office might be 10
units of light and the units we use are
micro moles of photons
per meter squared of area per second
just like it was little
invisible marbles falling on a surface
it might be 10
in a well-lit office outside
at noon on a sunny day it's 2
000. wow 2 000
divided by 10 that's 200 times more
light
outside and plants respond to that
they grow almost 200 times as fast
outside as they would in a well-lit
office and that's just stunning to
people
when they've never measured light and
they hold the meter
and they walk around and do that they
they just can't believe it on that
hundreds of times in my career i've seen
that the light bulb go on for people and
they go my goodness
i didn't know what i was missing and now
they're measuring light everywhere
and the plants do see it and that's one
of
that's probably the single most common
problem is
people under appreciating the amount of
light
that plants need and they don't provide
enough
light and then they blame it on the
fertilizer or
something else when it's just plain not
enough light
so that sort of thing is how apogee
started
it was i recognized that and i started
making low-cost meters for
people to help people measure light and
specifically
like for plants which we call
photosynthetic
radiation and
no that people just kept buying them and
the company got bigger and the products
got better and
multiple different kinds of products but
i think
to get back to your original question
you asked me
something about you know how would you
measure this
and in the simplest sense there's a
single
sensor that makes an electric signal
goes to a meter that integrates
all the colors of light in one sensor
it's
we call it a quantum sensor because a
quantum is a
mole of photons and
it's a relatively low cost sensor
but it doesn't tell you if you have red
light or green light or blue light it
just tells you the total
so for that you need a spectral
radiometer
and now the price jumps up to about two
thousand dollars
and and depending on the quality of the
spectroradiometer
but that tells you the individual
wavelengths so for research we're always
using spectral radiometers
and but for just spot checking things
we're just using the quantum sensors
so just a quick summary of a lot of
different things but
um there's a lot of different kinds of
light meters
yeah i wanted to try and recap this so
and please correct me if i get anything
wrong here so when we talk about a light
meter
we want one that's going to be measuring
uh par that 400 to
700 nanometer range because that's the
range that
is associated with plant growth and
we want to know the intensity i use the
word intensity i don't know if that's
the
best definition the amount of photons
that are going to be hitting
the meter and and and that tells us
uh the ppfd or uh that longer
term that you threw out there i've
always used ppfd just because it's
easier
for me but um being able to
measure that as an important tool
because when we talk about
a grow light for example we want to know
how far away from that light should we
position our plant based on
the the stage of growth of the plant um
you know how hard we're pushing the
plant you know and uh
every every light is going to be
slightly different
so that i think that's an important tool
and a facility to be able to know oh boy
if i'm a foot away i'm at 1200
ppfd versus two feet away that light
that light intensity falls off quite a
bit
yeah yes and then yes
people say that all the time are the one
foot away two feet away three feet away
and um that's almost like sticking your
finger
in in orange juice and seeing and
licking it and saying oh
i think the ph is ph4 you're not
measuring it you're just kind of
guessing and an experienced person
can make a reasonable guess but boy
given how sensitive the plants are to
the total amount of light
and how fast it changes you can measure
it and go a foot away and it's a
different number
and you just cannot see that we cannot
see that with our eyes
that's where light meters come in and
gosh in my experience they're they're
very underutilized
in the world of uh indoor agriculture
outside we have we take what the sun
gives us
we can measure it but we can't change it
anyway
now we just measure it
the inside we can change it and to
optimize it
you got to measure it so when we're
talking about light just as an overview
um we're really talking about a few
different things we're talking about the
intensity of the light uh which would be
the amount of photons hitting a leaf
or a given point we're talking about the
quality of the light
in terms of the range and spectrum of
that light and then we're talking about
the
dli which would be the amount of light
that plant's going to receive over the
given
photo period when the light is on can
you kind of
talk a little bit about those three
things or if there's
if there's a major component that i'm
missing here in the summary
feel free to add on to that too
well we can certainly break it down into
quantity
and quality and both of them are
important
quantity is under appreciated and
quality people over worry about quality
we should be all thinking more about the
quantity of the lights that it get
and less about the
the ratios of colors because the
quantity is a
huge factor all of the meters
measure light they're calibrated to give
you a number
per second and and this is all good
but what the plants respond to is
the daily light integral which means the
total amount of light
over the day and
meters don't automatically give you that
you have to connect it to a little
microprocessor
that adds up the photons and the best
analogy is like a rain gauge
at the end of the day you want to know
how much a
total it rained in that day and you look
at the total for the day so
you hook your sensors up to a little
microprocessor
it adds them up and and records the
total for the day
either gives it to you on a screen or
records it
so the daily light integral
is a step above just measuring the
instantaneous
light per second
it's if you have electric lights it's
possible to say this is what it was per
second
my lights were on for 16 hours and
multiply
to get the baby light integral as long
as the light is exactly constant
but it's any in a greenhouse anywhere
that has variable light
you need to record it and
so that's the intensity and and this
the ppfd that you mentioned is stands
for
i think you know this but photosynthetic
photon flux density
and it's the amount of light per unit
area
per unit time and amount of photons
we try not to call it light because
usually
the word light refers to what the the
ratios of colors that people see
um we we in my papers you'll see we
rarely use the term light we always say
photon flux
because that's more precisely what it is
even though that sounds
very technical after a while you get to
use you used to
saying photon flux and then your then
you can
impress people at parties because you
didn't say light you said photon flux
but so that's quantity of just the
pure total that the plants get the
quality
is the races of the colors and
for that to measure that you need a
spectral radiometer
little prism and it divides up the
colors of light
and measures them all separately and
that's a good bit more
sophisticated instrument apogee
instrument sells a couple different
models and apogee is always working on
better quality cheaper
spectroradiometers
there's a now there's a fairly wide
array of spec radiometers on the market
and oh if you get a lower cost one
the optics aren't as as good uh
the resolution isn't as good for ev
for example telling
um cyan from blue
or some you know some color some
discrimination of color that a human
could easily see
the the instrument might be not be able
to do that
in the lower cost meters but
now we get ratios of colors
and as everybody knows we can manipulate
plant shape with ratios of colors
and i don't know if this is the time to
i could make a review of all of that
here if that seems appropriate sure
you know i think it relates to a comment
that you made uh
on one of your youtube videos and you
touched on here too saying that
light quantity is more important than
quality in relation
to cannabis i you know we do get caught
up in looking at spectrum when we look
at
bulbs when we look at led lights
but your research is showing that that's
not as important
or you're not seeing as much variability
in plant growth
can you talk about that yeah
that that's correct quantity is more
important than quality
and i i think it comes from what we see
our eyes are exquisitely good at seeing
tiny differences in color
i mean you go to a paint store and
there's what is there 10 to the six
different shades of colors of paint
because we can tell
all those colors apart we can tell
those colors apart better than a plant
can
because just because our eyes are so
exquisitely tuned to see
shades of colors but our eyes
as i mentioned a minute ago our eyes
can't really tell intensity very well
so that you then you say well
intuitively no wonder we're so worried
about color
and we don't worry about intensity
because we worry about what we can
see but for the plants it's really the
opposite
the intensity is what determines
photosynthesis
and plant growth and the color
for the most part determines plant shape
meaning a tall skinny plant a short fat
plant those
those sorts of things
so if we went through the
colors there's
really divide them into five categories
and that's if we start with ultraviolet
those are the photons below 400
nanometers
we can barely see those they're they're
just not
visible and of course
humans think oh i'll provide it as bad
you got to put on sunscreen
but what we really ought to be thinking
is
some ultraviolet is good it's just how
much
and it some ultraviolet is good for
people because it makes vitamin d
and some ultraviolet is good for plants
because it makes them tougher and it can
trigger chemistry
that is associated with flavors
in plants so
ultraviolet and now we have uv leds
that are they're called uva 360
i think the peaks are 365 and 385
nanometers
they're almost visible you can tell
they're on but just barely
so can we manipulate those to change
flavors in food and quality in plants
and the answer is yes but in the
laboratory it's been harder to do that
than we
thought we thought oh this will be
pretty easy we'll just shine these and
all kinds of things will change and
it's not been as easy to do that as we
thought
but that's uv the next
color up is blue and blue has powerful
effects on plants
sunlight is full of blue light and it
makes plants
tougher it they synthesize
pigments that protect the plant plants
make their own sunscreen
and protects them against uv
but blue helps keep plants short and
that's almost always a
good thing in plants we have found
blue photons can have a bigger effect
on some of these flavor compounds than
ultraviolet
protons that's a con contrary to the
popular belief that
ultraviolet are really powerful but
blue blue photons help keep plants short
green photons are sort of they're in the
middle
and you know people say other green
photons they just bounce off that's why
plants look green
but that's just a tiny fraction that
bounces off
green photons are primarily valuable
for the people if you have some green
photons in the lights
you can see the plants better and
you can distinguish tiny insects that
are and
tiny disorders diseases
just when they're just barely starting
from
the green light from the led so i'm a
huge
advocate of led fixtures should have
more
green photons in them so that people can
see the plants better and better
diagnose the plants and if they can keep
going just a minute
red photons are really well absorbed by
plants and they're very efficient the
number of photons you get
per watt or per joule of electricity
is excellent that's the most efficient
led but they're expensive to produce
for a manufacturer the leds the red
leds can cost five times as much
as a white led so
we don't always put a lot of red leds in
the fixture
but other than that they're
photosynthetically efficient
and they're electrically efficient and
then
as more and more people are coming to
know all the time
there's far red photons which are
700 750 nanometers
and again those we can barely see
they look like a burner on an electric
stove when you just when you can barely
tell it's on
that's far red light be hard to read a
book
by that amount of light but those have
big effects on plants
and mostly they increase stem elongation
ah that's not good we don't really want
tall
plants but in lettuce
they increase leaf expansion which is
really a good
thing so particularly in lettuce
far red photons really help the plants
expand
more so it just
went went through five colors of light
from uv all the way up to far red
in a fast overview that was that was
perfect uh i did want to go back and ask
some specific
questions regarding these various
spectrums
in relation to cannabis so
uh you know i know you've talked before
about
dark cycles and i know people will use
green lights
typically when they want to go into a
cannabis room
during a dark cycle have you done any
research to really see i mean
they used to say plants don't see green
light but i think that's been disproven
um can you touch on that a little bit
yes
yes we have and yes that's that's a
common thing we even call green lights
safe lights because you can turn them on
the plants won't see them
i can tell you that's completely wrong
plants see that green light almost as
well as blue and red
so it's
it's really
if you have to go in at night just use
this gimme light as you can
but the green light the plants do see it
at night
and in some of our studies they can see
it just as well as the other colors of
life
which is sort of unfortunate because
wouldn't it be nice to go in there with
the green light and
be able to see the plants and the plants
can't tell you're there but
they can they do so um
be careful about the using green safe
lights at night
well that's good advice because i know i
bought a green light back when i very
first started growing thinking if i ever
had to go into the room or see the
plants that's what i would use but
it sounds like again you're saying light
intensity
is more important than the light
spectrum or light quality i guess
in that case yeah yeah so
if you have to use dim light make it as
a green light
make it as dim as possible good so
talking about cannabis specifically then
um
you mentioned uv you mentioned far red
how did these spectrums affect you know
terpene production cannabinoid
production
and how important are they because um
like like you just stated you you don't
seem as focused on spectrum as
i would have thought that kind of
you know that's surprising to me uh
so can you touch on like i mean
obviously these spectrums
do have an impact on the the morphology
of your
of your plant uh so how
what recommendations might you make or
areas for research around
you know spectral analysis and cannabis
we are certainly researching cannabinoid
synthesis
full time and and we're also getting
into terpenes
but we've got lots more data on
cannabinoid synthesis
and we have not found
as nearly as big of effects of
ratios of colors as we thought we would
you know that many other people this is
you get
this will go up with this um now i
didn't say there was none
no effect they're just smaller than they
thought they would be uh here's one
specific
example that growers often observe
because those red leds are electrically
efficient and good photosynthesis
many manufacturers put lots of red in
their pictures it's real
common now to have white leds with a lot
of red
that's a that's a great combination of
colors because
you get enough white so you can see the
plants you need a little bit of blue
you put some blue in and then you have a
lot of red
when that red the fraction of red
photons
starts to climb up above
maybe 70 percent we
see white tips on the flowers
and and that's a common thing it's real
striking because these big flower buds
and the top half an inch the top
centimeter
doesn't have any chlorophyll in it it's
it's
white at best it's light yellow
wow this is a striking thing
and many people have reported this
and we have done enough studies on it
now we know that it
only happens when the fraction of red
photons
is very high maybe above about 70
uh what we think is happening is
the red photons are god i'm going to
make an analogy they're like dessert
and they're just great the plants soak
them up and they love them
but the plants don't make photo
protective
pigments when they have a lot of red
photons
these these are nice photons we don't
have to protect ourselves against these
so they don't synthesize photoprotective
pigments
at least in the tips of cannabis flowers
and then it causes photobleaching the
the light degrades the chlorophyll
so empirically we regularly see it with
high red high fractions of red and we
think that it's
the lack of photoprotective pigments
plants always have to
synthesize things to protect filter the
light
and protect the chlorophyll protect
other things in the leaf
so that's just a little sidebar story
about those white tips
in cannabis flowers under high fractions
of red light
so i always thought that was associated
with
too high of ppfd now i know cannabis can
handle
very high ppfd uh that kind of leads me
into one of my questions though is like
transitioning plants uh from
you know different levels of
of light i've seen that
you know moving from hps to led lights
for example changing that
spectrum can have an impact on
on your plants um even just you know
ratcheting up the
intensity or the photons on a
on a given plant too rapidly seems to
have detrimental effects
do you have any research on or any
information i see i thought plant
bleaching was caused by moving
you know a plant that was under fairly
low light let's say you know 400
ppfd up to like 1 1200 overnight
you would see that sort of effect but um
that is a common thought that it's that
that photo bleaching is either too high
a light or too fast to change
we don't have evidence for either one of
those um
we've grown plants with very high light
and the
all the flowers are nice and green um
and and a
lower level of light but a high fraction
of red
the tips turn white so that's far more
related to the fraction of red than it
is to total
intensity that's a non-intuitive thing
because you see bleaching there must the
light must be too high
but what it really is is the red photon
fraction is too high
now relative to changing light levels
that's common people sometimes lots of
growers just
very carefully ramp the lights up
but when we have done studies with
photosynthesis
where we're measuring the photosynthetic
rate of the leaves
they adapt to new light levels very
rapidly
like certainly within one day to a
change in light so
it's a good idea to to
not change the light too fast but
it you don't it doesn't have to be and
our
data doesn't indicates it doesn't have
to be as gradual
as most people do it we've gone from
a light level of 300 micromoles to the
next day
1200 micro moles and provided
the proper water and nutrients the
plants are just fine
they jump right up the photosynthetic
rate quadruples the light quadruples and
the photosynthetic
quadruples right away the next day
so i wouldn't say
rapid changes in of light don't matter
at
all because i because i think they do
but they just don't matter
nearly as much as people think
that's so interesting i i want to touch
on that a little more because i
i remember from my botany classes and
this was a little while ago so
i'm a little shaky that uh plants would
have you know shade leaves so light
leaves that were the levels of
chlorophyll were more adapted to
less lower light conditions and that
would change over time
based on the amount of light that leaf
was receiving
what you're saying though is that
cannabis can make these
changes just pretty much in
overnight yeah then in a couple days
it can change now a shade leaf is a
thinner leaf and a sunleaf is thicker
and a thin leaf doesn't just become
thick overnight that's for sure
but the chloroplasts inside the leaf
orient
um if you can imagine if you took your
hand and held it flat in low light it'd
be flat
then you give it highlight within
minutes the chloroplasts turn on an
edge so that they don't
have so much light shining on them and
then the light penetrates
deeper into the leaf so there's an
example of
the change that happens in minutes and
certainly within an
hour as a plant goes from low light to
highlight
and then in highlight the next set of
leaves which starts to come out a few
days later
is a highlight leaf so if the plant has
a short-term
adaption that's rapid and then a more
profound long-term adaption
to the highlight but i've seen some
really good
growers that oh my they inch that light
up just
50 micro moles a day and
i'm thinking they could go much faster
than that
in in terms of optimizing production per
unit
area i mean if you have the capability
of giving them high light
i would give them highlight so that they
can just
ramp up faster and start growing faster
yeah i've always heard about 10 a day
was sort of the
the rule with leds in terms of ramping
them up
um it sounds like we could maybe
adjust that uh one one question that had
me thinking about was
since we're changing the photo period so
dramatically with cannabis
indoors and that's not really something
that
we you know we can change necessarily
how do we best utilize light would it be
better to
say ramp up the light uh intensity the
the ppfd uh prior
to flipping to a 12 12 cycle while
you're still in veg
or is it better to keep the light
because
you're using lower light levels in veg
traditionally in the facility
when we make that jump is it better to
do it before switching the photo period
or after have you seen any research on
that
so this is where is instantaneous light
micro moles per meter squared per second
interacts with daily light integral
because we're always drawing cannabis at
18 hour roughly 18 hour photographs make
sure it stays in veg
and then we switch to 12 hour photo
periods
so if you didn't change the intensity
you just cut the light by two thirds
but going from 18 to six or you cut it
to two thirds of
what it was that's a huge change
and given that the plants perform based
on daily light integral
you can ramp it way up in
in the uh if they
let's see if i did the math you know if
you're at roughly 600 micro moles for 18
hours
you'd go to 1 000 micro moles for 12
and the plants would have the exact same
daily light
integral even though you increase the
intensity it's
less time so that i think that's common
to do
um sure you could you could ramp the
light up in veg
um but i think the plants will adapt
just fine even if you don't do that
okay so keeping the dli closer
yeah keep the dli the same okay
um okay so talking about uh light
intensity there when we
when you mention the amount of micro
moles
uh what and this is a tricky question
but what are you hearing is optimal for
cannabis i get asked this question a
fair bit
i hear numbers around a thousand up as
high as 1200
i realize that some of your research has
shown that cannabis can handle much
higher levels
of light but when we're talking about
the cost of
wattage and i realize that you know the
value of the crop
you know what you're what you're going
to be able to get for the crop what the
cost of your electricity and your
facility is all of these things are
going to be factors but
do you have a general recommendation
for optimal levels
sure um now when we say optimal
we usually mean an economic optimum
yes and the return on investment for
per unit of electric power and then
to be really comprehensive it's the
return on investment for the whole
facility
that all the costs there's so many
fixed costs in a facility you can afford
to be
sub-optimal electrically but your
overall return on investments better
because the yield goes up let's say
grams per watt
how's that for a standard grams per watt
would be would typically peak
at maybe five or six hundred micromoles
some really fairly low level of light
but if we do grams per watt per meter
because you have to calculate the area
in there okay
now it's going to peak more like 1000 or
okay because it's the area's in there as
well
and cannabis as as i pointed out in
previous videos it was just
certainly a highlight crop oh it
responds just beautifully to some
real highlight so we have pushed it in
some studies
higher than that pushed it to 1600
and the yield keeps going up but
you had 30 percent more light and the
yield goes up
maybe 15 so there's a decreasing return
on investment to
push it with higher and higher light and
the capital costs go up
he's got to buy all those lights and
lots of lots of other input costs go up
at higher
light levels it also depends on how
optimal a grower is able to keep the
root zone
the nutrients and water have to be just
right
all the time if and you don't have much
margin for error in highlight
you're driving a race car at 600 miles
an hour
and you better have good tires and good
brakes and a good steering wheel
and all the other things have to be
co-optimized
with that higher knight because it's
it's harder
to get everything optimal if the light
input is real high
yeah i wanted to touch on that because
you've you know you've repeatedly said
that
in order to run higher light conditions
you have to have
optimal grow conditions which which
i just want to be clear you're
referencing more water
more nutrients more
co2 i assume um
in order to achieve this i mean let me
let me clarify that a little first of
all
you always want to be enriching with co2
and
most of the effect is optimal at a
thousand
you get a little bit more to go to 1200
this is parts per million
co2 you just always want to be
optimizing that
it's lots of advantages and the cost is
tiny to to do then
nutrients if you're watering
with a liquid fertilizer
you automatically get more nutrients
when you go to higher light
because the plant will use more water
if you if you double the light the water
use
roughly doubles if your water always has
the nutrient solution in it is what
you're
watering with the nutrient solution okay
so you
put twice as much water on you
automatically put twice as much
nutrients on
uh if it's a slow release fertilizer if
it's coming in some of the ways young
then you do have to increase the
fertilizer just because you're going to
have a bigger plant
with with higher light so it's
it's getting it right all all the time
all hours of the day not and especially
water
just making sure plants not gonna
run out of water so we
i i work with a facility that did a
trial a lighting trial
and they were able to increase their
yields quite dramatically by switching
from
double-ended hps over to a full-spectrum
led light
however they also were looking at using
you know hps in veg and then
flowering in led and different
combinations of such so
so you know using leds for veg and then
flowering and with hps
and they got significantly different
yields on the final crop based on
what that combination of you know
lighting technology was
um how do you have any information
relating to
transitioning from lighting technologies
one to another i've heard people say
you know going from uh led to hbs is
fine but going from hbs
to led is or maybe i'm confusing him now
is a little trickier
well let's let's take the the old days
before leds with cannabis production
and in the old days it might have been
like 10 years ago
i mean it's sorry the old days they
weren't that long ago
everyone always used metal halide lights
for veg and high pressure sodium for
flowering
do you remember that then oh totally i
yeah and then i use the cmh lights which
are popular again now because there's a
lot more options on them
um definitely so when you if you ask
people why why do you do that they just
well that's it's always been done that
way
but in reality what was happening was
metal halide lights have a lot of 30
blue photons way high blue photons
that kept the plants short in veg
which is a good thing but metal halide
lights are not very
efficient electrically so when you went
to
flowering where the height was already
mostly established then you could use
the
high pressure sodium which are more
efficient electrically and you can give
them
much higher light levels so without
knowing
really the underlying reasons people
were doing something reasonable given
a lot of blue photons to keep them short
keep make the plants short early and
then just using a really efficient light
later
our studies if anything high pressure
sodium is a near perfect spectrum
it's four percent blue um it's got
plenty of green it's got some red
um it's it's a good spectrum for growing
plants
but now of course leds have passed up
high pressure sodium
by quite a bit in efficiency
so they're they're certainly been coming
on strong
but it really isn't because the spectra
is better
leds with the high fraction of blue blue
photons are not as photosynthetically
efficient
as red photons so you don't want to put
more blue
in your fixture than you need just
enough to
keep the plants short keep in making
photo protective pigments
and that's something we're studying in
detail now on a range of crops but
what's the minimum amount of blue and
it's somewhere between
about three percent and maybe
10 percent depending on plant species
but a lot of lights have 15 20 even
25 percent blue
and that's a that's not an optimal
spectrum for photosynthesis
um and it may keep the plants too short
um so i want to talk about since we're
kind of getting into this idea of
commercial led lights but before we do i
had one more
spectral question for you here does the
660 to 680 nanometers play a part in the
increase of anthocyanin production in
plants
and is its level too high in current
grow lights
um that's 660 to 600 to 680
that's all those are all red photons um
no they do not uniquely enhance
anthocyanins
blue photons do blue photons enhance
anthocyanins which are the red pigments
in plants
and that red pigment is one of the most
classic
photo protective pigments why do plants
make red pigments it's to protect them
against excess light and
too much protect them against uv light
those photoprotective pigments absorb
photons
and they don't cause photosynthesis
anthocyanins that's
red lettuce grows slower than green
lettuce because those red photons are
blocking some of the light
but to more specifically answer this
red light doesn't trigger them no
okay it's blue light does that's why my
uh
purple varieties of uh tomatoes grow so
much slower
than my other tomatoes it seems like
yeah yeah you get the price to pay for
that nice color
yes well higher in antioxidants too
there's supposedly more nutritious that
was the trade off that's right
that's right yeah yeah that's right
okay well let's talk about commercial
led lights
uh how do you go about evaluating them
you know it seems like we've moved to
full spectrum lights with leds
that we've moved away from that bluish
purple
color so we can now see our plants again
which i'm
grateful for what what should
as a as a grower if i were to outfit a
facility
what questions should i be asking a
company that makes
led lights so i think the first one is
just was real simple it's
what's the cost per watt of fixture
because the last thing manufacturers
want you to know is what the fixture
costs
but obviously if you're getting a
600 watt fixture and and a 300 watt you
can pay twice as much for the 600 watt
fixture so
um that's a simple ratio but
knowing what you get cost per one then
after that
it's the efficacy of the fixture
which is measured in micro moles per
joule
but it's really the output of the
fixture divided by the electrical
input to the fixture this is explained
in
some of my papers and some of my talks
but
one way to think about this is the micro
moles per second
out divided by by watts
of the electric input
fixtures can vary quite a bit in that
efficacy
and if the manufacturer has paid to get
more efficient
leds in there the fixture is worth more
money
because the the light output is better
so you could also you could say how many
moles of photons does this fixture put
out
and how many watts of electricity does
it
have coming in and then what's the cost
of the fixture
those are just very fundamental
ratios in considering a fixture
and lots of people still use high
pressure sodium because the pictures are
so cheap they're yeah just remarkably
cheap um so after that
after we're dollars and photons out
one consideration that people need to
think about is
how much focusing of the light do they
want
it's possible to make leds very focused
put a lens on the led
and they can be very focused almost like
a laser
of light and that's both good and bad
it's good if you know exactly where you
want the light
don't shine it on the aisle put it on
these plants
but it's extremely difficult to get
uniform light
if your fixtures are so that focused
so often high pressure sodium we mount
them up high
they spread the light out the light goes
everywhere
and and you say well some of it falls on
the aisles it's wasted
but it's also real uniform over the
whole crop
and that's something leds have been
working on is
spreading the light out more not making
it less focused
so the photons get spread out over a
bigger
area and and the result is more uniform
light
for the for the plants so
to summarize this it's really cost of
the fixture
wattage output efficiency
or or efficacy of the fixture
and then beam spread of the photons
is it can you want focus photons or do
you want spread out photons
thinking about the application
so that the photons are uniform and they
maximally fall on leaf surfaces
now to further complicate things if i'm
understanding you correctly from
what you were saying earlier the
spectrum also
influences the efficiency of the light
if there were more
blue leds in the light it's going to be
a less efficient light is that
is that right was i getting that correct
tip
well typically we don't put usually just
blue leds
the blue leds come from white um leds
but it's a blue
led with a phosphor coating okay that
fluoresces and gives us white
light so we don't usually see fixtures
with just
just blue we see white leds and reds
those two colors are that's that's
becoming a very common
led fixture and it's very effective
it's just the ratios of the whites and
the reds
and that ratio will affect efficiency
yes it does the efficiency rating i
guess the more reds you put in
the the more efficient the light because
the reds are more efficient than the
lights okay so
this is going to probably be a dumb
question but i'm going to ask it anyway
because
i don't know the answer uh when it comes
to photons
and hitting a canopy i've heard claims
that
you know certain lights are more
more effective at infiltrating a canopy
as in penetrating deeper so you have
less light
fall off over a given distance
how does that work is that is that
accurate are we going to see big
variations between different lighting
manufacturers on something like that
and i know there's lots of claims that
this
two factors affect it and the second one
people don't often think about the first
one is green light
green light penetrates deeper than the
other colors
because it's reflected off the leaves
and it bounces around and gets
lower in the canopy so green light is
helpful
for penetrating canopies but
the bigger factor is the ratio of direct
photons to diffuse photons
direct photons would be like a sunny day
where the light's just shining straight
down
and diffuse photons are like a cloudy
day when it's coming from
all directions and diffuse light
penetrates canopies much better than
direct
light if it's coming from all directions
let me use an analogy here
this might have to be with a
flower because i can't really use bbs
for this analogy but if you were gonna
put put a scoop of flour on a plant and
you just dumped it straight down
the flower would stick to the top leaves
and it wouldn't penetrate down to the
lower leaves
but what if you took your scoop a flower
and shook it so it made a cloud of dust
and that came in all directions
you would get more flour on the lower
leaves of the canopy
and that analogy is like diffuse light
and high pressure sodium then leads to
quite diffuse light because a lot of the
photons
come out of the fixture sideways and
they're going into plants
three rows over at a low angle
and those protons can penetrate the
canopy better
than direct then ones that shoot
straight down from the top
so fixtures that spread
have a big beam spread spread the light
out better
lead to more better penetration of
photons
into canopies and diffuse light means
light from multiple directions so it
comes in sideways it comes in straight
down
that's a that's a bigger factor of
penetrating the
canopy than the color color matters but
not as much as diffuse photons
so i'm picturing these photons
i guess uh bouncing off of different
surfaces
maybe you have a white wall for example
next to a row of plants
or bouncing off of leaves and possibly
penetrating deeper that way
do these photons
so as i understand the spectrum defines
the the speed of the photon is that
correct
um not the speed it's the wavelength
the wavelength okay they all travel at
the speed of light
it's the it's the well that's not as
obvious as it might seem but
but it's the uh the wavelength of the
vibration
level of the photon so the vibration
level
i guess i'm picturing like this at this
agitation
does that allows for different levels of
penetration
into a leaf or off or bouncing off of a
surface
um let me here's another analogy
this this is a confusing thing this this
frequency of the electrons
if we had blue photons or high energy
and high energy would be like a bunch of
third graders
and as the wavelength gets longer these
the
you could consider it by analogy the
photons are getting older
and by the time you get out to red
photons
they're like a 70 year old they are not
moving as fast as the third graders
you know and bouncing around everywhere
but both of those get
that's that's an analogy for energy of
the photons
but the plant doesn't care what the
energy level of the photon is
one high energy third grader photon
causes the exact amount of
photosynthesis as one
low energy longer wavelength photon
after
it's absorbed okay photosynthetic
pigments
but no that it's just a matter of
absorption and
blue photons and red photons are
very highly absorbed right in the
surface of the leaf
they don't bounce off so they don't
penetrate the canopy
green protons bounce off and they rattle
around and they penetrate deeper
so at what point then do we determine
that a leaf
is a is a nutrient sink versus a
photosynthetic
benefit to a plant is there a
certain you know ppfd if we're using a
light meter where we could hold it down
and say okay
we're getting down to 400 or 200 ppfd
here underneath the canopy these these
leaves need to go
yep for sure people spend
a lot of time pruning canopies we
we don't prune we've been the reason we
don't prune
is those old leaves automatically
translocate their nutrients and their
carbon
up to the younger leaves of the canopy
they they don't die and fall off and
take all these resources with them
they they move it to the younger leaves
and if you take those off
you're removing nutrients and and
carbon compounds that could be used by
the top of the canopy
now we do prune when we have inadequate
air flow
for disease reasons pruning really helps
move air and minimize disease
but many people prune thinking that
those old leaves are bad
for the plants get them out of here
but we get very high yields without
pruning because those leaves are
translocating
re-mobilizing their resources into the
top of the canopy
and if you cut them off they can't do
that
i'm picturing like a fruit tree in the
fall where it sends its sugars back into
the plant itself for stores for the for
winter to make it until the next year is
that
essentially what you're that referencing
yeah no that's exactly right
those leaves that fall off of all trees
not just fruit trees
don't have very many nutrients in them
the plant took them back in
before winter and stored them in the
trunk of the tree
so i i have so many questions but i'm
going to narrow it down to just a couple
more so i don't keep you on the phone
too much longer
yeah i think we're coming up in a little
over an hour already
all right this will be fast so uh real
quick i'm seeing
lenses on more and more leds have you
done any research
with the use of lenses to focus light
in relation to cannabis or indoor indoor
plants
yes um it's if we think of lenses as
focus electron also spread it out too
depends if the lens is convex or concave
um but as a very general rule i see more
fixtures where they're spreading the
light out to get a more uniform
amount of photons in a canopy and also
to help
kind of get those sideways photons
penetrating
deeper in the canopy so this is a type
of lens that
does the opposite of focusing it it
unfocuses the
photons and spreads them out more
sideways
okay so how useful then is really uh
changing spectrum in in light some
lights give you the ability to do that
other lights don't the ones that don't i
hear
the common things saying growers are
more likely to you know
screw things up than actually make any
benefit based on where our current
research is on lighting spectrum
do you have thoughts on that tuning
tuning the lights
comes at the cost of the total number of
photons
as it comes at the cost of fixture
efficiency
when you when you start adjusting them
it's it's always takes a little bit more
electricity to do that
um and even though it's possible to
change the spectrum over time and and
there's if you do that you can
have benefits but gosh
if for me i would take a fixed spectrum
that then and i would take the total
intensity of photons i would
take an efficient fixture that gave me a
lot of light
rather than one where i could change the
colors that gave me less light
so as a rule of thumb
i like fixed spectra because you get
more light per unit of electricity
now research-wise is another matter sure
you know we
change colors all the time in research
but that's different than production
that makes sense yeah so this is my very
last question
what future research are you most
excited about uh
right now in the world of lighting
oh we are continuing to
investigate ultraviolet light
and there's lots of kinds of ultraviolet
all the way down to uvc
using uvc potentially for short bursts
of time
for disease control and also to keep
plants short
the studies on the potentially
beneficial effects of uv they're just
understudied we also have a series of
studies going on with the minimum
amount of blue light that plants need
uh we're doing a lot lots of work on
light pollution at night how much light
can the plants can cannabis
tolerate cannabis is real sensitive to
light pollution
and do the colors matter at night
that's another thing that's an active
area of research
and then we talked about variable
spectra over the life cycle
we're more interested in variable
intensity
over the life cycle when we put more
photons on when could be
be putting less photons on that's
another active area of research for us
yeah i can imagine you know maximizing
or optimizing
your light efficiency would have huge
ecological impact on this industry in
terms of the amount of
electricity that we're potentially you
know quote unquote wasting
uh with the way we're growing right now
and it's gotten more efficient
compared to where it was 10 years ago
but i'm excited to see what you guys
come up with on that
yeah yeah well it's yeah it's exciting
stuff
it's a it's a it's a cannabis is a new
crop
sensitive to light so and
boy it's so high value we can afford to
grow it indoors
under electric lights and then take
advantage of all the
control we have over delivering light to
the plants
yeah well i sure appreciate your time
today i learned quite a few things
myself
and i know that others will appreciate
appreciate you've done a lot of
good work and research for the the
cannabis industry and the plant industry
in general and i'm just really grateful
for your time today thank you
i might mention here at the end we are
getting ready to teach
a class called the science of cannabis
cultivation
this will be taught through utah state
university
extension it's an online class
the tuition is it's it's 30
lectures 30 hours of lectures covering
all aspects of
light and nutrition for the plants the
tuition is going to be 950.
for this class and it's taught my by
myself
and three other uh faculty colleagues
that that have done lots of research and
lots of consulting in cannabis so
that's another thing we're looking
forward to it's not available yet
but we're getting close to offering it
online well let me know as soon as it is
i will uh be happy to share that out to
the audience too as well as
a direct link to it in your pod on your
podcast page so
that's wonderful thanks dad all right
thank you visit with you all right have
a great rest of your day bruce
yep bye now
[Music]
that was bruce bugbee and you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast
don't forget to check out the podcast
page at www.kisorganics.com
click on the learn tab then podcast and
please take the time to leave us a
review if you listen on apple podcasts
or other platforms i do read them all
and appreciate the feedback
and more reviews help us rank higher so
others can find the show
and if you want to support us or the
podcast please take a look at the
variety of soil amendments soils
lighting fixtures and other growing
products that we offer on our website
we carefully research all the products
that we offer and manufacture to make
sure they are science based and meet our
standard of quality
thanks for listening