[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge this
week's podcast is all about lady bugs or
lady beetles as they are commonly known
and why you should never purchase them
online or in a garden center
one other thing to mention if you find
this podcast as fascinating as I did you
should check out the lost ladybug
project at lost ladybug org you can find
and photograph local ladybugs and send
them to entomologist at Cornell for
identification and data logging it seems
like a fun project to do with science
minded kids or something I planned on
doing myself the next time I see an
interesting one in the wild my guest
this week is JP Michelle
dr. Michelle is a professor of
entomology at Kansas State University he
is an insect ecologist specializing in
biological control and other aspects of
crop protection entomology he has a
background in evolutionary ecology and
many of his research endeavors are
guided by the implications of
evolutionary theory his interests
include cultural and conservation
approaches to biological control of
aphids in field crops ecology of the
Coxon elodie which is a the proper word
for lady beetles I learned and the
interface between host plant resistance
and biological control dr. Michel
completed his Bachelor of Science at
McGill University and his master's and
PhD at Simon Fraser University hey JP
thanks for coming on the show oh thanks
for inviting me yeah I got to hear you
speak down at the bio Controls meeting
last month in Portland and you were the
keynote speaker it was a great talk I
really enjoyed it and one of the things
that you talked about was why people
should not be buying ladybugs or lady
beetles as they're called can we talk a
little bit about what ladybugs are talk
a little about their lifecycle before we
dive in
these reasons why they're they're not a
good idea to purchase oh sure and and to
be clear I'm referring to one particular
species of lady beetles that's harvested
from the wild but in terms of life
cycles they're all pretty similar so
let's cycle depending on temperature
we'll take about 25 to 30 days about a
month so they are they have a full
metamorphosis so egg larval pupil stages
followed by the adult and so both the
larval stage and the adult stage feed on
aphids and other small soft bodied
insects and the eggs of other insects so
the larval stage is gonna last anywhere
from I would say 14 to 20 days and
that's the period where they're
consuming aphids and of course the
bigger they get the more they consume
now the adults can live quite a variable
period of time they also feed on aphids
but the females eat a lot more assets
than the males especially when they're
producing eggs but come fall and shorter
days cooler temperatures different lady
meals have different strategies for
surviving the winter most of them in
North America go into some kind of diet
pause they hibernate just like other
animals do in winter so they become
dormant and very quiescent and then when
they're and they remain that way until
spring so in the fall generation they
can live as long as six to eight months
but once they start reproducing in the
spring then they start dying very
quickly but then you have another
generation so for example here in
Central where I am in central North
America the number of generations per
year will vary from anywhere from two to
five depending on the availability of
aces now out here in the high plains
it's harder for them to survive the
summer than it is the winter when it's
hot and dry because there's no ancients
so they actually go into a type of
different type of diet pause we call
estivation
so they're still active they're out and
about trying to glean a bit of foods
stay hydrated but they're not
reproducing and they do that if you stop
reproducing they can live several two or
three months even in the summer but
again once they find a good patch of
aphids they start to produce eggs the
females will will again start dying very
quickly so there's the trade-off to diet
plus when you do reproduce you reproduce
less but it's better than reproducing
when there's no food around mmm that's
really interesting I know that I've seen
different types of ladybugs in my area
up here in Seattle some that look more
like what I would see available in like
you said when you go to a store or
garden center you a lot of times you'll
see them there in the little bags moving
around how many different species of
ladybugs are there approximately in a
given area and and is there an easy way
to tell them apart
well they are cool because lady beetles
are what we call Apple somatic so most
of them produce a kind of bad tasting
alkaloid in their blood you know which
makes them very distasteful for birds so
they're brightly colored to advertise
that and so because of that they have a
very very distinctive coloration pattern
so they're not as far as insects go
they're pretty easy to tell apart but
you there's hundreds of species and you
still really have to know the common
species around are a very abundant and
everybody will recognize those but
there's a lot of rare species that are
probably in areas where you don't see
them as often and some of them are
extremely small as small as two
millimeters across so most people are
unaware some of us eat just mites so
there's a lot of there's a lot of
different species but the most the ones
that most people are going to be
familiar with there's probably three to
five very common species that occur all
across North America and one of those of
course is the one you're seeing that
people sell in these bags or containers
it's called the convergent lady beetle
HIPAA Damien convergence and this is the
one that is sold by mail order all over
the country and probably should not be
allowed by law
unfortunately because the beetle itself
is widely distributed as a species
there is no regulatory control of this
and so what were people are doing now
the interesting thing about HIPAA damia
in a mountainous area like in central in
the Sierra Nevadas of California in the
fall they form aggregations to go into
this hibernation state so you can
actually people actually go up there and
they find these sites and they can
shovel them into buckets that's how many
there are and so they're collecting
these beetles for free and so this has
really put all the people who used to
rear and cell lady beetles out of
business because it doesn't cost
anything to shovel them into buckets but
it costs a lot to rear them in a
laboratory and yet these are the very
these beetles should not be shipped
because first of all let's get to
efficacy these are the old beetles that
have survived the winter so the females
are very little lay eggs left in them
and they're held in cold storage so once
you bring them out of cold storage you
know they're there automatic response is
to fly away because they're way up in
the mountains and they have to come down
the valley in the natural situation to
find something to eat in the fields so
they don't tend to stay where you know
people release all these beetles in
their garden they come back next day
there's nothing there now if you have a
greenhouse you can contain some of that
too but what you really want ideally and
releasing adults you want them to lay
some eggs because it's those larvae that
are going to be diligent about combing
every plant and getting every last acid
and and again these older beetles
they're hardly they don't have any eggs
left in them they're like little old
ladies with canes at that point and so
they're really not very effective but
there's bigger and more to be more
concerning ecological issues which is
the fact that they are have their own
little ecosystem associated with them so
they're they have parasites they have
diseases and those diseases and the
whole suite of organisms associated with
those beetles in California is not going
to be the same as that occurring in
other parts of the country so when we're
moving these things around and mailing
them across the country we're also
redistributing their diseases
they're natural enemies to other
beneficial populations which may not
have the same level of resistance or
co-adaptation to these diseases and
parasites okay that's one thing another
thing is they have very different
behaviors even the same species
different populations and very different
behaviors here and for example in the
high plains than they do on the coast or
where you are up in Seattle a completely
different climate weather systems even
different patterns of prey utilization
without what they can survive on what
they can't dramatic differences between
populations and so when your mother's
beetles around and they leave and they
get out they ain't going they interbreed
with the local populations and so what
we have a term for that we call is
genetic admixture so they don't have the
genetics appropriate for that region so
they're actually whatever traits they're
conferring when they interbreed with
local populations are not going to be
suited to those areas so it's just
another way we're weakening local
populations these beetles by you know
distributing them all over the country
to habitats and environments they they
don't come from yeah I want to kind of
highlight that point cuz I think that's
really crucial what you're saying there
so this idea that even though you may
find the same species in another part of
the country from where they're
originally harvested they're gonna their
behavior is going to be different their
disease resistance is gonna be different
so we could actually assuming let's just
say in theory we had a greenhouse and we
had a few native lady lady beetles
already in there if we bring in if we
order online and bring in these other
wild harvested ones we could be in
theory really damaging those lady
beetles ability to protect our plants in
that greenhouse is that essentially what
you're getting at yeah a much larger
scale because you know it's not it's not
gonna affect everything in the
greenhouse but it's gonna have the
potential for negative impacts on yes on
your local populations of the same
species because there will have
completely different biology I can tell
you this I've gone to see the hip edenia
poor
convergence is in Puerto Rico it's lost
its ability to die apart but guess what
I can see them some tropical aphids that
you could put our you know would not
even support the development and
survival of our populations and so it's
acquired over over the years completely
different set of adaptations and to
survive where it is and yeah you could
still bring them here and interbreed
them with our beetles but then you'd
have a mishmash of traits that in the in
the hybrid progeny that really wouldn't
work well in either setting you know so
the the difference between these
different populations is remarkable as
something that I've been studying for
over twenty years
I mean there we we've done comparisons
in our lab of hippedy Mia from Georgia
from California and from right here in
in Kansas and I'll tell you for example
insecticide resistance the ones from
Georgia you can you can spray them all
day long with pyrethroids and and
organophosphate insecticides and they
don't even die I mean you can reach we
basically reach the does the the
solubility limit of the insecticides and
we couldn't kill them and over here
they'll just die at the drop of a hat
and the reason for that is because in
Georgia they have a lot of cotton
production and it's very chemically
dependent so all the all the hippo
Damien Georgia have this ridiculously
high level of insecticide resistance
that you don't see in other populations
so that's something that we did you know
as a result of our agricultural
practices so imagine what nature has
done in terms of making them different
that's amazing I had no idea and the
insecticide thing is really interesting
because that's sort of what we see with
a lot of our our pests and why bio
controls are so important is because we
create these pesticidal resistances from
spraying all these these pesticides and
insecticides you know consistently over
time on a given population you can go
down to brazil and you've got completely
different species of [ __ ] and ellas
that are abundant in cotton production
there
what they're resistant to pesticides do
now because they had to be Cox now
that's the Dino campus is that the that
you're talking about there I'm sorry I'm
sorry for that I Carson Ellen is the the
generic term for lady beetle that's the
family Cox Adela tea so it's just a yeah
the coccynelle it is just a lady beetle
in so what's the Dino campus Coxon Ella
Dino campus a coccynelle II used to be
called a different name it's it's a
Hymenoptera s' parasitoid in the family
bruh comedy so that's the family that
has a lot of different parasitoids
including the little aphid Paris - it's
they're all in that family these are
much bigger than the Ava desert read an
interesting thing is they are all female
so they don't produce males and see
there's a big advantage of that of
course because when they emerge from
their host in the spring they don't have
to look for a mate they can just go out
and start stinging beetles they attack
the adult beetles and then the larvae
develops inside and crawls out of the
adult beetle and it's very interesting
because it's there's it's turning out to
be a very complex relationship and the
parasitoid doesn't just inject an egg
and some it also injects some viruses
which modify the behavior of the beetle
and so what actually happens is once the
mature larvae exits through the anus of
the host it spins a cocoon because it's
a little wasp larvae but the adult
beetle that's still alive clings to it
and protects it and stays alive for
quite a few days and they've actually
shown in the field that if you remove
the the old terrorized beetle from the
cocoon of the parasitoid its survival is
greatly reduced so the parents so he
needs the beetles are sort of hug on to
it until it finishes its development it
leaves behind this virus in the in the
beetle even efforts it's controlling the
behavior its host even after it's
physically left it wow that's kind of
that sounds a little like Bavaria
this yes and and and again sponge I do
the same thing they alter the behavior
of their host before they kill it so
that they end up in a suitable
environment for their when there's a
dispersal but this so this is an
internal parasite though that's found
inside of harvested lady beetles that
will come back and kill your lady beetle
or lady brought those harvested lady
beetles that the past toys are died
opposing inside the beetles so they're
hibernating inside their hosts they're
waiting for spring just like the beetles
are so there are there kind of
metabolism is all on hold they're trying
to just you know slow down everything
and just stay alive until it's
springtime and of course when they
harvest the beetle they're and Mail them
all over country they're mailing the
Pastorius and you can we've done it we
bought bags abby'll you can see air
between five and 15 percent of those
beetles are parasitized and it's not
just parasites they have different
spiral plasmas and different types of
little parasitic bacterial infections
and things so chronic infections you
know just like you can have a chronic a
sexually transmitted disease it's not
going to kill you but over the time it
really you know I can really affect your
your your fitness and your health so
these beetles have their little sexually
transmitted diseases
literally and also mites that live on
the surface and suck their juices and
all these kind of things so but of
course in within a localized population
that's isolated from others like on the
other side of the Rocky Mountains those
all of that ecology adapts you know to
what's around it and so the mites and
the parasites well they over time
attenuate their impact because if they
kill they're too many hosts they kill
them too quickly then they don't have
any hosts right so this complex truce is
sort of between all these different
organisms but don't you take them and
you throw them into a completely
different population and they're
interbreeding and they're sharing all
the psychology well those introduced
those populations where you said it may
not very likely do not have the same
levels of resistance to those parasites
or diseases and so this is
the ecological concern there that this
is one of the most important species of
lady beetle we have for controlling
Athens certainly here in Kansas but in
many many agricultural settings
worldwide continent-wide and by moving
this population if everything from this
one population in and spreading it all
over the country we're actually you know
doing more harm than good to our one of
our most important species nationwide so
if people want to utilize ladybugs or
lady beetles in their garden or attract
naturally attract these ladybugs what do
you recommend for people that want to
promote lady Lady Bird ladybug health
okay in our area same thing for
attracting parasitoids so is the natural
attraction if you have a healthy little
ecosystem in your garden or wherever
that will come by themselves now granted
some areas there's Ana landscape of fact
or some areas where they don't have good
reservoirs of lady beetles to attract
them from you know if you're a very very
even well why shouldn't sit there's some
species a few species that are thrive
even in cities where you have just one
little abandoned lot you'll have some
weeds or some aphids on you'll find
certain species that will be there now
it won't be the same diversity you'll
find out in an in a wildlife reserve but
mostly if people have a live in an urban
habitat where there's a patchwork of
gardens and some floral resources you
should have a good reservoirs of natural
enemies they should come by themselves
and what does it take it take flowering
plants okay so if you look at all your
beneficial your different beneficial
insects that we want whether it's
parasites whether it's predators like
lace wings or lady beetles at some point
in their life stage at some point in
their life cycle they need floral
resources and for the adults beetles out
here it's during the summer in the adult
stage because sometimes the only source
of moisture they can get is from a
flower in the form of nectar or extra
floral nectar in some cases so the
flowers act as an actual well or you
know as a source of moisture
in very dry situations and so but but
the pollen is also important because the
pollen is a source of protein and so it
can actually help them as a source of
protein now almost all lady beetles will
feed on pollen and nectar very few of
them but some of them can actually
complete their whole lifecycle on just
pollen there's only one species that we
know of but it's a very important one
and that's the twelve spotted lady
beetle the pink one so it's very very
prolific it can eat a lot of different
things and so the point is flowers are
going to attract them and they maybe
really need depending on their
physiological condition they may really
need that pollen or nectar so they'll
come for the flowers and if they find a
fitter than they lay on the aphids they
can smell the essence so they can find
the aphids quite well on their own but
yeah it's also devoting a certain is a
certain area of your garden to perennial
flowers will be really beneficial for
the average person and if you're growing
in a greenhouse it's the same thing we
looked at high tunnel situations and you
you do better in a high tunnel situation
by putting lures which smell like plants
smelling all the Greenleaf volatiles
odors and things you can buy them and
then actually having some flowers they
are flowering and they will attract more
natural enemies that will do you more
good than actually releasing natural
enemies and try to contain them in there
because they'll find a way out and if
they're not where they want to be
they'll just find a way out and whereas
if you produce the environment that's
attractive they'll come all by
themselves and I mentioned perennials
and outdoor settings because perennials
and outdoor settings you're probably
going to be worried about weeds and
certainly out where we are here but the
thing about Prairie all the weeds
they're annuals they can't compete with
perennials so if you can establish a
good perennial garden not only will
leave you with a mix of species that
flowers all summer long so some will
flower early summer flower mid summer
for our late and the weeds will never
have a chance to establish because the
perennials are coming up and
when they have the stored reserves in
their roots and so they out-compete the
weeds and then they give you a longer
period of floral resources and so a
longer period of attractiveness for all
those beneficial insects and again you
know the same thing are going to benefit
pollinators if you have a crop that
needs pollinators you know so you're
doing a double good thing when you do
that you're not just benefiting the
beneficials that eat your past you're
benefiting pollinators you know one
thing we haven't talked about is
pesticides you mentioned that the ones I
think you said it was Georgia are highly
resistant to pesticides but in general
what sorts of effects do traditional or
even organic applications of pesticides
have on on Lady Bird populations well
that's a deep topic but you know the
older materials that were not very
selective the contact insecticides we
were using up until the end of the 20th
century mostly are all neurotoxins and
so yes there's certain populations of
lady beetles that I've had so many
generations of exposure what they really
have is high titers of enzymes that can
detoxify these things but really fast
but in the last 20 years we've had there
are a lot of really good more selective
insecticides that are for example just
kill ace it's okay
and they don't there's there's a lot of
safer materials that won't harm the lady
beetles at all now they're a little more
expensive but they're really selective
because they act on you know they'll
usually be a systemic get absorbed by
the plant and then the aphid tries to
feed and such juices and the juices of
the plant and then the aphid dies but
not all systemic materials are safe for
example the most popular one is probably
the worst the imidacloprid and the
thymus toxin that group there are
actually very very toxic to all natural
enemies and so their uses their
widespread use of seed treatment is
another as a seed treatment is another
source of concern because again you're
you know that's basically a
scorched-earth policy you want no
insects on your crop
client you'll have no natural enemies
when the seed treatment wears off yeah
plus these systemic pesticides just
should not be used on edible crops
they're not they're not legal but for
people that aren't growing legally
there's a lot of concerns for this
safety and efficacy of them in terms of
consumers consuming or combusting a
final cannabis product yes yes and you
know I'm not sure about the regulations
and all of that but I can guarantee you
there's a lot of stuff you could use to
kill a fit so it's going to work really
well but you don't want that in your bud
yeah exam I know in Canada that's part
of their national program all that stuff
has to be tested the residues just like
food because there is that temptation
for people to use things should give
this I mean if you can use the stomach
insecticides Ava's aren't hard to
control but the problem is many of those
are some amongst the most toxic of all
insecticides you can go all the way back
to all the carb which is banned now I
think in most applications is just so
toxic to everything you see to be
systemic in a plant you usually have a
water soluble molecule that's more
linear so it can travel through the
plants vascular system that means it's
going to travel into you pretty easily
too yeah definitely yeah so you know
there's a lot of stuff that you shared
today that I had no idea about lady
beetles even more from more so than your
your keynote speech that's really
fascinating do you have anything else
that you just would like to share
regarding these lady beetles it's sort
of maybe some interesting facts or other
information before we sign off well
there's nothing wrong with the idea
about mending lady beetles in a
greenhouse setting but if we could get
some that were mass reared safely in
secretary conditions you know and one of
the candidates might be harmonious
Carrodus which is the Asian multicolored
lady ballistic tremendously a voracious
predator of aphids in so many different
cropping systems and I know it's present
in hop orchards and places like that so
it probably did fine in cannabis it
doesn't you know
has good Asians it'll go out almost any
plan but at these things would not be
hard to rear in the laboratory in large
numbers but the problem is you know I
don't know anybody that does it because
they can't compete with the ones that
are being wild collected yet no one
should be using but if you can rear them
there'd be nothing wrong with augmenting
lady beetles in a greenhouse if you had
a sustainable system and that's another
thing we don't know how sustainable all
that harvesting of the lady beetles will
be over in California eventually though
they may start depressing those
populations but yeah there's nothing
wrong with the concept of amending lady
beetles if you could have some that were
massive weird and you knew they didn't
have any parasites and you knew you
could read you knew they were young
beetles how old they were that they were
gonna start reproducing in a couple of
days and lay a lot of eggs all over your
playing and all that would be great but
I don't see that we have that system in
place so if you have an open system
where you can have devote a little space
to some floor of some floral resources
planning some floral resources you're
going to attract your own lady beetles
and you're going to attract a lot of
other beneficial insects not just lady
beetles that sounds great well I thank
you so much for your time today and
sharing this I love hearing your passion
for these insects it's really it's
really awesome yeah so thanks again for
your time and I hope to talk to you
again soon
oh it's a pleasure you can call me
anytime
[Music]
that was dr. JP Michelle and you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy don't forget to
check out our website at WWE
information and resources and links to
topics we discussed on the show today
please sign up for our newsletter on our
website home page so you can stay up to
date while you're there and give us a
follow on instagram @ k is organics
thanks for listening
[Music]