[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host
tadd hussey of kiss organics this is the
podcast where we discuss
the cutting edge of growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge
my guest this week is dr eleanor koontz
eleanor is a trained herbalist and
geneticist bridging the gap between
traditional herbalism and modern science
she is the ceo and co-founder of
leafworks a botanical verification
company using genetics to improve
medicinal quality
sustainability and transparency in the
supply chain
she is also co-founder of candor the
people's herbarium the first herbarium
committed to documenting and preserving
cannabis cultivars and varietals
along with the collective knowledge
gained through community engagement
this is her second time on the show and
if you are interested in learning more
about herbariums
we talk more extensively about it in the
other podcast
in honor of this podcast release we will
be offering 10 percent off on the
leafworks gender id kits through the
kiss organics website for a limited time
we talk about the benefits of these kits
and how it works in the podcast along
with other topics around cannabis
genetics
now on to the show hey eleanor thanks
for coming on the show
hi it's so great to be here yeah i
wanted to
uh start off you know the last time we
talked on the show we talked a lot about
candor and intellectual property and
those things and it was a great podcast
but i wanted to follow up with you and
talk a little bit more about leaf works
this time
so um why don't you you know why don't
you give us a brief overview of kandor
for people who might not have heard that
podcast and then we can really dive into
uh leaf works excellent yeah so camera
is
a cannabis herbarium it's the first and
only dedicated
cannabis herbarium and what that is is a
repository of
physical pressed specimens that help to
define
the diversity and the cultivars and
varietals or strains that we see
that have been held in the community and
have been lovingly not only
bred and differentiated but caretaked
by many many individuals over decades
and so candor is really a spot where we
can just look at those plants
and have a place where the community can
define the plants that they
are working with yeah i highly suggest
that people are interested in learning
about herbariums to listen to that
podcast because i learned a
ton of stuff there that i had no idea
about from talking to you guys
um and that's a separate project
yes it's a totally separate project it's
um it's really a project that grew
out of necessity so leaf works
at its core its fundamental core is a
botanical identification company
and so the entire goal of leaf works
is to know what you're buying selling
and growing
and that really extends into the entire
herbal market so the natural products
market so you know when you go into
a health food store or your local
grocery store and you buy
either a tea or a tincture or an herbal
supplement
you have a list of ingredients that are
in that product
and what we do is as a third-party
verifier we look at those botanicals
that are going into that product and
verify
if it says there's echinacea purporia in
there we verify there is in fact
echinacea propria in there and there
aren't any other plants in there as
filler
and so this is a really big deal and in
the
natural food space it's required that
you
have a third party or a verification of
the botanicals that are going
into your products you can't just say
you're selling ginkgo and then
you know sell celery instead
yeah and it's it's important because
in the botanical trade there's actually
quite a lot of fraud
which is i guess an unfortunate truth
and um some of this fraud is purposeful
so it's very much like we're gonna add
these plants into this mix because um
the
adulterant plants are cheaper and we're
gonna make some money
so a lot of the fraud is purposeful but
some of the fraud is inadvertent so you
have plants that are wild crafted or
are harvested and occasionally people
are going to pick the wrong things and
so
what we do is we work to identify those
botanical materials that are going into
products to verify that they are in fact
the thing that we think they are or that
they're you know that the label is
saying that they are
so when we started to work in cannabis
we realized
you know it's hard it's hard to do that
you know if you say it's bubba kush or
you say it's tangy or you say it's
cookies
how do you really know you're getting
that plant and so that's where we
started with
cannabis
and really looking into that and so as a
botanical identification coming
if we're going to make a test to verify
that you have ginkgo inside that product
the first thing we do is go to an
herbarium and get herbarium samples that
have been vetted by a botanist that is
an
expert in the particular plant of
interest in this case ginkgo
and when you use those herbarium
specimens as reference materials
certified reference material which is a
very important thing and not only
science but in the botanical trade
and so once you have the certified
reference material you can then use this
as your gold standard
to make in our case a genetic assay
that is going to identify that plant
based on a reference material that we
know is 100
the material we're looking for and so
when we moved into cannabis and we're
really looking to do this
value add for our cannabis customers and
our
growers there wasn't this vital resource
where we could find
certified reference material and so if
there isn't something out there what do
you have to do
you have to build it yourself and so
that's how candor came into existence
was
this lack of this very important
resource that the community really needs
in order to be able to empower
themselves to define their material
and so we really are just the vessel
that holds that information for the
community
so just to make sure i'm understanding
you correctly
like for example if someone wanted to
know if this plant was truly
let's let's just stick with tangie i
guess um
you would have to because there's no
good standard right now i would think
you'd have to collect a bunch of samples
that people say hey this i have a
true you know pure tangy
genotype here and then that would be
your uh you would kind of collect them
all and throw out any outliers and then
that would become your
the standard for changi moving forward
is that
how does this work in an industry where
we don't have
an existing standard i guess
yeah so for some plants it's very
difficult and other plants it's very
easy and so
if we're working so we worked a lot with
subcool before he passed
so that was a very easy way of defining
plants they were his plants he was a
breeder he was putting propagules into
the market
and so we took his plants if they were
cloned super easy we're going to take a
pressing of the clone we're going to use
that as our reference standard
a lot of his crosses were seed processed
so same mom same dad so we take
a sample of the dad we take samples of
mom and then we take a
panel of the siblings and say this is
the breath of diversity that now
is you know terrigasm or whatever the
the plant is that we were
speaking about in that moment and so
those those
types of definitions when you're working
with a breeder so we also work with you
know organizations like
humboldt seed company you know
organizations that are breeding and
putting proper bills into the market
it's a much more straightforward
cut and dry kind of definition
when you're working with things that are
like bubba kush or things that are
like community standards things that
have been traded around
and in the community for a very long
time
it's much more of what you describe what
we do is we take
many samples from organizations that
have held the material for a long time
we've taken you know all of the
information we have
where they got the plan how long they've
had the plant the
important characteristics that define
that plant
and we will take a wide swath of those
individuals
and then compare them to one another
and say okay out of these 80 samples or
10 samples depending on how great our
sampling is this you know these
let's say it's 10 samples these nine are
all
holding together and this one doesn't
fit and so we're going to throw it out
as an outlier
and so that's it's sort of like eating
an elephant you just start where you're
at and you get as much information as
you can and
you know you do this low hanging fruit
first the ones that are easier where you
still can communicate
with a breeder a specific person that's
doing that work
yeah and then there's other plans that
are you know sort of in community
you you have the community help you
you know you have multiple people who oh
i know i gave this to this person in the
80s or i you know
um of really good examples of harlequin
so wade laughter
is the original breeder of harlequin he
knows that he
gave some of those plants um to be sold
to herbicide during a certain period of
time so then i run into an individual
that's like oh i bought this plant
you know in 92 from herbicide then i
have confidence that it's the same plant
and then when we compare them we see
that yes they do genetically hold up and
they physically hold up when we compare
the herbarium specimens to one another
and the
you know characteristics that are
driving the phenotype of the plant
so it's a little bit of investigation
but it's really having the community
lead us to where we need to get
to make the definition of the plant so
can you know
it's a lot like any other plant yeah so
so basically can do can you say
that uh like let's let's just take the
example with harlequin um
you could you could say that a plant
then it does has no harlequin actually
in it like if they claimed it was a
harlequin cross and then conversely
uh if harlequin was derived and not into
the plant genetics like
some people are let's say it was derived
from another
cultivar originally another varietal
would you be able to see that
in the harlequin so you could say oh
this was originally pulled it had a
little bit of
you know cushion it or a little bit of
something else
or yeah yes you can definitely do that
and you need
you know you need a lot of information
to do that from genetic information but
yes that is part of what we do is
um you know some individuals would come
to us and say
i think i have this and then we make
sure we have enough of the reference
samples to be able to
investigate is it that and we can look
and see
if that is a possible parental cross for
a mystery plant or we can take a planet
where someone
thinks they have what they you know they
think they know what they have and then
we look at it and
you can say yes it looks like it is in
this line it looks like it is a cross of
these
individuals or no that we can't find any
evidence of
this particular plant in its pedigree
so this is kind of an off question too
i'm wondering
how often do you just see plants that
have the same
physical morphology or growth habits
that and
you know someone might think it's a you
know cookies for example and then you
you do the genetic testing on it and
you're like this really isn't
related to cookies or you know even
though it may look similar
does that happen yeah it does happen
it absolutely happens but the cannabis
is an amazingly
plastic plant so plasticity is this kind
of cool genetic term
where the environment really affects the
phenotype so you can have
the same phenotype looking very
different
in different environments and conversely
you can have a lot of different
genotypes converging on similar
phenotypes so there's a lot of
complexity and and one of those those
aspects is the plasticity of cannabis so
it's it's a beautiful aspect and it's
also a challenging aspect of the plant
yeah now i've been saying and maybe
you'll correct me here
that cannabis one is probably at some of
the greatest diversity we'll
we've ever seen and may ever see with
this plant just because of
uh this latest surge of you know
legalization
and breeding but i assume over time
with capitalism work and commercialism
we're going to see diversity
go down but it seems like we're at sort
of a peak
in that regard i'd be curious to your
thoughts on that
and then along those lines in terms of
in terms of diversity um
are you are you feeling like we're still
discovering new
things regarding the genetics of
cannabis and um
learning more every day or do you feel
like you're starting to get a handle for
what
what this plant contains
oh man well the answer to the first
question
cannabis is exceptionally diverse
it is sort of it is the
the best example of the more you love
something
the more diverse you'll make it i think
we have a couple of excellent examples
of humans
um in the plant world i think we can
you point to something that we just love
so much we really
make the diversity that we you know we
have access to
we we expand it and we explode the types
that we
um the types of plants that we have
around us
so yeah you can definitely see that in a
lot of our ornamentals but i think roses
is a big one
and dogs is another one right so yeah
i can take a wolf and make all of the
different breeds that we have
and you know it's just something like
anything that we love or find
useful um we as humans are very good at
caretaking things that can never
survive on their own and in doing that
we really do expand that diversity in
this immense and awesome way
and i think cannabis is absolutely a
really good poster child for that
the amount of difference that we have
not only in smells
and and statures and leaf shape
is kind of a mind-boggling and i don't
think we're at a limit i don't think
we're at the end of that
i feel like as we
not move away i don't think we'll ever
move away for growing
growing cannabis for its chemistry but i
think that we
will return to growing cannabis for a
lot of other purposes as well especially
as the hemp
movement gains traction
and that aspect of
agriculture expands i think we're going
to see a lot more diversity i think
we're going to see a lot more
cannabis and you know hemp same is the
same plant
so a lot more cannabis that is
specifically grown for
fibers or to be useful in concrete type
applications or packaging
applications and so i think we're going
to see a lot of
expansion of diversity in those realms
in the near future in addition to just
the fact that every time we look at
the plant we find more chemicals that
are doing more amazing things
you know it's like phcv or cbd you know
cbdg or
cbn or any of these compounds the more
we look and investigate the more we find
it's really this
treasure trove of amazing pharmacopoeial
chemistry that
you know as humans we really resonate
with with our own endocannabinoid system
so i think the diversity in cannabis
is only going to increase as we
understand it more and so that really
gets at the genetics
and you know we're really just at the
very very tip of the iceberg with
understanding
um the genetics of cannabis
one of the things i like to say quite
often is
really comparing it to corn so
when i went to grad school the
university that i was at
i think nadia just in the building i was
in when i was in the botany
i was in the genetics department um that
department i think had
seven labs working on course and then if
you went over to the botany department
you would probably add
five or six additional labs and then if
you went over to the ag department you'd
add five or six
more so you know you have 20 30 labs at
a single institution
that that work on corn and i think if
you
you know play that forward with cannabis
the same thing is going to happen
because we really don't know very much
prohibition has really limited our
understanding of the science of these
plants
and you know it takes a lot of work
to really drive down and understand
genes specific genes that are driving
phenotypes i mean we can get some broad
strokes pretty easily but
to really understand the interplay of
the entire genetic architecture so all
of the genes and all of the
other components in the genetics that
derive a particular phenotype
i mean that's years of research and loss
of mind
like time on task so i feel like we're
going to learn more and more
and the next decade is going to be a
very cool
time to be interested in genetics of
cannabis
i have so many questions
yeah so the one thing that you're your
recent comments uh just now made me
think about though uh
was a friend had sent me an article on
uh researchers it was in nature i can
post it on the podcast page and we're
done
uh of scientists uh brewing cannabis
using uh
beer yeast um the saccharomyces
cerviceae and
um i was wondering if you'd seen
anything on that because they're
actually able to
turn you know certain compounds into thc
obviously you're not going to get the
full
collection of diversity and compounds
that you get in a cannabis plant
i know as scientists a lot of scientists
are very derivative they're trying to
break down these you know individual
compounds like thc
you know we're seeing synergistic
effects between you know
different cannabinoids and terpenes and
how they all kind of play a role
together in terms of a
an experience for a user or a medical
a medical effect how do you think this
is going to change
you know someone who's a geneticist how
do how do you take an article like this
and how do you think that's going to
affect our industry
yeah i think it's been affected in a lot
of different ways but i really do look
to
the you know the precedent that's really
been set with
um herbalism and the natural products
world
we know that we can extract chemicals
from plants and use them in a very
pointed way
and as a site in my science brain i
completely understand
the need to approach things in that
derivative
kind of way and it's really just
to simplify it enough so that we can
understand
things about how chemicals are either
derived or how they're
specifically functioning within a
particular system or on a particular
cell type
and so i think those derivative type of
experiments that derivative or that very
like
let's look at one chemical at a time
kind of thinking
is exceptionally important to deepen our
understanding
but i don't necessarily think it
produces the best medicine
so i don't think that our you know
understanding and
utility are not the same thing in my
world
so i definitely have a deep appreciation
for that kind of work and the need for
that kind of work
but when we really look to something
when we really look at herbal medicine
in general
we often find that just because we can
pinpoint a chemical that has
80 or 90 percent of the effect on
whatever pathology
that we're looking at it doesn't mean
that it is effective
at curing the pathology
and i think we'll see that with cannabis
especially with the ensemble or
entourage effect with
the multitude of chemicals that are
acting in concert
i think it becomes so complex to really
understand
how all of those things are really
affecting
your you know positive outcome i
i don't think we're going to be able to
replace
the benefits of the herbal medicine with
a pill
i just and i don't think it's in our
best interest to do that but you're also
speaking to
someone who has a lot of faith and
i don't know confidence in herbal
medicine as
especially as a primary medicinal
modality
i mean western medicine is amazing at
what it does and
there's no there's no escaping the need
for like acute
medicine at certain times but if you're
looking at more holistic medicine
especially you know food as medicine and
herbs as medicine
for health and longevity and vitality
um you're never going to get that in a
derivative product
as far as i'm concerned and so you know
it'll be much like anything
sometimes we're going to be able to find
a single molecule that has like 90
of the effect to make something um
you know cure something or have you know
the positive medicinal
effect that we need but i don't think
that's going to be the norm
i think it's much more complicated than
that and
you know the chemistry of cannabis is is
radical
there's so many there's so much going on
i think that the plant the plant
medicine is still going to be really
important
and the plants themselves and i think
the industry can really lean on that
especially as we understand more and
more about
the diversity of plants how different
plants do better in different areas
right so we're going to start i think
epilations and the
and the real understanding of that
interaction between the genotypes the
different plants themselves and the
environments in which they're in and how
that really affects the quality of those
plants i think that's going to be
the most exciting information
that we you know dig into in the next
couple years okay
yeah i'm curious to see too i i mean my
brain was just thinking while you were
talking about how i could see
potentially people using
uh you know thc compounds derived from
yeast to boost their thc numbers
in their uh final product even if that
product had
oh yeah you know kind of like what
you're describing with the fillers
and uh the supplement industry at the
beginning of the podcast
yeah so yeah and i can see people
extracting terpenes not only
from cannabis from other you know if you
want something tastes like lemonade i
mean
you're getting from some citrus than it
is from you know i mean
i think there's a there will be there
will be
there will be a market for that and
there will be players do that feels like
the best solution
um and i think we're going to have
different quality metrics and that's
going to be a very
interesting thing to watch especially as
someone who sits here as like a third
party lab someone who is really trying
to communicate
the essence of the material that's being
sold so that
not only can individuals who have
special material
articulate that to their consumers but
so that consumers can start making
choices about what they want and i think
that'll be
the real power is how does the
consumer move the ball
forward right like does the consumer
want a high thc
product even if it means we're spraying
easter even thc on
on flour you know i'd maybe not
and so i think we'll be able to
i don't know yeah i don't know either
right like it's you know that some
people want to
when you look at the alcohol industry i
know this is not the best example or the
best parallel but
you know some sometimes you want a table
line and you don't care that it's
three different kinds of grapes and you
know it comes in a box
like that that's what the situation
calls for
and then other times you know it's
celebration and you want a very special
pinot noir from the wilmette valley you
know
and so i think we're going to have that
kind of product differentiation
and that's what's going to add in my
mind the value to the the smaller
family farm or the craft farm where
they're really growing a specific kind
of plant in a specific area
and the quality is what's going to drive
you know
the value of that product now using your
alcohol example i would look at it a
different way i would say
hey you know we have a market for wine
you know because i want a glass of wine
i don't want
ethanol you know like i want something
that has
flavor i want to have something that has
enjoyment i'm not looking for just the
effect of being like
you know inebriated so
that to me is sort of like a cannabis
versus
you know thc product derived from
another source i
but growing cannabis is hard you know
commercially it's difficult
so i i i do see where something like
this could gain
traction and it you know it concerns me
a little bit but
i was just curious from like a
geneticist perspective what you were
thinking so
yeah well there's this great little like
meme that's going around
about um you know potency and
effects and i think as we as
consumers get over the novelty
of being allowed to interact with
cannabis in a legal way
you know i think that novelty's got to
kind of wear off
so that instead of just having this
giddiness about being able to have
access
we can all of a sudden say oh it's not
oh i can get it it's
what do i really want and i think you're
right
i don't just want ethanol i would like
something that is delicious
and so i i feel like as we lose the
novelty
of
being able to access the plants
then we'll have much more of a
discerning
kind of um
pilot driven consumer
yeah but you know it remains you've seen
how it'll really play out but
i i don't think that everyone just wants
to get inebriated
for most people and you know and that's
it's also us growing up as a as a
consumer too
yeah learning about what's out there
it's hard to know what you want if you
haven't
had a lot of experience too absolutely i
was just going to say for folks who
haven't listened to my podcast with dr
ady ray where we
where she talks literally just about
this topic
and the idea of applying science to user
experience
and how thc is not the driver uh when
you start doing blind test
tests with people in terms of what
creates a better experience
it's really interesting i need to i need
to follow up with her but she's working
with uh you know jeremy
plum and uh stephanie barnhart and they
have a really cool thing that they're
doing in portland around
this concept so um yeah i will have to
follow up with her and ask her the same
question
um yeah i would love to hear
that follow up because it is true it's
absolutely true like right the teenager
is like yeah i'll drink some ethanol
but you know me i'm not
gonna do that so i i
completely am curious about how
it kind of um i'm curious about how the
education
of the consumer goes because that's also
a very important
aspect of you know deepening
understanding of the plant and the value
that differentiates different kinds
of growing methods and different kinds
of plants themselves
absolutely absolutely um
so there was something i wanted to ask
you a little while back here while we
were talking
i didn't want to forget um so as someone
who
loves growing tomatoes you know i will
choose varieties that
finish sooner you know i'll tend to
choose determinate plants depending on
how much
height i have um i'll look for things
that have some level of resistance
you know like uh may not be as likely to
get powdery mildew or
or rust or you know whatever whatever
crop i'm growing i look for those
you know disease resistance in the
varietals that i choose
for my vegetables are we making any
progress in that regard with with
cannabis
are you starting to see markers
associated with some level of resistance
to certain pathogens
yeah we definitely are slowly making
strides
the the hard thing with both
susceptibility and
resistance is that very very rarely
is it a single gene situation
where you know you have this gene and
you are resistant to this
that's sort of the exception rather than
the rule
and so those types of plants are going
to be
complicated to breed in a lot of ways
and especially because there's this
really interesting
and dynamic interplay between a lot of
the
the molecules we really like in cannabis
um that taste good you know a lot of
those are also
the molecules that plants are using to
defend against
their own pests and predators um whether
they be insects or
or viruses and and so
there is this this moment where
sometimes breeding
things to make them more resistant will
make them less flavorful
and i mean we see that in a lot of
plants and that's really just
understanding
understanding the plant and
understanding how to decouple those
things so you don't lose
you don't lose the characteristics you
like while moving the plant in a
direction that makes it more robust
to pests and pathogens and we're
definitely making moves in that
direction but i think it'll be a long
and complicated process
to really hone in on the nuances
of all of the different aspects of the
plants
especially when you're looking at you
know flavonoids and terpenes and all
those
taste taste molecules smell molecules
in addition to yield and
uh water you know water usage and you
know there's
there's so many things when looking at a
plant and
in a lot of ways we have as a community
a cannabis community
selected plants that are really great at
producing
the chemistry we want and not super
great at living
you know because especially if you're
doing it inside you can really baby that
plant in a way that
is just not going to work at scale and
so i think we're going to have a little
bit of a challenge to take some of those
plants that have been
bred in that extreme flavor
direction without any regard to
you know can the plants stand up on its
own like the plant might have
glorious colas but if the if the stems
aren't strong enough to hold them up
it you know it becomes more of a
challenge to grow and so i think we're
going to have to undo
some of those issues that we
inadvertently created
by growing in the styles that we've been
growing
through prohibition yeah
so two points i want to make one
resistance two is a sliding scale
like you may have a room with a bunch of
cultivars and one may be
less likely to get it or not display as
many symptoms too let's say botrytis or
powdery mildew
but that's not to say that if your spore
pressure gets high enough it's not ever
going to get it
so uh you know i think we have to be
careful with the word resistance
when people think of what genetics and
then uh
the other thing i wanted to mention
around it was um
oh just that uh you know when we when we
talk about this
this level of of diversity in these
plants
um it makes it makes
it makes it really hard to really know
what we're seeing over time i think so
um you know someone may say this plant
didn't get powdery mildew well
like i said you don't know how much
spore pressure you had in the room um
yep you know and yeah and maybe your
cover crop gets it but it's not the same
powdery melody that affects cannabis
you know there's there's all these
different variables so it's a long
i i totally agree it's gonna be a long
journey on in that regard
absolutely and i think that point that
you made is right
is hitting the nail on the head it's
it's just this dance between
you know something may not get root rot
but if you put it in standing water
it's probably gonna rot you know so it's
it's definitely um
that interplay with the environment
whether it be the number of pests or
kind of pests
and yeah some things are going to be
better equipped to deal with it but it
is
it is a scale so that's a very um
important point i'm glad you made that
yeah and i also you know you brought the
point of how we were breeding during
prohibition
well i think uh at that point in time
unfortunately there were a lot of
growers using systemic
fungicides so you were able to grow
these like massive
buds that literally would not get
botrytis because they had
you know your people were using eagle
20. uh and so
you just you cannot grow these things uh
to the same size and scale without
getting botrytis you know organically
for the most part so
i you know we're kind of working
backwards from some of that stuff too i
think
um i agree i totally agree yeah
and for some plants and you're moving
them outside it's going to help them
and other plants are just not going to
cut it they're just outside is going to
be
a violent and dangerous place for them
if they're not going to be able to
survive
so you know and that's and that's okay i
think we're going to utilize
the beauty of those plants and use them
in breeding programs and
and i think a lot of those a lot of that
diversity is going to help us
understand you know the
basically the genetics that underpin the
characteristics that we love
so that we can track those
characteristics down in plants that
are better suited for environments and
situations that don't
you know need massive amounts of water
or massive amounts of
fungicide i mean that's just not gonna
not gonna work
in a market where you're you know
testing your plants for
human health like yeah your uh your
outside
outdoor comment brought up another
question for me so i hear a lot of talk
around
genetic drift or genetic degradation
with clones
i've heard people say you have to move
you know take your clone and then grow
it outdoors
and read it every four years or whatever
length of time what are you seeing
you know with people who are cloning the
same plant over and over again are you
seeing
a lot of genetic drift over time or
mutation
slowly on a given you know clone
you know i don't think anyone has enough
really good data to give a robust answer
to that you do see something that drift
that is something we see like we'll i'll
look at clones or clone operations and
you know things aren't aren't 100
identical they're 99.8 or 99.9 percent
identical so
there is definitely somatic mutations
that happen
um i think that the the health and
well-being of clones though from
at least what i have seen in the in the
experiences that we've had at leafworks
and the groups that we've worked with
looking at this kind of question
most of the time when we have plants
that just aren't doing very well
and the idea of bringing them outside
it's generally pest
and pathogen load that's doing the
damage
it's not the drifting of the genetics
like the genetics are
similar enough you know 99.9 percent
similar
and there are other external
circumstances that are driving um
like the decline in the plants not so
much just the fact that it's a clone
okay so
i could see that yeah and i mean certain
things that are systemic that like
you know in terms of diseases that could
cause a a
different you know poor expression of
of that plant over time if you're if
you're cloning it i could definitely see
that
and just like anything if you're cloning
in and you have a plant that's 30 years
old you know i've had 30 years
to acquire bugs
along the way you know whether they be
viruses or
or you know just pressure from other
other
predators um
you know and a newly germinated seed is
seen as like a baby it just it hasn't
had as many
negative interactions to affect it
does extreme stress affect genetic
expression
over time like let's say you had a plant
that had huge amount you had a big
mite problem will that potentially cause
greater genetic drift
or other issues i don't
i don't from there's no evidence that it
creates greater genetic drift but what
it does do is it can
change gene expression
so anything that stresses a plant out
absolutely affects gene expression
and so that can be that can be positive
or it can be negative we have certain
medicinal plants that
you actually want to whack back or cut
all the leaves
right before you're going to harvest the
medicinal part of the plant because
the emulation of
predators like eating the leaves will
boost
the the production of the you know the
phytochemistry
that you're actually interested in as a
person using the plant for a medicinal
purpose
right and so that's an odd one where
predation actually increases
the chemistry that you're looking for
and that happens in certain plants and
i'm sure we'll see that with cannabis
you know heat stress is going to
i mean we see that with cannabis later
we already do see
yeah teeth stress makes them hurt and do
all these things
and so we definitely see um changes in
the gene
expression based on on stressors for
sure
but that's not necessarily going to
carry on to the next
um the next generation or even
necessarily into a clone like let's say
you had
a vegetated plant prior like before
cloning it
that um it just went through a variety
of stress let's say you forgot to water
it
maybe it got too hot maybe didn't get
enough light you know whatever and you
nurse it back to health
at that point you know i know as a human
like my cortisol levels have probably
gone through the roof and then come back
down but am i passing that on
to my children at some point when i have
to have a
have a child or like in this case if
you're cloning a plant is that getting
passed on
or is that just go away
yeah so it's going to go way more easily
if you go through a seed round
right because the genetics genetics are
transferred
um epigenetics so things that change
expression so like
change methylation patterns and and how
things are
are regulated that is much more um
damaging epigenetic change like
epigenetics
are not heritable in the same way that
stan you know like the dna
is heritable um and so
cloning though you're not actually going
through a gamete you're not actually
going through
you know sexual reproduction and so
cloning you can actually
carry those epigenetic changes
on for a lot longer right like some of
those changes are permanent and you
can't undo them
and so that stress really can affect the
plant more long-term
as a clone that's so interesting
you're just like you know like there's
these great twin studies that we've done
as humans where
you know one twin will smoke or one one
one trend will
run marathons all the time whatever it
is and and it changes
the epigenetic context of their genetics
diff you know so they have differential
expression of different genes and thus
have
differential health um as a result of
their actions and you know positive and
negative ways
and so i'm positive as we dig in
and and look more closely at these
things especially because we can look at
them with
the you know we have clones that's like
the best thing for a geneticist to be
able to understand anything
is to be able to look at clones and so i
feel like we're gonna
we're gonna understand more and more
about this
as we go but yes we can expect
that epigenetics will remain in a clone
a lot longer epigenetic changes will
remain in the clone a lot longer than
plants that are going through sexual
reproduction
that's so fascinating now before i
forget though i wanted to cover
sort of the elephant in the room we
talked about this in the last podcast
but
you know people are sending you plant
samples
uh you know t leaf tissue uh enough for
you to be able to do these
these types of genetic testing what
you know as a grower what are the risks
associated with that
in regard to protecting and preserving
intellectual property or that plant
themselves
that they feel that they have some of
ownership over
well leaf works is very very um
direct about their genetic our genetic
data policy so any plants that we
take in to do a test whether it be a
gender id test where we're helping you
sex your plants early
or other tests looking at
um different um either cultivar id tests
or sort of we do a double check just to
make sure that you have a plan you think
you have
all of this test we just run the test
and that's all we do
we also have a very robust genetic
data program where we
we work with a lot of different breeders
and growers
and look at the diversity of their
plants and we do different things to
understand the genetics that underpin
characteristics that those growers are
really interested in whether it be
flowering time or chemical production so
we do have an active research
side of the company but those research
projects
are separate from you're going to send
me your plants
to do gender id those plants don't cross
over
at all in our in our in our process
so we have a very um you know very
strict if you send us
something to do a test on that's the
only thing we do with that sample
and because we have such a vested
interest
in really promoting
the diversity that exists in the
cannabis community and helping those
individuals that have
taken the time to not only develop all
of these different
plants but steward them and
keep them safe and protected over the
you know over the last decade
we really work very very closely and
very hard with
organizations that have special plants
to define those plants so that they
can gain that intellectual property and
so i think that's something
that is confusing for a lot of people
like what
what is the intellectual property that i
own
as a grower or a breeder and and really
any plant that's been in the community
for more than a year
you can't own and that for the most part
is a really good thing
um and i think if we were talking about
any other plants everyone's like no you
shouldn't own plants but then
people get weird when they start talking
about cannabis plants
and there's this um there's this like
different attitude about these plants
and in order to really own a plant
you have to have done a lot you have to
have done work to breed something
special and unique and the best way
to define that is to define it in the
way that we define
all other plants which is to make
herbarium pressings
and write a botanical description that
enumerates
why that particular plant cultivar
varietal
is special and unique and what are the
characteristics that make that plant
special and unique and so
when we take in plants to do cultivar
registration
that's exactly what we do we take those
plants we work with candor to make
herbarium pressings
we do genetics that are then linked to
those herbarium pressing so that there's
something tangible
to link those genetics to right genetics
in a vacuum be nothing
i think that's really important so you
know if i go to my local dispensary and
buy a pre-roll and then sequence it even
if i'm the first
one to sequence that plant it does not
mean i own
anything right like it's kind of like
going to the store and deciding i'm
gonna buy
a gala apple and sequence it and then
tell everyone that i own gala apples
because i have the sequence of it i mean
that
doesn't really make much sense um but we
have this idea that that's how you gain
ownership of
of plants in the cannabis realm and it's
just it's a false
it's a false promise that i think a lot
of genetic organizations are giving to
people the sequence data really means
nothing especially because
just like anything i mean we look at the
sequence differences between
chimps and humans and right we're almost
the same at the sequence level
and that is also true with the plants
you have to really understand what is
the phenotype that makes this plant
different
um and you have to describe that
in order to gain any kind so the most
important thing in gaining ip protection
if you have something that is eligible
is to do
botanical description um the genetics
are kind of uh
the icing on the cake they're not you
don't need you need the cake
to do it you don't need the icing and so
the genetics really just add value
they're not the driver of any kind of ip
application that you would do for a
plant in general
okay so let me try and yeah let me try
and summarize my understanding of this
and please correct me anywhere in here
if i screw up so let's just say i'm a
grower and i have a very special plant
that i think
is unique and i want to preserve it and
have some love of ownership over it
because of the amount of time and energy
i put into breeding it
so i would at this point need to reach
out to a lab
and it has to be a lab that i feel
comfortable with and trust
i'd want to read their genetic data
policy so i know
uh exactly what they're giving me and
what i'm giving them
in regards to information and plant
material so
that would be the start and then in
order for that dna sequencing to have
any value it has to be tied to
an herbarium based on how
we currently value or view ownership of
plants so this is sort of unique to
plants as i understand it and then at
that point having those two things tied
together
and having this information from a lab
would allow me to have some sort of
legal framework
around which to show that that i own
this plant oh
oh and this plant also has to have not
been out in the world for more than a
year
publicly is that kind of covering that
those are the rules yes for plants and
and
and plants you know plant ip is not um
is not easy you in there you can get a
plant patent in there you have to
specifically show like how you've
altered it
um and it's generally for clonal
type propagation and then if you have
seeds and things
you can get plant varietal protections
which
you know so there's different nuances
and a lawyer is going to be able to
really articulate those
but the most fundamental aspect is
really the plant is the botanical
description so that's the same thing
like we went off into
some untarded territory and found a new
orchid
i think the first thing we're going to
do when we find that new orchid or
develop a new plant right just
breathe a new cannabis plant it's the
same thing so if you find this new plant
or breed this new plant the first thing
you do is do that botanical description
to describe what it is that's always
linked to a physical sample
right so you you have to have a tangible
thing to reference
and then the genetics really are just
the icing and the nice thing about the
genetic work that we do
with breeders is a lot of breeders want
to then license their plants to
different farms
so they go through this process of
writing these beautiful licensing
agreements they pay a lawyer a lot of
money and then
they don't have any way to enforce that
license
and so the genetics that we do are
really just a tool that then that
breeder can utilize
to audit you know they can they can
audit their grower are you growing the
right plants
are you giving these plants to someone
you shouldn't be now i can i can i
can sample those plants and say oh wait
these are my plants they shouldn't be
here
so you can really yeah that makes a lot
of sense your contract
instead you know so it's really just a
tool it doesn't
it's a valuable tool but it doesn't um
it doesn't like give you anything just
because you have the genetics right
because
anyone can sequence anything like
there's no rules about that
and around that note if someone sends
you plant material
you know we were talking a little bit
before the podcast about this uh you
mentioned this wasn't like a
jurassic park situation where you can
completely recreate this plant
and then start you know growing and
selling this plant yourself
the the sequencing doesn't give you
that kind of power um what what does it
give you
yeah so the sequencing gives you a
couple things the first thing is really
that like
that tool kit it's really a bunch of
tools so
genetics gives you tools to track plants
so
in this licensing example to be able to
track plants through a system
or through different growers it also
gives you the ability if you know that
this plant
smells like blueberries right you can
then utilize
genetics and compare some like compare
10 plants that smell like blueberries
to plants that don't smell like
blueberries and then you can
whittle down between that comparison
what are those things that are driving
the smell that you're interested in
and so once you have those tools then
you can look in
and you have to have your own breeding
stock right like you can't just recreate
breeding stock with
with genetics so if you have then you
can use those genetic tools to screen
your breeding stock
to find things that are most likely to
smell like blueberries if that's what
you're after
so it's really just a tool kit that can
help
facilitate and streamline breeding so
that instead of having to
grow a thousand plants and you know do
the chemistry for all of them
you can say oh out of these thousand
plants these hundred are
most likely to smell like blueberries
i'm gonna grow
them and focus on them and then you know
breeding is iterative so you're gonna
still have to do more work
on those plants to get where you're
going but what those genetics do
is they give you a tool kit to make it
easier
so the big issue that people had uh with
that company in oregon that was
collecting
people's plants and genetic information
to create
this uh collection was that
as a breeder if i'm giving you a plant
that i know is special and it's going to
have these specific genetic markers
that relate to its specialness whether
that's
resistance or thc levels or you know
some synergistic effect of all the
cannabinoids
you know as some as a lab that's
collecting all this information
you can use the data you know you're
getting a larger and larger data set
over time to where you can start saying
you know all of these plants
that people are saying are special for
this reason all have these same genetic
markers
i'm going to work with a breeder now and
say
hey we're going to breed until we get
the same genetic markers and now
we have an advantage over other growers
because we can use this as an extra tool
is that does that kind of summarize what
what the
the anger and frustration was associated
with i think the anger and
yeah absolutely and i think the anger
and frustration really came from
being duplicitous about the intent
and um selling a product that was sold
at or under cost not because you wanted
to sell a product but because you wanted
to gain
genetic information right it's different
when you're working with a breeder and
you're saying oh we're going to do this
project together
and we're going to push your material
forward and this is this is how we're
working in synergy with one another
that's a very different model then i'm
gonna take all this information from
individuals that may or may not want
to help that cause and i'm gonna
i'm gonna shift my i'm gonna shift my
direction
as an organization and at first i'm
going to tell you that i'm doing
i'm i'm asking genetic diversity for the
greater good
and then you're going to shift your
business model into i'm going to be a
producer of propagules and i'm going to
compete with my customers
yeah i think it's a tricky
yeah it's about what you're doing
and it's about um you know if you're a
breeding organization
that's fine but present yourself as a
and i think that's the issue is um
like nobody likes to feel like they've
been duped and nobody likes to feel like
they're dealing with someone who's
duplicitous in their
intent and so i i feel like that's
really where the anger came from
um because no a lot of people would
still work with you if you say this is
what we're doing
you just have to be like straightforward
about what you're doing
and with this particular organization i
think the anger really came from
saying a certain set
of things in community settings
and then saying a very different set of
goals
when it was coming time to talking to
their board or their investors
right like if you're whatever you say to
whatever you're saying to anybody about
the trajectory of an organization
it should be the same no matter what
room you're in
if you're in the investor room or if
you're in your client room or
you're in a community room and i think
that's the issue
is um yeah it's just not being
straightforward
no one really likes that yeah i did an
interview with reggie gaudino
uh when he was with the cso at steep
hill labs and he was very
clear about the fact that they are
collecting this data and
you know what their potential plans were
for it but he also said you know they
could get bought out by
dow at some point and that data might be
used for something entirely different
and
that's something you need to be aware of
and a risk associated with
who you choose to work with but
ultimately as a grower
or breeder you're going to have to pick
a lab at some point if you want to have
this genetic information so it's a
little bit of a catch-22 and
for me this happened to me in my
industry so
my father did a lot of work in the
infancy infancy around
compost tea in terms of paying a lab to
do a lot of testing around
you know how does
water quality affect what microbes are
grown out in
you know in our brewer or how does
changing these designs affect the
microbial diversity or the food sources
you know is e coli able to grow in this
in this brewer under these conditions so
any
you know spent oh tens of thousands of
dollars on all this testing
and then you know a few years later this
particular lab
started selling compost tea brewers and
i was very
very frustrated because all of us had
been using this lab to do
testing as sort of an independent
resource and now we were competing
directly with them and they had a huge
advantage of having all of our tests and
information
so i completely understand that's the
situation
that happened and i think it's important
like when you're looking for
a genetic testing company what
so one of the things i'm so proud of
about leaf works is
our core mission is to help individuals
define the plants that are in community
so it's doing cultivar registration
and the more of those cult of our
registrations we can do where we have
vouchers and we have histories and we
have breeding pedigrees
what it does is it immortalizes those
plants in the community such that they
can't be stolen
right you can't say that this is a
unique plant that makes cbdn
or whatever and all plants that make
this chemical
i now own with this utility patent i
mean some of the utility pens that are
being put out by some of the other
genetic companies that everyone is
working with
are so super overreaching and if they
would just look at
the resource of the herbarium or would
look at
the cult of our registrations that
leafworks is doing you would see oh
that patent is actually in violation of
you know all of is or is not appropriate
and i think that's part of the
problem if you don't have resources for
patent
lawyers who are you know looking over
these applications to say that it's an
overreaching
patent like there's not the information
you know you tell them this is the only
plant that makes this
this particular ratio of chemicals and
they grant you that patent and then i
have someone over here that has a plant
that has a completely different
evolutionary background is a different
plant that makes the same
pattern of chemicals like that would
prove that that
was you know that particular especially
the utility patents
should be you know vetoed should be
thrown out
and so we have we have a dearth of
information and so that's one of the
things that i'm
so proud of leaf works for doing is
the work that we do to define genetics
helps to preserve and empower those
people who have been holding those
plants to be
able to continue to use and breed with
those plants
so you can't have someone come in and
say oh i own this plant now so you can't
grow it anymore
because we have proof that well you
can't own it because this has been in
community or this has been
bred or this is a different version of
the same thing you know whatever the
story is that is gonna
give the power to know that those plants
are
out there and that's part of the problem
because we don't know what plants are
out there you can have people say this
is unique and special and i own it
as opposed to you know there's these
utility patents it's like
um between two and five percent thc
and between 12 and 16 cbg
if it has that ratio i own it and it's
like there's more than one
evolutionary background that can produce
that chemistry it's like
but it's hard for for people who are
assigning
you know it's i i understand
the patent lawyer right like that
doesn't know exactly how to
judge these patent applications so i
think that we're gonna have a lot of
things thrown out but
um documenting what we have is one of
the most important ways
to make sure that we have access to our
material long term
okay so what you're saying is it's not
so much about owning something
but it's about keeping community access
to it so
other people are going to be collecting
information and potentially trying to
claim ownership over it but by having
you know candor
and leaf works doing this work
potentially it allows the community to
continue
access to these plants without paying
patents too so it's not about just
having a special plant
but it's about protecting our rights to
all of this diversity and all these
plants is that
is that right absolutely okay that's
interesting okay i never looked at it
quite that way so
yeah it's both sides right it's and i
think the tomato
community has a really good framework
for this where you can breed tomatoes
but we have a really good understanding
of what tomatoes are out there and which
ones
have patent protection and which ones
don't
and if you breed something new you also
have a way
to articulate that it's new like the
rose society is great like if i
if i breed a new rose they have a
registration of you know the thousands
of
rose cultivars that are out there and
they can say oh guess what this one
is unique you can give it its own name
in its own
you know story around it um and so
that's another important thing you have
to have this
this reference in order to be able to
articulate that it
is something new and novel
that's great well before we run out of
time you know
i wanted one of the questions i had i
want to talk to you about was the
advantages of
gender testing so you offer gender
testing you list in your
genetic data policy that you destroy the
samples
they're not associated with the uh
the other aspects of your company around
the research program
so um can you talk a little bit about
why someone might want to do gender
testing
in terms of an roi or the advantages
around that yeah absolutely so
if you are growing from seed there's a
lot of different
reasons why you'd want to do gender
testing the first and foremost is of
course you can know
the sex of that plant seven to ten days
after germination so as
as soon as you can take a little tiny
piece of that plant or a little piece of
the cotyledon
and not kill the plant you can know what
what the sex is and that's great because
depending on how you're growing in your
growing style you can
you generally save when we do our return
on investment analysis
you save between 20 and 30 percent on
your
on your grow based on not having to
spend
the time the way on the labor the
materials of repotting and transplanting
taking care of those plants until they
show
until they show their sex the other
really great advantage is if you know
which plants are girls and you're
keeping only your girls then you can get
them into their final resting spot
earlier like their final pot and so you
don't have this issue where
you're like waiting for them to show and
then they're getting root bound and so
you just have healthier plants
because they're getting into their spot
earlier their roots are going to be
healthier
and healthy roots of course as we all
know makes healthy plants
the other thing that's really nice is
you
you know especially with organizations
that have square footage requirements
you really make sure you're using your
space
in the best way you're not using some of
your space to grow boys that then you're
gonna have to
fill in with female plants after the
fact so you're really
maximizing the number of plants that you
can get into your space that can be
productive for you in your in your
production
um yeah and plant count numbers for
people dealing with that too
on the flip side medical grower um
totally yeah it's so weird it's funny
i have a couple groomers that say the
funniest things like i have one
swami i don't know if you know this um
wonderful
human but he said the funniest thing
he's like i use you because i'm too old
this excess plants and my eyes aren't
good anymore
i don't know if i can put that on the
website but it was another reason why
why someone is using them he's like i
just have to
he's like this is such a waste of time
to have to walk around
and look at those plants and then my
eyes just can't always see them
well enough so you know there's all
kinds of reasons
yeah i do see people all the time online
asking you know is this a male
is this a female and then you'll see a
variety of answers a lot of times
um underneath in the comments section uh
and
you know at that point you've already
put in you know two three weeks into
this plant
uh so i think the time savings is the
big one
uh you know i'm so excited so we
recently ordered some cards
uh we are going to be offering them
through kiss organics
as another service you know to be able
to purchase these gender id kits and i'm
really excited to work with you guys on
that
uh full disclosure and um
yeah so the price just for people who
are interested
in just listening to podcasts and might
want to know more ranges
it looks like from 10 to 15 a plant
um you have a card the minimum would be
four plants so you're looking at sixty
dollars to try it out can you talk about
what the process is for someone who
receives a kit
in the mail absolutely yeah so we do
have variable pricings if you're doing
it at scale we of course want to help
you out and
it helps us out to be able to to do it
in bulk and so we give you a discount on
on bulk orders and when you're receiving
um your kit what you get is a collection
card
and on that collection card you're going
to take a little tiny piece of that
plant and you're going to
press and squish i like to actually use
the back of a sharpie marker to rub
back and forth over that card to really
press
that plant material onto the card and
all that juice is really going to soak
into that
special paper that dna sticks to and it
breaks down
proteins and then you just send that
card back to us and what we do is we
just take a little punch of the card and
just do a
simple test and we use multiple markers
which is really nice and that's
something that's unique
about our are sexing
is that we have five markers across
the y chromosome that we look for
instead of just using one
most um all of our competitors are just
using a single marker
and that's important because not all
males have all of the markers
we have a lot of diversity in cannabis
as we talked about
and so we really wanted to make sure
that we
offered the most robust tests and we
weren't missing any males and that's why
it was really important for us to have
multiple markers that were spread out
across that y chromosome so
we never missed anybody and so we take
in that card we take a little piece that
paper
we do that essay and then we let you
know via email
um which plants with which tags are
um male and female
great that makes it really easy um
you know when i first started looking
into this and
wanting to offer a gender id kit uh you
know you go online and you see other
kits that are
less expensive and then i think you were
the one actually that had to explain to
me that
uh you know those kits you actually have
to have a lab or other tools in order to
really process them can you touch on
that yeah
yeah so um you can buy a i guess there's
one that's like five dollar sample but
you have to actually have a pcr machine
and you have to do the work yourself you
actually have to do all of the
the lab work which of course requires
a 15 to 40 000 machine and a person that
knows how to do pcr
and a whole bunch of pipe headers to be
able to do the pcr which are you know
several hundred dollars each and so
unless you're really you know
equipped to put a whole lab on your
farm it's not really the cheap
solution that you think that you think
it is
um because you do need all the
infrastructure in order to be able to do
the test itself
that's great yeah that was just
something you know when you do a quick
google search
it's not very clear the difference is
there yeah i just wanted to mention that
for people
well i appreciate that because it's
funny it's like oh but we can do this
for five dollars it's like yeah but do
you have a pcr machine
yeah and like how many of them you have
to do and if you were like oh i'll buy a
pizza like well you have to do
500 000 of these to break even now
so you know it depends on you know if
your farm that's doing that
it might be worth it but i don't think
that everyone is at the scale
where it it breaks it breaks the
i don't know it breaks even very easily
yeah so for people that want just the
gender id this is a great way to do it
um
what what is the process for someone who
wants to
be more involved with uh you know the
cultivar
registration side of things what does
that process look like
so this is a wonderful thing so if
you're a breeder you have a special
plant
you can do a cultivar registration on
your plant but if you hold
like we have also individuals that hold
these immense collections
so they're not breeders they just have
had these plants for a long time
and we also do cultivar registrations
for them where we take in the plant we
do the botanical description
and we then take it and look at our
other reference material to make sure
that if they say it's plant a it is in
fact plant a
and this has been really um good for a
lot of reasons if you
are you know a breeder it makes sense
that you're defining your material and
you're getting all those ducks in a row
to really
have the documentation you need together
if you're a collector it's also a really
good way
to understand the plants you have
especially if you're someone who grows
plants in multiple locations
those cultivar registrations and that
process can really help you
understand like let's say of three farms
which farm is the best to grow what
plant
and so there's a lot of additional
benefits and that sort of plays in and
dovetails into a lot of the work that
is is coming into the epilatory
frameworks that are happening around
not only california but are um starting
to
to percolate in other states as well
and so that that cult of our
registration is really a
a great way of documenting the plants
you have
and being able to leverage that
information to
the best use for your organization
yeah i'm looking at this page right now
and it's pretty interesting the amount
of information you get about a
particular
cultivar what would i so two questions
one what would i send you in order for
you to do this service
and then two in regards to this service
i see you don't have any pricing are you
able to give a range of sort of what
something like this might cost or is
that
uh yeah something definitely yeah no i
definitely can so if you're registering
a single plant it's
5 500 to do a single plant and if you're
doing multiple plants that price goes
down
we visit the farm or we send you
a kit such that you can do the herbarium
portion yourself
and making the pressings and then we
have our staff botanist
take that information and write that
botanical description
we take in pedigree history and we do
all of those um
those aspects of the registration and
basically present to you and you know we
do the genetics
link those together and then we present
to you it's almost like a little
magazine
that pulls all that information together
and is this little
document that you have
in order you know to share about the
plant itself
um with other people customers other
other people who maybe want to grow your
plant if you're a breeder
and then it also gives you that tool set
with the genetics that are linked so
that if you have any additional
utility you can utilize those tools to
let you know track your plants um
articulate what's interesting about them
you can use it if you are going the ip
route with your lawyer as part of your
docket
all of those components can then be
utilized for those purposes as well
yeah i highly suggest that people go
onto the leafworks website and
look at the cultivar registration page
just because it's a really interesting
the way like you said it's almost like a
little magazine about the
about that particular plant in this case
your example is a pistachio chai
it's just kind of interesting to read so
even if you don't ever plan on yeah
registering a plant it's just kind of an
interesting thing to look at
yeah and the nice thing is where this is
going and so let's say we've
registered pistachio chai and now i'm an
extract maker
and i'm buying pistachio chai flour from
a farm
i can now take my flour and send it into
leaf works and verify that i have the
plant i say i have
that i can put a little leafwork
certified feel on my
product whether it be you know vape pen
or
some rosin or any other kind of product
so that then i can convey to my
customers
exactly what's in that label and so
we're really moving towards
bringing cannabis into the fold
and and treating it just like we do the
other plants such that
you know especially if i'm a product
maker that's one step away from the farm
it's a way that i can have assurance
that i'm getting the flower i i think
i'm getting i can have some assurance
through a third party
that you know not only is it the flower
i think it is but it's not you know
cut with trim from something else and
then i can also convey that to my
customers and you know as we get
just like we were talking about earlier
as we get more and more refined
in our own consumer
desires being able to really articulate
what plant is
in the product and having the customer
have confidence that they're really
getting what they want
it's going to be beneficial for everyone
so let's say that i've made
a pre-roll with a certain plant
potassium chai
and then you have made this beautiful
extract
if i know i like pistachio chai and i
see these two products they both are
leaf beef work certified it is that
plant in the product
i'm more likely to buy your product
because i know i'm going to like the
plant
and so what it does is it gives this
confidence
and it's a confidence that's then shared
between brands and so it increases the
brand equity because you know
that that label means something
so along along those lines
i assume um it's a lot less expensive
to do uh a check on a plant than it is
to do this whole registration what does
something like that cost
if if you wanted to just you know check
to see if the genetics match what you
thought they did
of something you'd already yeah so just
doing a double check
yeah so a plant double check is 250
for a single double check and then of
course if you're doing a excuse me if
you're doing a bunch of double checks
we we sell those in bulk as well okay
and then if i did go down this let's say
as a grower you want to do this cultivar
registration is there any risk
of you know potentially losing that
plant
to the lab like could you take what you
are collecting and somehow
grow out this plant through tissue
culture or some other methodology
um no we yeah we just the only access we
ever have to the plant is through the
herbarium and it's dried plant material
so you can't really do anything with
that other than
reference it um long term so you can't
tissue culture it you can't grow it up
um if anything what it is is it's a
it's a immutable reference that you can
point to
to make sure no one else is stealing
your stuff
okay and then last question for you is
there any way to view
some of these registrations like to wait
and know that like if
what i'm trying to create as a as a
certified reference material has already
been created or
uh if there's something yeah well you
can always contact yeah you can always
contact leafworks right now
um we've been talking about how to
present that in a more
user-friendly way and that requires a
lot of web
um web design alteration as maybe
maybe yeah so that's something that
we're talking about
um we've done quite a bit of work with
the humboldt seed company and their
plants
um mostly we're working with them on
doing feminized feed certification so
people who really want to know that
they're buying feminized seeds
that certification is important to them
and so
we um that's probably the first thing
we're going to put up as a
list of referenceable lists so you can
see um which cultivars from which
organizations have been certified
um with the feminized seed sir and then
as we do that we'll
we'll grow into adding those cultivar
registrations but you know it's this
weird
interaction between um privacy for our
customers
but then also getting the word out so
we're
we're figuring that out right now you're
hoping to somehow
in the future uh make some of this
information more available to the
cannabis
community that sounds like oh yeah
absolutely
absolutely yeah it's absolutely our goal
especially as we start to get
um you know plants that are really
utilized by a lot of different people
you know i know a lot of the biovortex
seeds are grown by a bunch of different
farms and all kinds of different
products are made out of those plants
so being able to reference the cult of
our registrations
of like black dog for instance and then
see oh you know movement is growing it
and making these beautiful pre-rolls and
you know bryson bracelin family farm is
is making well extracts and so that is
absolutely
the the shorter long-term goal for that
that whole process cool well i thank you
so much for your time today
i really appreciate i hope people uh you
know found a lot of this information
useful and uh i really look forward to
working with you
in regards to offering these gender id
kits
yeah me too it's exciting to get it out
to more people and help them
streamline their process that's why
we're here
[Music]
that was dr eleanor koontz co-founder of
leafworks and candor
don't forget to check out the podcast
page at www.kisorganics.com just click
on the learn tab
then podcast we are also offering 10
off on the leaf works gender id kits on
our website for a limited time in honor
of this podcast
these kits are highly accurate save you
a ton of time on sexing your plants
and they also store great if you wanted
to get some for a later date and don't
need them right away but wanted to take
advantage of the sale
and if you haven't already please take a
moment and leave us a comment or review
on whatever platform you listen on
i do take the time to read them all and
appreciate the feedback
you can also follow us on instagram at
kis
organics to stay up to date on the
latest podcast releases and information
thanks for listening