foreign
[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad Hussey
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawing top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge my guest this week is Dr
Daniela Vergara she's an evolutionary
biologist data analyst educator
scientific writer and public speaker in
addition to her multiple Publications
she founded and directs a non-profit
organization the agricultural genomics
Foundation agaf aims to make hemp and
cannabinoid science available to a broad
public Dr vergar recently joined the
Harvest New York extension team from
Cornell University as an emerging crop
specialist to help hemp Farms with their
crop Dr vergar's scientific Publications
include the comparison of the
cannabinoids by the federally produced
cannabis to that produced by the private
Market these results were featured in
news platforms such as the Atlantic
science and 538 recently she published a
comparison between the Genome of these
federally produced varieties to the
Genome of the varieties found in the
private markets some of our other
scientific Publications are a
compilation of the existing genomic
tools available for cannabis research
that was featured in science and the
maternally inherited genomes
chloroplasts and mitochondria Vergara
has authored these Publications along
with collaborators from the private
sector in the Cannabis industry as well
as academics from several institutions
worldwide through agf Vergara educates
the public about science data and
Analysis statistics evolutionary biology
and genomics now on to the show
hi Daniella thanks for coming on the
show today
hi Taz thank you for having me yeah I'm
excited that we're getting the
opportunity to talk why don't we start
off by giving listeners a little bit of
your background
[Music]
virgin crop Specialists and I am working
with
um M and Ops
um and I am a lecturer at the University
of Colorado in Boulder where I was for
eight years
um as a researcher and I still have some
uh ongoing research projects at CU
Boulder as well
okay so let's talk a little bit about
what that role is exactly as an emerging
crop specialist what uh
what does that mean like what's your
day-to-day look like
my day-to-day it's very flexible
um
but I have to go to meet a bunch of
people in New York state that are
related to
um the Cannabis industry
um for example Growers that are
growing uh cannabis work multiple
purposes whether it's for cannabinoids
or for fiber or for grain there's not a
lot of people growing for brain for
example but that's something that I hope
changes but also uh figuring out how to
help the industry Thrive so people that
are processors or I had a great meeting
last Thursday or Friday with this
company that has that they're doing
biochar and they're doing vinegar and so
they're now trying to do it with him and
how to figure out how to get all of the
Cannabis according for waste from these
um Growers into their facilities and and
make possibilities right and if you're
growing cannabis for cannabinoids your
stocks could be huge
um you can have these these massive
plants so how are you gonna
get that stock into tiny little chunks
what sort of equipment you need in order
for there to go to this machine that is
called a killing machine that makes the
vinegar and the biochar so we were
thinking about those things
so a better use for all the biomass
that's produced
during cannabis production
yes
so so because
because for fiber is getting a lot of
traction and there's companies that want
to get hemp for fiber and so you in
order for you to make a t-shirt
you need a facility that it's a big
facility and it's a multi-million dollar
facility how do you establish that and
then farmers are not going to start
growing hemp for fiber if they don't
have a buyer but the buyer is not here
because no one is producing it so it's
kind of like how do you break that
chicken and egg situation
um and also for grain right so now
there's people that are interested in
Grain but not a lot of people are
producing grain so how do we get that
started
so your role is to sort of support the
entire industry and make connections for
folks as a way of of sort of building it
within the state it sounds like you and
I haven't really talked about your role
exactly this is sort of off the cuff
we've been talking more about your
background in genetics which we'll get
to here in a second but I was curious to
learn just a bit more about exactly what
you're doing
and you you said it yeah and get
established connections and then put two
plus two together and figure out how
we're gonna get so for example with this
company it's like okay really what we
need to do is a transportation company
we need trucks to go from one place to
another and then is that profitable
right taking out all of those waste and
if you're in one side of the of the
state which for me New York state is a
new state I I moved here recently but if
you're in one of the corners of the
state for example in New York City does
that make sense to to take all of the
waste to let's say Buffalo right yeah
um so so figuring those things out but
basically that is my role right now I
think we're now yeah wonderful wonderful
very cool now your background though is
is wildly different with your background
in genetics
um I recently listened to one of your
webinars and uh do you want to just plug
the webinar series really quickly before
we talk about your webinar um so folks
can can learn about that
what I talked about in the webinar well
can you talk just really quickly about
what the series is that Cornell offers
for folks like I was able to listen to
this for free
um to your your webinar but there's
other ones that you you guys put on
as well so that one particularly was
between the USDA and Cornell it was a
collaboration and it was a webinar
regarding
um cannabis in general so there were
people talking about the economics
um there were people talking about uh
how you process it
um and I talked about the genetics part
but
um but yeah there were
multiple different talks it was I think
it was every other Wednesday for four
months the the spring semester and so
there were multiple talks in multiple
different subjects regarding cannabis
and the videos are all now on available
on YouTube I saw on YouTube exactly so
folks can check those out I'll put a
link in the podcast if people want to go
back and see what was offered there from
uh Cornell in the USDA and thank you I
didn't make all the webinars but I was
able to attend yours where you talked
about uh cannabis genetics and some of
your research that you've done around
cannabis genetics
um can you talk a little bit about some
of that research and what your findings
were
absolutely I mean I I will I've been
doing that for eight years so there's a
lot there's multiple
podcast contents that we can have
regarding all of my findings but uh but
yes so what I what I did and what I
continue to do with the University of
Colorado in Boulder
um is looking uh The genome the entire
genome so it's basically more genomic
genetics because genetics is more
looking at particular genes but genomics
you look at the entire genome
um and look at uh the different parts of
the genome right because the genome is
composed of multiple different parts
um you have for example that repetitive
contents of the genome which people call
the junk DNA which you know it's
repetitive right so you have a bunch of
things that look alike and are
pardon our founding scattered throughout
the genome
um so we have a paper trying to describe
the the repetitive contents of the
genome that was published I think that
was 2019
um I looked at the
um uh the cannabinoid genes I have done
a work in the hanabinoid genes as well
and looking at how these cannabinoid
genes
um
have different copies the different
varieties different strains
varying the number of copies of
cannabinoid genes that's something that
I did as well also characterizing where
do these different varieties fall right
like are all
um I don't know blue dreams related to
all blue dreams and all of the
um I don't know Girl Scout cookies
related to Girl Scout cookies and we
find that that's not necessarily the
case there are some for example Durban
poisons the ones that we sequenced right
when you sequence a genome you take all
of the
letters of the DNA and you kind of
transcribe them and then you compare
them right so you compare for example
yours and your daughters and you see how
similar they are and then you compare to
me right and you're gonna find that
yours and your daughters are much more
similar than either of you are to me
um well we found for example that
strains that are named
um Girl Scout cookies they may not be
related at all
um and strain can I ask you a question
about that now when you talk about
cookies I think of a very distinct
morphological plant structure like it's
gonna it's going to like I can look at a
plant and say okay that that probably
has some
cookies genetics in it or something did
you guys look at that by chance or were
you strictly looking at at the genetic
code
we were strictly looking at the genome
and then how were you determining
whether or not a plant fell into
was being classified as Girl Scout
cookies for example were you going just
strictly off how the name was listed or
known publicly based on how people were
describing it either the breeder or
grower or the grower yeah they would
tell us what is it that's okay
yeah
I you know that would fit with sort of
what
I think a lot of people think
anecdotally is that you know these names
these cultivars are not necessarily what
we thought they were
um yeah so your your findings on that
was essentially that
just because something was named Girl
Scout cookies didn't actually mean it
was related to other things named Girl
Scout cookies
exactly were you able to determine
exactly what was truly
you know in this case that particular
Cult of our goals Girl Scout cookies did
you have like a known
a known one that you could work off of
work backwards from I guess
so we had multiple Girl Scout cookies
and what we found is that these Girl
Scout cookies could be related to
something else there was one in
particular that was related to a strain
Jack Herrera we actually had two strains
that carrier that were not related to
each other
to each other as well so
so this is my take-home message right my
take-home message and when people ask me
about it what I tell them is look
go to a dispensary get whatever it is
that works for you whether that's name
Girl Scout cookies or whether that's
name pen doesn't matter
uh and if it works for you for whatever
it is that you're using it whether it's
for sleeping or especially for medical
patients right because if you're doing
it recreationally I mean I hope that you
have fun with whatever it is that you
got to take but if you're for medical
patients then go back to that same
dispensary and get the same thing
whether it's called again Girl Scout
cookies or pen get it again and then if
you go to another dispensary
um try to ask for the same thing and use
it but chances are that you're not gonna
get the same effect the chances are
pretty big so you're not gonna get the
same effects
now I
you know you and I can see each other
right now and I realize uh listeners of
the podcast don't know you're holding
you're actually holding up a marking pen
and that's what you're referencing pen
is the other name
um but I I guess I would take it a step
further I wonder so if you go to the
same let's say you go to a dispensary
um
and get Girl Scout cookies
couldn't that girl scout cookies from a
different farm at the same dispensary
give you an entirely different effect
and then to take that even one step
further couldn't that same Girl Scout
cookie plant
that was grown in another facility exact
same cultivar or even the cultivar
within the same facility if it's grown
differently you know under different
environmental conditions whether that's
nutrients media if the farm changes
something if they have uh you know
changed their lighting couldn't that
also affect your your expression Cameo
expression to where as a medical patient
you're not going to get a consistent
response and so it becomes really
daunting to really know
what's out there at all I guess
that is a great question and so you're
going to somewhere any physical
characteristic is a product of genes and
environments right yes
um so nature and nurture
um there are some physical
characteristics that are more
environmentally determined there are
others that are more a genetically
determined for example weight is a
characteristic that is very
environmentally determined depending on
how you eat weight can change or not
right so yield in this case too if we're
talking about cannabis
is more Perhaps Perhaps but we don't
entirely know we know that cannabinoids
there is a big genetic component to
cannabinoids we know that but we don't
know how much of the cannabinoid
phenotype is genetic and how much is
environmental we know that it's there is
a genetic component and we know that if
your parents
so for example there's this paper from
2014 by Nora volkov the Nida
um the head of naida the National
Institute on drug abuse I really like
that paper despite its name its name is
something like the harmful effects of
cannabis and they never really talk
about the harmful effects of cannabis
but they have a really good figure that
shows how THC
um amounts have increased through time
that makes us think that breeders and
Growers
have used
those individuals that have the most THC
to be the parents of Next Generation
offspring that makes us think that
cannabis is that that THC is a heritable
component in cannabis right so in humans
for example height is extremely
heritable if you're tall it's likely
that your kids are gonna be tall is
something like 80 heritable the other 20
is environment if you didn't eat the
right uh food especially when you were
growing up you're not going to achieve
that amount of height that you could
have if you had eaten the right
um diet right so with cannabinoids we
think it's similar you have the
potential of producing a bunch of
cannabinoids depending on your genes but
you could achieve it depending on
whether you have the right soil the
light is super important
um right so so the right conditions so
we do know that there is a identity
component but uh but it all depends on
the environment
now if we were talking about another
crop that wasn't cannabis something
that's you know understood genetically
like very well
like corn or corn you know some other
major crop wheat whatever whatever that
may be
can can you give us more could you could
you give us more definitively an idea of
how much is heritable in terms of
characteristics versus how much is
environmental is the issue I guess my
question really is is the issue the fact
that there's so much diversity in
cannabis and we don't really know so
much that much about it or is the issue
just plants in general
when it comes to understand genetics
like this
no I think it's cannabis
this because I mean for multiple reasons
right
the eagle for so long because kind of
has not been
cultivated
um in um
in a very scientific manner right
um with corn for example we know that
there are particular cultivars that are
for sweet corn right
um and so there is a genetic component
to it
um now
again we know that in cannabis there is
a genetic component to it if you are
gonna cultivate for cannabinoids for THC
or CBD you're not going to use a fiber
cultivar right so we we know that that
exists now
for example the word cultivar means
individuals that have been cultivated
for particular reasons and I don't think
that we are there in cannabis right so
we can see it in in
at least in the Cannabis industry for
for recreational purposes for for
marijuana you can see that these names
do not mean much and the names also in
the castle hybrid they do not mean much
either so that's why for medical
patients that's what I recommend go to
the same distance the same thing because
you know that hopefully it's going to be
the same grower that it's going to be
using the same soil or or cocoa or the
same nutrient regime
um and hopefully it's going to be the
same variety right it's gonna be a
mother or or the daughter of that mother
plant right so so you're expecting it to
be consistent at least with that same
dispensary
yes as I was ex this was explained to me
the term cultivar is really the best
term to use for what we're talking about
with cannabis you know sort of what
people are calling strains because it's
really a cultivated variety
um which is how cultivar was described
to me by my uh Bonnie professor which
allows like he's me it's my mnemonic for
how I remember that it's not really
varietal it's a it's a cultivated
varietal so it's a ver it's a cultivar
yeah but then you're expecting it to
have particular
phenotypic characteristics right so
you're expecting it to have for example
I don't know the stock diameter is blah
and the height is blah and the
cannabinoid production is black so you
know exactly what you're getting right
so I usually talk about dogs because
people you know people care about dogs
and people I guess but when you think
about ashiwawa you are and I tell you
Chihuahua you close your eyes and you
picture ashiwawa you do not picture our
Rottweiler yes so they have been bred
for this particular
conditions which we do not have in
cannabis right and something that we do
find looking at the genome is that there
is a lot of variation right and if the
word on the street is right that for
example
Camp dog number one and can cancel
number four so number one was the first
seed that popped or the first one and
then Ken book number four was the fourth
one but they are siblings and yet they
have entirely different phenotypes
so you have full sibs that are entirely
different from each other and that means
that there is a lot of variation that
it's out there and that when you're
doing crosses you don't know what to
expect when you are crossing a female on
the male and I think that that's why
it's so popular to
to have mother plants and to do cloning
because then that way you are having
more consistency right because the
breeding has not been
um done in a
enough inbreeding for multiple
Generations you don't you don't find
when you talk to to people in the
industry it's like oh yeah it's you know
like four generations in breeding and
it's like well no you need several
generations to assure
that there's going to be homozygosity
which means that you know the gene
coming from Mom and the gene coming from
that are going to be the same that
they're going to be homozygous right
um so so you need multiple Generations
uh of inbreeding that has not been done
you know maybe 20 at least
at least eight or twelve and that is not
common so you get a bunch of different
things when you cross two individuals
like 12 Planters or plant you know high
cannabinoids or cannabinoids right
so in order to be a cultivar it needs to
have a consistent
expression is essentially we're saying
and we're not there yet
um it wasn't part of the challenge then
for breeders the fact that the general
population you know its consumers are
constantly changing
uh what they want chasing these you know
what people call hype strains this idea
that you know
there's always something better around
the corner
yes
uh
and that's why you do Fino hunting
uh right
however that comes with a cost and the
cost is the lack of consistency and the
lack of
if you have a limited amount of space
and you cross these two plants this
female and this male or or use reversed
this female and you're Crossing them
and they're awesome both of them are
awesome
chances are that
their kids
could there could be awesome kids I'm
not that awesome right you can have some
offspring that are not that cool and
then if you have a limited amount of
space you have to choose which ones
you're gonna be
um planting which which seeds you're
gonna be popping and and maybe you
didn't pop that one seat that was the
coolest one so
so yeah so consistency brings
consistency when you have inbreeding
then you are assuring that all of your
individuals are going to be the best
you bring up this the challenges around
breeding um
now genetics and testing have allowed
have allowed shortcuts in this process
um some of which are more controversial
than others uh with with Growers now
I could at a very relatively young age
know the gender of my plant or no get an
idea of what the uh
phenotypic expression might be right
from from testing if we look at the at
the genetic sample
um you know I'm not and this is not
talking about Gene editing at this point
um what what tools are there out there
to Growers
um that is that are not I guess Gene
editing
well I don't think that we're engine
editing yet
although
it's coming though right it's coming
yeah yeah I mean for any for every crop
right for the strawberries that you had
this morning in your cereal yeah for
Rice yeah
um
but um but there are certain tools look
sex in sex determination sex expression
in cannabis is another big kind of worms
um because
you can sex reverse them right
um and so if you put in I don't know
collodial silver or silver nitrate they
can produce flowers from the opposite
sex
um or atop and in males they can produce
female flowers
so even though there's an accidental Y
chromosome like cannabis has an x on Y
chromosomes like we do and we do think
that the X and the Y chromosomes in
cannabis
um are very important
to establish sex but we also think that
there may be other genes somewhere else
related to sex expression because even
if you are on xx and they put silver
nitrate you can produce flowers of the
opposite sex so
even if you're not lacking a why right
and there's multiple companies out there
that um
that they have feminized seats so they
take a female they stress it or put
colloidal silver the female produces
male flowers and then they use that
pollen to either self-fertilize that
female or to fertilize another female
and then you're assuring that there's no
Y chromosome right so even if you have
that sometimes you can even produce male
flowers right so it's likely that the
genes related to sex are found somewhere
else in the genome that are not
necessarily DX and the white chromosomes
um I don't know why I started talking
about sex but okay gender identification
at earlier stages we don't have to
flower a plant out to determine its
genderness
yeah exactly whether you have
there are
so yes that is possible that doesn't
tell you whether that individual when
stressed out is going to produce flowers
of the opposite sex it doesn't tell you
or if that individual is a monishes it
doesn't tell you that but it does tell
you whether it's gonna have it has a why
so those are available there's also uh
tests related to cannabinoid production
and whether your plant is prone to
produce cannabinoids or THC at least
um yeah there there are some tests
available are there any available right
now that can give us an idea of terpene
expression is that's become
much more important I think to
cultivators
um not that I know of I may be mistaken
but um so we don't know that the genetic
markers for
pining or limonene or any of these
different
um
terpenes that you're aware of
with terpenes
there is something that we call
pleiotropy on epistasis and they are
interacting to to produce the phenotype
and that means that there could be one
gene that affects multiple traits
or that there's
um
one trait that is affected by multiple
genes
okay right the opposite so it's not this
causes this it's a more complicated
picture
yes and there is a paper that I really
really like by uh Jordan zagger and his
in from Washington State actually yeah
in Oman and he's a his advisor uh Mark
Blanche and they are proposing that
there is this network of genes which I
think that it's very accurately they do
more of mathematical models and stuff
but I I do think that that depict not
only that terpenes but also that can
happen it's right it's this complex
network of genes that are acting
together right now I'm working on a
paper
and although I'm using
only nine individuals total because for
those nine individuals we have like the
entire genome placed together that we
have the entire puzzle so we were able
to count the genes and to look for the
location of the genes but what we found
is that
um well yeah there are multiple genes
that are related to cannabinoid
Productions
um and for example there's this one
individual cannotonic
a and these individual kind of tonic has
truncated to an incomplete CBD Gene and
also an incomplete THC Gene however it
produces CBD and THC
so
there
that suggests right like this is not a
definitive answer but it suggests that
there are multiple other genes that are
affecting the production of cannabinoids
despite the canonical THC and the
canonical CBD there's other multiple
genes that are affecting the the
production of these cannabinoids
interesting I actually had Jordan on the
podcast to talk about his paper around
powdery mildew and a marker that they
had found on that so folks could check
that out now
from what you're saying it it sounds
like there's there's quite a bit we just
haven't figured out about the Cannabis
genome and how it's expressed
um what do you think
what do you think the future holds in
terms of research
oh there's so many things
so many things I mean all of what I said
about sex right like where are the genes
that are related to sex determination
all of the what I said about
cannabinoids right like um
are these genes interacting how are
these genes related to the expression
when you grow I mean good conditions or
in bad conditions how do the Expressions
differ and then or terpenes right
um and also
um
when do you express certain traits for
example in in interpense or in sex right
when when would you express like we know
that if we
poor colloidal silver or silver nitrate
then it expresses the male flowers but
I am applying that chloridal server
in nature when why would you do that
like what is the advantage for you to be
producing flowers of the opposite text
so so I think that there's so many
questions about it and right now for
example we do not have an assembly is
when you take the genome right when you
have all of the genome all of the DNA
letters and you transcribe them you have
to chop him into little pieces and then
you have to put them together
um and so we have assemblies that are
pretty complete
however we're lacking the white
chromosome and we're lacking Dominic's
chromosomes so we still need to complete
those
um we haven't done it yet so we're still
figuring that out and uh and the end for
terpenes right some terpenes are
produced when under stress like if
you're being eaten by a caterpillar then
you produce a terpene
um so when are these serpentes produced
how are they produced
[Music]
um
if you are the same variety do you put
those different opinions on why
um
and
um yeah all of all of that part like the
phenotype
there's still still a lot of work to do
in the phenotype like and then you put
the genotype and thoughts even more and
then you put expression and that's even
you can add more and more and more
layers
do you see us eventually
understanding cannabis as well as we
understand a crop like corn or is it
just too much genetic diversity and
since we're chasing so many different
I guess medical therapeutic or
recreational
outcomes with this particular plant that
will never get the stability to really
get the that would then further lead to
the research that would allow us to like
completely understand what's going on
no I think so yeah we have enough tools
we have genetic tools we have smart
people I do think so that that's gonna
happen
um I think that much faster than it
happened to many other crops because we
have the tools available and it has been
done for other crops right so it's kind
of like taking what has been done in
rice or in tomatoes and then applying it
uh I think
the other thing in cannabis is that
first
people think that they're gonna make
money
right now like okay like this is it and
I'm gonna make money tomorrow and
science is slow and breeding is low and
bringing differs depending on the
environment right
whatever you have in Oregon may not work
here in New York whatever you have there
in Washington
where you are may not work here or may
not work in Colorado right
um yeah as a cultivator we see genetics
plays a you know a significantly
heritable role when it comes to
um disease for example well and yield
but I mean particularly disease you know
we'll have
um with an outdoor crop or even with an
indoor facility and there's certain
environmental conditions you'll always
have certain plants that will thrive in
certain plants that will suffer because
most Growers I know are running you know
20 30 sometimes 40 different cultivars
or more
varietals whatever you want to call them
in their in their facility or in their
field and and we do see that certain
you know certain plants will suffer more
than others and certain plants will
thrive in the exact same
environmental condition
so we know genetics plays you know a
fairly large role right I mean we don't
know exactly how large but
pretty large what interests me I think
is figuring out how if we took
particular genetics
um
how we maximize the genetic potential of
that plant so if we took you know
whatever you mentioned you know chem dog
number four figure out exactly how that
plant likes to be grown that we could
cater our lighting our nutrients our our
media
our environment to really optimize
whatever particular cannabinoid
expression or terpene expression that we
that we really want from a plant like
that to me is is really
the most interesting because right now
as a grower I'm just trying to create
conditions that are optimal for most of
my plants to at least achieve a certain
amount of yield or a certain expression
that I know that the general public or
the the medical community is going to
want to purchase right
mm-hmm but yeah you know how do we take
that a step further to where we really
dial it in by you know eventually a
cultivar but let's say a varietal
um
how do we get there what's that process
look like
complicated question but I do
think that if you're growing indoors
it's much easier right because
you have uh the environment is constant
and what I've seen for example I have a
friend in
in Denver what he does is that he has
his set conditions and this is the light
regime this is a nutrient regime and if
this variety does well here perfect if
not you're out like he doesn't adequate
the nutrients and over that conditions
to the variety but the opposite so there
are only certain strains that he grows
um which I think it's pretty smart you
know like he already has this
this figured out like okay this is going
to be the light this is going to be and
then he brings varieties or not
um so I think that that is pretty smart
now if you're growing Outdoors then it's
different right then that's then that is
where where things get complicated
um because as you were saying there's a
bunch of
there is a there's a bunch of things
that can happen right
um and disease is one of them for
example that you can't control indoors
much more than Outdoors right so so you
need to figure out which ones are those
individuals that are resistant and cross
cross those and then that means that you
need to do some sort of inbreeding
because if you're Crossing those and
then again what we were talking about
there's no one breeding so you can get a
bunch of different things and height
differences and
all of the phenotypes can vary
um so let's can we talk a little bit
about phenotypes so you you'd written a
authored paper uh called widely assumed
phenotypic associations in Cannabis
sativa lack a shared genetic basis
can you just touch on sort of what your
findings were with that
that was a nice paper
the paper I want to give a shout out to
Ben Holmes from Centennial seeds and uh
Front Range biosciences because he made
that possible and he's um known breeder
in Colorado
um
so
we measured a bunch of different
physical characteristics of phenotypes
in these individuals
these were across if they were a cross
between a hemp type and a marijuana type
so we measured a bunch of different
traits I don't know height pedial length
Leaf shape we have three different
cannabinoids and we found that they are
not correlated so
you cannot correlate the leaf shape with
um percent
THC or you cannot correlate height with
Leaf shape or right so you those are
completely not correlated so
there are
people in the industry that can say for
example oh this smells like I don't know
lemon or this smells like Pine and
therefore it was tall and had broad
leaves which it's not the case right and
how I say it in
how I explain it to people is that you
cannot
you cannot say oh you're tall because
you have blue eyes those traits are
completely not correlated or you have
brown eyes and therefore you're blonde
right like those things are completely
not correlated
um and so in the industry for example
those things oh it's a broad leaf and
therefore it's
this type of strain and therefore it's
this grouping it's a hybrid or it's an
indie car it's as a tiva that doesn't
that is completely not related
whatsoever you can have individuals that
have broad leaves and have high THC or
individuals that have narrow leave and
have high THC or individuals that are
tall and have high THC or individuals
that are short and have high THC that is
completely not correlated at all
was there anything from the physical
characteristics of of a plant that
correlated with the medicinal
therapeutic side the cannabinoid terpene
you know any of that side of things
nothing no
I mean we do see correlations between
the cannabinoids right the cannabinoids
are very
all of these genes are acting in unison
all of these genes right they have the
same precursor molecule which is cbga
right so cbga them mother cannabinoid
they all of these different enzymes thca
synthase cbda synthase cbca synthase
they act on the same precursor molecule
so we do see correlations between the
hannabinoids which is expected right but
not at all between height or video
length or Leaf shape or nothing no thank
you
interesting interesting so
yeah I don't really know what to what to
add to that uh other than that they're
just there's no correlation so we can't
look at a plant physically and have any
idea what's going on
internally in terms of what it's going
to produce is
found out yeah these physical traits you
have to measure them right you have to
measure the THC the CBD and then if you
do
breeding you can have
oh narrow leaves with all of your plants
could be narrow leaves all of them could
have like this really thin narrow leaves
and all of them can vary in the amount
of THC that they produce right and
that's so I have been asked before these
questions like okay you found that there
I had this other paper with the Leafly
with the people from Leafly where we
looked also at the sativa Indica hybrid
and we found that sativa Indica hybrid
has no correlation with the cannabinoids
or the terpenes that the plant produces
right
um
and we we also know that the genetics
right that the genome does not correlate
with the Indica sativa hybrid we also
know that what I we were talking earlier
that
you can have a strain named Girl Scout
cookies and another strain named Girl
Scout cookies that are not related at
all whatsoever
um so when
when people ask me like okay so what
does this mean and that for me it means
that if you have a
High Times best strain
that was this I don't know this
um purple haze or whatever this
Tangerine Dream
then change the name and next year just
call it
pen
and it can also be the High Times best
strain because that doesn't mean
anything the names do not mean anything
names do not mean anything when it comes
to the plan okay no no Market it again
and then call it something else like
that is my advice right
it is really challenging
um
it's it's unfortunate because I think
some of the
the oral histories around some of these
plants is is fascinating and it's
something that I'm trying to dive into
in another podcast right now
um unrelated I mean it's not scientific
at all but I think the Stories Behind
These plants is really interesting and I
think that all gets lost
as we move towards people you know just
renaming things and everything just
being jumbled and we don't really know
what's what out there in the industry
um unfortunately
but that's a that's another issue
but I don't think that we're gonna know
on their genomes
that create
barcode or these phenotypic barcode
right and and that's why I think that um
testing facilities and reliable testing
facilities are really important because
you go there and you know that this has
however much mercine and CBD and CBD
enterpinoline and et cetera et cetera
and then you can create kind of like
this phenotypic barcode for your strain
and then if you sequence it then you can
create this genomic barcode for your
strain right and I don't think that
these names and you know so and so was
in this concert in 1991 and blah blah
blah and that's how this
that's
that's just an anecdote
it's totally an active I just think it's
uh some of the stories are interesting
you know purely is anecdotal stories you
know entertainment
um but one thing you brought up was the
labs and I think that's a whole nother
issue is lab reliability I know in
certain States as emerging States came
into play the labs that gave the highest
THC percentages were the ones that then
survived and people would use because
they you know the cultivators could
market and sell their product for more
or the labs that were passing people on
heavy metals were the ones that didn't
that people used because you know it's
it so it becomes all economic at a
certain point and I think that's where
it becomes really hard to use any of
that data for science because
there is so much variability even on the
lab side I would argue
I agree and I disagree with what you
just say I agree because I know that
that happened
and I can tell you
which ones to go to in the boulder
Denver area like I I know that right and
however however
uh this paper that I was talking about
with the people from Leafly Nick Jacobus
and and Christiana Smith
so it's a paper that was actually
published this year
between a yeah Christiana myself
um Brian Keegan who's a professor at CU
Boulder and he and I have this is our
second paper together and uh nickomas
saw the four of us and what we did is
that we analyzed all of the strains from
Leafly all of the chemotypes and we
looked at cannabinoids we looked at
terpenes we looked at correlations
between cannabinos and terpenes between
terpenes and then you know the names so
so this is indica or this is sativa this
is hybrid and we we did this beautiful
statistical analysis and machine
learning analysis and the figures are
beautiful and I love the figures because
I did the figures so and I hope that
people like the figures because it took
me a long time to do those figures to
make him really pretty
um so
in the paper
Leafly works with six different Labs
across the U.S there's a lot in
Washington state Oregon I think
California uh Florida Michigan so
there's labs in multiple different parts
of the US
and something that we measured was how
different the labs were and the labs
were very consistent between them
despite one of them being in Florida and
the other one in Michigan and the other
one in Washington state they were very
consistent so I was and I was very
positively surprised because
despite the Cannabis industry being so
differently regulated everywhere despite
cannabis being still federally illegal
you have these Labs that are very
consistent and you have these people are
doing wonderful jobs and
you know like
I like
I want to congratulate these people
because they don't know each other
they and and they are
putting out very reliable results so but
you still have those labs which as you
just mentioned you know like so-and-so
will spot your THC or so on so we'll you
know we'll give you a pass on heavy
metals you still have those so also I
think that we should congratulate deeply
because Leafly now knows they have
really high standards and they're really
good at betting who they're going to
work with which was in a way my
take-home message like Leafly knows who
they're working with and legally knows
consistent results
so so there there are possibilities out
there as well
these weren't
six randomized Labs then they were Labs
that were vetted and are using the same
Sops correct better by Leafly I don't
know if they were using the same Sops I
know that they did have different
equipment I think you know like it's not
like everyone had Agilent where everyone
had shimatsu
um no but they uh they were Labs that
were vetted by Leafly and Leafly just
chooses those labs in order to gather
data their data yeah okay well that
makes sense well you know I got to
figure there's good Labs out there just
like there's
good cultivators that are following the
rules and there's other ones that are
you know spraying illegal pesticides or
plant growth hormones or things that you
know are not safe for humans so I just
think that's human nature
um I think Labs have potential but I
think we have to acknowledge that
there's challenges with lab testing as
much as there is with genetics and
diversity and everything else that's
going on with trying to better
understand this plant
yeah yeah no that's true you know
there's good restaurants and bad
restaurants yeah
wonderful well
um was there anything else that you
wanted to share regarding you know the
research you've done or anything that
you're really excited about in the
upcoming year uh related to the industry
so uh I don't know when
this podcast is gonna be
I also worked on the
varieties produced by the National
Institute on drug abuse Nida
um I have a paper on 2017 regarding the
phenotype where we compare the
cannabinoids of
um varieties or of strains that you can
find these dispensaries to those that
are produced by Nida
and then uh on 2021 we have the genome
we looked at the genome from
from
um naida's varieties I'm gonna be giving
a talk uh at the end of August regarding
that
um so the take-home message is that you
know Nida varieties are not
representative of what people are using
um neither in the phenotype nor in the
genotype right like varieties are
different than because Nida has this
Monopoly where they are the only ones
that produce the Cannabis that is used
for medicinal or
or a research right medicinal research
or or any sort of scientific research so
um naida's varieties are different from
everything that people actually consume
um so I'm gonna be talking about that
so if the plants that Knight is using to
it are used for
do they influence National policy or are
they primarily just what they're
supplying to the scientific community
um so so it does influence policy how
how does that work if they're plants
that they have are so genetically
different than what everyone else is
consuming and using
or is this just typical government uh
bureaucracy
I mean
how could that be
um
how could how could that research be not
biased right like how could you have
research that is reliable when you are
producing the varieties for research and
your weed is completely different from
everyone else's right so how how is your
research reliable what are those
differences then out of curiosity
um
in respect to cannabinoids
uh they have very little variation
so the diversity of cannabinoids is much
a less so less diverse and the amount of
cannabinoids is less so it's less
um THC less CBD
more CBN
more of the breakdown compounds so CVN
is actually significantly more and then
regarding the genome which was the the
2021 paper
they are different from everything else
right it's like
you know like they tell you
um you can study dogs but you can only
study Labradors forget about the
chihuahuas or French poodles or right
Great Danes you can only study this one
thing that's it right so so it's
completely different from what everyone
else is consuming okay and what are the
implications of uh really high CBN
relative to what is on the market
so CBN is a breakdown product right on
CVN accumulates usually when you have a
lot of heat when you leave your cannabis
in um for a long time long periods of
time it accumulates and um and then it's
usually that cannabinoid that gives you
the headaches
um or usually that that it kind of like
makes you drowsy
um so that is the cannabinoid that
um that night that has a lot of
interest and it gets expressed you said
from heat stress
no so it's a breakdown product so THC
um turns into CBN
CBN it's actually
um an oxidation process oh okay THC
turns into CBN and uh
um you know like something else that I
think
that is going on in the Cannabis
industry at least in the
yeah in the legal markets is that people
really put a lot of effort in producing
really good weed right and in marketing
themselves as you know like mines are
the stinkiest or yours are the prettiest
or minds are the tallest or yours are
purple right and it's this competition
in making the best weed how am I gonna
differentiate myself and my brand and
and making the best weed and then you
have Nida
producing the cannabis for research
which is not the best not diverse not
potent with a lot of breakdown product
like and that's what scientists have to
study
right so
yeah I don't know a lot about the
medical chemical side that's never just
that hasn't been my area of Interest as
much
um do you see the CBN thing is
interesting to me though so do you see
that
still existing in the General Market in
just much lower levels
a plant expression so like
when I go to a dispensary for example
I'm not going to necessarily when that
plant gets oxidized I'm not going to get
a headache because I'm not going to get
as much the same levels of CBN that I
would from a say a Nida plant
however if you leave
in your garage
the entire summer and then you know come
October you take the nug it's it's
likely that the THC would have converted
into CBN oh okay
I didn't I didn't know that that's like
I said that's not something I've ever
looked into so I'm sure there's a lot of
listeners that know exactly what you're
talking about right now so but hopefully
there's some like me that are learning
something right now and that's uh really
interesting so thanks for sharing
sure yeah well I I really appreciate
your time I know it took a little bit to
get on this call together with our
schedules
um but I really enjoyed it and and thank
you for sharing some of your research
and knowledge and I hope we can stay in
touch and talk again soon
yeah thank you thank you very much for
having me on this this was really fun I
I'm glad that you learned something new
all right have a wonderful day
thank you
[Music]
that was Dr Daniela Vergara and you were
listening to the Cannabis cultivation
and science podcast if you like the
podcast please leave us a rating and
review and give us a follow on Instagram
you can also sign up for our newsletter
on our website homepage to stay up to
date on the latest research and
information thanks for listening
foreign