[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge this
week's podcast is all about pest
management and is the second part of my
interview with Kelly Vance if you
haven't listened to the first part I'd
suggest checking that out first and you
can learn a bit more about Kelly and his
background in horticulture and
integrated pest management now on to the
show
so uh getting back I had this list of
questions and we keep we can already
kind of been floating around I've known
I've enjoyed our discussion I go into
the rock yeah I want to talk about your
experience in coming from large green
house and production setting like what
practices did you see that you were
using on the horticultural side that
hasn't really made it into cannabis that
you think should should be implemented
um you know I used to say and I will
I'll go back to help I'll just repeat
the crop staging just because I I
believe that all things that fundamental
things need to be repeated until you get
annoyed with them because at that point
is concreted into your head crop staging
is one I use to say quarantine although
I am starting to see more of it so I'm
I'm actually really excited to see that
and in fact the grower who was the
absolute best at it that I ever met
after two years of practically begging
him now works for us
that's our Repsol who I was working with
at the time that he's a large green
house cannabis operation in Salinas and
he had a whole greenhouse set up for
quarantine of incoming plants dip
dipping protocols I'm sure that you guys
have talked about dipping on the show by
now and actually quarantine after the
fact before any of these plants go out
in any of these greenhouses but I still
see tons of people especially this time
of year the early beginning of the
season they're bringing in plant
material from all over the place
sometimes I've had them tell me that
yeah I know that I got I know that i got
my russet mites from XYZ and then the
next year they buy from the same person
and okay let's pretend they're the only
source you still need your plants but
you haven't implemented some kind of a
quarantine when you know for a fact that
you've had issues from these so that's a
huge one and one that I see a lot of but
not enough of - when you consider the
value of this crop is just general PPE
in the greenhouse and
I don't know what the proper term
because all of this falls under cultural
control in the in a tired old IPM
pyramid but um you know you just don't
see any control of who's working in what
area and then moving to other areas I'll
say that sometimes I ask growers to do a
little more than I used to do in the
greenhouse but I because we didn't
really a lot of this stuff it wasn't
like we had it running like a Swiss
watch in my greenhouses we had very
chaotic days where I would end up in
every greenhouse by the end of the day
but for the most part we had our stock
fuchsia greenhouse which is those were
our mother plants so I am NOT going to
go spend all day in the Sun bersia which
I know are crawling with spider mites
and threats and then go work in the
stock fuchsias that I see plenty of
people in cannabis grows and when you
get into an indoor cannabis grow I'm
sure you've been in enough of them like
these guys are paying a lot for that
facility so they're trying to use every
square foot for plant canopy as possible
so like unless you are a teeny tiny
little person it's impossible to walk
through one of those rooms without I
like to say getting getting to know
their plants so there's no way you're
spending all day in this room that has
spider mites has athens has whatever and
then you're going to go work in the moms
for the rest of the day taking cuts that
to me is just like a no-brainer but it's
very frustrating when I see it happening
and you see these small facilities that
just keep recycling their problem yeah
Justin Justin has a good analogy for
this that kind of liked he looks at like
a river so he always starts at the head
of the river like the area that has the
least amount of pest pressure you know
like your mother in theory should be
your cleanest part you know and
propagation that needs to be the
cleanest part of your facility and it's
the easiest area to control because you
have the least amount of canopy so you
should be able to keep that area clean
and then you work your way through and
end you always end in the flower room
because these are your oldest you know
probably most stressed finishing plants
that are going into senescence then
those are the ones that are gonna have
in theory the worst amount of bugs
that's the first thing that when when we
visit whether it's a farm or and it's no
matter what the crop is no matter what
the layout is the first thing that we
ask is do you have any areas that are
really infested and if they say yeah we
should take me there last you know and
one of the things that that we try to
stay on top of is we try to keep our own
PPE on us as well so a lot of times if
we show up to a facility a lot of times
they provide you a Tyvek or you know at
least a lab coat or something to wear
occasionally you know you get there and
even I've done it where even the the
growers themselves aren't wearing this
stuff I throw it on just because I don't
want to be for one I might be visiting
three or four operations that day and
for another I don't want to be two
months from now when you have a problem
and you start thinking yeah but it was
that bug guy he walks around at bugs all
day and he came here and walked around
in our plants so uh yeah that that I
like to tell growers try to have I like
the river analogy I might uh whose was
that so I can properly credit them if I
use it my buddy Justin I think he met
him at the biocontrol conference he was
yeah yeah yeah yeah anyway so I just
would add like for me when I go visit
these facilities I'll only go to one in
a day and I'll make sure I'm putting on
clean clothes fresh out of the laundry
clean shoes especially like I'm not
going to take I'm not going to go walk
around my farm and then go visit a
facility and then it I have had to visit
two facilities in one day and I
literally did a full clothing change in
that case and especially my shoes not
because you know like you said you just
don't want to be a potential vector and
a lot of places don't I find don't have
tae Baek seeds or PPE and I you know
frankly I don't know that that's a
complete solution I think it's part of
the picture like we want to do
everything we can to reduce transmission
but I think every facility should just
plan on getting bugs plan on getting
you're gonna have to deal with rude
aphids and ham press it and thrips and
all of these things don't think that any
facility is immune from these so you
better have a plan ahead of time and you
should I think bowel controls are a
great preventative maybe we should talk
about that a little bit just because you
don't have insects now doesn't mean you
shouldn't be using bio controls now it's
a perfect time for bowel controls right
prevention is the key for us to have
success and it is it's one of the things
that you have to maybe slightly relearn
or at least learn from a different
perspective if you're switching from
conventional pest management into bio
control is but it is funny though
because I do recall back to my days of
doing a lot of spraying and a lot of the
classes that we would take when we were
getting our CE use for our applicator
license you know they're telling you do
preventive sprays so they're even
talking about spraying before you have a
problem so it is kind of a hard thing to
get a grower used to the idea of well I
don't have pest pressure why am i
putting out bugs and one of the
challenges of that to me is a lot of
times chemicals only have one rate so
you know that's the amount that you mix
whether you have a little bit of threats
or you have a lot of threats a lot of
times chemicals will have ranges we have
low rate high rate and that's when I do
try to put that into perspective for
growers where the whole concept of
having a presence in your crop to make
it unattractive for pests in the first
place is what keeps the control when
they do show up because they're
outnumbered if you wait until you have a
pest problem to address it it's all
about numbers it's all about
outnumbering and overwhelming the pests
so when you have five or six thrips and
here's the thing I have never ever in my
life been in a pest free crop and I've
had growers tell me they grow pest free
crops I don't believe them I have never
grown a pest free crop in my entire
career when you start out with a fresh
new dip you need to assume that you
didn't get thrips eggs that might be in
the lease
to assume that you might not have gotten
all the spider mite eggs you need to
assume that you might not have gotten
every last time for us it might so under
that theory there's no such thing as a
pest free crop beginning started early
and preventive and having these things
in place is what prevents the
infestation in the first place
and for some pests hamper us it might is
the main one that I use as an example on
a scale of one to ten with one being one
hem for us at night at my whole
greenhouse and ten being oh my god I've
closed the doors we're out of business
anything past three we can't really do
much about we can but it's gonna cost a
lot of money so compress it might is the
main one that I use is the example like
at this point everybody's either had
them or they're at least aware of them
the people that did have them caught
them too late the first time that's
usually a pretty common thing and they
saw what it cost them a good one to
compare it to in the ornamentals world
is in poinsettias
everybody talks about white fly the most
that is the most prominent pest in
poinsettias it's where most of the
research goes into a mite that doesn't
get as much coverage as a lot of other
mites it's called the Lewis mite Lewis
mite is a pest in poinsettias but the
problem with Lewis mite and poinsettias
it doesn't show damage until far long
after the feeding so you have to be
attacking these Lewis mites very very
early before you know that you have them
before it looks like you have them no
visual symptoms on the plants and the
thing is if you spray that when you cut
if you find it early and you spray it
you've now taken some of the sprays
options out that you might need later
for white fly so that's a good example
right there of Lee you have to go in
preventively against this almost non
pest to keep your pest management
program in place down the road for your
white fly if that makes sense
and yeah I want to highlight something
you said back because this was new this
was new information to me within the
last year I didn't realize that thrips
can lay eggs
inside the leaf so just because a plant
looks clean even with really careful
scouting that quarantine room is super
important because thrips could still
show up for sure and that's the the
Western flower threats the mama
basically has almost like a little nice
that she just opens the lease and
oviposit sin there so now there's
there's I'm sure that they're highly
skilled entomologists with keen eyes out
there that can spot what thrips eggs
inside of a leaf look like I can't I've
never seen it that I can tell you with
certainty that's what that is on that
leaf I don't know I know that I've seen
thrips emerge out of leaves that looked
100% pest free to me so that's one right
there that even dipping you know I love
dips and I encourage anybody to get into
doing oil dips if you're bringing in a
lot of plant material that you just
don't know why take the chance
Suzanne is out there spreading the word
about it there's there's it's a lot of
info available now about it online
really have no excuse it's cheap just do
it but still know that you might not
have got thrips eggs that might be
inside of the leaf strips are one that
get overlooked in cannabis a lot because
they're not seen as as big of a pest as
spider mites or aphids or hemp russet
might one thing I like to remind people
of thrips vector more pests more plant
viruses than any of those other bugs
taking the chance with the plant virus
if you I mean I think we're all starting
to learn the impact that human viruses
have if you've ever seen a plant virus
move through a greenhouse or moved
through a room the devastation that that
causes and I have been in a greenhouse
situation where my own negligence at
treating thrips in a crop that I that I
didn't think they were a problem in and
I'll say it's a crop called coleus
coleus are very colorful leaved plant
not a lot of flower production in a
coleus thrips get on them they don't
really damage them I never saw what I
considered significant thrips damage I
wasn't asleep at the wheel on them I
just wasn't prioritizing them as a pest
meanwhile they spread I nsv impatient
necrotic spot
through that crop to the tune of about
$25,000 worth of plants by the end of
the season stacked up plants wrapped
shrink wrapped in plastic because you
now have to dispose of them in a
different way because they are infected
and you have to dispose of plants that
might not be infected but you just don't
know so that was from me not paying
attention to thrips so rip legs and the
leaves and it can really lead to
problems down the road now I know that
there's still a lot of research and a
lot of work being done to research this
this hopped latent thyroid and cannabis
and the jury's still out on if cannabis
get certain plant viruses but I mean why
wouldn't it that's the way I say it why
wouldn't it why white why would we not
assume that thrips that vector is to all
these other plants that they would be
that they wouldn't do the same to this
plant how do you you know for a while
there it seemed like every weird display
of stuff leaf damage was being called
tobacco mosaic virus but I've never seen
an actual pathology report confirming it
on cannabis and I think talking to
Suzanne she hadn't seen it either it's
always a buddy's friend that has the lab
result you know but no one's ever been
able to produce them yeah you haven't
seen him yet you seen it yet either no I
had I had one grow that I worked with
out in Bend Oregon that they I mean then
these guys it was such a tragedy because
the first time I visited their place I
told them I'm gonna brag about you guys
to every grower I meet from now on and
and guilt-trip them for not having the
same setup that you do I mean these guys
had their PPE dialed in they had zip up
rubber doors between the rooms they had
maps in each room if you came in this
door you leave out of this door so there
was like a forced river there you
couldn't go back out the way you came in
really cool guys and very talented very
smart and look forward to working with
them and then about a month later the
guy sends me a picture of a plant that
looks like it has tmv and said is this
team
I don't know I was very honest with him
I only been working with cannabis for
about a year I said I'd really don't
know I have no idea what it would
display like in this crop and he said
well that plant looked beautiful
two days ago and I said I was out of
state at the time and I said I can't get
out there right now I could come like
Monday or whatever is as soon as I can
get there so do me a favor send me a
picture that exact same plant tomorrow
from the same angle and everything and
he did and somewhere I have those two
photos I put them side-by-side in one
day
whatever that I I guess I probably won't
ever know what it was it was definitely
viral as I've never seen anything impact
a plant that fast not even spray I mean
it was it was just it looked exactly
like tmv except it was starting at the
top of the plants so I called this guy I
said look you need to get a test kit the
contest for tmv Insp tswv which is
tomato spotted wilt virus I mean
anything you can I ended up connecting
them with Ag dia which is the company
that produces the the test kits that we
always used for years into greenhouses
it and these things aren't cheap they
had to pay fifteen hundred dollars to
get a box of them because they don't
sell just one so they tested all of
their suspect crops three tests and
negative for every one of the plant
viruses meanwhile they lost about I
don't know a hundred plants to whatever
was going on there the nexus sometime
when we see each other again remind me
to show you the photos it's it's
horrible it looks like it looked like
TMZ it was very decisively not tmv but
out there yeah maybe there is I the only
thing I've ever seen
damaged plants that quickly and this is
this is an awful but yet kind of funny
story back in a day we were when I was I
was growing outdoor with my my brother
and my father
I had taken a sprayer and filled it with
bleach to bleach an old room that we had
been growing in in in a giant
garage warehouse on this property and
then my dad without me knowing
took that sprayer and it's like oh yeah
I rinsed it out and then went and
sprayed I can't remember what it might
have been like neem oil or a compost tea
I can't remember something out of that
sprayer on do write plants and I came
out the next day and there was just like
necrotic damage on the leaves and I
couldn't figure out what it was and
literally over the course of three days
the entire crop was it was just gone it
looked like the worst case of botrytis
you've ever seen just my brother is
still mad about it yeah I chalked it up
as a learning experience but it was I
mean these were this was a lot of plants
I'm not saying that's what they did but
it was it was I was bad my probably
biggest time of ruining ruining plants
from a mistake and it's funny because
it's actually something that I find
myself talking a lot about working in
cannabis is the dangers of a sulphur and
oil treatment too close together which I
learned the hard way with a greenhouse
full of African violets which get
powdery mildew like you wouldn't believe
and I've had sold four burners in there
determined that I wasn't doing enough
and did a very light micronized sulfur
spray and it wasn't five or six days
later that an oil spray was done I
didn't do the oil spray but I also
didn't communicate with the person who
did and and in his defense he he was
still learning a lot and he didn't have
any idea about the interactions between
the two and yeah a lot of cannabis
growers have learned the hard way about
going after p.m. or Russ it might with
sulfur and oil and doing them within ten
days of each other I mean it's the
plants look probably about like your
your plants did they got hit with the
bleach yeah it was so it was so rapid
have a hemp press that question I know
were jumped around a little bit but I
had it I was on the phone with a grower
the other day and he was telling me that
he claims he got hemp Russ it from his
soil now I want to clarify not kiss soil
not my soil I have you don't wreck with
this grower just so I don't
people freaking out but alright he
claimed that the hem press it can
actually propagate in the soil which I
thought it was exclusively a plant that
lived or sorry an insect that lived in
the canopy and exclusive only to
cannabis or right what what about you I
mean I'm open to being wrong here
publicly off you're certainly here
you're certainly right about it being
exclusive to hemp in cannabis there are
other area Fayyad mites that at a glance
don't mean you wouldn't be able to tell
the difference
most entomologist without slide mounting
them would not be able to tell the
difference so there's a lot of mites
that look a lot like hand for us at
mites that are not hem for us at mites
and one of the fun little things i play
with in my head sometimes is do we know
that they only get him for us it might
it could be a different one in there to
a different area Fayed
but trust moves we all know that one as
as many as you need so they do all of
their feeding and they're there the
lively part of their life on the leaves
on the foliage feeding on the canopy of
the plant now here's where the jury's
out since I'm sure you know and it's
been said many times that you know a
hemp and cannabis exclusive test is
going to have little to no official
research done on it
the the actual University based studies
and to have Russ it might are limited to
a couple of things at Colorado State's
put out so they haven't been studied at
length to the level of something like a
spider mite where we know a lot about
the to spot spider mite you know so
we're the jury's out is the diapause
part of their lifecycle so spider mites
do diapause into soil or if they have
enough leaf litter if they can't get to
good soil if you have enough leaflet or
just you know just just soil litter
nobody really knows and I've had people
tell me that they've had people tell
them that oh yeah they died a pause in
the soil
the thing is area Fayyad mites
that whole order of mites is a very to
use the same analogy to forts like a
roulette wheel the ones that you can
find information on the full lifecycle
it doesn't help
because some diapause on the plant
itself which that doesn't make sense on
an annual so if their diet pausing are
they going down into the soil to
diapause possibly but the only way that
this grower would be getting area fired
my or hemp russet mites in purchased
soil is if he's purchasing the soil from
an old cannabis farm so they're not just
going to be naturally occurring in soil
that's being sold and being amended and
all of that and sold as commercial soil
there may be some sort of dormancy
period though where these are able to
survive potentially in the soil we just
don't know what we don't know that's the
thing we don't know and until until it's
kind of like when people tell me that
they've seen hemp russet my eggs they're
like well we don't have them but I know
we have them because we found their eggs
I'm like take a picture and proves that
it sent for us it might eggs and you'll
make a lot of money off of it because
nobody has a picture of them nobody
knows what they look like really
they haven't been studied on the degree
that they need to be which is in a
laboratory or research greenhouse
university setting so until then
unfortunately people have a lot of
theories but at the end of the day
they're just theories and the chances of
you vectoring hemp for us it might in
any way except bringing them in on
plants that you bought is very low in my
opinion yes they can travel on gusts of
wind yes they can get on your clothing
and then rub up against a plant can they
come in on other pests we don't know for
sure but we know abroad might do so I
think that I've seen photos of citrus
rust mite which is almost identical to
two hemp russet might they jump off of
plants and they can't fly so I don't
think they would jump off for any reason
except to either catch a wind current or
maybe catch a ride on it
who knows on a broad Mitel attached to a
white fly and
let the whitefly take it to another
plant but with all of those potentials
yes they can do all of that I think 99%
of the hemp rest of my cases we work
with I tell the people you bought these
you bought these we bought these plants
that they came in so like you know be
aware that you were killing bugs that
you paid for yeah that's that's a good
way to put it one okay so I have a
couple more questions for this podcast
and I think I'd like to do just a
separate follow-up one because I know
the thing that you want to talk about
was the cannabis aphid and oh yeah and
and and it's just it's we've talked it
to death this year in the last couple of
years it's just one that I feel like it
needs to be talked to death until
growers are terrified of it so they
actually stay on top of managing it a
hundred percent let's let's save that
one and do another podcast here but I
did have a couple other questions that
kind of fit with this sort of Q&amp;A
podcast that we're doing right now so
one of the things we talked about was
and because of Suzanne I always tell
folks to work directly with an insect or
go to an insect eree to make sure you're
getting you know not only just good
information as well as fresh bugs and
can you talk a little bit about that
process or what your thoughts on are on
it yeah and and for sure you know when I
used to buy a lot of bugs I would buy
through resellers and then occasionally
when I was lucky and working directly
with manufacturers now as times change
we do change our business approach
sometimes and the truth is I mean we
have a really deadly smart good team of
guys here but there's four of us and we
can't really get out and visit growers
all around the country so we do work
with some distributors that usually are
larger AG distributors that are selling
products that growers are already buying
already needed a lot of times they're
already set up with accounts with these
companies that are providing stuff like
the conventional stuff that they will
use fertilizers soil irrigation but one
thing that we do is we try
- at least with these larger companies
that we're working with we're doing drop
shipping so when a grower works with
this rep who it may not disrupt that
they're working with may not work for us
they're providing our bugs directly from
our company so they do we ship them from
our facility in Redding California to
you there's no middleman
so they're coming to you absolutely as
fresh as possible most times within 24
hours and also we try to work with these
distributors that are open to having us
come out and visit their growers with
them when we make time to visit
sometimes it's you know we have ones
that are working with growers in
Pennsylvania and Michigan Florida so
when we visit out there we'll link up
with these reps that are selling them
our bugs and these other products and
say hey let's go visit so-and-so so that
way the grower still gets direct access
to our specialists they have our contact
info they can reach out to us for
technical support and stuff a lot of
times we have other we do have a few
other sellers that there is kind of a
middleman person that they do keep a
separation between us and their
customers now most times companies like
that are going to be a lot more
knowledgeable and biocontrol
then say some of the bigger AG companies
because you have a rep who's pretty much
selling everything versus a rep who's
dedicated to biocontrol however those
companies may not want a direct
relationship with suppliers and their
customers so we're kind of cut off from
them it is kind of at the end of the day
I just want you to buy our box I really
I want I want to as many people to get
our bugs into their greenhouses to their
grow rooms or to their farms as possible
it is kind of the growers decision if
you want access with your reps with the
technical end of what we provide and
potential visits to your location you
need to be working with one of these
distributors it is getting it direct
from us that is open to us visiting and
you know the thing is these reps are
also selling
bugs for other producers too and every
chance that they're probably working
with them and visiting but that's that's
how we can connect with the growers and
it's how I'm not going to run our team
of four just completely ragged trying to
work directly with every single grower
that reaches out because it is it's it's
it's a challenge there's a lot of
support involved in what we do so the
key takeaway I think for people listen
this podcast is make sure the bugs are
being shipped direct from insect erease
for sure and and that's just to make
sure that they're as fresh as possible
because now if you're if you're a four
by four tent or you know a few lights
you may not have that option you may
only want a hundred 150 or something you
may have to go with you know someone
that's that's buying the bugs in as a
middleman and then read distributing
them well or may not be as fresh exactly
unfortunately we only go down so small
and order sizes so sometimes the the
third party that is a good a good time
for them to shine where they do they can
break things down into smaller units and
and in their defense it's not like these
are just getting shipped to some hot
warehouse where they're going to sit for
days
most of these resellers have cold rooms
that they're doing all of the open
opening and repackaging in there so it's
never coming out of that target
temperature the worst case is sometimes
you have an extra day in transit now the
reality of all of this is to be
perfectly honest we sell some stuff that
we don't produce some stuff that and and
that's the case with every producer
don't let them tell you differently
we all buy and sell bugs to each other
at times so sometimes we are buying bugs
from Europe there are 6 days in transit
I used European bugs for years in my
greenhouses because the I wasn't even
really producing a lot of greenhouse
products back then B I was mainly doing
lacewing and trikha grandma and a few
other things but no aureus no cuckoo
Marys nothing like that yet so I mean
for many many years everybody
successfully did biocontrol with bugs
that were sick
today's and transit so it's not that
it's not that extra Transit is going to
impact the quality it's just you're
adding a lot more chances for something
to go wrong and we do as much on our end
as we can these third-party resellers
are doing as much as they can by having
a cold room but we are totally at the
mercy of UPS and FedEx or whoever's
moving those bugs so the quicker the
less time they have it the more
comfortable I am yeah I know you and
Suzanna bull taught classes on how to
even evaluate the bugs that you are
receiving to know that they're viable
not just alive but actually going to go
out there and eat a target pest and
that's a whole other conversation in
class and probably better done live in
person but what I'm not I'm sorry good
oh go ahead just real quickly and it's
it kind of plays into and and I will
make it quick I just want to kind of a
promotion for bi but we have been one
thing that we have been working on
during this downtime which is cool I had
developed a series of released
instruction videos in the last year and
a half or so just kind of quick little
men and a half two minute long videos on
our YouTube channel where growers can go
if they get a bottle of what XYZ and say
because we send printed instructions
with them but a lot of times it's just
so much easier to just watch 30 seconds
of somebody actually using it to say
okay that's how I'm supposed to do that
so one thing that we have recently been
adding during this downtime the Repsol
that i mentioned earlier he's bilingual
so we have gone and all of our videos we
also now have available with Spanish
audio over for spanish-speaking IPM
management which is something we're
running into a lot more often now so but
that plays into now that we've got
pretty much all of our release videos
for our bugs done we're going to move
into the next project is a series of
videos on scouting and
series of videos on QC of incoming bugs
of knowing what to look for all of that
stuff so and moving forward now that we
have the gift of the of a bilingual
specialist all of our videos will debut
in English and Spanish at the same time
hey that's great we'll put a link on the
podcast page to the YouTube channel so
people can check that out oh yeah what
bugs are you most famous for producing I
wanted to cover that real quick i man
I'm probably speaking out of turn but I
thought I remembered it was 2 Khmer so
if you're on the west coast it's the
fastest easiest way to get to Camaros is
that right I would yeah if you're on the
west coast of the United States I don't
see a way for you to get them quicker
than us
I I would say VI is probably most known
historically because just the eyes have
been around for 35 years it's not until
the last about 12 years that Cynthia our
owner expanded it out and she recruited
some people with a bigger emphasis in
greenhouse products because for years bi
has been a huge producer of lacewing is
probably what we're known the best for
just because we I might be overstating
but we've got to be one of the largest
producers in North America of lacewing
we produced a lot of turkey grandma
wasps which are used to control various
mods you know but as far as what the
greenhouse is using these a lot of
lacewing in there but for me I really
fell in love with di when I found out
about our aureus aureus cuckoo Maris
strata Oh estradiol elapsed DeLucie
we have 10 or 12 organisms that we
produce right here and reading that ship
out like you said I don't see a way for
you to get them quicker
it's a no-knock against any other
company just they have to ship
internationally to get them to you
whereas you know you're up in the
Seattle area of course today's Friday so
it's an exception but you know Monday
morning you call hey Kelly I've got a
real problem I need a I need some cuckoo
marys bulk and I need some cuckoo Maris
sachets
you know the very longest it's going to
take you're in ham on Wednesday you call
us early enough on Monday you might have
them on Tuesday so uh yeah that's and
that's not even just because you're on
the west coast it could be you're in New
York it's it's overnight shipping either
way once we get it once we get it there
sometimes orders come in late in the day
we don't get the production into
shipping at time at that time now right
now things are day-to-day with the whole
covert situation just because of all the
shippers that we do use so a lot of
things I will just kind of put an
asterisk on just as a commune
just a cya type of situation right now
but so far we've had no issues with
deliveries we've had no issues with our
shipments being impacted but of course
we're living in strange times but when
everything's running as normal yeah I
mean I ordered aureus the first time
from beneficial and secretary and I got
him the next day I was used to placing
orders on Thursday to get my bugs the
following Wednesday that's a game
changer you know because a lot of times
in a green hot in a pest management
situation if you've been gone for a few
days or you just didn't Scout that area
good enough and you come in and you say
oh my god look at these spider mites
I've got to do something in the next two
days if your bugs if we can't get bugs
to you in two days at the most
all right you know if we can't get them
to you any quicker than that you're
going to spray and then you're gonna
nuke your bio control program so the
quicker that you can say I need to do
something about that I can get bugs for
it and attack it that way instead of
setting everything back and starting
again because I sprayed yeah I do want
to highlight there are other insect
erease out there beneficial is obviously
a great one
you know you come highly recommended by
Suzanne there are and there's there's a
ton of different insect erease well not
a ton there's a limited amount of insect
Ares in the world when you actually
think about it and I would highlight
that there's a lot of different release
methods that all of these insect Ares
and that's probably a whole nother
conversation that's probably better done
with visuals as well because there's
pros and cons to all these different
released you know sachets and bulk and
all of this stuff and I think once
someone gets on a program that works for
their facility and I want to talk I have
a question for you around this in theory
you're not having to order these frantic
you know orders last-minute and need him
in two days it's it's nice that that's a
possibility but I know someone like
Justin has he has a standard order now
and this works so he knows exactly when
he needs throughout the month to get
these bugs in there just to maintain his
preventative IPM but my note on that
would be on forums a lot of times or you
know on Instagram social media media you
see a lot of people like hey what's this
bug and not only do you see a ton of
misidentification and misinformation
around biocontrol advice but let's say
someone has you know a fan they say oh
you need you need a Phidias or you need
you know lace wings or whatever that
isn't enough information to get good
biocontrol
success and now I know one thing Suzanne
has really like parked on me for is that
sounds bad one thing she's really
drilled into my head is that every
situation an environment and grow
environment is unique and requires a
custom approach you can't you know these
rates vary so dramatically based on
every situation because you highlighted
there isn't a standard growing
methodology for cannabis like you would
get with other crops so can you just
talk a little bit about that yeah well I
mean especially I'm glad you used a fit
as an example because if it is the one
that uh I tell people like if you ask me
one question about your aphids prepare
for 20 out of me before I give you an
answer because the most important thing
is that what aphid is it that matters
because if if we're gonna if we're
approaching let's say you're in a
situation where you need to use wasps
it's critical to know what Jay said you
have or if you don't know which a lot of
growers don't and
they don't have a way to get it
identified you know in their defense you
know Suzanne and and me and and I are
big about get your bug ID if you don't
know what it is get it ID'd the reality
is I've sent bugs officer ID from my
greenhouse and entomologist have work to
do so you get an idea about five weeks
later four and a half weeks after you
sprayed because you had to do something
but it is important to know which aphid
you have with thrips too a lot of times
I I it's a bad habit a lot of us have I
just say thrips I should say Western
flower thrips because what's true for
Western flower thrips isn't always true
for chili thrips or onion thrips or
greenhouse thrips or a chi no thrips or
cuban laurel threats or all the various
ones so there's that for one you need to
know that you're using the right species
to attack now in the case of like
lacewing larvae that's what I love about
lacewing they don't care they're gonna
eat aphids if they have access to them
but are you in a situation where
lacewing might not be a good approach
and then you have to use wasps you can
release both and know that you're
controlling it but if you know which
aphid you have if you know for a fact
that you have a green peach aphid
there's no need to release a phidias ERV
I which are expensive you can release a
phidias coleman coal money which are not
as expensive if you don't get that aphid
Aidid you got to release both if you
want to know that you're covering your
butt and then another example of like I
said maybe you want to use Faust's now
this is this is uh this is something
that I have observed in the field quite
a lot in the last few years a couple of
the guys at work have also made similar
observations so a lot of times I like to
start with a disclaimer I'm not making a
scientific statement that I have
research to show this it's just field
observations and feedback from our
growers but one thing that I'm starting
to notice in cannabis and hemp and not
just cannabis and hemp any plant that in
its late pubescent stage gets these
heavy trichomes a good example in the
ornamentals world would be petunias or
just greenhouse
tomatoes is a good example as well where
if you're familiar with the lacewing
larva
with its anatomy and they look like
little alligators with six legs kinda
they're kind of dragging their belly on
the ground when they walk and they
they're not exactly small they do like
to get into tight areas and feed but
they don't seem to really they're not
thrilled about going into areas of
hugely dense trichomes that they
obviously have trouble navigating so if
you have an aphid issue on a plant
that's a week seven of flower throwing
lacewing larvae and it might not be the
right approach so then then it is
critical to know that's not the answer
that's not going to work we need to do
wasps and then which wasps do we need to
do white flies another good one why it's
why you need to know which white fly to
know that you're using the right
parasitoid for it so anybody that just
comes on a forum and says hey what do I
do about Athens and somebody gives them
an answer they really didn't ask enough
questions almost any almost any
situation I need to know what stage the
plants in what you're growing you know
if it's if it's something like thrips
you know it's important to know are you
a hydroponic growers because if you are
then we can't be putting strategy laps
in the soil that you don't have you know
so uh forums forums and social media and
I used to belong to a lot of different
insect ID groups on Facebook and I just
got so frustrated because it's assault
like and it's funny I I tease Suzanne
about this she spends 90% of her time
online just having to go in and just
correct all of this bad info and it's
great that people are out there doing it
it's just exhausting for me and at the
end of the day when there's no research
to back up some of this stuff you get to
a point where I can say everything I
just said but the next guy can come in
and say something and I can't prove them
wrong and they can't prove me wrong and
then it's like it's like when you go on
reddit looking for an answer to
something and you read this long
response and it's like huh that guy
sounds like they're really making sense
that's probably the right answer and
then you read the very next one and
you're like oh wait a minute that one
makes sense too so it's it's a little
Wild West in that area but anybody that
says what do I do for a Fitz hey just
throw ladybugs at them you didn't put
enough thought into it and chances are
it's not gonna work yeah I want to say
that timing also is important an
application rate and environment in
terms of your your lighting your
humidity or your temperatures can all
play a role so it's really important I
think that people get a program that's
really customized to them and I know
you've mentioned ladybugs a couple times
I just want to make sure if you're
thinking about buying ladybugs please go
back and listen to the last podcast
because there's a lot of challenges
around these wild harvested ladybugs and
like yeah I I hope people aren't
purchasing those I know there are some
insect or insect or reared ladybugs but
it's really rare and that's not what 99%
of the population and and most times and
they're not the ones you're going to be
buying at a grow shop either the
insectary reared lady beetles are not
the traditional ones that most people
think of when they say ladybug these are
ones that are specialized for going
after different pests like mealy bugs or
even one there is one that goes after
spider mites but not the ones that
you're buying at a grow shop those as
you said wild harvest it's one of those
things that if there's something to get
up on a soapbox about that's one and
that's that's my soapbox thing that I
get up on it's like look ladybugs
showing up on their own or your friend
you don't need to you don't need to
worry you're not hurting anybody by
letting them come and hang out in your
garden or on your crop but buying them
is just it's kind of spitting in the
face of sustainability in my opinion
it's taking them out of we're taking
them out of where we need them I just
wanted to clarify that just to make sure
growers weren't buying any any ladybirds
or anything like that yeah I'm not gonna
scream at you for it but I might wag my
finger at you a little bit yeah cool
well one other thing I wanted to cover
real quick was talking about your staff
and how you guys work with the grower
because we just talked about the
importance of a customized approach you
mentioned a little bit that some of
these
some of these distributors will allow
you and your staff to come in and you
know maybe even to her greenhouse or to
our facility or work directly with the
grower and coming up with a program
you're still buying the bugs through the
distributor you're not selling direct
but how do how do people interact with
your staff and let's do a quick little
bio about the four people that they may
interact with over a beneficiary
beneficial because I've met them all you
guys are all great guys let's take a
nominator and plug that yeah I've got a
great team to that well I guess three
kind of the numbers all of them I'm kind
of had a hand in getting them on board
here Greg Greg Bryant he lives in
Colorado
Greg joined up with us around the summer
last year a year before I'm sorry and
Greg actually came to us from one of our
competitors so he had a little bit of
experience already in doing exactly what
we do and prior to that had experience
working with nematode colonies and did
he did work in efficacy trials with
pesticides and greenhouses and stuff so
he's got a really cool entomology
background and then we have Sol Alba
who's down in Los Angeles Sol is the one
who was about 15 minutes into the first
time I visited him as a grower you know
as a supplier customer relationship I
asked him if he'd ever think about
coming to work for us and in about two
years later he he finally took me up on
my offer
Sol is licensed PCA in the state of
California he's got IPM hands-on
experience in large green house cannabis
which is and actually he when I first
met him he was working in organic herbs
he's grown done IPM and mushrooms and
vineyards and worked in wine chemistry
before that so he's got a really create
an incredible background of chemical and
and macro biological plus the licensed
PCA part not that we sell insecticides
that it's good to have someone license
to consult in it because we can go a
little deeper in working with growers
that are
coming off of conventional programs and
getting them more towards chemistry
that's a little friendlier to what we do
and then our most recent addition to the
team is Eric Vanderslice he lives up in
the Portland area
Eric was I knew him as IPM manager from
another very large ornamentals
greenhouse operation up there very
similar to the one that I worked for in
fact the two companies did business
together but prior to that Eric is one
of the weird ones that he crossed over
from cannabis into ornamentals not the
other way around because he had a couple
years as head grower for large cannabis
operation in Washington so our team is
just full of this diverse background of
experience so that's I just had to do a
little bragging about them the way
generally that they'll work with us it
depends if you know like the show that
we did in Portland where I saw you last
a lot of times we meet people we get
their information there and we'll reach
out to them get them connected with who
they need to to get orders placed and
then if it's someone within driving
distance of course we get out there as
soon as possible if it's someone that's
in a different part of the country that
we do have other area other stuff that
we work at there you know
personally I like to try to get a visit
to the place as soon as possible because
just like I said with the release videos
sometimes it takes 30 minutes for me to
explain something that takes 30 seconds
to show you sometimes like if I've had
growers that I've worked with for a year
or two years and never seen their
facility and then somehow something
happens where I get a chance and you go
out there and you're like oh this is not
what I it's like when you're reading a
book and then you watch the movie and
they don't look anything like you
expected them to some growers are really
bad at explaining I'm not just blaming
the growers but some are really bad at
explaining what their greenhouses or
their rooms look like or what they don't
know their own square footage a lot of
times so just me putting eyes on it one
time helps now with with kovat and and
our travel being very limited right now
trying to encourage more growers to be a
little active in sending us photos that
works that that works better than
explaining it to us sometimes just walk
around take about 20 photos of your
location send them to me and tell me
which one is green house a and green
house B or green house 21 and green
house 22 and then that way I have in my
photos I have folders for each of the
customers that I visited that I put the
photos in there from so it's like if if
CAD calls me and he's got an issue and
go and see what Tad's a green house
looks like because the sad truth is
after four years of working here it gets
hard to remember a lot of them sometimes
it's hard to even wrap my head around
how many places I visited at this point
but the sooner we can get a visit the
better sometimes that doesn't work out
if we can get photos and get growers
started a lot of times growers it's how
much they want to share with us if
they're willing to share stuff like a
production schedule with us we can get
them going like your friend Justin we're
okay we know when you're gonna plant
when you're going to harvest we know
when the plants are switching when
they're going to be transplanted we can
lay out some groundwork right here and
then there's no such thing as a
subscription biocontrol there's no set
it and forget it you can set up certain
things like sachets releases of strata
flike that we still in my opinion I
think it's like you got to go to the
doctor for a check-up we have to check
up every now and then and just touch
base you might have certain cultivars to
give a little bit of pest pressure but
you know most of the time we're just a
phone call away we do travel a lot so
sometimes run available immediately that
we all will get back with you within 24
hours of an email or text or phone call
coming in you know that's a good point
you're constantly tweaking your program
it's never a set it and forget it is
something that's always being you know
adapt to a given you know your given
situation seasonally you get better over
time you get better at just kind of
knowing what you need and some things
are pretty much set it and forget it
like you can Pro you can you can
forecast out nematode drenches or like I
said strata or lay lapse releases if you
know you're going to have
amount of plants but as far as pest
pressure goes you're not going to have
consistent spider mite pressure
throughout the entire crop consistent
thrips pressure so you have to but for a
certain amount of it it can be set up
ahead of time and then it's like you
know you you go out and you scout which
everybody should be doing whether you're
on a subscription biocontrol or
subscription spray or whatever you're
doing you need to be scouting you scout
and you say you know what sometimes if
you're doing really good you can reduce
what you were going to buy you know what
I don't need that extra blah blah blah
sometimes you say oh well that new
strain that we have is really getting
hit by spider mites so we need to tack
on an extra bottle of personalist to
push those back so for the most part
we're never done
communicating with the grower I mean
they're never going to be done having
pest pest challenges and I mean we do we
have some growers that they can't even
place an order without calling and
talking to us and that's what we're here
for
you know to support them yeah you know
you had your soapbox moment around
ladybugs or lady beetles and I want to
have a quick one around what you just
what you just mentioned cuz I get I get
blurry photos and videos all the time of
insects let me just start off by saying
I am NOT going to identify your insect I
don't I'm not a pathologist I don't have
enough experience I know what I write no
I mean I can guess I'm pretty good at
that but I'm not gonna do that for your
girl it's just not right it wouldn't be
ethical of me but I would write happily
refer you to someone like Suzanne
someone like Kelli and they can identify
but they're not gonna be lied enta PHY
awful happy you know 90% of the images I
get are not high enough resolution check
and identification and that's so invest
in something I know Suzanne loves Dino
lights I have a Dino light I love it I
don't want to sound like they're the
only things that take a good measure cuz
that's you know what
years ago though I gave up on trying to
not sound like a marketing Dino light
because they're they're so easy to find
there's so many other ones out there
that but I have bought the other ones
and it's really a crapshoot of quality
whereas again I don't get paid by Dino
life I don't think you
do I know I don't think Suzanne does
they really just are
it's like DRAM Auto foggers I don't get
paid by them I just want to tell you
what the best one to use is I do sell
Dino lights now because of Suzanne so I
do not very smell origin but I do I do
carry him now yeah dude they're they're
they're indispensable I mean nobody has
an excuse to not have one at this point
there you can get the dynamite basic is
like 125 bucks at the most I mean what
is your crop worth to you one plant is
worth I mean that's a fraction of what
you make off one plant so I have a slide
that I do and a lot of talks just called
help me help you and I use it as a
collage of all of the just atrocious
pictures that I've gotten sent where
it's like dude I have no idea what I'm
looking at I can't tell us that's a
might or an asset or if it's even a
plant you know so but there's someone
that will identify that for you on a
forum confident of course it's a
renascent thank you
now I'm trying to use kovat as a little
bit of an a motivator to people like
look you know things nobody could have
seen this coming but you know we need to
take into account things happen
sometimes it like I just cannot come out
there and see you and if I can't come
out and shake your plants out and
identify your bugs you got to get good
pictures to me you got to get good at
doing you know and and we're open to
doing getting on skype and you know put
us on your phone and walk around your
room with us and where we can see it but
this right now should be the biggest
reason for people to start communicating
being better I mean we're all doing zoom
meetings and stuff to to check in and
most people are working from home if
they can
so it's time times like this gear up and
have good ways to send us good photos
because the truth is I've been looking
at bugs for 20 years I still have I
still have to have an incredibly clear
picture for me to with certainty tell
you now I can with certainly to
certainty tell you if it's a strip or a
spider fight or thrips Oh Suzanne's a
rake
over the coals for that it's three no
never thrift it strips I can tell you if
it's the strips or a spider mite a lot
of times I can tell you yeah it's
Western flour thrips but those are rare
when I get a photo of that good most
times it's a blurry photo of what ends
up being springtails or something like
that but yeah that's a good soap box to
get up on and I believe was it you or
Suzanne who did a talk specifically on
that at the biocontrol show about being
better at taking photos and now Suzanne
mine was on evaluating products for your
garden making good production decisions
in terms of what you need to do in terms
of research and in scientific method
when you're going to bring any product
into your garden that was my talk which
was fun but the other side I see on my
side of the industry with soil is I'll
get a photo of a leaf and they want me
they want me to tell them what's going
on you know whether it's a deficiency
whether it's a powder yeah and you you
literally can't so like I come back and
I'll need to see a photo of the entire
plant for one so I can see if it's a
mobile nutrient if it is an efficiency I
need to know if it are pest pressure
what other things you might have foliar
sprayed what kind of lighting what your
environment looks like how are you
watering what's the hydrology process
with your soil like that's that's a huge
thing when it comes to deficiencies and
you know 9 the soil gets blamed for
everything in nutrient programs and to
be fair a lot of times it can be
something like that but with a lot of
these you know living soil programs I'm
finding a lot of times it's it's it
comes down to the watering or other
stuff that they're doing that they
figure that they do and that's where
going to the facility like you said you
may look over in a corner and see a
bottle of something and be like oh are
you using that they're like oh yeah we
used it and we just forgot to put it on
the email and those are the kind of
things that you miss from these photos
that's so important and that's just
something that I that would probably be
my biggest soapbox moment water water
management
it's I mean it really is the foundation
of so many things like it really ripples
out to affecting how effective every
other thing you do is and you know for
an instance like it's funny because you
say the soil gets blamed for everything
sometimes you just can't help the soil
you're growing in so you have to learn
how to manage the soil that you have
I have growers that they got in over
their heads trying to do living soil in
very shallow raised beds and now they
have gone a little overboard and they've
got this incredibly organic soil that I
mean it might as well be growing in
compost so now there's a lot of stuff a
lot of a lot of bio activity in there
they hadn't accounted for another thing
that's going on the same one all of
their old mulch and stuff that's in
there decaying is now just playing a
huge host to isopods suits Roly Polys
toe bugs and they're actually starting
to damage their young plants there
they're feeding on the skin like
basically girdling these small plants
now they really do need to just once
they harvest just change this out this
whole system out that's what I told them
the last harvest and they still growing
in the same spot this year with some of
the same problems but another thing that
has a lot to do with all of that stuff
happening the way it is is the fact that
they overwater under watering is not or
you know backing off the water is not
going to fix that problem but it's
certainly going it's not going to make
it worse
just like a lot of times we have growers
to get concerned when they see huge
abundance and springtails for one
springtails aren't really a bad bug but
I like to say spring tales are good
Scouts because spring tales like dead
roots so if I walk past a plant that's
just exploding with spring tails I know
that spring tales aren't the problem but
I want to know why so many spring tales
have something to eat that tells me
there's a lot of dead roots in this
plant so is it up is it a soil you know
do I have a root disease do I have
something going on there nine times out
of ten it's over watering because spring
tales for one are you familiar with them
yes I see them a lot in these girls you
know spring tales
you know a little bit about them they're
technically they're not even insects
they're a whole separate group of
arthropods called : Bella they're very
they share a common ancestor but they're
technically not insects and and if you
look at them you look at their Anatomy
you can see it - certain things don't
don't match up you know totally wingless
very very primitive compared to an
insect when it comes down to their
actual physiology and and the main way
is insects have very very primitive kind
of lungs that I like to compare it to
like the chambers inside of like a
harmonica or something isopods
or a colon Bela even less they have to
diffuse oxygen out of water so they have
to have they have to be wet to breathe
so what does that tell you if you if you
want to send their numbers out they
cannot live in dry soil but I have
growers that just keep battling
springtails not battling them but they
don't you know they're saying well why
do we have so many of them you don't
have any diseases you're over watering
they can't breathe if you take that
water out of there but they'll blame the
soil the blames the roots or you know
what do I need to spray you know you
need to spray less water that's what you
need to do well I always under the
impression that springtails not only a
dead roots but other forms of organic
matter as well so if you're using a soil
that has high levels of compost or
you're recycling
sort of your beds with these you know
flour rooms you're gonna have root hairs
that are just left over from the
previous grow is that yeah a concern
because my thought on the other side of
this is well if we start having a wet
dry cycles or allow the soil to dry out
too much then we're reducing our
nutrient cycling on a microbial level
there's there's a balance there for sure
you can definitely overwater right where
does their own balance lie I guess yeah
and you are right about them being kind
of a little more of a generalist debt
reward that they're gonna feed on other
stuff as well the concern with it that I
have actually seen
this in person and it's kind of like the
the the pill bugs damaging these these
plants usually pill bugs they're not a
pest good luck trying to find any
information on controlling pill bugs
because all of everything you're gonna
find that reads gonna say they feed on
rotting things they don't feed on new
cannabis plants but here they are
feeding on them and it's a lot of times
when you get an abundance of something
and it doesn't have it has way too much
competition for its preferred food
source they get creative they may not
you know infest a plant like they're
going to if they were a thirds or thrips
or anything like that but in my case it
was a crop of dianthus of carnations
that was just they're very tricky plant
to water and if you're not careful
you'll overwater them and people weren't
careful and they're pretty much
constantly over watered so that was my
little I called it the popcorn because
it's like just spring tail jumping out
of every pot and I would pull the roots
out to make sure you know that they're
they're not doing the damage that that I
assumed they could and then lo and
behold we start finding them feeding on
live roots and damaging our plants and
it was only because I had they're so
untended that they're running out of
dead roots
there's too many this it's like this
place is so abundantly good for them now
there's too many of them and at that
point you have to back off of the water
you want springtails in your soil you
know you want isopods in your soil you
don't want them to the point that
they're so hungry that they're gonna
start costing you money that's a good
point that's a good point I have seen
the roly-poly bugs girdling class like I
had never had never seen that until
working with this there's a lot of
things I had never seen until working in
cannabis and I'm not trying to poke fun
or anything but a lot of times growers
like the whole living soil and I have a
lot of growers that are big and you know
Korean natural the KNF growing it's one
like you can really screw it up if you
don't follow the fundamentals of it and
you can end up with a really funky
soyal going on that like you might have
just created a whole lot of problems for
yourself yeah no I I get that I there
are certain things about no-till growing
and you know some of these processes
that I don't believe translate well to
controlled environment agriculture now
as you know I'm a big proponent of
living soils
I personally however don't believe in
using cover crops indoors and living
mulch or even mulch is in general
because of the some of the challenges
that you mentioned we just don't have
the diversity about diversity that you
see outdoors it allows for these things
to be really effective but and some
people do it successfully so I don't
want to say oh there's only one way to
do it I don't own them but and and and I
have we have a grow that we work with up
in northern Washington like in the
northern Okanagan Valley that right when
I was starting to kind of almost think
like god I hate these things no-till
growers because they're not doing it
right I've went visited this farm and
it's to this day I use them as an
example it's like one of the healthiest
just like most kick-ass farms I've ever
been to because these guys are committed
it's and biocontrol is very similar like
when you commit to it you see what it
can do it's great but if you go in half
hearted and you're not going to stick to
it it's the same thing with something as
involved and time and with as much time
involved as building a good no-till
environment for soil and I would assume
much like ours you have a better chance
of succeeding when you have access to
people who know about it and can support
you with it soil much the same approach
I would assume yeah yeah I mean for me I
find that running a cover crop just it
creates another crop that you have to
manage which is challenging indoors it's
potentially going to be another vector
for anything from pathogens to insects
and pests and then these mulch is I
think you can get carried away with
organic matter it's
already gonna be really high if you're
running a living soil so those are my
concerns I mean they they all are very
cool sustainable concepts that I a
hundred percent believe in when it comes
to agriculture or outdoors but indoor
air I just you don't get that same level
diversity and then in terms of no-till I
get this question a lot so I have a blog
post on it with my thoughts again this
is all of my just my opinion but for me
I like to mix nutrients into the soil
and disturb the soil when I read a
living soil bed because we are cropping
so rapidly that I want to get those
nutrients down into the rhizosphere
quickly I don't if we're using organic
amendments and we're not using mineral
salts I don't have the luxury of that
time for that to break down like I would
outdoors cuz outdoors you know if you're
growing an agricultural land sure you
don't have to tell you can top dress you
can allow you can run you know other
crops during off crop cycles you can
allow that soil to rest there's all
these other things but if you're trying
to bring in your next crop 24 to 36
hours later in the flowering room I like
to get those nutrients mixed into the
soil and I get these questions a lot so
I just want to mention them on the end
of this podcast just because well yeah I
mean you got to take into account you're
growing a crop that you're growing a
crop that right out of the gate is just
a very hungry crop that is that you're
deliberately trying to give it as much
as possible to produce as healthy of a
plant so as you said outdoors you have
all of these all of these processes
working that you don't have working
indoors that yeah and with production I
mean we can do it as natural and as as
by you know by mother nature's guide as
possible but I've said this many times
there is no such thing as natural
farming we have to accept that when we
decide to put in a big mass quantity of
a crop that didn't just spring up out of
the earth on its own we have to do some
things differently we can keep it as
close to you know what Mother Nature's
providing us but Mother Nature this spot
didn't evolve over the last million you
years thinking that I was going to plant
a cannabis crop here or even even a
field of corn so we can do what was
naturally in place here we can amend the
soil naturally but we do have to take
some steps we have to ramp up some
numbers whether it's Predators or
whether it's nutrition in the soil you
know especially when we're growing at
such an a borderline unrealistic level
of quality you know that's it's grow
it's like it's like everybody's trying
to grow orchids you're growing perfect
plants so you have to have the nutrition
in the soil and something that I will
never shake from working in such large
environments and with such large crops
and working selling to box stores is
there was an incident emphasis on
uniformity hanging baskets had to be
identical
you know sometimes plants there were no
visual flaws it just wasn't the right
shape so it has to go so you get you
very early learn the importance of the
assurance of knowing like what you're
saying putting those nutrients back in
the soil knowing that that stuff's going
to be there because you know in an
ornamental world you have to produce
little cookie cutter plants that look
exactly the same there's no way to do
that without knowing ok I'm putting
enough in for this crop at each turn
yeah plus the the breakdown of these
cover crops like let's say we have some
nitrogen fixers in there it's really
hard to control the amount of nitrogen
we're getting from the you know renzo
via and the clover that may be it may be
living right so managing nitrogen levels
becomes more challenging especially as
we want a plant to senesce towards the
end of its life cycle as we go to
harvest it for flower so it's just it's
it's additional variability that
personally I don't like to do even
though it sounds really good and cool
and it fits with my ethics I think it
creates challenges on a commercial scale
but if you have a four by four ten by
all means like it's great in those
situations it's it's all about scale man
and we try our hardest to not become
factory farms but it
certain point you production dictates
the way some things have to go and you
know it's like I say there's always a
place for craft growing there's always a
place it's the reason there's still
craft brewery and there's there's craft
brews and there's Budweiser you know
there is a place for those true
approaches like that but when you know I
come from the background of for many
years punching a clock and then getting
in a golf cart to drive around my
greenhouses because there was no way I
could walk them all and realistically
scout them in a day so when you scale
out to a certain point yeah you do have
to but still I mean as long as you're
coming into it with that approach of
doing as much as you can and only only
adding what you have to and then when
you do add it's like with biocontrol
we're just putting in stuff that's
that's naturally occurring when you're
amending soil you're you're amending it
with organic stuff so the people that
get stuck in no-till and they refuse to
do make changes and we have a grower
who's dealing with some pylons every
year that's one that you don't ever
barely ever hear about some pylons they
look like little teeny tiny centipedes
that live down in the soil and they're
an annual pest every year in the exact
same spot on their farm they get a huge
issue with the roots being damaged you
know you have to do something about
problems like that with some pylons a
lot of times people plant potatoes as a
as a crop to kind of get them out of the
soil and that's what they're going to
start doing next season this the season
they didn't get to it in time and by the
end of the season I'll have some good
pictures for you of what they do to
plants hmm that's cool
well I feel like you and I could talk
all day I know your man yeah I got to
get back now and out with my newborn
clod I catch up soon as much time and
yeah I could talk about this stuff all
day and any time you want to talk about
the phorid on the cannabis aphid that is
one I could probably focus on and just
stay on topic for an entire so
alright I'll do a follow up with you
here on the canvas aphid but thank you
so much for your time today and you and
you and your family stay safe this is
gonna be a very dated podcast because
we're talking about this virus hopefully
every six months a year from now it
won't be nearly the impact that we're
all seeing so of course well man thank
you so much for having me and I'm sorry
it took so long to make it happen and
but yeah so let's stay in touch I look
forward to hearing it alright have a
great day thank that that was Kelly
Vance with beneficial insectary and you
were listening to the cannabis
cultivation and science podcast I'm your
host Todd Hussey don't forget to check
out our website at
www.extracareanimalhospital.net
thanks for listening