foreign
[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad Hussey
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawing top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge this episode is a bit
different I didn't know what to do for
our 100th episode and my friend Suzanne
who you all know as the bug lady
convinced me to let her flip the tables
and interview me to share a bit more
about myself how this podcast came to be
and some of what I've learned from my
amazing guests I've had the privilege of
interviewing over the past four years
when I first started the podcast I
really didn't know if anyone would tune
in to listen as of writing this
introduction we are at almost 2 million
unique downloads of the podcast since we
launched I'm grateful to all the folks
who have reached out and shared their
success stories or how something they
learned on the podcast has improved
their growing that's really what this is
all about
since the beginning I've avoided ads and
sponsors because I wanted to keep the
podcast accessible and free if you want
to support us please consider going to
kissorganics.com and check out our
growing list of products ranging from
soils and amendments to beneficial
insects or reaching out for any
Consulting needs that's what allows us
to keep the podcast going anyway enough
on that let's get on with the show
I'm super excited to be here with you
Tad for this hundredth episode because I
absolutely love your podcast and I have
to say I did nagtat about this a little
bit
um because he wasn't exactly keen on
doing this at first but I really thought
people would be interested in learning
more about you because I think you're a
super interesting and I I would I would
put you in the old souls category of
people that I know
um I feel you're a very genuine kind
human being and I'm thrilled to call you
a friend and I just think the world
would want to know more about you
well that's a very nice introduction
Suzanne thank you
um yeah this was your idea and wanted to
do something different for the hundreds
so uh yeah let's let's go for it see how
it goes all right
so yes so I'm not going to ask you
anything too crazy
um but we all know you is kind of like
the soils guy but uh did you actually go
to school for this or did you do
something different first
so I I did not I grew up with my parents
owning a Nursery and Landscaping
business so been around plants my entire
life I was not interested in Plants
until later in life I got my undergrad
degree at the University of Washington
after transferring from Gonzaga with a
degree in anthropology and the minor in
English and then I went on and got a
master's degree in at Macquarie
University in Australia in special
education
and so I don't really have any degrees
related to Horticulture or agriculture
it's all been sort of self-taught
through the industry and breeding and
and things like that but I will say that
having a master's degree was really
really helpful in learning how to read
and understand uh scientific journals
and and the statistics and what research
is actually saying
well I think understanding education and
how to teach also has made you able to
teach people and you know this is what
you're doing through your podcast and
through talks you give and conversations
is you are teaching people and being
able to communicate that valuable
information is super important because
people can be super smart but if you
can't communicate it it makes it very
challenging to get that information out
you know I just feel lucky that I have
this platform that allows me to get some
really great guests that are you know
amazing experts in their field and uh I
just get to ask them the questions that
I think hopefully every grower is
thinking is the person's talking those
are the kind of questions that I want to
try and pull out of them and make this
information more accessible so that's
really the goal of the podcast
well okay so you graduate you know
you're thinking you're probably going to
be a teacher but when I meet you you're
a soils guy how did you get from
thinking about being an educator into
soils
see I haven't heard your questions so
this is all um I didn't know where this
interview was going
um yeah so basically I came back with a
special ed degree and wasn't able to use
it in the United States without going
back to school and frankly that's a it's
a really tough career I worked in
special education for a while and it's
it's really easy to get burned out it's
it's exhausting
um very important I have a lot of
respect for people who do it
um but at the time my parents were
shutting down their Nursery their plant
nursery and my dad had started a compost
tea business and so at that point
um
I was looking for jobs in other fields
and I wasn't having much success finding
something I enjoyed I was actually
working at Red Robin as a server for
quite a while
and then I got involved with my dad's
business and I started learning all
about what he was doing with compost tea
and the really interesting part for me
was the microscopy and the micro the
microbes and that sort of thing and so I
started learning more about that and it
just kind of kept expanding into soils
and minerals and
you know other aspects of I guess
fertility around around plants
so how long have you had uh your company
well I didn't officially own it until
about two years ago I've been running it
since oh boy
2006 I would say uh so quite a while but
my parents owned it up until a couple
years ago when um
they finally sold it to me but the whole
time we had the farm and starting kiss
Organics and everything
um I was running the business but my
parents officially owned it
well that's that's a nice transition
because
um it's always nice to have like a
legacy to pass on to your children
because you see sometimes great
businesses and the children aren't
interested and the businesses end up
folding and you I always feel like we're
losing a piece of History so that makes
me very happy that you know it's able to
continue on for another generation and
you're doing such a a great job with it
so
um but like with your customer base
who's your furthest customer to you guys
ship to or work with
uh you know currently we work with some
people in Maine that seems pretty far
away from us here in Washington State uh
one of our largest customers for a while
was in Puerto Rico until Freight got too
ridiculous
um to be able to ship to them but um
yeah we work with people all around all
around the country ideally we try to
find people more locally to work with
just because of the you know the
sustainability of shipping material
around the country
um but yeah I guess I guess all over
really
have you had a customer that the
situation you deal with they're dealing
with
um was exceptionally challenging and it
it your guys were able to like finally
come to a resolution to to help them out
because I I know I run into some really
challenging problems it's always very
satisfying at the end of the day when
you can help them
yeah actually you know one of those
people
um so we do we do some Consulting on the
side in fact
um and one of them originally was a
Consulting agreement was with Mike over
at maincraft cannabis
and he was dealing with a lot of these
challenges we finally were able to sort
some things out
um
and and come to a resolution to where
now if you go check out his page you can
see he's he's an excellent grower but
what he was dealing with was a starting
soil material that was excessively high
in nitrates and just very unbalanced and
it took us a little while to figure out
what was going on before we were able to
solve it but once we did he's just been
off and running ever since
yeah he's I've been up to his facility
and I will obviously I just finished up
my bag he brought me a bag of chocolate
covered almonds from L.L bean when I saw
him a couple weeks ago in Ohio and I
just finished him up they were tasty
thanks Mike because I know Mike's going
to listen to this yeah he's a great guy
yeah yeah he's a lot of fun
um he he really is okay so you're being
successful you're doing soils but all of
a sudden
how do you end up having this I don't
want to say a media Empire but I feel
like you're on your way to having a
media Empire to having this amazing
podcast that
um Everybody listens to
oh man I think you're giving a little a
little too much credit I really feel
like we're the smallest guys in the the
smallest fish in the pond
um the podcast has been great you know
and uh I'm very grateful for it but you
know we're we're not a large business
there's six of us total like Kiss
Organics uh you know we were larger when
I had the farm and feed store and all of
that but we've really leaned down to
just a really a core group of awesome
folks
um
so yeah we're we're really pretty small
remember I'm a company of one so you're
a big company to me so
yeah I mean we we work with we've
partnered with uh soil mixing facility
about
10 years ago and it's been the best
relationship
um they're really close to us they do an
awesome job
um and I love working with them but it
gives us the infrastructure and
capability to be able to mix at scale to
mix you know a thousand yards if we need
to uh really quickly and have control
over the operations without having all
of the info infrastructure cost of
setting up an entire facility like that
so they've been wonderful to work with
and it's really allowed us to sort of
focus our energies not on the the
day-to-day production side but really on
customer service and helping folks
you know on that end of things and
really dialing in the fertility side of
the the science Side of Everything which
is the fun part for me
right
so the podcast was because I uh
oh boy this was back in like
2008 2009 I want to say
um whenever I first met my my dear
friend Jaya Palmer uh
I was learning about all this stuff and
I was having trouble finding good
information
having come out of you know sort of that
Nursery side of things and Horticulture
it was just so different than what I was
learning in the forums you know reading
about cannabis and the two were just so
completely different that I really
wanted to try and like marry the two in
some way and so I was like okay I wanna
I wanna eventually like write a book
from everything I've learned and
um share that information and then I
realized like as I was doing this I was
like I don't really want to write a book
no one reads books anymore
podcasts were becoming a thing and
frankly like if I did write a book I
didn't no I battle with imposter
syndrome a lot you and I talked about
this and the idea of trying like I would
want to have people come in and write
chapters for me because they know a
subject so much better than me
and as I was thinking more and more
about it and actually have some chapters
that I've written out that I've turned
into blogs on our uh
on our website but I was like I know
people like Jeff lowenfels and
um at the time you know clackam's code
or these people that other Growers want
to hear from you know why not create a
platform where I can just interview them
and let them speak to what it is that
you know they do and what people want to
hear about and as the podcast has grown
I've it's kind of been a lot of like
Word of Mouth from my
guests and kind of putting me in touch
with more and more people and so it's
gotten I think more scientific
as I've gone along
and so you know I get Podcast requests
every every week from people wanting to
come on the podcast and I really now
only I only take on new guests from
people that have are like know someone
that was already a guest and and like
you've been one of the main people who
have helped me in sourcing a lot of
these guests actually so that's been
great
um
but that's that's where it started
wanting to like kind of combine and
bridge the gap between you know
Horticulture and
what was going on in the Cannabis
industry and now there's just so much
more information out there it's a lot
easier to get access to good information
so people ask to be on your podcast I
didn't know that was a thing because
I've never gone to somebody said hey I
want to be on your podcast I didn't know
we were supposed to do that I thought we
were supposed to be asked to be on
podcasts well you know a lot of people
work with marketing firms and those
marketing firms will reach out and email
you and say hey here's my they're the
CEO of so-and-so and they make you know
rolling papers they have the highest
best technology and rolling papers I'm
like this has nothing to do with
cultivation I'm not you know I'm not
really interested but I get I get them
all the time yeah oh so I need to hire a
marketing firm for me you probably
should oh gosh
I know
um from hearing your amazing amazing
amazing talk you did a couple years ago
at the bio control conference
um that you have worked hard to build a
various scientific platform on this and
you know I was totally Blown Away by
your presentation and you talking about
um
your transition on I don't want to say
learning science because I mean I think
you know science
um but just on becoming more of a
critical thinker about science
and you know with doing that are there
things that you are doing today to help
improve and I mean like how do you make
yourself smarter
well we we try to be science based we
try we're not perfect
um but we we really try and it I feel
like science is such a
polarizing word these days some people
think it's it's good some people think
it's bad at the end of the day it's it's
agnostic like it's just this idea of
applying a way of thinking
um
to come to a conclusion and
um you know the thing that kills me
about the Cannabis industry is there's
just such a
there's such a mix between marketing
hype and
science and it gets it gets very very
murky and it's hard to determine
um as a as a grower or as an end user
like what what I'm really need to grow a
healthy plant and then
um
how to go about finding those things and
so we we try to do that but I'll be
honest like it I mean my talk was
basically like how to try and see
through some of the marketing hype but
it drives me it drives me crazy when I
go online and see the ads or what people
are saying and the claims around some of
these products that I that I know are
not accurate and yet
you know they're
they're selling millions of dollars of
these products and it is what it is
that's probably why we get along so well
Tad because I feel your pain every day
on that
um now same same kind of challenges
um but with your podcast
um what has been like what are your
favorite episodes and favorite topics
that you've done
yeah well
there's been a lot of great ones
um I enjoyed my interviews with you
obviously
um I I think learning about something
that I don't know a lot about which is
bugs I mean I'm learning I'm definitely
learned a lot more about insects from
talking to you uh over the years
and now working with biobee I'm learning
even more I have to because
um now that we're you know offering bugs
to customers so that's been something
and I'm not the main person on that like
we have Brandon who's really been
spearheading that for us and he's been
great but I'm learning more as as
customers are asking questions I'm
listening in on the answers and so
that's been really great my other
favorite podcasts I I really like the
one with Dr yorum kapolenick on
mycorrhizal fungus I thought that was
fascinating my recent one with Dr Wendy
Zellner on Silicon
I've been looking for someone to explain
silicon for years and she was fabulous
um I would recommend that podcast to
everyone uh the one with like my mentor
on the Horticulture side uh Don Marshall
I really enjoy
um and just the way he looks at plants
and then uh I did one with my good
friend Justin McGill Dr Ben Higgins you
know talking to like growers in
facilities those were really popular and
then lastly I just went back about two
weeks ago and re-listened to my podcast
with uh Jaya Palmer he passed away last
year and
that was really hard but um being able
to hear his voice again was really
really special for me and so knowing
that that's preserved and people can
hear him that that meant a lot to me too
so those are my favorites
well I'm very sorry about losing your
friend I I you know it's tough sometimes
you know life's just not fair you know
but it's great that on that note I just
want to say you know if you have someone
out there that's struggling with
addiction
like uh please reach out to them and and
and be a resource for them and realize
too that when you see people that are
you know struggling or down and out like
know that they're they're they're human
and they're passionate and intelligent
and creative and loved like uh sometimes
it's easy to just walk by and see it you
know because you see addiction
everywhere unfortunately these days and
uh it's it's hard to have compassion for
that and I just
I just want to mention that because uh
Jaya was a really special guy but he was
very like neurodivergent and I don't
think
um
I don't think the world is really the
kindest place to him and so uh yeah I
know it's off topic but I just want to
throw that out there
well but I mean it's a good message in
today's day and age and you know what a
great gift you have given the World by
preserving that interview with him
because it's preserved forever now and
it will be available forever out there
so
this is why I like you
he's the big reason that we have kiss
Organics in terms of the soil like heat
he came over when I was working out of
my dad's garage literally mixing soil on
a tarp because he wanted to grab some
compost tea supplies and uh I was like
here you know take some soil back
because he was running a bottled
nutrient program at the time and I was
like just try it out and he came back
you know a couple months later telling
me how wonderful it was and from there I
was we kind of like worked together to
try and like formulate this soil mix and
you know try it in different size
containers and different methods and he
was the one that really pushed this all
forward
um so I'm eternally grateful for him
like Kiss Organics probably wouldn't
exist if it weren't for Jaya
wow so well on a more interesting let's
move forward
um if you could have anybody alive
or gone you know if you wanted Thomas
Jefferson who would be the one person
your dream guest of all time to have on
the show
well I've thought about this not from
that perspective but the people that I
would love to get eventually on the
podcast uh Paul stamets I would love to
have him come on and talk about fungus
just in general I think he's so
fascinating
um I also think Michael Paulin would be
really interesting because I've read all
of his books and some of his things
around plants I think is really great
too so those will probably be the first
two that come to mind
for me in terms of like famous people
that I don't have access to that I would
love to get on the podcast someday
yeah no both of those would be amazing
because I've read Michael's books too
which you know with all the plant
history and everything but also Paul
salmon you know I'm you know being a
Star Trek fan and they have you know
Paul Simons is now on Star Trek you know
doing the Mycelia web and how they tied
that all in you know yeah I'm I'm a
bigger fan because of the Star Trek
tie-in now but um yeah those would be
two very interesting people to hear yeah
so but um you know with the podcast
being part of social media
um because it kind of all I don't want
to say it all ties in together but you
know going to social media for advice on
growing Tad
um how do you feel about that
I mean you know it's it's interesting
because
nowadays we don't have as much
connection and social media really is
that tool for Connection in a lot of
ways
um so in in some ways I think it's great
in other ways I think it's awful in
terms of advice for plants I don't think
that's the best tool you know
interestingly enough we've been posting
um every Tuesday a weekly plant trivia
photo or video and folks are you know
able to kind of guess at what they think
is going on and it's all in good fun but
when you look at the answers you can see
how much it varies you know and if it's
an insect it can be in anywhere from
spider mites to thrips to aphids you
know people are all over the place or if
you post a you know a photo of a leaf
people are like oh that's a phosphorus
deficiency or magnesium or calcium or
you know pretty much anything you can
imagine and it just shows how hard it is
to one even diagnose something from a
photo but two get like consistent advice
usually it's not enough information
you can't put enough information in your
post for someone to give you a very good
answer and a lot of times like even
you know trying to diagnose something
remotely as a consultant I think is
really challenging because you almost
have to walk into the room and see
everything that's going on because you
may spot something out of the corner of
your eye and be like oh well this is
this isn't right and this might be
what's causing this problem over here so
it's I think it's very tough
I back you up 100 on that as being a
consultant and I mean I am not a miracle
worker when it comes to diagnosing
problems from bad pictures I try to be
but I'm not but uh yeah it's a challenge
out there and I I mean I think
everything you're doing to try to put
good information out
um is is super helpful because it it's
it's very challenging though because you
know you have a daily business to run
and you know doing the podcast and then
trying to keep up with all the Social
Media stuff
um
can be very time consuming but I do give
you you credit for actually doing a good
job for keeping up with it because you
know I'm a little challenged sometimes
with that on that well you know you you
and I have the same problem like we have
to be the marketing department and the
social media department and the
technical department and you know all
these different things and granted I
have more help than you do but I will
spend as much time with a person with
two plants as I do with a person with a
thousand plants so we really do try and
answer everyone if you send me a message
uh you know through social media I will
answer it it may not always be like a
super in-depth answer but I always get
back to everybody and really try my
hardest to help as many people as we can
well again uh you guys do a great job
um but with that
um you know thinking about the business
and there's a lot of stuff you know that
is out of our control with our
businesses that are affecting us
for the soil company what what do you
see as some of the biggest challenges
coming up for you guys
oh you know it's been all over the board
lately I mean over the last two years
with everything with covet and supply
chain shortages
um it's been getting things material uh
and then cost increases with inflation
and then
um
Freight Freight's been the killer uh
it's been so hard to ship things because
of the cost of freight lately so
that's probably our biggest challenge
so we've been trying to uh work on
helping people Source things locally you
know and making recommendations that
allow them to do that but even that's a
little bit challenging because when we
go to make a soil we want to build it
around the compost and so if I don't
know what your starting compost is or if
it's not high quality it makes it really
challenging to build a soil and and also
build a safe product because we have to
know the heavy metal levels now that we
have heavy metal testing in a lot of
States and it's just it's more
complicated I think Than People realize
and it takes a while and and I've been
looking into other options because we
have people reach out and are like hey
you know I don't want to use anything
um that comes from the industrial
you know AG or slaughterhouses I I want
to or anything from the ocean you know I
want to be use vegan inputs or I want
things that are more sustainable and
I want those things too it's a matter of
figuring out how to maintain our
fertility and our plant health because I
don't want to sacrifice those things
either so it's it's a balance because as
we move for example
phosphorus the the easiest sources of
phosphorus are are bone meal fishbone
meal things like that they're they're
cheap they're you know relatively low
and heavy metals but they're not maybe
not sourced from an industry they're a
waste product from an industry that
maybe you don't want to support so now
we start looking into other things where
you can get them like for example insect
frass or some some uh plant-based
products that are higher in P or even
mined materials like
soft rock phosphate but now we're
looking at heavy metal levels that may
be higher than we want in order to get
our phosphorus so it I guess it can be
challenging like I've been trying to
find replacements for peat but I haven't
found anything yet that I can
effectively
you know I can put my kiss Organics seal
of approval or whatever on and say you
know I can get the same level of growth
or get near the same level of growth as
I can using uh peat moss in my mix so
it's a it's a constant thing we've been
working on this for years and I hope we
get there but it's been tough
yeah I've seen it with a lot of Growers
trialing all kinds of inputs who are
just even conventional Growers not even
to have the special Niche and the
standards you guys have
um just trying to find a replacement for
Pete and and trying to learn to grow in
it um and it's it's been very
challenging for the whole Horticultural
industry
um to find these Replacements but you
know over time you know we'll get it
worked out but finding something that's
sustainable is is a big challenge that's
uh
you know that's that's a hard one there
but it's it's good to see that you guys
are working to try to find Solutions
um and not just
sitting back and
um not trying to affect change you know
you are trying to make a difference and
try to do the right thing by the
environment and your customers which is
which is very good but go ahead no I'm
just gonna say like we are we are trying
our pet is sourced you know pretty local
to where we mix it so that helps quite a
bit and the sustainability thing you
know it's tough because it depends on
where you
where you're reading the the science is
it appears to be pretty mixed on how
sustainable Pete is as a product I put
together a blog post
um if you type in Pete versus Coco I bet
it'll just pop up in Google pretty high
on the list or go to our blog page and
type that in and you can see a more
in-depth discussion that I have on it
because there's really pros and cons to
to both yeah
um yes
that's like a whole nother podcast yeah
it's uh it's an interesting topic I
guess
um but the idea is like too like if we
can get people to reuse that soil and
not
be adding more peat to it you know by
managing it correctly
you know we have some guys like gold
leaf now I think they're like seven or
eight years using the same soil that
they they got originally that to me
feels pretty darn sustainable uh
compared to even people that are in
other media types that are you know
having to throw out their soil every
cycle and bring in new material
um I feel good about that
yeah no that's great but unfortunately
you know for the Horticulture industry
the plants have to get sold and go to
somebody's house so they don't even have
those options they constantly have to be
buying media so it's it's a challenge
um for sure
um but it's interesting to hear
everything that is happening
um in that area and see how things are
going to end up
um but you know as you mentioned you
know as compost basically being the
start of your soil
um and I know a lot of people that
listen to your podcast are obviously
very soil Savvy but
you know there are people that are
newbies and if somebody wanted to just
understand what compost is understand
about it do what do you have a
recommended resource for learning about
compost
no I know it's unfortunately oh man uh
that's tough it kind of depends on what
type of composting you want to do to
whether it's thermal or static or worm
or some combination of the three
um yeah I mean it's such a compliment
even the book that explains that
there was a book I had that went through
all the different kinds of composting I
mean I'm sorry it was not one of my
favorite classes I ha I needed one
elective and I like that was the
elective I got it was interesting
because I did discover a new species of
uh insect in my compost pile that made
it exciting for me
um but
um but yeah because I mean I I do think
um and I think we're all guilty of this
sometimes we're in conversations and
people are talking about a subject we
may know some about but we just sit
there and Nod and Shake our head going
along with we understand what they're
saying um because they're embarrassed to
say hey I don't know about this and I
think some people still
um want some of that background basic
information about soils and compost and
again just you're talking about the
different types of composting you know
people probably don't know there are
multiple types of composting
yeah I'm we're working on a some course
materials to put together something for
people
um
that may eventually and there are
there's books out there for sure I just
none popped to mine right off top of my
head I've read a lot of chapters and
books that are quite good on compost and
there's a lot of good information online
already I just don't have a ready
resource it's been a long time since
I've
done a lot of reading around compost but
I am working on putting together a
botany course with Don Marshall
for people who
you know like myself that didn't go to
school for this but I actually went back
to school just to take his botany course
but I want to put together an online
course where people like myself could
learn you know basic botany without
having to go back to school you know go
back to college and and take all the
classes where it could be broken down
into a more
Hands-On practical online course that
people could take in you know chunks as
as they see fit so we're working on that
right now together and I'm really
excited for that
and then also a cultivation course too
hopefully down the road that's also the
same sort of thing like easy tidbits of
good information all science based um in
sort of an online format so
hopefully we would have a section on
compost I think it's important
um
but just my big highlights on compost
it's not all created equal it really is
important if you're talking about making
an organic soil mix as you're to
incorporate that as your base to really
know what you're adding because that's
going to affect your pH it's going to
affect the microbial communities of that
mix it's going to
um
it's going to affect the nutrient load
and content it just it plays such an
important role and you know when I go to
the grocery store and I see these like
six dollar bags of compost and I look at
the ingredients or even just work
backward on the price I'm like okay well
the grocery store wouldn't have paid
more than like three or four dollars for
that so that means the company that made
it is if they're getting four bucks a
bag
they have to be making a profit on it
you know how much did the bag cost and
how much did the transportation cost by
the time you get down it that material
had to have been free or like pretty
worthless like what you're getting is
not high quality and
frankly I wouldn't use any of that stuff
in my garden
but um yeah it's just it's just another
way of looking at it like people think
all compost is good and it's it varies
it varies quite a bit so
yeah Source material
um because I lived in the land of
mushroom compost so it's it's yeah it's
very different than other compost for
sure
um out there but that's exciting about
the the botany class but botany was that
was a tough one in college for me
Horticulture Zips through that the
botany
yeah all the the Latin and anatomy of
all the plants and flowers so I'd
probably be interested in going back and
take a refresher on that because I took
botany in 1989. so well I know would you
probably weren't even born yet Tad were
you I was born 77. I'm I'm turning 45
next week
okay for folks
um yeah well you know also as a resource
in that regard uh Jeff lowenfell's books
like teaming with nutrients is a good
sort of like
basic botany book to give people an idea
of how
plant cells work and everything like
that so I'll shout that one out to Jeff
and he's got a new book coming out
teaming with bacteria which I'm I'm
going to be interviewing him soon on on
that topic so I'm looking forward to
that too so
well that's something
I'm looking forward to hearing those
um so again back back to the company and
you
um what does the future hold do you guys
have any big visions of projects coming
up you know where do you see yourself in
10 years
oh good question this is something so we
have a really good team right now
um it really feels like a family we all
work together really well
um very grateful for for who we have and
I really think
um everyone's in it for the long term
and
you know we talk about this and none of
us really have the ambition to be like
take over the world like we're not
looking to be a huge company because the
thing that we're most passionate about
is working with Growers and customer
service and right now we have a very
good handle on that I can confidently
say that you know everyone's going to
get a reply and a very good technical
reply to their questions and I think as
people get too big too fast you lose
that or even with a large corporation
you lose that so
I think uh you know we just want to stay
relevant and continue to do what we do
on the scale that we're at which
requires Innovation you know you can't
you can't expect to just keep doing the
same thing and and maintain your your
revenue and your your leads things come
and go and so we've tried to innovate a
little bit you know like we just added
the beneficial insects from biobee
um through your your advice and I'm
pretty excited about that we're always
looking for new
products that fit with sort of our
ethos and that we you know we would be
willing to use in our garden and so
that's I think that's where we're at
um we're potentially looking at
expanding to an East uh
sorry East Coast soil distributor that
could mix our soil out there but that's
going to be that's a longer process like
I said formulating a soil takes a year
or two you can't uh you can't rush that
process if you want to do it right it's
a lot of testing a lot of plant trials
and I want to make sure that if we do
put something out it's of the same
quality of what we're putting out right
now
that sounds great yeah I you know being
the biggest is not always the best I
think customer service and working with
Growers is I love working with Growers
just directly I I'm right there with you
on that
so so Tad if you didn't do soils and you
could have any job on the planet what
would be your backup career
oh boy
I don't know I mean it varies sometimes
I just wish I had a job where I didn't
have to be in charge where I could just
like go to work
do like a very like discreet activity
for eight hours and then go home and
just you know put it on a shelf and not
have to think about it and then go back
to work the next day uh as a business
owner you never stop working
um it it never your brain never gets to
shut off and it's it's challenging
sometimes
um
you know if I probably did anything
again it'd probably be back into special
education just because I really enjoyed
working with children and now that I
have a daughter of my own I I really
like watching her grow and
that I think the education teaching
thing is just it's really fun it's uh
it's it's very exhausting in a very
different way but it's so rewarding so I
I truly enjoy it
you know my mom was a special ed teacher
for many years probably didn't know that
yeah my sister was was a teacher too
until recently
um so yes I I watched my mom go through
the the the joys of what she was able to
do but also it's a very mentally
challenging uh profession to be in
um and it can be very hard
but well I'm happy you're on the soil
side of things so that we can be friends
and hang out and talk about bug stuff
um so I'm grateful to have you in the
industry so but with that
um if you had
um some advice to give people about the
industry
um what would you say to them
yeah so I thought about this as I was
like okay what questions might she ask
me and I thought about like what
from from all the years of doing the
podcast and everything I've been doing
like what are the pieces of advice that
I think would be most helpful for
Growers so I wrote down a few things
um so I'll just share that here if that
works um the number one thing that I
learned
and this was probably from Don Marshall
was figure out what your limiting factor
of growth is always start there you're a
detective when you walk into a when you
walk into a grow room or into a
greenhouse or whatever that scenario and
you know in maybe soil it may be your
watering it may be your light it may be
your environment but you really have to
figure that out first it's kind of like
you're you're a big push on you need to
identify that bug before you do anything
it's the same sort of mentality like you
gotta you've really got to be a
detective and figure that out first and
I think if people can start thinking
like that
it goes a long way to making like good
decisions in your garden and really just
paying attention you know some people
really have an eye for it I have to
really stop myself and slow down and
take a look around whereas I have other
Growers that I work with that like they
can walk into a room and instantly spot
it I just don't have that skill I really
have to like pause myself so that's
probably my biggest piece of advice
some other things that I thought about
is like try not to fall for marketing
hype you know I see these feeding
schedules and Organics that require
people to use like multiple products and
these are like popular companies with
popular products and people are all
excited about it but the end of the day
like to me that's no better than feeding
a bottle of nutrient line and you're
just you're throwing away money you
don't need all these products with these
enzymes and ferments and teas and all of
these things at the end of the day like
if that's it's all about that limiting
factor of growth and it's probably not
these things and so if you do get a
response from whatever you're adding
then you need to go back and figure out
why and figure out what it is that
you're that's lacking in your garden and
at the end of the day it's not a it's
not a product it's a mineral it's uh
something with your watering it's it's
something else
some other things is like you know read
the labels like know what's going on
with the product and realize that when
you read a label you're not getting all
the information you're probably not even
getting
half the information that you need on
that product and that's why it's
important to do your own sort of testing
don't trust manufacturers on things that
you know could ruin your livelihood like
heavy metals for example I've seen
I've seen heavy metal tests on reports
that people put out on social media on
their products and then I've had Growers
send me
heavy metal tests on that same product
that were vastly different and they they
sent it to me because they're like hey
we were you we failed for heavy metals
and so we tested everything and this
thing was nowhere near what we thought
it was and it's really really sad
because they lose they lose their crop
on it and
so I think as a grower like you you have
to do your due diligence
um you know don't don't trust anyone
when it comes to something that could
ruin your livelihood
um let's see what else oh soil tests so
I'm a big fan of soil testing I think
it's very important but I don't think
that it tells the whole picture so I
don't like to rely on Strictly on
calculators I think they're interesting
and they can point you in the right
direction but I still think you need to
talk to an actual agronomist or a person
who understands a soil test and can put
that into a context that makes sense
within the grow itself because
just looking at the mineral balancing of
a soil does not tell the whole picture
you need to look at the environment the
watering all these other things that I
mentioned before it's a complex
ecosystem and so this just gives you
another tool but it's not the full
picture especially if you're a
commercial grower I think you need to do
more than just a soil test you need to
have someone looking at the soil test in
relation to your plant Health in
relation to your bug pressure in
relation to your environment and
lighting and CO2 levels and then make a
fertility recommendation around all of
those things
um so it is complex
uh and then the last thing would be
don't fall for simplistic models of
thinking um there are so many different
camps right now just on the organic side
like not even talking about people who
are using salts but like on the organic
side there's
you know regenerative guys there's k f
guys there's soul food web guys there's
oh boy I could go biodynamics you know
there's there's this huge list there's
people who are using the you know so and
so's grow method it's everywhere and
some of them you know they're fine and
and
you can grow plants but I just want to
caution folks that there you know if
someone it's never just microbes or
enzymes or fermentations or nutrient
lines or lighting Brands none of those
things are keys to a good grow the keto
good grow is getting all of these things
correct within the context of you know
the all the variables so when people say
you know you just need the right these
microbes
um that's not the whole picture that
they're not taking into account your
temperature humidity your you know your
lighting all of these other things so I
I would just say at the end of the day
like just be careful and it's
unfortunate that I think that all of
these camps they almost feel a little
cultish to a certain extent where like
if you're growing in a different method
it's wrong and it just at the end of the
day especially on the organic side man I
feel like we should all be on the same
side like we're all trying to do right
by the environment we're all trying to
grow
safe cannabis healthy medicine and it's
it's crazy how much infighting that we
have going on because everyone wants to
be an expert and you and I we talk about
this a fair bit off air it it's it's
really unfortunate so those would be the
pieces of advice that I've learned over
the last I don't know how many years of
doing this I think
well I think that's super helpful
information because again I think all of
us are like you said are heading for the
same goal and
um you know it's it's challenging
um
when you feel like everybody's not
moving together it's it's it's for some
reason people have to go against each
other and and that's something I
appreciate about you because you are a a
very calm reasoning voice for me when
I'm having some challenges I'll call you
my you know industry therapists to help
me get through things
um and you know you've been a again not
only you know super great for the
industry but as a personal friend I
really enjoy being friends with you and
learning from you and looking forward
um to being friends for many more years
and hopefully working together in the
industry and you know again move all in
the same direction so we can take care
of this planet and
um leave uh behind a great place for
your daughter
I I appreciate that yeah it's uh I feel
very lucky to have this this opportunity
with the podcast and with the with the
business to do what we do like 99 of the
people we work with are awesome but
there is that one percent that sometimes
just uh makes you just throw your hands
up and wonder why you're doing what
you're doing
but I think that's any any industry
um
hey are we allowed to talk about your
new poster that's coming out is that
something we could I can mention or do I
know
um
so yeah speaking of things that I'm
excited about uh in terms of
collaboration with you is this poster
that you're working on um I can't wait
to get my hands on it and to be able to
get it out to Growers through catch
Masters I've been talking to them do you
want to talk a little bit about that
um
branding but
um cashmaster people just such nice guys
they really are I really enjoy them and
they wanted to do a collaboration of
making
um the first poster we're doing is for
what insects look like on sticky cards
and are they a pest are they a
beneficial or is it something you don't
have to worry about because looking at
pests or insects well has been officials
on leave sometimes can look a little
different on sticky cards because they
can change colors and the reflections
and so will be a poster Growers can hang
up at the facility to help them with
identification so I'm super excited for
that too
awesome yeah me too
I know you've been on me for years about
it is it almost ready
um I have to check back with them
because I
had graphic design I provided them all
the information I think the idea is to
um have it at the MJ bizcon in Las Vegas
this fall oh great well I I think I'm
going to be in the Bios Booth so maybe
we'll see you there
hopefully I'm planning on being there so
we'll definitely
um have to see you there and ride in the
Tesla Loop which was super cool and I
was out there last time
um but yeah no I think it's going to be
a good show this year again
well you're the host is there any any
other questions right I forgot well um
there's a lot of the key questions I
have and I think you know again people
that listen to you interview other
people are curious about you and you
know give them a little more insight
um you know about you a little bit about
your personal life where you came from
where you're going
um and I again I can't say it enough I'm
I'm very grateful for your friendship
and looking forward to learning more
from you in the future you know here's
to another another 100 podcasts well
thanks Suzanne I appreciate it you've
been too kind and
way too complimentary
um I'm glad you got a taste of what
hosting is like and I promise we'll get
back to our regular scheduled
um podcast I've already recorded too
with some awesome uh University
professors that I will be releasing for
101 and 102. and then uh I don't know
what's up next but I'm excited for it
well I guess since I'm supposed to close
this out thank you again Chad Hussey
from Kiss Organics for attending the
podcast today and answering questions
for us and looking forward to talking to
you in the future all right thanks
Suzanne foreign
[Music]
and colleague Suzanne Wainwright Evans a
bug lady Consulting interviewing me and
you are listening to the Cannabis
cultivation and science podcast if you
like the podcast please leave us a
rating and review and give us a follow
on Instagram you can also sign up for
our newsletter on our website homepage
to stay up to date on the latest
information and research thanks for
listening