[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and draw top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge if
you're enjoying these podcasts please
take a moment to subscribe to our
newsletter on our home page at WWE is
organics calm to stay up to date on the
latest podcast product announcements and
videos our guest this week is Amba clay
and is the co-author of the hidden half
of nature the book she wrote with her
husband David Montgomery in my last
podcast interview and is a biologist
writer and gardener with wide-ranging
interests she has over two decades of
professional experience spanning field
biology watershed restoration
environmental planning and stewardship
and public health she uses her broad
background and endless fascination with
the natural world to examine connections
between people and their environments
and attended the University of
California Santa Cruz earning bachelor's
degrees in biology and Natural History
she also holds a master's degree in
Landscape Architecture from the
University of California Berkeley well
thanks Ann I appreciate you coming on
the show today I'm really excited to get
to talk to you today yeah me too dad
thank you so can we start off giving
listeners a little bit of your
background yeah sure so I I come from
sort of a very broad background for you
know sort of formal education wise I
have degrees in biology and Natural
History and graduate degree in a field
that's called environmental planning
which is sort of a sub-discipline of
landscape architecture and so that's
that's kind of my formal training and I
have to say it's no surprise that I have
ended up
enamored with the botanical world
because of all of those things one of my
earliest memories as a kid I grew up in
the suburbs outside of Denver and one of
my earliest memories was wandering
around in our yard because you did that
when I was a kid there were no screens
or anything like that so what you did
was you went outside and you explored
the world and to me as a little kid the
yard was you know plenty big as a four
or five year old so here it was early
June you know memories of cold and snow
or dim in my mind but the garden the
garden hadn't really quite woken up but
I have to say this my parents were not
like green some kind of people there was
no big gardening history or anything
like that in my family but they had put
plants in and they had established a
couple of small rock gardens within the
larger yard and I remember walking
around to the back the back of the yard
one day and I was looking down at these
iris rhizomes and you know how ugly
those things look they look like a piece
of ginger and then I followed the stock
up and there was this flower that I just
could not believe that it had come out
of that gnarly you know dead looking
rhizome thing and so that's what I
credit with sort of the beginning the
beginning of what I now call a pretty
bad case of plant lust on my part I I've
always I've just always enjoyed being
around plants and growing plants and and
again in Colorado you can't you know now
I live in Seattle so we've got you know
pretty you know year-round growing
season for many things here Colorado
that was not the case so what I did was
I commandeered this very large table in
our living room and I started filling it
up with plants all different kinds of
plants and that was that was how I sort
of satisfied my my green thumb and my
plant lust as I got to be older and
figured out you know how to plant a
plant how to watch it grow and how to
take care of it and so on one of the the
things that I have always done though it
you know whenever you know one time once
I moved out of home and went to college
and stuff like that right you start
renting places and what are the yards in
most of these places that anybody rents
sort of look you know they're kind of
cruddy they're just there's not much
there most of the time and it's about
the last thing that a landlord really
wants to take care of so I sort of cut
my teeth on gardening at a lot of
different rental places over the years
and what was good about that is I think
growing plants is it's definitely one of
those trial and error kind of
experiences some things work out and
some things don't and a plant will let
you know you know pretty much right away
if it's if you're doing the right things
and if you're doing the wrong things
yeah yeah I think that's great and so
then you moved out to Seattle and
established your own garden I know you
talked about it in the beginning of the
Hidden half of nature which you wrote
with with David can you talk a little
bit about that experience with I know
you focused there on mulching and and he
had some unique perspectives from a
geological perspective on how quickly
you're able to build the soil in your
yard yeah yeah yeah sure it's funny
because it was about this time some
years ago that we really that we got
going so we had bought a house in
Seattle years ago and part of what drew
us today and this is in the middle of
the city pad you know this is not like
some extra large lot or something like
that so we're in the middle of Seattle
and what originally drew us to the house
remember we looked at the house in
February and so at that time of year
there's there's early February
there's not much going on but you know I
could see that there were
couple of trees you know obviously at
that time of year the all lawns in
Seattle are you know yeah that emerald
green color and and and what really
attracted me was it the house is built
on once it's it's was built on one side
of the lot and so that left the other
side of the lot really largely a blank
slate and I saw that and you know I just
had I had plants plants adorning my
eyeballs that was like all I saw was oh
man the garden potential here I've never
seen anything anything like this so we
didn't get get going on the garden quite
as soon as as we wanted we sort of had
some fixer-upper stuff to do inside of
the house and what's what's what's kind
of humorous at this point it was
definitely not funny at the time is that
once we did break ground to to do the
garden we began with sort of very unlike
today where people are demolishing
houses left and right around here we
didn't demolish the house we started
demolished everything that was out in
the yard and by that I mean as it turned
out the the trees that had looked alive
at least a couple of them were actually
dead and so so the first order of
business was to remove these couple of
dead trees there was a tree that's
called a horse chestnut that was
engulfing one side of the house and so
we removed that oh god and then there
was a mulberry tree that actually had
wonderful mulberries in the summer but
in the winter time it looked horrible
somebody had previously topped that tree
like about you know no less than ninety
nine times it looked like this Medusa
head and so anyway we got we we got the
stuff out of there that and it was
nearly everything because there was
really never to my eye anyway anyone who
had seriously gardened here at all it
was when we looked into the history of
house it was
Norwegians the austere Berg's who had
bought this lot and built the house and
think like a lot of people in this
region they at least at that time anyway
whatever blew in on the rain and the
wind that's what your yard was made of
so so the long and short of it is we got
everything cleared and we were doing
this you know as that summer progressed
as we were putting the garden and you
know we started like I said it was
around well actually it was Memorial Day
weekend that's right because the guy was
supposed to show up the Friday before
Memorial Day weekend and it had been put
off numerous times that this guy was
going to start and I remember just
laughing and Dave and I saying oh right
somebody's going to show up the Friday
before Memorial Day weekend to start on
a large job so we didn't be the guide
cancelled so many times we were so
surprised then when somebody his name
was Jim and he walked up the driveway
with a chainsaw and that's all he had
and he all he said was names Jim piers
start the job oh that day Jim let loose
he was a he had been a logger previously
so you know a handle a chainsaw you know
how to take all the stuff out and within
about three or four hours our place
looks like a moonscape and I completely
freaked out and I thought oh my god is
this really what we want this place
looks horrible there's not a stitch of
green left and some bare spots soil
we're starting to emerge and it only got
worse from there tad because we took
like this is about a month later or so
you know there was like a small
bulldozer thing driving around on the
lot doing leveling and this and that and
by that time of year
the lot our soil just I realized Dave
wasn't he wasn't you know he doesn't
need mammogram come to him it was like
dirt is dirt is dirt to me though I
thought oh man this is looking worse and
worse the soils getting like lighter
colored by the day the
rocks seem to be breeding and how is
this ever going to grow anything and
worst of all we got
we ended up planting you know many of
the plants that that I had because I'd
been sort of stockpiling them for the
last couple of years and they really
wanted to get out of their pots so we
start planting them and then we run into
the dreaded glacial till which is all
over Seattle the glacial till is this
hard pan layer it's almost as though
somebody snuck in back in time poured
concrete all over the place about 8 10
12 inches down and then they put the
soil back on top and so we'd hit this
hard pan with a shovel and it was just
like I broke my elbow broke my wrist on
that stuff and what this so we had that
was one problem and with just what had
happened on the lot over the years there
was no there was not any really organic
matter buildup because there were really
not many sources of organic matter at
all and so I so I'm asked I'm sort of
this guy bringing on PTSD or something
oh I remembered also the other big
problem at that time of year is like
water I'm like God we are you know I was
cursing the Landscape Architect oh my
god I can't believe we're out here
middle of August you know there's a
water shortage on the Cedar River and at
the time I worked in the water or in
salmon field and I'm like I'm just
killing salmon trying to you know keep
these plants alive and what I knew from
you know previous short short-term
gardening things that I had done you
know at these various places that we had
rented I'm like I gotta get some organic
matter and I just get organic matter and
bring it and just layer it on top of the
soil because that is going to cut down
on the watering first of all so I
scramble around for much of that August
and into the months of you know
September through December in the early
the next winter
getting any kind of free and cheap
organic matter that I could and bringing
it home and layering it on top of the
beds and it felt there's just something
really satisfying to me when especially
after having going gone through that
sort of you know somewhat traumatic
experience to mixing up just a really
nice mulch that has like you know at
least two maybe three or four different
kinds of organic matter and it's a nice
texture and there's a nice moisture
level to it and just laying it out on
the beds and I sort of feel like it's
everything's just taken care of and I
can walk away and I can let the green
bodies of all the plants in the garden
just do what they know how to do because
I there's there's definitely one thing
I've learned in putting this garden in
and taking care of it over the years is
all of us gardeners and I don't care if
you're growing cannabis or other things
although I definitely understand the
tendency with cannabis is intervention
intervention we gotta you know we're
trying to grow this stuff it's a cash
crop and so on and so forth but I really
have come to see over the years that if
you just give plants what they need
their their bodies really know how to
how to take care of themselves and it's
when we get in and start mucking things
up that it starts mucking up the way
that a plant's green body works and then
we run into you know pest problems or we
run into various other things and then
that turns into sort of a feedback loop
where then we have to jump in with some
other intervention to take care of the
first intervention that we caused so
that's definitely something I've seen in
my own garden especially as plants
mature and the trees in particular a
tree is just a really amazing thing
because the
it grows and as it begins to mature it
becomes in in sort of normal situations
it becomes better and better equipped to
take care of itself because it's
dropping these loads of organic matter
in the form of leaves on on top of the
ground and it's the perfect kind of
plant food for the tree itself so you
know I'm still so that that's sort of
the story of the garden and how it was
really by returning organic matter to
the soil that that I feel like it got it
got our garden off to a good start and
it really saved it really saved our
butts that first does that first couple
of summers when we were watering and
it's only continued to I think build the
health of the soil you know cuz some
people will come over and they're like
really you don't use any fertilizers or
anything like that and I'm like no I'm
not I I don't first of all I'm not going
to buy that stuff second of all in a in
the kind of garden that we have I'm not
looking at the exception of the
vegetable beds I'm not looking for rapid
not looking for these plants to put on a
lot of biomass and rapid growth because
these are all for the most part right
trees or perennials and these shrubs or
perennials and I want them to have a
nice steady rate of growth because any
any biomass that a plant puts out and
really sort of rapid short order that's
beyond what its body would do normally
that's just like putting out pest food
and pathogen food and that is something
you know no gardener no gardener wants
and so it's I like to see an I like to
see a plant that has a nice rate of
growth say you know in the spring and
then it slows down in the summer and
then that that's kind of that it just
you don't get gangly looking plants you
get robust and full looking plants and
like I said there's I don't think a
plant has the ability when it is putting
out a ton of growth I don't think a
plant always has the ability to to stock
all of its defensive chemicals
throughout all of the new new growth if
if you're you know heavily fertilizing
something I mean you ask anybody you
know oh when did the aphids come on or
when did this thing came on it's like
you know most of those problems happen
during not always but often during you
know growth spurts of of plants because
the pests know ah there's that nice
young fresh tissue there's where I'm
gonna go you know insert my my pincher
thing or my sucker thing and start
eating up this plant so I I really like
to think about I I what I like to do is
sort of is try to match a plant both to
my goals as a gardener and to what the
capability of the soil is and I feel
like a well grown plant is reflecting
the quality to soil and the quality of
the environment in which it lives so I
wanted to touch on this idea of organic
matter a little bit a little bit more
thoroughly in the sense that I know that
not all organic matter is created equal
I mean putting out chicken manure is
very different than putting out arborist
chips just based on the carbon to
nitrogen ratio can you touch on your
experiences with that and what you were
using as sources for orchid mulching in
your garden yeah yeah yeah you bring up
a really good point because I I I had a
beautiful tree it since died and I and I
blame myself partly for that it was this
it was this tree called two Red Bud so
this is a versus occidentalis is sort of
a native one what this tree is it's got
these gorgeous heart-shaped leaves and I
had a cultivar of it that had this great
name that I love Forest pansy
I mean who came up with that anyway this
tree this tree was was gorgeous that the
leaf color was knocked my socks off it's
actually the fall color on this tree and
when I planted that tree it was a bare
root tree it was like maybe the diameter
of my thumb and my index finger together
so pretty small tree and I was fortunate
enough to win the zoo do lottery and the
zoo do for those listeners who don't
know this is composted manure of the
herbivores at Seattle Zoo so the zoo has
a program where they handle all the
composting of that manure and then every
spring and fall you send a postcard in
and you can get to do and it is an
animal manure and it is animal manures
are high in nitrogen and we know that
nitrogen is what fuels mostly the green
growth of plants and so I thought I'll
just tree needs to do so that's what I
did I put a lot of Zuzu on that tree
probably two or three seasons in a row
and boy let me tell you that tree grew
it really grew but that tree also has a
problem it's got really lousy branching
structure which is to say that that tree
really wants to be a shrub it has no
central dominant leader that you know
shoots up and that has you know
well-behaved and well-structured lateral
branches coming off of that central
leader so I what this tree had was maybe
four or five dominant leader stems
shooting up to the sky and the problem
with that after about its tenth year was
that those branches those little stems
became bigger and bigger and bigger
branches heavier and heavier and it
began to split right where those
those branches joined the main trunk of
the tree and I thought back to what was
going on and part of it was like I said
it's just the natural structure of that
tree but also I had boosted the growth
like crazy of that tree in the early
years with all of that zoo do you know I
knocked that off after like several
years because I was sort of standing
back going wow this tree is growing
bigger faster than I ever thought it
could and at that point I just started
doing straight wood chip mulch as and
straight wood chip mulch for me I really
like because it's really really good at
doing two things yet suppresses weeds
and it does not give a seed a weed seed
place to germinate and because woodchips
are almost well they're from a
composting standpoint they're considered
you know purely you know all carbon very
they're not really they're not a
nitrogen source at all so I like that
because it's a very slow feed slow
decomposition process as as the
woodchips come in contact of course with
microbial life in soil and other and
sources of nitrogen in the soil it they
will decompose but it's but it's a slow
process so that was my hard lesson in
learning the difference between carbon
sources of organic matter and nitrogen
sources of organic matter and now around
my trees because they're all they're
healthy they're they're doing their
thing of putting on a normal amount of
growth for whatever species they are I
don't I do straight wood chip mulch on
my trees and what I save my nitrogen
rich sources of organic matter for which
these days my primo source of of
nitrogen rich organic matter my prized
source which I always wish I could have
more of is the worm compost that I get
out of my worm bins and that is solely
dedicated to my vegetables my vegetable
beds because you know vegetables I
they'd be you know the closest thing to
cannabis right these are annual crops
and what you're looking for is lots of
biomass rapid growth in with my
vegetables you know I want to get them
to whatever they're harvestable state is
whether that's a fruit like a tomato or
a floppy floppy green leaf or or
whatever so that's where I dedicate my
nitrogen sources of organic matter is in
the vegetable bed and other places I do
I'll do spot I'll juice I'll do spot
composting say you're not composting but
I'll I'll put out my zoo do as
perennials are coming up if I see that
one is sort of poking along I'll go and
I'll I'll call top dress with compost
might add I never I rarely rarely well I
actually never I I never did organic
matter into my existing soil and in part
that's because I've got an existing
plant there and so I don't want to be
messing around with its roots and be
trying to get organic matter down you
know in you know several inches down
below the soil what we're really blessed
with in Seattle here is with all this
rain
you know I can put compost around the
crown of a perennial I might throw a few
wood chips on top of that compost and
then I let I let you know the rain and
the heat and microbial action decompose
that and and pull those nutrients down
into the soil which then brings him in
contact with the roots and the plant can
take up what it needs and wants in that
way so that's that's uh that's sort of
how I think about organic matter I have
to say I'm somewhat I think there's
something instinctual in human beings
both both about hoarding things the
friend who says yeah that's the whole
problem with agriculture turned us all
into a bunch of hoarders we're hoarding
grains were
reading plans well in my case I'm kind
of an organic matter order and and that
is to say that mostly what I coordinate
this has to do with the quantities in
which it comes and that is wood chips if
I get you know three or four or five
yards of wood chips I don't the soil
can't take I you know all of those wood
chips at one time so I store I store
wood chips and I will pull them out at
different times of the year you know
typically fall in spring is when I like
to spread wood chips but if I'm doing
something in the summer and I know oh
yeah I've got my stash of wood chips I
can just go quickly you know get a
wheelbarrow full and do some spot
mulching where say you know I'm finding
it thin in one area because that's it's
it's very you know organic matter is and
the way that it breaks down and and
becomes incorporated into the soil
it's very elusive because you'll think
you've put an adequate amount out there
and you know by that I mean you know
three four five inches let's say and
then I go out in mid mid to late summer
and I'm like where'd all that stuff go
I'm like scratching around and you know
I have like a half an inch or an inch
left so sometimes depending on the plant
in the situation and exposure and aspect
you know I might I might sort of touch
up mulch in the summertime but I i
generally I guess the upshot on all of
that is nitrogen where I want lots of
biomass and especially leafy growth I'll
put that out the other thing I pay
attention to with vegetables is so that
you know the end the bag of fertilizer
and the whole NPK thing so fruits in
order for you fruiting vegetables you
know tomato or cucumber or something
like that
I put always a little bit of phosphorus
out later a little bit later in the
summer to get to make sure that the
plant has enough phosphorous to get it
going in its fruiting stage and of
course what comes before fruit is the
flower so I like to pay attention to
that for when I'm growing you know
fruiting vegetables something something
else
oh yes basil I love to grow basil just
because there's just nothing that beats
fresh pesto and that's certainly a
nitrogen and nitrogen hog of a plant and
you'll get some pretty fantastic results
I remember one garden I had before I
knew a whole lot I was always putting
barely composted chicken manure out
around some basil it didn't burn it but
oh my god I got like just incredible
incredible leaves a basil that year
somewhere almost as big as the palm of
my hand so you know that that's what
nitrogen and nitrogen rich sources a
compost in organic matter can do for you
so just real quick I just want to let
listeners know that when you're talking
about woodchips you're talking about
arborist chips and I know for us with
our with our farm we have a relationship
with local arborist he's a good friend
of ours and so whenever he gets a load
of deciduous chips we always request
those in because they break down faster
and then we'll use the Evergreen chips
or things like that from those trees as
our pathways because they take a little
longer to break down right so we use
wood chips a little differently they're
great in our in our chicken yard because
the high carbon is balanced with the
nitrogen from the chicken manure so they
they break down quite quite nicely and
give us a nice layer of compost
underneath yeah so it works really well
yeah but I wanted to go ahead and
transition in
talking about sort of your area of
expertise in terms of the biological
aspects and the role that the microbes
play in breaking down this organic
matter and in sort of making these these
nutrients available to the planet yeah
we just posted on on Twitter the other
day this really interesting paper that
that came out that I knew this before
but I always like to be reminded of it
and it and it's this we think we think
about organic matter as being plant
derived in a garden and I'm thinking of
my garden specifically you know I'll see
leaves in the fall and they've come off
the trees and they're right where I want
them I think about that organic matter
you know being a part of the nutrient
cycle that is feeding the tree what this
paper showed is that most of the organic
matter I don't know about most much of
the organic matter in soil it's true
that it starts with plants but all of
that organic matter becomes incorporated
into the bodies of trillions and
trillions of microorganisms so that's
bacteria that's fungi that's protists
that's all kinds of things and not just
the microorganisms but becomes
incorporated into the bodies of the
things that eat the microorganisms so
you step it up to you know slightly
larger forms of life you know worms and
nematodes and and so on so that most of
the organic matter that ends up in soil
it's getting there not because it's dead
plant matter but because it's dead
microbial matter and this is a really
interesting way to think about organic
matter in organic matter cycling because
how do we get a lot of microorganisms
you know flourishing and thriving in
this
by this I mean the beneficial ones we of
course are not talking you don't want a
bunch of pathogens in the soil we want I
always want our beneficial
microorganisms and other life forms to
be in larger numbers bigger populations
and so on than the the pathogens and
pests and so when you have all of these
life forms in the soil they're just like
us at our dinner table and they need to
eat and so this is what the plants are
doing this is what all this dead plant
matter is doing whether it's wood chip
or a fresh green leaf that is food for
all of the microorganisms which become
the organic matter that is what ends up
in the soil and it it even goes beyond
that because we know now that there's a
one of the most life dense zones on the
entire planet is around the root system
of a plant and that area is called the
rhizosphere RHIC oh and then sphere so
sphere is you know just area around and
raizou
is I can't remember if it's Greek or
Latin for root but I think about it as
the house of the root the area of the
root and that's where bacteria and fungi
in particular are running to the root
system of a healthy plant and a healthy
soil as though that is you know their
dinner and there's a very good reason
for that this area called the
rhizosphere is where a plant will take
up to like 40% of all of these compounds
that it has made through photosynthesis
and these compounds are things like
carbohydrates and fats and proteins and
it turns these compounds well a
microorganism considers all of that
stuff food and so a plant is exuding
these compounds out of its roots that
the the name for that is exudates you
just think outward flowing food from the
root system marker ordinate Mike
organisms lap that stuff up and then in
return they're making metabolites out of
this out of these compounds that they've
received from the plants and like any
organism they excrete things out of
their bodies and some of the microbial
metabolites that have been discovered in
the soil include things like plant
growth promoting hormones and so this is
pretty this is really interesting you
know you've got one part of the world of
life the microorganisms making things
that help another completely area of
life the botanical world so these are
some of the things that happen in the
rhizosphere
and it it tells us that this is also one
of the we often think about coevolution
as as being on occurring in the
above-ground realm of a plants green
body you know the birds and the bees and
the flowers and intricate intricate way
in which that all works but the
symbiotic relationships below ground are
just every bit as sophisticated and
long-standing as what is going well
there actually go back even further
because they predate flowering plants so
this is this is really this is really
fundamental and it's really important
that we have some of the grandest
symbiotic relationships on this planet
occurring right beneath our feet and in
a place that we still don't understand
that well and we don't we we may never
know how everything works and what what
that tells me is is a couple things
because this is what's going on in the
soil around the roots of a plant is so
fundamental to a plant's health and
well-being that really what we ought to
be doing with whatever kind of plant
we're growing is seeking ways to support
those symbiosis because
long before we had agrochemical
companies long before we had bags of
fertilizer and and all of these other
various things in the agricultural and
horticultural world all the plants ever
had was the symbiotic relationship where
it's feeding the microbes the microbes
are making metabolites and the plant is
pulling in those metabolites and it's
not only just metabolites but fungi in
particular will they they can greatly
extend well functionally anyway the
reach of a plant's roots and so they'll
be out far away from a plant pulling
things like phosphorus that's the P of
the NPK out of the soil and they
transport it back to the plant and give
it to the plant and so these are the
sorts of natural processes that we don't
need to pay for them I'd rather have I'd
rather have fungi doing my work for me
then you know running out and buying
synthetic fertilizers and it we also
know that you know plants and the
microbial the soil microbiome they've
worked out their relationships with
their their trades in the rhizosphere in
ways that keeps both you know the rate
and growth of the plant sort of in
balance with the soil so you're not
getting excess growth that becomes you
know food for food for some pests or
pathogen so I really think of the
microbial world the soil microbiome
which you know in the root microbiome as
it's sort of like the plant Arsenal
combined with the plant pharmacy
combined with the plants say cellular
communication device because there's a
ton of signaling that goes on between
the microbes around the roots and in the
plant itself that that are related to
how plants defend themselves against
above ground and
low ground pests and how plants are
communicating with one another I mean
it's it's a really really fascinating
world and I I would love it if I know a
lot of cannabis growers for legitimate
and historic reasons they're growing
they're growing these plants inside and
I think that that is that's just the way
it is and I get that
but there is it I think that's hard on a
plant's body to be to be sort of taken
out of out of where a plant would
normally grow which is in the soil
outside in sunlight exposed to you know
all kinds of biological and
non-biological factors that give the
plant its its hardiness the case of food
plants taste and flavor in the case of
cannabis you know all of these
phytochemicals that translate into
flavors and smells and whether one's
using cannabis medicinally or psycho or
for recreational reasons everything that
it that everything that went into the
that plants growth is manifest in in
some ways by the growing environment
that it came out of so I would love to
see more cannabis grown outside and in
the Sun although I completely understand
why it's not and why in such cases you
know you just need more interventions
you need more more assist of plants if
they're grown indoors but it's I don't
know how that's gonna ever turn you know
whether it's yeah I think that's a
that's a difficult thing because it's
just not this is just not sustainable
either so anyway I hope that I hope that
things can turn around on that front
with cannabis cultivation well I think
there are some issues
around temperature in in terms of in
some areas like here in Washington okay
yeah it's just it's too cold to grow it
outdoors for large portions of the year
right one of the things that we work
with Brewers on is trying to incorporate
what a lot of people are calling living
soils with the idea being that we're
cultivating these microbial interactions
and reusing the soil to create this
ecosystem similar to we would have
outdoors because like you mentioned
these phytochemical reactions that are
going on or interactions really do have
a large influence on the odor and the
flavor of whatever crop you're growing
and there are some nutrients that are
tied to to terpene expression like
sulfur but a lot of it is the microbial
community and one of the one of the
interesting statistics that I think
really shows how important that is to
the plant is it's been it's been
established that something like 30% of
the of the energy that the plant takes
in through photosynthesis is putting
back out through the roots as a way of
fostering that microbial relationship in
the form of exudates which she described
I just think that's that's amazing that
they would give up that much of the sort
of nutrients that they're taking in just
to you know promote this symbiotic
relationship yeah
and you know it makes a lot of it makes
a lot of sense biologically because
plants have this thing that no other no
other life form has and that is the
ability to capture sunlight combine it
with water oxygen and through
photosynthesis make food you're some
soil organism living in the dark
subterranean and and you're on the roots
of this thing that is basically a food
factory and and at the same time you're
able as a microorganism to do equally
impressive chemistry with you know the
things that are available
to microbe in the soil and then hand
that over to a plant I mean it it's what
it really does is it takes sort of the
genomic potential of a plant and all of
its photosynthetic capability and it
takes a genomic potential of say a
bacterium and it makes this new organism
that is sort of fully fully capable of
using everything that's in the
above-ground environment and the below
ground environment and bring it together
into this I don't want to go so far as
to say a new life form but with a lot of
the microbiome research that's that
conceptually at least is how people
think about not just plants but also
people and you know all kinds of things
from the goldfish to the to the polar
bear there's what we see in what we
think is the life form but then there's
what we can't see the invisible that
tells us that we are all sort of in
amalgamated
at that is a really different way to
think about a plant a person anything
like that yeah yeah isn't there
something about how the majority of what
the number of cells on the human body
the majority of them are actually not
human cells but microorganisms or other
other living I think you know yeah yeah
that's right there at when early several
years ago there was sort of an estimate
that got out there that was inaccurate
that there was ten times as many
microbial cells as human cells in the
human body and it's it's since been
adjusted and it's around at least at
least equal numbers if not slightly more
microbial cells but however you look at
that if if you look at a person you
think okay that person's half person and
half microbe it you know it puts a whole
new light on things like what are those
microbes doing
maybe people should take care of their
microbes since they're a part of their
body and since they do things like you
know they help us digest our food really
interesting work is being done around
sort of brain health and the gut
microbiome because for example Sarah
serotonin is a neurotransmitter and it
helps our brain work and it affects
whether we're feeling happy or sad and
so people had assumed for a long time
all that serotonin that must be made up
in the brain because that's where most
of it's used no in fact most of the
serotonin is made in the lower reaches
of our gut by our members of our
microbiome so that tells us that you
know there's some pretty fundamental
connections between health of our bodies
the health of our minds and what our gut
microbiota are doing and this is where
much like the diet of the soil you know
we talked about different forms of
organic matter and what the responses of
a plant are to the different forms of
organic matter and really are our gut is
is very much analogous to the root
system of a plant because we've got all
these microbes living living in our
digestive tract especially the lower
reaches and they need to eat and as it
turns out all you know for years and
years we've all heard oh you should eat
your fruits and vegetables are good for
you they're good for you no they're not
so much as good for you as they are the
fodder that it appears feeds the
microbial strains and species and
communities that are the ones that churn
out a huge number of compounds and
molecules that have medicinal effects in
our body so you know I mentioned
serotonin is one such metabolite there's
another compound called butyrate that is
really important for
: health and also important in sort of
modulating and regulating the way our
immune system works so just like the
root the root microbiome is making
things like you know I've mentioned the
plant growth promoting hormone which is
a good thing for the plant our
microbiome is making all kinds of
compounds and molecules that have it's
not just there's many beneficial effects
but you get just like in the soil you
get something funky going on and then
you can have your microbiome may be
making compounds and molecules that
aren't so good for us but we do know
that across the board it seems that you
know a high-fiber diet which is to say
one that is an abundance not exclusively
but certainly an abundance of
unprocessed plant foods is is something
that our microbiome really really
thrives on yeah it's very it's it's very
interesting yeah I I recently heard a
podcast by Paul Stamets oh that was just
it was great it was on the Joe Rogan
podcast I can send you a link to it if
you haven't heard it but he talks about
the role of a fungi and how it it's in
its impacts on human health certain
things like lions made for example he
said there's found that you can actually
form new neurological connections in
your brain so I've started taking some
of his muscle mushroom supplements
Beyonce and I and we feel like they're
making a difference in terms of how we
feel and there is some research to
support this it's pretty interesting and
I'm not talking about psychoactive
mushrooms so that is something he
discusses as well in the podcast which
is really interesting but just the
normal mushrooms that you could find in
the grocery store right right yeah there
are there are it's it's the whole
mushroom world is I think greatly under
researched you know we know we know a
bit of
you know phytochemicals say for example
in cannabis you know we know about
phytochemicals in tomatoes or carrots
and some of these things but thinking
about the phytochemicals say from fungi
because what happens in our gut with
with these phytochemicals that are that
are bound up when we're eating whole
plants or whole whole mushrooms or
mushroom extracts I would also expect to
some degree is that our gut microbiota
get ahold of these phytochemicals and
they they basically they're fermenting
them and when they ferment them it turns
it in to other bioactive compounds and
products that our body knows what to do
with those things so that's where
mushrooms whole plant foods I don't want
to call them drugs but they can have
drug like effects in us and I think part
of that probably goes way way back in
human evolution where when we were
hunter-gatherers right all we were doing
was eating wild plants and sometimes you
know maybe you ate the wrong thing and
you were done with but knowledge and
tradition was passed down from
generation to generation and that's
where of course all the traditions of
herbal healing come in and so these
plants were you know I think in some
ways became a part of our bodies because
people knew in those times okay this
plant for this ailment this plant for
this malady we know this plant comes up
in the spring and we know this malady
often comes up in the spring and so
let's put those two things together I
don't know maybe this is the deep roots
of my plant lust yeah I think I think
anybody who ventures into growing a
plant of some sort it gets you in touch
with our relationship to the botanical
world and really how ancient how ancient
it is and how much we need to have
plants in our lives for
kinds of reasons you know from aesthetic
to medicinal to recreational to you know
just the amount of carbon cycling that
plants are involved with on this planet
we we all I think tad would would do
better if we got in touch with our the
roots of plant lust I'll leave it at
that
so beyond mulching how else can we
foster the this microbial relationship
that the plant has win it its microbiome
yeah I think you know as much as we love
our plants and I certainly get it
especially somebody in a in an
agricultural or a cannabis growing
environment right are our hands in our
minds in one way or another are all over
that plant we want that plant to grow
and we will do anything just about to
get that to allow that to happen and I
think I think our penchant for sort of
interfering with the interference isn't
the right word
our penchant for sort of manipulating
and managing things I think we need to
maybe check that at the door more than
more than we do because the more we sort
of think we're gonna one-up Mother
Nature or we're gonna one-up you know
how this plant is growing and variably
you're altering you're altering
something about about the trajectory of
that plant's life and that in the way
that that plant is growing and I think
stepping back and going okay on the
whole you know what are the consequences
of me doing this is it going to get it
going to net me really what I want or is
it or might it possibly have this
downside as I think I really think
growing plants is figuring figuring out
okay what does this plant want to do
what is its body primed to do
what can I do as the grower to give it
everything it needs to let you know to
let that growth occur so I like thinking
about sort of getting out of the way of
natural processes but not to the point
of just walking away from something but
being mindful about okay how are my
practices how are my practice is really
going to help things along and so for
example I realized that for some
situations in cannabis is certainly one
of them you know actually I would I
would I would almost consider cannabis
to be in the same world as bonsai but
you know they're in different places on
that continuum these are both highly
manipulated kinds of plants and growing
environments and you can get beautiful
results in both cases but to just be
aware that we are in the end you know
working with the botanical world as
opposed to you know trying to get the
botanical world to do things that it
just really you know isn't isn't going
to be good at doing so you know and in
fact I've done my own share of you know
manipulating and managing plants in my
garden from the way that I prune things
from the way that you know I'll take a
look at a plant and if it's if it's if
it's been sickly for too long I don't
have many plants like this but I've been
known to to pull a plant up and say okay
I'm done with you I don't know I don't
know what is ailing you you know I've
tried this and this and this but you're
out of the garden and this just was not
a good place for you so there's also
there's also that space of of knowing
that you know the chemistry and and I
don't mean that in the you know
synthetic chemistry the metaphorical I
mean this in the metaphorical chemistry
sense you know the chemistry is just not
right between you and the soil between
me and you between the place that I have
for you and so we're you know gonna put
everybody out of their misery right now
and all I will I'll pull up a plant and
and that that's that's really hard to do
though tad because for a person with
plant list right you're like oh what am
I doing here then in the end you know
most the time it actually works out okay
because I gained some new real estate to
put something else in that spot that I
think I've made a better selection about
how it's going to respond to you know
that particular setting in the garden
yes so just to keep things moving along
for the listeners I wanted to ask a
little bit about your upcoming work I
know you and your husband David are
working on another book I was curious
what role cannabis might play in that
yeah we think so you know not
surprisingly after writing the hidden
half of nature and actually call it you
know there's the dirt trilogy hidden
half a nature is the middle book and
dirts the first one and then growing
revolutions the third one it's odd tad
that despite these three books we have
not really we've touched on but we have
not really taken a deep dive into
exploring the question of does does soil
health affect and influence human health
and if so how what are some of those
connections and relationships anyone
listening to this podcast anyone who
talks to me will know that yes and and
and day for that matter think that there
definitely are some connections but what
we want to do is dig deep into the
science and bring the story to readers
in ways that are you know entertaining
and informative and there's two crops
I'll call them crops that we think it's
every bit as legitimate to talk about
cannabis and wine grapes in the same
breath as we talk about our food crops
and the connections between soil health
and human health because wine grapes and
cannabis are part of the botanical world
in one way or another we bring the
tissues and products that we make from
those plants into our bodies
and we know they're doing things inside
of our bodies and so it stands to reason
then that what is how we cultivate
cannabis specifically what does that
have to do with the quality of the
products that we're using whether it's
medicinal or recreational or
what-have-you
so that so we wanted we want to take a
look at that as I think with cannabis
you know the trajectory despite I think
what's going on at the national level
I just think cannabis is going to be
come legal in more and more states and I
think consumers to have resources at
hand to know how is this cannabis grown
and also to educate consumers to about
sort of the role of phytochemicals in a
plant's body and how that translates to
the desired effects whether you're
looking for some kind of couch walking
or whether you're looking for something
more clear-headed or whether you're
looking for something on the medicinal
and that's that's all really important
and we hope in the new book to sort of
spill the beans so to speak on that
story so whether it's terroir that
you're talking about with wine grapes or
cannabinoids and Turkey an expression
with cannabis really it's a mat it's a
combination of that sort of relationship
between nutrient content and soil health
and the microbiome in the rhizosphere
and how all these interact these complex
interactions are occurring that creates
sort of that final plant tissue or fruit
that we're that we're consuming
ourselves right yeah I would just add to
that what I'm seeing with these living
soils and getting feedback from some of
the growers that we work with is higher
levels of terpenes down there seeing
traditionally across the same cultivar
so it used to be in the medical days
here in Washington that you would go
into a store and they would just say
here
you know this is what they have and it
would be let's just say oh gee cush is
one of the names of one of the cultivars
for example and so you would just get
you would get that there wasn't a lot of
test results you weren't talking about
the you know odors and flavors of the
crop it was just it is what it was it
was just the name sort of thing and now
you'll see different growers growing the
same cultivar and getting very different
results and before I think it used to be
more about just THC levels like people
would get in trouble for carrying high
amounts of cannabis on them so they want
to carry less cannabis so they'd want
stronger cannabis so they could carry
less of it you know if they can get 20%
THC versus 10 percent THC they could
carry half the amount or you know
consume half the amount so now what
we're finding is the as the as the sort
of the community evolves and is the laws
change people are more interested in
these terpene levels that were they're
testing for and how they affect the not
only the psychoactive effects of
cannabis but also the you know the the I
guess I would say the recreational
process of consuming it which is you
know similar to wine in the way that we
evaluate it in terms of how when
described it so I think that that's
really interesting as you know as the
industry evolves yeah you know what I
think would be really really fun in the
future to do is to have you know we have
there's cannabis cannabis tasting events
like the Emerald cup I think is one and
there's wine tasting events and there's
tomato tasting events I think it would
be great to organize an event not based
on these crops but hey let's have let's
have an event about all of the wonderful
edibles and quaffable 'he's from the
whole botanical world and so it would be
an event on phytochemicals like okay we
know this tomato has you know
particularly high levels of like
okay tasters you know what do you think
and then also be having it the same kind
of thing okay what about the
phytochemicals in you know the wines
what are what are we what can we
associate with these and what about
these phytochemicals in cannabis and I
think I think in modern life were just
so disconnected from not only how we
grow our food but you know what this
whole endeavor of agriculture is is and
has been all about I mean sure it was
always about survival in getting enough
to eat that's that's obvious but
certainly at another level part of all
of this is about pleasure and it's about
fun and it's about flavor and taste and
effect and being knowledgeable enough to
know okay yeah right okay I've had
enough of sugar or I've had enough okay
no more no more cannabis for me or you
know no more wine for me so I actually
think if people were more educated about
the effects of all of these botanical
foods beverages and so on it would be it
would it would be I think I don't know a
more interesting way to move our way
through the world of a grocery store of
farmers markets you know a party you
know having guests over and so on I mean
there's there's there's no doubt in my
mind that humanity has long long flocked
toward you know things like sugar and
alcohol and and getting high it's a
matter of okay well let's let's take the
pleasure from that but let's not overdo
it yeah I think it's interesting as
someone who works around a lot of
chickens as a farmer we find that they
can regulate their calcium levels we can
just put out eggshell or oyster shells
and they will they will regulate that
based on I need it you know what they
need
Wow 16 did
you know I think it's 16 18 percent
calcium in their diet or maybe it's
protein I might be confusing the two
right now but basically you don't have
to regulate that for them and I think we
do the same in terms of our own needs
like when we crave sugary foods or salty
foods based on what what our bodies may
need but interestingly enough I met with
Tom Wagner who's a local plant breeder
specifically known for tomatoes and
potatoes Green Zebra being one of the
ones locally here that's oh yeah that
he's created and what he's really
interested in is Tomatoes with high
protein content which is associated with
the flavor
umami oh wow they've found this
association between the umami flavoring
and protein so he's purposely breeding
for tomatoes with higher umami levels as
a way of flavoring as a way of selecting
for higher protein so I thought that was
interesting you know that is really that
is really interesting and it's it's also
interesting to me because of the ability
for us as as human beings to equate
flavor with quality and right proteins
protein is an important thing that our
bodies have and umami is a flavor that
we like and so voila the two come
together and we're consuming a diet of
food that is actually good for us yeah
I'll have to put you in touch with them
I think you guys might yeah yeah yeah
this whole I've been reading this
reading some books on wine lately and
the whole way in which I recently
learned for example next time
Ted or listeners whoever's out there
next time you take you're drinking wine
take in the equivalent of about a
teaspoon
of the wine and don't immediately
swallow it but imagine its food and kind
of chew on it and it pushes the wine
into all these parts of your mouth and
you're sort of back at the throat area
and it hits taste receptors that I
didn't even knew I didn't even know I
had and the wine washes over these taste
receptors and it tastes completely
different than the normal way of just
sort of pulling in them out you know
some wine and swallowing it and it was
it it had it completely the flavor of
the wine like I'm like wow I'm actually
tasting this wine I never I know I don't
it was a whole new experience and
because we chew on food we are probably
hitting more taste receptors with food
than we are with the things that that we
drink so anyway I just recommend that to
people and see what you think about it
you'll find how many different flavors
there are and wine and it also makes me
think about the phytochemicals in wine
and what what's going on with them as
they you know pass through your mouth
and then further on down in the gut so
really really interesting connections
between phytochemicals flavor nutrition
and health and wellness and I think I
know there's books out there people have
talked about you know part of the
purpose of taste receptors in our body
and actually receptors in our gut as
well on on cells is to pick up
specifically on phytochemicals because
they're interacting biochemically with
our bodies in all kinds of ways all
kinds of ways yeah it's a it's a
fascinating topic one of the books I
really enjoyed you might want to check
is called proof it's by a gentleman
named Adam Rogers okay he looks at the
science of booze and that's one of the
one of the things he talks about is how
how we evaluate wine and just how
qualitative that process is it's pretty
interesting I think I think you'll
really enjoy it yeah I will send you a
link to that as well but cool thanks
again for your time today
I enjoyed chatting it's such a beautiful
Seattle day that we get so rarely here I
feel like we should get off the phone
and allow you to get back outside of
your garden get out to the garden get
your hands in the soil yeah okay that
that sounds good Chad yeah I've really
really enjoyed this I love talking about
as you can tell I like I like microbes
and soil and plants and the human body
and how we're living on this planet and
can take better care of it yes so just
just to summarize your big takeaways
would be for people to however their
gardening is to increase their amount of
organic matter in their soils in the
form of mulching which has a bunch of
benefits and then also not overdo it
allow the plant to sort of reach their
own genetic potential without without
pushing them too hard in the traditional
garden is that is there anything else
yeah no those are great that that's that
is exactly it and and I would just say
one last thing that we didn't we didn't
hit on but I think about in the context
of not pushing your plants too far and
the organic matter is to realize that
the soil has a metabolism I think of it
as a metabolism just like our body does
and overwhelming the body of soil with
too much of any one thing is what we
want to you know veer away from is it's
sort of like you know even too much
mulch too much organic matter the soil
can't handle all of that it's like
sitting down to you know instead of one
plate at dinner like three platefuls you
just you're going to feel not
and overfed and it's just not going to
just not going to work well so being
mindful of the soils ability and the
microorganisms in the soil to process
that organic matter in a in a timely
fashion and I I think they're sort of
like the secret mission of the natural
world is if a gardener is paying
attention to the metabolism of their
soil it also keeps that gardener
connected to the natural world right
because you've got to be out there sort
of checking on that metabolism a little
too much here oh we need a little more
over there and so it it I I think about
maybe a gardener as being more maybe
something more like a shepherd tending
its flock it's just that our flocks are
green and stuck in place so we need to
sort of herd them along with the things
that we know about what they like and
how their bodies work great well again
thanks for your time today and I look
forward to talking to you soon and
hopefully having you out to the farm
that was an McClay co-author of the
hidden half of nature an excellent book
on the role microbes play not just in
our garden but also in our bodies you
can check it out on amazon.com or on
their website at WWE
the number to grow calm you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation in
science podcast I'm your host Todd
Hussey don't forget that there's more
information articles available on our
website and blog at WWE and accomm as
well as links to the data and
information we discussed in this episode
on the podcast page and you can enjoy
these podcasts please take a moment to
leave me a rating and review on iTunes
or whatever platform you're listening on
and send me your feedback and
suggestions through our website contact
page or ta d @ k is organics calm I have
some exciting new podcasts coming up
including an interview on lighting and
environmental controls and a follow up
podcast with my good friend Nelson
Lindsley a cannabis consultant in
California stay tuned and thanks
listening