[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of KISS organics
this is the podcast where we discuss the
cutting edge of organic growing from a
science-based perspective and drawn top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge if
you're enjoying these podcasts please
take a moment to subscribe on iTunes or
stitcher or whatever platform you're
listening on and leave me a rating and
review this is really helpful and allows
me to keep producing good content by
drawing more of the top names in the
industry to the show also sign up for
our newsletters on our website at WWE
I send out a newsletter approximately
every two weeks and this is the best way
to ensure you know when the next podcast
has been released they also have the
latest discounts new product information
blog posts and what's happening in the
industry our guest this week is Suzanne
Wainwright Evans she is an ornamental
entomologist specializing in integrated
pest management Suzanne has been
involved in the green industry for more
than 25 years with a primary focus on
biological control and using pesticides
properly she is a graduate of the
University of Florida with degrees in
both entomology and environmental
horticulture she has worked throughout
the United States and internationally
consulting to greenhouses nurseries
landscapers and interior scape companies
she's the owner of bug lady consulting
now in business for over 16 years if you
missed my first interview with Suzanne I
highly suggest you start there it's
episode 15 and will cover much of the
basics
Suzanne reached out again recently
because she wanted to come back on to
clear up some questions regarding the
practice of dipping cuttings as well as
discuss prayer options and the critics
of bio controls just a reminder if you
are a large-scale commercial cultivator
and are serious about consulting or
setting up an IPM program utilizing
beneficial insects I cannot recommend
her enough her website is WWE TLC com if
you're a small grower then I highly
suggest that you try to attend one of
our upcoming lectures or workshops
we talked about a couple in the show and
I'll have links to them along with other
information on the podcast page she has
a ton of information including her
upcoming events article she's written
and much more on her website please do
check it out
now on to the show all right thanks
Suzanne I appreciate you coming back on
the show I wanted to you'd mentioned you
wanted to come back on to talk about a
few things that we didn't cover in the
last podcast and some general questions
you've been getting starting with
dipping with propagation can you talk a
little more about that yes well first
thanks for having me back and thanks for
the good solid email questions that I
have gotten but I definitely did get a
lot of questions about dipping because I
think we kind of just brushed over it
and dipping is not complicated but you
do have to understand what you're doing
because if not you can make some
mistakes but the whole idea of dipping
and a lot of this information has come
from researchers up in Canada Rose
Mountain House is one who's been working
on this a lot for things like
poinsettias because again since since we
the universities and government
researchers really aren't free at this
point to work on him or cannabis what we
have to do is we have to look to other
research and see how can we translate
that to help us with this crop and this
is one situation where it started in
poinsettias and mums and even in the
ornamental market it has definitely
moved through a lot of their other
varieties of ornamental plants and I
definitely think that in cannabis this
is really critical because again the
pest you're getting most of them are
coming in on cuttings or plant material
and you need to have better sanitation
practices and stop it right at the door
and and this is the same thing that's
been true with poinsettias we know that
when poinsettias come in they've been
coming in with things like white flies
and so these dip programs have been
developed so you can dip your cuttings
in a solution and then stick them so you
can start a lot cleaner it
now I'm going to guarantee you a hundred
percent perfect kill everything all the
time but it's definitely going to get
you started much cleaner than you would
without a dip and I think with what I've
been seeing out on the west coast with
the the growers out there you really and
almost everybody has a story of about
well their grow was clean until somebody
brought some plants or until they
brought some cuttings in and so this is
a way you can stop that from happening
now I think we might have mentioned a
few products before and you do have to
you know depending on what state you're
in you have to see what's approved and
what's not allowed and stuff so I'm
going to speak very general so you know
you have to think about your situation
and see if this applies to yours but
soaps and oils are definitely some of
the leading dips being used in addition
to another product that's being used
quite a bit is Bettina garde but when
selecting what dip to use you have to
look at what are your target pests you
know Bettina garde and soap have been
very popular for poinsettias because one
of their big issues is white flies now I
have seen white fly in cannabis but it's
not as big of a problem I would say as
like ham present might there's been a
lot more broad might I've seen lately
and to spot spider mites and Botanic
Gardens not going to really do anything
for might issues and that's why there's
a lot of interest looking at a product
called saw foil X which I know some of
you if you've talked to me we've talked
about saw foil X was actually tested up
in Canada for poinsettias and when they
did their dips it was at a 0.1% when you
read the label for a spray for this
particular oil which by the way is an
Omri listed product so it is approved
for use in organic production the spray
rate is 1%
but in the research where they were
dipping cuttings in Canada it was at a
0.1% and at that level they were still
able to get the insecticidal properties
of killing pests but they didn't get
phyto toxicity from it on the points
that he is and I believe they tested
mums also in the United States right now
the cephalic from a federal label does
not have dipping on the label so it's a
very in a federally you technically
can't do it it's a real challenge
because we've got to stop these mites
and this is a product we do have some
research on and we have a rate four so I
can't legally tell anybody to dip it but
I'm just telling you there's research
out there at a 0.1% solution that it's
shown very good insecticidal properties
or let me call them pesticidal
properties at that rate now the cell
we're waiting for the dip to come for
the label I mean it's not that it's
going to be disallowed we just need it
to show up on the label but it it has
shown to be very effective at stopping
pests there is the information is out
there online very easily that you can
find the research and how they use this
0.1% solution to dip in they've also
done combinations again with like
botanic garden dizzy R 0.5% soap
solution as a dip so there are other
combinations but from an efficacy
standpoint we found the saw file we I
have to say in ornamentals and cannabis
as a foliar spray product it has been
very very effective for mite management
but you have to get spray coverage you
have to get spray coverage and that is
what is critical that a lot of people
will spray it and say well it didn't
work well no it's because you didn't get
good spray coverage and that's why if
you're doing dips you get
Hunter percent spray coverage once you
have you know a large plant whether it
be a mum whether you have it
cannabis whether you know it be anything
getting 100 percent spray coverage is
nearly impossible especially when you're
using paint sprayers but that's a whole
nother issue but this way you can start
clean and and it's been very frustrating
to me talking to growers you know we're
like well what's your program and the
cannabis people are being too reactive
they're waiting to they get a pest
problem and then trying to treat you've
got to do your dips let your plants dry
and then immediately share predatory
mites right out and start on your
program then and I'm seeing too many
suppliers of biocontrol agents not
setting these programs up for growers
they're really doing a dis justice to
their growers they're on it now there is
another product I've been looking at and
it's called tetra kirb tetra curve is on
the 25 be exempt list so it is exempt
from EPA registration so there's no
reentry time on it no protective
equipment really requirements for it and
that also is proving to be a very
effective miticide for to spot spider
mites I know they're working on testing
for different dip rates because again
dip rates are going to be different than
a spray rate so but that's another
product I think there's a lot of
potential with and from being in grows
and seeing the price people are paying
for some of these spray products you
know this uh foil is so inexpensive to
use buy in comparison and you know by
the saw file from a traditional
horticultural Supply Company it's I
think it's almost twice as expensive on
Amazon if you buy it but if you buy from
you know companies like southern egg BFG
you know these Carlin these kinds of
people on you can get a good price on
the product and it will go a long way
for you yeah I did have a question about
that now the stuff file X you said was
also on the market under another name is
that correct
well you can't the
same inactive ingredient the oil is last
I thought you know and things may change
since like a few days ago but the
Monterey lawn and garden product which
you can buy a lot of garden centers in
small quantities that is the same highly
emulsified oil in there okay I just
wanted to make sure yeah I added that to
my website it was a lot harder to get
this off oil accent as it as a new
company to try and offer it to customers
plus I think the the smallest size was a
couple gallons or like a five gallon jug
which is a lot more than a lot of
growers may need that we work with so
yes and I just had a discussion with
Bioworks
about packaging size so maybe might be
some smaller packaging might be coming
sooner than later oh that would be great
I'd love to get into smaller size of
directly from them yeah I just remember
a lot of people I'm dealing with do mix
up 100 gallons of spray at the time and
they need these larger quantities but I
do understand and especially when it
comes to dipping you need very small
quantities of products yes so that
brought up a couple more questions I
want to ask you around dipping before we
move on
so you mentioned soaps when I think of
soaps I think of dr. Bronner's but what
kind of soaps do you recommend for for
dipping and it things like that impede
you know again and this you know soaps
are a whole nother podcast because a
soap is not a soap is not a soap you
have different carbon chain lengths I
mean they're they're some organic
herbicides that are soaps and you just
never know with soaps sometimes what
kind of soap is actually in there
it gets scary when people start using
detergents you don't know about what
other additives are in there impede
insecticidal soap is designed to be an
insecticide and it you know as with any
insecticide product you always have to
make sure that you know you're not going
to fight Oh issues you don't want to use
it when your plants are wilted you don't
want to spray it in the middle of the
day in full Sun I mean there's all these
things that you know you can do to
reduce the risk of using or having
burned from soaps and oils you know the
dr. Bronner thing is
is you know it I would say it I know
that if you get contact with a mite you
know you can you can have mortality you
can kill it but again it all comes down
to spray coverage you know with a lot of
these products that it just depends on
how good you spray and that's it and
there's been no real research on dipping
and dr. Bronner because it's not on the
25 be exempt list nor is it at a
registered pesticide so really um it's
tough for people to do research with it
because it's not you know recognized
really as a pesticide allure
insecticidal product in the US and so
you know you have to be just very buyer
beware using that kind of stuff but that
is very as soon as somebody calls me and
says you're using dr. Bronner I know
it's a cannabis grower right from there
for those telltale cannabis signs and
I'm not saying it's necessarily a bad
thing because you know what I would
weigh whether a grower do something like
that then go spray you know orthene or
you know some of these other products
that can be way nastier but you know
just it's a risk that you can have Fido
with that stuff and also dr. Bronner's
has a million different flavors and
those innards can make a difference too
but it's basically the soap working as a
desiccant on on the insects and mites
that's basically what's happening and
when you get impede again you're getting
the right carbon chain length as an
insecticidal soap without all this other
stuff in it yeah I typically hear people
choosing MIT based dr. Bronner's ones
because they think they'll get some some
of the qualities of the mint in terms of
the pesticide properties but well let me
tell you twice this week I've been with
two mint growers because they can't
control the insects on their mint so wow
yeah mints got some great insecticidal
properties going okay so a couple other
questions I had on this dipping thing so
yes no go ahead ask them because I've
got a list of things to make sure I tell
you okay so you mentioned mixing botanic
garden insecticidal soap can you use
more than one product
at a time it's well that is something
that has been tested and we know it
works together you can get yourself into
trouble mixing too many things at a time
because you don't understand how they're
going to all interact together you know
one real interesting study on that is
looking at nematodes and tank mixing oil
mixing them in a dip with Botanic Garden
but Tanner guard won't kill nematodes
but when they were doing some research
about it they were getting nematode
mortality and it turned out what
happened is the this is what they think
is happening the the as the Botanic
Garden it was pinning the nematodes down
to the bottom and basically suffocating
the nematodes down on the bottom so it
was actually a physical issue of of the
two products so it's something that you
definitely have to keep aerated and mix
but there is work from bio work showing
and again bio works does have a
technical bulletin out on their website
it's called cleaning up incoming plant
material by utilizing dips and they have
in there where you know they talk about
dipping the you know the putting the
nimma shield together with the botanic
garden the new Micheel there are the
nematodes and the rates and how you can
mix them all together and if you're
dipping something with roots because I
got an email from a grower saying oh you
said on the podcast to dip the whole
plant and oil and that's an eye I hope
that message across because when we talk
about oil dips we're talking about
cuttings you know or clones as the
cannabis industry calls them but just
the foliage when people get rooted
cuttings in and we see this much more in
ornamentals and even some vegetables
growers are dipping those young plants
with the root media in there or the the
oasis or whatever media they're using
but they'll tend to dip them in a
botanic garden emmitt ode and roots
yield mixed together and those three
products we know work very well together
because then you get the nematodes into
the media which are going to kill what's
what's our flower thrips
pupae they'll also kill fungus gnats and
then you get a bat and a guard giving
one
sent coverage on the plant and then you
get rude shield which is actually a very
good biological fungicide so Bioworks
has really good literature on this
telling you how to do it how to mix this
stuff up with these products so you do
have to be careful now the rates for the
dipping with the soap and the botanic
garden that's out of a Canadian study
again that rose mountain house was
involved with and you know they're
wrecking recommending a 0.5% soap
solution and then they were adding in
125 grams of per liter of the botanic
garden to gether to dip so if you go
online and go to you know university
government website and look about dip
information you can find these rates and
what's been tested and what we know does
play well together in a dip okay and
just to be clear you're suggesting as
well so if you have a if you have a
facility you should be dipping even off
of healthy mother plants at just as part
of your or your IPM strategy this is
something that everyone should be doing
when they're taking cuttings if I had a
facility I would be doing that because
the risk is too great you're not talking
about 25 cent marigold the risk is too
great and with these mites it's
generally just taking one coming in and
and something you know you may think
your grow was clean but if your employee
went somewhere that had mites and they
hitchhiked back in or you know it's just
it's you know it's very rare that you
know someone says I absolutely know
insect problems I have no mite problems
and my grow at all and most people start
clean and end up with problems so I
think it's a good preventive step to do
because the cost is low the labor is low
and as of yet and you know things may
change as more research comes out you
know we may find there may be varietal
differences maybe some some cannabis
varieties or cultivars don't like to be
dipped as of yet
I haven't had anybody contact me and say
this was a problem unless they were
doing it wrong and and that's the thing
I found with some of the emails I got
and actually visiting some of the groves
that they weren't dipping correctly
because you know you want to take your
cuttings or again your clones you have
your and also never take them off
dehydrated plants make sure the plants
are well watered before you take your
cuttings which I think everybody knows
that but you know you want to mix up
whatever cocktail you're going to dip
your cuttings in it needs to make sure
it stays well mixed again if using
things like nematodes but an agar that
kind of stuff can easily settle out if
you're doing a lot of cuttings one of
the easiest ways to do it is to take two
like 1020 mesh flats lay the cuttings in
there and have the open parts of the the
mesh flat facing each other so basically
you've made a cage and you could
submerge it down and you want to hold it
five to ten seconds and kind of shimmy
it a little bit in there until no air
bubbles come up because that means that
once the air bubbles stop coming up that
there's no air left touching the
products down there I mean on the the
cuttings because if there's an air
pocket that means part of the plants not
getting covered most cannabis people are
going to be doing that volume of cutting
so what people do is they basically will
just mix up maybe one gallon of solution
put on your gloves and depending again
what you're using you might need
different protective equipment but
basically taking a hand full of the
cuttings and then submerging them and
just kind of shaking them not violently
but shaking underwater again you know
ten seconds or so until no air bubbles
come up pull it out kind of you know
drip it off a little bit and then you
can either some people you know will lay
them out and then you know keep them
cool to the next day or you you know get
them stuck right then on there the thing
that I'm seeing and believe me
ornamental guys made this mistake at
first but now I'm a little concerned
because some of the cannabis guys are
don't use that dip solution day after
day after day because you
you do have a risk of diseases getting
in that water so you know it between
cultivars are between you know different
groups of plants you might want to
change that water so don't hold it over
and use it again and again because you
will spread problems and especially if
using something like botanical I mean on
nematodes they'll all be dead they'll
end up drowning in the water so just mix
up what you need and use it but then the
question is is what do you do with that
leftover product after you dipped your
cutting do not spray it on your plants
no no no no no no no don't spray it in
your greenhouse you need to dispose of
it however your state you know allows
you to dispose of it what I know some of
my ornamental guys do is they go and
they spray it around outside around
their greenhouse so you want to just
dispose of it properly
obviously with something like dr.
Bronner's which again I have no idea to
dip rate for that that isn't a
registered pesticide so that's easier to
dispose of but you don't want to take
you know a product that you've just
washed all these bad things off your
cuttings and go apply it right to your
plants wow that was a lot of really good
information thanks for sharing all that
I could visualize the dipping so that
really helped and I'll try and put up
some photos if I can find some too to
help listeners yeah Bioworks has some
and like I said you know I teach these
workshops all over the place and Debbie
from bio works I have pulled her with me
in fact that's what she and I are going
to be up in Alberta teaching some
classes and I think it's two weeks or so
one day we're doing ornamentals one day
we're doing vegetables but I call her
dipping Debbie because she does a really
good demonstration like when you mix up
roots yield what should it look like in
the water when you mix up a Tanner guard
what should it look like in the water
make sure you know you get it all mixed
in because some of those powdered
products can clump now I know like
seeing this is where you've got to know
your state because you can't use the
powdered you can't use the wettable
powder in Oregon of the Tanner guard so
you gotta you know know what your state
rules are and use the right formulation
but if you're using a powdered
formulation those clumps are easy to
sink to the bottom and you got to get
them and she'll use like a whisk
to make sure that it gets all mixed in
but she does a really really amazing
demonstration on it also the Vineland
research and innovation station er where
again rose mountain house
works they've been putting together some
videos on dipping again little more
point study oriented but it definitely
will help provide good information
because again I mean I mean I you know I
was out there was that a week and a half
ago two weeks ago some of you people
listening probably saw me come by your
facility but it just I feel so bad for
you guys because you're just not getting
good solid science information and
you've got to have this stuff in order
to stay in business these days I want to
get into that a little bit but before we
do we had talked a little bit about
sprayers we didn't give any actual
recommendations I know you love the
company DRAM that's dra mm do you have
any particular Spurs that you recommend
for getting good coverage I know you
don't like paint sprayers
well because paint sprayers aren't
pesticide sprayers and this is I am not
a I'm not a spray equipment expert you
know I I have my niche of you know how
how to kill them and this is you know I
I what I tell my growers should do is
contact Grant
Graham DRAM and say you know I'm an
indoor grow I'm an outdoor grow on
average we mix up this much product this
is you know and have them tell you what
the right equipment is for you because
they know there are equipment and that's
what's what they're experts at and you
know I am a firm believer of no one is
an expert on everything and I do I mean
if you've seen me in person you know
unfortunately I'm an eye roller because
like when I meet somebody and I'm like
well what do you specialize in
oh I specialize in everything no one's
an expert in everything so what you have
to do is find the expert in the field
you need to talk about or again you know
like you can talk to one expert and
they'll say well I don't know but this
is the person to go talk to you know
that and that's
what I do I built this network of other
experts because I don't know everything
but I think DRAM has good solid
equipment it's a lot of what my
ornamental guys use I'm not knocking any
other spray company out there it's just
I've just always had very I've heard
very good things about them I see my
customers are happy and they're
innovative which we'll talk about later
about their nematode bucket which
unfortunately I didn't realize that the
cannabis industry didn't know about the
nematode bucket but we'll talk about
that later well why don't we cover it
now since he meant brought it up and we
were talking about DRAM already so you
had an experience at the last conference
you were at where someone was talking
about having trouble getting even
distribution of nematodes in greenhouse
applications and you said the solution
was out there do you want to cover that
yeah and it's an amazingly simple
solution so there is the I would called
the sophisticated way to go so DRAM has
made because we were years ago having
problems in the ornament market keeping
our nimma toad suspended in water you
you make your stock solution of
nematodes up and again if you don't have
aeration to keep oxygen in the water and
you don't have the water moving the
nematodes sink out and you don't get
even distribution and I've had
discussions years ago with DRAM and
other people and one thing my growers
have done it that the the this is the
unsophisticated answer you just
literally can use a fish bubbler that
you can get from a bait store and it's
kind of like instead of you know having
your your bait well for your little fish
with your popular in it you just drop
that bubbler into your bucket of stock
nematodes you have to be very careful
your bubbler and that what you're using
because people have tried different
things doesn't get warm because you
don't want to cook your nematodes and
it's easy to cook your nematodes the
idea again is to keep oxygen in the
water because then Kadima totes like
fish and you want to keep them moving in
the water and so a fish bubbler can do
that but what DRAM developed and I know
sorry DRAM it's a little pricey but it's
easy it's done it's simple and I it's on
my tits an it
get proof products and I think sometimes
you know you're going to pay a little
bit more but it's done and you don't
have to worry about it it's a bucket
that can you can plug it in or it can
run off battery and it keeps your
nematodes in suspicion in suspension and
aerates them and what my ornamental guys
do is they'll take those buckets and
then you just stick a dosatron in it and
then you can use that to evenly dose out
your nematodes per pot and you're
getting an even distribution it's it's
it's a beautifully simple answer and you
know you can use that bucket for other
things you want to keep in suspension
and you know you can use a dosatron for
a lot of different things to give you
better better even distribution in your
greenhouse and dosatron and BASF and BSF
is the world's largest producer of
nematodes do have literature out there
telling you how to use a dosatron with
with the beneficial nematodes and
because you do have to remove a filter
out of it but it's actually very simple
and again if some of you been to some of
my workshops we actually did a live
demonstration of this out in California
I think is about two years ago with a
plug and cutting conference and we are
going to be doing it again
I'm for those of you that are coming to
the cultivate show which is the right
now for the ornamental slash hint of
edge and vegetable and they're the
largest greenhouse show we have in the
US it's in July in Columbus Ohio it's
like I think maybe 30 bucks to get in
the door I think education is maybe two
hundred dollars it's a really
inexpensive show but it brings about ten
thousand greenhouse people on the
Saturday before I have put together a
workshop in the morning it is going to
be insect ID you want to learn those
five or six a food you need to know
we're going to teach you you want to
learn the few common thrips we're going
to teach you then in the afternoon we're
going to go out to a commercial
greenhouse and I've set up with myself
and then some of I will call them my a
team biocontrol producing companies and
their their specific people
they're coming up hand pick who have
asked to help me and we are going to
unpack biocontrol agents and show you
how to apply them correctly and we're
going to do everything from wasps to
mite to nimah totes so if you want to
come learn how to do it first hand we're
going to be doing that there
unfortunately well you know I'm teaching
in a couple weeks at the bio bio
pesticide bio control conference we're
doing that specific bio control for
cannabis producers but that were limited
to being inside the hotel there
and trust me hotels don't get really
excited when you start applying bugs
around on things in hotels so we're not
going to be able to do live
demonstrations there which by the way I
think that has already sold out possibly
because the conference contacted me and
asked if they could add more people
because I was trying to keep it to a
limited size but they said there's been
just so much demand that we might be
expanding the size of that so if you
haven't gotten registered you better
register now or get on the waitlist if
you want to be at that meeting it and a
tad you're coming yes I'll be there I've
got my ticket I signed up right away so
I'm really excited I also signed up for
the greenhouse 2 or field tour the day
before the conference yes well most
likely it's because that sold out too
and it sounds like because they want me
to go on that to help with information
so I'm probably going to be in a chase
car going around with that too so I'll
see you on on that Wednesday too but you
know for these applications that you
know it's one thing to sit here and talk
about it it's another thing to see it
being done right in front of you where
you can ask questions and touch the
equipment and have the experts in their
fields do that so I think that that is
you know going to be super helpful that
show in in Columbus and again it's not
it doesn't break the bank to attend that
show I actually last year we did another
workshop and actually there were
cannabis people that came because again
there is a lot of crossover between
cannabis and ornamentals just like this
nematode bucket here you know the
ornamental and vegetable guys we've had
the answer to this and it's just somehow
the information didn't flow over into
cannabis
oh now here you go cannabis guys here
here's your easy solution to doing that
either the DRAM nematode bucket again
they've got videos and information right
on their website or use a fish bubbler
and with the dosatron and there you go
now with the fish bubbler are you
putting an airstone or anything on the
end of it are you just putting a line
directly and it's just bubbling hey
depends on what size people are doing
and you know we've done some tests with
some of my growers but if you can kind
of aerate it where the hose is if you're
in a round bucket shooting so it kind of
makes a toilet flushing world because
you again you want to keep everything
kind of mixed up now another girl of
mine made like a bigger a bigger one in
the middle it almost looks like a
sprinkler head so it's pushing the
nematodes up and they're coming down the
sides but we did find some of the
nematodes we're getting trapped in the
corners there and that's why I dram you
know I didn't realize because again I'm
not an engineer but you know we are
waiting for this bucket for a while and
it was because it was a lot harder to
engineer than they thought and I and it
depends on the again back to the shape
of what you're doing because you got to
keep them moving and you don't get them
trapped in corners but you also want to
aerate so look at what you're doing um
and you know as long as you're getting
them out in a reasonable amount of time
you just you don't want to let the
nematodes sit for hours in that you want
it you want to get them out into your
grow I will warn you I had one
greenhouse operation to run there
bubblers they tapped into the airline's
for their I guess pneumatic greenhouse
tables because you know the they use the
the they step on a petal and it lifts
the table up but there were oil in those
lines and then oil got in there
nematodes so it sounds crazy but you got
have a clean air source and you have to
make sure it doesn't heat up and that's
what DRAM said was the other engineering
challenge is because if you compress air
it can create heat and in their early
designs the bucket actually heated up
and it would cook the nematodes so they
had an engineer a way to keep the
nematodes moving and oxygenated without
getting warm and is chlorine or
chloramines an issue when you're using
nematodes
know it can affect the microbial content
and compost teas when I look under the
microscope but are you seeing anything
with nematodes is a big deal not really
I mean your average tap water drinking
water is fine and if if if if something
does kill nematodes then it would
probably being used as animat aside out
in the farm fields okay fair enough so
one of the things that you mentioned was
that informations not making it over
from say the ornamental industry or the
horticulture industry over into cannabis
and some of that relates to I would say
the the consultants that are out there
and I know you and I talked off air
about that a little bit in terms of
pricing and the economics of the pest
management that you're seeing on
cannabis do you want to touch on any of
those topics real quickly yeah so and I
don't know maybe I'm snob I don't know
but I I consider if someone is a
consultant they just consult I I don't
understand how you can consult on your
own product you're selling you know I
consider if you are have a product for
sale and you're providing information
then your your technical support for
that product because to me consultant
means unbiased and that's why I've
worked very hard with my business is I'm
not financially connected you know to I
don't get paid by the chemical companies
I don't get paid by the insect arees to
to to promote their products I you know
if I recommend a product I never never
take any kind of kickbacks and it's been
tempting at times because people have
offered me money they said hey we got
this huge sale let us give you a
commission it's like no I can't take it
because that kind of ruins my neutrality
that I've worked so hard to build over
all these years so you know when when
somebody says they're a consultant you
know that's for you know find out well
do you sell anything and the other thing
I say always ask is is what you know
what is your background
to be giving me advice even as a
technical support person okay you're
here to advise me on on insects well you
know what your background how have you
been doing this you know
these kinds of things and the thing
right now with the cannabis industry is
because there's been so much money in it
from the sense of people selling product
to cannabis growers what I have found
that I'm seeing this as nice as possible
you can make money selling products and
not know anything about your products is
the biggest thing I've learned in the
last you know few years because there's
such a demand for products and such a
demand for people that are willing to be
able to work with the cannabis industry
because you know the university people
can't the government people can't and
you know there still is some stigma out
there with some companies where you know
they don't want to be associated with it
so you know the pool of people the
cannabis industry can pull from to get
help is smaller than if you're a corn
farmer or if you're you know a mom
grower and so with that you've got to be
able to vet what people say and my first
thing is is just because you say it with
confidence doesn't mean it's true and
that has been you know and I literally
had a grower that was buying product
from a company and the recommendations I
just did not understand the
recommendations at all it was the
complete wrong predatory mite for the
situation and I asked the groom like
well why are you doing this well because
the supplier told me to and I'm like
well did you ask him and question him
why are you telling me to use this might
and she's like well no because he said
it with such confidence he was so sure
the way he said things so I just
believed him and I don't want to say you
know you had to be skeptical and not
trust anybody but the canvas people just
need to do some better vetting and it's
it's hard to do because you know I was
at a meeting where I met you and you
know there was a lot of talks on
lighting and I'm not saying anybody said
anything about lighting was wrong or bad
because you know what I don't know
enough about lighting to even know if
what people were telling me was true or
not and as I was sitting there that's
what I was thinking and they're saying
you know this is the best to do here and
use this here and there and it's like
how do I know they're true yeah they're
standing up on the stage
and saying things but how do we know and
it's very hard to be able to vet a
subject that you're not educated on I
can only vet really you know people that
I can vet what's being said about
subject areas I know about but like
Lighting's not one so you know I can't
tell you if it's true or not and it's
how is a grower do you do that and it's
very very difficult um there is no doubt
yeah it is difficult we were talking
about that how from the outside looking
in it's it's almost impossible to know
if the information you're getting is
good or not so how would you if you were
a grower go about vetting they go about
vetting a potential consultant when it
comes to insects so I have like my my
list of questions that I will tell to my
growers and like ask these questions and
see what kind of answers you get and
that can they're there certain things
like that that are just sure telltale
signs that they don't know what they're
talking about and it can be - you know
knowing about lighting on insects and
you know who needs light who doesn't
need light things like that the other
thing is - if if you know you you have
an insect problem and all right let's
say let's say you've got broad mite and
I come in and I said okay you know let's
let's queue cmaras you as a grower
should say to me okay Suzanne why are
you telling me to use Q camaris and I
just say well because it's the best not
good enough that is not the right answer
we should be able to discuss
temperatures what other crops we've done
this in and all this kind of information
and if any of anybody on your listening
or one of the people that I've been in
your groves you know I and it's almost
too much I'm going to overload you with
information because I want to give you
all the facts and all my years of
experience of doing this to be like this
is you know what we're what you know why
we're making these decisions because
there are situate
and cannabis and I'm you know dealing
with us a lot we have a pest we may not
know how to treat it
and I'm going to say we don't know and
let's try this but here's our
contingency plan and and anybody that
comes in is just like well I'm going to
solve all your problems overnight just
buy all these bugs for me and dump them
out that isn't that is not a plan and
you have to be very careful on that to
do that and I don't want to I don't want
to give you away my lake telltale
questions necessarily because I know
that some of the people that sell BIOS
are going to listen to this podcast and
if I get then they're going to be able
to hear the questions no that makes
sense I know it's just such a challenge
and yeah one of the others good you can
always contact me believe me I get
emails and again I'm struggling right
now because I do get between like forty
to sixty emails a day right now and I'm
struggling to keep my head above water
but you know if you just say hey Suzanne
you know it you know you're a smaller
girl or something and you know you don't
necessarily that you don't I'm not
looking for people to hire me but if you
just are like okay this is where I'm at
this is what we're doing who's somebody
good to work with I can just be like go
talk to this person go talk to that
person because I can't handle
I can't work with everybody and some
people did they don't need me I'm more
of the the problem solver when
everything's gone to crap I come in and
help fix a situation or you know do
training to like teach you how do you
recognize the problems early how do you
set up you know better SOPs for you know
your workflow on pest management in your
greenhouse but just as far as you know
hey I don't have problems really but I
want to get started with BIOS you know I
can definitely point you in the right
direction and it's going to depend where
you are in the United States are you and
endure you outdoor grow
what are your keep s I mean there is not
I'm not always going to tell everybody
to go to one supplier for one thing no
it's it all depends on those different
variables and there's no reason growers
can't do their own research and track
data and
use the scientific method to figure out
what works in their environment so I
think that's important too I mean
consultants can point you in the right
direction but you can still learn a lot
yourself oh yeah and the one thing that
I'm seeing with as you brought it up the
scientific method cannabis people are
not doing controls and this is I keep
telling people that are buying these six
seven eight hundred dollar spray
products that there's like you know five
dollars worth of product in the bottle
you know spray your plans with that
triple wrench or sprayer and then spray
a couple plants with just water the
exact same way and see if you get the
same results because cannabis growers
can get much better spray coverage
because you have a much you have a lot
fewer plants you know my background is
coming from you know where someone has
to go spray ten acres of plants and
they're not going to get good spray
coverage and that's why you know they're
using you know they have these like
systemic and trans laminer pesticides
and things like that because they can't
get as good a spray coverage with the
soaps and oils cannabis you should be
able to get really really really good
spray coverage and you can get they have
what are called water sensitive cards
there are these yellow cards and they
look like sticky cards and on a sidenote
sticky cards if I go into another
cannabis grow that does not have sticky
cards I'm going to poke somebody in the
eye you guys need to use sticky cards
but let me go back now I will go back to
my focus so these cards look like yellow
sticky cards but once they get water or
moisture on them they turn blue and so
what my ornamental people will do is
they will basically kind of hide these
out on the crops and then have somebody
come through and spray and then you can
come back and look and see what kind of
spray coverage you are getting and if
those cards are still yellow then that
means that area got no product but you
know there is you know something to just
washing your plans off with water for
things like spider mite management even
if it's just that physical knocking off
the plant it also raises the humidity
and spider mites don't necessarily like
that so I'm suspect about some of these
products these mega expensive products
that they're putting out that I think
that pause
the water is doing a lot of the control
because we've tested a lot of these
products in the ornamental market and we
just don't get the results yeah having
been in the cannabis industry for a few
years now I'm it's made me a really big
skeptic
in terms of products and marketing
claims and so the first thing I do when
I'm evaluating a product is I want to
see all the ingredients so I want to
know that they're willing to list all
the ingredients and the moment I hear
the word proprietary a lot of red flags
come out and then the next thing I look
for is is this product being used in
horticulture or an ornamental industry
somewhere outside of cannabis or are
they marketing strictly to cannabis
because if it really worked all that
well and had all this efficacy whether
it's a fertilizer or a pesticide it
wouldn't just be in the cannabis
industry so people really need to do the
research because the they're spending
way too much money on these products I
totally agree and and for you those of
you that were at the organic meeting
where I spoke in Portland I guess two or
three weekends ago you know but the one
thing I talked about a lot was
poinsettias and poinsettias make so
little money off the plants you know
they have a few cent profit margins on
them and so if a product is being used
in poinsettias you know it has to work
because a grower like if I go to a point
set a grower and say okay we're going to
spend five cents more a plant they are
going to be like there's the door
because they can't afford to put a five
more sense of input into that plant so
that's a good indicator if it's
something that is used in point study a
production actually used you know it
works because you the poinsettia guys
can't afford to use it unless it does
work and we do a lot of product testing
and poinsettias because again the
product profit margin is so slim and I
came off I mentioned this before but one
of my greenhouse growing operations or
ornamental ones we did order in for
entertainment purposes I will say you
know a bunch of these cannabis products
that are you know on the twenty five be
exempt list so they don't have to have
EPA registration and we tested them and
we just we either burn the
is up or we just didn't get get any kind
of control with them and so you have to
be very careful and I mean like I think
soil is a good example and I don't you
know keep going back to that you know I
mean it's not that you know again this
is not a commercial for stuff oil but
just looking at costs where you can get
a jug of stuff well I think from the
[__] supply companies it's maybe 60 $70
for a large jug I think Amazon I think
they want like 120 where I'm seeing
products that have half the size of that
and they're being sold for six or seven
hundred which don't have the efficacy or
safety track record and also these plant
botanicals we don't know how they impact
the biocontrol agents we have a solid
history with using some oil acts with
predatory mites but once you get in to
plant extracts as we talked about some
of the plant extracts have repelling
qualities we know neem is a repellent
doesn't even work well enough to repel
all your pests away but there is some
research showing you know where they
spray leaves with neem they spray and
leaves with as it are actin they put
predatory mites on them and they just
like nope we're not going to stay as
compared to untreated leaves they will
stay on and you know the period of with
self ILX of when you can start
reintroducing yes of oil once it's dry
will spray on a Monday we're releasing
on Tuesdays now with the Tetra curb I
just had a conversation with them I
think they're after their miticide
product they're saying they would they
just feel comfortable as a general rule
two days is what they're recommending on
that and you know they're being very
general because well are we releasing
cucumbers are releasing sworsky are
releasing for symbolist because when you
get into more specific chemistry's I
think floor mites a really good example
even though legal cannabis you know
they're not using it but flora might has
always been very toted touted as very
safe with with beneficials and predatory
mites it's interesting cuz it's very
safe with using personalists and QQ
marys but it can be very toxic to
sworsky so when you get into some of
these other chemistry's you have to
specifically look into you know the
specific you can
just paint with a broad brush and as
soon as a product says to me we kill
pests but we're safe with beneficials I
call BS on that product because whether
something is a pest or a beneficial is
all subjective to who you are and what
you're trying to do the products are not
sentient and can't make those decisions
and so that's another telltale on
products for me is is how they are
marketing what their claims are and with
the 25b products technically they're
supposed to not make false claims but
they're not really getting police and
I've seen crazy claims that products
being systemic when they're not and and
eventually it will probably catch up
with them because again with a twenty
five B you know you can list whatever
insecticides you want but you're not
supposed to lie on those labels and if
the government does come and knock and
you better have proof of your claims and
again it's eventually they're going to
start cracking down yeah and you
mentioned I would just throw that that
also includes plant washes as well
people are listing things as plant
washes and then telling you you know off
off label that they're insecticides so
that's something else to watch out for
yeah because they've proven you don't
know what's in them yeah and you also
mentioned that phyto toxicity is not
always something you can visually see so
some of these botanicals may have an
impact or be stressing the plant and you
might not even realize it
yes and you know they did that the the
most I think the most textbook study
that was with you know when they were
using the ivory soap on tomatoes where
they got lower yield using Irish soap
and compared to an insecticidal soap
even though you didn't see photo
toxicity on the plant it definitely
affected the yield on that so I want to
circle back around we talked a little
about two other consultants out there
and some of the recommendations you were
hearing that you weren't very excited
about and one of the things you had
mentioned sorry off air was that
consultants were not recommending
treatment and propagation or early in
the plant's life when there's so much
less leaf tissue and it's easier to you
know easier to do lower rates do you
want to touch on that a little bit yeah
and see this is what makes me think that
they don't know what they're doing or
they're just trying to make more money
off off the growers and you know what
everybody deserves to be in business
everybody deserves to make a living I am
not trying to take a living away from
anybody just you know when you have to
do pest management and propagation you
cannot wait because if you wait you may
not be able to treat the problem or it
may be too expensive to treat for the
problem and it can get very expensive to
try to be curative and I'm sure a lot of
people are going to be shaking their
heads because they look at the money
they've spent and some of these
recommendations I've heard if just the
person that said hey this is what we're
going to do for that I could have told
you from the beginning it wasn't going
to work I now get it I don't know
everything and some situations and you
know we don't know but there's some
things we know just aren't going to work
and you have to be you know talk to more
than one person I I tell all my growers
work with at least two different insect
arees you know so that you have you know
do you have more than one person to talk
to
like Kelly vans with beneficial insect
eree
I think he does a great job but I
guarantee you he will not be offended at
all if you know you turn around and you
go ask you know like Paul cool from bio
best you know hey we've got this problem
I think that people like Kelly and Paul
will kind of be glad that the grower is
taking initiative to do your homework
and what you'll often find is that with
these people that I think have been
doing a very good job you'll get very
similar answers not that you always have
to do the exact same thing to get the
same answer because you can have spider
mites and there's possible different
routes to take to manage spider mites
but I don't think that with that these
good solid pest management people get
upset when you question their
recommendations because again it makes
me feel good when you question me it
does because that means you care and
you're taking the time to educate
yourself so you just have to be very
careful with these recommendations and
if somebody's working with you and if
they have no
but put together a program for your
propagation or you know they've been
just focusing on you know releasing at
the end of the crop I would say find
somebody else to work with you've got to
start and propagation and you know and
again I hate keep going back to
ornamentals but like the ornamentals
we're sticking our cuttings and we're
getting the beneficials right out they
all get nematodes you know right as soon
as they're stock and you need air quotes
here because you've got a look at your
media and you know those kinds of things
and how you're propagating because
they're not going to work in all systems
but if you're rooting in soil you should
be putting nematodes right in from the
get-go I mean that's just standard
that's standard inexpensive practice
because if you can stop the fungus gnats
then I'm not going to get the call when
you're out in your grow with a mascara
brush trying to brush you know fungus
gnats out of your blooms yeah and the
last thing I wanna touch on on this
subject is pricing so you said you've
seen some pretty dramatic price
increases for cannabis growers over
other crops I don't know I won't say
it's a price increase I will just say
that the cannabis people are paying way
more than then the ornamental markets
are and I will say this very delicately
as possible without everybody hating me
and I'm sure I'm going to get some nasty
emails but it's typically through the
distributors I'm seeing some pretty
exorbitant pricing now I do understand
you know that if they're caught if
they're calling on you providing a good
service they're educating you you know
you do have to pay for some of that in
your pricing there's there's no doubt
about that I think that you know if you
pay five percent and I'm just making
that number up ten percent more but
you're getting good customer service
it's worth it you know and I have no
problem for I mean I don't think that's
an issue but what I take issue with is I
am seeing as much as you know a hundred
percent if not more price increases and
they're just not even getting good
information so the bottom line is people
need to do their own research as a
grower you need to you need to look
choppy round you need to find out who
knows what there
talking about and double-check what
they're telling you with someone else so
that that just puts the onus on the
growers all it really comes down to
right right and I mean and and the thing
is is it may seem like a huge hump at
first but once you get over this hump
and you learn these basics then it gets
easier sadly I don't think my job gets
easier every year but because I always
have new challenges but you know you
once you've experienced a problem and
been able to get through it you know
then you know for the next time and it
does get easier as for a grower when
you're dealing in a mono cropping system
in that way and again with the
information I mean I really feel like
the cannabis industry is hijacked the
internet just be very very very careful
and selective about what you read online
and many years ago I had to stop trying
to answer all these questions and then
now it's like I even struggle with some
of the the group's the the message
boards because I just I get mad because
I see what growers are being told to do
or someone puts up a picture of an aphid
and someone's like oh you know that's a
winged you know fungus gnats because but
they say it so it's sort of like they
know and it's not accurate information
so you just really have to you have to
educate yourself and you have to go to
good sources to get educated so that you
are not more knowledgeable and you're
not spending you know I've heard growers
paying $1 a sachet you know for the
release systems and you know ornamental
guys and again there's differences in
pricing between biocontrol agents you
know is it q comparison there is a
source key in there is it Andrew Sony in
there and then also volume you know if
you need five sachets you know you're
probably going to have to pay more than
my grower getting 10,000 sachets but you
know the the sachets with like cue
cmaras you know they can be you know
ornamental people are paying maybe 15
cents for those you know and to hear
people paying you know these exorbitant
prices and again everybody deserves to
make a living and you know the
distributors do need to have a bit of a
mark
for their business for the service
they're supplying and everything but it
better come with some really really
really good information and some amazing
customer service if ah you're getting
those kinds of markups I don't think
it's been any secret for me I mean I'd
really push my growers to you know buy a
bit more direct from the insector ease
in the sense of having the product
dropship direct to the insectary direct
to you from the grower but if you got
three plants at your house you're not
going to be able to your the volumes are
going to be too large the packaging is
going to be too large for you to do that
the insect trees are really set up to be
sold to commercial growing operations
yeah and something I want to touch on
again that you mentioned that I think is
important that we've kind of glossed
over is once you have an IPM program in
place and once you have the right
procedures in place with the dipping and
the scouting and you have the right
staff there it becomes very easy it's
not like at that point that you're
putting in all this time and energy and
money into bio controls it really runs
itself so I don't want people to get
discouraged like you mentioned because I
think that it is very possible in yuria
you're working with people that are
doing it already and doing it really
well
so and you know this idea that
biocontrol doesn't work so when do when
do I get a phone call when they have
sprayed and tried everything and they
want me to come you know sometimes fix
the problem because they can't get it
under control and this is true across
you know all crops but the thing with
the the cannabis again if you start
early that you don't get there but
imagine cannabis growers out there if
you had to grow you know 200 varieties
of plants and you perpetually had new
cuttings coming in the door from other
countries and from other growers and you
had this perpetual train of pest coming
in and how hard that is to manage this
is why not all but a lot of the
ornamental people have definitely
shifted into using the bio controls
especially in propagation because
they're able to stop the problems there
before they get started and also they're
not spraying pesticides there that
can create resistance issues even if you
rotate pesticides through motives of
actions you can still develop resistance
issues and you know you when you get
spider mites in your greenhouse you
don't know necessarily their pedigree if
they had come you know from an
ornamental crop where they've had
exposure over and over to different
chemistry's you know some of your
chemistry's may not work so you don't
know the pedigree of the pest you have
and even if some of I will say the
synthetic pesticides will work and
that's why we go back to the soaps and
oils because they're more of a physical
kill and they really don't care as much
about you know what genetics you have
for resistance and I have a bug lady
consulting t-shirt that says you can't
build resistance to being eaten and so
you know with some of these past we're
dealing with a lot of white flies spider
mites and aphids that are resistant to a
lot of chemistry's well you know when
that Liesman comes and chows down on you
or that parasite comes in six are egging
you she doesn't really care that much if
you're resistant to you know or Athene
or Abid kind of thing you know and so
that's why there's been this real growth
to with the bio controls is because of
we don't have to worry about resistance
issues that much and even so far with a
lot of the microbial products we haven't
had any resistance issues - like bavaria
bassiano or trichoderma or things of
those nature and also with a lot of the
beneficials you know some of our limited
mobility they can't fly but you know
they are going to search high and low on
that plant to find a food source and
most of the chemicals you are using in
cannabis well they're not systemic you
guys can't use the systemic products
you're using contact products so unless
you get a hundred percent spray coverage
you're not going to be able to get them
and one of the big things that came up
that we discussed at the meeting in
Portland a couple weeks ago there's no
such thing really as a systemic miticide
out there if someone saying they have a
systemic miticide again move on down the
road because it's not true
I'm not going and you know you will
probably get into that more at the
biocontrol cannabis conference in
California but it
doesn't really exist because of the way
the chemicals move and the plans and
plant biology and and physiology and the
way insects and mites feed differently
in plants it's a whole other discussion
so really when you have critics that are
saying the bio controls don't work you
really want to focus on some of the
variables associated with the bolts that
you know the application so like the
sprayer that you're using the consulting
advice and the rates even if you're
applying the right the right bugs to
deal with the right situation in a given
environment or even the quality of the
insects that people are purchasing to
know that they're alive and fresh and
arriving in a condition where they're
going to want to eat whatever the pest
is so I I think there's a lot of
variables though that people need to
consider before they jump to bio
controls don't work and I just I think
that's a factor right and what cracks me
up to no end is and again this is across
the board
ornamental vegetable cannabis everybody
people will spray a pesticide it doesn't
work what do they do they spray it again
doesn't work they'll still spray it
again and you'll see this but you know
one little hiccup in a bio control
programs bio control doesn't work not
not the fact of an out the top reasons I
will say now and it has changed through
the years like a series we were doing
this podcast let's say 20 years ago 20
years ago and I was actually selling
biocontrol agents 20 years ago my first
one of most issue would be you know we
really didn't know a lot what we were
doing and we're having to do a lot of
trialing so we expected failure but then
also product quality wasn't as good
today
the reason I'm seeing people failing
honest to god is I think the number one
thing right now and I will say cannabis
and I will even include ornamentals and
this is bad advice I I just I I mean
it's just some of the basic simple stuff
I was in a greenhouse that runs at 60
degrees and they were putting out
sworsky for control of Western flower
thrips
sworsky does not like to be at 60
degrees you need little tiny mittens for
the sworsky and scarves for them and
they're it's too cold
and you know this is what I'm like why's
this person even making this
recommendation they should know better
and so right there that program was
failing solely because it was a bad
recommendation now from the again
product quality standpoint and
periodically I do you know these product
quality workshops on how to assess your
your bio control agents but we've gotten
way way way way better on it and I think
as long as the products come to you from
the insector ease and the key the key
players as far as in sectaries where the
bugs coming from you have bio line you
have bio best you have coal pert you
have beneficial in Sector E and also
BASF now BSF just does the nematodes so
that they're only an imitator producer
but these other four companies those are
I would say the the largest producers
and like copra it's probably largest in
the world bio best is probably behind
them and bio line might be right up I'm
not sure where if they're right behind
bio best but those are the big in sector
ease now most of them have production
overseas I mean if you go look at a map
you know there's production in Canada
and Mexico and in different locations in
Europe and Spain and Africa so they have
multiple and sector ease but a lot of
the products we're getting here in the
US does come from Europe that and it is
it's FedExed over and then so it comes
from Europe over to here and then it
goes to the end sector E and then if
you're buying from an insectary it comes
to you from there now it's going to a
distributor that distributes it
physically themselves so then it gets
ships to the distributor and this is
where things you know how long is it at
the distributor for you know I've gotten
emails before from companies
distributors that have over ordered and
it's like we're sitting on all this
product you know anybody that wants to
buy it well that's another day the
products been there and some things can
handle that but other biocontrol agents
don't do so well I mean like purse
emilis man you want that out of the
bottle the second you get it there's
been research done on how they can
cannibalize themselves and packaging the
personalists so you really you need to
know your sourcing and
another thing when you do go to buy from
a distributor whose product am I getting
am I getting bio lines am i gettin bio
bests because there are different
packagings there's different carriers
there's differences between the company
and different companies and you know I
when I talk to people that are buying
through distributors I'm like well whose
product you getting they're like well
just depends the thing is is you get
familiar with the way packaging is you
get again familiar with carriers I mean
a good example is if you look at a food
parasites you get it from bio line
there's no carrier in the bottle well
you get it from bio best it's got
buckwheat Hall in there you get it from
Coker they have like a sawdust carrier
and so you do have to do different
release methods for those products
beneficial insectary doesn't use a
carrier and there so you you have to
know what to expect and you don't want
to have carrier one week and not a next
and the person going to put them out
gets confused so you know these are all
things that have to be looked at when
trying to make a program work and I
think sometimes people are getting
products that are a little old and I've
actually on some of microbials I've had
growers buy product that were expired
through distributors that are holding
the product so you have to you know you
got to watch all that stuff and be aware
of all of that and then the other reason
I do see biocontrol programs fails is
pesticide residue that there's something
on the plants that we we didn't know
about or that was sprayed and that is
incompatible with a bio control agent
that's another reason we can have issues
there great well I think I cover it or
we covered all the topics that I wanted
to cover today was there anything else
you wanted to chat about before we sign
off for listeners um I don't think so
and again you know again I'll say it
again people deserve to be in business
but you know just I think for the
cannabis industry people need to do a
better job getting information to the
cannabis industry as a cannabis grower
you need to just you know put on your
thinking cap as my mom used to tell me
to do all the time and you know at you
know analyze what you're being told I
mean does it make sense someone is
telling you to dissolve aspirin and
water
and water your plants does that really
make sense and if you think about some
of these things growers are being told
to do it just it doesn't and back to the
root a fit issue which you know I got
some emails about that we're doing work
looking at nematodes on Rue David I
didn't say we had the solution for that
I'm still right now my strongest
recommendation is still using botanic
garden a no guard correctly you know you
can't just you know magically spritz it
on the soil service and expect your Rudy
Fitz to go away and you know there's
differences between the soils a volume
of pots there's a lot of variables in it
but I just don't feel comfortable enough
recommending nematodes Rove beetles or
even you know hypo a space miles which
is now straighter lapses as a control
option for rude aphids they may help
suppress it but I've talked to people
that have spent thousands of dollars on
those three previously-mentioned
biocontrol agents and not gotten control
of rudy foods or even suppression of it
so be careful about the information
you're getting out there and when
someone makes a recommendation you know
does it suppress it or does it control
it that's a big difference there that
was entomologist Suzanne Wainwright
Evans also known as the bug lady her
website is WWE TLC comm I posted the
links and information we discussed in
this podcast right on the podcast page
at WWE is organics calm just click on
the podcast menu on the top of the home
screen and don't forget to sign up on
our website right on the home page so
you can stay up to date with all the
latest information and podcasts right
when they come out you were listening to
the cannabis cultivation and science
podcast I'm your host Todd Hussey thanks
for checking out the show and stay tuned
is we have some more great episodes
coming up including Chris Jagger a blue
fox farm and founder of the living soil
symposium which is coming up soon and
also Ben hartman owner of a bottom farm
and
the lien farm and the lien farm guide to
growing vegetables to books that are
revolutionized the way we manage our
farm thanks for listening
[Music]