[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of kis Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
organic growing from a science-based
perspective and drawing top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge Our Guest today is
Jeff lowenfels Jeff is the co-author of
teaming with microbes the organic
Gardener's Guide to the soil food web
published by Timber press in August 2006
to Great ACC claim and revised in 2011
it is touted as the most important
gardening book published in the past 25
years and won the prestigious Garden
writers of America Gold Award for
gardening books has been translated into
Korean and French and soon Slovenian
Jeff is also the author of teaming with
nutrients the organic Gardener's guide
to optimizing plant nutrition published
by Timber press in May 20133 the
shorthand title is how plants eat and
what to feed them it is sure to make you
appreciate the beauty of how plants
operate as well as make you a better
Gardener and Steward of the earth his
latest book teaming with fungi was just
released at the end of 2016 and is all
about micro risal fungus Jeff is an
extremely respected and popular National
Garden writer he is the former president
of the garden Riders of America was made
a gwa fellow in 1999 and inducted into
the GW Hall of Fame the highest honor a
garden riter can achieve in 2005 most
important Jeff is the founder of a now
National program that started as plant a
row for beans the soup kien and
Anchorage and is now plant a row for the
hungry the program is active in 48
states and resulted in over a million
pounds of produce being donated to feed
the hungry every year Jeff has been a
good friend now for over a decade and is
a wonderful advocate for organic
gardening compost tea and the microbes
in our soil thanks for coming on the
Jeff sure I'd love to talk to you more
about um first off your books uh in
terms of the amount of success that
you've had with this how how do you
recommend for users to make uh practical
applications for a lot of the
information in you know teaming with
microbes teaming with nutrients and
teaming with fungi sure well I think
each one has a different different sort
of indicator things that people you know
walk away with um you know for example
teeming with nutrients I hope people are
walking away with the idea they need to
test their
soil you know no one ever does uh and
and then they go buy any fertilizer they
think they need and put it on and you
know they have AB or micro food either
way and they have absolutely no idea
whether or not their soil or their
plants need it and so I think that's
that's the important takeaway from from
that one in addition to maybe uh picking
up a little bit of wonder about what
goes on inside those 30 trillion cells
that are in every individual tree you
know that you're looking at etc etc te
with microbes I think is just is is is
something that the the takeaway is that
we've been doing things wrong we've been
we've been feeding the plants instead of
the microbes we've been concerned about
the fertilizer impact on the plant
instead of thinking about what
everything is doing to the environment
that the plant is growing in and what is
the impact on the soil and the soil
structure uh you know we've been really
just looking at how we grow things the
wrong way and I I don't think you can
read teaming with microbes and walk away
thinking that that oldfashioned post
World War II you know throw on Miracle
Grow kind of setup makes any sense
whatsoever so that's that that one and
then the third book teing with with h
fungi uh is is really to
me sort of Paving the way to the
future there is no question that when
you grow plants they need micro risal
fungus and and uh what what we're
learning about that is encapsulated in
that book we were just talking before
the show about some of the problems with
micro risal fungi products but but
there's no question as we move forward
we're going to solve a lot of those
problems and these are going to be uh
items that we use you know just like the
Aver average American uses Miracle Grow
today as far as I'm concerned they'll be
applied to every plant no plants will be
sold without them being added to the
soil first all nurseries will be using
them you know etc etc
etc well Monrovia Nursery is one of the
largest wholesale producers in the
country they've been using it for years
now isn't that right through M risal
applications absolutely and and more and
more uh nurseries are but but yeah
Monrovia has been a real Pioneer every
single plant they sells got got got a
micro Ral partner to it so yeah that's
it's the way to go I mean let's face it
96% of all plants have a micro risal
Association well if that's so then 96%
of what you're growing needs to have
that micro risal Association and we now
know that it's not necessarily there
naturally 15 years ago we would have
said well you know these things are
ubiquitous they're everywhere you don't
need to add them well if you're if
you're cloning a plant you know then uh
there really isn't a chance for it to be
introduced naturally right well it's not
so much a clone situation but even in
even in regular normal soil you know we
we used to think that the spores would
blow all around the earth okay you know
G after they're so small well you know
it turns out that the Ecto micro risal
which are the ones that you might find
in a you know in a big Conifer Forest
yeah they may blow three or four miles H
that's interesting so if you got a nurse
you're three or four miles away yeah you
don't need to use Ecto micro risal fungi
but if you're 15 miles away yeah maybe
you do we now know that rotor tilling
destroys the S the situation we know
that using fungicides certain fungicides
not all of them uh creates a situation
where you need to add them we know that
when you're planting seeds that it makes
sense to make sure that the roots are
infected uh instantly and so it makes
sense to put the micro risal uh fungus
or fungi on the seat itself so that you
get you get inoculation immediately
rather than have to wait you know so
that there there there any number and
and now we know that if you use too much
phosphorus or too much nitrogen you know
you've created a situation where the
plant won't won't signal for the
relationship to begin and so you you
begin to get a whole different view than
what we had 15 or 20 years ago which is
why I wrote the book frankly I mean uh
the the progression of knowledge that
we've had with regard to mecar reszel uh
fungi has been amazing absolutely
amazing uh and and so when I wrote team
with microbes the F the first edition of
teaming with microbes you know had a
paragraph on them uh I had to revise
teaming with microbes in order to add a
chapter on them and then finally I think
things changed so much that that it just
made sense to write the whole book so so
because really it's an area just like
the soil food web subject matter and and
really even even with with with how
plants eat we don't learn how we don't
learn these things in
school and you know we should we learn
the names of dinosaurs but we don't
learn the names of you know what I'm
saying I mean it's sort of interesting
but uh it is important stuff and if
you're a gardener uh I believe and you
know that's just sort of my my opinion I
believe you have to know the science
behind what you're doing so let's let's
back up just a second for people who may
not be as familiar with micro isal
fungus as as you or I sure you mentioned
Ecto microa which uh as as you know
forms a relationship with conifers most
of our gardeners and Growers are going
to be wanting um Endo micro isal fungus
can you just give a quick right a quick
background on some of the benefits of
micro isal fungus sure well first of all
you know there's seven or eight
different kinds of micro risal Fung and
they're all defined based based upon how
they enter the plant uh and how they
relate uh inside the the the plant root
they as you know they don't these fungus
don't invade the cells of the plant they
are invaginated there's a
little an area formed around them and
then there's a transfer between the two
membranes between the fungus and the
plant ET so anyway depending how they
how they do that uh they get a different
name so there's an orchid micro risal
fungi and then there's the endom micro
risal fungi which are are invisible they
have to be stained in order to be seen
they have relatively large spores which
can be seen with a magnifying glass
quite easily and you can even C them out
of soil and then there's the Ecto which
have very small spores uh you know we've
all seen those little mushroom sport
prints they are Ecto micro risal fungi
are are visible you can see them uh as
they wrap around roots and you can you
can generally see their fruiting bodies
which are normally mushrooms or or or uh
you know underground mushroom like
structures now the Endo you're right are
generally for things that uh we would
grow in a garden row crops uh cannabis
those are all those would all be Ecto
crops and Endo endoc crops I I'm so
sorry yes thank you very much uh endoc
crops and there
are these two basic devides the endo and
the Ecto the Ecto were the were the fun
fungus it was the fungus that it made uh
you know plants able to grow on Earth
terrestrial land and uh they were 400
million years old or so the Endo are a
little bit later they're about 200
million years old and you know we've
really discovered that that even though
they're many many of them there's about
350 Endo Ecto mecar risal Fung that
we're aware of now we can only breed
about 8 to 15 of them in the laboratory
conditions and and fortunately for us
the endom micro risal fun fungi sleep
around with different plants so that
they can uh those same one that will uh
inoculate a cannabis plant will also
inoculate a carrot or a potato I hope
I'm right on that one I I I should
really go look that up before I say that
but so we're lucky that these eight or
nine ones that we're able to to produce
are able to to associate with a bunch of
different kinds of plants and if you
know the right one to use then you're
going to be golden so for example uh if
we may speak about cannabis since it's
legal in many states the the Endo micro
risal fungi for cannabis uh is readily
identifiable and very available and when
you pick up a package you can see
whether or not that package contains it
uh it's riseof fagus
irregularis that's one of the names
unfortunately because of the uh
inability to really be able to to
identify what they are up until the past
year or two uh they these things have
had various different names uh and now
what we've been able to do because we
can now do RNA and DNA testing on them
uh to give them their proper names now
we know exactly what to call them and so
over the next five or six years people
are going to have to change all their
labels uh but right now uh you know if
you buy the book for example you'll see
certain names and four or five years
from now those names won't be in use
anymore because now we're we're doing
DNA stuff so but in any case you can
look up on the web and find out what
micral fungi or Fung fungus your
individual plants might need and then
you can see if they have them on the
label and and put it down now when you
say put it down let's talk about best
practice in terms of a applying so you'd
mentioned applying it to seeds right
yeah I like to roll my seeds in them
well first of all let's back up a second
when you read the book of course I'm
giving all the great little Trade
Secrets away it's the plant that sends
the signal out to make the association
and the and the plant won't send that
signal out if it's already getting what
the micro isal Fung I will bring back to
the plant so if you're giving the plant
too much phosphorus or enough phosphorus
it's not going to make that signal if
you give the plant too much nitrogen
it's not going to send out that signal
so you got to make sure first of all
that you're not overdoing the the stuff
that you're already using once once you
make that determination and again really
you got to test your soil see what's in
it see what kind of levels you have Etc
everybody should be doing that again
that's the take-home for the second book
uh once you do that then there are
several different ways that you can
inoculate your uh your plants which is
is sort of a funny word because you're
really not inoculating your plant the
plant is calling for the fungus to come
and infect it but but we use the word
inoculation so rolling the seeds is one
way uh and certain plants for example
Orchids with their particular kind of
micro risal F fungi won't even germinate
unless they're in the presence of that
fungus not so with with cannabis and
carrots and you know tomatoes and that
kind of stuff but if you roll it on the
seeds it's right there so that as soon
as you get germination
the seed can send the seed root can send
that signal out you want to get early
early early inoculation yes so so tell
me what you think of this of this
procedure so yeah the way I look at
micro isal fungus is as a insurance plan
essentially so if my plant isn't getting
enough phosphorus uh I I'll know that
that micro isal fungus is in there as a
way to make sure that that happens and
fully realize that micro isal fungus has
a lot more benefit than just phosphorus
uptake right the way I look at it's a
it's a you know one or two time
application when I'm transplanting
directly to the root zone right I roll
the roots in them if I can or sprinkle
it right on the root yeah and I think
when we're talking about a high value
crop like a tomato or or a cannabis
plant that this seems like a a really
great option um and also another reason
to use maybe a little bit less nutrient
Rich initial propagation media
absolutely so that we aren't applying
too much phosphorus potentially
that's right yeah that's exactly right
your attitude is is a good attitude you
know if that's if that's your approach
to to the way you farm and garden and
and that is a good approach which is I'm
taking care of the plants I'm here I
want a little extra insurance okay some
people's approach is I really don't want
to I don't really want to do anything I
want the plant to do it all
itself you know and that's that's a
slightly different approach but I think
they're they both start the same way you
you have to inoculate the plant sure
make sure that that that it's impacted
uh or not infected so that you can do
either way the challenge I find is that
gardeners and Growers are all alike they
can't leave well enough alone they want
to Tinker and they want to keep they
want to feel like they're in control
it's that whole Miracle Grow right
Paradigm that you talk about in your in
your talks and in your book so uh right
knowing that just adding it just in case
and then giving the plant what 10 to 14
days for micro isal colonization before
you start doing any sorts of phosphorous
application as a good rule or what well
as long as as long as you can I mean it
can it can take you know up to two
months for for Sometimes some of these
things to work so you want to do it as
early as possible and you want to wait
wait as long as you possibly can but
you're but you're right I mean we we
have a tendency to think that we're in
control and and and that's okay there's
nothing wrong with that but it's but
it's one of the things that you know you
have to temper and it's and again it's
one of the reasons why I wrote the
second book teaming with nutrients which
is a book I wrote for myself not
necessarily for the general readership
and the reason why I wrote it is I
really didn't know how plants ate how
did they take stuff in how do they use
the food that the micro risal fungi
brings back to them you know what
happens inside those individual cells
and I was dumbfounded by the complexity
of what goes on inside cells I was
dumbfounded by the similarity of what
goes on inside the cell versus what goes
on in our universe and the the old
Horton hear a who kind of thinking
pattern is what I come away from after I
read that book uh and and it's the
reason why I'm sort of waxing about this
a little bit is because as you think
about your approach to gardening as you
think about what these micral fungi are
doing and when to put them on and and
how you want to use them and what you
want them to do your appreciation for
that can only multiply once you fully
understand the internal functionings of
a plant and I'm not talking about botney
you know I'm not talking about learning
pistols and stams and all that kind of
stuff I'm talking about you know how
what do they do with the stuff that you
give
them you know when that Michael risal
brings that phosphorus back what is the
what what does the plant do with it and
once you get that you you get an
appreciation of how the plant operates
then when you decide gee I'm going to
give the plant everything it can I want
a little bit of insurance or gee I'm
going to let the plant just do its own
thing you get a rationale for why you're
doing what you're doing does that make
any sense yeah no that makes a lot of
sense I think that's great what I find
interesting about that is you and I when
we met oh yeah decade almost um yeah
yeah on the compost T side well fact I I
I I probably changed your
diapers no no that's not true but I knew
your parents yeah so uh all those years
ago when we met yeah I had no
understanding of you know plant
physiology or or how how a plant uptakes
you uptakes nutrients and we were so
focused on the biological aspects in
nutrient cycling right and I I'd be
curious to hear now that you've written
team with nutrients it seems like you've
sort of broadened your approach to to
reincom some things like soil testing
for example yeah yeah I mean yeah I mean
you and I both know that uh uh you know
that you could you can most probably get
anything to grow in soil if you you know
but you know what's if you change the
biology we that's that's what that that
was our approach you know it was all
biology microbiology was the base and
etc etc and you moved on up that's
that's teaming with microbes and and you
didn't need to test the soil you just
needed to make sure that the biology was
good but if you do test the soil you can
not only adjust the biology you can you
can adjust what's in the soil for the
biology you know I mean it's uh you know
when I when when when I got on a a list
where once that was wrun by Steve
Solomon who wrote uh a series of books
that basically are Al brick oriented
balancing the minerals in the soil you
know he he he didn't really read the
book and he just s he gave me a lot of
grief uh because he says you know this
this doesn't work you gotta you got to
feed the soil you know and and he kept
beating up on Dr elain Ingam who he kept
saying uh you know he heard on numerous
occasions and whether whether she said
this or not I'm not putting words in
herth I'm just saying this is what he
heard uh you know that you don't need to
add any fertilizer you can you can grow
a plant in any kind of soil uh based
upon the biology and he didn't believe
that well you know I still think it's
true but I think it's easier if you can
also adjust the nutrients in the soil as
well you know what I'm saying I mean in
other words I I think I think yeah you I
don't think you really need to add
anything to no one ever fertilizes the
Redwoods as I always say but on the
other hand if you get a redwood and
you're growing it and you give it the
right biology but you also give it a
little bit of you know biology plant
food things do pretty darn good so yeah
I've changed my attitude a little bit
you know what's interesting about that
so just to give you a little background
I actually interviewed Steve uh I joined
his Forum a while back out after reading
the intelligent Gardener yeah because I
found it I found it fascinating and I
too had heard Dr Ingam claims
essentially that if you get the bio the
proper biology in place there are
efficient minerals in all soils M so
that uh you don't necessarily need to be
adding minerals which was what I think
Steve Took a front to I guess and it's
unfortunate that these two camps take
such opposing philosophies but I will
tell you in the last year uh I have had
Steve using uh erated compost teas and
experimenting with it and actually
really liking the results so yeah I
think well and he also you know he also
asked me at one point in time to come
back on the Forum because he finally
read the book and and decided GE maybe
this isn't so bad so yeah we're getting
there you know me maybe you and I just
need to push a little bit more on some
of these folks but uh uh there's there's
no reason to be so dogmatic about these
things that you can't listen to somebody
else yeah so coming from the background
that we have I'm learning more about
soil testing and I'm definitely uh a big
proponent of it now I'm finding that
it's very helpful when we're especially
when we're looking at container soils or
re amending potting soils that don't
have everything that you're going to
find in a traditional garden soil um
because it's all man-made don't you find
that the information is power I mean you
know if you've got information if you
don't use it you know what's going on in
your soil yes it's power and we know
that and we and you know gardeners know
that and every other aspect you know you
could be a stock broker and you're a
gardener and when you're doing your
stock stuff you get information when
you're doing the gardening oh my mother
did this you know that's not information
that's myth and you're right so you got
to you got to study this stuff and what
you do is absolutely correct so we're
not just buying the bag of tomato
fertilizer because it has a tomato on it
or the Cannabis bottle of nutrient
because it's you know it's recommended
but we're actually doing a little bit of
uh a little bit of research and have a
little more knowledge so that we can uh
right we can make better decisions yeah
you're cutting through the marketing so
for example I know your one of your
practices same my practice When I grow a
lot of different kinds of plants and
again I'll use cannabis as an example I
don't throw my soil away I don't reuse
my soil every single new pot what why I
can't understand why people do that it's
because they don't understand they don't
test and they don't understand what's
going on in their soil for their plants
you know and the reason why they don't
is because marketing doesn't want them
to sure you know they want you to buy
new everything every time it's crazy so
so on that note in in terms of the the
biological aspects of the soil since
this is an area that you're you're
really knowledgeable in uh can we talk a
little bit about uh compost teas and
nutrient cycling while I have you here
yeah sure yeah let's do it you know
again pretty controversial subject
Cooperative Extension Service would say
we're all you know we're crazy for even
talking about it uh any number of people
would think gee doesn't work etc etc etc
but why do you and I continue to use
compost tea are we C back when we
started it was an aquarium pump with an
AirStone yeah everyone did think you
know Dr Ingam was crazy and none of this
was was going to work and yet now
there's there's a ton of companies
selling compost te Brewers you see it at
more and more nurseries it's definitely
catching on oh no question about it and
there's no question that the uh the
concept behind it is catching on the
biological people are coating seeds now
there are companies that do nothing but
coat seeds with bacteria well you know I
mean the origins of that are compost tea
as far as I'm concerned so yeah you're
right the compost tea Brewers have
changed they used to use the one that
you felt and had drunk yeah we we've
learned an awful lot about this stuff
and a lot of it's because of guys like
you and Tim Wilson and and of course Dr
elain continues and you know carolan so
there's a lot of work continuing in the
area but yeah I love compost tea um and
there's no question in my mind that it
works let's talk a little bit about some
of the reasonings behind it can we give
people some of the theory behind why why
we're making compost tea and what it
does sure well yeah well let's start
with compost we know that compost is a
very effective growing uh Tool uh either
you grow directly in compost or you
amend your your soil media with compost
and we know the reasons why we know that
compost contains the fertilizer bags in
the soil food web which are the bacteria
and the fungus these are the bottom of
the soil food web and when they are
eaten by the fertilizer spreaders
protozoa and nematodes which are also
plentiful in compost the resulting waste
products contain nutrients nitrogen in
particular uh that feed plants because
it's in plant usable form that's the
first part of it the second part we're
beginning to understand is that when
these microbes die their bodies May in
fact and most probably are what create
humus because it's one of those things
that people have always been you know
what is humis and it's most probably the
dead bodies of these microbes so compost
te
contains because it's compost with
energy supplied to it that strips out
the bacteria in the fungus the nematodes
and the protozoa uh in some instances we
also feed them at the same time and
multiply them uh so compost te contains
the fertilizer spreaders and the
fertilizer uh bags that are in compost
that's about as simple as I can I can
make it and if we're feeding it while
we're making the compost tea uh getting
those to increase in numbers and or size
and so then when we apply the compost
teed to a plant either as a folar spray
or as a uh
drench those microbes then uh have an
opportunity to impact the soil food web
that feeds that plant perfect that
explains it well I I do want to clarify
one thing that I think is important for
listeners is to realize that not all
compost is created equal so that that
bag of compost that at Home Depot that
may have been sitting on the shelf for 6
months is probably not the same quality
as something uh you may pull out of your
your very own worm worm bin for example
um and that makes a huge difference when
we're making compost tea because yes a
good Brewer can only replicate The
Beneficial microorganisms that we put
into it that's right and there's
probably little question that what comes
out of your worm bin is better than yes
what you buy you know at these other
stores and and then we'll go one step
further I think a lot of us we like the
idea although it's not it's it's not
from my perspective uh something that's
should be written as a law but I like
the idea of indigenous microbes to the
extent possible I like I like to know
that the microbes that are brewing in
the tea come from my area because I know
that they're going to live now not all
of them have to be from there so when we
talk about micro risal fungi yeah we're
bringing in you know etc etc and you use
Alaska humus you bring in you know a
different set but by and large you want
to use your own compost I think but
that's just my opinion yeah no I I have
heard that something like
99.6% of so microbes are found pretty
much worldwide but in I assume in
different concentrations in different
areas so right uh things may be more
successful in your soil up in Alaska
than my soil here in the Seattle area uh
so that that does make sense and I think
even if you're using you know let's say
you don't have your own worm castings
and you know that you can Source those
commercially and they'll be you know you
know microbially active there's no
reason you couldn't add some of your own
compost or some of your own soil into
the brew as a way of uh inoculating your
your soil with that absolutely
absolutely I mean it it you know I guess
what we what what we're saying is if you
got to get compost from the store you
know make sure you get the best you
possibly can but if you can make your
own boy that's the best way to go that
sounds like a good rule I like that so
from that let's let's uh let's expand so
you have the you have the high quality
compost and you're going to feed that
with a food source whether it be
molasses fish
hydrolysate um whatever whatever product
you add to feed those microbes that are
in the compost we're putting it into a
brewer as a way to increase the
populations of those microbes and adding
oxygen and to strip out these guys
because they stick to the soil and so
you got to you got to strip them out and
you can't you know what I always tell
people is the stuff that's sticking soil
together starts with bacteria bacterial
slime it's the same stuff you're
brushing off your teeth in the morning
you don't get up in the morning and just
you know whoosh water over your teeth
you get up in the morning and you use
energy to strip that slime away from
your teeth and so that's what those
Brewers do energy to strip that stuff
away also to keep the oxygen up yes
great so here's here's a question I have
for you A lot of people see the plant
succession chart in your book and say
okay well I am growing yeah Tomatoes
Tomatoes they're going to want a
bacterial dominant soil so so they get
focused on making bacterial teas but in
your book you also and when you talk you
talk about how the plant really controls
this process of what it needs based on
the exudates it's putting out into the
soil so right is there any reason not to
just make a a balanced tea with good
nutrient cycling every time and let the
plant control that yeah that makes a lot
of sense let me back up for a second
though because you picked the wrong
example okay it turns out uh you know
that you can keep a tomato growing for
years and years and years and years is
it really an
annual H haha I don't think it is I I
think tomatoes are perennials and I I
mulch them with brown mulch but that's
just
me okay so uh but I understand what
you're saying uh you know the plant puts
out its own exudate in nature it
attracts what it needs the plant has the
ability to change its exate to attract
uh different things that it needs and so
yeah I mean I love the idea of
first of all when we talked about
reusing soil a lot of times I'll make my
tea out of a out of a soil that I or or
compost that I get out of a pot that's
grown a plant that I want to use the tea
on makes sense doesn't it I think I like
that I see um looking under the
microscope at at our different potting
soils and such if you use good compost
your your potting soil can have quite
High biological activity and there's no
reason you couldn't increase that in a
compost T Brewer so I I love that idea
yeah yeah well not only increase it in
Temple but but in theory again it's hard
to tell unless you get DNA testing you
know in theory you're multiply let's say
you're growing a tomato plant you use
soil from an old tomato plant in your
compost tea in theory you've got extra
dates from the tomato plant that
attracted the microbes that it wanted in
and so those microbes are in that stuff
you put in the microb tea and in theory
that's what's being multiplied some of
so giving the plant back again the very
kinds of microbes that it wanted in the
first instance which makes its job a
little bit
easier so is there any time you would
brew a fungal dominant tea or a
bacterial dominant tea because I see a
lot of these recipes online on various
forums and websites I haven't seen a lot
of microscope work to back a lot of
these recipes yeah yeah they're tough
and and uh I would you know if I was
trying to throw something on a tree
trunk that had a you know a weep on it
you know uh I would try to make it as
fungal as possible you know if I'm
throwing stuff down around perennials I
try to make it as fungal as possible
whether I'm achieving the fungal ality I
I don't really think I am but I'm trying
and at least what I think I'm doing is
I'm imparting into the tea the right
kind of substrate for fungus to be able
to use once it's down in the soil or on
the leaf so maybe I'm helping it in that
regard does that make any sense I think
so so we always want to try fungal teas
are are it's hard to get good fungal
growth in tees in general but overall
right that doesn't mean we're we're
losing any bacteria I've yet to see a a
tea with good fungus that didn't also
have you know relatively good bacteria
levels yeah yeah I mean my thought is
the bacteria levels basically stay the
same you know uh it's the fungus that
you increase so to speak the way not
just that's not really true I should
take that back but it's sort of what it
feels like yeah and ultimately it's a
shotgun approach so if we put out you
know a good diversity and and biomass of
uh right of beneficial microbes then the
plant can really control what it wants
the others will die you're not going to
hurt a plant by putting a a fungal tea
on an annual crop like like cannabis
right oh heck no and and as you say what
what's not used will die and will either
turn into humor or get eaten up by
something else in the soil food web so
it's all good you know all of those
little microbes whether they're used or
Not by the plant at least the microbes
themselves contain organic matter
contain nutrients they are retained into
in the soil system right at the root
level and when they die all the goodies
that are in them go to somebody else
eventually it ends up in the plant so
it's all good all right well while we're
on the subject of soil dominance I want
to kind of throw you a curveball
here let me just back up one other thing
I think ex extract is also something
people might want to think about I mean
I obviously I like compost post heas
better uh but a lot of people just want
to you know a couple of times a year
they don't want to make a they don't
want to they don't want to buy a kiss
Brewer you know they're crazy this is
the best thing in the world but you know
so so they take some cheesecloth and
they put compost in it and they just
knead it in water for 15 or 20 minutes
and they'll get good microbes in that
soup not they won't get the multiple
numbers that you get in a compost tea
but at least they'll get some of the
stuff out of the compost uh and they can
make sort of extract that that way so if
they want to just sort of fool around
with a a little bit they can try that
instead that's a great point it doesn't
have to be expensive it you don't
necessarily Tim Wilson on his microb
organic site has a stir method that he
lists that he's tested with a microscope
that people can use so right right right
right and people really need to go to
his site it's it's a great Psy got he he
really knows this stuff but okay yeah
yeah he's on my list for an interview as
well here here's the question when we're
talking about microbial dominance in
soil and we look at that plant
succession chart and I know you're a big
proponent of no H for for a lot of
reasons right uh I see that taking off
in the Cannabis Community now a lot of a
lot of cannabis Growers are doing that
and I just recently published a blog
post on the subject I am not completely
on board and I'll give you my reasoning
and then you tell me what you think so
we know that cannabis is an annual crop
it's going to prefer a bacterial
dominant soil that's why tilling is
effective in a lot of cases it's
unfortunately why they're tilling the
rainforest is to reset that soil and
Destroy some of that that soil structure
now the big problem I have with Rota
tilling is as as you know it creates
that compaction Zone um at the depth of
the tiller and completely destroys you
know fungal H and all of that but when
we're talking about indoor cannabis
growers in beds and containers we're not
getting out a roto tiller we're not
actually doing we're not actually
tilling the soil if we were to dig that
soil to allow us to get more nutrients
back into the soil rather than just top
dressing
continually I found in side-by-side
tests we seem to get better results
without the same levels of microbial
loss but I would love to get your
opinion on it yeah well again I mean
Roto tilling you're Absolut let's back
up for a second let me back for a second
you're absolutely right you want a
bacterially dominated uh uh situation
when you're growing cannabis uh and most
of our row crops for that matter um so
so what you're saying in theory could
also apply to your carrots and your
parsley and not parsley because that's a
banial but you know what I'm saying
apply to your row crops and things
you're on outside garden as well so what
you in the S what you're saying is Gee
is this no till make a lot of sense it's
not just what it does in terms of
bacterial versus fungal uh you know
there are other things going on in the
soil food web that we got to balance out
and I'm I'm you know this I'm just we're
just discussing it I'm not saying you
don't know this so for example when you
when you Roto till you chop up the micro
risal Network um and and destroy it and
so it has to reestablish itself self
that impacts the carbon that gets put
into the soil uh because the endom
micral fungi are coated with glomalin
that's where about 30 35% of your carbon
comes from it comes from those micro
risal fungi and if you mess up the
system by Roto tilling you know then
You' got a then you've got a diminution
in in carbon for example when you cut a
worm in half as I like to say you don't
get two worms you know unless you hit it
at the 18 segment you get two halves of
a dead worm uh and and if you hit it at
the 18th segment the first half lives if
you can believe that so so yeah so there
are other things that you do to the soil
food web I I understand what you're
saying and when you're when you're
talking about a uh a container grown
plant or a small bed grown plant I mean
we're really not talking about Roto
tilling we're taking a shovel and maybe
at Max double digging a a raised bed is
what I'm comparing yeah which is a very
different thing than Roto tilling you're
you're not pulverizing the soil are you
no you shouldn't be yeah you shouldn't
be yeah yeah I mean what you're doing is
you're opening up the soil and you're
adding in some amendments but basically
you got big gigantic clumps of it so you
know it goes under the rule of the least
disturbance possible least disturbance
possible would I would I Roto till if I
was growing in big beds no but would I
would I you know make sure that I had
the ability for my roots to be able to
grow part yeah I would you know I mean
I'd be I'd do a little bit of
disturbance wouldn't serp the entire bed
though and I certainly wouldn't throw
the soil away that's the other thing
sure I think we're both on board for
reusing the soil I just I find that it's
it's hard to provide because one of the
other issues with with indoor cannabis
or cannabis growing in these beds where
they're reusing the soil with no till is
that it's very hard to get in an organic
system all the dry nutrients down into
the the rizosphere
with zero downtime you're reusing that
soil you know 24 to 36 hours after you
pull a crop out of it that's right and
that's been the real challenge I think
with you know strictly not tilling or
disturbing the soil yeah and I think
people also don't understand the full
rationale behind the Edict of no till I
mean it's not necessarily because you're
screwing up let me correct myself it is
basically because we're losing our soil
because of Roto tilling that's the real
reason why the Department of Agriculture
says no till works and why it's so good
is because if you till in the middle
West that soil ends up in the East you
know that we have dust bow situations
and no till is we destroyed our soils by
tilling during the during the dust bow
and pre uh we created this situation
which we lost tremendous amounts of soil
so no till save soil so let's start
right there that's the most important
thing about it from a soil food Weare
perspective no till prevents damage from
from happening to the soil food Whip and
the third thing is there's a general
acknowledgement among organic people who
grow things that it is difficult to get
the solid stuff down into the soil food
web I like to I like to tell people gee
you put the compost on the surface I
think Elaine says the same thing uh you
know and in uh you know 18 months it's
worked its way down 8 10 15 inches
because of the soil biology yes well
that's fine that's fine if you want to
put the stuff down in the
fall and wait till Springtime but if
you're doing as you say a crop every
months blah blah blah you know maybe
that doesn't work so well then you have
to balance the the concept of loss of
soil which doesn't happen indoors right
sure uh so you don't have to worry about
that from a rotor tiller perspective uh
versus you know it's balanced off with
damage to the soil food web that you
want to maintain when you're doing an
indoor grow most of the soil food web
that you're really concerned about is
microbiological uh you know and micro
arthop as opposed to macro M would you
agree I would I mean I would I think
that's true would you agree yeah
definitely you know so so again the
concept of rotor tilling indoors doesn't
quite do the same amount of damage as it
would Outdoors you're not cutting the
worm in half so to speak uh you know the
the beetles that you want to make sure
are they making air holes and you know
you don't care about those on the indoor
growth so yeah you can disturb the soil
but I still wouldn't pulverize it great
great no it's good to get your opinion
on that now let let me let me just add
one other thing and that is when you're
ret teing with nutrients and again I
hope everybody does a very to me it's a
difficult book to read I mean the F the
first and the third book those are easy
books uh but but teaming with nutrients
required chemistry and nobody likes
chemistry nobody nobody likes the idea
of chemical formulas uh and then when
you start to get the idea that not only
you're going to have to know chemistry
but you're going to have to know the
photosynthetic formulas you know then
people back off and I want to just
assure everybody I did not ever want to
write about the kreb cycle or
photosynthesis and so that you will not
find that in teaming with nutrients but
it's a little bit thicker book to read
than the other two because it does
involve a little bit of chemistry and so
uh but I encourage people to read it
it's really important stuff and all
three of the books fit together and and
so you know hold your nose and just take
your time and read it
uh I forget why I was even mentioning
that something important you oh oh in
that book uh you know when I what what I
say is that when you start your systems
uh and if you're planting in the fall
and I mean you're preparing your soils
in the fall and getting ready in the
springtime you put a band of those
nutrients down just below the root
system so the roots can grow into it so
you anticipate it you put it down
already you know and then you put the
soil on top and then you don't rooto
till for four or five years because
you've got a nice layer of good Organics
and good nutrients down there so so
there are all sorts of ways to approach
it you could you could at let's say
you're doing a bed indoors you could put
your nutrients down at the bottom of the
bed and you're good for three or four
grows I would imagine interesting
interesting so that brought me to
another question because it got me
thinking about teaming with nutrients
because uh I've I've read that book a
couple times and the the biggest
challenge for me is the vocabulary
there's a lot of words that you're just
not used to hearing or pronouncing or
even remembering what goes with what so
that's and and that's you know you did
what you could with that but the the
words are what they are there's no way
you can change the vocabulary and what
and again what a shame what a shame that
we don't know those words because
they're words about what about what
happens inside plants you may not be a
vegetarian you know but that cow you're
eating is I mean everybody's the this is
what runs our world from oil you know
coal everything and we don't know the
VOC abary because they didn't teach it
to us in school because they didn't
think it was important it is and and for
our hobby it's very important I I agree
I I think it's it's it's a challenging
book like you mentioned but it's well
worth the time and I mean teaming with
microbes is sort of the the the Bible of
a lot of gardeners and Growers nowadays
and I think it only covers one aspect
like you mentioned of this whole process
and and I think you've grown and learned
and changed your philosophies even since
you wrote it I mean that book when did
you write that book it had to be over
what 10 15 years ago yeah 2006 is when
the first edition came out and then the
revised Edition came out
201 11 I think and and you're right and
and what I what I discovered and I hope
everybody else discovers this as well
because I don't want to write any more
books uh uh you know when you write a
book it's like yeah you know you go in
this little teeny rabbit hole and you're
down there and that's it you're down
there till you're finished and so you
know what I got out of it was enough
tools between the three books because I
learned I didn't know any of this stuff
you know I mean I got enough tools I
think to be able to sit down and be able
to piece together things and so when
people ask a question for example and
you're the same way now I can see well
let's see under from a soil food web
perspective this is part of the answer
you know but from a nutrient perspective
that's part of the you know it's and and
I've got enough tools to be able to
figure out what I need to what I need to
know and where to go when I don't know
it's it's amazing Google folks is the
best gardening tool there is I have to
say yeah so one one thing from teia
nutrients that I took away was that
there's a few different ways that a
plant can uptake nutrients right um and
and the biological aspect is just is
just one of those ways I what got me
wondering a little bit more about humic
and fulvic acids because a lot of
gardeners and Growers are using them and
swear by them as I understand it the
hemic mo molecule is a little bit larger
in keates or bonds with these minerals
and then the fulvic molecule allows it
to be taken directly through the
cellular wall into the plant is that
correct yeah I think it can you explain
that a little bit better than I just did
I think it's well I I think it's broken
down so that it can be taken in uh I
don't think it goes in as fulvic acid
per se but I I could be wrong in that
regard first of all let me let me
suggest God I'm saying that an awful lot
aren't I first of all let me back up
carbon in your soil is not coming from
the umic acid the fulvic acid that's
133% it's coming from the micro risal
fungi it's coming from the glomalin that
the micro risal fungi are putting out
into the soil which is another reason
why you don't necessarily want to
disturb the soil too much that glomalin
is there uh and and when the branches of
the fungi die off of course I guess it
doesn't really matter fungi is dead
anyway but um so if you're rotor tilling
soil that's already you know been
harvested it probably doesn't make that
much difference that's where your
carbon's coming from but as far as the
acids are concerned the um the umic and
fobic acids they go into the plant
through the membranes and just I guess
to make it easy the membrane your every
cell in the plant has a membrane around
it and the membrane has different little
proteins in them and these proteins act
like uh tunnels or pipes or revolving
doors depending on what kind of protein
they are to allow different kinds of
nutrients and and substances to get into
a plant and each individual protein will
only allow one kind of molecule through
it so a phosphorus well a phosphorus you
know molecule will not be able to go
through the tunnel that's been designed
for nitrogen and so uh Boron for example
has its own tunnel yeah every one of the
nutrients has its own individual way of
tunneling into or getting into these
individual and folic acid goes through
one of those tunnels probably not as
fulvic acid but but probably as as
broken down and then it's constituted as
fobic acid once it's inside but I could
be wrong in that regard I'll have to
look that up or think about that a
little bit but so that that's why when
before we were talking on the show we
were talking about the idea that there
are uh you know 62 different nutrients
in kelp but your plant takes in 18
different nutrients into those cells so
what happens to the rest of that stuff
well the rest of that stuff may be in
the area that is between the cell walls
so there's there's the ability for
nutrients to get into a a a a root get
into the actual cell itself so it's
swimming around in the cytoplasm in the
cell and it can go from one cell in the
root all the way through the plant from
cell to cell to cell to cell not going
through xylm or folm or any of that kind
of stuff but just through the cells and
it can go all the way up to the to the
tip of the plant through the cells and
then there's the that's called the
simplest then there's the apoplast which
is the system of uh
structure on of the cell walls so that
if you got into a cell wall in the root
of the plant in theory you could hike
from cell wall to cell wall to cell wall
to cell wall never getting inside the
cytoplasm inside the cell never going
through that membrane and also find
yourself all the way up at the tip of
that plant so a lot of the things
including folic acid and other things
may in fact reside in those areas of the
plant where they're useful and helpful
for the microbiology that's you know
helping operate the plant and feed the
plant etc etc etc it's a Trippy
[Applause]
world so do you see a lot of benefits to
say foler applications using fulvic acid
in a particular nutrient I know Steve
Solomon likes to say if your plant is if
you think your plant's deficient in
boron then do a foler application of of
boron or copper or manganese or whatever
particular micronutrient we're
discussing yeah you know I'm not I'm I
mean I I think they have their purpose
uh I am not a I'm not a big fan of
feeding your plants Fuller and I I'm not
I don't even Boron I'm not sure Boron
even ah you know some of the nutrients
are mobile some of them are not mobile
um and they're all listed in the book
Etc you know it was a very complicated
what one of the hardest things I had to
do when I was researching the book was
which which which nutrients are mob are
really mobile and which ones aren't
mobile because some people think that
you can put any nutrients on the leaves
and all of them will travel to where
they need to go in the plant and that's
that not true and you know some people
think none of them travel Fuller other
than you know three or four or five
cells away so it's you know um so I'm
not a big I'm not a real big opponent of
it in fact I got some stuff sitting here
somebody wants me to test you know they
sent me a bunch of stuff it's a foler
some kind of foler nutrient food okay
I'll test it you know I don't I don't
know why the science would change but
I'll try it it's made in Holland so what
the heck you
know can it hurt the plant generally no
and I and and I could very well be wrong
because I usually am so maybe it'll even
help the plant so I'm not I don't want
to discourage people from trying but I
think people have to test I think
testing is important too so when you
talk about that you mean setting up an
experiment and having a control and
making sure that you're comparing Apples
to Apples yeah if you can or finding
somebody else who did you know again you
can go on on Google Scholar and find
tremendous amounts of information in
tests and etc etc and then and then you
can sometimes you can contact
manufacturers and talk to them about how
they do their stuff you know or you find
people like you I mean you're testing
all the time you put your stuff up in
blogs and things like that you know Tim
Wilson he tests all the time and you
know people just people need to you know
pay attention little less of the lerve
of uh you know you know people talking
about how big their vegetables are and a
little bit more about how they got there
well I think that the Cannabis industry
has come a long way in that regard
especially because it was such an
underground industry in a lot of in a
lot of states there really wasn't a lot
of research and testing and just shared
knowledge beyond what was going on in
some of these some of these forums and
that information was really all
speculation for the most part so it it
we're starting to a lot more research
and testing coming out which I think is
is amazing well I think it's mandatory
it's so important uh and I and and one
of the great things about the Cannabis
industry is that it can only go one way
and that is organic using that I'll use
quotes around that if if you want me to
but no State
regulator you know wants their state
cannabis to be full of pesticides and
bad things and so and no grower I think
wants to to
being bibing their own stuff full of bad
things and so it's wonderful for for for
the soil food web business seems to me
and all the more reason why people need
to understand what's going on so that
they you know they can control if that's
the proper word uh the environment so
that they don't need to have bad things
and if you want to reuse your soil it's
important that you're not putting a lot
of you know mineral salts onto it that
would require a ton of leeching to
remove yeah oh absolutely absolutely I
mean again I I don't even think about it
I mean I've I've always reused my
soil I just don't understand why people
would throw away good organic soil you
know I guess the thought process is the
nutrients have been sucked out of this
soil really is that possible uh you know
A and B so what you know it's everybody
should understand and again this is one
of the lessons out of the second book
there's so many lessons in that second
book even though God it's not my
favorite of the three you know I mean
the normal rule is called the law of
return the law of return is what
operates in nature so the reason why
nobody feed the Redwoods is because when
their needles drop they go through the
soil food web process they're recycled
the nutrients that are in those leaves
uh you know are recycled and go back
into the plant nothing is lost between
the lip and the cup when you're growing
a crop you're you're breaking the law of
Return by removing the stuff that
normally would go back into the soil and
put the nutrients back in again okay if
you understand that you're breaking the
law of return then you put yourself on
parole and you you put this stuff back
in some form or fashion either either by
using a chemical fertilizer if you're a
chemical head or by putting in
substitute organic material if you're a
soil food Webby and there there you go
simple as that it's it's the law of
return it's the law of return and if
you're broken it you know then it's
nothing's going to work doesn't matter
whether you're a chemical head or
whether you're you know and so your soil
of course is great stuff it's just got
that little teeny missing piece put it
back yeah so every time we harvest the
plant we're pulling out organic matter
we're pulling out nutrients we can
replace those and the advantages if I
understanding correctly of replacing
these these nutrients and reusing the
soil is that we get we get soil
structure in our in our old reused soil
and we also get uh nutrient cycling and
all these beneficial microbes working
together rather than starting from
scratch well I guess there's two other
things I would add I hope I can remember
the second one the first is of course is
that you've got the microbes there in
that soil already they're dormant
perhaps but you've got the makings of
what the plant was using while it was
alive and so if you're planting the same
kind of plant in that soil again you
know it doesn't have to try to attract
you know the French microbe that it
needs all the way from France because
it's already in the pot or in that soil
bit and then the second thing of course
is that soil is if you do it right it's
it's not only
structurally mature but it's got a setup
designed or a condominium already built
for new Roots so for example if I was
growing a tomato or cannabis in a you
know pot when I har Harvest it I cut the
plant at the base I don't pull the roots
out all the organic matter that's in
that root is there all of the nutrients
and all of that have flown towards that
root system as a result of mass flow one
of the ways that nutrients gets the all
of the uh microbes in the rizosphere are
still there
and when I plant the roots of the N
plant will follow into the tunnels and
byways and Pathways of the old plant
because it's easier for it therefore it
expends less energy so you get you get a
lot of benefits by reusing that soil not
the least of which is you're saving
money and of course on top of everything
else you're being sustainable which is
ultimately what we all need to be great
so I I don't want to take up too much
more of your time my last question would
just be what's what what's probably the
most common question you ask with with
all the talks that you're giving around
the country and with the all all three
books out now uh what what are Growers
asking you can I get the book on Amazon
or do I have to buy it more expensive
from
you that's the question they ask me and
of course they get over uh it's not fair
right no of course they can buy it from
Amazon uh and should what what I don't
care who who where you get it you should
just buy them I think the number one
question I I get from Growers it's a
tough one and I think you you know a way
you sort of alluded to it and that is
it's awfully hard to be organic because
you're using you're using solids versus
liquids I don't know if that makes any
sense but the there is a perception that
using the chemicals because they're in
liquid form they go right to the root
system instantly it's easier and it's
quicker and it's less mus and fuss and
you know it's better for your plant
because they get the stuff right
away versus gee you know if I'm putting
stuff down in my soil it takes so long
for it to get there and you know unless
it's bat guano the nitrogen is not going
to be available for six months and all
you know I think people are concerned
about the timing aspect of Organics and
I always tell tell them just calm down
well so there are lot a lot of Growers
are making various types of nutrient
teas now too um and certain things like
fish hydrolate like you mentioned Banos
there are there are other organic
liquid nutrients that are are a little
faster acting I I would say the big
difference for me is ionic versus non-ic
forms of nutrients so yeah like you
alluded to is that nutrient immediately
available in an organic in organic
growing system no you know we may be
waiting 7 to 14 days for that plant to
respond well even biologically that
happens I mean it takes it takes 10 to
14 days for those parium you know to
start eating those bacteria down there
you know going crazy so
yeah I mean it's uh there's no question
there's a place for tea nutrients no
question in my mind but if you you know
you should be starting with great
composted mixed soil or pure compost
with good drainage if you start with
great stuff that's got great nutrients
in it to start with because you've
tested it you've fed it you've given it
what it needs uh either either directly
or or you know through the compost
system then you should be good to go as
long as you understand understand the
law of return and I think the other
thing where Growers get stuck is they
think that they can go with that
chemical Paradigm of giant plant in a
tiny pot which just doesn't work for
Organics you have to give the plant
enough soil yeah if you want to grow it
organically and that's been a big
challenge I think for a lot of Growers
that try and do a full cycle plant in a
one or two gallon container and want to
know why they're unsuccessful yeah
because they're used to Hydroponics you
know where they can it's just different
when you're using soil and again you
have to understand how the plant
operates you don't understand how the
plan operates unless you read about it
because they didn't ever teach us this
stuff in B in botany and that's the down
that's the downside I I I never really
took formal botney courses I've looked
at Botany books obviously they just
didn't teach us this stuff how to think
about this stuff and as more and more
people are growing and coming back to
Growing the thing about cannabis is it's
it's it's the new tomato I think and the
plant is becoming we were having a
little blip now with Jeff sessions yeah
yeah you know all that kind of stuff but
but as the plant becomes legalized in
all 50 states which it certainly will
the idea growing these plants won't just
be for medicine or for the high they're
beautiful plants they're easy to grow
they're interesting plants they have
different colors different Leaf shapes
you know they're an ornamental plant and
they're bringing people back to growing
things again and you can't help but
start to grow some you know basil you
know all of a sudden cuz you hey what
the heck you know I'm and it's a war
wonderful thing that's happening with
this cannabis stuff but the best thing
from my perspective is it's I think it's
altering how people are looking at
botney it's got to include the roots as
Dr Lane would like to say I think it's
got to include the soil food web and and
and now that I've written a Trilogy of
books and I can call myself Lord of The
Roots I so
speaketh wonderful well I again I really
appreciate your time today Jeff it was
it was great just even just catching up
with you and I'm glad we got to talk
about some of these things so uh well
you know we don't we don't get to see
each other enough you know but I got to
tell you all my slides have little kiss
in it here and there you know I'm always
thinking
OFA thanks Jeff for taking the time to
chat today all the way from Anchorage
Alaska Jeff's books teaming with
microbes teaming with nutrients and
teaming with fungi are all available on
our website at
www.k organics.com or on Amazon as a
digital download you are listening to
the Cannabis cultivation and science
podcast I'm your host host Tad hussy
stay tuned for future podcasts from
leading experts around the industry
don't forget that there's more
information and articles available on
our website and blog at
www.k organics.com and if you enjoy
these podcasts please take a moment to
leave me a review on iTunes and send me
your feedback and suggestions through
our website contact page