[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad hussy
of Kiss Organics this is the podcast
where we discuss The Cutting Edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge this is part two of my recent
interview with my good friend Suzanne
way wri Evans also known by many as the
bug lady if you haven't listened to part
one of this conversation or any of our
other podcasts with me I highly suggest
checking them out she's an ornamental
entomologist specializing in integrated
Pest Management Susanna has been
involved in the green industry for more
than 25 years with a primary focus on
biological control and using pesticides
properly she is a grad uate of the
University of Florida with degrees in
both entomology and environmental
horiculture suzan has been on the
podcast multiple times and please do go
back and listen to some of her other
podcasts if you haven't already her
website is buglady consulting.com where
you can find links to other webinars
podcasts and information as well as how
to contact her for direct Consulting now
on to the
show so a couple of things that you've
taught me again correct me if I misspeak
uh around oils and the reason that you
like sufff oil which is mineral oil
based also montere Garden horticultural
oil is because uh it has uh less REI
requirements um it biodegrades faster
and it's something that you can spray
pretty easily and it has a lot of data
showing its Effectiveness uh there is a
new product called EP Shield um we're
working with them right now to try and
get into this smaller container size so
that it can be available to a wider
range of Growers uh and that product has
no
REI um and smells phenomenal and it's
Botanical based uh so and there's a lot
of data to support it but um that's one
of the advantages of these oils is that
they work as a suffocant and so the the
pest can't really develop a resistance
to them like they could something that
has a you know neural effect or or other
mod of mode of action um do you want
to correct anything there well I mean
you're absolutely right on you know the
the stff oil I mean one of the reasons I
like that too is because of particle
size it's a very small particle oil um
so that when you spray you just spray a
Mist you do not spray to runoff and you
have such fine thin particle layer it
can coat very tiny insects and mites um
that's why it works really well on area
fiad mites and even area fied eggs is
because you have just you know billions
of these tiny particles that can coat to
suffocate the eggs and um the the the
adults larval stages all those different
things um and so far we've not seen any
resistance to it and that's what I also
like I also like that once it's dry you
can release beneficials there's no
residue from it and ites doesn't clog
pores or stroma in your plants I mean we
you know as long as you use it according
to the label um you know you're not
going to have any issues with it it's
when people accidentally like oh my gosh
I applied it at you know a 4% rate and I
burned my plants or I sprayed it noon
you know those kinds of things um the EP
Shield is super interesting um because
it does have plant Botanicals but they
don't understand completely how
Botanicals always work as
pesticides um and so the exact mode of
actions are always not worked out on all
these compounds they just know they work
um and they break down quickly um
because uh they are uh derived from
plants and generally aren't very stable
ones applied
um uh
so we we again the EP Shield is
interesting because we don't don't fully
understand all the mo of actions of it
but it's the right combinations of
different things that the the the trials
have been excellent with it on mites um
especially two spot spidermite all life
stages and it's been looking very good
on cannabis aphid 2 without having an
REI um on it that
said you know if you have allergy
problems as I do that doesn't mean you
could not have a reaction from some of
these uh compounds um I've actually in
recent years because I've done so much
work with hibiscus the years when I go
into hibiscus greenh houses I tend to
now have some respiratory stuff
happening um because long-term low dose
exposure to anything uh can trigger
allergens over time um so even though
they have a zero
REI and don't have the restrictions I
would still it still is a pesticide and
I still would you know treat it with
respect and one of the nice things about
those two products that you you touched
on too is uh less risk of phytotoxicity
and lower you're using much lower
concentrations of active ingredients
than you might with other commercially
available products on the market would
you say you're making a face at me I
mean I I've one of the things I've seen
when reading about let me clarify this
maybe active ingredient was the wrong
word the the concentrations that you're
you're able to spray from what I've seen
is much lower and I'm getting this from
reading on the bioworks website with a
product like epich Shield than some of
the other commercially available
products how would you phrase that
better than I just did so
um just
like other thing you can buy different
things in different
concentrations and generally Big Egg buy
stuff more concentrated and dilute it
more homeowners pesticides are generally
more
dilute um and so that they because when
you mix up super concentrated
things and you mess it up a little bit
it can be disastrous because those are
so concentrated so sometimes dealing
with more dilute things are easier for
mixing does that that make sense yeah I
think what I was getting at is the
concentration needed for efficacy so Epi
yes so Epi Shield the way the product is
made um it takes a lot less active
ingredient to see the results than you
would with seoil x suffoil x typically
you're at a 1 to
2% active ingredient per set amount of
water so if you have 100 gallons of
water you're going to add one to two
gallons of suffoil X into it and you're
going to see efficacy there because of
the active ingredients in Epi Shield its
rate is
0.1% so it's you need a lot less of it
in order to see efficacy when you mix it
up the concern I have with that
is when you if you're a hom grower or
doing small amounts and you're going to
mix up one gallon if you get your rate
just slightly off it's going to be a
huge mistake um and can then cause burn
because you you uh are putting out too
much suffoil X um again you've got more
wiggle room on mistakes there and that's
why um if you go by biow Works booths at
trade shows they're providing syringes
to help measure because if you're trying
to pour out a tablespoon or a teaspoon
you know I do this because I do a lot of
candy making I pour you know cinnamon
oil into a spoon and they pour it out
and I'm like wow how much is really
staying behind and it's stuck to that
spoon because you're getting that full
amount and so that's why I think the
syringes are a much better way to
measure um for a homeg grower anybody
that's you know mixing up anything under
10 gallons of of product because um it
would be very easy to make a mistake on
the Epi shield and burn your plans um
also doing the math okay cannabis
Growers stop contacting me asking me to
figure out your rates for small amounts
for
you you um I math is not one of my
strongest points bio works for their
products does have a rate calculator on
their website that you can put in the
product you're using and how much you
want to make and it can help calculate
that for you also today with you know Ai
and all that stuff they can easily um M
do your rates for you but with the EP
Shield again a little more because more
is better is not good in this situation
you really need to stay with that um
recommended labeled rate for that
product so in my head what I was
thinking of with my comment about
concentration
was more was less comparing suffoil and
EP Shield but comparing EP shield and
suffoil to other commercially available
products less with epy Shield a lower
concentration of final applied product
that you're less likely to see compared
to other Botanical 25b products on the
market that don't have as much research
around them you're less likely to see
phytotoxicity or other issues and still
get the efficacy that you want um at the
end of the day that's what I was okay
yeah because you're you're putting out
less
AI um active ingredient not artificial
intelligence but you're putting out less
active ingredient and still getting the
results um for a good price point CU you
know at the end of the day Money Matters
on the cost of these things and I know
some people when they look at the cost
of epy Shield they're like oh my gosh
it's a tiny bottle it's so expensive but
you have to realize at the rates you're
going out at are very low um and so it
it doesn't take as Much Chemistry to
kill because of the not completely
understood ways it kills compared to an
oil or even a soap that you need a
higher percentage to smother and
activate it but yeah I think I think
when it comes
to um these
um plant Botanical
based uh products I think EP Shield's
going to I think it's going to take over
the market and that's going to be the
one standing um because of all the I
mean it's it's been a really really good
product now one thing it's not as
effective with as I understand it is
with uh
thrips that are pupating inside the leaf
tissue like whereas
with you're making faces at me I making
faces at you this is good this is good
cuz I I am not an expert here and I'm
learning myself so as I understand it uh
thrips can
can lay eggs inside of the leaf tissue
of cannabis and then when they emerge
there is some efficacy with seoil but
that is you don't get that efficacy with
EPA shield now please correct me if I'm
wrong on that okay so epy Shield was
originally the market was going to be a
midde that's you know where the focus
was but as the product's been used um
we've seen activity on other end insects
and that's where it's like wait a minute
you know it's knocking back a it's
pretty good um with rips you are correct
most not all thrips but most thrips do
lay their eggs inside of plant tissue
Western Flower thrips onion thrips Ayo
thps um parvy spinus they lay their eggs
in the plant tissue now there has been
some new information and I feel like a
dumbass because I didn't know this and
apparently there was some research done
in Canada looking at suffoil
x and they did find and I I'm I'm
guessing this didn't get published um
and our our buddy Mr MB over there is
the one who told me about this and he's
like well how do you not know this
Suzanne um they found with stff oil they
were able to kill about
50% of Western Flower thp's eggs why is
because when insects lay their eggs
inside a plant tissue and if you come
doing my presentations you know I've got
videos of like oras inserting their eggs
and things like that they they leave the
tiniest bit of the eggs sticking out and
that's where the air exchange is
happening they're respirating through
that little tip there and if you put an
oil over it it suffocates the eggs just
the same way as if an egg is laid on a
plant surface and you cover it with an
oil it will suffocate it because they do
need to respirate so this is some newer
information that the suffoil can and
again the work was only done on Western
Flower thrips which you know we
generally do not find in cannabis um uh
but it's very interesting now I don't
know if they
have done any of the work looking at egg
efficacy with epy Shield my guess is
leaning towards no because I don't think
it's as much as a Suffocation mode of
action and it's more of a chemical um
you know I don't want to say it akin to
pyrin but something's happening with
those
Botanicals um in there and the other
ingredients but I I don't think they
know because they haven't looked at it
because for years we've always said you
know no pesticides kill um Western
Flower thrips eggs but then all of a
sudden Boop wait a minute no oils can
kill like 50% of the eggs but after they
do hatch and I think where you're going
for with the not all that's that's where
I was going actually because I talked to
Michael two weeks ago and he explained
this to me so that was what I was trying
to say but they don't the the pupa is
not in the leaf tissue okay so depending
on the thrip species some drop to the
soil to pup
others pupate on a leaf surface but they
don't go back into the tissue to
pupate okay that makes sense so I you
were close screwed it up but I was close
it was just one word but that's okay I
mean no that's that's good that's good I
and I appreciate the correction because
that's how I learned too um on that note
with thrips one of the things that
Brandon shared with me from from one of
your workshops was that or webinars was
that you're seeing a higher incidents or
or primarily onion thrips now in
cannabis not now I've always found onion
always onion thrips okay so some of our
management options should not be based
around Western Flower
thrips Behavior yes or life cycle yes um
I if you go out online a lot of people
talk about Western Flower thrips and
Canabis and I mean it's because they're
not doing their due diligence collecting
samples and identifying things I not
going to say you cannot find Western
Flower thrips and cannabis um but every
sample well let me just say this I I
have not gotten a Western Flower thrips
sample from a cannabis grower I found
other thri species um and we just had
you know you were mentioning before
about oh you've always got interesting
stories you know I just had a a thing
not too long ago with somebody had
another consultant in there the
consultant told him they had Western
Flower thps they wrote him this whole
thing about managing Western Flower
thrips um I went in behind this other
person in his facility and immediately
I'm like those are weird thrips um and
they were absolutely they did weren't
even close to being Western Flower
thrips cuz so Western Flower thrips and
onion thrips you almost have to micro
put them under a microscope and slide
mount them to tell them apart um because
you have to look at the positions of the
hairs on the pronotum you have to look
at the sil ey color those are the spots
on the top of their head you have to
count antennal segments and you have to
do all that to tell them apart I think
people are just doing quick looks and
doing quick picture matches um so I mean
I could understand where people would
get onion thrips and Western Flower
thrips confused that's easy but this
thrips wasn't even close um
and
uh I had to reach out for help because I
could only get it to genus um and it's a
species that hasn't even been really
described in the last report of it was
in the
1960s um
and so my point is on on the thrips is
you have to do your due diligence and
identify which one it is so that you can
put a better Management program together
um and this is true ornamentals
vegetables cannabis everybody um
because uh onion thrips and Western flow
thrips do have
different chemistries that work on them
differently because of resistance issues
um the biology between onion thrips and
Western Flower thrips are very similar
but once you start getting into a kind
of thrips and this other thrip species
um they're not the same biologies so um
you just you know you got to stop
guessing and you've got to stop matching
pictures of just people's quick pictures
online um because you're going to end
you're going to get yourself into
trouble so we're we're already getting
run out of time here I had a few other
questions for you maybe I just wanted to
skip to do you have any other sort of
stories of common misidentifications or
where these improper application rates
cuz I know you and I have talked off air
and you've talked about how like
sometimes people will work with a
consultant or a thirdparty distributor
of of beneficials like myself that
supplies you know we sell biob insects
for example and they might prescribe
rates that are wildly too high or too
low to get control um so people may
either be wasting money or they may be
spending money but not enough to get
actual control at based on the size of
their
crop I mean I think the problem with the
rates is if somebody calls me and
they're like hey you know I've got two
spot spider M and I want to control a
pmus what's the
rate it's it's there's not an easy
answer
because is a propagation where your
plant is an inch tall or are they 10-ft
palm trees and so rates can be all
across the board I know I know companies
try to put out a
basic middle of the road kind of rate
but you really if if you just call
somebody and they don't ask you more
about you know what you're spacing how
tall the crops even Leaf texture can
make a difference um we're talking about
spider mites like in tomatoes uh pmas
really struggle to get through those
tricomes so you really have to up your
rates of per simulus in tomatoes
compared to Tropical foliage because you
have that smooth Leaf surface where they
can run around it's like ice skating for
them so there's a lot of variables that
go into rates um and so that's why it's
important to talk with somebody and it
does not have to be me um but talk with
somebody that's
really
understands these systems and you know
takes the time to ask you questions to
figure out what the right rate for what
you're going to to need is now when it
comes to Hom grows homeowners you got
five or six plants you can afford to put
out insane numbers of mites because even
like pilus I think the smallest they
come in really is like
2,000 and that that covers a lot but you
know you're talking maybe 15 bucks you
know so a homeowner's like yeah I can
afford that for my commercial Growers
when we need to treat like 50 acres you
we really like have to get the numbers
exactly right because if not it gets
very expensive very fast so there's all
these variables that go into making um
rate recommendations and that's where I
really you know working with a lot of
bug people out there um you know the
guys from biob guys from beneficial
insectary um you know um copert um
biobest you know of all these different
companies
most of their people have had a better
experience and that can take the time to
help put those better rates together
what we did see happening is when
cannabis legalization happened there
were some unscrupulous people that are
like well cannabis don't know any better
and they were selling them ridiculous
rates of products I mean it it was
insane and in charging Crazy
Prices like for what my girl are paying
14 cents for I saw Growers paying $2
cannabis Growers paying $2 for which I
just have zero tolerance for that kind
of you know gouging um I think that the
Cannabis scores have become more
educated on bios and even chemistries
and how to purchase and they're buying
for more traditional suppliers or
they're getting better pricing these
days um but we pesticides the label is
the law the rates are right there it's
easy to figure out bio rates are very
subjectives and um you really need if if
you're new you need to work with
somebody that can help guide you um on
the program because again there's a lot
of variables that go into making these
rate
decisions yeah and I just wanted to do
one quick Shameless plug because we do
work with biob and Ship Direct from
insectary and when we have situ with
like a facility or someone U you
mentioned you know you're not the only
one that can do this frankly you can't
do this for everyone um so if you can't
afford to have Suzanne come out uh one
of the resources that we do have is uh
Kelly Vance and Saul Alba with biob both
excellent um technical advisers and uh
friends of Suzanne and so uh it's been
great to be able to use them as
resources at least with helping our
company and and other companies should
have someone similar something similar
that would allow you to get uh better
dialed rates for what you're doing um in
your facility or even in your home grow
I love
Kelly yeah I mean I you guys are good
friends I I've known him a long time um
and um he's a real I mean Saul's awesome
too but I know Kelly much better I've
known him a lot longer um and I'm I'm
always proud to walk into a greenhouse
with Kelly next to me because he's not a
bullshitter he is you know he was a
grower he he knows um he's been in your
shoes and so he doesn't want to be taken
advantage of um so he doesn't take
advantage of people he's a he's a really
good
guy yeah so if you're listening to the
podcast and you'd like to know more
about insects or get in touch with with
these guys as well uh please don't
hesitate to reach out to me directly I'd
be happy to make that
connection Okay so moving on last
question of the day I'll let you get
back to your day
um common misidentifications that you
see in the Cannabis
industry um I know a lot of times people
will at least online say like what is
this and it turns out it's um like a
mold Mite that may have been introduced
when they introduce beneficials or
another one would be springtails that I
see things that are not necessarily of
um considered pest
within
um within within your within your garden
I don't know what what are your thoughts
um I think the Cannabis grows have
gotten a lot better um I I've saved on
my computer that in the early days of
legalization somebody put out this ID
manual and for their fungus naap picture
they had a winged aphid and I think that
started everybody off onto the wrong
footing um because people were trying to
be helpful but they put out a lot of
misidentification and there's still a
lot
of bad ID photos online um I've seen
pictures of pilus that are actually
velvet mites
um so I mean again I think the Growers
have gotten better um they they've
learned from coming to classes whether
it be my classes or you know hearing
talks from again like Kelly or Stephen
authors um they've gotten better so
there's less
misidentification um but there is still
confusion between fungus knats and um
winged rude aphids that does come up um
broad mites and area fied Mite sometimes
can be a little confusing um for for
Growers if you don't have enough
magnification uh to look
at um I also think another thing that
periodically comes up and it's not a
pest issue but their concerned it is is
if is
um insects from outside flying in and
then flying up to the lights and then
dying and then falling back onto the
plants I've had that a handful of times
now where people think they're these
weird insects on their plants
and excuse me they're typically some
kind of mge um that have come from some
fresh water that got sucked in some
somewhere and they come in and die but
because of the tricomes they stick to
the
plants and so those can be mistaken
sometimes for fungus Nets but you have
to look at you know the venation on the
wings um to be able to tell these
different species apart but I do overall
I mean I think the Cannabis SES are
getting smarter um they're getting
better um they've done a really good job
of of um getting educated but just make
sure you're getting education from good
sources um because there there's still a
lot of bad information out on the
internet and the stuff in the internet
just never goes
away on that note of bad information one
last friendly reminder uh to not buy
ladybugs and in my opinion please don't
support the companies that are sending
them for free in with their product or
selling them now there are a few there
there is some commercially rear lady
ladybirds available now correct but it's
rare well it's not that they're rare
it's they're expensive because they have
to rear them um which um I'm waiting to
see on the permit uh but we might may
have some other ladybird species
available on the market this year um
more to report on that um and also which
this is kind of important um if you're
looking for ladybug alternatives
micromus which are the brown lace wings
um beneficial inory and applied
bionomics now have permits for the US um
it's not that it's a it's not a new
species to the United States it's here
already in the environment it's that
they have the permits to sell them here
in the
US um and um it's it's a little bit
state byst state basis so you have to
check to see if they're available in
your state but why BR Brown lace wings
are
interesting is they are as their their
cousins I going use it
usely to to to try to put in perspective
they're kind of like cousins to a Green
Lace Wing um but what the difference is
brown lace Wing as adults are predatory
Green Lace wings as adult are not
predatory so with brown lace Wings not
only do you get the larvae feeding you
get adults feeding and the adults fly
around they're a little
bit the wings are a little bit I don't
know how to describe it they're like not
as long and narrow they're a little
shorter and fatter where their larval
stages are a little bit longer and
skinnier than Green Lace wings but what
I really hope with these is we'll be
able to release some of the adults out
they'll be able to fly around in crops
and
they are excellent aphid predators and
I'm hoping with their size because they
are larger um that they wouldn't get
stuck in tricomes but at the same time
there's a chance they could get stuck in
your buds just like ladybirds could but
they're big enough that you could you
know remove them uh easily because of
their size but it also may be something
that will want to use earlier in the
crop cycle to help manage uh fuler aphid
speed species um so it's all they it's
kind of new on using them we've got I've
got one trial going um on Botanical
plants at a Botanical Garden in Georgia
we're doing a test there because they've
got birds in the area and so they can't
use any pesticides um so we are doing
some trials now with them um I have not
had any of my cannabis scorers use them
yet but I'm hoping we can not I'm not
hoping for a cannabis squore problems
but waiting for an
outbreak of of either cotton melon aphid
or cannabis aphid um to see if we uh
release some adults how well they'll do
in the system one of the drawbacks is is
there's almost zero information on
pesticide compatibility where there's
seems to be a lot more information on uh
you know the Green Lace
wings um and other commercially reared
beneficial since this is so new there's
not much information available on it um
also the permits have come through now
for anisus which is uh the whirly gig
Mite um if you're outside during the
summertime and you like look down on the
sidewalk and you see a m running in
circle crazy patterns um that's the
whirly gig Mite um I find him in Florida
all the time on hibiscus uh I sometimes
find them in trees it is a larger
predatory frite that looks more like a
crab um but um applied bionomics uh did
get the permit for them to come into not
every state but certain states in the
United States and again we're setting up
some trials right now it's generally
going to be more of an aphid Predator
even though they can feed on thrips the
concerning thing about this one is it is
very non-selective and it will Le your
predators just as much as it would eat
your pest but if you if it eats your
other beneficials to maintain its own
population you know I kind of you know
I'm kind of okay with that as long as
they're controlling um the other pest
but again zero pesticide compatibility
information and it's still so new um
that we really is it going to be happy
on cannabis don't know is it going to be
happy on tropical foliage don't really
know we've got to you know trial and
test all this stuff um to see how it's
going to work out in the real
world oh that's great I love hearing
that there's new stuff coming along and
for those just to go back to the
ladybugs ladybirds uh the reason we we
don't want to be buying them is because
they're wild harvested they can spread
disease to Native ladybug populations
even though they're the same species if
you want to read more about it they're
they're the same species but remember
they're the just like cannabis has
different strains
the ladybird beetles even though it's a
species because it's hippodamia
convergence and you you know if you're
in Virginia you're like oh hippodamia
convergence here it is a different
strain of hippodamia convergence that is
on the East Coast so you're you know
you're a as science goes on and we're
there's more molecular work and genetics
and all that happening you know you're
going to really un we're going to
understand more
how we need you know
basically more taxonomic levels breaking
down even further I mean you know we do
have subspecies and and things like that
but we're really starting to understand
it more but you know I always relate to
plants you know Acer rubri red maple the
ones growing in in Maine and the ones
growing in Florida those are not the
same plants you can't dig that one up
from Maine and send it to Florida and
the Florida one and send it to main
they're not going to do well so we
definitely have to think about that with
insects and just like Bavaria basana now
you have the strains of Bavaria it's
more than Bavaria basana is it the ant
strain is it the GHA strain same when
you're getting
into um insects I mean like pilus
commercially there's several different
pilus strains on the market phyto cilus
pilus is not phyto cilus pilus um there
was some very interesting research done
by um a friend of mine where she
actually looked at can cannibalism rates
between the different commercial strains
of pmus and there are actually different
cannibalism rates between the different
colonies which are basically different
strains or cultivars to put into to uh
plant
terms that's I wasn't aware that that
applied with insects as well as with uh
plants because I think of it from a
microbial perspective like micro risal
uh inoculant Riso fagus irregularis is
not the same from different companies so
you and sub one particular spray and may
have offer better drought resistance um
may be able to survive in a different
range of abiotic conditions than another
one so trying one if it doesn't work
doesn't mean that micro risal fungi
couldn't work in your environment it
just may mean that you need to try a
different strain out and it sounds like
the same could be said for
insects well the thing with the insect
is is is I mean the damage is kind of
done because of everybody buying them
and shipping them around but um back if
you go back into the 90s um back when I
actually sold beneficials um uh we used
to sell uh one of our one of our native
species comum Milla macula and we
actually had they they sold different
strains of it or different cultivars
whatever term you want to use for
Association but depending on what part
of the country you were in so there was
like a West Coast one and there was an
East Coast one so if you in Pennsylvania
you'd get the East Coast if you're in
California you get the West Coast they
had actually different colonies um to
have the right one and they've just with
and now it's a hot mess from all the
plants moving around people moving bugs
around I mean again the whole rly poy
thing you know with all the hobby
trading and this and that you know it's
going to be hard to even track any of
all this um because humans have just
moved all this stuff around without a
thought a care and of the environmental
impact and essentially what you're
saying is we don't know what the
ecological impact may be and we've made
this mistake in the past with uh
introducing species to a to a new
environment and causing problems I I
think of Hawaii as a great example of
that but yeah I mean Hawai is a good ex
I me Florida Florida gets um One new
invasive a month I I think is the
current going rate and the thing is is
is like everybody knows about you know
the problem with like the iguanas in
Florida and everybody knows the pro the
problem with pythons in Florida because
they're big and it's very easy to see
with the insect stuff and even microbial
stuff we don't see it so directly so
people don't think about how harmful it
could be but it's one of these things
that I think one of these times
something bad's going to happen and it's
it's going to catch up and even though
everybody's intentions are good people
need to stop and think about where
they're sourcing all this stuff from and
should it be here or not um granted a
lot of mistakes were made early on uh
with moving stuff around you know the
can toads released in Florida for
control of pests in sugar cane big
mistake again happened a long time ago I
always compare it to Medical Science
because Medical Science again when we
had our last the Spanish Flu our last
big world pandemic problem they were
bloodletting giving whiskey enemas we
were doing all kinds of crazy stuff that
doesn't mean we throw all medical
science out and don't do it because they
made mistakes years ago we learn from it
and try not to repeat those mistakes but
unfortunately when it comes to the
insects and the other arthropods and
things and microbes since it's so
small we don't see it the same way we do
as with like hey I've got mice in my
yard I'm going to go buy some cheetahs
from Africa and release them nobody
would think to do that um and it's it's
weird why people aren't concerned as
much about moving arthropods around I
mean the government is but not Growers
because a lot of I know there's a lot of
legal movement of arthropods in this
country
so some of these more exotic species of
isopods probably are not legal to sell
just because of the risk of them getting
out and we don't know what the
ecological implications are but also at
the same time the government doesn't
have the capacity to really enforce or
regulate as well as they probably should
for this sort of thing right right no
they they don't have the manpower to do
it and to move the isopods R you do have
to have permits you can't just ship them
around there's a permitting process
involved just like with uh the
commercial beneficial insects pimus Cuca
Merit you those things there are permits
and that is all regulated by the USDA to
make sure people aren't moving invasive
things around um
but with the the pet trade of of uh
these other arthropods it's it's there's
all these shows
that you can go buy stuff at and this
you know it's it's just there's not
enough
government they don't have the manpower
to regulate all of this and I think
we're setting ourselves up for some
serious problems down the road and how
the best way to stop this stuff is you
know make sure if you're buying
something do you have the right permits
is this legal for me to buy and be a
better human and don't be like oh the
government's just you know trying to
control us and there's a reason why this
stuff is in place to prevent these major
problems we've had with invasives in the
past and be a better human being and
think about the impact down the road of
what you're doing not just what's right
in front of your face
today well said well thank you so much
for your time today Suzanne I enjoyed
our conversation I always learn
something new every time we talk and uh
so yeah thank you thanks Tad and I'm
looking forward
to Montana so mark that
calendar yeah you can come we'll both be
there along with a bunch of other folks
and Collective elevation is one of the
nicest uh facilities I've visited
personally uh and I've done a tour it's
available on YouTube uh great great
people and phenomenal facility to check
out so I'm excited that they're hosting
it and opening it up to us for it all
right I'll see you there Tad
[Music]
that was Suzanne way wri Evans also
known as the bug lady and you are
listening to the Cannabis cultivation
and science podcast don't forget to
check out the podcast page at www. kis
organics.com just click on the learn Tab
and then podcast and if you want access
to podcasts as soon as they are recorded
along with additional content and video
we do have a patreon channel we also do
book clubs Hangouts and have a private
Discord Channel just for members the
kiss Organics website also offers a
variety of soil amendments lighting
fixtures beneficial insects and the
highest quality commercial soils on the
market we carefully research all our
products we offer and manufacture to
make sure they are science-based and
meet our standard of quality thanks for
listening
[Music]