[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host tad hussey
of kiss organics this is the podcast
where we discuss the cutting edge of
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge
my guest this week is dr monique mchenry
monique is a botanist with a background
in plant diversity and evolution she is
the director of the university of
vermont cannabis science and medicine
and plant biology certificate programs
director of the medical cannabis center
for research and education and
co-director of the cannabis pharmacology
course at the university of vermont
medical school she is also co-founder of
the case institute a plant-based
pharmaceutical research enterprise
dr mchenry completed her bachelor's and
master's of science at the university of
colorado and her phd at the university
of vermont now on to the show
hi monique thanks for coming on the show
today
hi ted thank you so much for having me
yeah i'm excited to talk to you today
can we start off with a little bit of
your background you tell me a little
about yourself
sure
so my background in plant biology um
currently i am a professor in the
pharmacology department at the lawn
record of medicine at the university of
vermont
and i was one of those interdisciplinary
hires so i could teach about the
different chemicals found in plants and
how they affect the human body
and i am the director of the medical
cannabis center for research and
education at uvm and i run
a bunch of our
educational programs in cannabis
that's great i definitely want to talk
some more about the what you have going
on at uvm um but can we start off with
just a real uh basic foundation here in
terms of the different classes of
cannabinoids
sure
you know
basically there's there's three classes
of cannabinoids and
sometimes people misspeak about them and
you know even the top level scientists
can interchangeably use the word
cannabinoids which can really mean all
three
but specifically there's the
endocannabinoids that are produced and
found in the human body there's the
phytocannabinoids that are produced by
the plant hence the phyto in front of
them and then they're synthetic
cannabinoids and those are produced in
the laboratory
and sometimes used for therapeutic
treatment
so as a as a cultivator we're obviously
most interested in uh phytocannabinoids
um what are the different types of of
cannabinoids and how might we um
cultivate uh from you know for best
practice in terms of selecting for uh
not just better yields but also
consistency and i know that's a big
question so
right yeah i mean if you take a step
back and we think about what
phytocannabinoids are
you know they're a secondary metabolite
that the plant produces
and the plants produce tons of secondary
metabolites and secondary metabolites
are usually synthesized for specific
functions where your primary metabolites
are synthesized for essential functions
so these secondary metabolites can often
be produced very inconsistently between
plants that have genetic um
are genetically identical and it's
sometimes due to the environment
sometimes we don't know why the plants
produce you know different chemicals at
different times
and so with phytocannabinoids the
research has been going on for a long
time
you know there's there's papers back
into the 70s as to why different
climates have plants that are producing
different amounts of
thc delta 9 thc for example
and it seems to be that different
stressors sometimes cause the plant to
produce
more
phytocannabinoid especially delta nine
thc
and
uh other environments
can seem to make more yield so the plant
actually produces more in this cat in
this case you know biomass being flower
of the plant but the chemicals might be
might be at lower levels so the
percentage of
phc per gram might be lower in those
plants in different growing environments
i want to touch on that with you so
is there a sort of a
genetic
maximum in terms of the amount of thc a
plant
can produce and therefore the variance
in
vegetative biomass would determine the
concentration of thc in the
in the flower
well ted i mean i think that's that's
probably a million dollar question
excuse the you know cliche there but
okay there has been some some hypotheses
in the literature that there is this
dilution effect where yeah there is a
maximum and whether it's a genetic
component or something else in the
biosynthetic pathway we don't know but
there's a maximum of what the
plant can produce in terms of you know
particular phytocannabinoids
but we just it doesn't seem like anybody
has really had solid evidence to say yes
to that or no to that
okay so it's a possibility but we we
don't know
um
you know a big buzzword
lately in the last year or two has been
crop steering this idea of sort of
targeted plant stress
for
you know selecting
is a way of increasing i guess
cannabinoid production and thc
specifically um
you know i've been of the impression
that every
real life facility has plant stress and
we don't
i'm still at the point where we want to
reduce it but
do we know enough from a research
perspective to really figure out like
what triggers really work
across the wide range of genetics that
we see in cannabis production right now
possibly you know i can i can give you
some literature out you know that's out
there so back in the 70s actually
specifically 1975 kaufman and gentner
these
two authors published a report and they
found that
low magnesium increases the amount of
thc and cbd content and so i think you
know a lot of
cultivators out there right now play
with their calcium and magnesium ratios
so there is published literature out
there that suggests
you lower the magnesium you increase the
thc and cbb
other stressors
that have been
shown to
i guess increase the amount of phc is
uvb radiation so in the 80s a paper by
linden and colleagues
said that plants with higher levels of
uvb radiation
had higher amounts of thc
and then we can go to recent papers like
i think i've actually had a podcast with
um
with with kaplan he was a graduate
student up in canada and he has a lot of
work published
and so his stuff from 2018 where he
intentionally you know applied drought
stress and he found that
that if you increase
intentional drought seven weeks into
reproductive stage
um you have these major
phytocannabinoids so thc again increase
yes i did have uh
i had darren kaplan on the show a while
back yeah that's right that's right
um it's wonderful to see the new
research that's that's coming out
um
you know some of the more common
practices that i've seen are uh
you know more more extreme pruning
removing all of the the fan leaves and
also
targeted
drought or nutrient stress
you know some sort of osmotic shock
towards the very end near
closer to a harvest date you know maybe
anywhere from a week out from harvest
have you seen any research on on either
of those topics
yes so the the intentional drought was
the cat with um
that's kaplan he he did that and i
haven't seen any published literature on
selective pruning yet
um but i don't want to doubt that it's
that it's out there we haven't done
anything like that at uvm we've
definitely done uh
you know played with
amount of nitrogen and found just um
kaplan again during his phd
did another study on
changing the amount of
nitrogen and there is a sweet spot where
you get you know a maximum
biomass yield and highest percentage of
of thc and he published that work and
uvm has put out reports on it too
so
nutrients are key absolutely
some of the work we did at uvm
showed that you know if you if you add
too much of
you know kind of pre-mixed bottle made
nutrients sometimes it's just
leaching right off we checked our runoff
and we found well that was pointless and
you do increase the biomass of the plant
but you see that dilution effect with
thc
where you don't have the same percentage
of thc per gram that you would have
in plants that are actually producing
less biomass
oh that's really interesting
so you had two genetically identical
plants and
one produced significantly more biomass
than the other under you know slightly
different nutrient conditions is that
absolutely yep yep so we saw that with
thc with cbd it was a little bit more
consistent and it seemed like when we
you know applied
um
some stresses to the plant or changed
the nutrient regime with cbd we couldn't
see that dilution effect as much
and again genetically identical plants
they were clones of the same plant
but with thc we definitely saw that
you know you hit a point where you
seemed to kind of maximize the amount of
thc the plant would produce even though
it would produce more plant matter and
dried flowers but with cbd we didn't we
didn't quite see that in a couple years
of trials
that's really inner is this a published
accessible paper or is this one that um
has not been published yet with the seat
right so with the cbd
um that work you can find um it's dr
heather darley writes reports every year
um and she puts him up on the industrial
hemp
website at the uvm through uvm extension
program and so you can see the results
of you know the different nutrient
gradients as well as
everything i mentioned there for cbd for
thc that work isn't published because it
was done in conjunction with a
dispensary here it couldn't be done at
uvm because of
the legality issues
oh that makes sense um
well
can you talk to me a little bit about
the uvm program and what sort of um
offerings you guys have as well as some
of the research that you're currently
doing
sure i would love to i did want to
mention there was one other thing
hormones did you want to get into that
um oh like we have uh
yeah absolutely so
people are also i think applying
jasmonic acid right and there has been a
paper recently published
um
by
epic
and colleagues in 2021 so just last year
and in that they show that jasmonic acid
so ja as a lot of people know it as
after two weeks
can increase the amount of thc
so that's another i think that's another
thing some cultivators have been doing
is using these plant morphe genes or
plant hormones applied to
different stages of flowering to see
what changes the
the amounts of phytocannabinoids there
but
sorry for that interruption i would love
to talk about the uvm program well let's
why don't we talk a little more about um
hormones while we're on the topic and
then because we have plenty of time
still um
right that's that's really i actually
just saw an interesting paper on
triacontinol from 2020
by uh i'm gonna mispronounce the name
shyastol islam i reached out to him
directly but
one of the challenges is since he's not
working in cannabis and he's in another
country it's sometimes hard to get those
folks to come on the podcast but
um
what what sort of research are you
seeing around uh plant growth hormones
or what what sort of maybe speculation
do you have of what might work well with
cannabis or hemp production
well
i mean if i think about the plant's
reaction to you know different plant
morphogens or wounding so like you said
selective pruning you know there's
usually a
spike in calcium levels um and
i would say that's almost a stress and
when you have a calcium spike in in
plants just like you can have in humans
as a stress you know i would hypothesize
that that that could increase the amount
of thc but i haven't really seen anyone
delve into that science yet but um
you know that seems to be an expectation
you know at
a more scientific level of what is going
on inside the plant
um and so you know what hormones would
would cause that reaction in the plant
um
you know
i don't know you know jasmine acid seems
to
you know oxen is another huge plant
hormone or morphogen some people like to
refer to it as and it's responsible for
cool things like sunflowers turning
towards the light
you know it collects in the bending side
so
perhaps you know hormones or morphogens
like that are involved in
some of the phytocannabinoid
inconsistencies but i haven't seen much
in the literature on that so i don't
know what other hormones you know i
would suggest
besides
the ones we've already talked about
yeah
so
for folks that uh
i guess
as an organic
producer myself
it's hard to find organic sources of a
lot of these
hormones that will actually translate
into plant available in another plant
like i know for a long time i just
i would apply alpha meal to myself
thinking i was getting tricontinol
but in reality from talking to a plant
hormone expert it sounds like it's
it's quite difficult to do like it um
decomposes rather rapidly unless applied
at high levels like an alfalfa mulch
how as an organic producer might we
access some of these tools or if if at
all i guess
be the question
you know chad that is a great question
and you might you might have stumped me
at that one because i was so thinking
about what happens in the lab
you know where we're wearing
purple gloves and you know we're using
special
hoods for special flows that we aren't
worrying about what the chemical would
do to us as humans because we're not
ingesting it
but you're absolutely right
if you're trying to grow something
organically you know what what would be
a good source i might have to
think about that and talk to some of the
people at uvm extension to see what
ideas they would have um because
i don't know because we're we're not
necessarily
doing that in the lab and these papers
that i'm talking about these other
researchers aren't necessarily doing it
in the lab
and so to translate that into a field
science i'd have to have to think about
that one okay no that's that's fine i
could get you an answer yeah
that's
sometimes i don't know is the best
answer uh
it's because i know like for example
with jasmonic acid there's commercially
available i could go buy jazz spray for
roses today
um and go spray it on my plants but um
are there other potential risks
associated with it because that would be
an off-label use i just want to
i don't want
people listening to podcasts to
necessarily get ahead of themselves and
end up in a situation where they may be
doing something that could be unsafe for
consumption so
right can you touch on that a little bit
before we get too far ahead of the on to
another topic
absolutely right so i mean
i think that's a great emphasis point is
that you know people listening to
this podcast from agricultural
perspective or even from a production or
a medical perspective you know some of
the things we're talking about are done
in
scientific settings right it doesn't
mean they should be applied to um
something for human consumption right
like
yes you know there are synthetic
cannabinoids out there that people use
off-label you know approved by the fda
people are using off-label but i
definitely don't encourage people to do
that and same with
pesticide applications
is
you know there's not that many
pesticides with cannabis on their label
so i don't want to encourage anyone to
use things off label
um
what harm could it do you know we don't
know because there haven't been those
same kind of studies or if they are
they're in their infancy um you know a
couple years in
of
you know at what point
um is it safe to apply certain
pesticides to cannabis
because you know
it will be inhaled and a lot of people
say well why can't you just compare it
to the tobacco industry and i mean
that's a whole can of worms do we really
want to compare it to the tobacco
industry
you know i don't know i don't know if
it's safe to answer that question but
um it's hard because you can't really
compare cannabis to lettuce you know
probably 10 years ago we were writing
white papers to try to help
legislatures determine
you know
what levels of pesticides are safe and
you know when can they be applied you
know what levels of residues and the
truth is you can suggest what is known
about other crops but with cannabis
there's not
enough quite known yet
so as you all know especially
people in different states every state
has its own list of allowable
levels and
sometimes it's not based on science
unfortunately
yeah that brings up another question for
me uh you know you've listed some great
research to support some of these ideas
um
and concepts and as a
as a curious
grower
i'm always looking for more information
trying to learn more
where what resources does the average
layman have
for you know finding information like
some of the ones you listed
how do we go searching for that because
you know if i go to google scholar i can
type in
you know magnesium for example and thc
and get
probably like a ton of different hits um
what what do you recommend are there any
like
publications to follow or anything that
you that you really like to use for that
sort of thing
well
ted i think you
you kind of hit the
you know snail on its head there you you
had a great suggestion i mean that is
the most uh
you know path of least resistance is to
look in google scholar
um and then you know a trick there is to
once you find a publication that's
interesting if it's older look at the
papers that are citing it
and a lot of our public libraries or you
know if you're connected at all to any
kind of research institute or
or university then
you have the availability to do what's
called cross library loans so even if
your public library doesn't have that
resource electronically you could ask
the
librarian the reference librarian
usually to help you know ask for that
from a library that does
so
you know it is a little more challenging
to get access to some of these articles
and fortunately a lot of things are um
open source now so they're still
peer-reviewed so they still go through
that scientific rigor you know
to get up to publication status
but they don't cost money
because unfortunately the ones that
aren't you know it's quite expensive
it's like 35 to download a pdf of an
article that i'm referencing
um
but yeah for the for the lay person i
think google scholar is a great start
and then they're looking at um the
sources that cite it review articles are
a treasure right so if you have a
scientist that basically compiles the
literature
and
finds um you know everything they can
publishes it
as a review
you know
a little slice
for that particular time
of all the past
research done those are those are huge
fines you know as well as textbooks too
um especially textbooks that are going
to have a reference list so that you
know somebody took the time to actually
find if this information was scientific
or not
and i think there are some some up and
coming you know cultivation books out
there
that are helping
the old kind of bibles that people have
used in the past
oh that's wonderful i wasn't aware of
any upcoming books that's
that's great
one question i thought about as i was
listening to you talk about
research is
how does one
extrapolate research
effectively because i realize
what happens in the lab doesn't
necessarily translate to
commercial production or
you know real life
real life production um
how how do we take
you know say
some of these ideas
um and translate them into actual
production in a way that makes sense
without drawing too many conclusions
like for example like i did with the
alfalfa and tricontinol would be a great
example like
i see that triangle has these benefits
so i make this assumption um
the work wasn't done on cannabis like
you know what
what can we really do there as from a
from a cultivation perspective
right so i mean i think there's there's
one way for for the brave people is in
any article you're going to see a
corresponding author and it will have
their contact information using an email
address
and just you know ask the author first
if they know a different
a different way or how to translate what
they did in the lab to the field
if not uh
you know you can you can ask the you
know knowledgeable people at
at your local
uh hydroponic or garden store right if
they know uh a particular
methodology to
utilize you know jasmonic acids but i
like like we talked about with cannabis
it is harder because again you'll
probably be using things off label
and perhaps like you were saying um
incorrectly so
i mean really the best answer is for
people like you to have these awesome
podcasts where uh you have researchers
who say oh yeah this is exactly how you
should do it but
um or you
you you take a class you know there are
a lot of uh
cannabis classes out there where
uh like ours we bring in subject matter
experts who go into detail um and you
know you have question and answer
sessions but yeah it's basically getting
the scientists behind a microphone so
they can help answer
yeah and i i do want to caution people
from drawing too many inferences for my
paper like
even just for example the the kaplan
paper on on drought stress would be an
example of this like um you know he got
a very
you know statistically significant
response with a very particular cultivar
under you know very specific conditions
that may lead us to believe there's a
trend there
but there's absolutely room for
replication
over time with various cultivars under
various conditions to see if this is
actually
the case um i think we're still in our
infancy in cannabis
in that regard and
you know i just hear a lot of people
confidently saying things in the
cultivation space
based off of one paper or one idea that
um
maybe we need to just take a step back
and
you know take a little more of a wait
and see process as we do more research i
guess i just want to throw that out
there for folks
well that's a good idea and you know
chad i would i would really encourage
anyone working for
you know a larger cannabis company to
encourage the company to have a small
side r d
room right so that you can explore this
obviously if you had a huge cultivation
facility um or field you're not going to
want to
um blindly apply
a stressor to it and uh because it will
affect your yield right i mean it's what
what i was saying and what we were
seeing is your yield does go down even
though your percent of thc goes up in
lots of cases
um
and you know it would be great if
everyone had an ability to do a trial
run before they
you know applied some of this on their
whole crop but
yes you're right we are in our infancy
and and people shouldn't get carried
away
well the biggest challenge i see with
facilities is one they're just swamped
with the day-to-day and two they don't
always have the tools to
apply you know proper scientific
methodology and rigor and then
understand how to collect that data in a
way that they can get
um you know
accurate statistically significant
um
you know results and so uh that's that's
been a challenge but there are so there
are some in-house researchers in some of
these facilities doing amazing work that
i've gotten to talk to over the years
and so hopefully
more and more of that information will
become available over time but
yeah i agree i think every facility
should have
should have a little r d space because
we have to continually keep improving
and and uh i think that's a great
suggestion
but let's uh let's switch direction here
and talk a little bit about uvm and uh
your programs can you tell me a little
bit about what you guys have going on
there
sure so um
we you know it's been going on for about
let's see
2022 so at least since 2015
we've been doing educational programs
and before that there was hemp research
going on and dr darby out of the uvm
extension was leading
research mostly in
fiber and feed crops
for hemp um
but then in 2015 we started um
we developed a program and the first
program we did was an undergraduate
program
uh we actually had a lot a lot more
people than undergraduates take it
it was the first
cannabis
educational program for cannabis course
it's called medical cannabis
and
offered by a medical school
from there we had such high interest in
that that was a you know it was back in
2016 it actually ran that january so it
was a in person you sat in a class you
weren't in front of a computer there
and we had so many people sign up that
we had to get a bigger classroom
and then we we kind of had to do it by
lottery because we were worried that
other people would come in and take up
those seats
so we had to give a code to have people
come in and we had i think five
different of our local you know media
channels there recording our first class
it was it was a scene wow but besides
i know right
even seth meyers mentioned it uh late
night television said something like oh
uvm is offering a canvas class and
hilariously it did start at 4 20. but it
started at 4 25 but you know that was
that was a good joke for everyone too
yeah but with that interest what we saw
is a lot of professionals took it and
that's why we offered it later in the
day so that people could take it after
work so then we decided to develop a
couple
programs and the first one we developed
was targeted at medical professionals it
was cannabis science and medicine and uh
it you could earn uh continuing medical
education so cmes with it it was i think
you know close to eight cme that you
would earn
and you know the interest in that grew
so much that there was always a wait
list
and a lot of people were not in the
medical profession and a lot of people
wanted to learn more about the plant
biology aspect so then we developed a
cannabis um
plant biology professional certificate
and that one's been filling especially
because in vermont they have an upscale
program where the state helps people
gain more professional skills by paying
for a couple of their programs and that
is one of them
and so we do offer some free webinars um
you know not nothing as as as impressive
as yours chad you know where you have
people from all over the world talking
about today but uh so so sometimes and
then there's a community medical program
where
we have different professors come in and
talk about their research and with all
this activity like most universities we
started a cannabis center so ours is the
is the
medical center for cannabis education
and research and
basically what that does is it helps
researchers
work together
because we do have a lot of cannabis
research going on at uvm both in the
college of medicine and in the college
of agricultural life science
so
you know i'm focused on the education
with a little bit of research going on
um and
uh then i'm you know to have some
administrative tasks like directing the
programs and the center
but yeah it's it's been really fun and
oh boy have things changed since 2015
right in the last seven years we've seen
an explosion of cannabis science
you know and
as well as
laws
pools regulations changing all over the
map
um in the us and abroad
yeah well kudos to you guys for kind of
starting this process here in the united
states with your courses um
i wasn't aware you were the first until
i was reading about it uh earlier this
week um can you tell me so if i was a
cultivator and i wanted to learn more
about cultivation
what
what would that process look like
through your through your school
right so there's there's
two
i call them in-person courses but we can
call them matriculating student courses
that you know you have to be a student
or you have to go through the continuing
and distance education which is now
called peace
program to enter
and and those those you need to be in
person um i mean obviously the last few
years they're somewhat offered remotely
as the pandemic progresses
but one is through the department of
plant and soil science
and that is talked by
scott lewins and dr heather darby and i
teach it as well um some a few courses
in it and that is focused on
you know
hemp
and then the other is the medical
cannabis course that i mentioned
and again that's the in-person
pharmacology course focused on the
effects of cannabis on the human body
but then we have online so anyone can
sign up
you know we ask that you have a bachelor
degree in science but we waive that
requirement frequently for people that
are willing to make the effort to get up
to speed so that they understand the
science enough in the courses and people
definitely do you know a diverse
background we have a lot of
you know we have pharmacologists and
uh retired you know medical
professionals as well as
uh
lawyers and business people and we even
have media fellows so we give out media
scholarships
each program for members of the media to
take the course for free and then they
have to contribute uh after the course a
little bit
and that they might come be a guest
speaker for the next course and share
what they've learned
so so those courses are are wildly
accessible we have we run them twice a
year so in the fall and in the spring
um
and
with that it's basically uh there are
pre-recorded lectures so it's
asynchronous as well as synchronous live
sessions but if you miss them that's
okay because they're recorded so it can
be something that you know we've had
people from all over the world
thailand
um
you know all over south america take
these courses so we do get a diverse
group
and then like i said there's um
sometimes there's webinars there's lots
of pre-recorded webinars available and
then we have community medical school
programs but those again are in person i
don't think they're remote anymore
so there's lots of ways to get involved
and take these courses at uvm
and the nice thing about uvm versus
other
programs out there is that we stick to
evidence bases so in class we're only
presenting um
peer-reviewed published literature or
literature that's or research that's
ongoing at uvm we try to not you know
present
anecdotal and we try to discourage
you know students from
from sharing their anecdotal knowledge
without saying this is anecdotal
knowledge and then here's some research
that's backing it up because that's
what's so cool is
you know people do discover things on
their own and they have you know there's
this wealth of knowledge from people
that have been growing for
50 years
and then nowadays it seems like some of
the research is really backing up what
they've already
found out
so i'm looking specifically at the
cultivation one here it's a professional
certificate in cannabis plant biology is
that is that the one that you're
referencing in regards to
like say a cultivator who wanted to
take a take a course is that the best
option
yes so if a cultivator wants to take
course that's the one i suggest actually
if anyone wanted to take the course that
is the one i would suggest and the
reason why is because that's the one
that dives deep into the plant
it's eight weeks long you know the first
week is just
history business law and policy
um the basics right and then we go into
basic science and then we deep dive into
the plan we have a week about
um
cannabis cultivation we have a week
about post harvest we have a week about
extraction and we do have a week about
how cannabis affects the human body
taught by
uh physicians and pharmacologists
but most of it is focused on the plant
and in the past then we would offer our
uh
medical cannabis or clinical modules a
la carte and we're just in the process
of kind of
updating those and we will be offering
them again so if you took cannabis plant
biology and then you thought oh i really
want to know more how cannabis affects
the human body body you could then go on
and take you know a module called
cannabis and the endocrine system so i
would absolutely say for anyone
interested in cultivation start with
plant biology or anyone in general start
with plant biology unless you're
specific you know and just want to learn
about how cannabis affects the human
body
okay well we're recording this right now
in june it looks like it starts uh end
of september
um it's purely online and an eight-week
program with a time commitment of about
eight to ten hours per week and it's a
non-credit professional certificate does
that i'm just reading off your website
page does that all sound correct
that yup that is all correct
so yep it wraps right before you know
the u.s holiday of holiday of
thanksgiving
and so
it runs this fall and then it will run
again next spring
oh okay
and um
i love that you mentioned here that's
fully online evidence-based program uh
that sounds that sounds wonderful
um
is there what sort of research so you're
many of your professors are teaching and
then also doing research is there a
student component to the research as
well or is that
um i guess how does that work at uvm
yeah so well that's a great question so
because it's fully online you know
the the participants in the program are
not actively
doing research at uvm
you know we we have had a lot of
students come and tour our glasshouse
facility or
our uh
our field research
but the student research component of it
is
in the second to last week we turn the
you know educational component over to
the student and they design a
a presentation so we utilize a bunch of
online
platforms where you know students are
actually recording themselves doing a uh
a presentation for their peers and a lot
of people think that is
the best part it's their you know great
learning experience and we do have
people that are presenting on
laws or business proposals but a lot of
people think up research projects and
some of them actually go on to do them
and so they're getting feedback from
our team of uh
you know different subject matter
experts
on
their particular proposed research
and then obviously if they do them we
want to be involved and hear about each
step
but as far as hands-on in-person
in the lab the field or the glass house
this course is not that because
it's online
sure and what sort of
feedback have you gotten on the course
or any stories of folks who have taken
the class
and utilized that in their professional
career
yeah i mean we get we get pretty good
feedback from it it usually fills every
every session and
you know i think people
people like
the learning experience
online you know a lot of people it's
it's new to them
to learn online like that
um but you know become increasingly
popular in the last few years to learn
online
and uh
and yeah i mean we sure you know maybe
what i should do is is tell about some
of the people that we have teaching it
because um
you know that in itself is
is the value of it people really enjoy
uh getting exposure to the different uh
subject matter experts and professionals
we have and then also the other members
of the class
for example in this you know in this
last
plant biology program
we had the
cultural editor from rolling stones and
um
you know a writer for forbes and l.a
times and um
and then we you know we had we had
people who hadn't ever planted a
cannabis plant before
we had people
that you know were well entrenched in
the industry um you know a lot of a lot
of times some of my colleagues in the
industry will say oh monique do you know
so-and-so and i'll say oh yeah they took
my course and now they're running you
know a cultivation center down in
massachusetts so because it's such a
broad group of students that enter and
participate
what they do afterwards is equally as
diverse
that's wonderful well
tell me a little bit about the
professors that you work with and um in
their backgrounds that would be great to
hear
yeah so so i i teach a couple of the um
lectures and you know my background i
didn't really go super into it because i
said i'm a plant biologist but it's in
um evolution and diversity so i teach
the taxonomy sections i'm really into
the way cannabis is named
and
you know
you i
love to talk more about that if we ever
had time um and
then we have dr linder clumper
and she is our clinical pharmacologist
she's the course facilitator so i'm the
director and she's she plays more of an
instructor role and she has a whole team
that she works with um out of canify
that she brings um
and they are they're all on the
pharmacology side
uh and she's been working in cannabis
for
cannabis research for
maybe
15 years
she did her phd in
the netherlands on
cannabinoids and then we bring in um
business professor at uvm dr uh william
casperell
he's an associate professor
and he's you know been working on the
medical
side of business for about 25 years
he you know he worked
with the cannabis industry for a little
while too
and then we have um people in in
agronomy like dr heather darby
she's an
agronomic and soil specialist for uvm
extension
and she's been doing hemp research for
um you know
probably close to 10 years so she
originally had a dei schedule 1 license
to work on hemp before it was allowed
to be studied without a dea
schedule one license before i connected
with you i actually had i was looking
through my notes and i had her name
listed as someone that i wanted to
connect with for the podcast so i've
i've been hearing her name for years now
i just i needed to reach out but um yeah
i've heard wonderful things about about
the work that that she's been doing so
that's that's great yeah and a lot of
the work she he does is with scott
lewins and so he is a um
you know he does like applied
agricultural research and mostly on
biological control of agricultural pests
so he also teaches with us
and then we have
dr john mckay
and he's a
a chemical person he
he had his phd in organic chemistry and
he worked with
the waters corporation early on when
they were just starting to do extraction
and um now he's the chief technology
officer new bridge
gold ventures and he's the founder of
synergistic technology so he's very much
entrenched in the cannabis industry as
well as dr john mcpartland who is a
family medicine doctor associated with
uvm
but he you know he wrote a book about
cannabis pests and diseases and he's
authored a lot of papers um and so he he
works with us in both programs actually
with his he has a master's in plant
sciences and so he you know he
he does teach some of the the plant
stuff as well as some of the
endocannabinoid stuff because he is a
medical professional as well
and then we combined that with some
local
experts that are in the cannabis
industry
like the director of one of the labs
here in vermont and
the director of cultivation of one of
the dispensaries who used to be in
vermont and now is in massachusetts and
i believe moving to rhode island soon as
many cultivators do he's making the
rounds at different places so yeah we
blend it we also have a medicinal chem
chemist wolfgang dr dawson dr wolfgang
dachman and a physician scientist so md
phd dr carla freeman um for you know and
this is all in the plant biology program
so as you as you just heard you know we
have kind of people from from lots of
different aspects from business to
medical to chemistry to extraction and
people in the field
at
plant soil scientists
and pest management people so we have a
a great group i think and um
you know they're they're all doing
cannabis research kind of on the side or
have some associations with the industry
as well as
some of them have day jobs
in the er at uem or
studying traumatic brain injury so it's
a great
a great group and they're all passionate
about helping people uh
learn more
especially when you have um an
understudy topic like cannabis science
that sounds like a wonderful group
absolutely
quite an extensive background and so
diverse
yeah that it sounds like a great course
um thanks for sharing about that
you know one thing as you were
speaking about your background um well i
had two things i thought were
interesting i thought the taxonomy thing
was interesting and i'd love to touch on
that but what really got me interested
was
your background in
in biology and evolution
um
in
the soils that or i guess soilless media
that we're using what what the industry
calls living soil but is really
um
probably better described as
you know very fertile soilless media
we see
a higher
at least
qualitatively
higher levels of biomass
and activity
in these
in these living soils
than i see in traditional agricultural
soils or even you know traditional
soilless media
when we reuse that media
we tend to to get better results on the
second or third cycle
i assume as we're establishing more of a
functional ecosystem can you talk a
little bit about
i guess your thoughts on any of that
yeah
i guess
i mean
sure
i mean when you're talking about that so
so
here's my little secret i also teach in
the galapagos right because i can't not
do that because i love the galapagos
islands and as you were talking i was
thinking of
island evolution galapagos
because yeah when an island emerges
right the first life on it
is often lichens and then you get some
fern establishment
but
it's kind of what i would say you were
using you know the next round is then
you start to get more and more diversity
and so as the island rises so at some of
the highest points on the galapagos
islands is where we you know find the
most diversity and it's because those
points have been around the longest so
perhaps we can
relate that to what you just said in
that you know you're you're using a soil
medium
and soilless cultivation and you know it
it takes a little time to become
established because you have those
pioneers
that are first colonizing it
and um sometimes it takes those pioneers
to attract other
you know i don't know in this case if
it's microbes or um
you know abiotic factors for those to
collect you need the pioneers and so
that you know that would make perfect
sense from an evolutionary standpoint
and then you probably get to a point
that you know your your medium is not as
useful i'm guessing because some of the
material is used up by the plant do you
find that too ted
well it's interesting and so my my
bachelor's degree was in anthropology so
i love that topic
still more on the cultural side but
evolution i think is fascinating and
then one of the people i work with who
also works at a cannabis facility
dr ben higgins got his phd in functional
ecology looking at marine systems so
this is an area that i think is just
so incredible and the microbial
level at the microbial level is just
there's so much we don't know
um
so i i really love this topic i
what we find in in these soils is we use
a large volume of soil usually in a bed
rather than a small container and and
that seems to be critical for
establishing
the right
microbial populations
and as well as managing fertility but
what we see is every cycle you know it's
since it's
closed environment agriculture we're
you know it's not
we're not getting the same inputs
into their as we would say
agriculturally outdoors
you know we're removing organic matter
every cycle removing nutrients and those
are leaving the facility in the form of
the cannabis biomass so uh we have to
replace those every cycle
but we find that we you know if we are
testing the soil
um and managing the media appropriately
we can continue this process
um for multiple years with multiple
cycles per year
you'll provide we're managing pests and
managing fertility correctly and then we
don't have to move the media in and out
of the facility
i don't know from an evolutionary
perspective how
microbially
that might may change or may have an
impact
the biggest issue we've had to face
at least that we're aware of is
more managing you know sodium when the
cultivator doesn't have the ability to
have runoff
based on the design of their facility
that can be a challenge or certain
nutrients can build up or if we get
something awful like a root not nematode
cannabis aphid some of these things
depending on the facility's ability to
manage them can be
a real challenge too
yeah
but around this topic that i think is
interesting is the the way we would
research it i think is really really
tough because
there's so
it adds such a layer of variability
to or the number of variables and
vectors to what traditional
you know agronomy would want to to do at
a research level um versus you know if i
could do research like uh you know
darren kaplan did with
i think he was using either coco core or
pro mix a fairly inert media and
chemical mineral salts
that's a much easier experiment for
controlling variables than using this
biologically active soil
and managing it cycle after cycle so
this is sort of a situation where
infield
or
sorry
you know actual production
doesn't really translate well to good
research conditions for academia i guess
yes it's it well it depends on the
researcher
you know
people that are used to working in labs
would say there's too many variables
like you just mentioned yes but um i
mean there's a
there's also a way to
um
to design your experiment
to you know embrace the variables
instead of try to
pinpoint them one by one and it does
seem like the cannabis microbiome is
becoming more popular there's you know
been some publications about it recently
um
we we were actually doing some studies
of it when uh in the glass houses at uvm
when uh kobe shut us down in march 2020
and we actually just didn't resume them
because the young man running them
moved on to a different position
but um
but people are studying the microbiome
and and you know i'm thinking that's
going to be
uh completely
correlated to what you're talking about
too because as you're
studying
the soils and
you know
thinking of how do you
translate that into more specific
laboratory studies
um
i think that you know the progress
that's being made genetically where you
can test your samples that way will help
with it because it will help eliminate
some of the
guesswork and what variables are
affecting it because you can know
exactly what's what's there
but
yeah so like i said i think it depends
on the researcher and that
some people would shy away from that but
other people would would embrace it
with a different experimental design
i think yeah i think about this topic a
lot so for me it would have to be the
control is literally just
that you know what we're calling living
soil or that enriched media
rather than trying to
define every variable within the media
itself that would just have to be sort
of the control for the experiment
but
one of the things related to
microbiology is
in and of itself is the variability so
you know i saw some research a while
back around
how much fluctuation you get in
soils from a biological perspective in
terms of bacteria and fungi and that
ratio just based on hydrology
alone that was the only variable they
were looking at there
but there's so many different things in
terms of rhizosphere interactions
hydrology all these things that affect
tilling that affect
the biology in the soil how
do you feel like it's even possible for
us to really um
ever fully understand what's going on or
make assumptions based off of
the the microbiome in our in our soil
well
i think
you know i think i'm going to answer
that like politician
so i think what you can think is i mean
look at grapes right and so you develop
a chore right and so as cannabis becomes
accepted as more of an agricultural crop
you instead of trying to pinpoint
exactly what's changing you know the
production of every secondary metabolite
you
you categorize it in some way and you
name it you know
using
using some kind of system the problem is
i think you have to create a system and
everyone has to agree
um
and you have to know there's going to be
some inconsistencies
but you know
that changes when you're trying to
use something therapeutically right
because you know why not
wine is not necessarily used
therapeutically so there's a little bit
of inconsistency you know they're still
going to be able to determine the
alcohol level and so they slap that on
the bottle but it might not have the
same
taste that you would expect but it's not
going to
change the way
you know it's it's helping somebody
therapeutically because it's not being
used that way so i think there's two
factors right and that
if we really truly want to understand
what's going on in the cannabis plant
some of it is going to have to be done
in a very controlled setting
but if we want to think of it as an
agricultural crop and not necessarily
something that's used
solely therapeutically
then we have to embrace it and just come
up with you know some kind of
system that can categorize it like we
have with with wine
so taking that to a microbial level i
know right now that we have
classifications around certain
bacteria for example as being phosphorus
solubilizing or nitrogen fixing
um so so some of those sort of classes
already exist
but as i understand it
a lot of times it's a
i guess a sort of a symbiotic
relationship where it's more than one
microbe working together that creates
the sum of something greater than its
parts
how do we really begin to classify and
understand
what's going on there
right well with that i mean i think we
do need to scale back and look at things
one-on-one for example
um you know people are using mycorrhizae
with cannabis do they even colonize the
roots you know i haven't seen
publications that say yes you know
you could say that if you add
mycorrhizal to
the soil that you can get more yield but
like you're saying there's a lot going
on in the soil so it might not just be
that
but if we go really in depth you know
and look microscopically at the roots do
we see uh colonization from
uh mycorrhizae so i think for that you
know if you if you really want to
science this
you have to you have to do things um
you know in a controlled method
and answer the very basic questions
first
like does mycorrhizal colonize
cannabis roots and then you can move on
um you know what about rhizobium you
know are there are there
are there
little facts developing like they do uh
in fabaceae so in in the pea family
where you're having nitrogen fixing
bacteria
probably not i'm guessing but just
one-on-one like you like like we did
with all other crops right
i mean that makes sense um
there's just more and more
microbial products and biostimulants
coming out
targeting cannabis and i mean
agriculture in general it seems to be
the next wave
of
fertilizers and ipm options is really
the microbial stuff
i don't know i mean i'm excited to see
where it goes but it also seems like
there's a lot we still don't know and we
may be jumping the gun like you're
suggesting on on some of these products
yeah it's hard to know and it's actually
fairly simple experiments we were doing
it again when
uh we were looking specifically and we
actually weren't seeing a ton of
colonization that's why i bring it up of
mycorrhizal
so
yes but you know we kind of i can't
that's not published that
you know hasn't been
repeated and triplicate because um
when the pandemic shut it down we just
never picked up that piece of
of research but it's it's a great
question right and um you know you
compare it it's an easy experiment you
plant
uh something that you know is colonized
alongside cannabis use the same product
look at the roots stain them under a
microscope and see is there is there
colonization
and if there isn't then how could you
say that that particular product is the
one benefiting cannabis right
and you know it's a simple experiment
and i don't think it's been done yet i
haven't seen a publication but um it
could have popped up recently
so like i said you know we just we have
publications now on
um cannabis microbiome so we know what's
going on there at least
yeah you know i was very skeptical of
mycorrhizal fungus in cannabis due to
the short crop cycle and high p levels
in our soils and some of those and uh
the rampant use of
various trichoderma
um
but then i spoke to
dr joram capulnick i had him on the
podcast he's a
mycorrhizae research out of israel
and uh he kind of changed my mind on it
but again i haven't actually seen a lot
of public research public
published research sorry on this topic
either um
can i can you explain a little more
about what you
what you guys found so you were using a
commercially available
um
endomycorrhizal
product i'm guessing
um
and it and you weren't getting
yeah
um infection you know and i should
probably take a step back on that
because
again it was like such in its infancy
when
when that when that research program got
shut down um just because you know
people
um stopped coming into the glass houses
and we just never took it back up
but um
yeah i mean we were applying i'd have to
go back look back in my notes it wasn't
me doing it it was a research assistant
and he was applying commercially
available products and looking at him
under a microscope and comparing them
i think the plants that he was using as
the control um i actually don't remember
which one
has to control so this is this is
something that i probably shouldn't go
into because i don't i don't remember
enough about it it's been a long two
years
but
yes
so
um
[Music]
it was seeming like
their whatever product we were using was
not um
going to really uh
be present in the roots
well you know regardless of the results
of the research you bring up this
interesting point though that
you know we do at the end of the day
if we can default to available research
that's always a good idea and if the
research doesn't exist it's always
something we can test ourselves and even
if you don't have the ability to
you know stain roots under a microscope
you can absolutely trial
in you know mycorrhizal fungus in your
facility on some of your crop and not on
others and see if you get a plant
response in regards to disease
resistance or
biomass increases that make it
worthwhile to use it rather than just
you know blanketly applying all of these
products and assuming that you're
getting a certain result based on a
you know
sales pitch or something for example so
yeah yeah chad i agree with you applying
the scientific method is always a good
idea when you're trying new products but
i know that people can't always do that
and um
but yeah i mean i think you know we had
talked to a lot of different lighting
companies too and it was the same thing
people were claiming that certain
spectra did this in the that
but the research isn't really there to
back it up so um you know
using a different wavelength on the
plant definitely has an effect but if we
can't definitively say what that effect
is you know maybe you don't want to go
ahead and switch all your lighting to a
different wavelength um
and it's hard because this is
you know i feel like with the whole
cannabis industry everything got ahead
of itself
right it's the same with
medicinal cannabis used therapeutically
is
a lot of anecdotal information was put
out there and you know states were
making rules and regulations
and they were having to go off uh
anecdotal
evidence um
that isn't necessarily
uh true when it's when it's tried um
and replicated using the
scientific method there's just no
scientific rigor or truth to it
yeah well i know i know we're getting
short on time would you have time to
just talk a little bit about cannabis
taxonomy and sort of um
your thoughts
on it um we've had people on the past
talking sort of about how
this idea of um
indica and sativa are is not accurate
and sort of an outdated
terminology um
can do you have time to just shed a
little bit light on on that topic though
from a taxonomy perspective i always
have time to talk about taxonomy
absolutely and i am wishing i you know
had had reviewed some of those earlier
podcasts to 50 people's opinions i can
say one thing we absolutely teach in our
in all of our programs
is that scientifically
the species uh
cannabis is cannabis sativa l
we don't you know we don't uh
we don't teach cannabis indica we teach
about it that
you know lamerick used it when he
named uh the plant
um
you know
dr mcpartlin actually gives
some taxonomy information he's published
uh in that area as well
and um
you know he
he goes into great detail in one of his
publications about
some of the problems with those
scientific names that are out there
and the truth is you know it doesn't
seem like anyone has been able to
morphologically
genetically
or chemically
categorize plants as cannabis indica or
cannabis sativa
in any kind of consistent fashion
and so if you want to use cannabis
indica and sativa
in kind of this popular vernacular as
it's used right now in
dispensaries
that's a different story but the problem
is you know if you look at the way it's
used
and you then try to
look at the chemicals that are found in
those plants there's nothing that really
is categorizing things as indica and
sativa consistently chemically
and like i said morphologically or
genetically so those names should really
not be applied and um there's there's a
funny there's a funny thing we talk
about in our classes because i think dr
mcpartlin pointed it out um in one of
his publications is
that you know
one cannabis cup had i'm forgetting the
strain name
and let's say
jack herrera win as a sativa and then
two years later it won as an indica
so
yeah yeah so i mean that's the problem
right there and and
maybe you know it's a it's kind of a
placebo effect where somebody thinks
they're getting something uplifting
because it's sativa and then it makes
them feel uplifted
but there just isn't really a scientific
basis to it right now
that makes sense and it seems like
genetically all these plants are so
mixed now um
there really isn't anything that one
could say is
purely one or the other but you know we
for years
you know people would say oh that
plant's a sativa based on its growth
habit or based on the
the therapeutic effects they may receive
from it um and vice versa
and it was always the assumption and it
wasn't until um
well frankly until i talked to some
people on this podcast that i really
learned the difference there and
interestingly enough what we're seeing
from a consumer perspective
with
blind blind research is that folks
when you know people are using thc as a
purchasing decision in terms of higher
ghc being
better but when consumers when you take
away the thc percentage and just give
them
the cannabis
uh through a double-blind study the ones
that are having the best effects are not
the highest thc
products um which
is interesting so um i'm hoping the
industry will change its terminology and
come up with something that's a little
bit
better but i don't know what that looks
like i've had some longer conversations
with folks
way uh way smarter on this topic than me
but i think it's really interesting
yeah i mean it's a problem it's you know
when when you have an industry that
has this deep roots
and some of them aren't based on um you
know what what
uh nestian industries are you know
usually based on is oversight and um
rules
then
you have something that's hard to get
rid of and the truth is
i don't know you know i'm not in
marketing at all and i have no idea how
you would convince
consumers to not want stream names or
indica or sativa
but yes the truth is you know
there's published literature out there
where people have tried to separate out
indicas and sativas out of you know
dispensaries in california for example
and there's no consistency um and then
even strain names you know what you're
getting
at one dispensary under one straining is
definitely not what you're getting at it
at another
and part of it goes back to the growing
process so say you have a genetically
identical plant but it's grown in
different
uh methodologies even you know say
nutrients
light wavelength
time of harvest or even
post harvest the way it's stored those
can all affect the chemicals in it and
make it that you have an inconsistent
product that's labeled the theme and
that's the problem is all if all you're
labeling it is these names so it's not
the same thing because they're
the botanical rules of nomenclature are
not being followed
there is you know a cultivated plant
code
and there are you know temp cultivars
but we are not there with with marijuana
um but to be clear i think you can tell
apart hemp and marijuana right our our
government thinks so too by by setting
this limit
on the amount of thc
and there does seem to be two groupings
of plants ones that are high in thc and
ones that are low and now clearly
there's all sorts of hybrids but going
back to the indica and sativa debate i
think that's going to be a hard one
to ever really truly separate and if
there ever were two
different cannabis species before
you know they were domesticated
i think it would be really hard to to
un-domesticate them at this point and
go back to you know their ancestral
forms um because
right now everything can hybridize
marijuana and hemp can hybridize you
know every strain can hybridize and
produce a viable offspring
and that is the very basic concept of
you know the definition of a species
it's the biological species concept if
you can have two organisms
mate and produce a viable offspring
then you don't have separate units
and
in that case species
yeah i mean even the use of the term
strain
versus uh cultivar is really um just an
example of the nomenclature in our
industry and how
how you know what's become common is not
necessarily what's botanically correct
exactly yes
so yeah this correct term would be
cultivar but you have to prove um
you know consistency with cultivars and
that you know you're getting something
that's considered a cultivar and you
plant it you can know what you would
expect
and
cannabis industry is not there so this
main strain which actually has no i
don't even know the origin of why we
call things strains but it doesn't seem
there's nothing scientific about it
i think because of things like bacteria
it probably just was a carryover from
from there right yeah
and black market um
i don't know but um wouldn't it be
called a cultivar because it's not a
variety because it is a it is something
that's been cultivated
by humans um
with an intended purpose as i understand
it from botanical perspective but i
could be wrong what else what else would
we call it
even with the genetic diversity that you
see across
you know given plant you'll call
something a cultivar once it hits
that
you know
kind of
standardization that a cultivar would
require because that is you know
cultivars
um
it doesn't so you have it you have a
species right and
then you'd have a cultivar so if we take
corn for example like vmas and then if
you're buying a cultivar of vmas you'll
have that half per that half parenthese
and it will say like super sweet
right and so that's eventually what
cannabis should be it should be cannabis
sativa with
the cultivar name um and that's you know
that's what people would be
used to buying in
current agriculture
is a cultivar and you plant super sweet
and you're not going to get flower corn
right you're going to get corn on the
cob that you eat yeah yeah
but yeah that's that's not really
happening with with marijuana right now
um
uh hemp you can definitely import
hemp seeds like
for example
is a cultivar of hemp
and you can get what you expect
um
but
and i think part of that goes back to
following the
rules for uh the botanical nomenclature
because there's ones for cultivars too
um and then and then oversight of
following those rules
that's i didn't know i didn't know all
that that's really interesting yeah
thank you
yeah
um well
we've been talking for quite a while i
know you're you're busy um
i just want to thank you for your time
today on the show and i hope folks will
check out the
program that you have and i'll include
links to all that on the podcast page if
anyone wants to go back and i'm going to
try and track down what research i can
that you mentioned as well and
put that on there too so thank you for
your time today
sure it was a it was a joy thank you so
much for having me kyle
[Music]
that was dr monique mchenry with the
university of vermont cannabis science
and medicine and plant biology
certificate programs and you are
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast i'm your host tad
hussey if you like the podcast please
leave us a rating and review and give us
a follow on instagram you can also sign
up for our newsletter on our website
homepage to stay up to date on the
latest research and information thanks
for listening
you