[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation in
science podcast
I'm your host CAD Hussey of KISS
organics this is the podcast where we
discuss the cutting edge of organic
growing from a science-based perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge it's been almost a year now
since we launched the podcast and I want
to thank everyone for all the positive
feedback and support I've received I've
got some amazing guests in the works and
can't wait to share the information with
you guys I'm also hoping to add some
more educational videos and blogs to the
website in the coming months don't
forget if you want to stay up to date
with everything we are up to you can
subscribe to our newsletter on our home
page at WWE is organics calm I promise
we won't share your information and
won't blow up your inbox with emails
anyway let's get on with today's show
our guest this week is Casey shoenberger
Casey is the Director of Sales for drams
corporation's fertilizer and farm
segments DRAM produces dramatic fish
hydrolysate fertilizers in addition he
and his wife Shelley operate happy
little farm in Conway Washington growing
a variety of fruits vegetables and nuts
I brought him on to educate us on fish
hydrolysate and other fish products how
are they made are they sustainable
what's the difference between fish
hydrolysate and fish emulsion and much
much more here's our conversation all
right hey Casey thanks for coming on the
show today I really appreciate it thanks
crabmeat dad
yeah can we give listeners a little bit
of your background into how you got into
farming and specifically more these
these fish products yeah sure kind of a
funny story taking me from my home and
leading me back to my home so I grew up
in Wisconsin and went to college there
and while I was in college I came out
here to where I'm currently living in
Seattle area and I came out to study
killer whales and out in the San Juan
Islands just off of north of Seattle and
loved it out here and ended up sticking
around in the area in getting into
teaching environmental education and got
really into that really enjoyed that and
kind of found a calling I guess and that
led me into really looking at the
environmental side of our food systems
diving in deep on that trying to figure
out how we're gonna grow food in the
future so that we're not harming future
generations that led me to spending a
year on a permaculture farm out there
called Bullock's permaculture farm where
I learned a lot of sustainable living
skills a lot about growing food and just
honestly really nerded out with the
stack of books from the library next to
my bed every night and learning
everything I could about growing fruits
vegetables nuts let's see and then left
there my wife and I moved back to her
family's farm where she grew up
and we ended up buying a 20 acre chunk
from her parents and started doing a
community supported agriculture farm and
immediately planted everything we could
so every fruit nut and vegetable that
you can grow in the climate which is
know for your listener is a great way to
make sure that there's always something
to do outside and also a really good way
to make sure that you never turn a
profit trying to be so diversified but
it's you know our pantry always looks
amazing and it's really fun and
educational just probably not the
greatest business plan in the world so
we continue to do something like that in
some form every year we do a lot of work
trade because we both work off the farm
and so that led me I went back and
visited my family in Wisconsin and ended
up bringing my wife and kids to take a
tour of this fertilizer plant this
organic fertilizer plant I had her
about that's just five minutes from my
parents house though this is kind of
near Green Bay Wisconsin right on Lake
Michigan and I took the two are not
really knowing what I was getting into
and watch the process of this recycling
of fish scraps that we'll get into more
here on this call and got to the end of
it and just said wow this is amazing you
guys are taking a waste waste stream
source and making this incredible
fertilizer out of it and this is five
minutes from where I grew up this is
crazy
and we got to the end and they actually
mentioned that they're looking to hire
somebody out in the Seattle area to work
with the Alaskan fisheries on obtaining
scrap and I said give me a call and one
thing led to another and Here I am eight
years later of working for DRAM so now
I'm currently the director of sales of
our fertilizer division now I grew up
knowing about DRAM because my parents
owned a nursery but when I think of DRAM
I think of sprayers and I think of hoses
and and things like that so what can you
talk a little bit on what DRAM overall
as a corporation does I know they have
hands in a lot of different aspects of
agriculture sure and that's yeah I'm
right with you we're where I had worked
at a nursery as the you know the edible
food the edible plant specialist and and
that's what I knew drama is is anything
that you screw onto the end of a hose
has drams name on it so the water wands
so the company actually started like 80
years ago now we celebrated our 75th
anniversary just recently really cool
company created and and are started in
Wisconsin and the the flagship invention
was the water breaker so you're familiar
with that that the screen that softens
the water spray so that you don't
trample your flowers when you're when
you're watering them and so that's still
what a lot of people know DRAM for is
you know go into any flora culture
greenhouse or anything and what you
screw onto the end of a hose DRAM also
has a you know developed a line of home
gardener tools and so you go into an
independent garden center and you'll see
a big colorful racks of sprinklers and
hoses and and don't you screw on to the
hoses and then our commercial division
that I was just describing does
you know if you build a greenhouse we do
pretty much we can do pretty much
everything after that so the fan layout
the irrigation systems known a lot for
really high quality sprayers chemical
applicators we do the hoses and so on we
have another division that deals with
it's our newest division dealing with
water purification systems using ozone
the more high capital projects and just
the coolest company I work for with you
know
family-owned and and nobody ever leaves
the joke is you know nobody ever leaves
the company so a lot of people have been
there for 20 30 years and so on
so that was a long way of saying about
20 years ago the the owner of the
company Kurt Graham started using a fish
fertilizer in Wisconsin and was amazed
at his little you know his small hobby
greenhouse at the results he was seeing
you know just on plants like cyclamen
and so on and he went to the to the
plant and took a look at it and at that
time it was pretty rundown and open
tanks and it was near the high school
near the high school that I actually
went to and ended up buying the plant
and buying a building and really making
everything you know state-of-the-art as
far as fish fertilizer goes and so we're
really proud of our plant it's very
clean and we've just recently invested
in a lot more storage so that we can age
the product of product longer you know I
can get into that a little bit more
later but yeah we've been doing the fish
fertilizer thing for about 20 years
reason a lot of existing Graham
customers don't know about it is we you
know we do a lot of the other dram
business for indoor growing the flora
culture industry and the fish fertilizer
just naturally fits a lot more in the
outdoor agriculture so we sell a lot of
it in 5,000 gallon tanker loads to
outdoor growers yeah and I want to get
into that on scale affordability and
some of the issues issues around
application methods and rates but can we
just talk a little bit more about the
process itself so most people have heard
of fish fertilizer but that carries a
lot of that falls into a lot of
different categories and many people
aren't aware of the different
and I would say the two big ones in
terms of liquids when we talk about
liquid applications would be emulsion or
hydrolysate or hydro lysate we were
talking before the podcast and you said
it could be pronounced either way I've
always said hydrolysate so can you
describe sort of that process in terms
of how emulsion is made and how
hydrolysate is made and then we can look
into some of the ways that they're
different sure yeah I mean it's a common
question like you said and and you know
especially when I when I started
emulsions were around more I I don't see
it as much especially on the on the
commercial scale I think you you know
still go into a box store there's gonna
be a fish emulsion on the shelf the fish
emulsions are a thicker material they're
usually lower there I mean they're
always lower price tag and so that's
always attractive usually less than half
the price of a hydrolysis the emulsions
as far as I know are usually made from
menhaden from the Gulf of Mexico and so
there's some concerns there with
sustainability and now I say that
knowing there's probably some other
emulsions on the market that aren't made
from that that source a lot of times as
far as I know the emulsions they'll
remove proteins and some of the oils
that's a big one for us is the
hydrolysis will usually have a good fish
oil content in them and we think that
that's very beneficial so what you get
at the end with the emulsions is a
thicker material that's going to be
higher in nitrogen so that's obviously
something that growers like so you have
a cheaper cheaper fertilizer that's
usually an analysis that's something
like five one one so five percent
nitrogen one percent phosphorous and one
percent potassium it where is like the
hydrolyse that are hydrolysate our base
is a two five zero point two so two
percent nitrogen five percent Foss
zero point two percent potassium and
that's we're a little bit higher in
fosston some other ones but that's those
are those are in general are pretty
close to the numbers so then you might
ask why would you buy the hydrolysis why
is it more popular than the emulsion the
big difference is we're not heating it
up and removing all that stuff
so what you have is this this low heat
process where the vitamins the proteins
the amino acids are not broken down and
so the the the general thought is that
the hydrolysis speed beneficial fungus
and bacteria like nothing else so I
would say that more than 50% of our
business is customers not buying on NPK
they're definitely not buying on
nitrogen per dollar that's just never
the case with hydrolysis with what
they're usually buying is this
incredible food stores and so you know
we can get into this later but a lot of
times our fish will be sold right with
some sort of biological product you know
that I'm sure you're familiar with the
bugs in a bottle idea big industry of
folks trying to isolate the good guys
you know compost tea would be a way of
of doing that by yourself and then you
know there's plenty of companies that
are really trying to isolate a handful a
really good bacteria and so they would
sell that along with our fish to help
multiply it once it goes on your on your
plant or on your yeah I definitely want
to talk about that aspect of it that
microbial side of things but can you
just explain a little bit about how
emulsion is just how it's made you
mentioned high heat in that process and
then typically this menhaden this yeah
and I guess you know I I've never been
in an emulsion Factory and so I'm a
little bit hesitant to you know go on
record telling you how it's made
okay but but yeah what what I've been
told is that you're using ocean fish
your your your heating to extract the
oils and the proteins sometimes that oil
will be sold off separately as a
cosmetic industry and so on and in some
cases protein is removed for livestock
feed and then you have this thicker
liquid left at the end and so it's you
know a waste product of a waste product
that said I'll I tell people you know if
you're looking for a cheap source of
organic nitrogen you know try to make
sure it's an actual organic emulsion you
know that they're using an organic
process and not throwing something else
in there and usually if it's a 5-1 one
or four one one definitely not a bad
source of nitric
it's just not gonna be as good of a
microbial food source as a hydrolic that
will be yeah in my experience and also
this is a lot of the work from Tim
Wilson of microbe organics was that when
you start using these fish products
emulsion or hydrolysate in compost teas
the emulsion would actually inhibit
microbial growth in a lot of cases
whereas the hydrolysate is one of the
best fungal foods out there I mean it
feeds the bacteria as well so you get a
good good growth with the bacteria but
specifically it's an excellent fungal
food which there's not a lot of great
ones out there for that so yeah that's
what I've heard and I've done that here
I have a decent-sized compost tea brewer
and so that idea of if you're gonna use
your compost tea on your orchard where
you're going for a higher fungal
population and I've definitely heard it
both ways of whether to add the
hydrolysis at the beginning or wait
until the end but that's interesting
about the inhibition on the on the
emulsion you know it kind of surprises
me a little bit right yeah and it was it
was this was over a decade ago so I
don't want to totally go on record there
either but I will say that there is
quite a dramatic difference I can
confidently say that between hydrolysis
and emulsion from microbial perspective
with hydrolysate being far superior now
you did mention adding it at the end of
a brew I will say Tim Wilson did a lot
of research on this and found that if
you add fish hydrolysate at the end of a
high quality compost tea brew you can
drop your dissolved oxygen levels within
minutes so it's much much better to add
at the beginning or use it as a separate
application from a compost tea
perspective at least what we're seeing
when we use a dissolved oxygen meter and
a microscope to evaluate the quality of
compost tea brew wow that's that's
fascinating yeah and I I mentioned the
DRAM water division that's what we're
seeing a lot is you know we the main
idea at the beginning was a good
effective way to clean clean water using
the ozone the what's come out of it
you know and we of course knew dissolved
oxygen is good we had no idea how good
and so studies and a lot of the
anecdotal evidence coming out of these
greenhouses putting on extremely high
levels of dissolved oxygen in their
water
as far as edelen's doing way better but
of course the inhibition of pathogens
you know we know that pathogens love
anaerobic environments and they don't
like high levels of dissolved oxygen but
that that benefit of of high levels of
dissolved oxygen has become incredibly
apparent so one other key difference I
believe is that the emulsion tends to
have a much stronger odor I just opened
your bottle of hydrolysate the same way
I mean it definitely smells like fish
there's no denying that but it's not
overwhelming though I don't have the
best sense of smell either I have heard
that emotion is a much stronger odor
I've heard that too I've used emulsion
it's been a while since I used in
emulsion obviously you know the guy I'm
not going out and buying fish emulsion
but I literally have our product on my
face right now
oh it's just outside excited giving
giving a dose on our vegetables and I'm
I can be a little bit clumsy when I'm in
a hurry and add some splash up on me and
yeah what we like to say is it smells
like fish you know it doesn't smell like
rotten fish you know Kirk Graham cold me
you know right off the bat it smells
like the ocean breeze I like that I like
that description but yeah it shouldn't
smell like rotten fish and I've heard
people say that emulsions are a little
bit more of an offensive odor the good
part about it especially outdoor using
it outdoors is it literally goes away by
the next day you know so your neighbors
you know people in suburban areas using
it on lawns you can definitely smell it
for a couple hours but it it goes away
I've also heard you know you had some
people will add if the smell is really a
concern molasses can actually act as a
masking agent for it
we've experimented a little bit with
like peppermint oil and that kind of
stuff but I I just you know it smells
like fishy peppermint which I don't know
that that's a whole lot better I've
smelled that it gets a little weird I
agree yeah right so we've talked a
little bit about emulsion but let's
let's talk a focus really quick on how
hydrolysate is made right so how do you
have this product what's that how do you
make this product yeah it's funny
because it's pretty simple yeah and I'll
get into what the complicated part is
it's simple but I wouldn't recommend
starting your own plant because
of the complications so so we take scrap
from from the fishing industry so we're
taking all wild fish scrap after they
take the fillet off we'll take
everything else it's really important to
us for Graham it's really important to
us that we get some of the duck material
that has the natural enzymes in it kind
of a just a cool synergistic thing with
natures that those those enzymes and the
fish guts help break break down the fish
for it so what we're doing is obtaining
scrap in our case it's almost all
completely from the five Great Lakes the
fishing industry on the five Great Lakes
will bring them into our plant in in
totes grind them up and then will digest
them and at that point we're adding an
acid so all the hydrolysis use an acid
at that stage we prefer to use
phosphoric acid it's a little bit more
expensive than the alternative which
would be sulfuric acid at this point a
lot of people ask how how we can use
phosphoric or sulfuric acid seeing as
though on their own they're not
considered organic and that's the
National Organic Standards Board made a
ruling that it won't be possible to make
fish burger like that fish fertilizer is
a necessary ingredient for organic
agriculture and we need to have a
stabilizing aid so we're allowed to use
enough of it to get it pH stabilized and
so that's the key here tad is that what
what we're really doing is pickling fish
got it's not unlike you know your
grandma making vinegar pickles and
putting them in the pantry so we're
grinding digesting so we're letting it
sit in the tank with the acid and digest
then we run it through an emulsifier and
then a key for DRAM is that we have an
incredible amount of storage tanks where
we can eat the product longer and really
let those fine bits of bone break down
and get into the liquid and so that's
that's a big one for us as we end up
with almost always 1% of calcium in it
and that is a little bit rare some of
the other companies will filter those
filter that bone out and sell that as a
separate product I'm sure you've seen
fishbone meal
floating around and that's that's that
would be that product we're trying to
get back into the liquid does that give
you phosphorus as well because I know
fish bone meal tends to be high in pee
yeah okay yeah this boat it would be
high yep
so then that helps us get to that 5%
phosphorus number you know some some
hydrolysis that are made from like a
product fish that are more a cartilage
based they that would I've seen numbers
that's three so you'd see like a two
three one again two percent nitrogen
three percent one percent
faciem so then it's at the very end
we're screening it and blending it and
so what's pretty cool about our places
you you you go and what's left at the
end you know the the the solids that
come out at the end because we're aging
it so long is not much at all
you know like for how much fertilizer
comes out of our factory you know you'll
see a couple 55-gallon drums of solid at
the very end and that's a combination of
the enzymes and the fish guts and then
the acid breaking down those solids and
getting them down to where they can make
it through a 200 mesh screen twice
before we ship it out but that's it in
so and so I got at the point that is a
fairly simple process the hard part tad
is we're taking something that I just
said earlier feeds beneficial biology
like nothing else and then we're trying
to stabilize it so we can put it in the
little bottles and ship it all over the
world literally we sell it all over the
world and sometimes it doesn't get used
for six months and so that's the tricky
part is we're trying to take this this
extremely bioactive product and
stabilize it for this moment in time and
so that's all about hitting this correct
pH there's other factors besides pH you
know as far as getting it able so just
so I understand that you get in all of
these this these fish guts and fish
carcasses essentially this by-product it
goes into a giant tank or multiple tanks
and then the phosphoric acid is added
first as a way of establishing a pH a
target pH so you're aiming for is that
right right otherwise we would end up
smelling like the emulsion you're
talking about
right so if we're not ph stabilizing
that early in the process you're going
to start to have a beautification okay
so then you hit this pH and then and
then sort of stabilizes everything and
then at that point your you say you
emulsified so you're just mixing it
really well and then the natural enzymes
and the fish are breaking down all the
organic matter I guess you would say
that the carcasses themselves over time
and then when you're done are you
restabilizing it or is that really the
whole step so now we do need to check so
we have we do check before it goes out
the door to make sure it's within the pH
parameters the quality control pH
parameters right so somewhere in between
3.5 and 4 pH okay but that if we do need
to we in rather than adjusting will do
like blending if we do ever do have a
problem there you know where we're we're
up above where we want to be or in that
situation you know and a lot of times
there's wiggle room there as far as
being above four we'd probably still be
alright since we really prefer to have
it in that range so there shouldn't be
any real microbes coming in on it at
that point because of the high acidity
is that is that right and that's what
allows it to stay stable in the bottle
right except there is some life so we're
good on the good news is that pH range
kills a really bad guys so Salmonella
e.coli and so on there will be some life
if we stick it under a microscope but
not enough life to make a a 275 gallon
tote below up which which if you talk to
people veterans of the fish fertilizer
industry everybody's got a story right
of something getting away from them and
a lot of times that happens that more
often with sulfuric acid products that's
part of the reason we don't like to use
the cheaper sulfuric acid is there's a
reaction going on between the the
fishbone or any of the solid and the
acid where as that bone gets broken down
the pH will rise and when we use
sulfuric acid that tends to happen
faster or less predictably I guess would
be the best way to say it and so you'd
be more likely to have
a pH shoot up when you don't want it to
be but to answer your question there you
know some of this is a little bit
unknown to us of you know that what
exact parameters and so we're constantly
logging and trying to learn more about
that so people really aren't making
their own fish hydrolysate at home they
might be making it more of a fish
emulsion it sounds like if you were to
take fish and grind it up and then let
apply it to your plants that's
essentially an emulsion more or less
yeah yeah except I don't know that this
I mean I your emulsifying fishing so I
guess you know I can pick a trout in my
Vitamix here that would technically be
an emulsified kraut you know whether
that would actually be what what on the
market has sold as fish emulsion you
know because the in that case there is a
heating process and stuff removed but
yeah I have seen some some YouTube
videos of some guys make it homemade
what I've recommended to people is
because it does happen where somebody
gets a line on say University doing
Studies on fish and having these fish
carcasses that they need to dispose of
and actually yeah bollocks permaculture
farm where I live they had a great story
about that where they had a line on
Aldous dish and so big and this is what
I do recommend is composted hot compost
it you know if you have the means to do
it get a lot of good carbon source but
if I remember that story you know from
20 years ago there was that was that
they buried it all you know in the
compost pile and then maybe forgot about
somebody forgot about it and went and
tried to move it with the traffic
tractor loader and there's you know not
much worse smells than that of you know
rotten anaerobic rotten fish so you just
want to keep it aerated obviously yeah
and wild animals are gonna go crazy yeah
that so that's yeah right but as someone
who's hoping to get into fishing here as
a personal hobby as I get older I have
heard of people taking those fish guts
and burying them right into their
gardens Native Americans used to put
them under there
I believe under there corridor tomato
plants and things like that so people
can definitely use fish in those ways
and there's so much information online
people can go read about about that but
it is important I think differentiate
that hydrolysate is a totally different
product that you're not you're not
making it at home I guess is what out
the point I wanted to get across to
people right
one thing you touched on was shelf-life
you said six months like that was a long
time what isn't what is a good
shelf-life for these products do we need
to worry about that when we're buying
them from say a garden center or you
don't you know we need to put a shelf
life on it you know just because that's
what you do
there's some people who think that
there's actually a continual breakdown
going on in the bottle I'm not sure that
that's true as far as the microscopic
you know solids that make it through the
200 mesh screen but I would be I would
feel perfectly comfortable if I found
you know out of my barn an old bottle
from eight years ago when I started
working for DRAM using it all right
the way that I say I'd like I've said it
a couple times already is treat it like
you would a jar of pickles that you made
a jar of vinegar pickles that you made
that you found in your pantry and I just
just ate some spicy pickled asparagus
from 2015 yesterday and it tasted just
fine
you know what I'm saying so so if it's
pH stabilized nothing should be
happening in there and so that is an
advantage of the hydrolysis versus some
of the other you know like biological
amendments you'd be buying in the
organic world yeah I've got I got a 50
grand 50 gallon drum right now at my
farm that we found who knows how old it
is it could be two to five years now I
don't know quite what I'm gonna do with
yet but they didn't have a really bad
odor so I was just gonna use my nose
sort of as a guide there and hopefully
still use it on my on my plants so the
one thing that wouldn't be uncommon
there that is is for you to look down
into that drum and see some white mold
on the top and when that's been tested
it's a simple bread mold I mean you know
if you
want to be really careful you would
actually get it tested but a lot of
times what that would be is a very
simple safe bread mold and so you just
need to filter that out but I would feel
I would feel okay using that personally
yeah and I don't worry too much about
these sorts of things when I'm applying
them to ornamentals or to soil directly
because I think the nature kind of
handles a lot of that now spraying it
directly onto my finished vegetables or
my crops is probably something I
wouldn't recommend but exactly yep yeah
I think you just have to look at
different materials and treat them
differently depending on all these
circumstances so we talked a little bit
about how fish hydrolysate is made
versed in the difference between that
and emulsion can you talk a little bit
about the quality and the differences
now I'm not trying to throw you under
the bus regarding other companies but
I've heard you know there's a bunch of
companies out there making this you know
just to throw some names out there
Organic gem Neptune's harvest what's the
one close to me Pacific that's gonna
grow is if I grow so there's other
companies making fish hydrolysate and
some are putting in you know biochar
you're putting in kelp
I've heard of some putting in crustacean
meal can you just talk a little bit
about the are there differences I guess
across these different companies besides
like maybe the species of the fish is
that all the exact same process yeah
you're I mean obviously that's a tough
spot for me because up because what I
can really speak about is our process
you know and what we're doing that I've
kind of went in-depth on so yes there's
a difference between ocean oceans are
there a difference is ocean fish versus
our fish from the Great Lakes but just
because the place is on the coast
doesn't necessarily mean that it's all
ocean ocean fish I don't know that
that's a conclusion you want to draw in
this case I think that pretty much is
the case that the the the ones that the
the companies you mentioned on the coast
are using ocean fish are you going to
see higher sodium levels in fish drawn
from saltwater versus freshwater or do
they wash them so family is that not
and in the flesh I believe though I
don't know that it's going to be harmed
you know the levels that you're using
fish unless you're you know we do have
some growers who really dive in and use
you know over a hundred gallons per acre
you know hop growers really like our
fertilizer a lot and some of them will
used extremely high volumes of it to the
point where if we add higher sodium
levels and ours that would be
detrimental or if you're in the you know
in eastern Washington you know near
where we live on the other side of the
mountains where there's just not enough
rainfall to wash out that sodium and you
were using extremely high levels but I I
don't have a recent comparison of our
lake fish versus ocean fish of whether
it's really a big difference in sodium
levels as far as process I can't speak
to that as much I mean you can always
look at the NPK and get an idea from
that so when I said the the lower
phosphorous levels the it's possible
that the bone is being pulled out
earlier and this in sold as a separate
product I would ask if you think calcium
is important like I do in you know most
crops or all crops
she's like apple growers and Eastern
Washington trying to prevent bitter pit
I say hey if you're buying somebody
else's fish just ask them you know for a
lab analysis showing what their calcium
is that's something we're proud of in
ours see I'm trying to think of Bo and
then yeah you hit on it a little bit we
do several different blends with ours
and so we have a fish a fishing kelp we
have a fish helped fall Vick and humic
acid product and then we also will
dissolve sodium nitrate or Chilean
nitrate into some of our blends to get
out four percent or five percent
nitrogen product that has a quick
release organic nitrogen source along
with that slow release sorry we have the
the quick release nitrate nitrogen
source in the Chilean nitrate that's
still certified organic and then that
slower release nitrogen from the the
other 2% of the nitrogen and so I really
like that combination especially you
know like a
said I was just out fertilizing
vegetables here in the Skagit Valley
where the soil takes forever to warm up
you know I'm three feet above sea level
and so getting that little bit of
nitrate into those plants as they're
they're popping up here and in the
spring is really important but those are
things you know as far as different
blends that the companies make would be
a difference you know at the beginning
is if you're asking making sure you're
getting any hydrolysis if if one of your
goals is to really amp up your your
biology in your organic system you're
you're already you know starting out
really well you know they're they're
just a you really should be thinking of
emulsions and hydrolysis is two very
different things not as all being fish
fertilizer okay so start with the idea
that hydrolysates are gonna be superior
in a lot of ways to emulsions but one of
the things I like you said is there's
different ones that are put people are
putting in different different
ingredients and I think it's important
that people look further into that so
like and again this is not a comment on
any particular product in general or
company but I've seen some they're
adding biochar which on the surface
sounds great now we don't know the
quality of the biochar and we don't know
the concentration of biochar so that's
the sort of stuff that as a grower I
would want to look further into and I
don't actually know the answer to these
questions in those particular products
but that's what I would want to know
before I started really getting heavy
into applying them and same with you
know even the kelp or the crustacean to
find out sort of what levels are going
to be in there because I know getting
something on a label versus putting
enough in to actually make a noticeable
change in your crop it can be very
different based on the bureaucracy
around the fertilizer industry so and
the other thing I want to touch on too
is you mentioned that your products it's
a lot longer than maybe traditionally
done by some of these other hydrolysate
companies that's another thing I would
look into when I'm trying to determine
quality of a product so just just some
things some pointers for listeners to
maybe think about as they consider using
fish products in their garden and
one of the things I wanted to touch on
that I know is a little tricky for you
too is just the idea that when you look
at a bottled nutrient an organic bottled
nutrient product whether it's a bottle
of nutrient line from pretty much any
company out there in the cannabis
industry if they list fish on the on the
label as I understand it's most likely
fish hydrolysate is that correct yeah
really tough for me to answer you know I
mean I know that we do work with some of
those companies sending ingredients over
right but very difficult for me to
answer whether some of them are using
emulsion and what you know the labeling
laws are so tricky and as I'm sure you
know is like each state has different
regulations to the point where it's not
even legally possible to have the same
fertilizer label you have an Oregon of
the label you have in California where
the requirements are are at odds with
each other and so as far as what you're
required to list on there and I think
some of those cases so I'm very lucky in
that I am not the person I drafted has
to deal with all that we thank our
friend Tim Daly for being the one who
has to jump through those hoops but if
you're using you know as you're alluding
to if they're adding a such a small
amount of some of this stuff where
they're just trying to put it on you can
actually omit some of that from the
label is my understanding in some state
so I you know the best thing to do is to
ask and in that case it's a little bit
harder to ask and that's what I was
gonna you know say about comparing the
fish fertilizers a lot of times or
usually in our case it's sold through
distribution so that's a little bit
trickier but a lot of times our
distributors will send customers
straight to us and I'm totally fine I'm
happy with that you know I mean I'm
proud of the way we make our fertilizer
but that would be my advice for your
listeners is ask you know if you're
buying from a certain label and they're
obviously not a fish fertilizer
producers end of an email and say hey
whose fish fertilizer are you using you
know they might got they probably won't
give you the answer to that but is it
hydrolysis it or isn't an emulsion yeah
at the very least they can tell you that
and the labeling laws are a mess I gotta
tell you I've been working on our
California label now for a year and a
half it sucks it's just it's been
terrible like you're in Washington I can
call us kiss organics but in California
I can't unless all of our products are
certified to produce an organic or an
agriculture by them which I totally get
because it can be misleading to
consumers but they're just very they're
very strict in terms of what they allow
and don't allow and they don't accept
Omri they don't accept double USDA and
it's it's been really eye-opening like
for example with your product being a
two 50.2 in Washington Oregon you could
actually have five percent nitrogen or
ten percent phosphorus in theory on the
label on your on your tests but you
don't have to declare that on your
actual label so if you were great you
know and that gets in you and I could go
on for a while and I don't know yeah I
don't want to hear it but it's crazy
that you know because there's laws in
some places about phosphorus fertilizers
because of runoff and that it's my
understanding that you can put down a
zero for phosphorous even though you
have five percent phosphorous in it to
get around those to get around the
labeling laws that are supposed to
supposed to prevent people from dumping
too much on their lawns and having it go
into their the the lake next door so
yeah some of it's crazy we fight through
it
yeah yeah that's it probably is a whole
nother podcast so I just I just want to
encourage people to really look into the
sourcing and and use that as a guide for
determining quality when they're
evaluating different products in general
not just not just fish products but
let's get back into some of the aspects
of applying these products so this is a
liquid it's a concentrate you're gonna
be mixing it with water can you talk a
little bit about application rates and
methods for applying fish hydrolysate
yes and so one of the big advantages for
me is that fish fertilizer
in so many different ways and so it
there is no one-size-fits-all or this is
how much to use and this is the way to
put it on so that's the strength of our
fertilizer and most liquid organic
fertilizers is there's a lot of ways to
put them on that said I will get into
some of the obstacles so you can apply
it straight on the plant you can apply
it on the soil one way I really like for
especially for larger growers is
dripping it on on the seed at planting
getting back to what we talked about
about its ability to grow beneficial
fungus you know if you can put your your
mind there on that seed popping up and
having that what I call the fungal force
field you know that does beautiful
bright white mycelium helping protect
that plant from some pathogens I love
that idea so we but we do have a lot of
growers who use it as a foliar
application we get anecdotal reports of
fungicidal effects and there are some
studies of fish products going back on
like blueberries showing some you know
fungicidal properties and I don't know
whether it's oils preventing those kind
of things or whether it's more just
promoting biodiversity and creating an
environment in which pathogen aren't
interested in in thriving sorry getting
off topic as far as application rates in
general a lot of folks will use it not
as their primary source of nutrients and
so they'll be using some sort of dry
fertilizer or cover crop in that
situation 2 to 5 gallons per acre per
application is common so the five
gallons more for for like orchards and
so on I'd say the most common rates
would be a two gallons per acre per
application three times during the
growing season that's a really common
one and so when you get into cost on
that say say you're buying the
fertilizer for four five or six bucks a
gallon you're not talking about a big
investment
to add into your program so when you're
talking about acreage right now a lot of
our guys maybe let's say they had a
small small garden so there may be
applying it by the gallon of water are
you're adding like what like maybe an
ounce or so per gallon right yeah so
we've ended dilution rates the two most
common dilution rates would be 20 parts
water to one part fertilizer okay that
probably that's the most common some
folks prefer a 50 to one in a lot of
cases though it comes down to you know
I've had it here where I'm traveling a
lot for work and I miss I'm only able to
get my one application in so I'll go for
a stronger fertilizer so I'll be using a
stronger amount and a stronger dilution
ratio and I'm not at all scared to get
down to ten to one with our fertilizer
and I would even go stronger dilution
rate than that I did some experiments
here trying to you know just using a
backpack sprayer going with some because
the concern the next question would
usually be how low can I go or how
strong of a of a dilution ratio can I go
before I start burning stuff and I went
to like 3 to 1 on our product that has
the sodium nitrate in it and I saw a
little bit of brown spots on some
broccoli you know but that was where it
looked like straight fish fertilizer
coming out of the end of the end of the
sprayer so the versatility so it so in
but in some cases folks will do 5 7
applications you know if you're already
going out with your tractor the fish is
really compatible and in fact can work
as a spreader sticker for other products
and so some people just like to mix a
little bit of fish in their tank with
just about everything now because of the
phosphoric acid you want to avoid using
it with calcium products I'm sure you
sure you've heard that you know those
two two guys don't get along you'll have
a precipitate all out now are you pa
Qing the solution at all prior to
application I'm not I I don't know so so
we're it's gonna come out of our bottle
at a 3.5 before and then by the time you
dilute that it pops up quite a bit
that's not an area I mean
time's a lot of your listeners have have
programs and ways to test that stuff and
I just don't even get into it and again
I sell you know I sell a lot through
distribution and so I don't end up
working directly with with those growers
and what about growers in eastern
Washington hacked a lot of calcium in
their water already do they need to
treat that prior to using that water
with application you know that's a good
question I don't know that okay well
hopefully the people that have high
calcium waters already know how to deal
with that kiss we're really fortunate
here in the in the Western Washington to
not have we have wonderful water that's
that's one of the best things about
living here yeah so you mentioned a
little bit about affordability
you know you threw out some numbers like
I think you said seven to eight dollars
a gallon that sounds low to me but so
you must be talking about buying on
scale is that correct yeah that's where
you get into the single digits when
you're when you go in 55-gallon drums
are larger and so that's a big quite you
know a lot of the listeners for your
podcast are going to be that's a
decision that they would make of the two
points so our next size lower than a
55-gallon drum is a five gallon size and
so that's two two and a half gallon jugs
and that's what we decided to go with
rather than the five gallon bucket
people really like the convenience of
those the fact that you can just pick up
a 2.5 gallon jug and shake it you know
and get it nice and agitated so I think
where you're going with the question and
we're where the big question is is it
worth it to scale up to a 55-gallon drum
that you have to get shipped on a on a
on a semi that's going to weigh 600
pounds so you have to deal with it but
you're gonna pay about a third of the
price per gallon and so if you're going
to go through that much and then another
big advantage of fish hydrolysis is that
you could use half that drum in one
season and then use the rest the next
season and again you know watch for you
know whether bread mold will grow on it
in between you know if you're not using
it for four seven months you just check
on those things but that's what you'd be
looking at is saving that kind of thing
so say five dollars five to six dollars
per
gallon in the 55-gallon drum and I'm
using bag numbers for a couple reasons
as it depends you know how close it is
to you with the shipping and everything
then also we sell several different
blends that are all different price
points you know the more more extra
amendments we put in the higher the
price gets but then you'd be getting up
to say fifteen sixteen seventeen dollars
a gallon in in the 2.5 gallon jugs if
that gives you a good idea the
difference yeah a range and then of
course we saw we sell gallons and quarts
and in all of that - for even smaller
amounts but a lot of times that's the
big decision to grow our estimators
should I save the extra money on the
55-gallon drum but then I got a you know
use a paint mixer on the end of a power
drill it's really not that bad and you
have to have a 65 gallon drum pump but
those are all the considerations to make
you know and the more frugal growers you
know we'll we'll go ahead and do the
55-gallon drum and sometimes growers
will just say I I don't want to deal
with that
yeah I'm looking forward to talking to
Kurt Becker about applications and
spraying and he's a genius and that I
know he works for DRAM as well I get the
opportunity to meet him last year but
he's the man yeah he's out he really a
note that stuff inside and out of of
what you what the best solution is for
your problem in your greenhouse so we'll
dive into spraying and and all of that a
little more with him you did mention
drip systems as being a little bit
problematic I can't remember if you had
talked about them yet on this podcast
say it again you'd mentioned drip
systems as being a little bit
problematic for yeah that's where I was
gonna go with that thing thank you for
reminding me is that that's the big
question we get is can I put your stuff
through our drip system you know and
it's gonna the answer to that is gonna
depend a little bit on what type of drip
system you have how long you want it you
know some people will bury their lines
and want to keep them for several years
my answer my first answer is I don't put
it through drip at my place and I
recommend if you can put it on any other
way then putting it through a drip
system do that now you still get people
growers where their system is just not
going to have another way to get it on
and so if you're going to use it to drip
and lots of people do
and this would be for our fish
hydrolysis or for any liquid organic
fertilizer is you just have to be
vigilant about flushing with water and
then I recommend you occasionally using
some sort of organic you know bio side
so you got to make sure you're sticking
on label you know with things like wood
oxidate or sand a date or the I'm
hesitant to even say it on a podcast
because I don't know what you know
things would be allowed for it there's
also some enzyme products and I don't
know how are you familiar with there's
something EF 300 a guy in California
makes that I've heard great things about
I might have the name of that product
wrong I know you had Chris Jagger on the
podcast and I think Chris would be to go
to for that he's got an enzyme product
and he really likes for eating up living
stuff in the lines so that's your
concern is I'll say it again nothing see
it's beneficial fungus and bacteria like
fish hydrolysis but sometimes it feeds
those in places you don't want it and
that would be the inside of your drip
line right so algae growth and so on
yeah we're trying to avoid that biofilm
so if you actually let's say you're
putting it through piping that you can
reach your finger into if you'll slimy
or anything like that that's that
biofilm created by the biology that's
eating as a food source and that's what
that one dad is a really good place to
go with script Becker's he knows a lot
you know that's that's where our ozone
systems are big on um you know it's a
common problem how do we get rid of that
biofilm in our irrigation system and
that's something he's really dove into
coming up with solutions for growers on
yeah I'm looking forward to talking to
him there's so much I didn't even think
about when they came to spraying that
yeah I'm excited for that you know
Suzanne's always saying stop using paint
sprayers and he really explains what the
difference is in terms of the actual
size of the molecule or drip that you're
applying and it it was fascinating I
really enjoyed his presentation so I'm
looking forward to that for sure now
let's see for you the other the other
question I had then was can you use like
a so for example at my house here I just
put in a new lawn of sod and I was going
take the sample you gave me and put it
through a hose end sprayer as a way to
get it out onto the pond of the lawn
what do you think of something like that
that works great so we even sell you
know like the small retail bottles with
that hose end sprayer it's being
attached to them um you know that works
great another one that I've done here is
our you familiar DRAM actually sells the
siphon jekt
be familiar with that product no no so
it's it's kind of the next step down
from like the smallest dosatron and it's
just this incredibly simple technology a
little venturi injector and you take
that little you can look on the internet
for a dram size inject I think they're
less than $20 and it's got a little hose
line so you can do it a couple different
ways the one thing you need to make sure
is that you're following all the rules
on how to use it if you want to make
absolute certain that you're pulling the
product the fertilizer out of the bottle
at the right dilution rate and now for
our product it doesn't really matter
that much if you're doing you know
you're not gonna specially for how
you're talking about using it if you're
pulling it out at twice the dilution
ratio it doesn't really matter that much
so what I'm getting at is you you would
um you could either put it on the front
of the hose or the back of the hose so
back up the spigot and then you put the
little hose thing down into your
fertilizer bottle you screw that onto
the spigot and then you screw the hose
on to that part and so it's a little bit
difficult to describe over the phone
near but um then if you start spraying
with your with your hose and go through
a normal water wand and you are pulling
an exact dilution ratio pretty sure it's
fifty to one I should know that you get
what I'm saying so totally simple
technology of a injector that you know
you're not plugging it into an outlet
you're not doing anything like that it's
just really simple yeah so in my house
we have I'm on city water so there's
chlorine in the water so I'm going to
apply things like this fish hydrolysate
the dramatic kay here that you gave me
and things like seaweed extract powder
through my hose end sprayer because I'm
not applying anything that really has a
lot of
official microorganisms in it or that's
not the point of the application it's a
food source whereas when I go to apply
my compost tea to my garden I'm not
going to use that same sprayer because I
haven't filtered out the chlorine and I
would want to also determine that that
sprayer doesn't damage the bacteria or
break up the fungal hyphae during the
application but for things that are just
food sources or nutrients I think it'll
work great yeah I would I would love to
talk to you more often offline about
that because that's I have chlorinated
water here our farm also which surprises
people but you know like I said birds
I'm three feet above sea level here and
we just don't have well water where I'm
at in the Skagit Valley and I always
wonder about that when I was making
compost teas and so on I'm obviously not
gonna run when I brew beer here at the
farm I run everything through a Brita
you know or run everything through a
water filter but I'm obviously not going
to do that for irrigating crops so I
often wonder about how to handle that
situation I just put up a photo on our
Instagram also on our Facebook page for
kiss organics of compost tea that had
been made or added to chlorinated water
versus D chlorinated water and you can
see they're in petri dishes and it's a
dramatic difference I'm gonna be
interviewing a golf course
superintendent that I met oh boy almost
a decade ago that has gotten into using
organics and beneficial biology and he's
reduced his fertilizer applications on
his golf course is something like 70%
because golf courses are terrible when
it comes to the amount of pesticides and
inorganic fertilizers that they have to
use to keep the grass looking the way
you know golfers want it to look so go
check that out you might find it
interesting and even I can definitely
talk offline about about that for sure
in terms of compost tea but ya know I'll
definitely check that out thanks well I
think we covered all the questions I had
on on fish for the day and hopefully
this will help listeners know a little
bit more about the differences primarily
between emulsion and hydrolysate and how
to use
product and all of its benefits and yeah
I think I think we covered a lot here so
thanks for that
I appreciate it that it was fun and if
people want to get a hold of Casey or
have other questions and are interested
in trying out some of the DRAM fish
products I will put all that information
right on the podcast page as well so you
can get ahold of him or you can contact
me and I can get you as information I
appreciate that
all right I'll let you get back out to
your farm thanks again for today take
care kid that was Casey shoenberger the
director of sales for DRAM corporation's
fertilizer and farm segments you can
find many of their smaller sizes online
or local garden centers and if you're
interested in the five gallon size or
larger you can reach Casey directly to
place an order at three six zero three
three three four zero four four or via
his email which I will have on the
podcast page don't forget to mention the
podcast you are listening to the
cannabis cultivation and science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy don't forget
that there's more information and
articles on available on our website and
blog at WWE is organics calm as well as
links to the data and information we
discussed in this episode on the podcast
page thanks for listening
[Music]