[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
i'm your host tad hussey of kiss
organics this is the podcast where we
discuss the cutting edge of growing from
a science-based perspective and drawing
top
experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge
our guest this week is tom miles tom is
the president of tr miles technical
consultants in portland oregon
a biomass energy consulting firm which
designs
develops installs and commissions
systems for processing wood
agricultural and urban residues
innovative biomass systems includes
pyrolysis
gasification and combustion sizing
drying
densification handling modification of
boilers and gasifiers to improve
efficiency and emissions
and systems to recycle nutrients he has
developed heat and power systems in
developing countries
his knowledge of ash transformations and
biomass led to recycling nutrients using
pyrolysis of residues to biochar
which can improve soil health and
sequester carbon he has sponsors and
hosted online discussions of biomass
energy and biochar since 1994.
he is a past chairman of the
international biochar initiative
and executive director of the u.s
biochar initiative
now on to the show hey tom thanks for
coming on the show today
well thank you it's good to be here yeah
so tom can we start off with you telling
me a little bit about yourself
well i am a an engineering consultant in
portland oregon
uh fourth generation in wood products in
oregon
and so i grew up in the wood products
industry if you will
our firm has been doing mechanical
engineering for
wood products and renewable energy for a
few generations now
and about 15 years ago
after spending something like 25 years
working with
renewable energy projects everything
from improved cooking stoves to
very large biomass boilers
was about the time that biochar was
rediscovered
and we always have a certain amount of
the
charcoal as a co-product or byproduct of
combustion gasification pyrolysis
processes
and when i learned that the that biochar
could be used to
manage nutrients from manures and that
sort of thing i got
got interested in the use of biochar
production of biochar as a co-product of
biomass energy and the use of biochar
for
improving soils and and managing uh
managing nutrients and i uh
i worked with my father for about 25
years and and i've been
uh on my own for about 20 years and
uh at my office is here
again in in portland and my role with
the u.s biochar initiative
we created the u.s biochar initiative in
and i've been the executive director of
the organization for the last five or
six years we're all volunteers
trying to create biochar as a
as a business and as a productive
enterprise
that's great so let's uh let's go back a
little bit
and just cover the basics for folks who
aren't as familiar with biochar
you know a lot of people when they talk
about biochar they think of
the amazon basin and put maybe like
terra preda
but that's obviously a very different
product than what we're producing with
biochar but there is some relationship
there can you
maybe touch on that a little bit well we
can start with tara prata i led a
group uh from the international biochar
initiative
uh we we had a conference in brazil in
2010 in rio
de janeiro and we went up to the amazon
where ambrapa the brazilian research
organization
agricultural research research
organization had
dug pits for us in the soils that were
both terraprita and what they call terra
mulatta
and i wound up being the interpreter for
the trip uh having lived in brazil and
speak portuguese and so on
and it was interesting to me to discover
uh the
the along the banks of the amazon
growing up we were told that
the amazon had this rich soil the
amazons has
has rich tropical life and
that drops nutrients down to the soil
but the soils are actually very poor
clay soils and as it happens
uh along the banks of the amazon where
the natives lived
over the last three or four thousand
years
they would grow their crops around their
around their dwellings and then they
would burn that crop residue
um both wood and grasses and so on
and leave a charcoal residue and there's
some debate as to whether they need the
charcoal intentionally or not
but that then would combine with
nutrients in the form
of their kitchen waste and sewage
and compost together and become a
combined with the clay soil and become a
a rich charcoal rich
carbon rich compound and the carbon
would capture the nutrients from the uh
from the vegetation and so that it
wouldn't leach down and just into the
group that would stay there and the
natives were cropping
annually uh every year on the same soil
without going into the slash and burn
into the jungle
and so when the spanish and portuguese
arrived they found the natives is
with a fairly uh rich native culture and
civilization
so that's where a lot of the stories
came from the uh the stories of
the amazon women and the and the men
covered in gold and
these kinds of things the
spanish and portuguese priests and
explorers found
that basically these natives had a a
good renewable regenerative agriculture
and a strip not more than about a
hundred yards wide on either side of the
amazon but if you follow
all the way up the main trunk of the
amazon main river and then it splits
into two different rivers
and you add all those soils together
there's an area the size of france that
was
enriched with this charcoal enriched
soil and so if we look at at biochar
what biochar
is is charcoal that is made instead of
charcoal that's made for
cooking the cooking charcoal typically
contains
tars and oils to help ignite the
charcoal
the biochar is you cook it long enough
so that you
have baked out the tars and oils and so
you have this nice honeycomb
kind of structure and so it has physical
properties that are very similar to
some of the soil amendments like
vermiculite and perlite
and it has chemical properties and it
will have surface area that will
absorb both absorb and adsorb
chemicals and nutrients potassium and so
on many of the soluble nutrients that
that are available from
not only from manures but plants and so
on
and then scientists are now discovering
that it also has
electrochemical properties which assist
in the with the metabolism for example
that
feed to animals uh it actually helps the
metabolism and the rumen improves the
efficiency of feed conversion
uh helps keep animals healthy and so on
and so you have these
these physical chemical and biological
uh
attributes of the biochar the biochars
themselves are good
habitats for microorganisms and so
biochars have sometimes been described
as
geo batteries and that they can hang on
to
chemicals and nutrients they can help
cycle carbon from photosynthesis
through the soil solution and uh
and thereby help both with not only with
carbon cycle but also with the nutrient
cycle and help to feed the
microorganisms that are so important
so the difference really between the
biochar and the terra freita is that
terra preta was the full full package
of a basically a composted
biochar mineral complex the biochar plus
clay plus
uh the nutrients and the biochar
is the building block it's just
basically the the charcoal but it's
charcoal
for use in the soil and the term biochar
was coined
by our friend the late dr peter reed
from new zealand
uh who felt that we should use a term
of charcoal intended for use in the soil
rather than charcoal intended for use
as a fuel
well that's great i wasn't aware of that
benefit with
the rumen with livestock that's really
interesting
um i would i would be curious the same
yeah the same electrochemical properties
also reduce the amount of energy
that it takes to transfer nutrients to
plant roots
and so it's also partly what's
responsible for the efficient
as you well know uh wherever we use
biochar
um it in the root zone and the
rhizosphere
we get this really generous rick growth
a very active
root growth and so now it's being used
for example
as backfill and planting urban trees and
landscaping because
early on it helps the tree establish
really vigorous root structures and it
turns out that part of the mechanism
is that by facilitating the transfer of
nutrients to the
root hairs with the tree roots it
helps to encourage that root growth
so how do we make biochar ranging
from you know a commercial operation
down to someone who just wanted to try
experimenting with home i mean you
touched on the fact that we don't want
to be using
charcoal necessarily and that there is a
difference there
can you can you touch on how it's how
it's made in the importance of
you know the pyrolysis process
well let's start with uh with where i
started
and that is with with wood with either
wood or grasses
you start with biomass and the biomass
contains about 50 percent carbon
in its structure and as you
heat the biomass that solid converts to
gas about 80 percent of the solid
converts to a gas and about 20 percent
of the solid
uh converts to charcoal and
so when you're burning wood for example
as you can see in your fireplace what
you can see the little uh gas coming out
of the fire log
that accounts for about 80 percent of
the mass of that car log converts to a
gas and then it burns as a gas
whereas about 20 percent burns as
charcoal and you can see in the glowing
coals
actually the glow in the coals is
actually
the those are more tars and volatiles
that are just simply burning on the
surface of the charcoal but the charcoal
will burn
in direct contact with air the charcoal
doesn't need to convert to a gas to burn
it can it can burn and direct at the
right temperature it can burn in direct
contact with air
and uh by burning it's basically
oxidizing it's the oxygen
reacting with the carbon and creating
co2
so in order to make charcoal we need to
heat the biomass
and you can heat it in different ways
you can heat it through what's called
pyrolysis where you heat it
in the absence of air you don't you're
not adding any air
and sometimes this is done by putting
biomass into a canister and then putting
the canister into a fire and then
providing the heat from the outside
and you're doing the same thing you need
a place to to
vent that canister because the solid
will convert to a gas and the gas will
come out and
when you ignite that gas you see that
it's a it's a it's a
combustible gas you've converted the
solid to a form that can burn the next
step is called gasification
and in that case you're using a third
ear that you would ordinarily use to
completely burn
the solid and you can think of it as
burning about a third of the
uh a third of the wood to convert the
rest of the wood to gas
so in that case uh in the case of
pyrolysis
your char yield is going to be in the 20
to 30 percent range
of the of the dry weight of the wood you
start with in the case of gasification
uh the yield typically is in the 15
range
because some of that some of the air
reacts
that you've introduced reacts directly
with that charcoal converts it to co2
and so it reduces the amount of
charcoal yield and the rest converts to
gas which
hopefully you use and recover in some
way to
generate heat or power and the third
mechanism
is simply through combustion or
ordinarily burning
wood you always have charcoal embers
left over or in a a boiler
typically you'll have fine charcoal
particles that will carry out of the
boiler with the
combustion gases and those can be
separated
in the gas cleaning device and recovered
and used
as biochar so in each one of those cases
you want the material to get to a
temperature that's in the
in the centigrade range in the 300 to
350 to 400 to 600 degree
centigrade range for uh most jars you
get high temperature charge that are
above 600 degrees centigrade
to put that in perspective in terms of
fahrenheit
typically the gasification range where
you add a little bit of air gets you
into the 12 to 1400 degree fahrenheit
range combustion will get into the 15 to
1800 degree
temperature range and pyrolysis
you hold down to the 800 to 1000 degree
range
um to provide each of those
products now the simplest way to make
biochar is in what's called a pit kiln
in which you simply dig a
pit a conical pit or a sleep-sided pet
and
put the biomass in in malawi for example
we have
smallholders who farm small plots of
land and in that case they dig a small
pet
and take their corn stover from their
corn stove or their corn or maize
harvest and put it in the pit
and the pit is as steep sides
and by lighting the
lighting the material from the top
it tends to it's what we call a top lit
updraft
the heat from radiant heat from burning
material on the top tends to heat the
material that's below it in the pit
and the pit contains the keeps the
oxygen from
getting to the material and so the
material is sitting there bathing in a
pool of
so-called pyrolysis gases the gases that
evolved from
heating the material and that tends to
to promote
charcoal production and so they wind up
making a charcoal
and they make it that it winds up being
made at a low enough temperature so that
a lot of the nutrients in the corn
stover aren't cooked off
and so they take that they eventually
cover the pit
to cool off the char and take the char
and
combine it with a nutrient source
typically manure
at planting and they plant their corn
crop and
so that's one way of of making in a pit
kiln you're basically
using the radiant heat from the gaseous
combustion to
heat the solid convert the solid to char
and gas
and then you use the char beneficially
in the in the soil another way of making
biochar is in a
in a gasifier where you use add a little
bit of air
to burn some of the gas to provide heat
to
char or carbonize the fuel again in
malawi what they do is
is use a gasifier to gasify
the corn cobs and they take that char
and feed it to their chickens and cows
and
and wind up with healthy animals with
less disease and
increase their milk production a lot of
those kinds of benefits
unfortunately in the united united
states we it's illegal to feed
charcoal or biochar of any kind to
animals
we're trying to change that we have some
feeding trials going on in nebraska to
try to change that
but at any rate makes a good feed makes
a good soil amendment in an industrial
case you basically use a a reactor which
is
sometimes called a retort typically it's
an auger
and you heat the outside of the auger to
heat the material you run the material
in the auger
takes about 40 minutes to
heat the material convert the the solids
to
to gas and you burn the off gas often to
dry the material that you're putting
into the auger
and then there are larger kilns that are
rotating drums
and you feed the material into a
rotating drum that looks like a
cement mixer long kiln and you use a
either the off gas from pyrolysis or you
you use an auxiliary gas
and you heat the drum you either heat
the drum from the outside or you
burn the gas and and put the gas through
the inside of the drum
and that again heats the material
converts the solid to a gas and you wind
up with a char product and the yields in
these different processes
can be something in the order of 20 to
30 percent
of what you start with you wind up with
as
char and that char contains about 50 of
the energy content that you started with
with the biomass
so you've converted uh
again about 80 of the mass and about 50
percent of the energy into a gas
so it's important to be able to recover
that gas and use it
to make steam
you can generate power except that's
expensive but if you can use the steam
to
heat water for processed water or or
our nurse team for processing the
material in china for example they
provide an incentive to the farmers to
bring their corn stove and their wheat
straw to a fertilizer plant
the fertilizer plant converts that
stover to
char by using the same industrial
process of pyrolysis and a rotating drum
and then they will use the off gas to
heat the stover to
create the biochar and at the same time
they'll use some of the off gas to make
steam and that steam then they'll use
to treat the char to activate it as it's
called which will
improve the properties of the char they
add
fertilizer components to the char and
then they granulate it and they sell a
granulated biochar based fertilizer back
to
the farmer and they're producing about
500 000 tons per year now and they
expect to get to
3 million tons before long uh so
they're making a very active industrial
use of biochar in china
by contrast here in the united states
we're producing somewhere in the 50
to 70 000 tons a year we have about
150 biochar producers and suppliers in
the united states
and it's slowly growing as people are
discovering
the many uses for char uh and and
developing markets
and understanding more importantly the
uh
the needs of their of their customers
so you mentioned a few different methods
for making biochar
how does the quality of the final
product
vary from a soil health
perspective when you when you talk about
gasification versus
pyrolysis for example well if you
control the
if you control the factors of production
if you control temperature and time
then you typically can make a similar
quality of biochar
uh regardless of the process the
gasifier chars tend to be
slightly higher temperature jars they're
because they're partially oxidized
you've
used a little air in the process and so
they tend to burn off more of the
the tars they're very clean clean jars
the
wood chars from gasification and
combustion work very well
for filtration where you're trying to
capture
heavy metals from storm water
they have good surface properties
pyrolysis jars can if you cook them long
enough
have very similar properties but then
they also have different
uh some different surface
characteristics what are called
functional groups the functional groups
have different abilities to attract
certain
nutrients but in general most chars
many chars are very similar for
most common uses so if you're using the
chars in the soil if you're using char
as an additive to organics and
co-composting composting them together
uh that's a very popular and very
effective use
you use about five or ten percent
biochar by weight or ten to twenty
percent by volume
together with organics and you wind up
with a biochar based compost
in that case you can actually
accommodate a wide variety of
qualities of high temperature and low
temperature
one of the challenges we've had
commercially is that
many of the people who've been producing
biochars
have not necessarily had
industrial experience and they produce
an inconsistent quality of char so it's
not necessarily the fact that their char
is good or bad
it's just simply that different batches
of char maybe
have different qualities and so the
buyers complain about truckloads
having different different qualities
if they're going to use the char in a in
a recipe and a soil amendment recipe
they want to have
at least a consistent product that they
can depend on
as they add char as a component to
two other materials for a soil amendment
for example
but there's there's a lot of what we
call a buffering capacity in char and
that
there's a certain amount of leeway in
quality
and you can make some pretty good
quality chars people look at the
at the kilns the the pit kiln in its
metal form
took the form of what was called a
contiki kiln generally we're calling
those flame
cap kilns because that flame that burns
above the pit
is providing the heat that's doing the
carbonization
and that style of making
biochar makes actually a very good
quality biochar it's a slightly oxidized
gasification char
and but those units the small portable
units are more
place-based applications where you're
you're making char from uh orchard
prunings or
vineyard prunings that sort of thing for
use actually right there in the orchard
and
in the vineyard you're not gonna take
the material very far
and you you move the uh metal carbonizer
or kiln around
where biochars are made in a stationary
application
about the size of today's modern
charcoal plant
then you're looking at chars that are
being shipped
pretty good distances to specific
applications and in those cases they use
more sophisticated processing
and very carefully control chart quality
for specific uses and often they'll
they'll make what we've been calling
designer chars or
chars that are made for specific
applications
and what's different about those jars
typically is that
they're carefully controlled for their
size and other characteristics so if
they're
meant to absorb mercury and metals for
example in filtration applications or
remediating soils
you might tilt the process a little bit
if you've got good
control over it to have the chars have
slightly different
qualities there's some sort of basic
tests for chart quality and that is
if you you want it to be basically clean
and porous and so if you take the jar
and crush it in your hands
you hope that it's it's friable that it
crushes
um if you taste the jar you want the
or smell it you don't want to smell a
lot of
oily tarry products and we want it to
smell
pretty clean and if you if you take the
char and you
and you put your hands in it you want to
be able to wash that char off with water
instead of needing soap to wash it off
and that's an indication that it doesn't
have any
tars and oils in the char and that it's
pretty clean uh so those are
those are the kind of feel and
and and taste uh and and wash tests
that we use just to understand that
you've got
a char that's been cooked long enough at
an adequate temperature so that it's not
carrying a lot of tars and oils the tars
and oils can be recovered
uh in a contained device whether you're
heating char in a 50 gallon drum or
whether you're putting it through an
industrial process
you can condense uh three different
densities of liquids
those gases that are made by heating the
char
contain some light we call it wood
vinegar or pyro-igneous acids
and those are used sometimes as growth
stimulants
i understand that you can pay six
dollars for a liter of
wood vinegar in japan
use it as a foliar spray and it turns
out that that
one of the active ingredients in the
foliar spray are actually
nano carbons they're very very small
size carbon particles that can penetrate
the stomata of the leaf
directly kind of main lining biochar if
you will
and that within the wood vinegars there
are what they call signaling compounds
or the smoke smelling smoke-like
compounds that
[Music]
actually act as as as growth stimulants
so the wood vinegar can be used as a
grow stimulant it can be used
straight as a the tars for example which
are heavier
can also be condensed and those can be
used as a preservative
so in brazil for example they will take
the mix of wood tars and vinegars
they'll take the tar and they'll dilute
it 200 to 1 for use and
to as a wood preservative to protect
against termites and they'll use it 2
thousand to one
uh with water to use as a growth
stimulant
but those those products are not widely
used
here in the united states we import some
wood vinegar
products from china i think there's only
about one producer that
has industrial uses for wood vinegar
here here in the united states but
as we look down the road we look to see
more of those products being refined and
developed and sold here in the united
states
yeah now tom you'd mentioned um we
touched on a lot of stuff there uh
one thing though that i wanted to go
back to was how you evaluate
uh a charcoal or biochar
and how how would a consumer
be able to you know tell the difference
between these different types of burnt
products whether it be
soot or ash or charcoal
can you can you touch on that a little
bit more yeah there's a
there's actually a uh um
the there there are labeling uh rules
about biochars um about
four or five years ago the american
association of plant food control
officials which is an association of
agricultural departments from each state
around the
country and in canada and mexico
all get together and they decide
what constitutes a label for a product
and they decided that biochar
to call something biochar on a label it
had to have at least 60 percent carbon
and so if you buy a product on a shelf
a soil amendment for example that has
biochar in it or if you buy a straight
biochar
it it it should have 60 percent or more
carbon in the biochar so that it would
have more carbon and less ash
the ash are you know natural ash
ingredients calcium
uh potassium other components that when
you
cook down the uh cook down the biomass
to
to biochar that ash will increase
as a proportion of the total because you
you've reduced the amount of
cellulose well some of the chars will
have a high ash component so if you make
biochar
from the straws or agricultural residues
they start out with a higher ash content
so they're going to wind up with less
than 60 percent
uh carbon but that doesn't mean they're
bad biochars it just means they have a
different balance of ash
to carbon and so you need to understand
if a char is coming from an agricultural
residue and it doesn't
isn't labeled biochar then typically
it'll have a slightly higher ash lower
carbon
component so then you use it sort of
proportionally you use it
maybe in a slightly different way than
then you would use a wood ash
it kind of depends on what you want to
do with the biochar if you want
biochar to change the texture of a soil
or a growing mix
then any kind of a soil additive whether
it's biochar or whether it's a mineral
like a vermiculite or perlite
you really need to add about 25 to a
soil mix before you really see a change
in texture
but if you want it to be a
an aid to water holding capacity
that sort of thing then you may only
need to add
five percent or ten percent uh biochar
to
uh to a compost or two a soil amendment
so it really depends uh in terms of
quality it depends on how you're going
to use the chars there are also
chars that are made from manures and
those only have 10 to 20 percent
biochar or 20 10 to 20 percent carbon
but they have lots and lots of other
beneficial
nutrients and
typically not as much nitrogen because
nitrogen is cooked off in the process
but you'll have
potassium and phosphorus and calcium and
a lot of other
minerals in the mix so
in terms of of biochar quality
if you're buying it in a bag it often if
it says biochar then it'll
have 60 carbon uh some
biochar producers claim that they will
have eighty percent carbon
um that's a very high carbon typically
made from a
from a wood product uh if
if you're buying a bulk char and you can
do that sort of c
and field test and uh and
and it passes that sort of wash your
hands and feel it and taste it test
uh it's gonna be a pretty good quality
char that's gonna be in that 60
or better uh uh char range
so you know as a consumer i think what
you do like any other
uh for a soil application any other
growing media
uh you you try it out and and you make
sure that you're feeding the uh
the plants sufficiently with enough
nitrogen one of the things to be aware
of
is that if you add jar to a growing mix
the char will actually preferentially um
absorb initially absorb uh
nutrients like nitrogen and so on and so
if your plants go
yellow and you wind up being a little
chlorotic
if you need to add a little extra
fertilizer whether it be an organic
fertilizer
a feather meal or a nitrogen
source of some kind to
for the biochar to absorb and not take
it away from the plant
and then and that's just really with the
initial application after that it
doesn't you haven't lost that nutrient
it just simply resides in the char
ultimately the organisms will make that
nutrient available to the plant but
initially you want to be able to
counteract or offset the
nutrient demand of the char itself it
just simply will
take up a certain amount of nutrient
i kind of use the analogy of feeding
straw to a beef cow for example it takes
about four percent nitrogen just for the
to supply enough nitrogen for the animal
to be able to metabolize the straw
and with char it takes a certain amount
of of nutrient just simply to
satisfy the appetite of the char if you
will
and uh and so it won't take it away from
the plant
but yeah the quality issue is a
challenge we really as an as an
organization as a
as a an industry we need to
find ways of identifying grades of
biochar
suitable for particular applications and
that's that's really the challenges
there are many different qualities of
char that can be used in different ways
but it's matching the quality of the
chart of the application is really the
key
yeah i do want to highlight that for
people because i think it is important
if you're purchasing biochar
that you you do your homework and know
what you're buying
a good biochar company should be able to
provide you with testing and information
about the product that they're producing
and it should be consistent
i've seen this problem in some of you
know the industries that i'm more
involved in in terms of
certain people you know putting out
product at lower cost that may not be of
the same quality and so it's really
important to
i think do your due diligence especially
with an industry like this that's sort
of an emerging technology
as people are still learning about it
well the other thing too
is simply really has less to do with the
biochar than it does
to do with the fact that it is a new
industry
you get people who have great ideas
about biochar they pro
over promote the product and then they
deliver a product that doesn't
doesn't help they don't show the
customer how to use the product
appropriately and so things fail and
then everybody
uh has a bad idea about biochar in
general
but it you know it typically takes three
to five years to start a business and it
takes three to five years for people to
get
used to
generate developing a product that that
is
that is useful and matching the product
of the customer and
and so i can always tell when a biochar
producer calls i can typically tell
whether that producer is has gotten to
the point where they really understand
the needs of the uh
of the customer yeah i mean we've been
using
biochar now oh boy
i want to say close to a decade my
father
you know was got really as you already
know i'm just sharing this for listeners
got really involved with the contiki
kiln
we have a contiki kiln that we use
fairly regularly
to burn material and then
we've been working with black owl
biochar
as the product source for us and our
soils and we've seen wonderful results
i've seen on average you know across a
variety of different growers you know
somewhere around the range of like eight
to ten percent better
plant growth and yield with the addition
of biochar
uh in the in the mix
well and one of the one of the nice
things about the black owl biochar is
that
they the producer is a
a user producer and that she was growing
organic vegetables when she discovered
biochar and growing peonies
and it was a result of her doing some
testing of adding biochar 2
to her favorite growing mix with peonies
that
got her excited about biochar because
she saw the the positive benefits and
then got into the business of
producing it so her criteria for biochar
quality
comes from the point of view of of a
consumer
you know a user and similarly
other companies that have incorporated
biochar into their product
like kellogg garden for example in
california they have about a thousand
outlets
outlets they're a pretty good sized
company that's been in business since
since the 1930s they spent about four or
five years
experimenting with biochar before they
decided to
incorporate biochar into a product with
their label on it because they
needed to to protect the integrity of as
well of their label
and uh they've been very happy with the
with the products they make they make a
couple of biochar amended products
uh there are other some organic products
one called sustain that has taken their
basic organic
fertilizer and added biochar to it and
their customers are very happy so
again the there are some quality
producers
and at the other end of the spectrum
there are people that
put together what they think is a
quality material that may have worked
with the
with in their own soils in their own
garden but when they put it out and sell
it to the general public
they may or may not be very good about
explaining how it should be used and
in what soils and circumstances
so can you talk a little bit and talk
about why biochar is so important from
an environmental perspective i mean when
i hear the idea of burning wood
for the sake of improving my soil on the
surface that sounds like a really
negative
environmental experience can you talk
about why
it's important and beneficial
well the carbon in making biochar you're
converting the carbon
uh that has been developed through
pulled out of the atmosphere through
photosynthesis
and you're converting it to a form that
can be as they say recalcitrant it'll
stay in the soil for a long time so
you're really
you're really removing carbon from the
atmosphere and you're
putting it into a form where you can put
it in the soil and it will stay on the
soil and not only that
the the biochar will will
catalyze the uh
the whole biological process so i always
like to say that the magic of biochar is
biology you're really
stimulating the biology by providing by
improving
the ability of the plants so on to
uh to photosynthesize
uh carbon and remove it from the
atmosphere and cycle it through the
through the soil and at the same time
you're taking a renewable source of
energy
and you're you're converting it either
to energy or to chemicals
and there's a great deal of research
there are
about 3 000 peer-reviewed
academic papers a year on uh
the use of biochar in different
applications and about half of those are
devoted to
uh improving the conversion processes of
making biochar
and recovering more and more carbon so
typically in
in a contiki kiln which really is an
engineered pit kiln
you're recovering about 50 to 60 of the
carbon
that it was in the plant to start with
and what we're finding now
is is ways to recover even more of that
carbon and put it into forms
that are recalcitrant that won't break
down for thousands of years
and that was one of the exciting things
to soil scientists a hundred years ago
when they discovered the
tariff rate in the amazon and also the
biochar that's been used
in man-made or anthropogenic soils
and seven or eight hundred locations
around the world
and that is here you could put carbon
into a form that was going to last in
the soil for
literally thousands of years so it's
carbon removal
we've seen the first sale of carbon
credits for using biochar
from a producer here in the united
states selling on a in the european
market
volunteer market and we see other
methodologies and other markets evolving
for trading
biochar on the carbon market and that's
because it's got
a value of removing carbon from the
atmosphere so there's
that um that carbon side
and then in addition to that there's the
biological side and as evidence of
the the the nexus of the two of the
carbon and the biology
where they've been doing trials where
they've been looking at
the degree to which carbon is removed
from the atmosphere where they've used
biochar
over a 10-year period they find that the
far more
carbon is actually accumulated in the
soil
than just the amount that accounts for
the biochar
so there's typically 10 percent or more
increase
in carbon sequestration from having used
biochar
to stimulate the the
biology and and truly regenerative
agriculture
so we get uh we get some real benefits
the challenge with biochar part of the
challenge with biochar today is simply
the cost of making it when you're making
it in a
uh in the smallholder situation in
thousands of smallholders in asia and
africa
and south america have been using
biochar
as a soil amendment and there they make
it in very
simple kilns and they
use their own labor so they don't have a
lot of capital invested
and they can benefit from its uh
its attributes pretty directly in
developed countries in europe the united
states it's
growing more slowly as a as a material
simply because
we do things in an industrial process
that requires labor
and more expensive inputs in terms of
electricity and so on
and so the biochar becomes fairly
expensive so
we're looking forward to those carbon
markets helping to offset the cost of
biochar so it can be less expensive to
our agriculture and on the carbon side
we're also
seeing products that are incorporating
biochar
into building materials where it will
also last for a very long period of time
so
it's being incorporated into cement and
asphalt being
incorporated into plastics a number of
different
combinations that liquid portion
is being polymerized into
you might call up natural plastic like
materials
which will last for a very long time so
we get this carbon benefit as well as
getting this agronomic benefit
and the biology oh that's great i didn't
even
know about the building materials side
either that's really interesting
i've been focused on the agriculture
uses
a couple other things i want to touch on
that that you you kind of uh
you kind of danced around too was this
idea that it'll help fight global
warming
it's improving our soil fertility which
you talked about
and then the thing that my my father was
most interested in is this idea of
reducing agricultural waste and also
forestry waste where we could take the
you know
when when the logging occurs they can
come back in and grab some of that i
believe it's just
called slash material and burn that to
reduce
the risk of forest fires while also
sequestering the carbon that can then be
applied back onto those
lands or potentially sold as a byproduct
to you know an agricultural source
yeah our principal supporter for the u.s
biochar initiative is actually the u.s
forest service they're quite interested
as you know the wildfire hazard is quite
large
we had 57 000 wildfires last year in the
united states
covering 10.3 million acres uh the year
before that we had about 43
000 fires covering about four and a half
million acres and i think the year
before
that we had about uh in the 50
000 fires again covering about eight and
a half million acres and
according to the insurance folks there
are four million homes that are
uh in uh in danger from
from wildfires and of course it varies
from state to state
uh but pretty much across the country
there there are uh
serious problems with wildfire and so
the
from the forest residues and so it's the
buildup of not only the
forest residues that are left from
logging but also simply the buildup of
poorly managed
forests we have this great
collection of forest fuels which causes
the
the wildfires so the forest service has
been interested in the conversion of
these lower value
materials which can't be converted into
solid wood products for building and so
on
into into biochar and biochar for use in
applications to improve
forest health so biochar is a great
filtration media
for cleaning up waterways and in our
natural forests we have about three
hundred thousand
abandoned farm uh mine lands that are
leaching chemicals into waterways
and by taking some of these forest
residues
converting them to biochar we can
actually filter
and permanently tie up
those minerals that cause problems
there's
restoration work going on in places like
colorado and so on that have
demonstrated this
and here in oregon in southern oregon at
a nickel mine
various other mines so we're working
with a forest service looking at
at locations where biochars can be used
for
improving rangeland for example they
found in the rockies they
found that by adding biochar to grazing
land they can
improve and increase the water retention
in grazing land so they can actually get
an additional month of grazing
by adding biochar to the to the grazing
land in the forest
we also have of course the crop residues
here in oregon we export about 700 000
tons
of our straw from our grass seed harvest
to
japan and korea and taiwan for as a feed
supplement as a dairy feed supplement
but that's more difficult with straw
residues like in eastern washington
where you have wheat straw that has a
different texture and application we
find we've finally seen in
eastern washington now there's a paper
mill
that will be that's making paper from
wheat straw
there hasn't been a market for that for
the last 30 years 40 years ago we were
we did have paper mills that were making
paper from straw but we've been
importing wood from around the globe
at a very low cost and so that hasn't
been an option well there are also crop
residues and processing residues like
manures
anaerobic digestion the digestate from
anaerobic digestion that can be
converted to
to biochars and so
the combination if you look at the u.s
we have supposedly according to the
department of energy about a billion
tons
of both residues and potential energy
crops of various kinds it could be
converted to
fuel and other chemical products and
and byproducts and biochar can be a
co-product of some of that processing so
potentially we could make biochar as a
co-product there's a plant in oregon
that we'll be making in lakeview that
will be making jet fuel from uh
wood and one of the co-products will be
will be biochar so here we can
help work on our improve the increased
renewable
energy at the same time find a home for
the
some of these residues and some of the
parts of the
residues that can't otherwise be used uh
heavily barky residues or some of the
crop residues
and and manures and waste and so on by
converting them to
uh to energy and biochar
that's that's really interesting
i look forward to following up with you
about uh about this jet fuel option and
the
biochar that's coming out of that that's
wonderful to hear about more renewable
energy sources um just to uh
tie everything back together though i
wanted to ask you so
we talked about you know from a user
perspective
uh growing plants and talk in regards to
soil health and that use for biochar
if we start you know for example in our
soils
when i talk about uh making soilless
media
essentially we're at five to eight
percent of by volume
of our total mix you mentioned people
using biochars up to 25
and and considering it more as a portion
of your aeration
essentially in your soil so using it to
control you know gas exchange air
exchange
there are some properties of biochar
that i think we should touch on which is
the fact like you mentioned it has a
very high cation exchange capacity
it tends to be alkaline which raises
your ph
how are these things sort of accounted
for
on a practical level when combined into
a soil
well to start with most of the biochars
are analyzed the system of analysis was
developed by the international biochar
initiative and there are certain
laboratories like
control laboratories in california that
follow the international biochar
initiative
protocols we're identifying other
laboratories around the country that
are capable of analyzing biochars
and so you do you do get numbers or
reference numbers you can use
on alkalinity on cat ion exchange
capacity we have a tool on the
international biochar initiative website
where you can plug in the properties of
your biochar and it will suggest
uses is as a soil additive or as a
growing media looks at particle size
all the different characteristics the
as as part of a grow as far as growing
media is concerned for example in one
case
we looked at biochar as a co-product
from gasification for use
in a nursery growing tree seedlings and
the nursery was using
typical what used to be called the
cornell mix which was
50 percent bark because bark is cheap 25
vermiculite and 25 percent peat
and so we started substituting we did
some
tests substituting different levels of
biochar from the gasifier
uh substituting the biochar for the
vermiculite looking primarily
at at replacing the
[Music]
sort of physical properties of
vermiculite with
biochar and we found that we could add
up to 25
biochar until we ran into the situation
where
uh because of the um we instead of using
peat we were using compost as a peat
substitute
the compost happened to be uh alkaline
and so
we ran into an issue with one of the
tree i think it was sugar pine one of
the tree species
one of the fun parts about doing
experiments in a tree industry is you've
got hundreds of thousands of trees to
look at in the
in the greenhouse as you look across and
you can tell whether
a species has a particular problem or
not uh but we were able to
actually go to high rates of
substitution with the biochar
again relying primarily on the physical
characteristics of the biochar
but in that case you've got fertigation
so you're actually supplying
the fertilizer and so on to the tree
seedlings
and you're not depending on you know
other
attributes of the biochar but typically
it's interesting because
five percent keeps coming up again and
again as
sort of the best uh between five and ten
percent
sort of the best rate of application of
biochar
to regardless of whether it's an organic
media or soil
soil mix and uh
that seems to be a a level where you get
the best
benefit that's interesting
yeah now relating to this tree trial you
did did you
see um
did you see other issues associated
with the high rates of biocharge besides
just alkalinity did you have to treat it
for
with some nitrogen prior to adding it in
so it didn't cause plants yellowing and
nitrogen robbing
well again in that case with the
seedlings you've got a
fertilizing fertigation type
situation where you're you're constantly
adjusting and balancing
nutrient levels so we probably did
increase
increased nitrogen initially to
balance the effect of the biochar
especially at those very high rates uh
and in other words the
the high rates to give you an example
there's a composting operation in
missouri that's using a lot of biochar
because the more biochar they use
the more food waste they can take in
well food waste has much higher nitrogen
and higher
nutrients than their typical organics
and the composting process
but what's interesting and they'll
openly talk about this is that the more
biochar they use the more food waste
they can use the food waste has a higher
tipping fee so that helps their
economics
they wind up making a richer compost
that they actually
charge twice as much for compared with
their regular compost
so by using but they wind up with
uh after composting they wind up with uh
they advertise 16 biochar by
volume so that's about eight percent
biochar by weight so you're still back
in that five to ten percent range
and uh that that seems to be sort of a
magic
range and it not only just seems to be a
magic range
it's been very well documented and
tested in multi-year
trials and and research in europe and
and here in the united states
so last question for someone who's
really interested in learning more
passionate about biochar
can you talk a little bit about how
someone might get involved with
the international biocharge initiative
or ibi yeah we have we have two
organizations we have the international
biochar initiative and we
also have the u.s biochar initiative the
international biochar initiative was
created back in 2007
with the idea of developing standards
and practices for the use of biochar
for carbon trading in 2010 we created
the u.s biochar initiative
with the idea of focusing primarily on
the needs for
the use of biochar in north america so
you can go to
biochar hyphen international.org
for the international biochar initiative
or just google international biochar
initiative
or the u.s biochar initiative is biochar
hyphen us.org
for the u.s biochar initiative we have
a youtube channel with about 60 videos
that we put together last december
and what we call the national biochar
week we've held about
seven or seven conferences and one
virtual conference
we have a monthly newsletter the u.s
biochar initiative does
you can sign up for the newsletter on
our on our website
we're basically a volunteer organization
uh we rely on
donations and grants from forest service
and other sources
for promoting the use of of biochar we
work very closely with the international
biochar initiative and so we
we actually uh work in an
international community if you will a
very active biochar community in
in australia and in europe and china
and in latin america connecting all
these folks i
chaired the international biochar
initiative for about four years and for
the last five years i've shared the
us biochar initiative so uh we're slowly
uh our biggest challenge is educating
folks we also have a biochar discussion
group
at biochar groups dot io
and that's a discussion list that i've
hosted since 2006 we have about a
thousand people online and some very
knowledgeable and experienced people
in biochar and the challenge with those
listservs or discussion lists
is always you have to ask the question
to get an
answer and sometimes you'll get answers
from armchair experts who really don't
know what they're talking about but we
have a pretty high quality of
expertise and exchange on the list that
i'm pretty proud of so
a number of ways bylander by sea of
getting the message
and i certainly welcome people to
to join us at the international biochar
initiative
which is a membership organization and
the us biochar initiative
which is basically uh just an active
community
well that's great i sure appreciate your
work in promoting this
technology and renewable uh resource
for people and i'll be sure to put those
links on the podcast page as well for
people who are listening
and uh i look forward to staying in
touch and hearing
what the future holds for biochar
well thank you we certainly enjoy
your participation and promotion and
and so on of biochar and and we think
that everybody can benefit
so oh absolutely i absolutely i love
using it in our soils i see such a
difference
uh in the quality of the
vegetables and other you know other
plants that we grow in it so
i yeah i can't say enough good things
about biochar
so i i don't i don't think we'll ever
stop using it it's just it's so great
so yeah well thanks again i will
stay in touch and appreciate your time
today great thank you very much
all right bye tom
[Music]
that was tom miles and you were
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast
don't forget to check out the podcast
page at www.kisorganics.com
just click on the learn tab then podcast
and by the way we carry the black owl
biochar from biochar supreme which in my
opinion is the highest quality
most researched and most consistent
commercially available biochar on the
market
we've used it in our soil mixes for
years now and also have it available by
the cubic foot bag or by the yard
thanks for your support and happy
growing