[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host
tadd hussey of kiss organics this is the
podcast where we discuss the cutting
edge of growing from a science-based
perspective
and drawn top experts from around the
industry to share their wisdom and
knowledge
this week's podcast will be a bit
different than my usual topics
as many of you know there's more to
cultivation than just what happens in
our gardens
whether we like it or not taxes and
proper accounting are crucial to keeping
our businesses afloat
i sat down with two cpas betsy moram and
mark waller who have founded an
accounting firm specializing in working
with folks in the cannabis industry
my upcoming podcasts include another
visit with suzanne wainwright evans
also known as the bug lady to talk about
what she has learned and encountered
since last being on the podcast
and i also had a wonderful conversation
with dr abby wick who is an assistant
professor at north dakota state
university
and is an extension soil health
specialist her knowledge of infield soil
health practices and cover crops was
really incredible and i'll be putting
that podcast out here soon too
now on to the show hi mark hi betsy
welcome to the podcast
thanks for having us yeah thanks for
having us absolutely
now uh i heard about you guys because
i heard mark talking on clubhouse about
a particular form
that we'll talk about here in a little
bit
but accounting is something that is is
not
not you know something that we normally
talk about when we're talking about
cultivation but i wanted to cover this
because i think it's something that we
all have to be aware of it's just the
reality of growing in a legal market
and uh so i wanted to have you guys on
to talk a little bit about
what you do and how uh you know
accounting fits in um and the finances
fit in
from uh for the cannabis industry can
you guys give me a little bit of a
background and talk a little bit about
that
sure yeah i'll start so so my name is
mark waller i am
a cpa i co-founded
morom and waller cpas with betsy moram
who's with us
here today obviously and uh our our
biggest thing that we do is really
provide
world-class accounting services for
cannabis businesses from month end
annual compliance all the way down to
your your
audits that you have to think about and
we really try to use kind of a data
driven tech forward approach so one of
the things that's
unique about cannabis with regard to
other
businesses is that cannabis
businesses don't have as many tools in
the toolbox
that most businesses do they're very
stringent on what they're even allowed
to do at all
with banking there is there are many
regulations for
banks that say you can't work with
cannabis due to it being a federally
illegal substance on on schedule one
of the the federal government's schedule
of
of drugs and because of that there
are there are some banks that do work
with with cannabis businesses for sure
but there are not very many
and even the ones that do work with
cannabis businesses
are fairly well regulated so
it's almost uh it's it's almost like uh
searching for something that you aren't
quite sure to find
that normally any business can go
down to the corner and and find a bank
and and most banks are happy to pick up
new businesses it's
it's much trickier for for cannabis
businesses so
we we really try to be kind of a partner
with cannabis businesses knowing
knowing what we know about partnering
with other banks
uh making sure that they have banking
services
and then providing end-to-end accounting
services so that
uh all of the different things that
become very complex especially for
cannabis growers we try to we try to cut
down that
that red tape as much as possible
thank you today yeah betsy do you need a
little bit of your quick background here
and then we'll dive in with some i've
got some questions for you guys
yeah absolutely um my name is betsy
moram and i'm a cpa as well
co-founder of morgan waller cpas um i
got into
i became interested in the cannabis
space a couple years ago
but but didn't really get into the
accounting side of things
until last year but i have been
providing
accounting services for small businesses
since about
2014. so um i think that that experience
of working with startups and small
businesses from the ground up
has really helped me with
cannabis clients because a lot of these
clients
are starting from from ground zero
so um yeah i'm really excited to be
joining forces with mark and to be
providing world-class services to
cannabis clients across the u.s
great well i guess uh you know for me
i guess my first question would be um
what are some of the things as someone
who is setting up a facility
or a grow a legal grow in a state what
are some of the things that you guys are
seeing
as potential pitfalls or roadblocks that
people should be aware of
though i think right away it's the
challenge of just finding a bank
is it hits you right in the face when
you when you first start
um we we work with some some startup
farms
and uh you know some of them are are
lucky enough to to come to us
with uh a banking relationship in
existence and uh
some of our other clients are coming to
us and saying you know we
have a license we're ready to start we
bought some land but we don't have a
banking relationship yet
and cannabis are not and not having a
banking relationship
really puts you at a disadvantage right
away for account
for accounting because once once if you
don't have a banking relationship
and uh you're tracking things either
through
your individual uh your individual
accounts sometimes maybe you have cash
that you're working
with but it makes just the day-to-day
record keeping
much hairier than it really needs to be
which is unfortunate because so many of
our clients that we work with
want to do the right thing they want to
they want to be
uh you know upfront with their record
keeping they want to keep things really
organized so it really puts them at a
disadvantage
uh you know i've been i've been tracking
federal federal banking bills
and i think i think there's one in the
uh the federal government right now that
has some promise of happening
um but you know there's there's no
guarantee that it's going to happen
this year uh so so for the time being
growers that are starting a new farm
just get faced with
with that reality right away um that's
not even that's not even getting into
some of the other things that
cannabis growers have to think about
like section 280e
um handling cash handling internal
control for cash um irs
audits uh you know banks requesting
information etc
um just getting off the ground is hard
enough
so so mark um along those lines
if you were say a grower coming into the
legal market
and you may have been on the medical
side and working strictly in cash
you know you may or may not have been
paying taxes um
you may or may not have claimed all of
this cash do you have to be able to show
where all the cash
came from before you know when you go to
set up a banking relationship and then
if so
um you know how does that work from an
irs perspective i guess
um you know when establishing a business
primarily from you know a business has
been run by cash for for years
absolutely so so one thing that that
kind of goes unnoticed is that there is
an irs form called form 8300
that any business that is handling large
transactions of cash over ten thousand
dollars is required to fill out a form
8300 every time they have those
transactions so just the administrative
burden
that alone is is huge and so
short of having a strong you know a
banking relationship in place
uh growers really have to think about
compliance right away
and it's not uh many many small
businesses
and are set up the irs i should say is
is geared toward helping small
businesses
get started but for cannabis businesses
they the iras does what they can but but
they are faced with something that's
that's really just kind of a
it's a beast right from the get-go
so i do want to talk a little bit more
about for 8300 but i guess my question
is you know
if let's just say i had a few hundred
thousand dollars in cash and i wanted to
start
a legal cannabis business um how did
from an accounting perspective how does
that happen
or is that more of a legal question um
in terms of
i assume you need to get the money into
a bank and set up a banking relationship
to where you can start accounting for
things
uh so that you have a audit trail uh
that the irs
yeah i mean but yeah i mean if
if there isn't a banking relationship
there yet
it doesn't mean that we can't do our
accounting
um it just means that how we do our
accounting is going to be a little more
complex
um we do have uh within our firm we have
kind of all the work papers that we need
to
to kind of handle any type of situation
so so
certainly there are our businesses that
have started that
that don't have a banking relationship
um they may have an attorney that
they've
hired and are tracking a few different
things from
how they're creating their entity you
know a lot of a lot of
new cultivators who are looking for
investors for example
might be looking to be founded as an
as a c corp which in many respects
is is more beneficial to new businesses
that are looking for investor dollars
um so there may be already some of these
professional relationships
set up um then what our job is as as
their their accountants is to track any
of those
those contributions to the new entity
um any expenditures out of the new
entity you know what we try to do is
kind of tailor
our accounting software in a way so that
you can kind of
track any any owner contributions or any
owner distributions
legal invoices any any of those types of
things that that
come into play especially from from a
startup
free revenue standpoint but it is really
important to capture all of those things
accurately because regardless of what
you have going on
uh once you start that entity the the
clock is ticking on filing
uh your annual reports with the irs and
certainly with the way uh irs
is is going right now there's
there's a federal movement to beef up
the
the budget of the irs to increase
tax compliance and collection on tax
revenue
i would i would be very surprised if
there wasn't also an
increased compliance effort made by the
irs
especially toward cannabis businesses
that
because of section 280e potentially can
earn more tax revenue and that's the
thing i think
this is this is just me opinion
opinionating here but
i do think when we're talking big
picture about section 280e
certainly as as legalization becomes
a bigger topic federally
um 280e is is a big piece that
obviously a lot of people want to go
away but the elephant in the room is
if that goes away where does the revenue
come from
so there there's certainly a delicate
dance
being done i think in the in
the federal government with respect to
that that
it would be great to legalize tomorrow
but there's a lot of things that need to
be sorted out before that happens
okay do you have any recommendations for
a new facility in terms of
potential banks to look into that you've
worked with or
also um accounting software that you
really like
i mean we use quickbooks online right
now but i've used a variety of different
accounting software um on my end what do
you find
most popular for for both of those
options
i can answer that question mark yeah go
for it
uh so i think in general um
those that are looking for banking i i
would i would look to your local credit
unions
um we've with with our clients we've
found that
uh they're able to establish banking
relations
relationships with more credit unions um
and and i in general think that credit
unions are great to work with
secondly in terms of the accounting
software
mark and i um we use
two different mainly two different
systems
quickbooks online tab which you said is
what you use and then
xero and i know some people have run
into issues
with quickbooks some canvas clients have
run
into issues with quickbooks so we are
sort of guiding most of our new clients
in the direction of xero
but you know in general what's great
about both systems is that they're both
web-based so that gives
that gives cultivators um
better access to their books being that
they can just
you know log on to the web at any point
and and take a look around
so if i may uh add to that a little bit
as well
um yeah like betsy like you were saying
the
the web-based tools are really nice and
one thing that
that makes working with businesses
not just cannabis but all businesses
right now really
interesting from an accounting
standpoint is is because all of these
tools are online
and so many of them are built to work
together
and interact with each other and having
a
an online platform for your base
accounting system
like quickbooks or xero gives you a big
advantage going forward because
as more tools especially in the cannabis
industry get developed all of those
tools are being developed in a way that
makes it so that it interacts with your
accounting software
so i would i would advise i'm i'm
personally not
for or against any of any of the
different accounting systems
i think they all have have pluses and
minuses but i would definitely advise
if you're thinking about going online
versus going desktop i would definitely
advise going online
yeah the cloud-based systems are great
i've actually done a lot of research on
this from my company um
because we were using quickbooks desktop
one thing i'll say is switching
financial software is really challenging
from a
comparative perspective year over year
so once you pick one it's really great
to stick with it
um zero is great you know it's it's
actually spelled x-e-r-o for people who
want to look that one up
but for me it didn't work because uh
here in washington state if i ship
something to
eastern washington i have to pay sales
tax based off of that location
not off of my location and uh some of
these
for some reason xero just didn't offer
that functionality at the time
and so we ended up going with quickbooks
online just
strictly for that reason but you know
looking at what other software
integrates in is really important too
because you know i've had to have uh you
know apps and other software allow me to
connect my shopify site with
you know quickbooks desktop and all this
stuff so yeah
that's less of an issue for a cultivator
i think as it is for someone in the
retail side like me but um
yeah definitely look into that the pros
and cons are great and then
um in terms of the credit unions
yeah i've had the same issue that you
guys mentioned
my bank basically you know they told me
not to answer that i work in the
cannabis industry because technically
i'm not growing cannabis
so they were they felt okay about that
but if you say yes
you do which you have to legally if you
are growing um
it really limits your ability to to do a
lot of
banking stuff or work with a lot of
banks like i've been denied loans just
because
they you know googled my name i think
and decided that i was
in you know i fell into that into that
category so
right it's unfortunate um
yeah as far as specific banks to work
with um
if a new client comes to us and doesn't
have a banking
relationship established and they're in
another state that
perhaps we're less familiar with we have
contacts
within our network who can offer up
suggestions
of credit unions within that state that
state
that that work with cannabis clients
great
great yeah i think that's wonderful um i
i do want to talk
a little bit more about section 280e
i am looking at the definition for
people who aren't familiar with it
uh it's a section of the irs code that
forbids businesses from deducting
otherwise ordinary business expenses
from gross income
associated with the trafficking of
schedule one or two substances which is
where cannabis falls
can you kind of explain that in uh more
you know more common language as to
exactly what that means for
a cultivator yeah
absolutely so section 280e
your definition that you read is is is
spot on
the thing that makes it tricky for
cannabis growers is really twofold
one is the the record-keeping that's
required
to kind of have your ducks in a row with
respect to
ensuring that you would be able to make
it through an
audit of the irs are very tricky
and and the reason for that is is just
like you said
is there are a number of different
expenses
that for a quote-unquote regular
business
would be able to be deducted your you
know basically kind of anything
outside of the realm of the actual
production of
your product uh rent expense
uh you know utilities
uh you know meals and entertainment
travel
things like that that are a normal
course of business type of expenses
are generally not allowable to be
deducted
for cannabis growers so until until
until the federal law changes
to move cannabis off of schedule one
that is going to be the law of the land
and what that really means
is you're paying more in taxes and
obviously nobody wants to pay more in
taxes but
that being said you run a big risk
by trying to push the envelope too much
with regard to
what types of deductions you take on
your tax return
there have been a number of oh go ahead
oh so just to clarify
you know if you're working with a cpa
that's not aware of this
and say does take these as business
expenses you talked about meals
entertainment
you know some of these other things like
utilities uh
if you get audited you will have to pay
these taxes plus potentially uh
penalties or back taxes
on on this so in the long run
it could end up costing you quite a bit
if you don't claim this up front
is that correct yeah absolutely
absolutely yeah
and especially like i was saying earlier
there
there's definitely going to be an
increased presence
on cannabis as more and more states
become
federally legal and there is just that
kind of this
this this uh unfortunately
not many many cpas will touch cannabis
because of all the reasons that we've
talked about and so there's
a shortage of good cpas that will help
growers navigate through these kind of
tricky
tricky situations so
you know along these lines uh the one
that i see a lot on my end as being a
someone who provides soil and nutrients
and those sorts of things
is some growers that we work with
will give us a resale certificate or
some sort of agricultural exemption
either in the name of the business or in
a shell corporation of the business that
owns
that business is this
okay because it's about 50 50 here
in the state in terms of people who pay
the sales tax that are growers
and those that hand me a certificate and
essentially by giving me this resale
certificate it's passing the buck so if
i get audited
what's going to happen is they're going
to say hey why didn't you collect
you know sales tax from this grower or
this company and i'll say well they gave
me this resale certificate and it kind
of passes the buck
and they'll follow up potentially with
that company and say hey why
you know are you charging the sales tax
on your end does that
work with cannabis is my question
because i know
you know with farmers and other uh
non-cannabis
companies this isn't really an issue but
i don't i don't know with cannabis
yeah that's a really good question i i
would be
really cautious about
not doing as much as you can to stay in
compliance as a cannabis business
just because as cannabis becomes legal
there there's still all of these
different issues that
cannabis businesses are going to be
facing there's you know
if if it turns federally legal
there's still likely going to be you
know
local opposition you know certainly
you'll see
you know even in states where cannabis
is legal
there are often groups of local
municipalities sometimes means
independence depends on what the state
law is written like but
occasionally there can be municipalities
that say
the state law says that cannabis is
legal but we don't want cannabis in this
town
and so there is there's i would always
advise
any of our clients to
be overly overly compliant more than
than try to push the envelope just
because
there's going to be a huge target on on
their on their backs
so i do realize my question is is a
state
tax question versus a uh you know
national or federal tax which is what
the 280 eve
refers to um you know here in washington
for example
if i'm oh if i'm making
you know a product and i use these
inputs to go into my product i don't
have to pay sales tax on those inputs
because i'm going to be charging sales
tax to the final user so i'm not being
taxed
twice for the same product
but um i i maybe that's a state specific
question
i don't know if that's something you've
come across i was just curious
yeah i i think it's gonna it's gonna
vary state by state obviously but
um i do think that's going to be
something every state is going to deal
with
maybe slightly differently but
ultimately what's going to be most
important is that
you are doing what you are supposed to
do to pay
pay what tax that you need to obviously
try
not trying to overpay tax by any by any
means but
but doing everything that you can um all
the way down to something
something like an exemption certificate
uh sales tax or
exemption uh forms that you may have to
fill out
for your states um just doing all of
that as as
above above book as you can
have you worked with any campus corp
companies that have been audited
yet and seen anything there that were
things to watch for i guess
uh we haven't we haven't worked
specifically with them but um
we've definitely as as part of the
national network of
cpas that we're involved in we have
have seen other accountants in our
network that have had that
happen and uh you know there's there's
been
a number of different court cases some
that have gone all the way to the
supreme court
that uh a lot of us are tracking really
closely
um most recently uh the
the case regarding harborside which is a
cannabis business in california
uh went all the way to the supreme court
and they still ruled
uh in favor of maintaining section 280e
so
there is there is still quite a bit of
um work to be done i would say
you know it the irs hasn't gotten to a
point yet where
um a point where like i've seen in other
industries
in my prior experience in public
accounting for example
in the mid 2000s the irs audited many
credit unions and that was a result of
finding parts of their business to be
not uh not really part of their exempt
mission
which resulted in a lot of credit union
businesses
um paying more tax than they needed to
or that more attacks than they had
expected to
and that really was a result of what the
irs i think is doing right now which is
kind of
gearing up their budgeting and certainly
you know cannabis could be a target for
increased audits like that in the future
we don't know for sure we don't know for
certain that that's going to happen
obviously the irs is not going to come
out and say
hey we're going to audit you but um it
certainly
certainly would make a lot of sense that
that that would be
coming especially with the the
complexity of
the accounting um it just
it feels like cannabis client cannabis
the cannabis
industry would be sort of an easy target
um
for additional revenue with irs
and i and i would say too um i've
actually been on conference calls with
with the irs who section that would be
dealing with this
and you know a lot of people have
kind of a bad feeling about the irs that
they're they're the big bad guys
uh but when you actually work with the
people that are in charge of these
they don't they want you to stay
compliant in fact they
really like working with cpas like our
firm
because they're not necessarily the
subject matter experts either and they
want to make sure
the way that they approach things is
doing it right and they
they look to see what's going on in the
industry as much as we look to see what
they're doing
so um i you know and maybe this is just
me having
having worked uh with uh with the irs
for many years
on many different areas i don't see them
as the big
bad scary you know wolf in the corner
necessarily
but you do want to make sure that you're
doing what's right and
and following what they have to say they
have actually
over the past year they have released
more
information about marijuana related
businesses
um actually if you google irs marijuana
they put out a really nice web page uh
probably six months ago that that
starts to talk about some of these
things so i would just say
they're not they're not scary
necessarily if you're doing things right
but you want to
do things right
yeah you know i've had a kind of a
roller coaster relationship with irs
myself you know we got audited uh you
know before we were ever even doing
business in the cannabis industry and uh
the lady who came out did our audit was
really nice but man it's it's a ton of
hours
it's a lot of uh it's a lot of work and
even if you're trying to do things by
the book it's really easy to screw up
um unrelated to that audit i uh
got a letter in the mail oh it was
probably like 10 years ago now
from the irs saying i owed 15 000 in
back taxes
and basically uh what happened was i had
you know when i was setting up my
business paypal account
i had put in my social security
number instead of the business ubi
number because it had a spot for my for
a social security number
and then when the laws changed around uh
the accounting for
you know companies like paypal right
around that time
um they came after me for claiming i
hadn't paid taxes now i paid taxes on it
through the business
uh because it was business income that
money did not go directly to me it went
to the
business which was owned by my parents
at the time so we had accounted for it
there but getting this corrected with
the irs
uh i probably had 60 hours on the phone
with them
at least just on hold and then talking
to them and you know they're like hey
you need to go into the local irs office
so then i have to go and make an
appointment
and the lady there like she legitimately
laughed at me and she's like
you're wasting my time i absolutely
cannot help you with this
you need to go uh you need to go back
and talk to him on the phone
and it was a nightmare the whole time
you know i've got this
fifteen thousand dollar bill that's
accruing
you know more and more penalties and
finally i ended up paying
my cpa at the time um over
two thousand dollars to essentially just
write a stupid letter
saying that we'd accounted for it
another way but
you know it took me about two months
of trying to get this figured out and uh
it was a nightmare and even then you
know having to pay that money to my cpa
who i think overcharged me quite a bit
um
it just it's it's not fun and it it's
really easy
you know it was a simple mistake i made
i just i saw a spot for social security
number i put it in and i shouldn't have
i should have used my federal tax id so
it's just the little stuff like that
that can get you and it's really
frustrating yeah oh yeah
yeah i can't believe that it could be
really scary
um and that's kind of the the the value
that we bring
uh to clients is making sure that
they're audit ready at any given point
and ultimately that helps them sleep at
night so
um yeah that's kind of priceless to the
to the business owner it absolutely is
and i want to say that's sort of how i
heard about you was because i was
listening on clubhouse and heard mark
talking about form
8300 which was one of the reasons i the
main reason i want to get you guys on
the podcast because i never heard of
form 8300
and uh so why don't we start there and
then i'll share a little bit of
my backstory on it but um could one of
you describe what that form is and how
it relates to
you know our industry
yeah so so basically any any
cash payment that is over ten thousand
dollars
uh must anybody who receives that type
of payment
should file a form 8300 with the irs
so obviously for cannabis
businesses that don't have
a cash a bank
relationship or do a lot of work in cash
um that requires quite a bit
of extra paperwork that that
has to be kind of earmarked by form 8300
and there are penalties for
not filing those 8300 so when we talk
about
potential audits that could be
targeted toward cannabis businesses
certainly that's going to be one of
their
the irs's tools in their toolbox
of saying did you do you have cash yes
or no
obviously a lot of the business
businesses will say yes
and did you file all your form 8300s
most likely there's going to be a lot of
businesses that have not done that
and so that's just going to be you know
low hanging fruit for
for audits yeah so
when i heard mark talking about this uh
it kind of surprised me because i heard
something around this ten thousand
dollar mark
and i've taken a few transactions like
that and i thought the bank was filing
them
on my behalf uh and so if i ever deposit
more than ten thousand dollars
they would fill out a form and send it
off and i thought that was the end of it
and since i'm doing everything legal i
figured that was enough
what i learned was the bank doesn't send
anything
they have an internal process over and i
i can't remember the number at my bank
it might have been 5 000 or 8 000. where
they make a notation on my account
but they're not sending anything off to
the irs it's it's my responsibility
to fill out this form and uh the other
thing i learned was that
um all transactions that are considered
related and exceed that 10 000 as a
whole must be reported
so it doesn't matter how many
transactions transactions a deal is
broken into or
how long within you know a 12-month
period if you space it out
if the irs considers them related you
can be penalized for failing to file so
uh there's some nuances with it that go
along with it too and as someone who
tries to follow the rules and
you know as someone who tries to be
compliant this was something that i had
you know dropped the ball on strictly
out of ignorance
right right exactly and i think that's
that's going to be the case for a lot of
a lot of businesses because it's also
not a very
widely uh widely circulated piece of
information
um you know the irs you know i talk
about
their website their website is actually
very good and it does have very good
resources about this but it is fairly
clear
when you read into the the form 8300
reference guide um on the
on the irs website what is required and
and what's uh you know
what you could be facing if you don't do
it so you know you scroll all the way to
the the penalty section and it goes
right into
civil penalties uh for negligent failure
to
file can be up to you know starting with
a hundred dollars not to exceed
not to exceed 1.5 million for per
calendar year so
range they absolutely do not mess around
with this
um obviously the the purpose of form
uh is a good one i mean the real purpose
is to provide an audit trail
for uh to to avoid anti-money laundering
basically to
enforce anti-money laundering efforts
so having a paper trail with irs
certainly
it covers you if you are dealing with
a lot of cash transactions and they are
all for legal cannabis
certainly you want to have yourself
covered as well as as a business owner
um but well yeah i would want to be
aware too
if someone el you know if i'm paying
anything with a cash transaction that
they're going to be listing this down
because you actually
um put the identity of whom the cash was
received from
you can select if you think it's a
suspicious transaction
if you don't get all the information
that you need from them but it's a
fairly
extensive report and you have 15 days
from the time of receiving the money to
get this filed
so it's good to know like i now that we
know about it we're
absolutely doing this and so i have to
talk to growers and say hey you know if
you want to pay me cash
be aware that this is a form that i have
to fill out legally
um yeah and so they're aware that their
names going down in this information now
the other thing too to be aware of is
you know whether
they deposit that cash directly into the
bank account
you know um or they uh
you know send a cashier's check or a
money order all of those things are
considered cash
so the only just be aware of that that
that you don't get around it by you know
doing money orders in thousand dollar
increments you're still
expected to fill out this form or
someone's expected to fill out this form
if you pay in that manner
absolutely so um
yeah that was the biggest thing i wanted
to cover in this podcast because it was
it was totally new to me
um so thank you for
allowing us to get that out is there is
there anything else in terms
of you know potential things to watch
for
or even things you know warning signs
maybe
that maybe your cpa isn't up to speed on
your industry uh
what are the the things that like i'm
thinking as a grower
what what can i look for to sort of
improve my accounting process
um i can start with that one i i think
you know we talk a lot about cannabis
specific
things such as uh section 280e
you know increased compliance efforts
that are required for banks for
cannabis but i always come back to
the accounting 101 or your accounts
reconciled
and it doesn't matter if you're a
cannabis business or
you're a flower shop in town or you're a
restaurant
if your accounts are not reconciled if
your
inventory is not reconciled if your cash
is not reconciled
those are also low-hanging fruit for
for the irs and for auditors honestly uh
there
there are a number of different places
both in the irs website
um banks etc that expect
that as a business owner you have
reconciled
reconciled accounts and
that's challenging enough let alone
having all of these extra
complications as a cannabis owner but i
you know when we start
working with new clients we
reserve about 90 days just to clean up
your books especially if they're if
you're a business that's coming from one
account to another
there's always things that we need to
clean up to make sure that you're
running like clockwork on a month-end
basis because that
that's that's your minimum requirement
as a business owner is to have
clean books that anybody can can look at
and and review
and and uh feel confident in
betsy did you have anything you wanted
to add in that regard
i think mark said that perfectly if
anything i would just say
you know if
if you're a business that um i think
some people
like i'll use the analogy if you haven't
filed your tax return for five years
um some people might feel embarrassed to
approach a tax accountant with that
information but
we are here to to help business owners
and so um i i would just encourage
if someone is feeling intimidated by um
by everything that has to be done from
the accounting
perspective or if they're feeling behind
just to
um you know not feel embarrassed about
what they are be where they are because
we we can always you know do our best to
fix things retroactively so
the important thing is just to kind of
get get things right going forward
absolutely and just to end on a positive
note i do have
a very good friend who was on the
medical side wasn't paying taxes
and you know for over a decade and was
able to
get into a legal campus facility
get you know get squared up with the irs
by working
with directly with irs and his cpa and
you know in a few years time was able to
show enough income to get a mortgage
purchase a house and uh be
totally legal and above board and
for him in this case just the amount of
uh stress and everything in getting that
all resolved
was huge you know knowing that he was
above board with the irs
and and it was able to fix some of this
stuff so
you absolutely can get it done and you
know there is
there is some work to do there but it's
it's absolutely possible
yeah well said well said
all right well i i super appreciate you
guys taking the time during
uh i know your busy season to come on
the podcast and talk a little bit about
accounting
if there's anything else you'd like to
add before we end the podcast
feel free otherwise i just want to thank
you for your time today thanks so much
for having us ted
yeah thank you for having us all right
have a wonderful day
was betsy moram and mark waller and you
are listening to the cannabis
cultivation and science podcast
i'm your host tad hussey of kiss
organics don't forget to check out the
podcast page at www.kisorganics.com just
click on the learn tab
then podcast and if you haven't already
please take a moment and leave us a
comment or review on whatever platform
you listen on i do take the time to read
them all and appreciate the feedback
you can also follow us on instagram at
kis organics to stay up to date on the
latest podcast releases and information
thanks for listening
you