[Music]
welcome to the Cannabis cultivation and
science podcast I'm your host Tad h of
Kiss Organics this is the podcast where
we discuss The Cutting Edge of growing
from a science-based perspective and
drawn top experts around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge my
guest this week is Bryant Mason I've had
Bryant on the podcast a few times in the
past and he's one of my favorite guests
Bryant is a certified crop adviser who
specializes in organic cannabis
nutrition he has spent the last 5 years
working to combine Precision laboratory
techniques with data science in an
effort to unravel the complexities of
cannabis soil and crop nutrition along
with his work on soilless media he also
helps outdoor cultivators around the
United un states with nutrient
management and cover cropping if you
would like to do soil testing help with
interpreting a soil test or interested
in an online course on these subjects
his website is
wwwd consulting.com and if you want to
save $100 on his course you can use the
discount code kis Organics all one word
and I've taken this course and was
recently going back to review some of
the content it's excellent and I highly
recommend it for anyone wanting to do a
deep dive on cannabis fertility and
reusing your soil now on to the
show okay we are jumping back in with
part two of my conversation with Bryant
Mason talking about soil fertility and
cannabis
nutrition why don't we talk about
potassium but
briefly it's quite loquacious with the
calcium so we can we can condense it so
potassium I've been thinking a lot about
due to the fact that for years I've
recommended potassium sulfate
for potassium and that's
because um well two reasons one is I I
always suggest recommend I always
suggest compost um well not always I'm
sorry I also suggest compost which is a
major source of potassium but the
content of potassium varies between
composts and um when I look at a soil
test it's often in the middle of a round
and so they it needs potassium
immediately sometimes going into flour
um so potassium sulfate is the best
organic option pottassium silicate is
not technically organic when it's soil
applied it's allowed in certain
circumstances as a um fungicide foler
applied um but nutritionally it's not
allowed so potassium sulfate is kind of
the the product
um and I've made a couple changes in the
last year in my thinking around
potassium sulfate I still think is a
great product works very well um but I
believe Growers should verify their need
for pot potassium with a tissue test so
if if they get a recommendation that
says use this much potassium sulfate I
best practice would be to verify with a
tissue test because often times I'll
see relatively low pottassium at least
below my target level but that's there's
sufficiency in the tissue test and so an
application of pottassium sulfate is not
necessary um and I haven't seen that
many tissue tests that show deficient
potassium so it's possible what I'm
reevaluating my soil targets slightly
and I I might lower them what's yeah so
that's just a that's just one change I'm
thinking about um the other thing is
because of that high solubility of
potassium sulfate I believe Growers
should increase the frequency of
application so let's say the soil doctor
tool recommends A cup per cubic yard of
potassium sulfate which would be a lot I
don't recommend doing a cup all at once
the more you can break that into four to
10 applications the better
um because again you're reducing the
salt stress but also when you flood the
soil solution with that much
potassium it will completely change the
cation uptake Dynamics so when it comes
to Epsom salts and potassium sulfate
Epsom salt is usually not used as I
don't recommend it very often with as a
soil drench potassium sulfate I do I
think those two you you increase the
frequency um and then the final thing is
I do think it's good to be constantly
building potassium levels slow relasing
um more organic meaning carbon-based
sources of potassium using Alternatives
like compost and Al phalam the reason Al
falam is so great and I know you've
always used a lot of Al falam and I've
always I recommend it as kind of one of
this the few default nitrogen sources
when I write
recommendations
um historically because of the more slow
releasing nature of it and the triol and
some of the BIOS simulant effects but
now it's because it also brings in a lot
of potassium because when you apply
Alfalfa it doesn't have a ton of
nitrogen in it and so you're applying a
large quantity and it also brings in a
lot of potassium that's slow releasing I
would say green sand but green sand I
don't think in cannabis makes sense
because heavy metals um so just always
be applying high potassium compost or
just any moderate potassium compost and
green and use Al phalam as one of the
nitrogen sources um I would say that the
the second place sort of the silver and
bronze metal would be insect fras which
I know you love and granular poultry
which I love those two both bring in
about 4%
um uh potash K k2o
so yeah I think those are the things i'
i' I'd say about potassium is is just
trying to reduce potassium sulfate um
not entirely but thinking about other
sources as
well yeah I I love potassium sulfate I
mean it's one of my favorite amendments
I think it's something that every grower
needs to have in their Pantry um in fact
I want to do a a talk on that here soon
like the the products I think every
grower should have and they're not
really products you know they're things
like gypsum and uh potassium sulfate
they're not expensive but you want to
have them on hand for when you need them
um but like you said 50% potassium
highly soluble if you see potassium
deficiency you want to address one it is
the fastest and best way to get
potassium into into the plant age the
what you brought up I think is really
interesting in terms of splitting up
your applications to lower the salt
stress um I'm I want to I want to think
about that a little bit and see how I
can incorporate that um you mentioned
compost and while I think compost is
great I have moved away from
recommending it quite as much um for a
few reasons so one you're reintroducing
fungus knats that next cycle on a
commercial scale it's just annoying and
can get expensive with all the
beneficials and other stuff I mean
relatively easy to deal with but still
you know Annoying uh bringing in bugs
and it's it's a it's a vector for
pathogens potentially so I I've stopped
doing compost additions every cycle um
just for that reason and the fact that
like not everyone tests their compost
compost can be inconsistent so even
though they have one test showing it's h
potassium one cycle the next cycle that
that compost Source could be something
totally different um I still love
compost I just I'm not quite as
enthusiastic about it as I used to be um
in the past but fair just some just some
things for people to think about as
they're uh determining what they're
going to add each cycle I I love insect
frass like you mentioned um it's clean
it's got good microbial activity and
life in it in addition to having a
pretty balanced NPK value um but we you
do have to account for the other the
other nutrients in there the n and the P
that you're bringing in um and then
alphalpha meal like you said it's such a
low NPK value for the most part um I the
the end it brings in is pretty
negligible and it just has a ton of
different other
benefits um the triacontanol is
interesting because I think from what I
from talking to a plant growth hormone
guy uh I'm gonna butcher his name it was
Jim Gray maybe it was Jim something or
other I I interviewed on it a little
while back he was a retired plant
hormone guy and he said that
triacontanol breaks down so quickly that
unless you're putting out
like actual Alfalfa and just laying it
on the surface that triacontanol is just
not going to make it into the
interesting interesting um yeah that
that could be I mean I don't Al Alpha 4
the triol which is more of just like a
yeah and just to clarify I would only
apply I would not apply alala insect
fress or Gran poultry for pottassium I
would apply those I would choose those
products for
nitrogen knowing that it's going to a
secondary benefit is it'll build uh
potassium but you always fulfill your
nitrogen deficit
first just just for listeners who that's
no that's a that's a really good point
um I'm glad glad you I'm glad you
brought that up um and I I would add
further that I don't like to use
potassium sulfate all that frequently um
when re amending my soil uh at high
rates I I because it is so soble I like
to use it during the growth cycle kind
of as that like liquid bottled nutrient
sort of application it's my Band-Aid to
except you don't have to use liquid
bottle nutrients that's the exct well so
my my liquid bottle nutrient is fish
hydraulic usually that's right me too me
too yeah that that's my go-to when I see
a problem yeah yeah yeah no I I I agree
that's you know there's a few things I
use in bottles and they're not yeah one
of them is liquid fish I love it um yeah
and I would mention with compost for
those who have received recommendations
from me you usually don't see compost
because I don't recommend it if your
sodium's high or your nitrogen's high or
your salts are too
high and i' I've gone back and forth
about recommending it at all because if
I don't know what it is I mean there's
just such a wild difference
between uh horse manure and uh worm
castings made in someone's basement like
it's just they it it varies so much that
unless I have a test which I rarely do I
don't like recommending it so in
addition to fungus snaps there's a
number of other thing considerations
with compost for sure even the carbon
niton ratio it's like that can really
that can really screw people up quickly
um um so I don't necessarily because I'm
not able to control for all those
variables uh as just writing a slil
recommendation I too have sort of
straight away from it but anyway I just
mentioned it because it is a good
potassium Source um so if people can
account for all those other factors it's
something to
consider a absolutely and I I think an
interesting way to get the Amendments
out is to use compost to mix them in
with a little bit of compost to get that
biology in there when you're top
dressing um when you're amending mix it
in with a little bit of soil or apply
some of those um amendments into your
worm bin or into your compost pile as a
way of raising the fertility of the pile
itself um but interesting enough this is
a little off topic too it's a a tangent
but I've been having this discussion on
a um soil analyst for Forum with Steve
Solomon because someone posted a um a
soil recipe that they found online for
living soil for cannabis
indoors and so we got in this huge
discussion about it and um my my point
and I I think you'll agree with me on
this one is all living soil recipes all
soil recipes should be based around your
compost because it is so variable that's
where I always start absolutely so when
you see a recipe online that says you
know 20% earthworm castings or 20%
compost that fraction is going to vary
so much and determine what the other
inputs are are that I don't trust any of
these recipes and I say this as someone
as a manufacturer who sells a nutrient
pack which is designed to be mixed with
you know either something like ocean
forest or promix or um you make your own
sort of living soil by taking you know
our mineral nutrient pack and adding
compost and Peete moss and even with
that my degree of confidence goes down
because that compost can can like you
said it can it can be imbalanced it can
have way too much n nitrogen ammonium uh
you know potassium whatever totally yeah
so um I think that's that's and that's
why I don't like soil recipes and I
don't people have I can't tell you how
many requests I've had for so like do
you have a soil recipe it's like no and
that's why it's because comp the compost
variability um so yeah and like to kind
of piggyback on that is I get requests
like I want to make my own soil mix and
to that I always say like that's great
and then I just say but just so you
understand the process for me like for
me to formulate a soil is going to take
let's say six months aggressively at
best to probably two years realistically
before it be something that I want to
like put out with my name on it because
the amount like initially you got to
find your compost Source you got to test
that then you got to mix up a soil um
and see what you get and then you have
to make adjustments and then once you
get everything where you want on the
soil test then you do plant trials and
see how that goes and so right that
process just takes a really long time if
you want to do it right you know you
can't just throw a bunch of things
together throw a plant in there and if
it grows well assume that you've got
this amazing soil mix now if you're a
hom grower I think that's that's fine
and I absolutely encourage
experimentation but um if you're on a
commercial scale that's just not
practical um and that's why I would add
too that like the first thing I coach
people to do is to to not even worry
about the chemistry well first you worry
about the chemistry of the compost and
you test as many composts as you have
access to and you you choose the right
site or single compost and then you go
you forget the chemistry you choose
those combos and then you just do like
physical tests so you try to get your
percentages right and you want you put
it in the bed or the pot and you water
it and you w and you just you feel it
and you watch the infiltration rate and
you have to dial in the percentages and
then you go back to the chemistry and
you just get the base mix right before
you do the any of the Amendments because
to me you want to customize your
amendments based on what your um your
base mix is and I go through all of this
in my course and that like you said the
the process is
um potentially totally
worthwhile but no doubt laborious and
long and involved it's not a simple
Coots mix or whatever if you really want
to do it right it's a
process yeah and even cot says like you
don't have his mix because you don't
have his vermac compost and I think
that's really true um that's why I hear
people that say you know C Mix works
really well for me and other people that
say like this this is a terrible recipe
and uh you know it's not balanced at all
it really depends yeah right right right
well let me can I can we chat about iron
real quick before we talk about carbon
yeah yeah go ahead let's do it okay so
it's sort of similar I've evolved my
thinking on iron iron sulfate
specifically but iron in general
because I have
observed wildly varying levels on tissue
tests of iron and it's hard to note
because iron contaminates both soil
samples but more so tissue samples all
the time it contam soil samples
sometimes on the past test because um
little pieces of soil or clay
specifically can slip through the filter
paper at the lab and it will show a
really high iron level in on a pace test
which isn't a huge deal what's more
important is if you have dust on a
tissue test on any s tissue sample that
dust can can go through the the tissue
test and show that you have
extraordinarily high levels of iron so
that could be the case it also just
could be that the plant actually will
sometimes accumulate huge amounts of
iron at different points mostly further
into flour um but sometimes I'll just
see really high iron levels and and
sometimes I'll see really low iron
levels and there are some Growers that
my recommendations of iron sulfate have
not been able to effectively address
their iron hunger I don't want to say
deficiency because it's not usually not
so acute that it's visual it's usually
just we're seeing it in the data and I
can't get that that number to move and
that's almost I'm almost I'm 100%
confident because iron sulfate when you
apply it
um it oxidizes very quickly imagine like
the the chemical reaction of rusting and
so once it oxidizes it goes into an
ionic State that's not available to the
plant and so when you drench iron
sulfate in a high oxygen soil and in a
high pH soil and when I say high pH I
mean anything over six it it could
oxidize like immediately even with a
humic substance like you know when you
mix iron sulfate with humic acid and you
drench it into a soil pH of seven I
think it oxidizes I don't see the and
and the data constantly humbles me
because I think I know how to do
something and then I always just follow
the data and sometimes it tells me I
don't and so this is a big learning for
me is in know in these soils that we're
working in I think iron is oxidizing and
very little of it is making into the
plant immediately it's not to say you
shouldn't apply iron sulfate because I
do think there's something to say about
loading your soil with iron which will
be reduced in the risos spere um or by
you know in with different sort of
magical risos spere reactions and
organic acids but I think if your plant
needs
iron um a better technique may be to
core the iron
sulfate uh 50 50 iron sulfate and
Elemental
sulfur somewhere in your root Zone in a
little pocket when I say core I mean
like a pocket of iron sulfate and
Elemental sulfur and what that does is
it creates this little pocket of a low
PH environment really low like in the
fours maybe
and at least in the fives and that keeps
the iron in a reduced form and you don't
what I've uh learned again in tree fruit
production this is a technique I get
from orcharding uh orchardists can have
an iron deficiency their whole canopy is
like that sort of yellow chlorotic look
and they core just a little bit of iron
sulfate at the base of their trees and
it it works very quickly and they're
their trees can green up and
um yeah I mean you could also throw a
little manganese sulfate in there
actually but manganese sulfate to me is
more effective with a drench so you
create that pocket in the Roots it
doesn't need to be homogeneous The Roots
can just tap into that little pocket and
take up iron in the available form so
and then the only other thing I'll
mention there is again there are
alternatives if you use alala and blood
meal for
nitrogen again you're using those for
nitrogen not for iron but in doing so
you're bringing in a lot of slow
releasing organically complex iron into
your into your soil system um which will
help prevent the iron hunger in the
first place I believe I see this all the
time in cannabis when I I was growing
commercially six years ago or something
in Oregon and I would the tops of the
plants would always be a little bit
yellow and I just thought because a lot
of plants it's just sort of normal they
always green up eventually but that sort
of top choot growth that new apical
growth when it's sort of light color I
always attribute that to iron
um but again I just follow the data and
I like to
just look at what the tissue numbers say
and address it that way that's really
interesting
so I I haven't thought as much about
iron uh Brandon and I um Brandon Hudson
who you mentioned before we we've talked
about this um and we just look at we've
just always uh his point was that yes
the plant may need a little more iron
right there but that's just because it
can't keep up with the amount of growth
it's getting at that point and that's
just going to Green up and go away
because it does um so we haven't I
haven't really addressed it the one
thing when you said low ph and pocket my
brain immediately just went heavy metals
like ah are we are we putting ourselves
more at risk for heavy metal uptake by
having a pocket of low PH soil in the
rise ofhere I don't that's a good that's
a good question but I would I would my
mental model to answer that question is
that the nutrient uptake is evenly
distributed across the entire bulk soil
and the pocket is is probably less than
1% of the bulk soil so yeah you're going
to make heavy metals potentially more
available in that pocket and I'm talking
the size of your fist like so yeah the
heavy metals be will be more available
in a in a pocket of soil the size of
your fist but that's just such a small
pocket of soil that unless you had an a
large heavy metal load I don't think it
should matter it's just so dilute not
dilute but it's so small
um that's a really interesting
experiment I would love to run it but I
also don't want to then throw off all my
soil tests moving forward because well
okay so that's oh that's a great point
that is a great Point as soon as you
start coring iron sulfate you you have
to ignore the iron number on the soil
test so if you put your soil test
through the soil doctor
tool you have to disregard the iron
sulfate recommendation coming out of
that tool and you have to go solely off
of tissue tests and
visuals because the soil is
non-homogeneous so you're either going
to see low iron because when you're
sampling your soil you don't hit that
pocket and so it's going to show or
you're going to hit the pocket and
you're going to have really really high
iron on this on the soil test both of
those situations are are suboptimal and
they're not accurate so you have to go
off
tissue have you done this with cannabis
and seen that immediate Greening of New
Growth then where you don't get that
well the grow I I don't see it but the
Growers I work with do and okay so
people have this and seen I I haven't
gotten reports of the visual of of the
top growth yellowing I haven't asked
that question what I see is the tissue
test finally
moves okay interesting yeah I but they
but but the grower who did it did it at
a kind of a high well a couple people
have done it now but the first one who
did it was did it at a rate that was um
maybe a little too high he said they
they seemed to have a little bit more
transplant shock but they grow out grew
out out of it really quickly to me that
means you lower the rate I don't think
transplant shock is ever good um
especially from a a fertilizer so I told
him to cut the rate in half and and do
it again this guy had really cool guy up
in Michigan worked with a lot tests like
a bandit and so he's got this amazing
body of data and we just it's like iron
sulfate every round and it the numbers
just wouldn't move and finally we got
him to move with this this
core that is really interesting I'll
have to think about that um and that's
actually a really good segue into the
next topic which
is uh amino acids because
um well maybe not the best segue but my
point is you'll see products now and and
we talked about this a little before the
podcast how um there there's products
out there you know primarily with
micronutrients
um that are approved for use in organic
production and they're supposedly like
organic forms of these minerals um but
when you look at the derivation
statement the ingredients they're all
derived from sulfates so you may have
like an organic manganese product let's
say but when you look at what it's
derived from it's derived from manganese
sulfate so are these products really any
more organic um or really better than
just applying the meganes sulfate
directly so I realize this isn't exactly
what we're talking about but I want to
touch start there so the aminated
micronutrient products that I see that
are certified organic are primarily for
folar is that what you're referring to
so we're talking bioman
albon um I was using this year my
Orchard polyamine so what those are is
you're right they take these just sort
of raw mineral amendments like let's say
zinc salt sulfate and they combine them
with amino acids
probably the same amino acids we're
using which is um ground up soybean meal
it's pulverized like
soluble soy based amino acids
and that would be the mo I don't
actually know how they're made because
it's proprietary but that's probably
like the rudimentary way they mix them
together and they keyate them so when
you combine those two things it keates
them and in theory it keeps them more
available
um so when they hit the plant leaf
they're not going to oxidize as quickly
and there's just better um Leaf
penetration with amino acids better
uptake efficiency and so you're getting
more unit of nutrient into the plant
which I believe is true now now if the
increase in folar efficiency offsets the
increase in cost of the product I don't
know I've always wondered that I've
always wondered should I just apply iron
sulfate chelated with fulvic acid is
that going to be way more costeffective
on three acres than than applying albon
metalosate iron which costs quite a bit
of money um so in theory different
micronutrients are chelated better with
different individual amino acids so
manganese for example is a little
tougher to chelate so they might use uh
an amino acid like high in glycine or
something I'm making that
up um but are they more organic I mean
is your definition of organic like just
certified organic I mean they're both
both manganese sulfate
and uh bottled chelated manganese is
they're both certified so I don't know
if they're they're more organic I mean
you are applying it with carbon which is
way preferable
foler um but you could do that yourself
you could do molasses and a little bit
of a touch of kelp and well not in
cannabis produ I wouldn't do kelp but a
touch of molasses and fulvic acid would
be a carbon Source um my issue is
there's no way to know if that if how
much better they are if that if that
uptake efficiency and the and the
nutrient use efficiency inside the plant
is that much better to justify the cost
of of these branded chelated products um
I've always used them but this year I'm
breaking my farm in half this isn't
actually testing this specific
hypothesis but I'm break breaking my
farm in half and I'm going to do every
organic foler calcium foler
specifically um including the jadam
stuff and and a lot of these branded
Amino culated products on half of my
trees and I'm not going to do a single
calcium foler on the other half and I'm
just curious to see if any of them are
really making that big of a difference
um which let me just this is a tangent
and I know I'm talking a lot
but I want to just
pitch to every grower listening that
they should be split testing every time
there's an expensive
input if you can you can't do too many
split tests obviously but you should
break your bedroom in half or you should
break your field in half or you should
break your grow tent in half and do no
treatment on half and do the treatment
on the other half because it's
amazing the level of faith that Growers
have in products it's amazing and
because in part you kind of have to
because you just have to believe
something and then do it but I'm here to
say to argue if if possible break your
your room in half and you can be a
little less faithful and actually put it
to the test I think this is a
characteristic I see in so many really
good Growers who I've spoken to is
they're constantly testing something
even if it's just one thing one thing at
a I mean preferably one thing at a time
split test whatever is your highest cost
input that you're not 100% confident is
justifiable I couldn't agree more with
you it drives me nuts the amount of
products that are hyped to this
specifically to the Canabis industry but
it's not even unique to cannabis we see
it in egg too which is crazy because
I'll go to an egg conference and I'll be
like talking to a guy and be like I'm
pretty sure you're full of [__] but like
you're obviously selling a lot of your
product you know like you're a business
yeah it drives me nuts and and well go
ahead go
ahead well I just I I was just going to
say that and even and I think that the
the salesman too they they they believe
it so it's it's hard because when
another human looks you in the eyes and
they they have conviction that something
works there's there's a natural tendency
to to want to believe them so I I don't
think it's like yeah I don't think it's
like a
a character flaw I just think it's part
of human bias and I think we all just
should be fighting against it all the
time and and to your point I'm testing
these folur primarily because every tree
fruit grower in my
area is is spending an enormous amount
of money on Amino kated folar
sprays and no there's no nobody knows if
they actually work they either think
they work or they think they don't work
but there's no there's no trials there's
no evidence there's
there's nothing and so split tests are
the only way to know and they're they're
not they're not scientific in that
there's not replicates so you can't find
statistical significance but we're not
scientists we're Growers so we just want
enough evidence to make the right
management decision so split tests are
totally
great and to your point realistically we
just have to know what works in our grow
in our environment in our garden it
doesn't matter how effective it is in
New Zealand you know it matters what
works for me here in Washington state um
and there's so many variables involved
in that like we've talked about you know
temperature moisture environment water
um you know sunlight all of these things
are going to come into play and when I'm
Consulting and I walk into a facility
and I say show me what you're doing for
IPM show me what you're doing for
fertility and that list is really
long the first thing I want to do yeah
you have no idea you have no idea what
is doing what um I want to I want to
just simplify everything and then if you
want to use that you know hype product
that you saw on Instagram fine but let's
work it back in let's come back to a
Baseline and then let's do some of that
you know split testing AB testing and
see if you're actually getting results
from it because at the end of the day
all we're doing as Growers is trying to
address what the limiting factor of
growth is you know leig law of the
minimum like this idea that you know if
if the limiting factor is the fact that
our facility has lights that are you
know 400 ppfd and flower it doesn't
matter what you know what
enzyme yeah ferment product I'm not
getting enough light so um and to add to
that you know I was talking to a grower
the other day on scale and every time he
does a foler application um for IPM it's
$6,000 you know that's a significant
chunk of money that he has to SP scale
is this cannabis yeah it's pretty
they're pretty large farm you know and
that I don't know if that's strictly
just product or labor I'm pretty sure it
was just the product and it was a more
expensive IPM product a a good product
you know but if he's having to spray
these things in in in uh on his crop
it's it adds up now for the hom grower
it may not seem like much 10 bucks 20
bucks you know whatever for a similar
comparative scale but um there's no
reason we can't grow healthy plants for
for significantly less money um if we
just start thinking about this idea of
split testing and and well yeah and I
would also argue let's just put money
aside which obviously is everything when
it comes to commercial operation but the
only way to become a better grower is to
start to tease out what
that what that low hanging fruit or what
that bottleneck is in photosynthesis so
um if you just want to improve your
general ability as a grower you have to
start to to to reduce inputs that's the
only way to do it um and then increase
you know you're FL you have to learn I
guess that's what I'm trying to get at
is you have to be constantly
learning you know Kaizen all the time
otherwise you're not going to be
improving yourself like you
could all right so let's talk a little
bit about Amino assets I know it's
something that you've been thinking
about you know we just covered a little
bit of how people are using amino acids
as foliar because I suppose they have
better efficacy um I don't just give me
your thoughts on that
topic sure so the brief synop synopsis
on amino
acids as it relates to plant nutrition
is that well there's a few things that
come to mind the first is that they're
definitely amino acids are definitely
the best source of fol or applied
nitrogen and there's quite a bit of
research that shows that particularly in
field Crop Production that the nitrogen
use the nitrogen uptake from amino acid
sources of nitrogen is by far better
than any other nitrogen Source ful or
applied so big big um proponent of amino
acids in folar they are also there's
there's this idea of metabolic
shortcutting we've talked about this
before where if a plant does uptake
nitrogen in the form of amino acids or
or any organic form doesn't necessarily
have to be amino acids um plants can
actually uptake larger compounds as well
there's this idea that they save quite a
bit of metabolic energy by not having to
reduce other forms of nitrogen like
nitrate or ammonium into amino acids in
the plants because they uptake them
they're already in amino acid form and
that is definitely a well documented
phenomenon um but not studied very
extensively um so research the research
generally shows I've done a deep dive on
um nitrogen from organic sources and it
generally shows that the maximum
nitrogen use efficiency results when the
plant uptakes various forms of nitrogen
uh and that's because of that metabolic
shortcutting idea so major props to
organic production in this regard
because all of our nitrogen is
essentially um being applied in organic
form with carbon so the body of research
is sadly lacking when it comes to
organic nitrogen um it's organic forms
of nitrogen like amino acids have
essentially been ignored as a third pool
of plant available nitrogen but there
are a few studies that show that when
you incorporate carbon-based amino acid
nitrogen it increases nitrogen use
efficiency but I think what's important
to point out for the Cannabis Community
is that all organic products are either
composed of amino acids or end up as
amino acids for a period of time in the
process of mineralization so I think
what is confusing or maybe misleading is
that um we say oh I want to I want to
use amino acid nitrogen well does that
mean amino acid like a liquid uh water
soluble liquid nitrogen from soy Bean or
fish that's technically marketed as
amino acid nitrogen because alala blood
meal feather meal all of these things
are are enzymatically digested in the
soil and end up in their constituent
Parts which are amino acids so how I
think about it is when you're amending
your soil with Organic
amendments uh that are nitrogen and
carbon in in protein form those are
essentially going to create a little
amino acid Factory in your soil so those
things as those mineralize they are
going to end up as amino acids in your
soil um and then at that point the plant
will uptake some of the those amino
acids it's debatable how much of those
are amino acids are uptaken um before
the amino acids are then converted into
ammonium and then nitrate so all these
different these three different forms
all exist in your soil at the same time
and all organic products are technically
going to contribute amino acids so so
it's a little misleading to say I want
amino acid nitrogen because anything
organic is in a sense going to lead to
that so whether I buy a soy Amino
product or soybean meal I'm still going
to be getting amino acids in my soil
because of how they're going to break
down that's exactly right that's exactly
right now the amino acid nitrogen from
soybean meal is going to be immediate
it's smaller particle size and
potentially already digested into the
constituent amino acids so you're going
to get amino acids faster but they're
both doing the same thing they're ending
up at the same place and I'll add one
more thing I put out a video on my
Instagram about amino acids a while back
and my point in that video is to say
that when you drench amino acids to the
soil again there's not a good
understanding of how much of that is
directly uptaken by the plant and how
much of it is is eaten by the microbes
um or converted by microbes into
ammonium and then nitrate these so these
pools are constantly in flux and my
argument is that the again just a tiny
bit of of research out there shows that
the microbes feed very quickly and so
the majority of the liquid soy based
amino acids that we're applying are
probably consumed by the microbes not
the plant and there wasn't really a
major reason other than to just try to
point out what's happening in our soil
systems because even if the microbes eat
those amino acids they'll die
and release organic forms of nitrogen
back into the soil it's a cycle so it
doesn't really matter um but it's just
interesting to think my general belief
is that the microbes feed first and and
amino acids can turn over in soil
extremely quickly so uh anyway that's
just another small Dynamic to for
Growers to understand and think about so
one thing that I'm a little unclear on
is if the amino acids
are if nitrogen is is in an amino acid
form um is that different than nitrate
and ammonium in Essen it is you talked a
little bit about that what's happening
inside the plant you said if it goes
into the plant then it's converted to
ammonium and then nitrate that's part of
the nitrogen cycle why would that be
superior to just nitrates in your soil
for example where the plants just taking
up a nitrate yeah so if a plant takes up
a nitrate it has to convert it twice
it essentially has to go in reverse it
has to convert to ammonium and then
amino acids to to complex it into a leaf
as a complete protein so if if the plant
uptakes an amino acid it doesn't have to
convert it twice which takes a huge um
there's a huge energetic cost to the
plant so if it takes it up as an amino
acid it can just put it directly into a
protein and complex it into the leaf so
you're skipping two different steps
inside the plant if the plant uptakes uh
an amino acid and by amino acid it
technically any organic form of nitrogen
um so it could be other molecules
besides amino
acids so then how do we correlate this
with a soil test because on a soil test
we're primarily looking at nitrate
levels we want to keep ammonium levels
very low in that nitrogen cycling
process um and you know that's a metric
so how does that
relate yeah and this is that is million
dollar question because we're not
testing on a soil test we're not testing
organic forms of nitrogen we're just
seeing ammonium and nitrate and we're
making our management decisions based on
those two things and that's a limitation
in soil testing there are ways that Labs
can test organic nitrogen but it gets
complicated and confusing because
there's different fractions and there's
different it's a totally different lab
technique and um
there's not a simple way to just test
small uh amino acids the the small
fraction of organic nitrogen compounds
which is amino acids so I wrote a Long
blog post about this called how to
manage nitrogen organically it's for
cannabis Growers it's on my it's on my
website
and I I break this down but to answer
your question Tad more
specifically we are just using ammonium
and nitrate we get to see two out of the
three pools of
nitrogen and so we don't get to see that
third pool and we're just using ammonium
and nitrate as a proxy um to sort of
understand how big those pools are
because they are correlated and so my
the reason I'm comfortable using
ammonium and nitrate and not seeing that
organic nitrogen pool on a soil test is
because if the organic nitrogen pool is
healthy you will end up seeing ammonium
and nitrate because the micro convert if
there's excess organic nitrogen excess
amino acids it ends up as nitrate so
when you see that nitrate number you
know between let's just say 50 and 150
you know that there was at one point
there was an excess of that organic
nitrogen pool and it converted in
nitrate when you see the the nitrate
number
low usually that means there's not
excess organic nitrogen in the system
and so those are sort of proxies if that
makes sense to to estimating how big
that organic pool is a lot of Growers I
know intentionally keep their nitrogen
their inorganic nitrogen so nitrate and
ammonium they keep those pools low so on
a soil test it might be 15 parts per
million or something and they feed those
organic sources of nitrogen as the plant
needs it and I think they do so
primarily based on visual symptoms and
occasional tissue tests so soil testing
is flawed in that respect in my opinion
for organic growers in particular um you
still want to know ammonium and nitrate
it's good proxy for organic nitrogen but
it's it's not a direct measurement and
then along those lines that total
nitrogen number that you can also get
from on on the standard test that's not
really showing us that either then huh
the reason that one's not good is
because it's also like if you imagine a
chunk of
alal that's not plant available that's
still a protein
meal so it's it's still plant material
and so that nitrogen has not been
enzymatically broken down biologically
digested into small enough organic
nitrogen pieces amino acids to be taken
up by the plant so that total nitrogen
number is going to give you all the
nitrogen in the soil much of which is
not yet plant
available so amino acids they're the the
building box blocks of proteins
proteins exist
in these amendments like fish meal um
blood meal alphalpha we're talking about
specifically in relation to nitrogen
here those get broken down biologically
through nutrient cycling microbial
processes in the soil in the rizosphere
and then what's released from that is
potentially all three forms of nitrogen
is what you're saying then we'll get
some organic amino acids some nitrates
some ammonium depend some ammonium
depending on uh what's going on in the
soil that's right that's a very good
summary okay and then these are all tied
closely to to moisture content and
oxygen gas exchange in the soil as well
do you want to just touch on that yes
it's it's the nitrogen Transformations
are are highly dependent on on moisture
and oxygen because they're biologically
driven but the third variable that I
think actually matters even more is
temperature so the conversion if you put
in feather meal into your soil and it's
cold it could take weeks or months to
really become available to to to be
broken down biologically into those
three nitrogen um
molecules but in a warm soil it happens
very quickly so and obviously um there's
higher biological activity when soil
moisture is optimal and when gas
exchange is optimal um when gas exchange
is not optimal the the nitrogen can
essentially um that cycle will get
plugged up and there'll be more ammonium
usually uh but I almost never see that
in a Pete based media in any kind of
living soil I almost never see that just
because gas exchange is pretty good that
would be a Mucky top soil like a really
clay heavy compacted muck um what I do
see is once you amend a soil or if you
were to blend your soil it would there'd
be so much um organic nitrogen that goes
into that system that the soil would
cook and ammonium levels would spike for
a period of time before they get they go
back down and get converted into
nitrate so if you were to test your soil
right after amending you could see high
ammonium if that soil is biologically
active as it's converting it to nitrates
absolutely have you have you seen that
before I just saw that recently on a
test um and it kind of surprised me
because I typically when my brain when I
see high ammonium numbers I
automatically go to unfinished compost
um that's just where where I head more
and more I'm thinking of Peete based
media or living let me call them living
soils because a p based media with a
significant um portion of
compost I kind of think of them like
composts because they're they're bi
they're very biologically active and
they're increasing in maturity over time
through through biological
mineralization and and um fungal
decomposition and and so
yeah it's unfinished compost is a great
coraly and essentially when you throw a
bunch of blood meal and alfalfa meal and
bone meal and and fish compost
into Pete Moss and cocoa core it
essentially creates a little compost I
mean it cooks and that's what that
temperature when you when you when you
like feel that temperature after you
really mix a soil when the temperature
spikes if you tested it at that moment
in time I'd almost guarantee that the
ammonium would be
elevated yeah so what what I I aim to do
when I'm amending a soil is I want to
get as much in there at the beginning of
a run that I can without going without
triggering that thermal
process because I don't want to wait for
the soil to you know what we call cook
like a like a thermophilic compost pile
so um the goal and so the goal is then
to amend at a rate that's high fertility
but low enough that we not causing this
explosion of microbial growth that's
causing this yeah temperature increase
and that's that's really the trick I
think um I what your thoughts on that I
I think the same thing and I put a
little note for for Growers who have
received soil recommendations from me
there's a little note uh in the Nitro I
have nitrogen tips and one of them says
please let me know if your soil heats up
because I want to know uh so then I can
adjust my rates to be what you said is
right under that that um that
temperature increase and some products
are more sus I mean blood meal is is way
more prone to to creating temperature
spikes because of the speed at which it
releases um just the properties of
certain nitrogen amendments will
sometimes cause that and you can also
smell it sometimes you can smell that
ammonium um
volatilizing yeah so it's important to
have your moisture content right your
temperature you know in your room is if
if it's an indoor facility like I'm
typically thinking about it the the
temperature is probably going to be
there already you don't have to worry
about that as much but I think um making
sure you're not over or underwatering is
really important to allow that process
to occur um the way you want it to and
uh you can always add more you know a
couple weeks later or a few weeks later
to get to the get to your target so you
don't have to get it all in there at
once um just just some other notes on
that that's right that's
right um and uh since you talked about
amino acids and the fact that we don't
necessarily need to
buy products that are labeled amino
acids to get amino acids uh you know
I've recently seen some products that
are you know called carbon-based
fertilizers um and this idea that
because they're carbon based um you know
they're Superior to other fertilizers uh
you and I talked about this do you want
to touch on that a little bit sure so I
think that the in organic farming that
label is kind of
meaningless um because for the most part
most of our or let me back up not all of
our nutrients are always carbon based so
we were talking about pottassium sulfate
we're talking about gypsum that's not
carbon based so um in general there's a
lot of benefit to to using nutrients
that are carbon based and that's kind of
baked into organic farming when it comes
to your phosphorus products and your
nitrogen products and and just you know
the mineralization of organic matter um
so when someone says this is a
carbon-based nitrogen product it just it
it doesn't it's sort of a a redundant
or um it doesn't mean a whole lot
because all of our organic nitrogen
products are already carbon based it's
gained a lot of popularity in
conventional production because
conventional Growers are starting to
realize that U there's a major metabolic
and plant Health Advantage
to incorporating carbon into their
nutritional programs so I think the
terminology the marketing terminology
comes mostly from you know the
conventional world
but I don't think it has a whole lot of
meaning when it comes to when we're
talking about organic uh
products and I would add that when we're
talking about living soils you know PE
based soiless media that's very
biologically active um we we have high
levels of carbon in in those mixes
already um our organic matter is you
know through the roof compared to
anything you would see in actual soil
and uh it's really important to
distinguish between living soil and real
soil uh I can't emphasize that enough
they're very different they it's like an
apple and a banana or something or you
know whatever two very distinctly
different things yes both can grow
plants but they do it entirely different
ways um and that's probably a separate
podcast but I I just think it's an
important thing to to remind folks of
yeah yeah definitely I'll also mention
that um like for example when I fertig
and we we talked about this earlier when
I ferate micronutrient sulfates so just
going kind of tying this around when I
need more manganese
sulfate maybe I'll put in 10 pounds per
acre in an application I always add a
carbon some kind of carbon Source
whether that's
molasses or kelp or usually it's humic
acids that I dissolve
overnight or even citric acid it's
carbon based so
so I always am aiming to apply carbon
with any application that I do and it's
really easy to do that as an organic
grower you just you just do the things I
just said and most people are very
familiar with this a compost extract or
if you're top dressing you know
something you can apply with a little
compost and then once that goes into
your soil like you said in a living soil
system there's so many carbon fractions
in there um from there's a lot of
soluble carbon a lot of active carbon a
lot of longer chained inactive carbon
compounds and our compost and our Pete
MTH so a lot of this is just happening
in our living soils naturally um so it's
not essential to necessarily do that
because as soon as it hits our soil it's
a giant carbon sponge um but in a top
soil system I think it makes a lot of
sense especially in fertigation but it
we don't necessarily need to buy bottled
products that are carbon based because
we can just add a little humic acid or
fulvic acid or molasses and do it
ourselves very very cool so last
question um I know we kind of went over
some of your
favorite nitrogen inputs already and how
you like to have multiple sources we
talked a little about your favorite
calcium inputs can you just give me and
I don't want to you know dive too deep
into this but just some of your favorite
uh
phosphorus and um magnesium I mean well
I already know the one for magnesium but
go ahead yeah just some of your other
major essential nutrient amendments like
what you like to
use yeah sure so
magnesium
um really I I only think of two one is
Epsom salt and one is lonite and lonite
I only use when potassium is also needed
it's kind of a it's kind of a niche use
case honestly um it's probably only
about 10% of my recommendations or less
so when I think plants need magnesium I
immediately go to Epsom salt and I and I
immediately go to Epsom salt in foler
that's the first thing I think about
it's complet it's totally inexpensive
and it's super effective in foler and so
the first thing I do is I hit my plants
with a with an Epsom salt foler and if
they respond positively it usually is an
indicator that indeed they're low in
magnesium and then only then I would
think about a soil dredge
um yeah that I think that covers mag
magnesium pretty well I like to run
magesium on the low side so I do think
Growers I work would tend to see
magnesium hunger because I like to just
run it kind of on the lower end of the
spectrum uh because I like to Max
maximize calcium and potassium uptake um
and it's so easy to feed that I don't
necessarily want to load my slow with
magnesium it's better to keep it low and
apply it as needed I do I have found
that different strains vary pretty
widely in their magnesium requirements
so some of them just just get hungry for
it kind of like a tomato Tomatoes like
it um what were you going to say oh I
just want to add that I rarely see
magnesium deficiencies on living soils
where you know if you have if you're
mixing a living soil you don't need to
add a magnesium input you're probably
getting enough magnesium from your
compost and other inputs um I would just
hesit I I would not add magnesium unless
you have a test showing you need
magnesium because it has a lot of
antagonisms like you kind of alluded to
there um it's going to it's going to
typically raise your pH with most of the
things you're going to add for it and
it's going to potentially tighten soil
not really the same thing in living
soils but just something that I want to
caution users about it's much easier to
add more you can't really remove it very
effectively yeah I would I would add to
what you're saying just to to say that I
I
would I think I probably see excess
magnesium five to 10 times more
frequently than I see uh uh deficiency
of magnesium so I'm way more common in
my recommending Growers leech excess
magnesium out of their soil and stop the
use of all magnesium inputs then I am
seeing a deficiency um I want to add
though oh sorry with certain LED lights
I do sometimes seem to see uh more
magnesium hunger in certain cultivars
and I haven't found an exact correlation
there the first time I heard that I
didn't believe it but um I'm at the
point now where I'm starting to see a
lot more of this anecdotally and I think
it I think it's really a thing that's
interesting yeah yeah I mean I I I
see yeah I I do think magnesium hunger
is quite common visually um and that's
why I like that foler application I I I
believe that works really really well in
in addressing light magnesium hunger um
um but yeah the LED thing is interesting
i' I I
haven't I don't have much experience
with
that or I haven't noticed that at least
so it's good to it's good to think about
that I wonder how that would be I think
it's a spectral thing or maybe it's
related somehow I don't think it has
related to temperature but those are the
only two big differences between LED
lights and uh other light sources is you
get less uh Leaf less rays and leaf
surface temperature and potentially a
slightly different Spectrum interesting
yeah fascinating um I'm sure I have more
thoughts on magnesium but let's let's
move on to
phosphorus in
In Living soil I really like to get most
or all of my phosphorus in the soil
ahead of the cycle through Dry
amendments I think that's the the best
way to do it I mean everything's going
to bring in some phosphorus depending on
your compost Source that's going to
provide quite a bit again slowly
mineralizing over time and then
otherwise my go-tos are bone meal and
softrock phosphate I used to recommend a
lot of fish bone meal but um which has a
percent higher nitrogen than bone meal
much better micronutrients but higher
sodium so I like to and and actually a
little bit less phosphorus so you're
getting more sodium more micronutrients
and more nitrogen per unit of phosphorus
so I just go with bone meal it's a
little cleaner um in that in that
sense and and heavy metals is also a
consideration there um I haven't seen
High heavy metal levels in really any
bone meal
so I like to have really sort of luxury
levels of of organically bound
phosphorus in in my soil at the time of
of
transplant but there's two sources I can
think about organic sources of liquid
phosphorus if you want to feed
additional phosphorus one is a high
phosphorous fish and it is a brand name
it's called sea fos
um and I still don't know how it's
allowed in organic production because
instead of stabilizing the fish with
sulfuric acid they stabilize it with
phosphoric acid and that pushes that
that uh phosphorus phosphate number up
to 7% so that's a really good tool in
the toolbox and the other thing I can
think of which is a little bit new this
is another update I've been testing tons
of jadam and KF inputs so
um f you know ferments
and
uh yeah primar I guess primarily
ferments jlf but just different plant
juices and the one Trend across the
board is that soluble phosphorus is
really high in um fermented plant juices
which is very interesting so I don't
recommend it I don't use it but it is it
is is a use case for these um ferments
is they're able to liberate quite a bit
of phosphorus I would say the other
nutrient levels are
are somewhat underwhelming once you
dilute them to their recommended
dilution rates um but phosphorus can be
you know somewhere like 60 parts per
million in some of these um fermented
plant juices so yeah I think that's sort
of interesting to mention I've seen
cannabis jlf concentrate that tests at
27 parts per million of phosphorus now
all of these levels are going to depend
on the nutrient status of the plant
being used in the ferment um but that's
significant so if you diluted that at
let's say 1 to 20 you'd have a a a
pretty healthy phosphorus application
that's soluble but all this can be a
little bit of a moot point in the sense
that Tad you still there sorry everyone
this is when my internet cutout I was
really looking forward to this
discussion and I wanted to share some of
my feedback on uh ferment tests that
I've gotten back from Growers uh
actually showing pretty high chlorides
and sodium so um maybe that's something
that we can dive into together in a
later conversation or possibly on
Instagram live or YouTube live but um
I'll definitely be following up with
Bryant and I really appreciated this
interview that was Bryant Mason and you
are listening to the canab cultivation
and science podcast don't forget to
check out the podcast page at
www.k organics.com just click on the
learn tab then podcast and just a
friendly reminder that we have a patreon
Channel with a free 7-Day trial and
teers as low as $5 a month we do book
club special cultivation tips and tricks
monthly video hangouts to connect and
share your grow and even give out seed
packs and other gifts at certain tier
levels in fact Steve Solomon is going to
be joining us for our last meeting on
the intelligent gardener book to answer
any tips or any questions we may have
about his book so lots of fun stuff
happening there and your support of
patreon or sourcing your products
through kiss Organics is what supports
the podcast and I really appreciate it
thanks for
listening