[Music]
so
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast i'm your host tadd
hussey of kiss organics this is the
podcast where we discuss the cutting
edge of growing from a science-based
perspective and drawing top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge
my guest this week is lee brees lee is
an independent crop consultant from
central north dakota he provides
agronomic advice to help farmers build
customized systems to grow and manage
crops profitably he specializes in
helping farmers adopt practices to
protect and improve their soil and local
environment including reduced till
no-till cover crops crop rotation and
increased plant and economic diversity
now on to the show
hey lee thanks for coming on the show
today
[Music]
hello
hey can we uh start off talking a little
bit about your background and uh sort of
what you do for a living
yeah sounds good so what i do for a
living is i'm a i'm an agricultural crop
consultant i actually work directly with
farmers to provide uh agricultural
advice and i tell everybody i'm a plant
doctor and i don't just mean that
metaphorically i actually went to school
and have that degree i have a doctor of
plant health from the university of
nebraska
but what i do is i work with farmers and
i go out and check their fields
and do regular checkups just like you
would think of it a doctor
and it's very similar to human beings
when they're small they need more
checkups and more more close attention
and as they get older they need a little
bit less attention so i do that so i
weekly check the farmers crops and look
for pests and diseases and problems and
environmental problems and all those
types of things and if we do find some
things that write prescriptions whether
they be fertility prescriptions or
practice prescriptions or whatever to
help them manage those situations and we
maintain it all the way through the
season
so you've probably seen a lot over the
years
how do you approach a given situation um
are there any you know critical things
that you look for when stepping onto a
new plot of land or we're starting to
work with a new farmer
yeah that's a great question i'm a very
visual and tactile oriented person and
so i really have to spend some time in
that production system and in that field
i actually like to spend a little bit of
alone time and then meet up with the
farmer later and talk about things what
i find is that my viewpoint is a little
bit different than the producers
and so i probably see things in a
different light in a different way and i
may find some things that are
challenging for them that may they may
have just assumed that it just is what
it is and they don't necessarily tackle
it or they may value a particular
problem more than another where i i may
value them differently so the the
combination of the producer and i
working together through these
situations seems to be very very
beneficial
you know i know there are a fair number
of consultants out there that will just
look at a
soil test or a biological test and make
their recommendations or determinations
around that
you know what percentage of
would you say
of your decision making is based off of
a test versus what you you know what you
see in the field and actually spending
that time
you know on site
while you ask hard questions okay so
um
yeah so the test is important it's an
actual measurement that you know we're
doing this but for me a soil test the
ones that i'm doing primarily are
straight up chemical analysis so we're
looking at fertility levels that's the
main thing that the test shows me so
that's that's important but the type of
soil and the lay of the land the
topography of it and all of that
influences how fertility moves and how
it's released a sandy soil versus a
higher clay soil or a steep slope versus
a shallow
flat field those all make the
differences on how that nutrient is
going to be utilized and how it's going
to be available and so those types of
things are critically important i'm
going to say about 50 50. but there's
also a point where i've spent enough
time on the farm so in the beginning
it's 50 50 but i think once we get into
it i mean there's this continuous note
taking going on right every time i'm out
in this field i'm taking mental notes
and i'm taking actual physical notes
writing things down and as i do this
over time my things change a little bit
and so then i adapt them to that
specific thing so then yes the chemical
analysis is still important but it
becomes a little bit less important over
time
as we see how the things fit in that
particular field or position
um so you mentioned that you
you primarily use a chemical analysis
can we talk a little bit about
biological analysis um
absolutely
what experience do you have with that or
or what benefit if any do you see
associated with it because
that's a question we get a lot
yeah there's a lot of it out there
um
you know i think scientists tend to
overdo this this
their particular field is the greatest
place to discover new things and i'm no
different i'm a soil scientist i think
there's a great amount of things for us
to discover in soils we simply don't
know yet and i think biology is that big
reserve of
kind of this cloudy hazy thing that we
we kind of know some of the things that
are going on but we certainly don't know
everything that's going on
and the other thing that's difficult
with biology is that when we're talking
about things we're talking about entire
kingdoms the differences right we're
talking about bacteria we're talking
about archaea and they're talking about
fungi and that's the highest level of
organismal order and so we're talking
about huge differences and when you
think about bacteria you're talking
about things on hours minutes and days
and versus fungi you were talking about
days weeks and months
and so
those life cycles affect it so
my my caveat with biological analysis
is as much as when you're doing the
analysis
as what kind of analysis you're doing
and i think i don't have a problem with
analysis because i think they've been
well tested they've been there's
established protocols and all that kind
of thing but if you take a poor sample
or you take a sample at a timing that's
different for a specific
biological indicator you're going to get
wildly different things so for example a
cold soil versus a warm soil or
a wet soil versus a at the end of a
drought
you're going to see some very different
things because biology responds to all
of those things versus a chemical
analysis is pretty straightforward and
this is
you know it's going to be a similar
thing in both situations so i think
there's a lot of things there's there's
the co2 respiration
there is uh pflas which are actual you
know genetic testing looking for markers
and to see who's all in there and i
think these are really interesting
things to pursue
so we can do this we can find out who's
in there at the time that you sampled
and under those conditions
but i don't know that we clearly
understand which ones we want to
cultivate or promote at any given point
in time yet we're not really sure what
their involvement is or how they work or
who's important who we want
you know if we're going to sort them to
the good guys and bad guys who's on
which team i don't think we're quite
there yet
yeah what i also hear you saying too is
it may not give you actionable
information in terms of um how you're
approaching your land i mean you could
say hey this soil should be more
biologically active you know even given
the fact that
you know it hasn't rained recently or
we're at this point in the season
but do you find that that really changes
the way you manage that soil i mean um
like for me my perspective is like i'm
going to be doing these things to
promote good biological activity anyway
you know
and let's talk about organic matter next
year
because i know that that really can go
hand in hand in a lot of cases
so so i don't find it it only gives me a
ton of you know actionable information
and i do also feel like when we talk
strictly about sets of organisms like
fungal versus bacterial and and what
those ratios may be
it's
it's too macroscopic of a view
to really
um
to really know what goes on i think we
we need our level of uh knowledge to
increase to where we can really start
looking at these species and how they
interact with particular crops and how
they interact with each other it's just
it's it's such a complex system right
it almost feels like an over over
simplification to me but you know what
are your thoughts on that
no i agree i think it is an
oversimplification and i think it's it
is this complex wild jungle and i think
there's a point in time when we're
trying to cultivate the antelope and the
lions are just gobbling them up right
and so that's fine if that's what your
goals are but i really don't i agree
these things aren't necessarily
actionable yet
i'm not saying it's not worthwhile to
try to catalog some of the stuff so
doing some type of regular analysis
potentially yearly analysis and again i
would do it under similar conditions and
similar time frames both you know
spatially temporarily and within your
production system so that it's it's it's
a repeated repetitive thing so you're
trying to measure the same point in time
the same kind of thing going on and then
you can maybe track some changes
potentially um but again what what
you're going to do about that i don't
know i think a lot of the things that
you're going to do you're going to do
anyway like you said you're trying to
you're trying to manage your organic
matter you're trying to manage your
cover you're trying to manage your water
you're trying to manage your nutrient
availability your ph's and all these
kinds of things to make sure that your
crop has the best and i think really the
best biological indicator
for us as people are the ones that are
easiest to see and i think your crop is
one of those when you have a healthy
well-producing crop i think it tells you
a lot about what's going on in the soil
and i'm not sure that we need to know
all of those details i i think that
little black box can stay black
if you have a healthy crop i mean that's
our ultimate goal why not measure that
rather than all of these
secondary indicators
yeah so i've stolen these and i can't
even give credit because it's so long
ago but uh so organic matter is composed
of you know three types of basic things
and it would be the living so the live
organisms the stuff that's going on and
and there and then it's the recently
dead the things that you can easily
identify you can see it's a plant or a
piece of a leaf or or or whatever and
then there's the the really dead they
call it which is the the dark colors and
you it's no longer distinguishable but
we know it's not a mineral we know that
it came from organic and it's not a it's
not a mineral so those are the three
kind of pools of organic matter and
those are all part of the deal and a lot
of people will call the long-term stuff
the humus
what's interesting is that after we
talked i looked into this more
and there's been some new science on
humus and the idea of long-term stable
organic matter and that may not be as
long-term as we originally thought
they've come up with new tools and
tactics to measure it we're measuring it
in different ways and prior to this
we've used a very harsh chemical
analysis
and then what came out of that at the
end was these very stable
compounds these organic matter compounds
when you use a really really strong acid
to dissolve things you change it
significantly and when it recombines it
combines into some very
strong structures
they've gone to using some microscopic
type of things as technologies improved
and they see that they think that this
longer term organic matter that the
really dead stuff that we can't identify
what it is may actually cycle quite a
bit faster than they thought it done
so that's quite interesting but um
again i don't know that it matters a
whole lot right
so so when i'm assessing soil i like to
i like to take a shovel i like to dig a
little hole i look for color i look for
structure or the pyramid ability the
ability of water to move through it the
ability of roots to move through it and
then i i love to smell that right i like
to get that earth and smell and see what
that smells like that smells good to us
and i wonder if that isn't an
evolutionary
thing for human beings that we're able
to smell good earth we understand what
that means
that those that didn't maybe didn't do
so well and so i think um part of that
is just this idea of this whole using
your senses to understand
what's going on and i think that
qualitative assessment can sometimes be
really really important and in certain
situations as important more important
than
a quantitative assessment because
quantitative only measures one thing at
a time versus when you or i are out
there with a shovel and a handful of
soil we're measuring and evaluating
several things at once
so you're almost like a detective
you know using those qualitative tools
and then the quantitative tools to
figure out whatever that limiting factor
of growth is
in regards to
plant health or maybe the farmer's
priorities um
you know those sorts of things right
yeah and so and i don't mean it to be
all you know fairy tales and rainbows
type of thing here but honestly when i'm
talking about we can measure you know
soil density and that type of thing and
bulk density of the soil it can be
measured and that tells us about pore
space and water permeability and all
those types of things or you can take a
shovel and you can put it into the soil
and you can feel the differences
between a compacted soil that has very
little pore space it's hard it's been
driven on your driveway versus
a really well-grown prairie native land
or trees or you know we have that
feeling and we can feel that as much
with a shovel and do that qualitatively
and understand what's going on so this
is something and it's actually much more
rapid than trying to take an analytical
test now i use the analytical test to
back up these qualitative
measurements right because
i need to calibrate it some way
if i'm in a good mood i tend to measure
things a little more optimistically if
i'm having a rough day it may not be
quite so optimistic
so i have to make sure that i calibrate
it a little bit
i think it's really the combination of
the factors and then it's it's fitting
these pieces together in a specific
set to make it fit that particular
piece of land that particular farm that
particular goal set
you know for people who are unfamiliar
with
determining soil texture
you know i went to the issa meeting a
couple years back
and they had a booth there where people
could do essentially the soul ribbon
test and to determine you know the
the fractions of uh sand silt and clay
in the soil and and
some people are are quite accurate at
doing this
you know very close to what a you know
what a full analysis would tell you um
it's it's pretty fascinating so while it
is qualitative i will say you know i'm
not very good at it myself but it was it
was fun to see people that were
right and it's again this is a practice
and time thing and an experience thing
yeah and so i think once you so you got
to start somewhere you got to start at
the beginning yeah and so going to a
booth where they have okay this is a
high clay soil this is a high silt soil
this is a high sand saw gets you started
and then as you practice with it and
then you again you double check with
laboratory analysis so i do i do that
ribbon analysis everywhere i go i don't
necessarily like
write the numbers down 30 clay and 20
silts and you know that type of thing
but i've always have it in my hand
when i've taken the soil up i dig it up
i've got it in my hand i'll perform the
ribbon analysis the other thing that
i'll look at that is very difficult to
measure in the lab we can do it is the
soil aggregates those little chunks
those little nubbins and you'll hear
people talk about soil should look like
chocolate cake or should have little
lego blocks in them rather than just be
this massive fluff you'd rather not have
it as flour
because all of those little aggregates
are
they're individual cities and universes
for all these things when you think
about the scale of bacteria
they they need small places or
microscopic organisms so within one of
these little aggregates
there's all kinds of different
spaces for them to live i really think
about it as a city so there's a downtown
where things are very dense and
congested and then there's there's kind
of that outskirts or the the area the
suburban area around the outside then
you get into the more rural area on the
outside of this aggregate
and to be quite honest with you there
are different biological things that
want to live in all of those different
spaces
and it has to do with you know oxygen
contents and water contents and nutrient
availability and all that kind of stuff
so those aggregates provide several
little cities with many many many
environments for different types of
biology
versus a fluffy soil that's more like
flower is a different type of landscape
it's much more uniform
it may be easier for us to manage
physically with planting equipment or
harvesting equipment and that type of
thing but it's not near as biologically
active as those little aggregates with
cities that have all these different
environments for those things and when
you look at it as a microbe if you're a
bacteria trying to move a millimeter
isn't a possibility it's like me trying
to walk to across the country from
california to new york i just simply
can't do it in a in a reasonable time
frame
so
those are things that are easy to see
and assess and then you put them in your
fingers and you you start to crush them
how strong are they how stable are they
now we can measure all of this in a lab
but you have to be careful in how you
take it you send it to lab and then they
do a water shake test and it takes some
time they'll give you the aggregate size
fractions large ones medium small that
type of thing but we can do this right
in the field with a shovel with a little
bit of practice so we've determined
texture
then we can determine aggregate
stability and that leads into water and
we've also determined bulk density and
all we needed was a shovel
so you're looking at in this case the
physical properties of the soil and then
from there you would turn to the sort of
the chemical properties and that's where
that lab test comes in handy
and then then we're then i'm
making assumptions
for the biology based on the physical
knowing that that
this aggregates kind of the build it and
they will come thing like if you give
them the environment the biology can
prosper in a better way
and i'm i'm not necessarily advocating
no-till for everything but you know
tillage is a necessary tool for us to
manage our crops and to do things in the
right ways where it's possible where you
can reduce that and maintain stable
aggregates it helps with your biology
it's one of the things that helps with
the biology
significant tillage
again and again and again is is
challenging for biology and this is
where you'll see some of those ratios
change i think this is what people try
to use them for he's like well if your
bacterial ratio is getting really high
those are the ones again the short life
cycle
they re
they rebound much faster
they can rebound in a few days versus
a fungi that you've taken and some of
them see my seal you're inches long and
you grind them up into these little
stubs well it's going to take them a lot
longer to regenerate and regrow and
their life cycles longer so you'll see
that if you do a pfla you'll see your
bacterial analysis will be much higher
than your fungal analysis and it might
be related to just you had to do tillage
and so does that mean you did the wrong
thing for your soil i don't know that it
does you may have needed to do that for
your production system
but if you measured it at that time you
may see that this is again a temporal
thing when you're measuring what you're
doing so all of these things that most i
can't see the bacteria but i can smell
them this is that good earth smell this
is the actinomyces bacteria
actinomycetes are their own little group
and those are
breaking down
organic compounds and they're releasing
specific aromatic compounds that we can
smell and we smell it as good earth
and that just means that your biology
biologically functioning i've been in
some soils that have a high salt content
just naturally and there's very little
if no smell to them at all
it's really because the salts are
preventing that biology from being
highly active
yeah you mentioned high salt so i mean
one of the things about be dealing with
outdoor crops is you kind of are stuck
with the conditions that you're stuck
with whether that's you know i've i've
seen high calcium
i've seen high salt
how do you approach these things so so
when you're testing you're testing
you're doing chemical analysis not just
on the um
the soil but the water as well
uh typically no this is undried soil um
but we can definitely do a chemical
analysis on water it's not something
that we do routinely one of the ways
that we measure salts or saline soils
here is actual electrical conductivity
and so we can do that in situ so this
isn't even sent to the lab so they have
a machine that
injects it
puts out an electrical current and so
electrical current and then it receives
how much comes through so we're actually
looking at conductance it's the inverse
resistance basically so what's going on
as long as we have a little bit of water
for the wire or the conduit that will
conduct electricity and the more solutes
you have the more salts you have the
more electricity gets conducted
so you'll have a higher reading and so
that's how
salts are typically measured is through
electrical conductivity that can be in
them done in the lab or in situ in the
field
so we can measure those things and then
the salts what they do is they really
it's pretty straightforward in most
cases
is it's just an osmotic thing the high
salts and the plants can't get the water
it acts like a drought as the salt pulls
harder than the plant can so then they
can't get moisture there are a few
situations where a specific ion will
interfere with other ions
and cause some issues or really high
concentrations of chloride per se can
become plant toxic that way
but it's typically a
drought inducing situation for us
yeah we use soluble salts or ec to
measure on the saturated paste to sort
of see what level of fertility we're
starting at
in uh you know indoor with
essentially potting soils or soilless
media
but it's a very different situation
because typically we can keep our sodium
content
you know substantially lower so we're
looking at what fraction of that is
actually sodium but
but we're also realizing that you know
this tells us sort of our fertility in
in some ways sure
it does because it's related to your
canada exchange capacity it really
relates directly because those charges
help conduct that electricity as well
so uh you know what are some examples of
when uh you feel like tillage is
important in a production system
so for me one of the main things um
tends to be a disease management type of
thing so while i'm
i'm a fan of
residue cover in in you know production
agricultural fields i don't like wind
erosion i don't like water version right
so so the plant material the biomass
from the previous crop is a really good
way to protect that soil or armor it
from heavy rainfall or high wind events
but it's also the perfect place for
the fungi and bacteria and those
microorganisms to survive and
proliferate and be ready for next year's
crop and to attack you
so there are times when we
we need to manage the residue and i
think that's part of it and and how
aggressive you get is is
there are grades right it doesn't have
to go all the way from complete
annihilation of all soil structure and
all plant material
there are grades across that and again
this is individual specific situations
what are you trying to accomplish is the
following crop going to be susceptible
to the potential diseases or did you use
that as one of your tools using a crop
that's not as susceptible to that
disease so then you don't have to worry
so much about that breakdown component
that type of thing the other time where
in production in particular where we're
using tillage as a tool is when we've
had to do field operations when we
shouldn't be there
when it's too wet
often we have too much moisture but the
crop is in jeopardy of being lost to the
weather and we simply have to physically
go out there and get it and with leave
tracks and ruts and
in the field and
some compaction and if you've moved soil
and you've made impressions with heavy
equipment out there
it's not going to just magically
disappear you have to move the soil to
fill that in and to make another level
playing space
so again we're using it targeted that
way when
when we've made a
a management decision that we need to go
do something
and we've caused a problem and we're
using it as partial fix
so that's typically what i'm doing
uh tillage is used much more broadly in
my region um and it's used to manage
water primarily
um so fall moisture so guys are doing
tillage this fall here now getting ready
to reduce the moisture so that next year
it's drier to plant into and they can
they can plant easier under good
conditions
there are other ways to do that
increasing your infiltration rate using
some cover crops but again they have
their own drawbacks too
so
what essentially what i'm hearing is
that none of these things are black and
white uh you know tillage isn't always
bad it isn't always good we need to look
at each situation
sort of
each field is as its own
you know
in its own light i guess
now you've led me right into my tag line
my my my details matter i i tend to use
that
i was telling you i have i have a
sticker with my ugly face on it that
says details matter and i think that's
really the important part of this whole
thing is that
you can you can get really good advice
from someone who has a little bit
different production system they can
tell you exactly how everything's
working
and and works for them and it's all
wonderful and then you go home and you
try to do it and you have a different
system or you have a different challenge
or you your problems are not that type
of priority or your logistics don't work
out that way
and so really fitting those things and
getting that information is critically
valuable it's really valuable to get
information from other people from other
sources from good science-based sources
and you know locally and get great
distances so that you can try new ideas
and try new things
but it's also critically important to
apply that directly i use the dieting
thing um i need to lose some weight i'm
overweight and i know it but
um i can't
there's certain foods that i i just
don't like and i won't eat and and that
type of thing so i have to fit this into
my system and if we talk about okay we'd
love to exercise so exercise is a great
part of personal health okay well that's
great but are you going to run are you
going to walk are you going to swim are
you going to bike what are you gonna do
how does it fit into your life what time
frame do you have can you go for an hour
on a half on a long walk or do you have
20 minutes and you need a treadmill like
those are the specifics
to each individual situation whether
it's the farm the farmer or the the acre
or that little small plot of land
those are the specifics that everything
has to be applied to
so for me i go for walks because i have
the time and i can do that and i tend to
do that at work rather than driving
around i'll just go walk across the
field so i'm getting more steps in and
i'm still doing two things at once
if you asked me to swim i would drown so
it's never going to work
so
no wonder swimming is a great way to
burn a lot of calories in a short period
of time but i don't swim so it's a very
poor fit for me
so it's along these same lines is like
you could have really really good ideas
from somewhere else do they fit into
your system do they fit into the
the hard
rules that you have and then the next
question is can you change some of those
things maybe i should learn to swim
right so
that's the next step but that's a bigger
step
when you're trying to change your whole
logistics and your whole production
system for a particular practice because
it sounds really good i would caution
people about doing a lot of that be very
careful
well you and i talked about using
science too and
you know we may see research that shows
something to be really promising
you know in a lab or
in a in a trial field that but we can't
necessarily take that information and
apply it across our own farm or our own
given situation um
basically what you're saying is there's
a little more due diligence we need to
do before committing to a new idea right
right yeah i mean science is a is a
system of probability and this was the
thing that i mentioned earlier is that i
think people under have this idea that
well science says this it means exactly
that
when we actually use statistics and it's
all about probability so a lot of times
it's like well you've got a 95 chance
this is the outcome you're going to get
if you do these things
but it's it's not only if you just do
these things but if you do these things
with these certain situations in a
certain area so sciences tends to be
done in a very specific way
now that's not wrong what it's doing is
taking a lot of variables away so that
when they change one thing they're
trying to make sure that's the only
thing that changes so that that's the
actual change they measure
now in a production system we can't
manage all of those things to that level
where this is the only that is actually
changed and sometimes when you do add a
new practice you've had to change
several other things to do that like if
you were going to do less tillage well
you've done less tillage but that's also
changed your water profile it's changed
your nutrient profile it's changed the
oxygenation has changed your aggregates
it's changed a lot of things that you
didn't intend it to change
so even though a producer did one
different practice it actually could
change
multiple things that are hard to track
so i think people need to understand
that science is a very good starting
point and it's critically important i
would much rather have that than rumors
or wive tales or
you know somebody exaggerating how great
their stories are and we hear that too
and i think those are all dangerous so
we need the science to back that up but
then the application so this is me i'm
an applied scientist so i i go and get
the science and then i try to fit it to
those scenarios and there are times when
really promising science doesn't fit in
a particular area
i had mentioned earlier we were talking
about cover crops before we started here
and and we talked about how they can be
a really really good tool but if you
live in a very arid place where water is
your absolute most limiting factor a
cover crop could be a very poor decision
for you
because it's going to take your most
valuable resource and use it for
something other than crop production
and that
that alone might be enough to say this
is not a good practice for us it doesn't
mean that cover crops are a bad practice
it just may not fit in that scenario
and how do you go about your cover crop
selection or determination
right
excellent so
my area makes a difference so i'm in in
north dakota and we have very cold
temperatures
the first thing we start off with though
is what are we trying to fix what are we
trying to manage what are we trying to
do with something with and i have
probably three or four main goals
one of those is erosion protection so to
help me from wind and water erosion
another one is to actually manage excess
moisture we might have too much moisture
for the next spring and then the third
one will have poor producing soils or
those saline soils we've talked about
we're trying to do something different
with them
but basically once you've figured out
what your goal is what you're going to
try to do it's much easier to help you
select a crop
because then you can figure out which
one's going to do what you want them to
do so for the moisture usage like if we
have excess moisture i try to use a crop
that's going to be there
more often
when i can't grow anything else so we'll
use a winter cereal like cereal rye up
here that we'll plant in the fall of the
year it'll grow in the fall use some
moisture in the fall it'll overwinter in
our harsh winters and it'll be growing
next spring early on when we have snow
melt and heavy rainfall and it'll help
us manage that excess moisture then we
can use
tillage or herbicides to terminate it
and plant our regular crop
so that's a really good fit
but if we're trying to do something
different it may not be the right fit
and there are times when cereal is a bad
fit simply because the following crop is
going to be affected by it so i don't
like to see producers plant
corn after cereal rye because the cereal
is very competitive and very aggressive
and it can actually hurt their corn
yield but if we're going to plant
soybean it's it's absolutely a great
idea
so this is those details matter what are
you actually going to do with it what
are you trying to get out of it and once
you've set a goal like i want to manage
moisture i want to reduce excess
moisture then it's much easier for you
to measure that both empirically and
observationally
it's much easier to see if you just want
to plant cover crops for a healthier
soil
well what does that mean it's very hard
to measure in any way
i i really like that
explanation
this is a little bit outside of you know
your area of
of work
but i get a lot of people running cover
crops indoors and when we talk about the
reasons why we use cover crops that you
listed there you know most of those
don't really apply like we don't have
the same
water challenges we don't have wind
erosion
um
you know we don't have these things and
and while cover crops are are wonderful
this is sort of where you get into that
you know it's not so it's not so black
and white like what is our goal because
when we talk about fertility well now we
just added a whole other variable that's
a lot harder to measure
versus being able to add a specific
fertilizer
to to get whatever you know macro or
micronutrient we're looking for now
we're trying to
you know gauge the breakdown of this of
this organic matter this cover crop you
know we have competition for nutrient
now with our actual crop because people
want to run them not as a as a separate
crop but as a as a
as a poly cropping essentially companion
plant
and then we have
you know disease and habitat concerns
for pests
it becomes a little bit of a nightmare
on scale you know i think it works fine
in a small tent and there are some
people that are doing it on scale but
it's it's rare and i think it's a you
know
i i feel like as a
as a gardener um or a farmer what we can
do to eliminate
you know labor eliminate or reduce labor
sorry and reduce variability
makes it easier for us to make decisions
on our crop if we're applying you know
50 different things and spraying all
these different things like we see some
guys do
it's hard to know what's good what's bad
what's um
innocuous
in this in the system like that it's
it's very complex and when i come on
onto the scene you know when they tell
me well i did this this and this
i haven't done a soil test you know
what's going on with my plant i
i really i really can't say there's too
many there's too many if there i
couldn't say there's no way and and i
think really this is you know when
you're when you're talking about this is
risk management right so you're trying
to manage your risk um because at the
end we want these people to all be
effective in
economically beneficial businesses we
want every business to survive and
thrive
so
really that's about risk management and
in the situation you described where you
actually have control over erosion you
have control over the water you have
control over the nutrients
that's a very different thing so those
are the things i don't have control over
so i'm using
the cover crops to help manage that risk
for us but you're taking those really
right off your risk plate and now you
add all of those alternatives and and
honestly all of these these additional
crops have their own biological
benefits but they also have their own
attractions like it's it's the idea of
when there's a lot of anything there's
going to be whatever eats it is going to
be proliferating
so disease can be a significant issue
and unfortunately a lot of our fungal
disease in particular are very good at
adapting to several hosts
and i'm very concerned about that too
for us for so white mold is one of the
problems that we have i would imagine
some of your producers have white mold
challenges and it's got a very wide um
host range
so a lot of different plants can
proliferate that and increase that and
that's something that's very very
difficult to manage once you get a high
inoculum
population is that essentially the same
thing as powdery mildew are you
referring to a different
white mold i'm referring to sclerotinia
yeah but well okay so white mold powdery
mildew does also have a fairly wide
um
host range and
it likes those high humidity situations
that you're having so yeah you could
definitely increase the inoculum in
there and make that much worse for the
cover crop versus
this is one of the things we do in
agriculture is we actually break natural
cycles
in order to produce a crop specifically
for our needs
yeah and that's i think this is i want
to kind of jump into that you know egg
is not nature even gardening is not
nature um you're trying to produce as
certain
things that you want
and to the exclusion of other things you
don't want this is the whole idea that
we have weeds
you can argue that an invasive species
always a weed but there are a lot of
times when native species are considered
a weed because they're less desirable or
they're hurting your crop or whatever so
um
we're trying we're not we're not trying
to replicate nature
nature produces whatever it can with the
resources it has and it doesn't produce
for any one particular species in
general it produces for everybody and
actually
to any plant
an insect is a predator typically a
caterpillar is always a bad thing to
plants because that's that's who eats
you
so it's not a beneficial thing so it's
about your perspective this again goes
to if you're watching the nature show or
you're cheering for the antelope or
you're cheering for the lion
because they're both biological
organisms
and it just depends on your perspective
in agriculture we're trying to produce
things for one species for humans
and and so that's it's a very narrow
subset so we're trying to stack the deck
in our arts to produce as much as we can
for us
and that's really a sustainability goal
because now we need less acreage and
less less resources in order to do that
so if we're really efficient
at producing what we want for our
species then we're using less in general
versus if we were all trying to forage
out of nature well then we'd have to
compete with everything else
so i think this goes back into those
ideas of like i think it's wise to
control these scenarios and to keep keep
your risk low and not add a bunch of
variables and you're producing a bunch
of other things you're using fertilizer
and water and organic matter resources
to breed disease because you grew a
cover crop
i don't know that that's a wise choice
yeah you know i think i think we have to
be
you know for someone who's passionate
about organics and sustainability i
think we have to be cognizant of where
we're sourcing our materials so if we
are going to use fertilizer how do we do
it in a way
that has less of an impact on our
you know local and world ecology
what industries are we supporting with
where we're sourcing these you know
micro and macro nutrients um
but at the same time adding you know a
cover crop or adding uh
you know a second crop
is it doesn't get us anywhere close to
the diversity and complexity that we
would have in a natural system
we're still essentially monocropping
when we look at you know just how vast
of a difference
in diversity there is
right now i think mono cropping on on
gets a bad rap and i don't know that it
should get as bad a rap as it's getting
um i i
again if it's if it's efficient and it's
producing
what we need it to
at the right timing then i don't know
that it's necessarily like after all bad
thing
um and i think it's just kind of cast is
all evil like monocropping now i'm not a
huge fan of growing the same crop
forever in the same situation the same
but it sometimes it makes sense
one of the challenges there is you're
breeding your diseases your pest
problems are depleting resources if
you're using the same crop it wants the
same demands again and again and again
so i think that can be challenging
but um
it doesn't necessarily i i'm not
convinced monocropping is bad it gets
this really bad rap like it's just a
terrible thing but if it's highly
efficient and highly effective then
maybe it's the right thing to do
there's been a lot of you know negative
press about livestock production
people are saying well why don't we just
use land that we're using for livestock
for crops because there's less
footprint there
well this land is not necessarily
suitable for crop production it's one of
the reasons it's in livestock production
you can't farm it it's either too hilly
too rocky too sandy too light all of
those types of things it needs a
perennial plant and really
the way that we're we're gaining human
benefit from most perennial plants is
through protein animal protein
and livestock has the ability to improve
land as much as it has to destroy land i
would say if it's managed correctly the
way it's managed
exactly and so those are some of your
organic inputs right so if you're using
livestock manures
as part of your fertility but then again
you've got to be careful because if this
we're talking about lettuce production
or we're talking about fresh market
types of things
there are little tag-along biologicals
that we don't want in there salmonella
and
clostridiums and all of that good stuff
so then you use another biological
process composting to to reset that
system so we've changed what type of
biology is there so
now we have biology that's less
threatening to human health
and so i think it's really about it
comes back to management and again your
management has to set goals clear goals
that make sense what are you trying to
accomplish where are you trying to go
what are you trying to get to and how
are you trying to do it and then you can
assess your system and see what are your
challenges your problems your your
bottlenecks
and then you can start to devise some
systems that
target those
and and then move forward this is i
don't think i think that's everything
from gardening a plant in your house to
thousands of acres of crop production is
you really have to have what are you
trying to accomplish
what are your limitations and what are
your plans and strategies to manage them
well you know for
for me what i hear a lot of it's just
it's yield you know people approach this
like a business
they say you know i don't
i don't care about the the methodology
the soil because in this case you know a
lot of people are i'm talking about
indoor production
they just want to know that they're
going to get a yield and then they can
get a price per pound for that yield
and some of that feels short-sighted to
me in some ways because i think we can
create systems that are more sustainable
and allow for lower cost of production
over time
with with our media choices and our
production choices but um you know at
the end of the day what do you do when a
farmer is just i you know just wants
wants to talk about yield
yeah well to me i i hear you on the
yield conversation but i think i think
we need to talk about economic yield and
that's more profitability like it's
really about profit because if you're if
you're producing a huge yield but you
it's cost you a lot of money to produce
it and your profits small
that's still really difficult to run a
business if you can maximize your profit
through some simple situations and
that's that's really where you try to go
and and my farmers talk exactly the same
way as yours do if they want to talk
you'll be you'll be all field and the
the hard part is it's much easier to
compare yield between your neighbor and
your friend and the next guy and the
competitor like that's just one number
to get their actual economics some of
these productions whether they're a big
egg or a small egg they don't know their
cost to production as well as they maybe
should
and then they're not going to share that
open either and
so you can't it's hard to compare
compare profit
i think there are significant gains when
you change some systems and you reduce
some expenses you can maintain or get
very close to the premium yield that you
had
even though you're doing these really
expensive um opportunities we've seen it
in production ag really regularly and
it's more due to tillage and the cost of
big tractors and equipment and tillage
and fuel and electronics stuff that if
we can reduce our tillage we save all
the expenses and we get very similar
yields
um not the same yields without all that
input
so what you're saying is
we have to factor in our expenses and
you know they may you may not know their
cost of labor you may not know their
cost of equipment or infrastructure
to get that
you know larger yield you know if you
can produce
a lower amount
with less cost of production you could
actually be coming out ahead at the end
of the day
yeah i think that detail in every
business matters i think you really need
to i really want people to
to do their profit analysis that's
critically important
and that is a detail that matters to
their business and not necessarily to
their neighbors business
but it's probably the most important
detail
yeah i i that makes a lot of sense i
i i see where people get caught up in
that sort of uh game of who can produce
the most but at the end of the day
that's not necessarily the
important variable in the coffee shop
bragging right and if you want to have
the best yield you'd be the last guy to
tell them what it is
because because who's actually checking
those numbers right
and
we're all susceptible to try to being
better than your neighbor and if you're
the last person to announce their yield
you might just edge it up a hair just to
make sure you get a little better
so
you know and in my industry
what's really important too is crop
quality
depending on the quality of that crop
really in terms of value and how you can
market and sell it um and i think that's
something
that is important when we talk about a
production system
well let's let's move on from that topic
uh and talk a little bit more i wanted
to just jump back to soil testing a
little bit when you look at a chemical
analysis of a soil
what are some particular
you know levers or numbers that you look
at that really stand out when you start
to first begin
you know adjusting uh you know the
fertility in the soil
right for my area
ph is a big one i think any area ph is
going to be something you really want to
have a handle on because it affects the
availability of all your nutrients and
it affects your crop growth so i think
that's a critical one
i look at soluble salts
more because we have excess soluble
salts and it's indicative of some of the
challenges we may have and then i focus
on the macronutrients i really do
nitrogen
phosphorus potassium sulfur and zinc and
i know zinc is considered a
micronutrient but it's on the higher end
of those levels and it tends to be one
of those it's more challenging for us
and again this is related to our phs
in my neighborhood a lot of our ph's are
on the higher side
we're at least seven two and sometimes
we get into seven eight and even eight
eight ph's in some places and that
affects our zinc dramatically so i pay
attention to those and those
interactions oh can i yeah
i want to talk about zinc but can we
uh well first of all i want to ask you a
real point black question regarding uh
ph but then i want to talk a little bit
about how you lower ph so first off
you know i get a lot of guys in organics
uh you know in this in the canvas
industry that say you know ph doesn't
matter i can throw out my ph pen um even
in organics do you feel like ph plays a
role in
in you know optimizing production
well ph is the overriding factor of
nutrient availability
now there's a fairly wide set where ph
is optimized it would be anywhere from
about five eight to six two six four is
really where your ph is where you want
it to be if you're going to choose it
that's where you you'd want to be in
that 6 2
range would be like the perfect ph for
nutrient availability
once you start getting down into the the
low fives you have aluminum toxicities
and you have other issues with
inavailability of that
high end ph you have calcium tying up
phosphorus and zinc and a lot of those
macronutrients and if you have high ph
and you're tying up all the nutrients
you can apply more but they get tied up
and they're not available readily unless
you're using a chelating agent so that's
probably the better way to manage it
so what i find with organics is
ph still matters we just find that a lot
of the practices people are using in
organics may lead them into a ph that
falls within a range i guess essentially
there's more buffering capacity
with uh when you have higher organic
organic matter things like that yeah you
have high organic matter soils it's
going to be in that
that sweet spot of ph and you have
you're going to have a lot more
exchange sites and i can see where
that's going to be
less of a concern
yeah than it would be in a mineral soil
when you're an organic soil it's going
to be less of a concern yeah i can see
that
and you know
with and again i'm talking about
artificial soilless media here uh
potting soils i find sort of for me six
six to six eight is sort of my sweet
spot where the soils want to settle uh
because of a lot of the alkaline inputs
we're using
you know specifically adding biochar uh
the high amounts of calcium in the soil
i have trouble keeping calcium and some
of the cations up when we start dropping
ph below six six
yeah i can see that yep yeah cause
they're gonna they're gonna get
associated with all kinds of other
things going on yeah and calcium is one
of the ways to kind of jack your ph a
little bit right so and carbonate um to
bring that up some limiting and that
type of thing
again retarding solace media it's a very
different thing so that's a little bit
outside of my parameters sure sure no i
do realize they're very different um
creatures and a lot of people don't
realize that
uh
and we have to look at the soil test
differently there's some numbers we just
have to throw out on a soil test because
they're just not
uh calibrated
for not meaning soils yeah
but um how do you so how do you deal
with lower lowering p so i had a
greenhouse situation uh where the
gentleman had a quite a high ph close to
eight uh we were looking at ways to
rapidly lower it and sort of the the
things that i saw mixed results with
people with adding you know peat moss
in terms of what the research shows
whether or not that works again this is
not on the scale that you're used to so
i know these aren't things that you
would normally deal with
or
agricultural sulfur um
things like that like what
what approaches do you take to lower
lower ph you know adding things to the
water
yeah that might be your your best bet
in that scenario so
you're talking about elemental sulfur as
one of those things and that that is so
anything that's going to be of an
acidific nature that's going to
going to grab on and
and leave hydrogen ions behind is going
to do that um
so
nitrogen you know ammonia and nitrogen
can can actually reduce ph
but we're talking about you know the
scale here is ridiculous and before you
you lower your ph much you tend to have
toxic levels of sulfur or nitrogen or
whatever because it takes so much of
that to move it so there is you know so
ph is one of those things that you may
not be paying a lot of attention to but
the buffer ph may be critically
important and that's really how much
abuse your soil can take before the ph
is going to move
um so if you have a wide spread in your
buffer ph you you're you're not going to
be able to move it very far with any
inputs
and a lot of times those inputs are
going to get to the point where they're
going to be
tying up other nutrients or causing
plant toxicity or you know emergence
issues or root growth issues because it
takes so much of that thing to
chemically change the ph of your soil if
you have the ability you might be better
off changing your media
to something a little bit different or
adding some other type of media base
maybe it's more vermiculite or some
other type of bentonite or some other
type of clay to help
trap some of those ions
those and and to change your ph a little
bit that way
but uh the
solution is probably the easiest way to
do that
now i haven't seen
uh
sulfur toxicity with with cannabis
specifically are you seeing
excessive sulfur really being an issue
with other crops i mean again i'm not
adding
uh you know high concentrations
every cycle
um and you know a cycle for us would be
two to three months but we're adding a
little bit and slowly over time lowering
the the ph
yeah well then you're you're doing it
really well uh no what i'm talking about
in our agricultural so we have a lot of
high ph cells we have some stuff that
gets up in that eight five eight eight
range
and they've done research on it for here
and and and we're talking about you know
per acre uh beyond the order of
elemental sulfur now five tons per acre
which is just this ridiculous amount of
sulfur
yeah it can move the ph a little bit but
the buffer ph kicks back in in a few
years it kind of bounces back
so it's become not only economically
unviable but that level of sulfur is
just
excessive to the point that it retards
plant growth
um so
if you're doing it with your solution
over time with your nutrient balances
and you're maybe maybe you're giving it
just a little extra kick once a while to
try to do that then i think you're being
very successful
the other thing is you know and i don't
know i this is again a little bit aside
my parameters is that you know saturated
calcium solutions can help
change some things sometimes too or or
just a high leaching like leaching your
soils may
may move something for you but that's
that's a guess and so i shouldn't even
say that
yeah we've used leaching for nitrates
uh potassium sodium you know some of
those more mobile nutrients and soils
and had good success with that you know
some of our guys will even just reset
their beds by
you know watering leaching through them
a specific amount of water and then that
allows them to put a
you know the same
nutrient load back into the soil kind of
giving you a reset close to zero and
that's that's worked well for some for
some growers that i work with but um
yeah i i see what you're saying so how
do you what do you do if you're you know
in actual soil
you have a ph of let's say seven five or
higher
um
how do you begin to manage a crop on
land like that
so we actually have gone to the point of
we're using some chelated nutrients so
the the most
problematic situation when we have high
ph
is we're going to have iron availability
issues now and our soils are made on a
wire like it's one of the main
constituents but when you have a high ph
this causes that in availability the
iron becomes inavailable and one of the
most susceptible crops we will grow is
soybeans you'll see iron chlorotic
soybeans it's called iron deficiency
chlorosis
and it's related to the high ph of that
soil and also the water content
but really the answer there is if you
have significant iron problems in your
soybean
you can try a chelated nutrient which is
you know instead of
that iron being attracted to the soil
particles we have a chelate that fills
all three sites
and it's organic chelate and basically
it makes it more available to the plant
but if you have a significant issue the
answer is don't grow soybean
that is literally the right answer so
it's one of those things where you just
have to you reach a point where
okay we can change some things
but there's a lot of things that simply
are not worth the expense to try to do
it because these chelated nutrients are
extremely expensive
and we need them at a really high rate
at those high ph's
and then they're not long-term stable so
it's not like we can build it up over
time it's just for that season or even
part of that season and it really isn't
isn't cost effective to do it so the
answer is to grow a more tolerant crop
so that's really the answer yeah so you
said you're not really measuring water
how often do you find water see like in
our area here we'll find
in some cases to be pretty alkaline
water or you know dealing with farmers
in oklahoma they have some really bad
water um you know sodium or calcium or
even iron in some cases
uh
great
do you you find that it doesn't really
factor in on the scale no control over
it
oh you can't filter it i don't use it
no i can't filter it and i don't use
irrigation
we're all natural rainfall
so it's one of those things it's not
that it's unimportant i simply have no
control over it so i think that might be
the same thing as your ph is like it
doesn't matter
we can't do anything about it or it
doesn't matter and for us i literally
can't affect it um i have two fields
that have irrigation pivots and
and we can only manage them a certain
way because they're on off-peak electric
and we either they tell us when we can
print them on and when we can't turn
them on
and so we run them as much as we can
when we need them and that's that's the
only thing we can do and overall the
water quality in north dakota is decent
we tend to have high calcium
and high sulfates because again we have
higher ph's we have fairly young soils
that have a lot of those nutrients in
them
so that would be our water quality but
our water quality is pretty good and
most of our water is very potable easily
drinkable water and so it's it's good
for plants we're not carrying a bunch of
dangerous things like what you're
talking about within oklahoma i can
totally see that
that there could be lots of things in
the water that can be problematic for
plants
yeah and you also mentioned um
you know aluminum as you get to a lower
ph that's the other concern is uh the
testing on heavy metals in some of these
states for cannabis is uh pretty pretty
strict and so eliminating
you know heavy metal availability or
filtering it out of any you know sources
whether it's water or fertilizer is
really critical
um
but you know i want to get into zinc
because that's something that i haven't
done
you know i know very little about i
haven't done much research on
i'd be curious to hear
why you mentioned it as a macronutrient
and the importance of it
so zinc in a lot of plants is related to
the reproductive system it's used as a
co enzyme in a lot of scenarios but it's
critically important for reproduction
flower set flower fertility and
pollination
um so it's it's it's not necessarily
used at a high level but it's super
important for those types of things and
we see it in several crops in north
dakota where zinc deficiency is a
significant yield problem
corn would be one dry edible bean or you
know pintos would be another and then
alfalfa is the third one that
they all respond really well to small
levels of zinc
and just the way the zinc is it it
combines with several things it has
several
sites and so our typical way of
placing zinc is actually with a
phosphorus fertilizer
and zinc loves to attach to phosphates
so again we use that chelated zinc
which is protecting it from that
phosphorus then we can use a lower rate
and we'll put that right in furrow right
next to the corn seed or the dry bean
seed within a few inches so that that
young seedling gets into this zinc early
on
and then that zinc will help with it
helps with photosys photosynthesis and
this is why you'll see white or yellow
coloring if you have a zinc deficiency
is it it's a coenzyme for photosynthesis
but it's also a core enzyme for all that
reproduction so when you're growing seed
or you're growing flower parts or
whatever it can be critically important
and high ph will be very very
problematic for zinc availability
so
can you give me a specific product i
mean when you say zinc i immediately
think of zinc sulfate um are there other
ways or other products
that are chelated yeah there's a
liquid chelated zinc it's a nine percent
zinc i'm trying to think of
specifically what it's called i don't
have it off top of my head but it's a
liquid formula zinc
that's an organic approved
kiwi i don't know if you're familiar
with bio-men they do a
they make a product like that
essentially so i know there's ones out
there but that doesn't get
you know ineffective uh price wise
using it would for you yes because
you're zinc sulfate it's highly soluble
and if you're using in a in a drench or
a liquid irrigation chemigation or
fertigation type of thing you're way
better off using zinc sulfate like that
would be the way to do it
but why don't we put in yeah sorry we're
putting it with the uh fertilizer so the
zinc sulfate's coming in as a granular
form yeah and the fertilizers that we're
using are liquid fertilizers
and but they're oil based liquid
fertilizers so the zinc goes in with
liquids we're putting a quart of zinc
per acre it's a very low rate there's
another reason why we put it with a
phosphorus because the phosphorus is
coming out at five gallons and that's
that's actually a consistent stream in
the equipment because if you try to put
a quart per acre like you have a dot
here and a dot there and
20 feet further you have another dot
right so that's not really good for
availability
so this is why we're putting it into a
starter right near the seed band and
we're putting it with a higher volume
thing so that we get it spread out so
that every seed gets a chance at it
and
then
it doesn't take a whole lot but it needs
to be highly available so this chelation
process is expensive
but it helps maintain it because
phosphorus will grab onto zinc in a
split second and tie it up and it
becomes a rock and it won't dissolve
so we're using it that way and it also
protects our zinc from our high ph
chemistries
so we're isolating it in a band and
we're keeping it away from a bunch of
chemistry
we do use zinc sulfate we'll broadcast
that on on land and we'll do that that's
a once every three or four years deal
because we use a high rate and then it
will it will last for three four five
years
um but the the consistency of the
product it's a granule right it's not a
pelletized most egg
fertilizers that i'm dealing with are
pelletized so they're
several orders larger than the granular
so it just becomes a logistics issue
when you're using this very fine granule
it's harder to spread it over wider
distances because these spreaders are
trying to cover
40 feet for the spinner spreader
and a small particle just doesn't fly
that far
so when you're saying granular
you're describing like almost like a
powder just for listeners
a little bit above a powder yeah yeah so
this
and then when i'm talking about
pelletize i'm talking about something
the size of a bb or bigger okay you know
so the pellets are larger and have more
density and they'll fly farther the
granule would be one-tenth the size of a
bb and then a powder is going to be very
fine and so
your zinc sulfate you're getting is
going to be a powder because it
dissolves easily in water yeah that's
what i'm familiar with
yeah that would be that'll be the way to
do it we're getting a liquid base of
zinc sulfate and it's got a chelation
agent in there and so basically the the
zinc is dissolved in the liquid with a
chelating agent
and
that's really what it is i mean it's
it's so here i just looked it up it's
derived from zinc chloride and zinc
sulfate
and we're adding a human component to
chelate
and so basically we're adding a little
bit of cep
that so that was actually when you said
chelation my brain went to hemic acids
and then i was like oh do i have time to
ask you one last question about your
thoughts about humic acids because it's
kind of a contentious
topic i feel like in the ag world a
little bit yeah
it is it can
so see here's the thing
so the humic acids are part of the the
cec right and if you have a really
really low cec
you could have amazing results
if you have a moderate to high cec
you're going to see nothing
because its percentage of
change is not enough when we're talking
courts or
gallons per acre even i mean
one inch of rainfall is 27 000 gallons
of water per acre
so when you start talking about five
gallons an acre even you're talking
about micro percentages but if you have
a highly sandy soil or something with a
very low nutrient holding capacity and
you add a little bit of a chelating
agent which is a human component
you're going to see that your nutrient
availability jumps drastically in
proportion to what you're doing
for us we have
very good clay soils a lot of silt we
have a high cec normally we have
decent organic matters two to four
percent for us is pretty decent so we
have pretty good cec so when we add a
little bit of humic components it moved
the needle 0.5 percent well we're not
going to notice that
if you go to a sand soil in some of the
coastal areas you go to florida or
california or something like that
there's almost a pure sand
and they add a little bit of humic
it has 10 times as much nutrient holding
capacity as the soil did so then they
see this huge benefit so this is where
the details matter what are you trying
to do where you're at what problem are
you trying to solve is it the right
solution for your problem
that's interesting because uh a lot of
the you know with potting soils we have
a fairly high cc high very high organic
matter percentage you know off the
charts compared to what you're used to
um right
i haven't gotten the same results from
humic acids that i would have expected
or would have liked to see
um
in some of those systems so yeah that's
that's just dangerous
yeah
this is like taking an aspirin when you
don't have a headache i mean if you have
a heart condition fine but it you know
if you don't need it you don't need it
this is the details part
and and it so the next thing on that so
you can have all of those things you can
have very high organic matter you can
have very high cec you can have very
high neutral capacity but if you're
flushing a lot of water through this
then you might see a difference if you
added the humid component to your
solution simply because it's going to
hold the nutrients in the water better
so that could be some of the variable
results is this this again goes back to
the different places like somebody's
flushing a ton of water through
something
for some other reason to try to manage
the ph
and they add a little bit of human
components they see the benefit and the
next guy is not flushing near as much
water and he has the immediate when he
sees nothing or he sees a negative
response
well this is simply you didn't need
aspirin
yeah i i think it is situational and um
as you probably experienced this in the
ag industry but this idea
that there's always another product out
there or another thing that's going to
be that amazing
difference in my crop
you know people don't necessarily look
at nitrogen as nitrogen they look at
this brand or that brand or
this
you know potential form of it
and i think sometimes we move a little
too far away from
just looking at the chemistry itself
and there's just so many marketing
claims out there and and frankly the
cannabis industry is even worse than the
ag industry in this regard i wouldn't
believe it yeah i don't believe it it
becomes very hard to evaluate a product
and know what's going to work in your
system which is gets back to your whole
science thing and how it's so important
that we
you know use experimental design in our
um
you know in our in our own
field
make sure you have replication make sure
you have checks and balances on this you
know the the non-treated check is
critically important
but uh yeah
so one of the things is just under you
know think about plants again when you
when you get all these wonderful claims
these amazing i call them the snake oils
right all these things that are just
going to save and fix everything that do
all these wonderful things
there's a potential possibly in certain
situations but i want people to think
about what a plant needs and what a
plant does when a plant uses for me
there was a big push for a while about
using sugars in in plant production
adding sugar as a as a nutrient
that's just absolutely counterintuitive
that's the whole process of
photosynthesis is to take carbon dioxide
and water and to make sugar this is what
a plant does
it's it's byproduct it's sugar so adding
sugar to a plant doesn't make any sense
because it's what a plant does
and when we talk about nutrients in
particular we talk about nitrogen
we we know that plants only assume a
couple forms of nitrogen they're
basically elemental forms they're
nitrate and they're ammonia
and that's what plants assume is ammonia
and nitrate that's what they bring up
so as long as your fertilizer turns into
that it's plant available
i don't care if it came out of the back
end of a sheep or it came out of the
haber bosch process or it came out of
nitrogen fixation through bacteria as
long as it's in that form the plants
happen
because the plant takes these elemental
forms and builds the things that
that other organisms like us need from
eating that plant we need the proteins
and we need
the sugars and the carbohydrates and all
that type of stuff
because we can't build them the plants
literally build them so all we got to do
is give them the lego blocks so honestly
as long as it's a four by four lego
block it doesn't matter if it's yellow
or blue or green or red the plant
doesn't care it'll use it to build what
it needs
so that's that's my short answer to all
of these wonderful claims about
this is you know ortho this and paulie
that and
it comes from such and such whatever as
long as it turns into the plant
ions that they need it's simple and
phosphorus is the same thing it's h2po4
and it's hpo4 that's it those are the
two forms of plants absorb phosphorus
too that's it that's the only things
they examine
so that's all it needs to turn into long
as it does that we're fine
yeah just real quickly you mentioned
sugar
could the count argument be that you
know sugars
would raise the you know bacterial
levels or biological levels in the soil
which may increase nutrient cycling
would that be the
theory behind it well it'll increase
it'll increase biology but it doesn't
necessarily increase the nitrogen fixing
biology because that's not the food that
source that they use
the nitrobacters
tend to use carbon sources and sulfate
sources to get their oxygen um
and they're getting their nitrogen that
way and that's how they're producing it
they're using nitrates and then they're
yeah it's they don't need sugar
some bacteria do but not those ones
yeah you're feeding some bacteria but
and it goes back to the point of okay so
how are you getting the food where they
need don't forget that the bacteria is
microscopic and again moving a
millimeter is a big deal and so if
you're you're broadcasting the sugar
solution on top of your soil is it
getting to the bacteria because
it's like applying
you know dropping a fruit basket in
russia and hoping the guys in iowa are
going to get it
it's just not going to happen and
they're going to get it before somebody
eats it
so it's going to be intercepted at the
point of contact and it's going to be
intercepted within
nanometers more so than millimeters or
even inches
and so
i just don't think it's going to get to
where it's going to get to
now some of these bacteria do trade with
plants for sugar this is this goes back
to
you know nitrogen fixing bacteria that's
what they do they trade
um nitrogen for sugar with the plant now
if you're going to be the guy in the in
the middle and you're going to give it
sugar why would it trade
nitrogen like
nature's just as lazy as as the laziest
human being they're going to take free
every time they can
so we see this with our legume plants
that if we give them too much nitrogen
at planting or early on they don't build
the associations with the bacteria
because they get it for free why would
you make an economic trade because
that's plants build sugars and they
trade it they buy nitrogen with sugar
and when we give them too much nitrogen
they don't buy any
nitrogen with sugar so then when they
run out of what we supply then they're
in short supply they've got to build the
factories we see this is this is a
biological fact
so
i i'm just saying
have a healthy soil
do a good job of maintaining managing
your plants and the biology below is for
the most part gonna kind of take care of
itself
one
last question saying this but you
mentioned that the nitrobacters don't
they they primarily use carbon but then
they also
receive sugar from the plant there
no nitrobacters don't there's different
ones oh other nitrogen
nitrogen producing bacteria is that what
you were
that was a little yeah there's just so
many different bacteria groups i i got
my words a little jumbled the
nitrobacter are looking for the carbon
sources that's what they're looking for
this is why
you know and the carbon source is often
sugar right it is because it's what it
is c6h12o6
that's sugar that's really what you're
talking about is carbon
but um they're getting it from so many
sources there's
it's just all over the place sometimes
you can even taste soil it has a
sweetness to it there's just so much
potential out there that adding a little
bit
agriculturally is
that's like eating a pinch of sugar and
calling it your food for the day it's
not enough
got it you got it yeah i just wanted a
little clarification clarification there
yeah i misspoke
it's all good you know i i think um
i think it's great that farmers are
trying new things and experimenting and
learning because i think we have a long
way to go in this industry like more so
than even most industries out there
um
but we have to do it intelligently and
based off of uh
you know a strict scientific model that
that gives us good information for
making decisions on our farm
right
i agree
well hey you know i just want to say
thank you so much lee for your time
today i had a great time chatting with
you um
i really appreciate you coming on the
show
yeah thank you so much for the
opportunity and i i hope
you're you're you're continuing to get
something out of it and and let me know
what kind of feedback you get appreciate
it
[Music]
that was lee brees with control
consulting you can find them online at
controltv.com you are listening to the
cannabis cultivation and science podcast
i'm your host tad hussey i'll post
pertinent links on the podcast page at
www.kis.org
just click on the learn tab and then
podcast and if you're looking for soils
or soil amendments or fabric beds or
blue mats for your facility or garden
please give us a call or hit us up
through our website contact page and
even with covid and all the current
supply challenges out there we are
currently shipping products out same or
next day so please don't hesitate to
reach out thanks for listening
you