[Music]
Welcome to the Cannabis Cultivation and
Science podcast. I'm your host, Tad
Hussy of Kiss Organics. This is the
podcast where we discuss the cutting
edge of growing from a science-based
perspective and draw top experts from
around the industry to share their
wisdom and knowledge. Before starting
the podcast, I wanted to share about the
cannabis cultivation and science
conference that we are hosting in
conjunction with Collective Elevation in
Bosezeman, Montana. The event is
happening on September 5th through 7th,
2025. And we are kicking it off with
workshops from the bug lady Suzanne and
Dr. greenhouse followed by a facility
tour and then a bunch of excellent
speakers that were former podcast guests
such as Jeremy Plum, Dr. Michael
Brownbridge, Les Evans from Drram, and
many more. It's going to be 3 days of
talks and networking. Then on the 7th,
the Montana Living Soil Alliance is
hosting a tasting event that will be
included in the price of the conference
ticket. The tasting event will be a
private event with cannabis donated by
the Living Soil Alliance as a way to
have an amazing sensory experience and
see what premium quality Montana Living
soil has to offer. Early bird tickets
are $200 and limited to 200 spots, so be
sure to grab a ticket if you're
interested. Tickets are now on sale at
kisorganics.com. Boseman in September is
pretty beautiful and is a popular spot,
so best to lock down your ticket and
accommodations early to guarantee a
spot.
My guest this week is Michael Gutenson.
Michael is an associate professor of
horiculture at West Virginia University.
He earned his diploma in biology from
the Julius Maximleians University in
Germany where he specialized in plant
physiology. While pursuing his PhD at
the University of Cologne in Germany and
during a subsequent post-doal position
at the Martin Luther University in
Germany, Dr. Dr. Guten worked on
multiple projects studying metabolite
and protein transport processes in
plants using biochemical and genetic
approaches. While at Purdue University
for a second post-doal position, he was
introduced to his current research
topic, the biosynthesis of volatile
organic compounds, VOCC's, in plants and
their various biological functions. His
research interests include plant insect
interaction such as plant defenses
against herbivores and pollinator
attraction to flowers, flavor compounds
in horicultural fruit crops, specialized
metabolites in medicinal plants,
classical genetic and metabolic
engineering approaches to introduce or
improve desired VOCC traits into crop
plants and mechanisms regulating the
flux in complex metabolic networks
involved in tarpine formation in plants.
Dr. Dr. Guten is also involved in
steering the operations of the
analytical biochemistry core lab in the
division of plant and soil sciences. Now
on to the show. Well, thanks for coming
on the show today. Yeah, thanks for
having me. I'm excited.
Yes. So, I saw an article about your
research and reached out to you and you
were kind enough to get back to me and
we've we've talked a little bit offline,
but I was hoping you could share some of
your research and findings with our
audience and what you've been working on
at Western West Virginia University.
Yeah, sure. Sure, sure. Happy to do so.
Well, so I mean basic approach of what
we're doing is is that we take a little
bit of a step back from looking at hemp
and cannabis more from the human
perspective
uh and maybe look a little bit more at
it from the from the plant side of
things. And we're trying to understand
why certain things as tarpen and
cannabonoids are being produced in hemp.
Um, and I mean the discipline that we I
and my lab are working in is also very
often called chemical ecology. And so it
takes exactly this approach like we're
trying to understand why plants produce
what on the scientific side of things is
called secondary or specialized
metabolites. Um, and in general define
that for listeners as to what falls
under uh secondary metabolites within
the constituents of a plant. Yeah, I
know this is probably a term that most
people are not so familiar. So, so in
general we we talk about either primary
metabolites or
secondary specialized metabolites.
Primary metabolites is something that
most people are pretty familiar with.
This is your your carbohydrates, your
carbs, how people call them, your your
lipids, your um and and your your your
proteins. Yeah. So, this is what we need
in our nutrition basically. And you
should have a little bit of a balance
there. This is what's primary
metabolites and they're produced by all
organisms including plants. What's
specific about plants is is that they
also produce a large set of other
metabolites and very small quantities
very often. And those are called
secondary or specialized metabolites.
And that has a little bit to do with the
lifestyle of plants. Um if I scare you
or one of your listeners, uh they
probably would run off and flee. Yeah.
Um, same thing for an animal. Yeah. If
an
animal is in a stressed situation, one
of the easiest ways to get out of it is
just to run away and flee. A plant is
rooted. It can't run away. And so it has
to fight back basically at the spot
where it is. And that's why um plants
developed into being absolute masters in
in in producing a lot of very
interesting and could also say nasty
chemicals. Yeah. Uh so a lot of these
these specialized metabolites plant
produce because they have to somehow
deal with their environment and to a
large extent with their what we call a
biotic environment. So with other
organisms, with other plants, with other
microbes,
uh, and of course also with animals and
among animals, I think for plants, the
most important ones are the insects
because that's that's number-wise
probably what they face most. And so for
doing that, they produce these these
metabolites. And that's no different for
hemp. So what we humans use or are
interested in hemp are actually
chemicals that are there for a purpose
to help the plants, not necessarily us.
And that's kind of the the little bit
the philosophy or approach that we're
taking. We're trying to kind of ignore
to some extent why humans are interested
in hemp and cannabis and rather try to
understand why is the plant producing
these things in the first place. Yeah.
um because it actually helps better
understand how these things are
regulated and produced in the plant when
where and how
um and then that creates a lot of very
interesting and useful basic knowledge
that then you can apply later on again.
So this is a little bit in in a nutshell
our our approach
there. So you studied factors that
increased secondary metabolites in hemp.
Uh
specifically, you know, the most common
ones that I think of when I think of
that would be CBD, THC, and and tarpen
would all fall as secondary metabolites.
Are there any other are there any others
that you were looking at in some of your
research?
Yeah. So, so, so I mean when we do
analysis we generally look at
cannabonoids but not just the ones that
you mentioned although those are of
course are the the the most abundant
ones. Uh we simp simply look from the
point of view of how much amount wise is
there. And then the other big group of
compounds that we're looking at are are
the tarpen. So the essential oils
basically uh what you normally perceive
as the the scent or the smell because
simply because they go into the gas
phase and you can sniff them. So that's
that's the two major classes, but we in
in in our analytics, we inevitably don't
just see a few compounds
there, like you mentioned THC, CBD, and
some of the other well-known cannabonoid
compounds. But when we do an analysis,
we currently are in in in a situation
where we can roughly see about 50
different cannabonoids. Although I mean,
if you look in literature, there's over
100 cannabonoids known by now. Um we
it's it's it's technically quite
challenging to detect all of them. Um I
mean we we over the last couple years we
definitely improved in our analytics and
can detect more things now. Uh and the
same applies for the turppines. I mean
we see basically everything that's
there. Question is just can we really
identify undoubtedly everything? And I'm
al always a little bit on the cautionary
side there. I don't want to lean myself
too much out of the window and claim I
can identify everything. But we we see a
lot of things there. But that's the two
major groups of compounds we're looking
at.
And yes, you're right. I mean, what you
said before that we're particularly
interested what induces the formation of
these things. Um and that is actually
the was sort of the onset of uh a USDA
grant um that we were awarded um in
2020 as one of the first ones that got
actually federal funding for working on
this. Um and the the the the major
question that we were trying to address
in this this in this project was the the
so so-called going hot problem. So
environmental factors triggering
triggering an an increase in in the THC
content that would push industrial hemp
from its legal status to surpassing
the.3% THC contently turning it from a
crop into a a drug. And we wanted to
understand or identify some
environmental factors that would do so.
and then also start understanding a
little bit the the metabolic and genetic
regulation that's that's behind that. So
why is that happening?
Now you were working on hemp. A lot of
people listening to this podcast are
growing cannabis.
Um my my question to you would be is it
fair to to assume with the similarities
between the crops that there may be some
overlap in terms of your your results
having similar effects on uh cannabis
plants as you're seeing with hemp.
Um I got to be a little bit careful
there. So I can c I can definitely say
we also tested um seed hemp varieties um
and not just CBD or CBG varieties um and
those so seed hemp and and CBD varieties
um behaved in the same way. They both
saw an upregulation of THC production
under certain stress conditions of
course at completely different levels.
Yeah. I mean the THC level in a seed
hemp variety is is fairly minimal
um compared to what you find in a CBD
variety. Uh but in principle in both
cases but with both different types of
hemp we saw an increase in THC. You're
not going to run anywhere close to being
in sort of risking or surpassing the the
legal THC limit with a seed hemp variety
because it's so little. Um but in
principle the induction you could see in
well as well there. So based on that I
would I would broadly conclude that yes
there's a similar regulatory mechanism
in play just that you're starting from a
different baseline so to say and of
course that that determines how much you
get. I can't say if that's the
same the same thing would happen in a in
in cannabis.
Um, as you probably know, the problem is
that we can still not work with cannabis
because it's on the research side in
academia because um it's still illegal
at the federal level and since we do get
federal funding uh we have to follow
federal rules and laws and regulations.
So, um, working with cannabis that has a
higher THC level than.3% is off limits
for us and will stay off limits as long
as there's no change in the legislation
on the on the federal side of things.
Um, so that might be confusing for some
people if they think, well, but wait a
moment, I'm in in my state where I'm
operating. Um, I'm a grower. it's legal
to grow it here and sell things. Um, but
the point is we get federal funding and
at that determines what we can what we
can do. So, it's basically depending our
our funding status. So, universities
cannot work with with cannabis because
of the the funding situation that that
limits us. And so, I I can't tell you
anything about cannabis because I'm
simply not in a situation that I can
work with it. I I understand. So, so
what you're saying is it's it's likely
your your hypothesis is that it's likely
but not definitive that you would re you
would receive
similar effects based on the
similarities of the of the two plants.
I'm I mean I would based on the the
results that I that we have I would if
if I would ever come into the situation
that I could work on cannabis my
hypothesis would be that I would expect
the same the same regulatory mechanisms
at play. Um but of course that would
have to be tested. Um, the question of
course is I mean what I could envision
what or or what you could put up as a
counterargument there is like well in
cannabis you have have already such a
much higher THC level maybe you're sort
of maxing out at some point. Yeah. And
then you can't increase it even more
because there is already so much that
there's there's no there's other
limitations that would limit it from
being further increased. Yeah.
Yeah. So, that could that could be one
thing, but I mean it's it's pure
speculation at this point before we're
not in a situation to test that. You you
actually won't won't know. Yeah. I I
want to talk to you about plant stress,
but before we do because you brought
this up, um there was some I think it
was Dr. Daniellea Vgar at uh uh Cornell
I believe that I talked to that
mentioned this idea of a dilution effect
where a plant has the genetic capability
to only produce so much um so so many
cannabonoids or so much THC and then
once once it reaches a certain level of
biomass that that THC level in theory
would be diluted across more you know
greater surface area because it's
producing more biomass. So in theory, as
your yields increase, some of the
concentrations of some of these
secondary metabolites would in theory go
down. Yeah, that's that's one thing you
could envision. Of course, I mean, the
question is like how do you achieve your
your final THC yield, so to say, if you
want to call it that way. Um, you
brought up biomass. That's of course one
point. I mean the more biomass or
flowers a a plant produces of course the
more yield you will have there and of
course that that can be influencedly by
the growth habit of the plant. Um so
that's one one factor. I would bring up
one other factor or argument in there
and that is um I mean I'm from my
background I'm a plant biochemist and so
of course I always look like more at
from that perspective at it and there
are other factors that can limit
production and and you have to think
about any any of these these compounds
um they're they're produced from certain
precursors that need to be provided from
the rest of the
And and at some point you might might
just reach a point where there's
limitations on that end. The plant can
just provide so much building blocks so
to say for making cannabonoids as it can
without at some point sacrificing other
things. Yeah. And then it's a trade-off
between producing more in this case
would be cannabonoids versus kind of
needing other things as well. Um, and so
it's very often this this kind of like
what gives the plant more of a benefit
producing more cannabonoids maybe versus
producing something else in a larger
quantity. So we we very often talk when
we in the in the science side of things
when we talk about metabolism we very
often talk about networks rather than
sort of
linear pathways. Yeah.
Um and and and and that's anyway where
science has moved on the last 10 20
years on the biochemistry side that we
understand that everything's kind of
like a huge network connected with each
other. And although very often we just
look at one final product because that's
what in a particular project you're
interested in. But you always have to
keep in mind it's that is not isolated
from all the rest that's going on there.
And so you have to kind of consider that
as well that that you're rather looking
at one tiny little aspect of a gigantic
network of things and just because if
you're up regulating one things
there's 250 other things happening in
parallel and you can't ignore that.
Yeah. So even though you're kind of
interested in bringing up the level of
that one thing that you're interested
in, you have to consider that that's
happening at the backdrop of everything
else that's happening there as well. And
so there might be limitations that come
rather from this whole network that say
like well that's enough now we need to
do other things as well here because
otherwise the plant's not doing well
either. Um so that could be one other
factor sort of limiting things at some
point.
Yeah. Yeah. So that has me thinking. So,
so what you're saying essentially is a
plant has uh a certain amount of
resources, limited amount of resources,
and it allocates those resources based
on its goals. Either plant defense to
protect itself. In the case like you
mentioned, if you someone scared you,
you could run away. Well, the plant
would have to produce these secondary
metabolites to protect itself from
insects, environmental conditions,
whatever. or uh as a way of
um a continuation of its of its species
by re reproduction essentially correct
so so if I'm understanding correctly we
have a limited amount of resources and
that plant is going to allocate those
resources towards one of those goals
whether it's reproduction protection uh
growth overall growth and so it's a
constant
I don't know what the word I'm looking
for here. Uh it's just a constant uh
process, I guess. Balance balancing
these various different things out.
Yeah. It's it's it's it's constantly a
balance and and if you you you chip if
you raise one thing up, you intimately
going to lose at some other end. Yeah.
There's only so much in total available.
Uh and ultimately if you want to really
go to all the way down I mean like
um ultimately anything that a plant
produces and does comes from
photosynthesis and the photosynthetic
capacity of a plant basil limits how
much is there how much resources are
there. You can't do more than what it
fixes in photosynthesis in for form of
fixing carbon dioxide and producing
sugar molecules initially or how much
nitrogen you can take up from the soil
or other nutrients that you need that
that ultimately limits things. How much
is there and that limits what you can
make out of that. Yeah. So there's an
input and there's an output so to say
and that that ultimately needs to be in
balance and there that so the all these
things limit in the end how much you can
produce of of a certain compound
basically and yes you're absolutely
right I mean growth reproduction in form
of seed production or in other crops it
would be fruit production
um that's other factors that play into
that yeah and you can't just ignore that
that it's just steer. Yeah.
So, one of the examples I think of that
kind of highlights this is the idea of
that plant that you threw out because it
was it was sickly or or a seed that got
lost and ended up in your compost pile
and it was neglected all season long.
And yet this plant was able to survive
and not thrive because it probably had
nutrient stress and drought stress and
and maybe heat stress, but it was able
to to survive through all these things.
So it was very resilient. um at the end
when that plant is ending its life
cycle we what I've seen is higher levels
of secondary metabolites higher THC
maybe higher levels of tarpen all of
these secondary metabolites but the
yield is dramatically lower sickly plant
it's not um necessarily healthy but due
to all of these stresses from being
neglected
um we tend to see higher you know people
will say the best cannabis I ever smoked
or grew was this poor plant that was,
you know, horribly stressed. Um, what
are your thoughts on that? Does that is
that sort of fit with this idea of
allocation of resources as the plant was
just trying to survive?
Yeah. And it's not necessarily just a a
the plants survive, it's the species
survive. Plants don't function
necessarily at the at the level of
individual plants. They try to survive
as a species. And so what plants very
often do if they're in in what you
described like a nutrient deficiency or
so like just a not a very good
environmental condition which yes you
can create in in your greenhouse in your
growth facility. Yeah. Because you
neglected it or over watered it or
whatever it's some something went wrong.
Um, one of the important things that
plants very often do is they they try to
reproduce produce seeds in the hopes
that the next generation actually finds
better conditions. Yeah. And so it will
try to somehow get through and produce
even if it's just a few flowers and a
few seeds. But it basically in the hopes
of maintaining itself as a species, it
produces seeds which is the next
generation and then hopes that those
seeds are spread somewhere in a place
where where there's better conditions or
next season is the the weather is
better. Yeah. there's more more rain or
better conditions or the seed is carried
to some other environment where the soil
is more fertile or something like that.
So yes, you always have to look at that
plants function in a different way and
that's something goes back to what I
said at the beginning. This is you you
if you want to understand what plants do
and if it is a crop plant and hemp or
cannabis are crop lands applies
to a crop plant in the same way like to
any wild plants. Yeah, sure. Crop lands
there's a few things that are different
because we humans over hundreds if
better say thousands of years have sort
of selected certain things and s certain
traits have been manipulated in certain
ways. But a lot of this basic regulation
is still there. It's not gone. Um and if
we want to understand our plants, then
we you really have to put yourselves in
the sho literally have to put yourselves
in the shoes of a plant to understand
how it's actually functioning. Uh and
that's that goes back to what I said.
Sometimes you you have to I think for
understanding hemp and cannabis I think
you sometimes have to take a step back
and say like well I know our final goal
is to grow hemp or cannabis for the
purpose of getting cannabonoids or other
purposes but why is why are things
happening there in the first place and
for understanding that you have to take
the human component out a little bit and
look rather from the plant side of
things and that's what we're trying in
my lab and in our research. We're really
trying to go back and like okay why are
these things happening in the first
first place and what are the underlying
mechanisms that are there? Yeah. And
then we can kind of understand one
factor with any crop plant is that you
have to consider well there was human
domestication and then cultivation and
breeding happening
for eventually thousands of years. So of
course that's not a wild plant anymore.
So some things were selected or changed
but a lot of the basic regulation is
still there. That hasn't gone away and
will not go away. Yeah. It's it's still
there.
Yeah. So
yeah. So you studied essentially what
would cause a plant to go pot to create
more of these secondary metabolites.
Um, before we go into what your findings
were, can I have a question about plant
stress? So, we've been talking this
whole time essentially about plant
stress. What stresses plants out? And
it's a variety of things off the top of
my head. You can have heat stress, you
can have cold stress, you can have a
variety of different types of
environmental stress like drought
stress, overwatering. And then you have
your, you know, uh, biotic stress like
insect pressures, um, things like that,
you know, herbivy with a insect eating
the leaf
itself. Are all stresses to this to
plants the same or do they have
different effects on the plant?
No, they're not all the same. Um that
that for sure.
Um so and that I mean plants need to
respond to all stresses and and we
basically you outlined it perfectly
there. So in in principle you can
categorize things in two major buckets.
The one is abiotic. So anything that is
is in the environment that's not another
organism. And you you mentioned water
stress, heat,
cold, you can I mean even light stress
in the sense of UV or or too much light.
Um so there's all sorts of factors that
can involve that. And then of course
nutrition, lack of it or too much
salinity, soil conditions. I mean
there's a lot of things that can go into
that. Acidity or or sort of pH where
value of water um there's a lot of
things there. So that's the one side of
things and then the other side yes as
you mentioned is the biotic side of
things and that's basically microbes on
the one hand side which very often are
like either pathogens that harm the
plants or they're helpful if they're
like fixing nitrogen or microisa that
help taking up nutrients and then of
course it's animals. Um and again they
can be beneficial or they can be sort of
harmful herbivores you mentioned. Yes.
Um, but there's also beneficial insects.
I mean, growers will know that
you your beneficial insects in your
greenhouse, in your growth facility to
kind of fight pests. Uh, and plants
actually act very often actively attract
these beneficial insects for helping
them.
Um, but how a plant responds to these
different abiotic and biotic stresses
can be quite different. I mean, you
can't generalize. Every individual
factor can have a different consequence.
Yeah. So plants, some of these
specialized or secondary metabolites
help the plant actually sort of cope
with some of these abiotic factors. So
you have certain things that almost work
like a sunscreen. Yeah. So they protect
plants from from too much light or light
stress. Yeah. Um other things very oft
sort of help with um sort of some of the
consequences of some of the stresses.
Yeah. Um, and so cannabonoids are maybe
not necessarily falling directly in that
category, but of course you're right and
you mentioned that before that
sometimes plants, hemp plants, cannabis
plants respond with sort of an
alteration in their cannabonoid level if
they experience some of this abiotic
stress. But that sometimes could be
rather kind of an indirect effect. If if
you're changing sort of supply of
nutrition
um if there's too much or too little
then that's kind of like if you see a
change on the cannabonoid level that
might be rather kind of an indirect
effect that overall metabolism of the
plant is affected and then that's
affecting cannabonoids as well. Um so so
that's the one thing that can happen
there with the biotic stress that's a
completely different thing because the a
lot of these secondary metabolites are
specifically produced and very often
upregulated to deal with these stress
situations. So with with biotic stress
with being attacked by pedagogens or
pests that's that's their one of their
main purposes. Yeah. And that's no
different for tarpen or cannabonoids
that that's why they're there.
So
um so basically what you're saying is is
all stresses are not the same and don't
have the same plant effect and what
we're what we're getting as in terms of
cannabonoid effect is
actually not the primary mechanism or or
necessarily what the plant is focused on
um when it's creating these is that am I
am I understanding kind of well I mean
we haven't done much on the abiotic side
but of course I'm aware that there's
quite a bit of literature out there but
I would have a little bit of a hard time
seeing how a cannabonoid molecule could
help a plant
um with dealing with some of these
abiotic stresses sort of directly
dealing with that yeah there is there's
other compounds where you can make a
direct connection yeah they produce some
of these things it like I said before it
works like a if you putting on sun
lotion or sunscreen basically. Yeah.
Cannabonoids don't do that. Yeah. Um
first of all from where they're being
produced.
Um and second of all also from their
chemistry I would have a little bit of a
hard time seeing how that would work. So
you're saying like drought stress like
increasing tarpine levels in a plant or
increasing CBD does not
directly help a plant that's
experiencing drought stress. So it may
be a some sort of secondary mechanism
that occurs. It could be either a
secondary mechanism sort of kind of like
just something in metabolism is altering
and that kind of results in some
consequence in cannabonoid or tarpine
formation. The the the only thing you
could argue for is a plant is in
generally stressed by an abiotic factor.
Of course, it's potentially also at risk
of being more susceptible to biotic
stress.
Yes. Yeah. So, you're anyhow stressed,
you're weakened because of some
environmental factor. There's a drought
or there's something else going on in
your environment. So, you're basically
in a in a weak um susceptible status and
that makes you more prone for being
attacked by pests or pathogens
basically. And then in that context, of
course, it would make sense to
upregulate some of these compounds
because you're still trying to defend
yourself. Yeah. But again, it's not the
abiotic factor that you directly are
kind of like dealing with. It's a
consequence of the abiotic factor
weakening you so to say as a plant and
then
that results in potentially you being at
more at risk of being prone to other
stresses. Yeah. Yeah. So, you're saying
as as the plant receives drought stress,
it it thinks, "Oh my gosh, I'm now more
I'm weaker. I'm more open to pests. So I
by increasing my tarpen or my
cannabonoids, I may better protect
myself from these pests that are more
likely to hit me now that I'm more
susceptible. So it's yeah, I mean that's
the biological explanation. That would
be the biological benefit of of of doing
that. Yeah. sort of you you you're
you're you're you're trying you're
increasing your your likelihood of
surviving or reproducing at least to the
extent that that guarantees the survival
of you as a species basically. So
there's there's you always have to look
at the biological purpose of something
and so yes you can draw that conclusion.
I'm not saying that that's what it is
because I don't know we haven't looked
at that but in other plants that's
clearly there is a connection between
abiotic stress and some of these
responses which is in in ina in some
cases it's not clear that they're the
the increased production of some of
these secondary metabolites would help
dealing with this abiotic stress but it
basically protects the plant from
potential other things in that
situation.
Now, a popular term or concept in the
last few years has been this idea of
crop steering, which is I don't know if
you're familiar with it or not, but it's
essentially intentional stress that
you're giving to the plant to create a
certain response. So some examples of
this um cannabis growers have tried
everything over the years would be um
you know uh what they call drybacks
essentially intentionally withholding
water to create drought stress at
certain stages of plant growth or with
withholding nutrients or um getting
closer to harvest. I've heard of people
um reducing CO2 and reducing light
levels to lower stress. But then on the
flip side, um, cooling the rooms that
they're in as a way of, uh, introducing
cold
stress. Do we know what sorts of
targeted stress levels will have, you
know, what mechanisms create this
effect?
That's a complicated question.
Um,
no, I mean in principle I can see why
people would try these things because of
course you're you're whenever you're
changing an environmental factor. Um,
and that's essentially what you're doing
with all those things that you you you
you were mentioning there. Um, of course
the plant was will will respond to that
in one or the other way. So yes, I mean
one of the first things that I would
bring up in that in in that point for
example and I don't know if if there's
there's sort of
more more trustworthy documentation or
scientific work on that for for hemp but
of course you have to think about some
of this might also regulate
um flower induction
um how many flowers you get the ratio
between flowers and vegetative growth.
It's kind of like you're you're
manipulating the growth of a plant in
the first place. Yeah. So that logically
has has some consequences there. Um so
that's one thing and yes I mean like I
said before I mean certain abiotic
factors will have consequences on on the
level of metabolites as well. Um, so yes
and I mean I'm very well aware that
people probably have done a lot of stuff
just by trial and error and trying to
play around with things with conditions
and see what the consequence of that is.
Yes. And that's not much different than
what we do on the science side of
things. I wouldn't say we play around.
We normally start off with a clearly
defined hypothesis. But in the end we we
don't know things and then we test
things. uh just that we do it under much
more let's say a little bit more
controlled conditions and and and we do
it not just one time but we do a lot of
replications and very thorough data
collection and then data analysis later
on to really kind of verify or or reject
a hypothesis that you might have had
before there but
yes I'm not saying that that's not not
reasonable to assume that some of these
things would lead to to respective
consequences in the plant. Like I said
before, I mean, we initially we were
kind of considering abiotic factors in
our our work a little bit, but since the
initial results we got in the first year
or year and a half were much more
promising and interesting on the on the
biotic side of things, we very quickly
then decided to primarily focus on that
uh in particular because that is also a
little bit more in alignment with other
projects not related to camp and
cannabis that are ongoing in my lab
here. I I in general I work a lot with
plant insect interactions and so
logically once we saw respective
responses in in in in hemp plants to
insects we kind of focused primarily on
that.
I I I want to talk about that um next.
But one question I want to just propose
to you is something that the sort of my
approach to understanding this is plants
all have this genetic potential and when
we're cultivating and we're trying to
get them to reach this potential and
then any sort of stress that they have
while it may increase secondary
metabolite metabolites it could also
impact yields negatively because the
plant has a certain amount of resources
it can allocate. Now, I'm under the
philosophy, and please feel free to
correct me on this, that every facility,
grower, cultivation I've ever been to
has stress, plant stress just naturally
occurring. We haven't perfected this in
real, I mean, in a growth chamber, maybe
you're able to get a lot closer to this,
but in the reality of cultivating it
commercially or even at home, we're
naturally going to have some of these
stress events occur already. And so my
goal as a cultivator is to create the
best environment I can for the plant to
reach its genetic potential and assume
that it's still going to have good
secondary metabolite
production.
Um do you have any thoughts on that
approach versus this idea of you know
more targeted stress events?
Um I think in general the take of get
providing the best environmental
conditions if you want to say
so is for sure the best way. You don't
want to intentionally harm your plants
because yes you're right. I mean um if
you do that in the in the wrong time or
in the wrong way you simply will will
sacrifice your yield overall.
um some targeted sort of treatment, if
you want to call it that way, at a
certain time point to sort of increase
the level of certain things that you
want to sort of achieve there. Yes, that
makes sense. But sort of from the get-go
intentionally stressing your plans all
the time, I would really not think that
that would be a particularly good idea.
Yeah. Um I mean initially you want to
make sure that your plant grows up
properly is in a good healthy condition
um good good growth
stage if you then at some point set sort
of the right trigger through some
treatment of your growth conditions your
environmental conditions yes you might
achieve something there but I mean this
is similar things you do with other
crops as well. Yeah I
mean but you got to be careful with
that. I mean like just sort
of trying to harm your plant
intentionally for an extended period of
time is is probably not a good good idea
there in the first place. So so what
you're saying is we may find that most
of and this is another thing is we have
such genetic diversity in cannabis that
we can't make the assumption that all
plants are going to reply you know
respond the same because of the
diversity that we see.
We may find that two weeks out from
harvest, for example, extreme drought
stress or extreme cold stress may have a
positive effect on secondary metabolite
production without having as large of an
impact on yield and that might become
best practice down the road, but we're
not there yet. Yeah. Yeah. I mean, keep
in mind you you you keep your plants um
in a vegetative state for quite a while
before then they start flowering. There
is no sense in stressing your plants
while they're in the vegetative state. I
mean, you want to have a good good base
line, so to say, of vegetative growth
because that's the resources that you
ultimately then can remobilize and put
into flowers in the end. Yeah. If you're
having a weak plant before, well, what's
the sense of it? Yeah. Um there that's
not going to work out well.
That's that's a really good point. Yeah.
So, we definitely don't want to create
any stress early on in the plant's life.
Um, okay. Well, let's uh let's talk a
little bit about your research. So, we
kind of hinted at it. Tell me a little
bit about about what your sort of
methodology was and what your results
were.
Yeah. So, I mean, this goes way back to
what I said at the beginning a little
bit, this chemical ecology approach. And
of course, one of the the major stresses
that any plant will face in its lifetime
is bibly biotic stress.
Um and and in particular insects,
herbivy basically. Um of course we can
talk about herbivy in a little bit of
broader sense. I mean not herbivy is not
just insects. Um, and I think this is um
something we might want to consider a
little bit more when we talk about hemp.
Um, we can get get to back to that in in
in a few minutes. So, herbivy could be
also by by other animals by mammals, by
little rodents or rabbits or or goats or
sheep or something like that. I mean, if
you consider the size of a hemp plant,
it's not a tiny little plant. It's
actually a quite substantial plant. So
you can imagine that other animals would
feed on a hemp plant as well. Not sure
if it the flowers, but definitely
somewhere on the plant. Yeah. But
definitely the other major factor that
kind of harms plants in that respect are
are all sorts of insects. Yeah. And so
um and that's normally why plants
produce a lot of these specialized
metabolites basically fending off this
herbivy. Uh so any herbivore that
consumes some of the the the the the
leaf material, the plant, the vegetative
part, even it's if it's in the roots,
um would be facing or would be exposed
to such specialized or secondary
metabolites. And that's no different for
for for a hemp or cannabis plant. Yeah.
And so one of the the the the early on
experiments that we did was we kind of
initially mimicked herbivy and you can
do that by some chemical treatment
basically that is a signaling compound
that's actually a plant normally
produces itself when it's exposed to
herbivy and then we measured tpine and
cannabonoid contents and we saw already
that that led to an upper regulation.
Yeah. And so that was a first clear
indication. Oh yeah, they're responding
to that. Which was not surprising. It's
just easier to do that because it's
bitly you spray a chemical on the plant
and you can see the response and you
don't actually need the actual insect
feeding on the plant. But logically that
was our next step. Once we saw this
first these first preliminary data and
seeing that the plant was responding to
that uh then of course we looked for
a an insect system that we could use on
hemp and we kind of looked around and
talked with some people from various
extension services to see like what are
real world real insect pests that you're
seeing in in in hemp and cannabis
cultivation. And then of course we also
looked for something that's actually
relevant and easy to get your hands on
in our region here in in
Appalachia. Um and it turns out actually
that beat armyworm was an a real pest
that was an issue that that growers had
to face and deal with. And at the same
time there's a a small company that
rears these insects these these these
larae and we can simply buy and they buy
them from them and get them shipped
here. And there's no legal restrictions.
You know, sometimes with pest insects,
you got to be a little bit careful. You
can't just move them over said lines.
But in case of beat army one, that
wasn't a problem because it is already a
natural pest here. So, we're not
introducing something that wouldn't be
here. And so, we finally settled on on
using them. So, we can we get little
caterpillars from that are pre-re. We
keep them here for a little while and
then we actually allow them to feed on
our on our hemp plants. uh and they
actually do quite a bit of damage um in
a relatively short amount of time. They
they start off feeding on leaves but
then at some point they also move to the
flowers. We have damage on leaves and we
also have damage on flowers and then
under very controlled conditions how
kind of determined how long we had to
leave them on there and then measured
cannabonoid contents and indeed saw that
cannaboid production um was quite
significantly
upregulated and actually upregulated to
a level where we would be in violation
or could get into violation if we were
would be growers.
of the legal limit. Yeah. So that this
clearly indicated that insect herbivy if
you're growing CBD uh hemp um can be a
can be a problem for you as a grower.
So, I mean, one of the easy to take
take-home messages from that work was
already just yes, you got to scout for
insects, pest insects if you're growing,
and you got to take care of that, which
I know is not easy because depending on
what time on life status or um of your
of your plants, you're you probably
don't want to spray much because I mean,
then you you're running into problems
there again. But scouting early on,
making sure you don't have a lot of
herbivy and if so, take the right
measures is definitely one of the one of
the core
things. So this this was the first
finding, but then story kind of
developed a little bit more.
Um, we saw that compounds, major
cannabonoids like THC, CBD, CBG, some of
the those things were
upregulated. But then we saw since we're
in
our cannabonoid analysis, we're not just
seeing those major cannabonoids, but
we're seeing a lot of other so-called
minor cannabonoids as well. And what we
were surprised is to see that those were
also upregulated and actually also quite
not all of them but some of them and
some of them actually quite
significantly. So things that were in
our analytics before tiny little peaks
and difficult to detect were very
detectable afterwards. So significantly
upregulated and increased and that of
course we we got really excited about
that and and sort of draw our attention
to uh because like we were wondering
like what the heck is going on
there and tpines were also upregulated
but
not all of them and also not to an
extent that was
really very extreme. Yeah, it was a
little bit of an up regulation, but um
nothing really that that was
particularly didn't knock me out of my
shoes that way. And that was a little
bit surprising because we originally had
my expectation when we started this was
that rather the tarpen might be
affecting insects because that's what
they do in a lot of other plants. So I
have a couple of other projects where we
do similar things and very often
turppins or some turppines are the ones
that are actually really kind of
affecting insects. And so my
initial assumption or expectation or
hypothesis was that yeah in hemp it's
probably also going to be turbines being
involved in that. And from the first
results it did not look quite like that.
I'm I don't want to exclude that the
tpines play no role but it was that that
the response on the cannabonoid side was
much more significant than than what we
saw on the tarpine side and that was a
little unexpected.
Okay, I have a few a few questions from
that.
Um first question is in relation to the
tarpen are we talking you know a
statistically significant increase?
Yes. Yes. For some of them, not all of
them. Yeah. But for some of them, it was
a significant increase, but it was from
the extent was not as dramatic as some
of the the the responses we saw on the
cannabonoid side. In in in case of some
of the cannabonoids, we see like a
five-fold increase. That was my next
question. So, you're you're saying
massive increases. Okay. Really massive
increases. Yeah. Uh I'm not saying THC
necessarily or CBD, but some of the
other things we really see like quite
significant increases and with the
turppines we maybe see a one and a
halffold increase or something like
that. Yeah. So by far not as dramatic.
Yeah. I'm not saying that that they
don't play any role, but it was really
not kind of quite what we had expected
initially.
Um, so that got us really kind of like a
little bit wondering what the heck is
going on there.
Um, and of course whenever you find
something like that, of course we want
to understand why that biologically
makes sense. Why do you have these
upregulation of cannabonoids there? Um,
what is it doing? And that brings me
back to what we were talking about
before with the herbyss. Yeah.
So, if if you have an upregulation of
THC or CBD and your herbivore is a
mammal, I'm not saying a human, but a
mammal, a little rodent. Um, you can
explain how that might affect that
herbivore. Yeah, they do have the same
cannabonoid receptors that we have and
I'm not saying they're getting a high,
but they're for sure going to have some
some experience there or some exposure
to it and would probably kind of
reconsider feeding on that plant the
next time potentially. So, you can see
how that would
work. Interesting thing is with
insects, they don't have the cannabonoid
receptors that we and other mammals
have.
And that of course brings up the
question like then how does it affect
insects? Are there cannabonoids that
affect insects?
Is so so one thing I was wondering is
how targeted is is are plants able to
distinguish in regards to like how
targeted is their approach defensive
approach. So like for example, can a
plant distinguish between thris damage
and caterpillar damage and maybe for
thris it may increase tarpen whereas
caterpillars it focuses on cannonoids.
Is that a possibility or are plants not
able to tell if I'm cutting it with
scissors or if it's I mean I assume
there's some sort of chemical
interaction happening like you mentioned
with being able to spray something to
get a similar plant response.
Well, the first thing that that the the
first thing you can distinguish on the
insect side is is what type of insect
you have there. And you brought two
examples up there. The one is
caterpillars, which fall into the group
of so-called biting chewing insects. So,
they actually really consume leaf
tissue. They bite into tissue and munch
it up basically.
Um the other example that you had was
thris or you could add a couple of these
other things like aphits,
uh white flies,
spidermitites. The those are generally
kind of considered as as as piercing
sucking insects. So they either feed on
the the the the the vascular tissue or
the content of it or they actually suck
out cell content. So they puncture
individual cells and like
suck the content of the cell up. That is
a completely different type of feeding
so to say and the damage that you you're
you you're seeing is a completely
different
one. So we did not see much
response
with piercing sucking insects although
we have not really used them a lot. I
know some people have seen effects when
they were using aphits. Uh so I don't
want to exclude that but we haven't seen
that in our
analysis. So we primarily kind of
concentrated on on on biting chewing
insects that really have consumable
tissue. Um we actually have used a
couple different ones in the meanwhile
and we we see the same response. So
we're pretty sure that that is pretty
uniform there. Um so and that is
something that the plant can can
distinct. Yeah. I mean there is a
difference in difference in the response
of plants if they're sort of um
experiencing herbivy by abiding chewing
insects versus a piercing sucking even
though the the sort of the the signaling
within the plant is different when
they're exposed to these diff different
types of insects. But you're right. I
mean what the other thing that you just
mentioned before is so what the plant
can perceive is not just this when you
have a caterpillar or a beetle nibbling
around there it's not just the wounding
of tissue the plant can
actually
recognize the insect side of things as
well. So plants do have per se in
general have receptors for the saliva of
insects. Uh so it's not just the
wounding. Um there is publications not
from hemp but from other plants where
plants can perceive the feces of
insects. So very often if there's a
caterpillar or a beetle or something
like roaming around on a plant, they
leave their they basically defecate on
the plant. They leave their feces behind
and there's things in there that the
plant can recognize. So, uh, plants can
recognize quite a lot of things,
[Music]
um, sort of traces that an insect would
leave behind if it's on a plant and
feeding there.
So, someone might develop a caterpillar
feces spray someday that we could spray
on our plant to get upregulation of
secondary metabolites. In theory, in
theory, yes. I can tell you from from
research that people have actually
collected the saliva of insects and have
diluted that and sprayed it on plants
and that led to a response with even
without the wounding but you can combine
it with the wounding and then you even
get a stronger response. So there's
there there's some good literature out
there, not from hemp necessarily or
cannabis, but from other plants. But I
mean, this is by now it's pretty
accepted that that's a pretty general
response of plants that they're capable
of recognizing these sorts of things.
Yes.
So, one other thing you touched on I
just want to highlight and make sure I
understand
is this idea that um chewing insects
like the caterpillars that you worked
with created a much higher response uh
in terms of secondary metabolite
production than sucking piercing
insects. Um, so the practical
application of this might be if you are
seeing aphids in your hemp grow that may
be less concerning than caterpillars or
rodent damage or other things in terms
of the THC response that you may see
from that herbivy in in theory just pure
hypothesis in theory. I mean like I said
we did not see a response when we
mimicked aphit feeding so to say and
again we never used aphits we mimicked
this kind of feeding with with with some
treatments there we did not see a
response there but I'm aware that there
are some reports from other groups where
they did see a response of plants upon
aphid feeding so I don't want to
completely exclude that I I I can't just
say we did not see it but that doesn't
mean this be could be again your what
you mentioned before your genetic
diversity basically maybe there are some
varieties where you see that response
and others not. Uh of course we only
used a few hemp varieties and not not
too many. I mean we it it needs to be
manageable for on our side.
Um I mean I wouldn't generalize it as
you said. I mean, you're you might be
right that I would be more concerned
about about sort of herbivy by
caterpillars or beetles or so biting
chewing insects if you're concerned
about your THC level. I would not say
that I would not be worried about aphid
infestation. Um the problem in general
is that piercing sucking insects very
often serve as vectors for uh for
viruses. So even a very low level of
infestation can create a lot of problems
because once your plants are infested
with a virus
um there's no cure. Yeah. Um and so you
definitely as a grower you definitely
should should scout for for these
insects as well very carefully and and
take respensic respective measures if
you if you find them on on your plants.
uh because any of these little critters
can can barely make your plant sick and
then then you really got a problem
there. Um maybe not because of the THC
level but maybe because of the the the
status overall status of your plants
basically and your entire facility.
That's the other thing. Sure. And in
general pathogens are pretty devastating
to crops but have you seen any research
of pathogens increasing secondary
metabolite production?
I personally not I mean we never worked
with pathogens. Um okay I'm not
necessarily aware of a lot of literature
but um I don't want to exclude it um at
all. Again tpines definitely have an
effect on pathogens. We're currently
working on something similar here with
in collaboration with another group here
with tomatoes. Um and it's there's
plenty literature
um where tip beans have have been shown
to have badly in general antimicrobial
activity which includes bacteria and and
and fungi or pathogens. Um so I'm not
aware that cannabonoids are having
similar effects but I don't want to
completely exclude it. I'm just not
aware of it but the tpines definitely
have quite dramatic effects there. So
that that could very well have have an
effect in in hemp and cannabis as well.
Now now cannabis seems to respond pretty
well to uh pretty aggressive pruning,
mechanical pruning. Uh would that I'm
learning today about how a plant can
sense all of these other aspects of
herbivy. So I had I had assumed that
what we when we were pruning heavily we
were mimicking at least certain aspects
of herbivy. But what are your thoughts
on that? I guess can we create these
similar mimic mimicry?
Um so any type of wounding of your pl of
a plant in principle kind of has
somewhat of that effect or can have that
effect. But one thing you have to keep
in mind is that if you do pruning or do
by accident wound your plant one time
that might very briefly induce something
but it's a a lot of this is happening on
a time scale basically. So if you wound
a leaf you might see a little induction
but that drops back down to baseline
level very quickly with I wouldn't say
within hours but within a day or so very
quickly. So for a more substantial up
regulation
um you would have to have a little bit
more a persistent and ongoing sort of
process and that's normally what you
rather face if you have an infestation
with a herbivore. Yeah, a herbivore
normally doesn't just come by bite in
one leaf and then move on and go
somewhere else. It normally stays on
your plant for quite a bit of time. And
unfortunately, a lot of insects have the
ability to propagate very quickly. And
so you're not going to have just one
insect nibbling on your plant, but in no
matter of time, you're probably going to
have multiple insects nibbling on your
plant. And then that that is this
persistent ongoing herbivy. And that of
course leads to a completely different
response. Yeah. From the extent that you
Yeah. Okay. That's really interesting
because when I when I think about it
like as a as a indoor cultivator, we
tend to have to do uh defoliation of
most most genetic cultivars uh just to
increase the amount of light and air
that's getting the plant and maximize
our photosynthesis and reduce the risk
of pathogens and and pest pressure by
having microclimates inside our canopy.
Um but what you're saying is when we do
that we
me certain plant responses but they're
short-lived whereas that insect is going
to be constantly nibbling and so it's
essentially just keeping the plant
stressed the entire time so you see
upregulation of that over a longer
period which is more likely to lead to
these increases in metabolite
production. Ah exact exactly. Yeah. So I
I one time pruning yeah you might see a
little bit of an effect there but it's
not going to be very persistent versus
if you have an a past infestation which
normally lasts for quite a bit of time
then you're probably going to see much
more of it. The other question of course
is
also at what time of the sort of the the
the the growth cycle are you going to
have that? Yeah, I would assume your
pruning you do not on the very last
stage of before you harvest. You
probably would do that sometimes earlier
because you kind of like like you
described, you kind of want to get
maximum light exposure. You want to have
air flow in there and maybe avoid these
microclimates, etc., etc. You're
probably not going to do that in the
very two days before you harvest. Yeah,
you're going to do that while you're
cultivating, while you're growing.
Um, so as long as you do that sort of in
the more vegetative part of the the the
growth stage, you're not going to have
much of an effect. Yeah. But if you have
that in the very last stage shortly
before you start um harvesting anything,
then of course and and then if it's
extended, then you might see much more
of an effect. Yeah. So it really it's
the timing and and and the frequency of
sort of the these events happening that
might have an influence there. Yeah. I I
I think there's a balance there. And we
do a pretty big defoliation, say like
week three of flower, week two, right
around there. Um but then I I I like to
go through and just pick leaves when I'm
in my when I'm in my grow um as I'm
going through it because the plants
always respond bounce back so quickly.
And I wonder if that might actually have
some benefit. Though the downside of
this, just to make people aware, when
you're doing any sort of wounding, you
are opening yourself up to greater risk
of pathogens. You've created a perfect
place for pathogens get your plants. So,
there's there's pros and cons to it, I
suppose. We may see increased benefit
from herbivy, but we may see, you know,
a massive a higher risk of of pathogen
pressure. Um well on a on a very on a
very practical side I mean if you're
using tools for doing your pruning uh
you want to be very careful because you
could be spreading diseases from one
plant that is affected infected to
others just using the same clippers.
Yeah absolutely
even without any pests. So I I I mean
like we're always very careful with
these sorts of things. I mean, you want
to wash and sanitize your your tools
that you're using in in in your in your
growth facility if you're moving around
and you're maybe already suspecting that
you have something that's diseased
somewhere in there because otherwise you
don't need any other factor for
spreading things is actually you
spreading things from one plant to the
next. Yes. And and insects can be a
vector too for folks. So, um I I do have
a couple other questions. I want to
totally switch gears, but I'm looking at
an article about you in greenhouse uh
management on online here, and one of
the things that it mentions is that your
lab was studying interactions between
microisal fungi and plant roots and how
that impacts cannabonoid production or
accumulation. Can you just touch on that
because I know we've been talking for a
while, maybe I'll have to have you back
on, but can you touch briefly on that?
Well, that was one one idea initially
and that really didn't get too far. Um,
we had we had another group here in in
in my college here that that that is is
is is working on on microisal fungi. We
actually for quite a number of years we
were hosting what's called INVAM which
is one of the largest uh um
international national and international
collection of microisal fungi here. Um
the in the meanwhile since the faculty
that was in charge of that retired um
that has moved on and is now in Kansas
um but um we still had some of that
collection here and we were just trying
to play around with that to see if micro
actually how good they interact with
hemp or not. Um and we ran into quite a
quite a bit of roadblocks there. I'm not
saying it doesn't work at all, but that
was kind of not
um particularly too easy to work it out.
Uh in particular, because for the
purpose of how we need to how we need to
do these inoculations,
uh for the for the research side of
things, the growth conditions, the hemp
plants really didn't like
particularly. Um, so I'm not saying that
microisal fungi would not interact with
with the roots of of hemp plants, but
under the conditions that these folks
here wanted to grow the plants for
inoculation, the hemp plants just didn't
like the condition particularly. So, we
kind of gave up a little bit at at some
point following up on that. Um, so um
can't really tell you much about that.
What I can tell you what we're currently
doing and that follows a little bit more
on along the the the lines of what is
what I was describing before with
herbivy. We're currently looking into um
interaction of nematodes
um with um the roots of hemp plants
uh because that could that could lead to
a very similar response as the herbivy
uh and we have some promising results in
that. Um we're following up on that
right now and I hope in the next couple
weeks we can actually collect some more
samples and then do some more analysis
on that. So, we're looking a little bit
into that because that could be another
point where you could have one of these
biotic interactions. And I mean, you're
probably not going to see neat hose if
you're growing in a controlled
environment. Uh, but if you have your
your your hemp or cannabis plants
growing in a field situation, you're
definitely going to see nematodeses. I
mean there's nothing you can do about um
what species of nematodes are you
talking like root not nematodeses or
what exactly and we're testing a couple
different ones but yeah that's that's
one of them we're testing there so um
and that is a little bit on the
backdrops and got to go back a little
bit to what what I said before so once
we had seen with the insect herbivy that
we had this massive regulation of some
of these minor cannabonoids we curtis
kind of started
think a little bit of how this actually
makes sense. And one of the things that
we did is that we actually looked into
other plant tissues than you would
normally do. So most people probably
know of course we're all aware that
cannabonoids are formed in tricoms of of
the flowers. Um there's also tricoms on
leaves and they do produce some
cannabonoids. Also the profile is a
little bit different than in the flowers
but there is and the levels are much
lower. But we basically systematically a
little bit more systematically looked
into different plant tissues
u in hemp plants as to if there would be
producing cannabonoids. And long story
short yes there are cannabonoids and
other plant tissues. It's not just
flowers and leaves.
And knowing that now it starts making
much more sense. Uh so we also found
some cannabonoids and roots. Yeah. And
that's a little bit the back background
of that. So now we're that maybe the
cannabonoids and the roots also have an
effect on on inter biotic interactions
in the roots. So we can't yet confirm
that finally, but I mean everything that
we have points a little bit in this
direction.
Um, and so that's why we're following up
on that. And and in
particular, it seems to be not the usual
major cannabonoids that play a role in
these things, but it's rather some of
the minor cannabonoids that play a role
there.
So it so what what could be is that some
of the major cannabonoids are actually
there either due to human
cultivation or more for interaction with
mammals and that some of these minor
cannabonoids are actually there are for
interaction with insects and other
non-malian herbivores if you want to
phrase it that way and then if you
consider that it would makes perfect
sense if some of these compounds are
being produced in other tissues that of
course are being exposed to herbivy
similar to leaves or flowers. Yeah. So
that's a little bit where we are right
now. And so yeah, I can't wait to see
what your results are on that. That's
really fascinating. Um yeah, that's
that's amazing. I had not something that
was even on my radar in terms of
thinking of like root herbivy from the
perspective of well I mean one one other
thing that is becoming clear now and
that was kind of one of the big
questions on the science side of things
is a little bit
um why are we aware of cannabonoids just
in the context of hemp and cannabis
plants and or are they indeed the only
plant producing cannibal oids. Um, and
that has a little bit to do with the
biochemistry of things because the the
building blocks that you need to make a
cannabonoid compound are actually
present in principle in any other plant
as well. And so is for us on the the
biochemistry side, it was a little bit
of a puzzle
to accept the fact that cannabonoids
would be really just produced in in
cannabis plants and not anywhere else.
uh
and actually in the last couple years
literally last three four years there
have been a few publications now from
other plants where cannabonoids are
being found. So it seems to be not just
cannabis but other plants as well and
fungi. Correct.
Yes. There there is there are some other
organisms that can do it but in in
plants there are some other plants and
they're not related to cannabis. That's
the other thing that's kind of
interesting. So, and that's kind of one
of the was one of the one of the
questions out
there that we were also kind of I we're
not working on this currently, but of
course we're following this this
literature and and and this this area
quite interest in particular with
knowing what we found with respect to
herbivy where we're like wondering well
if that's if that's if if you can
produce it in other plants as well then
then it might become much more
interesting.
So what we actually and I think I
mentioned that in our last meeting
already a little bit that we haven't re
recently submitted uh a provisional
patent on some of these minor
cannibonoids due to their insecticidal
activity that we discovered. Um because
we think that if if if if they really
have this activity as we've we've found,
this could be something where we could
actually use some of those as an organic
insecticide basically. And you could
also go down the road and basically not
breed because of course it's you can't
breed if it's not a cannabis plant, but
you could genetically engineer it in
other plants and and and basically by by
that protect other plants um through
cannabonoid formation.
So you're saying that
if if cannabonoids truly are response to
a rivery and may offer some sort of in
insect protection
um you would expect to find it in other
plants too because other plants would
have evolved to have this. And now
you're saying that in recent years we've
discovered that it does exist in other
plants. And so there there's just
stronger evidence that that the the
possibility these minor canabonoids
cannabonoids may play a role in plant
defense and that down the road we may be
able to
man manipulate that or understand
utilize it. Thank you. That's the word I
was looking for. Okay. All right. Last
question though because we've already
gone over our time.
Um, you mentioned this and I hadn't
heard this that you can use tarpen as a
bofuel additive in this article. Can you
just in a minute or two just touch on
that because I found that real
fascinating. I had never heard this.
Okay. Yeah, that that's that's a
completely different avenue. So,
totally. Yeah, there there is quite a
bit of interest in tarpen as sort of a
fuel um either as an additive or even as
a as a pure fuel by itself. Um the the
simple logic behind it is is turppines
are volatile compound. They're scent
compounds. So they they from their
physical physicochemical properties go
into the emit into the atmosphere at
relatively low temperatures. Yeah. So,
so barely at at ambient room
temperatures they they're they're
emitted into the into the gas phase and
and that's why plants are using them as
a way of communicating basically. Yeah.
But that's a property that you want to
have for fuel as well. So, one of the
problems with bofuels is that I mean if
you take your your canola oil as a
biodiesel
um if you put that in the tank of your
car and in winter the temperatures are
low um your your oil starts
solidifying basically your vegetable oil
turns into magarine. Yeah. And of course
you can't drive on that. Yeah. Uh that's
a problem because it's not liquid
anymore. uh and the same problem you're
also facing if you think about
sustainable
sustainable aviation fuels. So when
you're flying a plane at 30
35,000 feet altitude, it's -60 out
there. And of course any fuel that have
you have in your tank of your plane also
needs to stay liquid because otherwise
you can't fly on it anymore. And so that
that's with kerosene that's the case.
And so that's the same thing when you
want to have replace kerosene with
something more sustainable. You have to
make sure that whatever fuel you're
using it stays liquid at low
temperatures. Yeah. And
tarpines check mark that box. Basically
you can really chill them down to quite
low temperatures and they're still
liquid. And so either by using them
purely or by mixing them in and by that
basically also lowering the temp the the
the solidification. So basically the
temperature by which a a a fuel solid.
Yeah. The freezing or melting point.
Yeah. Yeah. Um so basically you can do a
mixture or a pure. So there are actually
this and this is actually being done
already. So even the the the the the US
military, the air force has already done
and flown planes on turppines. So
they're using it as as as an aviation
fuel already. I mean, of course, this is
experimental. This is not a final
applied state, but it is definitely an
idea that is is more than just the the
brainchild of some some weird scientist.
Um so this is this is really has some
some real world applications already.
And basically the idea is like you know
I mean we can drive our cars with
electricity now. Um we can replace fuel
consumptions with bally uh electricity
and hopefully you get that from
renewable sources but you can't fly a
plane on electricity at least not for
very far. I mean short distances you can
do but
international aviation doesn't work with
electricity. Yeah. that that that that
that it's just not doable. And so for
certain purposes, you still need a fuel,
a chemical. Uh and if you want to do
that a little bit more sustainable, then
you have to come up with ideas. And
turppins are one of those things that's
out there sort of in the uh in the in in
in in the portfolio of ideas that are
currently being considered and tested
out.
And I mean bringing it back to hemp, I
mean they're producing a lot of
turppines and so it could be in the long
run an interesting crop where you could
potentially produce turppines that then
you could use as a as a fuel additive
there later on. So that's this is one of
the other ideas or or or reasons why
we're interested in metabolism of hemp
and cannabis because there could be
completely different applications than
what we're thinking about right now.
And that could be one of those. I'm not
saying that that we're going down that
road at some point. Yeah, I just hadn't
heard that. It's fascinating and I just
wanted to, you know, hear your thoughts
on it. Um, so thank you for sharing and
thank you for your time today. I I have
a better understanding of uh plant
stress and herbivy and uh yeah, thank
you for the research that you're doing.
Sure. Yeah, glad to be on. Thanks for
the invite. Hope it helps. All right.
Have a wonderful day. Yeah, you too.
Good talking to you. Take care. That was
Dr. Michael Guten and you were listening
to the Cannabis Cultivation and Science
podcast. Don't forget to check out the
podcast page at
www.korganics.com. Just click on the
learn tab and then podcast. And a
friendly reminder that we do have a
Patreon channel with a free 7-day trial
in tiers as low as $5 a month. We do
book clubs, special cultivation tips and
tricks, monthly video hangouts to
connect and share your grow, and even
give out seed packs and other gifts at
certain tier levels. Your support of
Patreon or sourcing your products
through Kiss Organics is really what
supports the podcast, and we really
appreciate it. We also have the upcoming
Cannabis Cultivation and Science
Conference in Bosezeman, Montana this
year in September, and there's more
information and tickets available on our
website. Thanks for listening.