[Music]
welcome to the cannabis cultivation and
science podcast
I'm your host tad hussy of kiss organics
this is the podcast where we discussed
the cutting edge of organic growing from
a science-based perspective and drawn
top experts from around the industry to
share their wisdom and knowledge our
guest today is Ron Wallace Ron is a two
time world record holder three-time
world champion and was the first grower
in the world to grow a pumpkin over 1500
pounds in 2006 and in 2012 he was the
first to eclipse the 2000 pound barrier
at 2009 pounds today he is regarded as
one of the world's premier giant pumpkin
growers he has appeared on many local
and national TV shows and been the
subject of numerous books newspaper and
nationally recognized magazine articles
hey Ron thanks for coming on the show
today I really appreciate it it's great
to get to chat with you over the air hi
Ted yeah great to be on the show looking
forward to it well let's start off
giving listeners a little bit of your
personal history and how you got into
growing giant pumpkins sure well my dad
was I believe the first person in New
England to grow giant pumpkins you know
and start talking about it competitively
and that was back in the in the early
80s he started doing it in his you know
small backyard in West walk Rhode Island
back in those days there wasn't much
information on giant pumpkins out that
matter of fact it was none you had to
get on the phone and try to call
somebody or write somebody a letter and
you know so he did it you know close to
10 years and then never really achieved
any success that he was looking for so
he kind of got out of them get out of
the hobby at the time and I remember
back in 1992 and 93 I was at my parents
home for Christmas and somebody had
bought him a book how to grow
world-class giant pumpkins by dawn
Langevin so I read the whole book
the cover on Christmas Day and I said
you know we got to give this another
shot because now we have some
information that we can we can try to
use in a garden so since the early 90s
it's kind of been obsessive-compulsive
and education and knowledge trying to
grow the world's biggest pumpkin so it's
it's been a wild ride since the early
90s and you've actually had some success
in the giant pumpkin world can you talk
a little bit about where you started in
terms of what size your pumpkins were
and the genetics and how that sort of
evolved into eventually getting
literally the world record sure
well the genetics is what separates you
know this hobby and the networking
amongst the giant pumpkin community is
incredible it's like no other community
I've ever witnessed that's the reason
why we can take on 900 anywhere from 800
to a thousand square foot we're growing
pumpkins on the verge of heading towards
3,000 pounds I mean well records at 26
24 so it's been the genetics and a
sharing of knowledge and information and
all the genetic crosses that have taken
place since those early days that have
put us to this point and I was fortunate
to get a couple of really good you know
what you call hot seed stocks that
everybody everybody wanted in their day
and it enabled me to you know set a
couple of Guinness World Records and
some North American Championships but
it's it's been the work of the whole
community and when the internet evolved
in the early 90s and that's where I got
all my information from back then after
Don's books was getting on the internet
and talking to soil scientist if they
would talk to you know many would kind
of just hang up and brush me off if they
heard Ron Wallace was on the phone but
that kind of changed years later because
a lot of those people seek us out now in
the community to see what we're doing
and how we're fertilizing and things
like that so it's pretty much been you
know the networking of the community the
sharing of information the genetics
being a big one you know pruning
techniques you know being another one
and you know right soil biology and
mycorrhizal on
killings which have you know put parking
growing on the verge where if you don't
have 2,000 pound pumpkin you're probably
not going to win the way off you're
going to and that's incredible thinking
that when we started out to be a member
of the 500 pound Club was something
everybody strobe you know scribe for and
then it was you know the 700 pound club
then it was oh my god a thousand pound
club and at the seminars that they had
in Canada at the time I used to get up
there and be one of two people or three
people who grew a thousand-pound pumpkin
to be like oh my god I I really want to
be on that stage someday growing our
thousand pound pumpkin and now you know
with the right genetics and the right
system going on you know forty five
fifty days after you pollinate your
pumpkin there's a lot of pumpkins on the
verge of a thousand pounds or more and
that's just incredible that's amazing I
so I've been trying my hand at it for
the last few years I've been fortunate
enough to know Dona Geneva Emmons their
local to me and wonderful people and
then Ryan Ewing has been really generous
and sharing some of the genetics from
his squash and pumpkins and some of the
seeds that he has and I think a couple
years ago my record is 725 pounds but
I'm not doing all of the bearing all the
vines and doing all the training and
everything that really needs to be done
to really grow a huge giant but 725
pounds was a huge hit with the preschool
kids on the property and everyone that
came to the farm which is so blown away
by the pumpkin and I know it's not that
big compared to what you guys do but it
still was pretty pretty amazing for us
it was it was great well not everybody
gets involved in the Hobby is to try to
set set records I really wish I wasn't
so competitive you know I want all my
friends to do well and the network of
the family and the friends that we've
made over the you know 25 plus years has
been incredible but you know I swing for
the fences and a lot of people do and
Irish I wish I really wasn't that way
it'd be a lot less pressure growing to
be honest with you but the majority the
people get involved in the hobby is to
get something
oh that they can be proud of put her out
in front of their house I get emails
pretty much every day I get somebody who
call me the other day in it it moves me
when he said that he was making memories
with his grandson that are gonna last a
lifetime growing his giant pumpkin so
there's there's far more people who you
know still 700 pounds is a heck of an
accomplishment to grow something that
that big I bet people emailed me so it's
my first year I I didn't do that great
I'd only had a thousand pounds I said
well that took us you know almost twelve
years and thousands of thousands of
dollars and hundreds and hundreds of
hours of back-breaking work to try to
achieve those results to let the
information the information is out there
now and how to grow these giant pumpkins
there's no more secrets so there's a lot
of people who went before other people
nowadays to put the information out
there on the internet but that there's
far more growing just to enjoy it and
have you know a pumpkin for their family
than it is somebody who's trying to set
a record and you'll notice you'll never
hear me mention about winning money yes
there's money to be won if you went away
off and I've been fortunate to win some
but nobody grows giant pumpkins to has a
I set on winning cash prizes because
those are few and far between can you
give a little bit about sort of the
history of the giant pumpkin community
in terms of where you guys started and
where you are now
I mean you've thrown a few numbers out
there but I don't know if listeners
realize how much how rapidly the
industry has evolved over the last even
just the last decade and sort of how
your techniques have changed over that
time - sure well Howard dill a farmer in
Nova Scotia is the one that we can
credit for coming up with the Dill's the
Dill's Atlantic giant you know so and
how it was a he's a four-time four-time
world world champion and you know in the
late 70s and early 80's he was doing the
painstaking work I'm making the genetic
crosses you know that we still enjoy
today they all all of these genes
although they're different they all
revert back to Howard dill in his early
and his early work you know once again
back at the time I think his world
record was 400 pounds somewhere in the
1980s early eighties somewhere and you
know like I said once the Internet you
know came upon you know people start to
figure out that you have to bury these
vines in order to get a double root
system because with him where the vines
run wherever there's a leaf stalk
there's a root that will that will pop
up through the top and you have to
stabilize the plant so where we've made
the biggest advances is the technique of
pruning and anybody who knows anything
knows pruning alters the state of a
plant and generally for good
it forces growth in different areas and
so we only let the side vines go so long
now now we kind of know what's between
12 and 15 feet on the side vine we we
pretty much have figured out that to try
to be a contender you need a plant in
the square foot range of probably seven
hundred to a thousand maybe even a
maximum a 1200 square foot so the vine
burying you know became one of the big
keys and the pruning and along with that
is you know how much kelp meal you know
grow has put about 15 pounds of kelp
meal per thousand square foot in the
spring to offer a lot of micronutrients
and things like that the internet was
the first big push of the hobby in the
early 90s and then mycorrhizal fungi
took giant pumpkins to a different level
you know back in around 2006 when I set
my first world record I started studying
mycorrhizae around 2003 2004 I started
making phone calls and you know I found
Bob Linderman that I believe is Oregon
State University at the time when we
started educating me more on the
benefits of it so I started studying it
I it and set a world record in 2006 and
pretty much everybody today who's
growing competitively uses you know
mycorrhizal fungi either benefits
the benefits of it are endless and it
really helps us do what we got to do as
far as bringing water back to the hosts
and nutrients and people think
mycorrhizae is just about phosphorus
it's not it's about water it's about
nutrients it's about a healthy root
system so those have been the big the
big advancements and you know another
one that goes in there as a sharing of
the seeds and the education of it is
free because once again back in the day
people who were winning weren't letting
people know what they were doing and
back in the day the people who were
winning you know they were adding a lot
of compost and cow manure and yeah there
wasn't as many people growing as
nowadays not taking anything away from
him you know they were innovators they
had certain techniques that we still use
today but the internet took giant
pumpkin grow into a whole different
level as far as the sharing and
knowledge and education and and all for
free so for a while there weren't giant
pumpkin growers primarily growing
conventionally so using you know
chemical nutrients mineral salts and
then started reincorporated in back some
of these biological additives you
mentioned mycorrhizal fungus I know some
people use compost teas and compost what
what that what was that point in time
and how did that transition sort of
increase the ability of the pumpkin of
the yields of these pumpkins well and
that's a very good question because you
know compost teas certainly is used you
know essentially I still find compost
tea requires a little bit more education
on our pot because there's a lot of
snake oil as you know out there so a lot
of a lot of people need to be educated
on compost teas but there's a very big
percentage of growers who are either
using someone's or making their own so
that helps specifically but back in the
day all farming was was kind of
synthetics and you laid it down and and
that was it so even major farming now
has changed whether you find that you
know those fertilizers we will use him
we're killing the soil microbes and
because it was so heavy and so
and you know a lot of it is you know you
using potassium fertilizers that was the
same as throwing rocks all on your
driveway in the winter to kill to get
rid of the ice and that's what people
were putting in the garden so what we
found over the years is that there needs
to be a mix between some synthetic and
mostly biological most people's programs
are probably 80% biological 20% kind of
synthetic fertilizers because sometimes
you need that little extra push that a
synthetic will give you right away but
we've learned we've educated about we
feel like I tell people we feed our soil
and the soil feeds our plants we let the
microbes consume organic matter and
release it in the what I like to call a
micro rise fair right now area in and
around the roots where no plants can use
it and you know it will only take what
it needs for nutrients like when you use
synthetics or something else it's you
know it's just like releasing pigs in a
buffet I like to say because they're
just going to eat eat and eat and that's
not the best thing at times to because
we strive for balance so within the last
technique specifically giant pumpkin
growers have sort of switched their
programs to more biologicals there's a
lot of asel sprawling you know being
used bacillus subtilis and things like
that you know I could go on and on but a
lot of growers they're all using it they
all have you know their own little
system or maybe some biologicals they
like humic folic acid pretty much used
by me every time I water or fertilize to
help make nutrients more available helps
feeds microbes so whenever I'm
fertilizing my plant I like to say once
again I'm fertilizing my soil to make
sure I get a good population of microbes
doing their thing now feel free to
correct me if I get this wrong but as it
was explained to me that one of the
issues that giant pumpkin growers were
having was because of the high amounts
of chemical fertilizers that were being
used the plants were more prone to
cracking or splitting which is a
disqualification in the giant pumpkin
world for those of you that don't aren't
familiar with it if you have a crack or
split your pumpkin is is done for the
season but also you're more
open to diseases and things like that as
you're pushing this pumpkins so hard to
put on weight is that an accurate
statement yep that's all that's all
correct you know you can't push them too
hard
especially with you know like I said
with synthetics and stuff like that and
yes you're more prone to disease because
Fusarium Pythium Rhizoctonia all those
things that you know cucurbits which are
pumpkins they say you know plant like a
year on soil and then get off of it for
five years
because that's how prone they are to
disease and I've had my handful of
disease problems here and continue to
monitor it and you know all of those
diseases I just mentioned love nitrogen
and water and as a giant pumpkin grower
you're pushing both but the nitrogen
that you get from using synthetics far
pushes you know nutrient you know even
deficiencies at was because once they
get bloated they tie up other nutrients
say that you'll be missing but they also
help push disease too so we backed off
that yes but the splitting you know
whether it's a small crack that gets in
or in a ring what we call a dill ring in
a pumpkin where a pumpkin grows so fast
they get cross-sections and little split
stem splits used to be prevalent years
and years ago and I think a big part of
that was genetics number one and number
two was the use of synthetic so that
that's kind of been eliminated a bit
from the hobby you don't see many stem
splits anymore because people won't grow
them next year that's what I've been one
of the great things about chat rooms and
in the internet is you see what these
pumpkin seeds are growing and if you
don't like the shape or if you're a
color person you don't like the color or
that had a bad stem you just won't plant
it next year and it keeps sort of those
bad traits out of the hobby but yeah
definitely we've noticed that we've been
able to get more pumpkins to the scale
since we've since we've imported more of
an organic approach to it not to say
that any of us are strictly organic
there are some people who grow that way
it's possible but in in our area where
it's you know like today's 92 degrees
all the
80% humidity and tonight the low will be
70 degrees that we humid all night you
have to work in some chemicals on
occasion or you'll never make it to the
end of the season yeah you know I grow
organically because that's sort of our
philosophy but I get powdery mildew
every year which I know you know is
affecting my overall yield but I'm not
going for a world record either so it's
a very different situation it sounds
like it's a sort of a common a hybrid
approach that's really allowing you to
maximize plant growth and we actually
see this with the cannabis industry to
some of the biggest yields I've seen
have been sort of that combination of
biologicals and chemicals yes and that's
definitely what that's definitely what's
happening in our in our hobby it's a
combination too because you know when
you need to color up if you've got
something going on like right now we got
what we call fruit load stress these
pumpkins are approaching if they're
going to be an all-star they got to be
hit in between 30 and 50 plus pounds a
day for the next month and if you notice
you start to get a little lime green or
you stop the tie ups and nutrients or
you know if you've got to go to the whip
and color them up you know that's not
gonna happen you know you could only
feed the soil so much you have to pop in
some synthetics to get it to green up
and but it's such a small amount
compared to what it used to be so yes
the biggest yields we're finding is
people who are combining both and
there's plenty of studies out on the
internet using biologicals in
combination with synthetic fertilizers
where now you know a lot of you know a
lot of technology and the papers and
field trials that they're doing are
coming out saying that the yields were
increased using both in combination
maybe 80 20 or something like that I
know a lot of people who grow strictly
organic you know don't want to hear that
but the results are out there now where
you can see combining them both in the
program works it works a bit better but
it's all in what you want to go after
you know people who will grow in
medicine there's a huge market for
strictly organic and they should stay
that way you know people who just want
and yield and they go about it a
different way well and I think you
really hit on an important point there
when you said that you would everyone
was reducing the amount of synthetic
inputs that they were they were adding
into their patch and that's something
that is a goal for for myself as an
organic grower is to help people in
making that transition and get people to
use less chemical nutrients so the fact
that these biologicals are not only
better for the planet but also better
for your plant and allows you to reduce
your inputs on the chemical scient I
think is is really important all right
it's a fact and it works especially now
there's the stuff that's that snake oil
you know it may come on the market with
a great marketing pitch and fancy labels
and stuff like that but growers are
smart nowadays no matter what you're
growing whether you're growing flowers
vegetables cannabis or giant pumpkins
the word gets out they pretty quick if
the stuff doesn't work and people are
really good at looking at labels now so
if you look on there and your main
ingredient is less than 1% of 0.001 of
something that's very very reasonable
like a lot of people add you know shima
Kassadin as a base to a lot of this
stuff because it makes the water come
out nice and brown and everybody thinks
wow look at that look at all rich it is
but then when you get to educate
yourself and you read the label say I
just paid it I just paid this for a
quarter humic acid that's ridiculous so
people get shot real quick as they
should be nowadays that the information
is out there what you know what kind of
works and what doesn't
yeah I think that's an important point
because this really is for you guys a
passion it's a sport and sort of an act
of love you know it's it's not making
you any money you're really doing it
because you enjoy it so you have to make
sure you follow a budget so you're not
spending all your money on these on your
pumpkin patch I I read on big pumpkins
calm about all the people and all the
jokes that are made about how much
people love to spend on their patch and
how much time they spend out there it's
it's pretty entertaining yet you know
right now at this time of the year I'm
doing eight plants this year which is
too many I have to go back to four to
five because it's just it's just too
much you know I'm I'm 40 hours a week
out here to grow a poor
some people will put 40 hours in on four
plants or three I mean a lot of people
you get very very obsessive compulsive
with with doing this and yeah you can
spend you can spend an awful lot of
money doing this or you can get away
with some you know rudimentary skills
and go see a friend down the street or
less free compost and you can do well
too so it's just one of those things
probably like your community you kind of
get out of it what you put into it
anybody who's won these major way off
snow or something yeah they weren't
doing it by spending one or two hundred
dollars for the season to grow their
pumpkins you know they they made some
sort of investment other than time but
you can like I said you can put as much
into it or as little into it as you want
and still have you know some success but
the people who are doing it consistently
there are investing a little bit more
than time all right so you mentioned
some of these things that you're using
in your patch and some of these
techniques that apply to giant pumpkins
and I'm just wondering how might we
apply some of that knowledge to growing
cannabis so you and I just talked a
little bit off air about watering and
how important watering is can you touch
on that and how how it affects overall
yield sure our giant pumpkins here right
now my giant pumpkins you know around
for you know 400 500 pounds and like I
mentioned they're there at that stage
now or if they're going to be a stud
they got to start doing you know 38 to
50-plus pounds a day for a month so
having said that is you need water to
achieve that so I have an overhead
watering system I do a lot of watering
by hand I have 275 gallon totes where
any biologicals or any fertilizers I can
put right in a tow and I can hand water
and drench what I call a drench drench
the plants myself but these pumpkins
right now at getting close to a hundred
gallons of water a day seven days a week
we've had no rain in New England here
this season other than really early in
the spring so we have to be consistent
with our watering so I don't know how
that is in your community but our
watering has to be that you can't skip
well I'm not going to worry about water
today
hey I'm going to Beach with my friends
you know most of us have an automated
irrigation system that will go on and
off on its own me I'm home so I do have
an automated system but I choose to run
up myself where I'll have water twice a
day they'll get 50 gallons by around
11:00 11:30 in the morning I wait till
the plants a dry one of the worst things
you can do is water any plant whether it
be vegetable God and cannabis or
anything especially in the morning
especially if you're outside with this
dew on the leaves and then you start
watering especially overhead if you have
any mold spores you're just going to
blow them all over to all your plants so
it's best to let your plants dry so I
opted for kind of late morning to water
my plants so around 11:00 11:30 that
water will kick on then I'll come back
at the hottest time of the day right
around 2:30 2:30 to 3:00 o'clock I can
you know I run 6 overhead sprinklers at
one time and you know in 25 30 minutes I
can pump out another 50 gallons per
plant so I can do about 300 gallons and
in that time frame boat we find watering
has to be consistent has to be there
every single day you know if you get you
know 1 to 3 inches of rain
you can back off for a few days and
hopefully you don't get too much rain
because that's another thing we find if
you let the soil go dry and you take a
big big rainstorm you could explode your
pumpkins because now they were deprived
of water and now there's so many roots
and then they're just sucking up water
and you can have problems so we really
need to be consistent with our watering
yea because one of the things you're
finding too is without this consistency
you're losing yield which i think is the
big tick to take away for cannabis
growers is water stress whether
overwater or underwater watering is
going to affect your plants
accessibility susceptibility to disease
and also its ability to maximize yield
yeah there's a fine line on the watering
and believe me I pushed it too much many
a times because you know when it's
really hot and really humid especially
if you're growing outdoors what the root
system does is it kind of shuts down
because what it's doing is its protect
at least Amata it's protecting what you
call going up the chimney where your
vapor loss in your your water loss goes
right out through the stomata of the
leaves so when you're hot and humid the
plant protects itself so the roots kind
of close it down so you have to be
careful we do what you know watering a
lot at that time because now your roots
are just going to sit there in water the
longer they sit there in water without
working actively then you open yourself
up for Pythium water molds things like
that but I found with consistency of of
having a pumpkin what we call weighing
over the charts away non chart there's a
chart that we go by as to what your
pumpkins should weigh by inches it's
very very good shot it's very very close
in weight I fortunately have had many
that have gone over the charts which is
a good sign and that all comes from
genetics do you play some role in that
but it's watering once I started
watering a little more a few years ago
my pumpkins consistently started to
weigh more than what they should because
they're all work their water weight it
only makes sense but once again this is
a fine line as to am i adding too much
water or am i adding enough water it's
are very very very narrow so watering is
something that all gardeners no matter
what you're growing need to get dialed
in on what works
I have sandy wound soil here in New
England and people tell me all the time
hey how many gallons of water you're
riding well if I'm adding 100 gallons if
you're in Pennsylvania so when you have
a heavy clay soil that might be twice
the amount of water you need so I'm
always very leery to give watering
amounts or fertilizing the mouse I push
with boron a lot but boron rhymes with
[__] and and you can go toxic with
boron really quick but in my sandy loam
soil boron is tough to keep the levels
up I need boron for cell division cell
elongation so I have to use borax
sometimes twice a week and a pretty high
amount and I don't let that amount out
to anybody not to be secretive but I
don't want anybody doing damage to their
plants and getting toxicity because I've
been tissue testing for 25 years and I
kind of know what my plants need so I
find every Gardens different and maybe
in your community that's the same thing
a lot of growers are always
asking somebody you know hey what are
you doing it makes you always look this
good and somebody said well I use this
product and somebody says ok that that's
going to be the magic bullet well is
there's really no one magic bullet but
that person set up their lighting their
watering the drip system you know I find
that people who are successful doing
anything there's more than one thing
there's a whole program you know I hear
that a lot where people will be like you
gotta try product X it's it's the one
thing that saved my garden or made me
put on yield or it's a magic bullet yeah
but one thing that you alluded to there
was that you're doing tissue testing
you're doing soil testing and that's
something I want to talk a little more
about but really it comes down to any
deficiency so if that magic bullet
product is the limiting growth factor in
the soil or in that plant then yeah
you're gonna get amazing results but if
it's not like if your soil is already
high in potassium and this product is
high in potassium you're going to
actually potentially do something that's
detrimental for your plant so I think
that's a really important point that you
brought up that yeah I see that all the
time and somebody else said to me hey
what do you think of this product
so-and-so uses it I'm like okay well I
have respect for that person but
so-and-so has low potassium and they've
gotten and I try to teach people what
you'd be surprised how many people don't
know how to read a fertilizer label what
the three numbers mean and if you're
high in potassium like you said you're
putting potassium down to begin with
potassium is like the dominant dog you
know it is it's a number one thing that
gets in the X element a root system and
the leaf system of plant quicker and
faster than anything so if your
potassium sigh you'd know you're
blocking out magnesium and once your
plants top the yellow a bit you know
magnesium sulfur is a deficiency that's
been caused by excess potassium so I
couldn't stress that more I don't know
how the tissue testing goes in the
cannabis industry but I'm sure now with
the explosion of it that there's going
to be lad specifically testing for it
and I once you touched your garden so
many times I can tell a lot of times by
looking
what the deficiency is because I've been
in the same Gardens for 25 years and I
find the soil and the tissue test don't
vary too much in a year I tissue test
every two weeks at this time of the year
now my last tissue test will probably be
around the 1st of September and that's
pretty much enough for me to take it
home but until you really get dialed in
as to what's going on in your garden
then it really doesn't make sense to
know what's going on in a guy you know
I'm in the East Coast you're on the west
coast we're both growing cannabis but I
don't know what your conditions are so
it's tough for me to educate somebody
until they get dialed in in their own
patch and a good way of doing that is
with the you know tissue tissue testings
people tell me well I saw I'll test it
the other day well soil is only going to
tell you what's available what's there
the tissue test is going to tell you
what's going up the plant and that's the
most important thing at the stage we're
at right now we're on pumpkins it's
about tissue testing yeah it's a little
challenging with cannabis for a couple
reasons so one the big challenge is not
a lot of labs will do tissue testing on
cannabis because it is still federally
illegal so you can't mail samples in for
example so that's one challenge the
other challenge is that a lot of growers
don't know how to interpret soil tests
or tissue tests so the one of the tests
that we now sell is an artificial resin
test from this company called soil savvy
and what it is is it shows what the
plant potentially could take up over a
period of five days so the advantage of
that being it gives you a little better
idea of what the plant is able to take
out of the soil versus say like a male
like three tests that will just tell us
everything that's in the soil but not
what's available to the plant so that's
that's a good point there that you
brought up regarding regarding testing
so what you're doing is a combination of
soil testing chemical fertilizers in
small amounts and then biologicals is
that is that pretty accurate that that's
a hundred percent accurate and like I
said the biologicals have been huge for
us and you know specifically in the last
you know you know maybe about ten years
ago it started to get a big push because
you remember for years you know even
fine
didn't get much credit to biologicals
now everybody knows the important role
that they play in your garden so yeah
biological is a huge you know for us and
the combination of them and you know no
one's ever burnt their plants I'll put
on biologicals and then walk away the
next day and came out and had fertilizer
burn so bad that you that it affected
you yield from biologicals you know
biological is a little bit goes a long
way to it's all about you know
multiplying colonies in your soil and it
takes time I can tell people all the
time now it you got to stop biologicals
early because if you do have a if you do
have a problem yeah it's like taking a
knife to a gunfight point at some point
you can't come in with biologicals when
you have a problem you can't start
midway in the cycle of the season yeah
it's better than nothing you know if you
have no choice you can start at them but
if you stop them right from the
beginning right right out of the box
right into the soil that's that's how
you start with you know mycorrhizae and
any biological is when the plants small
so what are you using exactly in your
garden right now you mentioned humic and
fulvic acid
you mentioned potentially compost teas
and mycorrhizal fungus what sorts of
things are you using in your patch I use
a lot of seaweed a lot of seaweed powder
and you know I have a tremendous one you
know my site that I use pretty much
every watering as humic fall of it and
seaweed in it I mean seaweeds one of the
best overall things you can feed your
plants because of the you know trace
minerals and nutrients it helps
remineralize your soil that's one of the
best things that you can use and and I
use that pretty much everyone I opt to
feed daily and spoon-feed rather and put
on a heavy dose once or twice a week so
every day I'm feeding I use a lot of
l-amino acids is a great product out
there from growth products called
essential essential and companion
companions bacillus subtilis which is a
great you know biological to help shield
roots for diseases those two are like my
peanut butter and jelly they go together
every two weeks every 14 maybe 17 days
I'm going on with a drench of those two
you know biologicals and there they're
tremendous
also in that drench I'll use a Zoe's
from extreme gardening you know azo
Sperling I mean it's a tremendous fixer
of atmospheric nitrogen but another
benefit of it is it helps plants create
that natural growth hormone indole-3
acidic acid it it promotes that
naturally in the plant that's the
biggest benefit to me because the more
roots that you have that it creates the
more roots the more areas you have for
inoculation by your mycorrhizal fungi so
it's a total whole program you know I
also use you know like epsom salts you
know I take up many home gardeners know
by now it's not just for soaking your
feet as a sauce you know applies a quick
shot of magnesium and sulfur and my
potassium gets a little high in my soil
I made the mistake of adding too much
compost last fall so I paid the price so
far this season by tying up nutrients so
if I need to need add some quick a quick
shot of sulfur and some magnesium
there's nothing better or more realistic
in price than M some salts so so I use a
lot of fish you know seaweed powdered
seaweed you know I call it fish
efficient seaweed it's a mixture of the
two humic folic acid and those
biological as I mentioned pretty much
they're in my program once a week I'm
doing that and some of the other ones
I'm doing like the companion and
essential every two weeks that's by
labeled rate it was there's no need of
putting it on more than label rate
because you know some of that stuff can
get costly you don't want to waste money
but without ever expanding root system
on our plant we need to apply it a
little more often if you're growing in
like it seems to be like out in New
England the legal cannabis growers grow
12 plants and pretty much everybody
grows in between a 5 gallon 15 gallon
pot seems to be the home gardener here
to probably do it a little less because
your roots are contained our root system
is so vast and we'll find roots you know
tens
out past where the vines are in our
garden and there'll be no leaf or vying
around within ten foot those those roots
are just racing past a plant and you
know they're looking for they're looking
for water and nutrients so we have to
you know we probably have to cut the
rate down a little bit and drink a
little bit more with that stuff but
that's a pretty much the basis of my
biological you know program but then
like I mentioned the borax too and I do
that I put it in with my epson salt and
and I have to do that here for you know
for reasons I mentioned because of my
sandy loam soil yeah well you know
there's some good studies out especially
with seaweed that show that you know
micro dosa is a greater frequency
perform much better than high doses
fewer times a year so it definitely
makes a difference to apply these things
like you are in smaller amounts at
greater frequency especially with the
humic acid and a seaweed so I'm glad you
brought that up and then yeah I cut the
label rate down on that um drenching out
of 275 gallon tanks right now and like
the label rates you know what was called
a teaspoon per gallon you know you I
mean just think of how much product you
would need each drink so I cut that down
you know by less than half you know
sometimes a quarter of it I'll do like a
quarter of the amount but I'm doing it
three four days in a row unless I get
some rain so I'm like I said I'd rather
be there just a little bit at a time and
I can tell you another connection that
we have now to you know with with
cannabis growers is pretty much a lot of
the heavy hitters in the Hobby world pH
and I water now that's something we
never did up until a couple of years ago
you'd be surprised what some of these
nutrients can do with the pH G of water
once you start adding them I was shocked
when I first started pH in my water back
in 2015 just how something skyrocketed
it and some stuff dropped it and I find
kind of pH around 6-2 or something like
that seems uh seems to work best for the
plants but that's another common
connection and what we're doing you know
in what you know your communities doing
now there's a lot
of parallels there at one of the things
I like to bring up because you guys are
just as passionate about your plants as
cannabis growers are and you're both
pushing the envelope in terms of trying
out the latest in the greatest
techniques or the latest and greatest
products as a way of maximizing growth
and yield so there's a lot of parallels
there in fact I think you guys are
actually a little more fanatic because
you hear not getting you're not getting
a final product that's either edible or
smokeable or sellable you're really just
doing it for the satisfaction of this
you know having the largest vegetable in
the world yeah you know that's a very
good point because we're not you know oz
has not grown for you know for
consumption it has no medical you know
value to it or anything but aza grown
just yeah just for size and you know
some people grow for color you know some
people you know they like their genetics
and the only plant stuff that's gonna
throw a really pretty orange you know
pumpkin but you know most of us just
strictly precise oh yeah we do push the
envelope a bit more it's a very very
good point where you know someone in
your community might not because of you
know the medical you know value of the
things like that but yeah we do we do
push the envelope you know real hard and
real fast that's for sure you know once
again to think that you know we're
probably only four or five years away
maybe from a 3,000 pound pumpkin it'll
probably be done by somebody growing in
the greenhouse you know we got some
really good greenhouse growers now and
you know I I started a I used a bigger
greenhouse this year in the spring for
the first time ever I was only in it for
six weeks and it blew you know it blew
the plants right out of the water they
were growing so fast I mean I was not in
there for the heated season because
being in New England unless you had
thousands of dollars you could never
cool it I get the airflow in there to
mean pain but my first six weeks I grew
in a greenhouse was like one team
playing with aluminum bats and one team
playing what wooden bats is no
comparison so I think the first 3,000
pound pumpkin will be grown in a
greenhouse but they think that we're on
the verge of that is
incredible nothing should get that big
and once again I'll say it a hundred
times that comes from people willingly
working with each other and sharing
information and knowledge and you know
pumpkin growers like you said you said
it best we push the envelope because we
just called the size what I find with
the cannabis community that reaches out
to me this a small negro is who really
that I found that really want to educate
themselves and they really want to do
better they want better healthier plants
they want a bigger yield those are the
ones that are on the internet and
they're studying they're studying labels
as studying biologicals and those are
the ones that kind of reach out to me
and ask a lot of questions I find around
here in New England most who got
involved in the cannabis wave that came
in huge for us a few years ago and
everybody thought because maybe they
liked the effects of cannabis that
they'd be good at running a business
doing it well they kind of all went out
of business already but I found a lot of
them if their friend got him into the
Hobby and said hey this is all you need
to use you use this this cycle this
cycle that cycle and you're all done I
find a good percentage of those growers
never do anything else they use anything
else because they're perfectly happy
with enough for their own consumption
and then maybe sell some to a dispensary
or to a friend to make a couple extra
bucks I those that's that's a big
percentage of people in our area here
but there's a there's a 1/4 of that
that'll really want to educate
themselves and and push their plants and
they're not afraid to make a mistake
anybody who's growing anything better
than anybody else they've made mistakes
where they've lost a crop they've lost
yield they've made mistakes but then
they come back and they perfected it and
they've done better so it's those people
that I'm afraid to push the envelope
that eventually are going to get honed
in on a system yeah so really the big
takeaway in my book is it's all about
figuring out what the limiting factor of
growth is whether it's your genetics
whether it's your watering whether it's
some sort of nutrient imbalance or some
sort of lacking microbe or biological
activity in your soil whatever
is that limiting your overall growth or
you know in some case like you mentioned
it maybe root space and maybe you're in
a container too small but whatever it is
that's limiting is what's going to
determine your overall yield so if you
can reduce the number of things that are
limiting factors in your soil or remove
them you're going to maximize the
plant's ability to grow healthy to to
grow a giant pumpkin or grow a really
good high-quality cannabis that's that's
sure I couldn't have said it better
myself in how much acid are you putting
in what's it come down to the time you
know there's a reason why that people
consistently grow the best you know the
best quality the best yields whether
it's pumpkins cannabis or whatever
you'll find that they're working really
hard and they're putting in the effort
and I tell people time you can't expect
to get those results by putting in that
effort and so you know a lot of that
comes down to effort too at times and
how much of how much you're putting into
it but there's a real fascination the
connection between cannabis growers and
giant pumpkin growers because that you
know what I found is they're all very
friendly again everybody it's like a
mutual admiration society you get
everybody in a room it doesn't matter
what you do for a living what you did
what your race is nothing that all fades
away the common love for growing what
you're growing and then the information
starts come on I don't know about your
community but in our community there's
really no secrets everybody just sits
there and tells everybody I think this
will help have you tried this can you do
this you know because that's how we've
pushed along and and succeeded and you
know push him all right we've got people
growing eight pound tomatoes now that
they're pushing the envelope towards the
world's first ten pound tomato I mean
that's that's incredible you know that
really is incredible as someone who
loves Ingres Tomatoes I can't even
imagine they were going to eat anywhere
close to that but oh go ahead well I've
grown five pound Tomatoes and I don't
put a ton of effort into my you know
tomatoes and stuff I grow really nice
did the giant tomatoes I don't my
vegetable garden looks it looks really
good but they're just it's crazy you
know genetics of what some of these
plants are capable of now but you know
once again that all goes back to
everybody sharing it
in making these genetic crosses and
making the seeds you know available the
plants available to people you know this
at big pumpkins calm the website you
mentioned is yeah that's a go-to for
giant pumpkin growers always has been
and you know it's still as popular if
not more even with the onset of
Instagram and Facebook and all that
stuff where a lot of people get their
information big pumpkins is still a
community that we go to to post our
information yeah I heard Jerry Seinfeld
got on there for a little bit apparently
I did I did hear that somebody played
that for me awhile ago you know the
giant pumpkins have brought success and
it brought notoriety to people going you
name all those national shows a lot of
the pumpkin growers have been on them
it's really brought a lot of attention
to the Hobby because what might be a
little bit different you know where
cannabis sometimes has still looked upon
as not being as overall accepted as what
a giant pumpkin would be everybody loves
a giant pumpkin everybody smiles every
October it's like we got to see a giant
pumpkin so you know a lot of the growers
have been on a national news every
magazine you know TV you name it and it
brings a lot of attention to the Hobby
and you know which is which is great
yeah so let's talk a little bit about
what you're doing now so we talked you
mentioned mycorrhizal fungus and i know
that you now sell some of these products
you have a you have a website which I'll
mention at the beginning or you can
mention it right now and as well as some
of the some products that you really
believe in can you talk a little about
what you're doing now for a business
sure
well Wallace Wow dot-com is my website
and you know like I mentioned earlier I
got fascinated in the study of
mycorrhizal fungi you know back in 2002
2003 I started educating myself more and
became really fascinated by it and I you
know sent my first world record in 2006
and the big part of that was using
mycorrhizae fungi
I know I found over the years that there
was there was a market for people who
were very much interested in obtaining
high-quality mycorrhizal fungi and fresh
mycorrhizal fungi not something that
been sitting on a shelf y'all are in a
warehouse for a few years because all of
these biologicals they don't get any
better the longer they sit in a bag so
uh you know foodservice had been my you
know my trade I was a you know executive
chef and in the business my whole life
and four years ago now I started working
with a manufacturer and he said hey
Ronnie you would be really good at
running your own business you got brand
recognition a respected guy you know so
let's work together so we did so it's
been spent four years now and I retired
from my job at the Country Club and
February you know for a few reasons one
I worked in food service all my life I
worked every night weekend and holiday
for 35 years since high school and to
that business became so demanding and so
popular you know knock on wood that I
had to dedicate it could not be done
you know what part-time hours anymore
had to be full-time so so I do I have a
lot of you know happy customers and they
both the cannabis and you know giant
pumpkin community home gardeners people
growing flowers you name it
you know they found me on the internet
and you know what I find is I'm you know
I have kind of a grassroots approach and
you know if people didn't like the
product and it didn't work and then it
wouldn't sell but once again what I
found in you know giant pumpkin
community and the cannabis community is
they're very free to mention hey this
product really did worked well for me
you should try it and so that's kind of
how I got my grassroots approach and
built the business you know because you
know didn't have the budget going in to
be spending you know a thousand dollars
a month on Google AdWords or anything
else like that so kind of started slow
and it really it really took off these
people are very happy with the product
the labels are easy to read the
directions
you know I stand behind you know my
products and you know I sell a lot of
things that you know people use
every day gardens I have a you know I
was a starter pack a lot of cannabis
growers use and you know starting there
you know they transplants in they seem
to really like them you know the home
gardeners you know I find that women
drives the market for the home gardeners
because I get tons of email from women
and and they have legitimate concerns
hey I don't want my hands in a bag of
fertilizer so you know my starter pack
is enclosed in a tea bag and all you
have to do is take tea bag out don't
even have to open it up put it
underneath the plant and walk away and
they really like them so things have
been things have been going real well
for me and you know I brought on a
social media person recently and I have
some help now in my warehouse with
shipping and receiving because it
started getting out in front of me where
you know like any small business how
much inventory do I need and then you
know hey I'm sure you can attest to
these mistakes too you get get
short-handed a couple times in inventory
because you don't know just what you
need you don't want to have too much
because you know my whole thing is
freshness it if it's not fresh I'm not
gonna sell it to you so Wow but things
are things have been working out very
very happy doing it
I love the emails I get from people I
love be educating it's my passion
I love soil I love science it's been
very passionate about it and and the
members of the wall families what I call
them they're very passionate about
growing too so it's worked out really
well yeah that's really great you know I
hadn't you and I started talking when
you originally started the business we
were talking about my cries with fungus
just conversations over the phone and
you you and I had talked about you know
this some of the packaging sizes and
I've been using and selling the five
pound package that you have the wow Mike
ERISA for a few years now you've been
doing this it's great to hear you're
expanding and things are going well
that's really really great thank you and
thank you for your support
you've been instrumental in helping me
are you my first you know wholesale
account so to speak that kind of got me
going we work together on figuring
things out you've been instrumental and
helping with the packaging and once
again I've found that with many many
people but I've dealt with who have a
business they've been more than
open to saying hey take a look at this
here's how we should be looking at this
and I was to come in the business I came
from food service you couldn't call up
somebody who was a competitor or sold
similar products and said hey what do
you think I found that a lot of people
in this end of it have been you know
like karma they feel if they good to you
you'll be good to them everybody
succeeds and there's plenty of room for
everybody and and it's yeah it's it's
been it's been amazing every day I'm
thankful when I wake up and and I have
orders to fulfill I'm very very blessed
yeah you know we do sell similar
products but at the same time like you
mentioned we're all we're all doing
something better for the world I feel
like if we're getting people to use
organics and promoting biologicals so
I'm all for it and the the thing that I
really love about your product is it is
the right species it's the Glomus inter
a disease or rise Oh Vegas
irregularities the new name but it's the
right species of micro so for most
vegetables including pumpkins and
cannabis and I know if I'm buying it for
you I'm eating something that's fresh
and that's really important to me
because I'm not going through a giant
distribution system where it may have
been you know in a warehouse for a year
before getting to a hydro shop and then
I'm buying it there or online you really
don't know what you get either so no I
really enjoy working with you and I wish
you the best with your your business
thank you very much yeah we're gonna
continue to work hard every day and sell
a highness quality freshest you know
mycorrhizal product out there I'm just
just blessed to be and such you know
there's two big communities as you know
the giant pumpkins one cuz I'll always
be you know I am that you know giant
pumpkin man is what everybody calls me
uh-huh but and a cannabis community is
has accepted me very very well I think
they're like working with small business
you know people and I get a lot of
comments I was shocked they are that I
actually returned a phone call in an
email I said no I do that every day so
but that's wonderful communities to work
in some really nice people who are
working hard to you know make the world
a better place that's for sure and I
thoroughly enjoy it well hopefully you
can see another world record this year
that'd be great
well would be that's my goal you know I
have a goal I'd love to win another
world championship and that would be my
fourth and that would tie how would dill
the Creator at four World Championships
and I think if I could do that one day I
would probably take a year or two off
that is my goal is to tie to tie Howard
the world record that's always my goal I
think me personally I'm probably a few
years away from that
I mean 2624 pounds was and is an
incredible incredible pumpkin so I have
to perfect my system a little bit more
now I have to get a better start with my
greenhouses and I need some pretty good
weather and so it probably won't happen
for me this year but we're gonna have
fun whatever I get won't be from a lack
of effort that's for sure but yeah one
day I'll hoist that that record again
I'm sure that's my goal and if you if
you don't have a goal if you can't think
it you'll never do it that was Ron
Wallace two-time world record holder and
three-time world champion four giant
pumpkins his website is Wallace Wow calm
where you can see photos of the amazing
pumpkins he's growing along with other
vegetables I hope today's podcast was
helpful for growers when considering
yield and how we can incorporate some of
these principles with growing cannabis
if you're interested in growing your own
giant pumpkin I suggest checking out big
pumpkins calm it's a great form you're
listening to the cannabis cultivation
and science podcast I'm your host Todd
Hussey don't forget there's more
information articles available on our
website and blog at WWE and calm as well
as links to the data and information we
discuss in this episode on the podcast
page
you